<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:content="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >
<channel>

<title >Auto News | Latest Automobiles &amp; Auto Industry Information and Updates: ET Auto : ETAuto.com</title>

<description >Find the latest automobile Auto Insight, News &amp; Articles from all top sources for the Indian Auto industry on ET Auto.</description>

<link >https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology</link>

<language >en-us</language>

<lastBuildDate >2024-07-18T23:56:38+05:30</lastBuildDate>

<atom:link type="application/rss+xml" rel="self" href="https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/rss/auto-technology"/>

<copyright >Copyright:(C) Bennett Coleman &amp; Co. Ltd</copyright>

<docs >http://syndication.indiatimes.com/</docs>

<enclosure >
<title >Top Auto News | Latest Automobiles &amp; Auto Industry Information and Updates: ET Auto : ETAuto.com</title>

<link >https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology</link>

<url >https://img.etb2bimg.com/files/cp/upload-1679565869-et-auto-light-theme.png</url>
</enclosure>
<item>
<title>Jitendra EV announces new upgrades for JMT Model</title>
<link>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/jitendra-ev-announces-new-upgrades-for-jmt-model/111826779</link>
<description>With a starting price of INR 70,000, the JMT model is an economical solution for businesses transitioning to electric vehicles and consumers looking for eco-friendly travel options. The robust design ensures durability and lower maintenance costs, making it ideal for both commercial and residential users. Features include a split rear seat for comfort and a spacious cargo area, making it suitable for delivering food, groceries, dairy products, pharmacy items, and more. It's also a viable option for personal commuting.</description>
<guid>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/jitendra-ev-announces-new-upgrades-for-jmt-model/111826779</guid>
<enclosure type="image/jpeg" url="https://etimg.etb2bimg.com/photo/jitendra-ev-announces-new-upgrades-for-jmt-model-size-40778/111826779.cms"/>
<pubDate>2024-07-18T12:10:19+05:30</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Low-cost hydrogen cell startup Protonas bags funding in round led by Transition VC</title>
<link>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/low-cost-hydrogen-cell-startup-protonas-bags-funding-in-round-led-by-transition-vc/111827118</link>
<description>The company aims to deploy its solutions to offer cost-effective backup power applications in the North American markets. Additionally, it aims to power fuel cell engines for three-wheeler transportation and four-wheeler delivery applications in India and other Asian markets.</description>
<guid>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/low-cost-hydrogen-cell-startup-protonas-bags-funding-in-round-led-by-transition-vc/111827118</guid>
<enclosure type="image/jpeg" url="https://etimg.etb2bimg.com/photo/low-cost-hydrogen-cell-startup-protonas-bags-funding-in-round-led-by-transition-vc-size-78664/111827118.cms"/>
<pubDate>2024-07-18T11:20:44+05:30</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Hinduja Tech signs definitive agreement to acquire TECOSIM Group</title>
<link>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/hinduja-tech-signs-definitive-agreement-to-acquire-tecosim-group/111822816</link>
<description>Hinduja Tech is focused on expanding its mobility engineering services worldwide. The acquisition of TECOSIM Group, which employs over 650 people, will give Hinduja Tech a significant foothold in Europe. This move is intended to broaden the company's geographic reach and provide access to key customer accounts in the region.</description>
<guid>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/hinduja-tech-signs-definitive-agreement-to-acquire-tecosim-group/111822816</guid>
<enclosure type="image/jpeg" url="https://etimg.etb2bimg.com/photo/hinduja-tech-signs-definitive-agreement-to-acquire-tecosim-group-size-71108/111822816.cms"/>
<pubDate>2024-07-18T08:49:35+05:30</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Roadcast and AMU collaborate to make EV leasing more accessible and risk-free</title>
<link>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/roadcast-and-amu-collaborate-to-make-ev-leasing-more-accessible-and-risk-free/111806107</link>
<description>Roadcast is a leader in fleet management solutions, offering smart tools like GPS tracking, while AMU has been pivotal in promoting the adoption of EVs. By integrating GPS technology in the 3W e-rickshaws leased by AMU, the company will be able to predict and identify non-performing assets and potential defaulters. The analytics capabilities provided by Roadcast’s technology will also offer insights into the performance of original equipment manufacturers (OEMs), enabling AMU to make more informed decisions.</description>
<guid>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/roadcast-and-amu-collaborate-to-make-ev-leasing-more-accessible-and-risk-free/111806107</guid>
<enclosure type="image/jpeg" url="https://etimg.etb2bimg.com/photo/roadcast-and-amu-collaborate-to-make-ev-leasing-more-accessible-and-risk-free-size-74404/111806107.cms"/>
<pubDate>2024-07-17T14:58:04+05:30</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Electrics, hybrids and ICE: Suzuki advocates multi pathway approach for the next decade</title>
<link>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/hevs-vs-evs-suzukis-roadmap-suggests-hevs-lead-in-energy-efficiency-in-india-until-2030/111802053</link>
<description>Japan’s Suzuki Motor Corporation (SMC) has underlined the efficacy of HEVs, saying that in regions where adoption of non-fossil fuel electric energy is lower, HEVs are the best choice. In a 10-year technology roadmap outlined earlier today, Chief Technology Officer Katushiro Kato has said that EVs become the better choice only when adoption of non-fossil fuel electric energy reaches 75%.</description>
<guid>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/hevs-vs-evs-suzukis-roadmap-suggests-hevs-lead-in-energy-efficiency-in-india-until-2030/111802053</guid>
<enclosure type="image/jpeg" url="https://etimg.etb2bimg.com/photo/electrics-hybrids-and-ice-suzuki-advocates-multi-pathway-approach-for-the-next-decade-size-35048/111802053.cms"/>
<pubDate>2024-07-17T12:27:12+05:30</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>US to issue proposed rules limiting Chinese vehicle software in August</title>
<link>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/us-to-issue-proposed-rules-limiting-chinese-vehicle-software-in-august/111800240</link>
<description>&amp;quot;We're looking at a few components and some software - not the whole car - but it would be some of the key driver components of the vehicle that manage the software and manage the data around that car that would have to be made in an allied country,&amp;quot; said export controls chief Alan Estevez at a forum in Colorado.</description>
<guid>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/us-to-issue-proposed-rules-limiting-chinese-vehicle-software-in-august/111800240</guid>
<enclosure type="image/jpeg" url="https://etimg.etb2bimg.com/photo/us-to-issue-proposed-rules-limiting-chinese-vehicle-software-in-august-size-159184/111800240.cms"/>
<pubDate>2024-07-17T11:11:38+05:30</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Tokyo airport trials driverless cargo vehicle</title>
<link>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/tokyo-airport-trials-driverless-cargo-vehicle/111800112</link>
<description>Tokyo's Haneda Airport is trialling a driverless vehicle to tow cargo containers in an attempt to get around labour shortages as the number of tourists flying into Japan soars. The vehicle at one of the world's busiest airports can tow up to 13 tons of containers, joint developers All Nippon Airways (ANA) and Toyota Industries said in a statement.</description>
<guid>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/tokyo-airport-trials-driverless-cargo-vehicle/111800112</guid>
<enclosure type="image/jpeg" url="https://etimg.etb2bimg.com/photo/tokyo-airport-trials-driverless-cargo-vehicle-size-35186/111800112.cms"/>
<pubDate>2024-07-17T11:06:17+05:30</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Daewoo India launches AGM VRLA Silver+ 2W battery with advanced Korean technology</title>
<link>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/daewoo-india-launches-agm-vrla-silver-2w-battery-with-advanced-korean-technology/111753872</link>
<description>The new battery range includes four models: DW2.5LC, DWZ4, DW-Z5, and DW5LB. The batteries combine 24 months of free replacement warranty with an additional 24 months of pro-rata coverage, ensuring customer satisfaction and reliability.</description>
<guid>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/daewoo-india-launches-agm-vrla-silver-2w-battery-with-advanced-korean-technology/111753872</guid>
<enclosure type="image/jpeg" url="https://etimg.etb2bimg.com/photo/daewoo-india-launches-agm-vrla-silver-2w-battery-with-advanced-korean-technology-size-14370/111753872.cms"/>
<pubDate>2024-07-15T16:29:34+05:30</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>India can do to AI what China did to manufacturing: Bhavish Aggarwal, Ola</title>
<link>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/india-can-do-to-ai-what-china-did-to-manufacturing-bhavish-aggarwal-ola/111743287</link>
<description>&amp;quot;India has the largest number of developers in the world. It also has the largest number of silicon designers in the world, the largest amount of data in the world and the largest IT services industry in the world,&amp;quot; said Ola Founder and CEO Bhavish Aggarwal.</description>
<guid>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/india-can-do-to-ai-what-china-did-to-manufacturing-bhavish-aggarwal-ola/111743287</guid>
<enclosure type="image/jpeg" url="https://etimg.etb2bimg.com/photo/india-can-do-to-ai-what-china-did-to-manufacturing-bhavish-aggarwal-ola-size-29954/111743287.cms"/>
<pubDate>2024-07-15T09:32:09+05:30</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Green hydrogen consumption to be escalated from 2040, says Atul Jairaj, Deloitte</title>
<link>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/green-hydrogen-consumption-to-be-escalated-from-2040-says-atul-jairaj-deloitte/111683590</link>
<description>Deloitte's report at ETAuto Tech Summit 2024 calls for a transition from ICE to non-ICE vehicles like CNG, LPG, biofuel, green hydrogen, and EVs to reduce import bills and achieve sustainability. FY 2023-24 saw 232.5 million metric tonnes of crude oil imports. The report targets carbon neutrality by 2070 and greenhouse gas reductions by 2045, addressing vehicle afterlife sustainability.</description>
<guid>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/green-hydrogen-consumption-to-be-escalated-from-2040-says-atul-jairaj-deloitte/111683590</guid>
<enclosure type="image/jpeg" url="https://etimg.etb2bimg.com/photo/green-hydrogen-consumption-to-be-escalated-from-2040-says-atul-jairaj-deloitte-size-48240/111683590.cms"/>
<pubDate>2024-07-12T14:00:07+05:30</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Triton EV unveils hydrogen internal combustion engine</title>
<link>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/triton-ev-unveils-hydrogen-internal-combustion-engine/111682087</link>
<description>Triton EV's hydrogen engine marks a significant advancement in automotive technology. Utilizing hydrogen as a clean and abundant fuel source, this innovative engine produces zero carbon emissions. Unlike traditional gasoline engines, which emit carbon dioxide and other greenhouse gases that contribute to global warming.</description>
<guid>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/triton-ev-unveils-hydrogen-internal-combustion-engine/111682087</guid>
<enclosure type="image/jpeg" url="https://etimg.etb2bimg.com/photo/triton-ev-unveils-hydrogen-internal-combustion-engine-size-27950/111682087.cms"/>
<pubDate>2024-07-12T13:06:27+05:30</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Tata Elxsi and Emerson inaugurate Mobility Innovation Centre in Bengaluru</title>
<link>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/tata-elxsi-and-emerson-inaugurate-mobility-innovation-centre-in-bengaluru/111664758</link>
<description>The launch event was attended by Manoj Raghavan, MD &amp;amp; CEO of Tata Elxsi, Ritu Favre, President of the Test and Measurement Business Group at Emerson, and Drita Roggenbuck, VP &amp;amp; GM of the Transportation Business Unit at Emerson. Senior technology and R&amp;amp;D leaders from global OEMs, major automotive suppliers, and semiconductor companies were also present, highlighting the importance of TENMIC in enhancing automotive development and innovation.</description>
<guid>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/tata-elxsi-and-emerson-inaugurate-mobility-innovation-centre-in-bengaluru/111664758</guid>
<enclosure type="image/jpeg" url="https://etimg.etb2bimg.com/photo/tata-elxsi-and-emerson-inaugurate-mobility-innovation-centre-in-bengaluru-size-29580/111664758.cms"/>
<pubDate>2024-07-11T18:27:48+05:30</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Government to launch roadmap for electric mobility R&amp;amp;D on July 16</title>
<link>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/government-to-launch-roadmap-for-electric-mobility-rd-on-july-16/111658162</link>
<description>Currently, India’s dependence on foreign countries for essential elements acts as a hindrance for its e-mobility drive. </description>
<guid>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/government-to-launch-roadmap-for-electric-mobility-rd-on-july-16/111658162</guid>
<enclosure type="image/jpeg" url="https://etimg.etb2bimg.com/photo/government-to-launch-roadmap-for-electric-mobility-r-d-on-july-16-size-50106/111658162.cms"/>
<pubDate>2024-07-11T14:50:22+05:30</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>It's easy to criticize, hard to create; my motto is never give up, says Henrik Fisker</title>
<link>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/its-easy-to-criticize-hard-to-create-my-motto-is-never-give-up-says-henrik-fisker/111648162</link>
<description>Fisker admitted that while the auto industry might be the hardest to succeed, the nascent EV industry is even more difficult. But he is personally “excited about doing great work in this industry and bringing new innovative EVs to the world”. Charging infrastructure is in the early stages of becoming as reliable as gas fueling systems. Other challenges on the manufacturing front, development cost, government policies also exist.</description>
<guid>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/its-easy-to-criticize-hard-to-create-my-motto-is-never-give-up-says-henrik-fisker/111648162</guid>
<enclosure type="image/jpeg" url="https://etimg.etb2bimg.com/photo/it-s-easy-to-criticize-hard-to-create-my-motto-is-never-give-up-says-henrik-fisker-size-38832/111648162.cms"/>
<pubDate>2024-07-11T08:02:57+05:30</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Proactive cybersecurity: The achilles heel of the EV ecosystem</title>
<link>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/proactive-cybersecurity-the-achilles-heel-of-the-ev-ecosystem/111626593</link>
<description>Given EVs' interconnected nature and reliance on local power grids, a new set of risks is created for drivers, companies and infrastructure. This makes it critical for all organisations within the EV ecosystem to adopt a preventive security approach to get ahead of threat actors and deliver secure vehicles and infrastructure.</description>
<guid>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/proactive-cybersecurity-the-achilles-heel-of-the-ev-ecosystem/111626593</guid>
<enclosure type="image/jpeg" url="https://etimg.etb2bimg.com/photo/proactive-cybersecurity-the-achilles-heel-of-the-ev-ecosystem-size-11232/111626593.cms"/>
<pubDate>2024-07-10T12:21:44+05:30</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Altair and ARAI signs MoU to advance technology and digital transformation goals</title>
<link>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/altair-and-arai-signs-mou-to-advance-technology-and-digital-transformation-goals/111620676</link>
<description>Altair and ARAI signed an MoU to leverage digital twin tech, data-driven design, and AI solutions, enhancing electrification, connectivity, and energy management. Leaders Stephanie Buckner and Reji Mathai noted ARAI's testing benefits. Altair's advanced simulation and data analytics will integrate into ARAI’s consulting, promoting AI-driven engineering, cutting-edge technologies, and sustainable R&amp;amp;D processes.</description>
<guid>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/altair-and-arai-signs-mou-to-advance-technology-and-digital-transformation-goals/111620676</guid>
<enclosure type="image/jpeg" url="https://etimg.etb2bimg.com/photo/altair-and-arai-signs-mou-to-advance-technology-and-digital-transformation-goals-size-50820/111620676.cms"/>
<pubDate>2024-07-10T08:31:24+05:30</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Accelerating vehicle engineering from concept to road in 24 months</title>
<link>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/accelerating-vehicle-engineering-from-concept-to-road-in-24-months/111620621</link>
<description>AI is revolutionizing the industry, promising increased efficiency and less mundane work. While AI is not yet capable of designing a car with the push of a button, its rapid advancement is reshaping how we learn and work. The automotive industry is undergoing massive change, ignited by the EV revolution and fueled by software-defined vehicles and autonomy.</description>
<guid>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/accelerating-vehicle-engineering-from-concept-to-road-in-24-months/111620621</guid>
<enclosure type="image/jpeg" url="https://etimg.etb2bimg.com/photo/accelerating-vehicle-engineering-from-concept-to-road-in-24-months-size-56008/111620621.cms"/>
<pubDate>2024-07-10T08:13:56+05:30</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>ZF’s ‘flexible’ approach to bring in global technology innovations</title>
<link>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/zfs-flexible-approach-to-bring-in-global-technology-innovations/111604478</link>
<description>The German auto component major, which has a stronghold in areas like transmissions, feels its core strength lies in extending to all categories of vehicles, which puts it in a position to industrialize innovations “quickly” and offer them to customers at “competitive prices”. In the industrial technology domain, it is quite confident it will benefit from achieving economies of scale.</description>
<guid>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/zfs-flexible-approach-to-bring-in-global-technology-innovations/111604478</guid>
<enclosure type="image/jpeg" url="https://etimg.etb2bimg.com/photo/zf-s-flexible-approach-to-bring-in-global-technology-innovations-size-917530/111604478.cms"/>
<pubDate>2024-07-09T15:22:14+05:30</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Michelin collaborates with DPIIT to launch the Michelin AI Startup Challenge</title>
<link>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/michelin-collaborates-with-dpiit-to-launch-the-michelin-ai-startup-challenge/111600538</link>
<description>Michelin and DPIIT launch the AI Startup Challenge in India. Officials including Shri Sanjiv, Shri Sumeet Kumar Jarangal, Dr Ambica Rajagopal, and Shri Shantanu Deshpande attended. Hosted on the Startup India portal, startups receive mentorship, INR 5 lakh for paid pilot projects, and potential global contracts. Shri Rajesh Kumar Singh highlighted demos set for September 2024.</description>
<guid>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/michelin-collaborates-with-dpiit-to-launch-the-michelin-ai-startup-challenge/111600538</guid>
<enclosure type="image/jpeg" url="https://etimg.etb2bimg.com/photo/michelin-collaborates-with-dpiit-to-launch-the-michelin-ai-startup-challenge-size-64626/111600538.cms"/>
<pubDate>2024-07-09T15:09:21+05:30</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>