<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >
<channel>

<title >Auto News | Latest Automobiles &amp; Auto Industry Information and Updates: ET Auto : ETAuto.com</title>

<description >Find the latest automobile Auto Insight, News &amp; Articles from all top sources for the Indian Auto industry on ET Auto.</description>

<link >https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology</link>

<language >en-us</language>

<lastBuildDate >Sun, 15 Sep 2024 18:23:36 +0530</lastBuildDate>

<atom:link type="application/rss+xml" rel="self" href="https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/rss/auto-technology"/>

<copyright >Copyright:(C) Bennett Coleman &amp; Co. Ltd</copyright>

<docs >http://syndication.indiatimes.com/</docs>

<image >
<title >Auto News | Latest Automobiles &amp; Auto Industry Information and Updates: ET Auto : ETAuto.com</title>

<link >https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology</link>

<url >https://img.etb2bimg.com/files/cp/upload-1679565869-et-auto-light-theme.png</url>
</image>
<item>
<title>Lumax Auto Technologies acquires majority stake in Greenfuel Energy Solutions to enter green fuels market</title>
<link>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/lumax-auto-technologies-acquires-majority-stake-in-greenfuel-energy-solutions-to-enter-green-fuels-market/113352352</link>
<description>Lumax Auto Technologies Limited is set to enter the green and alternate fuels segment by acquiring a majority stake in Greenfuel Energy Solutions. This strategic move aims to expand Lumax's offerings in CNG, hydrogen, and other applications, positioning them as leaders in the growing alternate fuels market.</description>
<guid>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/lumax-auto-technologies-acquires-majority-stake-in-greenfuel-energy-solutions-to-enter-green-fuels-market/113352352</guid>
<media:content height="900" width="1200" medium="image" url="https://etimg.etb2bimg.com/thumb/img-size-34350/113352352.cms"/>
<pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2024 19:18:13 +0530</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Govt assures data privacy with satellite-based tolling</title>
<link>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/govt-assures-data-privacy-with-satellite-based-tolling/113345060</link>
<description>Sources said understanding the complexity of protecting data privacy, the scheme will first bring the commercial vehicles under this regime. “Detailed studies are being conducted on how to deal with this and how other countries have dealt with private vehicles. This may need actual testing to see and ensure that private data is not exposed,” said an official.</description>
<guid>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/govt-assures-data-privacy-with-satellite-based-tolling/113345060</guid>
<media:content height="900" width="1200" medium="image" url="https://etimg.etb2bimg.com/thumb/img-size-61938/113345060.cms"/>
<pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2024 13:38:40 +0530</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Bali launches app to attract public interest in EV</title>
<link>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/bali-launches-app-to-attract-public-interest-in-ev/113342670</link>
<description>Head of the Bali Transportation Agency, I Gde Wayan Samsi Gunarta, stated on Friday that the reluctance to adopt electric vehicles (EVs) persists among many people due to concerns over insufficient distance capacity and the fear of battery depletion during travel.</description>
<guid>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/bali-launches-app-to-attract-public-interest-in-ev/113342670</guid>
<media:content height="900" width="1200" medium="image" url="https://etimg.etb2bimg.com/thumb/img-size-4040/113342670.cms"/>
<pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2024 11:55:59 +0530</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Betting on lead acid battery tech still, Amara Raja Batteries plans inorganic move overseas</title>
<link>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/betting-on-lead-acid-battery-tech-still-amara-raja-batteries-plans-inorganic-move-overseas/113342298</link>
<description>The Hyderabad based battery major looks to expand its manufacturing footprint beyond the borders as it sees lead acid battery demand to remain healthy for the near future. Plans part of the group’s strategy to touch the USD 6 billion mark by 2029. </description>
<guid>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/betting-on-lead-acid-battery-tech-still-amara-raja-batteries-plans-inorganic-move-overseas/113342298</guid>
<media:content height="900" width="1200" medium="image" url="https://etimg.etb2bimg.com/thumb/img-size-625583/113342298.cms"/>
<pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2024 11:40:49 +0530</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>ZF Lifetec opens GCC in Hyderabad with EUR 5 million investment; looks to expand global R&amp;amp;D footprint</title>
<link>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/zf-lifetec-opens-gcc-in-hyderabad-with-eur-5-million-investment-looks-to-expand-global-rd-footprint/113315263</link>
<description>ZF Lifetec has opened a new Global Capability Center in Hyderabad, investing 5 million euros to advance passive safety technology. The facility aims to enhance road safety in India and globally, employing around 220 professionals with plans for future expansion. The Telangana government supports this initiative.</description>
<guid>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/zf-lifetec-opens-gcc-in-hyderabad-with-eur-5-million-investment-looks-to-expand-global-rd-footprint/113315263</guid>
<media:content height="900" width="1200" medium="image" url="https://etimg.etb2bimg.com/thumb/img-size-112916/113315263.cms"/>
<pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 12:24:16 +0530</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Affordable air taxis will soon be a reality, says Modi</title>
<link>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/affordable-air-taxis-will-soon-be-a-reality-says-modi/113307917</link>
<description>PM Modi announced that affordable air taxis will soon be available in India, highlighting the transformation of the aviation sector over the past decade. Speaking at the Asia Pacific ministerial conference of civil aviation, he emphasized technological innovations and a trained workforce as key factors for continued growth. The conference concluded with the passing of the 'Delhi Declaration.'</description>
<guid>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/affordable-air-taxis-will-soon-be-a-reality-says-modi/113307917</guid>
<media:content height="900" width="1200" medium="image" url="https://etimg.etb2bimg.com/thumb/img-size-39014/113307917.cms"/>
<pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 08:24:52 +0530</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>‘Automakers must invest in R&amp;amp;D to be world-class’</title>
<link>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/automakers-must-invest-in-rd-to-be-world-class/113282089</link>
<description>In general, he said, the Indian private sector roughly contributes about one third of the overall R&amp;amp;D spending in the economy while the remaining two thirds comes from the government. “Again, our studies show that it is not due to lack of government support for R&amp;amp;D spending in general, but it also depends on our ability to think over a much longer horizon...seeing the R&amp;amp;D expenditure as an investment, rather than as an expenditure against the profit and loss account,” he said.</description>
<guid>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/automakers-must-invest-in-rd-to-be-world-class/113282089</guid>
<media:content height="900" width="1200" medium="image" url="https://etimg.etb2bimg.com/thumb/img-size-19132/113282089.cms"/>
<pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 12:01:13 +0530</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>China asks its carmakers to keep key EV technology at home</title>
<link>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/china-asks-its-carmakers-to-keep-key-ev-technology-at-home/113275486</link>
<description>China has urged its carmakers to keep advanced EV technology within the country, even as they build factories abroad to avoid tariffs. The Ministry of Commerce advised exporting knock-down kits for final assembly overseas and warned against investments in India. This move aims to protect China's EV industry know-how.</description>
<guid>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/china-asks-its-carmakers-to-keep-key-ev-technology-at-home/113275486</guid>
<media:content height="900" width="1200" medium="image" url="https://etimg.etb2bimg.com/thumb/img-size-275986/113275486.cms"/>
<pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 08:22:18 +0530</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Global automotive ER&amp;amp;D spending expected to soar, with focus on digital vehicles, sustainability and AI integration: BCG Report</title>
<link>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/global-automotive-erd-spending-expected-to-soar-with-focus-on-digital-vehicles-sustainability-and-ai-integration-bcg-report/113275135</link>
<description>Investment in automotive engineering research and development is expected to grow annually by 8–9% until 2030, reaching up to USD 540 billion. Key drivers include advancements in connected mobility, digital vehicles, sustainability, and artificial intelligence. Automakers face challenges balancing software costs while integrating eco-friendly technology and AI-based systems.</description>
<guid>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/global-automotive-erd-spending-expected-to-soar-with-focus-on-digital-vehicles-sustainability-and-ai-integration-bcg-report/113275135</guid>
<media:content height="900" width="1200" medium="image" url="https://etimg.etb2bimg.com/thumb/img-size-89450/113275135.cms"/>
<pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 07:52:19 +0530</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Honda partners with IIT Delhi and IIT Bombay for advanced AI research in automated driving technologies</title>
<link>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/honda-partners-with-iit-delhi-and-iit-bombay-for-advanced-ai-research-in-automated-driving-technologies/113259440</link>
<description>Honda has initiated joint research with IIT Delhi and IIT Bombay to advance its Cooperative Intelligence (CI) technology. This collaboration aims to enhance AI technologies for reducing traffic collisions and enabling automated driving. The research will involve real-world testing in India’s complex traffic environments, leveraging the expertise of IIT researchers and students.</description>
<guid>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/honda-partners-with-iit-delhi-and-iit-bombay-for-advanced-ai-research-in-automated-driving-technologies/113259440</guid>
<media:content height="900" width="1200" medium="image" url="https://etimg.etb2bimg.com/thumb/img-size-302274/113259440.cms"/>
<pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 16:53:23 +0530</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>California passes requirements on carmakers and domestic violence</title>
<link>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/california-passes-requirements-on-carmakers-and-domestic-violence/113249242</link>
<description>California lawmakers have approved a proposal requiring automakers to enhance protections for domestic abuse survivors using internet-connected cars. The bill mandates carmakers to establish processes for restraining order submissions and to allow drivers to disable location access. Governor Gavin Newsom will decide on the bill by Sept. 30.</description>
<guid>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/california-passes-requirements-on-carmakers-and-domestic-violence/113249242</guid>
<media:content height="900" width="1200" medium="image" url="https://etimg.etb2bimg.com/thumb/img-size-243688/113249242.cms"/>
<pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 11:55:25 +0530</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>India has capability to become trusted partner in diversified semiconductor supply chain: PM</title>
<link>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/india-has-capability-to-become-trusted-partner-in-diversified-semiconductor-supply-chain-pm/113248737</link>
<description>Prime Minister Narendra Modi emphasized India's potential to become a key player in the global semiconductor supply chain during a roundtable with industry leaders. He assured a stable policy regime and highlighted India's focus on skilling, infrastructure, and investment. CEOs praised India's commitment and potential in the semiconductor sector.</description>
<guid>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/india-has-capability-to-become-trusted-partner-in-diversified-semiconductor-supply-chain-pm/113248737</guid>
<media:content height="900" width="1200" medium="image" url="https://etimg.etb2bimg.com/thumb/img-size-53622/113248737.cms"/>
<pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 11:37:46 +0530</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>CNG, hydrogen, fuel cell tech in ICE 2 wheelers a risk factor: Ather in IPO runup</title>
<link>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/cng-hydrogen-fuel-cell-tech-in-ice-2-wheelers-a-risk-factor-ather-in-ipo-runup/113248307</link>
<description>“Developments in alternative technologies in ICE vehicles, such as advanced diesel, hydrogen, ethanol, fuel cells, or compressed natural gas, improvements in the fuel economy or other features of ICE vehicles, or lower cost of gasoline, which lower the total cost of ownership of ICE vehicles,” is a risk factor, according to the draft red herring prospectus filed with markets regulator SEBI.</description>
<guid>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/cng-hydrogen-fuel-cell-tech-in-ice-2-wheelers-a-risk-factor-ather-in-ipo-runup/113248307</guid>
<media:content height="900" width="1200" medium="image" url="https://etimg.etb2bimg.com/thumb/img-size-60246/113248307.cms"/>
<pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 11:29:23 +0530</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>EV Day Special: This startup wants to till the field for electric tractors in India</title>
<link>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/this-startup-wants-to-till-the-field-for-electric-tractors-in-india/113172191</link>
<description>This startup is now planning to introduce similar technology in the tractor industry that Tesla has brought in the passenger vehicle segment, says the Founder. This is done by combining the company's electric tractors with advanced technology such as Level 3 of autonomous technology and quick charging capacity. </description>
<guid>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/this-startup-wants-to-till-the-field-for-electric-tractors-in-india/113172191</guid>
<media:content height="900" width="1200" medium="image" url="https://etimg.etb2bimg.com/thumb/img-size-389387/113172191.cms"/>
<pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 08:47:45 +0530</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>India is ready to lead the world in Electric Vehicle technology &amp;amp; innovation</title>
<link>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/india-is-ready-to-lead-the-world-in-electric-vehicle-technology-innovation/113178052</link>
<description>India is advancing rapidly in electric vehicle innovation and manufacturing, supported by government initiatives and a robust local supply chain. TVS Motor Company is at the forefront of this movement, expanding its presence globally. The country's commitment to Net Zero 2070 and forward-thinking policies are driving its leadership in the global EV market.</description>
<guid>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/india-is-ready-to-lead-the-world-in-electric-vehicle-technology-innovation/113178052</guid>
<media:content height="900" width="1200" medium="image" url="https://etimg.etb2bimg.com/thumb/img-size-22756/113178052.cms"/>
<pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 08:17:47 +0530</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Musk denies report his xAI in talks over Tesla revenue</title>
<link>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/musk-denies-report-his-xai-in-talks-over-tesla-revenue/113163048</link>
<description>Elon Musk has denied reports that his AI startup xAI has held talks to share future Tesla revenue in exchange for access to xAI's technology. He clarified that while Tesla has benefited from discussions with xAI engineers, there is no need to license anything from xAI. The Wall Street Journal had reported potential revenue-sharing agreements.</description>
<guid>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/musk-denies-report-his-xai-in-talks-over-tesla-revenue/113163048</guid>
<media:content height="900" width="1200" medium="image" url="https://etimg.etb2bimg.com/thumb/img-size-190298/113163048.cms"/>
<pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2024 11:53:39 +0530</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Tesla shares gain on plans to launch full self-driving in Europe, China</title>
<link>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/tesla-shares-gain-on-plans-to-launch-full-self-driving-in-europe-china/113099891</link>
<description>Tesla shares increased by 2.5% after the company confirmed plans to launch its Full Self-Driving software in China and Europe, pending regulatory approval. This announcement comes ahead of the unveiling of Tesla's robotaxi product, Cybercab. CEO Elon Musk expects regulatory approval for FSD in these regions by year-end.</description>
<guid>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/tesla-shares-gain-on-plans-to-launch-full-self-driving-in-europe-china/113099891</guid>
<media:content height="900" width="1200" medium="image" url="https://etimg.etb2bimg.com/thumb/img-size-283240/113099891.cms"/>
<pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 19:36:25 +0530</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>How India can leverage biofuels to build a sustainable future</title>
<link>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/how-india-can-leverage-biofuels-to-build-a-sustainable-future/113093373</link>
<description>Derived from renewable resources such as biomass and agricultural waste, biofuels provide a cleaner alternative to conventional fossil fuels in our energy palettes, for meeting needs, whether it is surface mobility, aviation, shipping, or even power production. Today, it is possible to leverage bioenergy to fuel each of these energy needs and that also with lower permanent emissions. India has achieved an avoidance of as much as 1.5 tonnes of GHG emissions per kilolitre of bio-ethanol replacing petrol in our cars, amounting to more than 40 million tonnes of savings in GHG emissions over the last decade.</description>
<guid>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/how-india-can-leverage-biofuels-to-build-a-sustainable-future/113093373</guid>
<media:content height="900" width="1200" medium="image" url="https://etimg.etb2bimg.com/thumb/img-size-25892/113093373.cms"/>
<pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 15:56:19 +0530</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Volvo Cars looks to Nvidia-powered software, 'megacastings' for future EVs</title>
<link>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/volvo-cars-looks-to-nvidia-powered-software-megacastings-for-future-evs/113083434</link>
<description>Volvo Cars will use a single software system powered by Nvidia chips for all future models and employ megacastings to reduce costs for electric vehicles. Starting with the EX90 model, this approach aims to enhance safety systems and allow over-the-air updates, without focusing on subscription services.</description>
<guid>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/volvo-cars-looks-to-nvidia-powered-software-megacastings-for-future-evs/113083434</guid>
<media:content height="900" width="1200" medium="image" url="https://etimg.etb2bimg.com/thumb/img-size-63382/113083434.cms"/>
<pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 11:14:44 +0530</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Revolutionising road safety with AI: India eyes ADAS technology to slash road accidents</title>
<link>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/revolutionising-road-safety-with-ai-india-eyes-adas-technology-to-slash-road-accidents/113078480</link>
<description>The rising percentage of road crashes in the country is alarming for the government of India, OEMs (Original equipment manufacturers), regulatory bodies, and other players, who need to address the concern. The heavy use of the latest technologies in the automotive sector might be a ray of hope to curb such incidents. Implementing artificial intelligence such as ADAS in vehicles might bring a paradigm shift toward safer vehicles.</description>
<guid>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/revolutionising-road-safety-with-ai-india-eyes-adas-technology-to-slash-road-accidents/113078480</guid>
<media:content height="900" width="1200" medium="image" url="https://etimg.etb2bimg.com/thumb/img-size-150938/113078480.cms"/>
<pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 08:04:18 +0530</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>