<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 08:55:40 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/italian-surfer-36-dies-after-being-impaled-by-swordfish-in-indonesia-6844071]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Italian Surfer, 36, Dies After Being Impaled By Swordfish In Indonesia]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/italian-surfer-36-dies-after-being-impaled-by-swordfish-in-indonesia-6844071]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 08:55:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[36-year-old Italian surfer Giulia Manfrini has died after being fatally impaled by a swordfish during a freak incident in Indonesia.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>36-year-old Italian surfer Giulia Manfrini has died after being fatally impaled by a swordfish during a freak incident in Indonesia. According to <em>ABC Australia</em>, Ms Manfrini was surfing at a popular surf break off the West Coast of Sumatra, Indonesia, when the accident occurred. She was fatally injured after a swordfish speared her in the chest while she surfed in the waters off Ombak Bengbeng, near Masokut Island. She reportedly had a 5cm deep stab wound on the left side of her chest.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Ms Manfrini, a surf coach and founder of the surf travel agency AWAVE, was well-known in the local surfing community, the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.abc.net.au/news/2024-10-21/surfer-killed-by-swordfish-off-sumatra-indonesia/104498760">outlet </a>reported. Lahmudin Siregar, acting head of the Mentawai Islands' Disaster Management Agency, said the swordfish "unexpectedly jumped towards Manfrini and pierced her chest".</p>

<p>Separately, James Colston, Co-Founder of AWAVE Travel said Ms Manfrini "touched countless people within the surf world" both in Europe and worldwide. "Her kindness, care and positivity were remembered by all that met her and she will be dearly missed," he said.</p>

<p>Frankie Smithurst, from surf charter operator Naga Laut Mentawai Blue, said she would be remembered for her "overflowing excitement for life". "Giulia will be forever known by her huge heart which matched her huge smile, an extremely selfless person who truly loved life," he told the outlet.&nbsp;</p>

<p>At the time of the incident, two of Ms Manfrini's friends were nearby. They provided first aid and rushed her to a nearby health care centre, but she could not be saved despite their efforts. Medical reports later revealed that she suffered a 5cm deep wound to her chest and showed signs of drowning.</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-rapper-sean-diddy-drugged-and-raped-13-year-old-girl-lawsuit-claims-6843642">US Rapper Sean Diddy Drugged And Raped 13-Year-Old Girl, Lawsuit Claims</a></strong></p>

<p>Following the news of her demise, Fabio Giulivi, the mayor of Venaria Reale, Ms Manfrini's hometown, expressed the community's sorrow over her tragic death in a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.facebook.com/fabiogiulivisindaco/posts/pfbid037c1RhyaJDYwNXT1Grw53YdeufyhJgkcZDaUTcr7L9w5tqb172wjaYZM5yeSUndfdl">Facebook post</a>, noting the support for her grieving family.</p>

<p>"Giulia, just 36 years old and from Venaria, had long pursued her twin dreams: her love of surfing and opening a travel agency for sports holidays," he wrote. "The news of her death has left us all in shock and makes us feel powerless in the face of such a devastating tragedy that took her life far too soon," he added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Ms Manfrini's Instagram page has also been flooded with emotional tributes. "The sea, that gave you so much, has taken your life. Rest in peace," wrote one user.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Our whole community in Portugal is heartbroken alongside you as we hear of the sad news. She loved life, and we spent (our) last evening (together) picking pomegranates and talking about making fig jam and what other fruit we would harvest together next year. She became like my new Italian daughter, and oh how we will miss her. We can only say how much she got out of her short life, and she filled it completely," her former volleyball coach wrote.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/hibh1ai_giulia-manfrini-_625x300_22_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Giulia Manfrini was a surf coach and founder of the surf travel agency AWAVE.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/naked-chat-blackmail-59-people-in-hong-kong-duped-into-undressing-during-video-chats-6843812]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[59 People In Hong Kong Tricked Into Undressing During Video Chats]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/naked-chat-blackmail-59-people-in-hong-kong-duped-into-undressing-during-video-chats-6843812]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 07:49:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[According to the police, the scam typically involves extortionists - often women - luring male victims into undressing during video chats and then secretly recording the acts.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In the past week, an alarming extortion scam has targeted 59 Hong Kong residents, including four women, resulting in losses exceeding HK$1.9 million (US$244,430), <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3282979/naked-chat-blackmail-4-women-among-59-hongkongers-duped-undressing-during-video-chats">South China Morning Post</a></em> reported. According to the police, who revealed the figures on their CyberDefender Facebook page, the scam typically involves extortionists - often women - luring male victims into undressing during video chats and then secretly recording the acts.</p>

<p>The scammers then use the footage to coerce victims into payment by threatening to share the videos online or with their relatives and friends. In some cases, scammers also pose as charming, high-income, educated men to target women on social media. They use flattery and sweet talk to gain trust, manipulating victims by learning about their personal interests and lives.</p>

<p>''They use sweet talk to learn about the victims' personal lives and interests to manipulate them. In the past week, police received 59 cases of naked-chat blackmail, with scammers extorting more than HK$1.9 million. Four cases involved female victims,'' the force said.</p>

<p>In the first half of this year, students comprised 20% of the 1,102 victims, with fraudsters pocketing over HK$31 million. Comparing year-over-year data, reports of "naked-chat blackmail" surged 50% from 1,402 in 2022 to 2,117 in 2023, while losses doubled from HK$22 million to HK$44 million.</p>

<p>Moreover, deception cases in Hong Kong have increased by 12% from 21,798 to 24,407 between January and July this year. Losses skyrocketed 50% to HK$5.14 billion during the same period. Law enforcement responded by arresting over 6,000 suspects linked to scams and related activities this year.</p>

<p>The police are now cautioning citizens to exercise vigilance when meeting people online. They emphasise the importance of verifying identities and profiles, avoiding intimate activities on video chats, and reporting suspicious activities immediately.</p>

<p>Recently, a few Hong Kong men fell prey to a romance scam that used deepfake artificial intelligence to lure its victims into parting with more than $46 million. As per CNN, the suspects aged 21 to 34, were mostly well-educated, with many of them digital media and technology graduates allegedly recruited by the gang after attending local universities.&nbsp;The suspects allegedly worked with IT specialists overseas to build a fake cryptocurrency platform, where the victims were coerced to make investments, police said.&nbsp;</p>

<p></p>

<p></p>

<p></p>

<p data-qa="Component-Component" datatype="p"></p>

<p data-qa="Component-Component" datatype="p"></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/qq3kd518_phone_625x300_22_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The police are now cautioning citizens to exercise vigilance when meeting people online.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/liam-payne-had-multiple-drugs-in-his-system-at-the-time-of-death-report-6843807]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Liam Payne Had "Multiple" Drugs In His System At The Time Of Death: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/liam-payne-had-multiple-drugs-in-his-system-at-the-time-of-death-report-6843807]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 07:44:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[British pop star and former One Direction member Liam Payne had a toxic mixture of drugs in his system at the time of his death in Argentina last week, ABC News reported, citing a toxicology report.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>British pop star and former One Direction member Liam Payne had a toxic mixture of drugs in his system at the time of his death in Argentina last week, <em>ABC News </em>reported, citing a toxicology report. The 31-year-old died on October 16 following a fall from the third-floor balcony of his hotel room at the CasaSur Palermo Hotel in Buenos Aires, Argentina. &nbsp;Now, a toxicology report revealed that he had "multiple substances in his system" at the time of his death, including a drug known as "pink cocaine".&nbsp;</p>

<p>In addition to pink cocaine - a recreational drug that contains a combination of methamphetamine, ketamine and ecstasy - the drugs detected in Payne's bloodstream included benzodiazepine, crack, and cocaine. The <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://abcnews.go.com/GMA/Culture/liam-payne-partial-autopsy-report-multiple-substances/story?id=114985701" rel="noindex, nofollow">outlet </a>said that a makeshift aluminium pipe for ingesting the substances was also found nearby.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to witnesses, Payne was acting erratically in the hours before his death. Emergency services were called to the hotel after staff frantically described him as "an aggressive man overwhelmed with drugs and alcohol." Upon entering his hotel room, authorities discovered a chaotic scene, &nbsp;with broken items and various drugs scattered throughout.</p>

<p>Forensic teams also recovered a whiskey bottle, lighter, and cell phone from the courtyard where his body was located. Investigators noted that the absence of defensive injuries suggested he may have been in a state of semi-consciousness or complete unconsciousness when he fell.</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-rapper-sean-diddy-drugged-and-raped-13-year-old-girl-lawsuit-claims-6843642">US Rapper Sean Diddy Drugged And Raped 13-Year-Old Girl, Lawsuit Claims</a></strong></p>

<p>Notably, Payne had previously entered rehab multiple times and also had expressed suicidal thoughts during his career. He was reportedly also battling significant drug addiction leading up to his death. The investigation into the circumstances surrounding his passing is ongoing.</p>

<p>Payne's girlfriend, Kate Cassidy, had reportedly been with him for a couple's respite in Argentina, however, she returned to Florida two days before his tragic death.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In a joint statement, Payne's former bandmates expressed their devastation over his passing, emphasising their cherished memories of him and calling for privacy as they grieve. "In time, and when everyone is able to, there will be more to say. But for now, we will take some time to grieve and process the loss of our brother, who we loved dearly," they said. They also stated that their thoughts were with the English singer's family, friends and fans.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/lck0ods8_liam-payne_625x300_18_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Liam Payne died at the age of 31.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/shirel-golan-hamas-attack-survivor-dies-by-suicide-on-22nd-birthday-family-cites-ptsd-6843774]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hamas Attack Survivor Dies By Suicide On 22nd Birthday, Family Cites PTSD]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/shirel-golan-hamas-attack-survivor-dies-by-suicide-on-22nd-birthday-family-cites-ptsd-6843774]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 07:34:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Shirel Golan's family blamed Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu-led Israeli government for turning a blind eye to Hamas attack survivors.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An Israeli woman who survived Hamas' attack on the Supernova music festival on October 7 last year has died by suicide after suffering from post-traumatic stress disorder, reports said.</p>

<p>Shirel Golan, the youngest of five siblings, took her life in her apartment on her 22nd birthday on Sunday.</p>

<p>Her family blamed Prime Minister <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hits-hezbollah-intelligence-hq-hamas-in-gaza-after-drone-launched-at-benjamin-netanyahu-home-6831469" target="_blank">Benjamin Netanyahu-led Israeli government</a> for turning a blind eye to Hamas attack survivors.</p>

<p>"I saw that she had symptoms of post-traumatic stress, such as withdrawing and distancing herself from her friends. I asked her to take care of herself. She said that she doesn't get any help from the state," her brother, Eyal, was quoted as saying by Hebrew media, the Times of Israel reported.</p>

<p>"She said that she doesn't get any help from the state. She said that she only gets aid from the [Tribe of Nova Community Association]," he said.</p>

<p>"If the state had taken care of her, none of this would have happened," he added.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hezbollah-hamas-israel-claims-it-found-500-million-in-secret-hezbollah-bunker-in-beirut-6843741" target="_blank">Hamas members attacked southern Israel</a> on October 7, 2023, killing about 1,200 people, mostly civilians, and <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/on-first-anniversary-of-war-with-israel-fate-of-63-hostages-held-in-gaza-unknown-6736725" target="_blank">taking 251 hostages</a>.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory military campaign has killed more than 44,000 people in Gaza, according to the territory's health ministry.</p>

<p>Israel believes that 63 hostages, including two children, are still alive, while 34 are confirmed dead but remain in Gaza.</p>

<p>For Hamas, which rules Gaza, the hostages are key bargaining chips in negotiations with Israel aiming to secure a truce and the release of Palestinian prisoners.</p><p><div class='table-div suicide'><table class='table'><thead><tr><th colspan='2'>Helplines</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>Vandrevala Foundation for Mental Health</td><td><a href='tel:+919999666555'>9999666555</a> or <a href='mailto:help@vandrevalafoundation.com'>help@vandrevalafoundation.com</a> </td></tr><tr><td>TISS iCall</td><td><a href='tel:+912225521111'>022-25521111</a> (Monday-Saturday: 8 am to 10 pm)</td></tr> <tr><td colspan='2'>(If you need support or know someone who does, please reach out to your nearest mental health specialist.)</td></tr></tbody></table></div></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/25q1m4so_shirel-golan_625x300_22_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Shirel Golan was reportedly the youngest of five siblings]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hezbollah-hamas-israel-claims-it-found-500-million-in-secret-hezbollah-bunker-in-beirut-6843741]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Claims It Found $500 Million In "Secret" Hezbollah Bunker In Beirut]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hezbollah-hamas-israel-claims-it-found-500-million-in-secret-hezbollah-bunker-in-beirut-6843741]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 07:28:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel on Monday said it has declassified intelligence which claims the presence of a secret Hezbollah financial hub beneath a Beirut hospital. According to the Israel Defense Forces (IDF), the bunker contained hundreds of millions of dollars in cash]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel on Monday said it has declassified intelligence which claims the presence of a secret Hezbollah financial hub beneath a Beirut hospital. According to the Israel Defense Forces (IDF), the bunker contained hundreds of millions of dollars in cash and gold, allegedly used to fund the group's operations.</p>

<p>This disclosure followed a series of targeted airstrikes conducted by the Israeli Air Force on Sunday night, aimed at Hezbollah's financial assets. IDF spokesperson Rear Admiral Daniel Hagari provided detailed information during a televised briefing, stating, "Tonight, I am going to declassify intelligence on a site that we did not strike-where Hezbollah has millions of dollars in gold and cash in Hassan Nasrallah's bunker. The bunker is located directly under Al-Sahel Hospital in the heart of Beirut."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">“Tonight, I am going to declassify intelligence on a site that we did not strike—where Hezbollah has millions of dollars in gold and cash—in Hassan Nasrallah's bunker. Where is the bunker located? Directly under Al-Sahel Hospital in the heart of Beirut.”<br />
<br />
Listen to IDF Spox.… <a href="https://t.co/SjMZQpKqoJ">pic.twitter.com/SjMZQpKqoJ</a></p>
— Israel Defense Forces (@IDF) <a href="https://twitter.com/IDF/status/1848436265143677104?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 21, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>Hagari said that the site had not been struck yet, despite the alleged presence of significant financial resources. "According to estimates, there is at least half a billion dollars in dollar bills and gold stored in this bunker. This money could and still can be used to rebuild the state of Lebanon," he said.</p>

<p>Sunday night's airstrikes targeted nearly 30 Hezbollah-linked locations, including sites operated by Al-Qard Al-Hassan (AQAH), a financial firm linked to Hezbollah. AQAH, though registered as a charity, has been accused by both Israel and the United States of serving as a critical financial arm of Hezbollah, facilitating its access to cash and gold reserves for military purposes.</p>

<p>Hagari claimed that one of the key targets was an underground vault containing tens of millions of dollars in cash and gold, resources that were allegedly being used to fund attacks on Israel. While Hagari did not clarify whether all the funds were destroyed in the strike, he said that further airstrikes could be expected, particularly targeting additional financial hubs.</p>

<p>The strikes followed an intensified Israeli effort to disrupt Hezbollah's finances. According to IDF Chief of Staff Lt Gen Herzi Halevi, the campaign involved over 300 strikes on Hezbollah positions in Lebanon over a 24-hour period, including critical financial and logistical hubs.</p>

<p>Al-Qard Al-Hassan has operated in Lebanon since the 1980s, providing credit to Lebanese citizens in exchange for gold deposits. While officially classified as a charity, Israeli and US officials argue that the firm is a critical asset in Hezbollah's financial network, enabling the group to launder money and finance its activities under the guise of civilian banking.</p>

<p>The Lebanese people and the Iranian regime are Hezbollah's two main sources of income, Hagari claimed. He alleged that the financial mechanisms used by the group, which include cash transfers through Syria and gold smuggled into Lebanon via Iran. Factories operated by Hezbollah in Lebanon, Syria, Yemen, and Turkey are allegedly used to generate substantial income to support the group's terror activities, according to IDF intelligence.</p>

<p>In a related development, Israel carried out an airstrike on Monday in Syria, targeting the head of Hezbollah's financial unit, known as Unit 4400. The unit is responsible for the flow of Iranian funds to Hezbollah, primarily through proceeds from Tehran's oil sales. The unnamed commander, who had only been in the role for a few weeks, was killed in the strike, according to Hagari.</p>

<p>This marks the second significant assassination of a Hezbollah financial figure in recent weeks. In early October, Israeli forces killed Mohammed Jafar Ksir, also known as Sheikh Salah, the previous head of Hezbollah's financial operations. Ksir had long overseen the group's revenue streams, which have been integral to its military and political influence in Lebanon.</p>

<p>The latest Israeli operations came amid an escalation in hostilities between Hezbollah and Israel, which have been ongoing since Hezbollah launched a series of attacks in solidarity with Hamas following the October 7 attacks in 2023.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Israeli officials estimate that approximately 2,000 Hezbollah fighters have been killed since the conflict widened in late September 2023. Hezbollah has retaliated with rocket attacks on Israeli towns and military positions, including a recent barrage aimed at an intelligence base near Tel Aviv.&nbsp;<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/macc8bs8_hezbollah-bunker-idf-_625x300_22_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The strikes followed an intensified Israeli effort to disrupt Hezbollah's finances.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-rapper-sean-diddy-drugged-and-raped-13-year-old-girl-lawsuit-claims-6843642]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Rapper Sean Diddy Drugged And Raped 13-Year-Old Girl, Lawsuit Claims]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-rapper-sean-diddy-drugged-and-raped-13-year-old-girl-lawsuit-claims-6843642]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 06:58:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Sean "Diddy" Combs, who is currently in federal custody following multiple charges of racketeering and sex trafficking, has now been accused of raping a 13-year-old girl with the help of two other celebrities at a 2000 MTV VMAs afterparty.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Music mogul Sean "Diddy" Combs, who is currently in federal custody following multiple charges of racketeering and sex trafficking, has now been accused of raping a 13-year-old girl with the help of two other celebrities at a 2000 MTV Video Music Awards afterparty. According to the <em>New York Post</em>, a 37-year-old woman filed a lawsuit in New York federal court on Sunday in which she claimed that the incident occurred after she went to an empty bedroom to lie down for a moment because she felt "woozy and lightheaded" from a drink she had during the bash on September 7, 2000. She said that at the party she was raped by an unnamed male celebrity, while an unnamed female celebrity watched before Combs raped her.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Combs aggressively approached Plaintiff with a crazed look in his eyes, grabbed her and said, 'You are ready to party!'" the lawsuit states, per the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://pagesix.com/2024/10/21/celebrity-news/sean-diddy-combs-accused-of-raping-teen-with-celebs-at-vmas/" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>Post</em></a>. He then allegedly "threw" the girl, identified as Jane Doe in the court documents, toward another male celebrity, referred to as Celebrity A, who proceeded to remove the teen's clothing as she became "more and more disoriented".&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Plaintiff was held down by Celebrity A who vaginally raped her while Combs and Celebrity B, a female, watched," the lawsuit claims. "After the male celebrity finished, Combs then vaginally raped Plaintiff while Celebrity A and Celebrity B watched," it added.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/maggots-slime-and-disease-worlds-dirtiest-cruise-ships-named-and-shamed-6832109">"Maggots, Slime, And Disease": World's Dirtiest Cruise Ships Named And Shamed</a></strong></p>

<p>The lawsuit also alleged that the music mogul attempted to force the victim to perform oral sex on him, but she resisted by hitting him in the neck, so he stopped. She then escaped the room and had her father pick her up from the party. "After the assault, Plaintiff fell into a deep depression which continues to affect every facet of her life," the lawsuit states.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The plaintiffs are not named in the court papers, but they are described as two men and three women, including the one who was 13 at the time of the alleged VMAs rape. One of the men and three women also accused Combs of drugging them. While one of the male accusers claimed he was drugged and sexually assaulted by both Combs and an unnamed celebrity, the other male accuser said Combs groped him at a Ciroc Vodka party in Los Angeles.</p>

<p>Notably, Combs has denied all the charges against him. He is currently being held behind bars at Brooklyn's Metropolitan Detention Center after being denied bail.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/f5t7ddf_sean-diddy-combs-reuters_625x300_03_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The plaintiffs are not named in the court papers.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ndtv-world-summit-2024-live-updates-indias-g20-sherpa-amitabh-kant-british-envoy-lindy-cameron-to-speak-on-day-2-6843569]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[NDTV World Summit Live: India's G20 Sherpa, British Envoy To Speak On Day 2]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ndtv-world-summit-2024-live-updates-indias-g20-sherpa-amitabh-kant-british-envoy-lindy-cameron-to-speak-on-day-2-6843569]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 06:32:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Narendra Modi opened the "NDTV World Summit 2024 - The India Century" on Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A day after Prime Minister Narendra Modi opened the "<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ndtv-world-summit-2024-india-century-live-updates-pm-narendra-modi-david-cameron-s-jaishankar-to-speak-6830644" target="_blank">NDTV World Summit 2024 - The India Century</a>", the day 2 of NDTV's flagship event is here with India's G20 Sherpa Amitabh Kant, British High Commissioner to India Lindy Cameron, and Former Permanent Representative of India to the United Nations TS Tirumurti, among a host of other dignitaries, to discuss global issues.</p>

<p>In his keynote address on Monday, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/digital-innovation-democratic-values-can-co-exist-pm-modi-at-ndtv-world-summit-6836676" target="_blank">PM Modi</a> spoke about why the 21st Century is 'The India Century' and how the country is growing rapidly and how investors from around the world are excited about India being the fastest-growing major economy.</p>

<p>He also launched NDTV World, a new home for global news at the Summit, with the tagline: "The World From Where India Stands". NDTV World aims to be a leading voice from Asia and India on the global stage.</p>

<h2><strong>Here are the live updates on NDTV World Summit 2024:</strong></h2>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/89pd05pg_ndtv-world-summit_625x300_22_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[PM Modi also launched NDTV World on Monday]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-says-us-will-bear-full-responsibility-for-israeli-retaliation-6843513]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iran Says US Will Bear "Full Responsibility" For Israeli Retaliation]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-says-us-will-bear-full-responsibility-for-israeli-retaliation-6843513]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 06:10:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iran on Monday warned the United States would bear "full responsibility" in case of a retaliatory attack by Israel on the Islamic Republic, after US President Joe Biden indicated he was aware of Israeli plans to do so.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Iran on Monday warned the United States would bear "full responsibility" in case of a retaliatory attack by Israel on the Islamic Republic, after US President Joe Biden indicated he was aware of Israeli plans to do so.</p>

<p>Amir Saeid Iravani, Iran's ambassador to the United Nations, called Biden's remarks "profoundly alarming and provocative" in a letter addressed to United Nations chief Antonio Guterres and the Swiss presidency of the UN Security Council.</p>

<p>The US president responded "yes and yes" when asked Friday by a reporter if he had "a good understanding right now" of how and when Israel would respond to Iran's missile barrage on October 1.</p>

<p>Iran launched around 200 ballistic missiles at Israel in retaliation for the killing of Tehran-backed leaders belonging to Hamas and Hezbollah, and an Iranian Revolutionary Guard general.</p>

<p>US ally Israel, at war with Hamas in Gaza and Hezbollah in Lebanon, vowed revenge against Iran for the strikes.</p>

<p>"This inflammatory statement (of Biden) is deeply concerning, as it indicates the United States' tacit approval and explicit support for Israel's unlawful military aggression against Iran," Iravani wrote in the letter.</p>

<p>"Therefore, the United States will bear full responsibility for its role in instigating, inciting and enabling any acts of aggression by Israel against the Islamic Republic of Iran, in flagrant violation of the fundamental principles of international law and the United Nations Charter," he said.</p>

<p>According to the Washington Post, Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu has told Biden that he intends to strike Iran's military sites, and not to target nuclear or oil infrastructure.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/6233k9ag_israeliran-war-_625x300_02_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US ally Israel vowed revenge against Iran for missile attacks on October 1.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-secretary-of-state-antony-blinken-heads-to-middle-east-as-israel-intensifies-strikes-in-lebanon-6843454]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Blinken Heads To Middle East As Israel Intensifies Strikes In Lebanon]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-secretary-of-state-antony-blinken-heads-to-middle-east-as-israel-intensifies-strikes-in-lebanon-6843454]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 05:55:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US Secretary of State Antony Blinken left for the Middle East Monday on a new push for an elusive Gaza ceasefire two weeks before US elections, seeing a new opportunity from Israel's killing of Hamas's leader.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US Secretary of State Antony Blinken left for the Middle East Monday on a new push for an elusive Gaza ceasefire two weeks before US elections, seeing a new opportunity from Israel's killing of Hamas's leader.</p>

<p>It will be the 11th trip to the Middle East by the top US diplomat since war broke out a year ago, with Blinken on his last visit to Israel in August warning it may have been the "last chance" for a US-led ceasefire plan.</p>

<p>That push did not succeed, and the conflict has escalated and expanded since then, with Israel pounding Hezbollah targets in Lebanon and warning of a new strike directly on Iran, whose clerical leaders back both Hamas and Hezbollah.</p>

<p>US President Joe Biden, who personally laid out the ceasefire plan on May 31 that would also free hostages from Gaza, has seen new hope since Israel last week killed Hamas chief Yahya Sinwar.</p>

<p>Biden, speaking to reporters on a visit to Germany, said he called Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu to congratulate him and tell him that Blinken would head to the region.</p>

<p>"I told him that we were really pleased with his actions and, further, that now is the time to move on -- move on, move towards a ceasefire," Biden said Thursday.</p>

<p>The Gaza war was sparked by the unprecedented Hamas attack on Israel last year that resulted in the deaths of 1,206 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally of official Israeli figures.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory campaign in Gaza has killed 42,603 people, also mostly civilians, according to data from the health ministry in the Hamas-run territory, figures the UN considers reliable.</p>

<p>Last month, Israel expanded its military operations to Lebanon, where at least 1,470 people have been killed since then, according to an AFP tally of Lebanese health ministry figures.</p>

<p>Blinken's trip comes days after he and Defense Secretary Lloyd Austin warned Israel that the United States could withhold some of its billions of dollars in military aid unless more humanitarian assistance is allowed into Gaza, where the UN warns more than 1.8 million people are facing extreme hunger.</p>

<p>- US election implications -</p>

<p>A breakthrough could be a major boost for US Vice President Kamala Harris, who is running in a razor-tight November 5 race for the White House against Donald Trump.</p>

<p>The war has been a political albatross for Biden and to an extent Harris, his political heir, with Netanyahu repeatedly brushing aside US entreaties to do more to spare civilians.</p>

<p>Trump also spoke to Netanyahu about Sinwar's killing, with the Republican saying that the Israeli leader was proven right in ignoring Biden's pressure to dial back military operations.</p>

<p>Trump suggested he would give freer rein to Netanyahu, telling reporters that Biden was "trying to hold him back and he probably should be doing the opposite."</p>

<p>Trump staunchly backed Israel in his first term. He has a complicated relationship with Netanyahu but Republican voters, unlike Democrats, are overwhelmingly supportive of Israel and Netanyahu.</p>

<p><strong>- Seeing ways forward -</strong></p>

<p>Blinken flies first to Israel and then will tour other countries in the Middle East through Friday.</p>

<p>An official on the plane with him said Blinken will visit Jordan on Wednesday and discuss humanitarian aid for the Gaza Strip.</p>

<p>The State Department did not list his other stops but on previous trips Blinken has visited a number of Arab countries, especially Qatar and Egypt, the key intermediaries in ceasefire negotiations.</p>

<p>Blinken "will discuss the importance of bringing the war in Gaza to an end, securing the release of all hostages and alleviating the suffering of the Palestinian people," a State Department statement said.</p>

<p>It said Blinken would also discuss post-war arrangements critical for a peace deal and seek a "diplomatic resolution" in Lebanon, where the United States has stopped short of urging an immediate ceasefire.</p>

<p>Blinken has also sought to coax Netanyahu into compromise by dangling the prospect of normalization with Saudi Arabia -- which would be a historic game-changer in Israel's quest for acceptance, as the kingdom is the guardian of Islam's two holiest sites.</p>

<p>Netanyahu, leading the most right-wing coalition in Israeli history, has called Sinwar's death "the beginning of the end" of the Gaza war but faces calls from his base to keep up military operations in Gaza, which has already largely been reduced to rubble.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-11/mqsci3sk_antony-blinken_625x300_30_November_23.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[It will be the 11th trip to the Middle East by Antony Blinken since war broke out a year ago.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/lebanon-says-child-among-4-killed-as-israel-strikes-near-beirut-hospital-6843174]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Lebanon Says Child Among 4 Killed As Israel Strikes Near Beirut Hospital]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/lebanon-says-child-among-4-killed-as-israel-strikes-near-beirut-hospital-6843174]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 04:19:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Lebanon said four people including a child were killed Monday in Israeli air strikes near the country's biggest public hospital close to south Beirut, with state media reporting over a dozen raids.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lebanon said four people including a child were killed Monday in Israeli air strikes near the country's biggest public hospital close to south Beirut, with state media reporting over a dozen raids.</p>

<p>"The Israeli enemy strike near the Hariri Hospital killed, in a preliminary toll, four people, including a child, and injured 24," the health ministry said, adding it had caused "significant damage to the hospital".</p>

<p>In a separate statement, the ministry said the strike hit the entrance to the hospital, "which is still operating and receives a large number of patients".</p>

<p>It denied claims by the Israeli army that Hezbollah had stored half a billion dollars under the Sahel hospital in south Beirut.</p>

<p>Lebanon's National News Agency reported at least three Israeli strikes on the Ouzai district of south Beirut.</p>

<p>While most districts of Beirut's southern suburbs had been emptied for almost a month, the densely-packed residential area of Ouzai was still filled with people because it had never been targeted before.</p>

<p><strong>- 'No room for escape' -</strong></p>

<p>The NNA reported more than a dozen strikes on various south Beirut districts including Haret Hreik, just south of Ouzai, and Hadath.</p>

<p>Hezbollah-affiliated rescuers told AFP they were looking for survivors amid the devastation in Ouzai, adding that the evacuation order, then the strike, caused "panic among residents" who "started to run in the streets".</p>

<p>"They did not leave any room for people to escape. The strike came closely after the warning," one said.</p>

<p>A Lebanese security official told AFP that the country's national airline had to switch landing strips after Israeli strikes near Beirut's only international airport hit close to the main runway.</p>

<p>"Middle East Airlines switched the runway it was using because the main runway is close to the site of the Ouzai strike," the official said, requesting anonymity to discuss sensitive matters.</p>

<p>AFPTV footage showed plumes of smoke rising from Beirut's southern suburbs, with AFP correspondents also hearing several loud bangs before the strikes.</p>

<p>The footage also showed two strikes that caused a huge fire, with black smoke surrounding dissipating orange flames.</p>

<p>Just prior to the strikes, the Israeli military called on residents to leave parts of southern Beirut, in their latest such appeal.</p>

<p>Military spokesman Avichay Adraee posted the new call on social media indicating several locations to be evacuated, including an area close to Beirut airport.</p>

<p>"You are located near facilities and interests affiliated with Hezbollah that the IDF will work against in the near future," he wrote.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/vjsmbq1g_lebanon-airstrikes-afp_625x300_01_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[At least 24 people also injured in Israeli strike near southern Beirut hospital on Monday.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korea-sending-troops-to-ukraine-would-be-dangerous-move-us-6843063]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[North Korea Sending Troops To Ukraine Would Be "Dangerous" Move: US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korea-sending-troops-to-ukraine-would-be-dangerous-move-us-6843063]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 03:33:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United States on Monday said it would be a dangerous development for North Korea to send troops to support Russia in Ukraine, as Seoul has asserted.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United States on Monday said it would be a dangerous development for North Korea to send troops to support Russia in Ukraine, as Seoul has asserted.<br />
<br />
"We have seen reports the DPRK has sent forces and is preparing to send additional soldiers to Ukraine to fight alongside Russia," Robert Wood, US ambassador to the United Nations, told the Security Council.</p>

<p>"If true, this marks a dangerous and highly concerning development and an obvious deepening of the DPRK-Russia military relationship," Wood said, using the acronym for the North's official name.</p>

<p>"We are consulting with our allies and partners on the implications of such a dramatic move," he added.</p>

<p>Seoul's spy agency said on Friday that North Korea had decided to send a "large-scale" troop deployment to support Moscow's war in Ukraine, with 1,500 special forces already in Russia's Far East and undergoing training.</p>

<p>The agency estimated the North could send around 12,000 soldiers in total.</p>

<p>The US State Department is "not yet at a point where we're able to confirm those reports and whether they are accurate," deputy spokesman Vedant Patel said Monday.</p>

<p>France's UN envoy Nicolas de Riviere told the UN Security Council that the deployment of North Korean soldiers would constitute a further escalation.</p>

<p>He added that Pyongyang's "increasing support for the Russian war effort is very worrying."</p>

<p>The United States and its allies have already voiced concern about North Korea providing weapons to Russia, which invaded Ukraine in February 2022.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2016-09/north-korea-army-reuters_650x400_71474875874.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The agency estimated the North could send around 12,000 soldiers in total to support Russia in war.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-to-form-doha-based-ruling-committee-instead-of-appointing-new-chief-6842331]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hamas' New Succession Plan After Chief Yahya Sinwar's Killing]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-to-form-doha-based-ruling-committee-instead-of-appointing-new-chief-6842331]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:07:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Two Hamas sources said the Palestinian militant group was moving towards appointing a Doha-based ruling committee rather than a single successor to its chief Yahya Sinwar, who was killed by Israeli troops last week.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Two Hamas sources said the Palestinian operator group was moving towards appointing a Doha-based ruling committee rather than a single successor to its chief Yahya Sinwar, who was killed by Israeli troops last week.</p>

<p>"The Hamas leadership's approach is not to appoint a successor to the late chief, the martyr Yahya Sinwar, until their next elections" scheduled for March "if conditions permit", a well-informed source from the group told AFP.</p>

<p>A five-member committee that was formed in August following the assassination of political chief Ismail Haniyeh in Tehran "will take over the leadership of the group", the source added.</p>

<p>The committee was formed to facilitate decision-making in view of the difficulty of communicating with Sinwar in Gaza before his death.</p>

<p>Sinwar was named the Gaza chief of the terrorist group in 2017, before rising to become the overall leader of Hamas after Haniyeh was assassinated in July.</p>

<p>The source said the committee is made up of representatives of the two Palestinian territories and the community, namely Khalil al-Hayya for Gaza, Zaher Jabarin for the West Bank and Khaled Meshaal for Palestinians abroad.</p>

<p>It also includes the head of Hamas's Shura advisory council Mohammed Darwish and the secretary of the political bureau, who is never identified for security reasons.</p>

<p>All current members of the committee are based in Qatar.</p>

<p>According to the source, the committee is tasked with "governing the movement during the war and exceptional circumstances, as well as its future plans".</p>

<p>He added that it is authorised to "make strategic decisions".</p>

<p>Another source from the group said that the Hamas leadership discussed a proposal that was made "internally" to appoint a political chief without announcing their name.</p>

<p>But, the source added, the leaders preferred to rule through the committee.</p>

<p>Sinwar was killed by Israeli troops in southern Gaza on Wednesday, more than a year into the devastating war in the territory sparked by Hamas's October 7 attack.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/gk9jnhcg_hamas_625x300_19_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hamas Chief was killed by Israeli troops in southern Gaza on Wednesday. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-strikes-hezbollah-bunker-containing-millions-in-cash-and-gold-6842285]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Strikes Hezbollah Bunker Containing "Millions" In Cash, Gold]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-strikes-hezbollah-bunker-containing-millions-in-cash-and-gold-6842285]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 23:58:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Israeli army on Monday said it hit a Hezbollah bunker holding tens of millions of dollars worth of cash and gold during strikes aimed at the group's financial network.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Israeli army on Monday said it hit a Hezbollah bunker holding tens of millions of dollars worth of cash and gold during strikes aimed at the group's financial network.</p>

<p>"The Israeli Air Force carried out a series of precise strikes on these Hezbollah financial strongholds," said military spokesman Rear Admiral Daniel Hagari. "One of our main targets last night was an underground vault with millions of dollars in cash and gold. The money was being used to finance Hezbollah's attacks on Israel."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2016-09/israel-air-force_650x400_51472816126.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel air force's main target was underground vaults with cash and gold. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-to-limit-some-trade-transactions-to-block-data-access-by-russia-china-6842137]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US To Limit Some Trade Transactions To Block Data Access By Russia, China]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-to-limit-some-trade-transactions-to-block-data-access-by-russia-china-6842137]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 23:31:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The US Justice Department on Monday proposed new rules to protect federal government data or Americans' bulk personal data from getting into the hands of countries like China, Iran and Russia by placing new limits on certain business transactions.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The US Justice Department on Monday proposed new rules to protect federal government data or Americans' bulk personal data from getting into the hands of countries like China, Iran and Russia by placing new limits on certain business transactions.</p>

<p>The proposal, which was previewed in March, implements an executive order issued earlier this year by President Joe Biden which aims to keep foreign adversaries from using accessible American financial and genomic data and health data for cyber attacks, espionage and blackmail.</p>

<p>In addition to China, Russia and Iran, the rule would also apply to Venezuela, Cuba and North Korea.</p>

<p>Washington has been trying to stem the flow of American personal data to China, part of a years-long struggle over trade and technology.</p>

<p>In 2018, a US panel that reviews foreign investments for potential national security threats rejected a plan by China's Ant Financial to acquire U.S. money transfer company MoneyGram International, because of concerns over safety of data that can be used to identify US citizens.</p>

<p>The officials said transactions will be banned with data brokers who know the information will end up in "countries of concern", as will the transfer of any data on US government personnel.</p>

<p>Monday's proposal for the first time gave more specific details about the types and amounts of data that cannot be transferred, including human genomic data on over 100 Americans or personal health or financial data on over 10,000 people.</p>

<p>The proposal would also bar the transfer of precise geolocation data on over 1,000 US devices.</p>

<p>The rule would allow the Justice Department to enforce compliance both through criminal and civil penalties.</p>

<p>US officials told reporters on Monday that Chinese apps such as TikTok could run afoul of the proposal if they transferred sensitive data from US users to a Chinese parent company.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/9q90snc_us-justice-department_625x300_21_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Washington has been trying to stem the flow of American personal data to China. (Representation)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/helicopter-crash-in-houston-kills-4-including-child-destroys-radio-tower-6841978]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Helicopter Crash In Houston Kills 4, Including Child, Destroys Radio Tower]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/helicopter-crash-in-houston-kills-4-including-child-destroys-radio-tower-6841978]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 23:08:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A helicopter crash has killed four passengers, including a child, in the southern US city of Houston, authorities said, with the accident also destroying a radio transmission tower.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A helicopter crash has killed four passengers, including a child, in the southern US city of Houston, authorities said, with the accident also destroying a radio transmission tower.</p>

<p>The private aircraft "either struck a cable or actually struck at the tower", Houston police chief Noe Diaz told reporters.</p>

<p>No one on the ground was injured in the crash on Sunday, he added, and investigations to determine the cause of the accident were ongoing.</p>

<p>Television footage showed burning debris on the ground after the crash, and other videos -- apparently from CCTV cameras -- appeared to show the helicopter approaching the tower and then bursting into flame.</p>

<p>John Whitmire, the city's mayor, said the crash took place near a residential area and close to a highly flammable tank of butane.</p>

<p>"We are fortunate that it wasn't worse," he said.</p>

<p>Whitmire said firefighters had responded to the sound of a loud explosion, with a "fireball" visible in the air.</p>

<p>The helicopter had taken off from an airfield less than 18 miles (30 kilometers) from the crash site, according to authorities.</p>

<p>Houston, located in the state of Texas, is the fourth-largest city in the United States, with a population of 2.3 million.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/0ve05k4g_houston-helicopter-crash_625x300_21_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The crash took place near a residential area and close to a highly flammable tank of butane.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ndtv-world-summit-2024-why-switch-to-electric-vehicles-makes-sense-charge-zone-ceo-kartikey-hariyani-explains-6841922]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Why Switch To Electric Vehicles 'Makes Sense'? Charge Zone CEO Explains]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ndtv-world-summit-2024-why-switch-to-electric-vehicles-makes-sense-charge-zone-ceo-kartikey-hariyani-explains-6841922]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 22:59:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kartikey Hariyani, the founder and CEO of Electric vehicle (EV) charging network Charge Zone, while speaking at NDTV World Summit 2024, explained why switching to EV makes Sense.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kartikey Hariyani, the founder and CEO of Electric vehicle (EV) charging network Charge Zone, while speaking at <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/na-chain-na-araam-pm-modi-at-ndtv-world-summit-on-hard-work-6836565">NDTV World Summit 2024</a>, explained why switching to EV makes Sense.</p>

<p>"In India, the purpose of an EV or a car is for personal mobility. 80 percent of the mobility requirement of an Indian consumer is less than 51 k a day. So, with this stat, EV becomes a natural choice for adoption but it also (poses) a question whether the cost makes sense. Then as an individual consumer, you will say I don't need an EV or the payback is not really attractive," he said.</p>

<p>Mr Hariyani, however, insisted that "there is good news around".</p>

<p>"Two developments have happened in the industry so far. In the last two quarters, the cost of the battery has come down by half. The second good news is some of the OEMs (original equipment manufacturers) have initiated battery as a service which means battery and charging will effectively becomes your fuelling system. So, what you are going to buy will be a car without the battery cost, it means (it would be) equivalent to the cost of a petrol car," he said.</p>

<p>Mr Hariyani stressed that one has to think through carefully in terms of how the recharging networks will be planned.</p>

<p>"For each of the EV segments, the industry players have started investing into this. Six years ago, standards got built into this. Later on, local ecosystem played a big part. Localisation did happen in terms of semiconductors as well as power electronics. Today we are ready with the chargers, localised both for three wheelers and four wheelers," he said.</p>

<p>He also said that even though fast-charging is a key for adoption of EVs but it's not just about cars but also buses and trucks.</p>

<p>"For a charging company like us, when we started off in 2019, there were green sprouts around electric cars coming into the market, then electric buses started coming. And today we see the launch of electric trucks. As a priority, I will enable inter-city mobility. In other words, charging infra on highways is our priority number one. We have electrified 33,000 kms of highways in India. Fast-charging is a cornerstone. But, if I invest into fast-charging only for cars, I won't be able to make money even in my whole life time. Inter-city buses and inter-city trucks are going to be the biggest enablers," he added.</p>

<p>Earlier in the day, Prime Minister Narendra Modi emphasised the importance of clean energy for a better future, stating that "clean energy is the need of the hour".</p>

<p>At COP26, India committed to reducing projected carbon emissions by 1 billion tonnes by 2030 and achieving net-zero emissions by 2070. These commitments necessitate a rapid transition to renewables.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/m12gafl_kartikey-hariyani_625x300_21_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kartikey Hariyani said that "there is good news around" as far as prices of EVs were concerned.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-sued-for-defamation-over-false-comment-in-presidential-debate-6841905]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump Sued For Defamation Over False Comment In Presidential Debate]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-sued-for-defamation-over-false-comment-in-presidential-debate-6841905]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 22:55:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The "Central Park Five," five men who were falsely convicted of rape in a notorious 1989 New York case, launched a defamation lawsuit Monday against former US president Donald Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The "Central Park Five," five men who were falsely convicted of rape in a notorious 1989 New York case, launched a defamation lawsuit Monday against former US president Donald Trump.</p>

<p>The lawsuit, filed in a federal court in Pennsylvania, accuses the Republican White House candidate of making "false and defamatory" comments during the September 10 presidential debate with Vice President Kamala Harris in Philadelphia.</p>

<p>The five Black and Hispanic men -- Yusef Salaam, Raymond Santana, Kevin Richardson, Antron Brown and Korey Wise -- were teenagers when they were convicted of the rape and assault of a female jogger in Central Park.</p>

<p>They were eventually exonerated and their convictions were vacated in 2002. They received $41 million in a 2014 settlement with New York City.</p>

<p>Trump, during the presidential debate, "falsely stated that Plaintiffs killed an individual and pled guilty to the crime," the lawsuit said. "These statements are demonstrably false.</p>

<p>"Plaintiffs never pled guilty to any crime and were subsequently cleared of all wrongdoing."</p>

<p>The lawsuit also recalled that Trump, 11 days after the Central Park attack, published a full-page advertisement in four New York City newspapers calling to "bring back the death penalty."</p>

<p>Trump made comments about the "Central Park Five" after Harris mentioned the ad during the debate.</p>

<p>"A lot of people including Mayor Bloomberg agreed with me on the Central Park Five," Trump said, apparently confusing former New York mayor Michael Bloomberg with former New York mayor Ed Koch, who was the mayor at the time.</p>

<p>"They admitted -- they said, they pled guilty," Trump said. "And I said, well, if they pled guilty they badly hurt a person, killed a person ultimately.</p>

<p>"And if they pled guilty -- then they pled we're not guilty."</p>

<p>The "Central Park Five" are seeking a jury trial and unspecified damages.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/bdehpaas_donald-trump_625x300_17_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump made comments about the "Central Park Five" over mention of the ad during the debate. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/william-dalrymple-on-why-it-is-a-surprise-that-india-dominated-asia-for-1-000-years-6841825]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[William Dalrymple On Why It Is A "Surprise That India Dominated Asia For 1,000 Years"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/william-dalrymple-on-why-it-is-a-surprise-that-india-dominated-asia-for-1-000-years-6841825]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 22:40:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Archeology and solid scholarship show that India lay at the heart of ancient world, argued historian William Dalrymple, underscoring that the myth of the Silk road has made India seem more peripheral than it actually was.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Archeology and solid scholarship show that India lay at the heart of ancient world, argued historian William Dalrymple, underscoring that the myth of the Silk road has made India seem more peripheral than it actually was.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"This map which people continue to reproduce in book after book of what is said to be the silk road. We are told that the principal trade east-west in ancient times was this single line which ran from the Mediterranean to the South China sea. Even its modern edition called the maritime silk road which runs down from Guangzhou through the Malacca Strait bypasses India. The line just dots around the peninsula," said the historian speaking at NDTV World Summit on Monday.</p>

<p>"It is the contention in the book that I have just written - The Golden Road - that this is an entirely false premise. Memorised from this map and rooted takes. Compare it with the actual shape of roman trade with India which is revealed by new map put out by Oxford University this year," said Mr Dalrymple.</p>

<p>He detailed India's waxing soft power influence on the culture, education, religion and civilisations of the rest of the world from 250 BC-1200 AD.</p>

<p>"This is not about the Indian century, it's about the Indian millennium stretching from around 250 BC TO 1200 AD when India was the centre of the world," he said speaking at the Summit whose theme was 'The India Century'.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Look at this extraordinary image that just turned up in an archeological excavation in Egypt. You can see very clearly it is the Buddha's head. What's surprising is the marble is carved from in what is now Turkey. It was found in a temple on the shore of Red sea. It seems extraordinary that a Buddha would turn up in Egypt but it should not be so when you consider that just as Buddha's head is found in Egypt, 6,000 miles to the west of India so Angkor Wat to 5,000 miles to the east of India is entirely an Indian planned project. In the galleries of Angkor Wat, you see the battle of Kurukshetra, the battle of Lanka, images of Krishna and his gopis inspired by stories first told in the area here around Delhi. Why is this not better known. Why is it a surprise that India dominated Asia for as much as a 1,000 years," asked the historian.</p>

<p>Answering his own question, the historian said the blame lay partly in colonialism.</p>

<p>"Partly, the story is clearly about colonialism about the way that Macaulay and others like him said that a single shelf of good English books is worth entire native literature of India and Arabia," he said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The historian pointed out Rome and India were the main trading partners of each other in ancient India and not China. He added that romans knew every coast on the west coast of India and couldn't get enough of Indian products, underlining the importance of the country.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Here is a map of Roman coin hordes discovered by archeologists. None are found east of the Pamirs of the Oxus. Not a single Roman coin horde has ever been found in China. But there is a notable concentration of roman gold all around the coasts of India. India is dotted with Roman coin hordes. India and Rome were the principal trading partner of each other in the early millennia BC," he said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Very Indian looking deities and apsaras seen floating over the Buddhist temples of China tell the story of Indian art having more and more influence, said the historian.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Indian ideas were soon being transmitted through Afghanistan, through Bamiyan to China, where by 2nd and 3rd century we find the Budhha taking on the physiognomy of China. Originally Buddhism is just the religion brought by traders into China, but by the 5th and 6th century we find Gupta sculptures being copied by Chinese all over Ghangzuo and beginning to head eastwards into the heartlands of China," said the historian.</p>

<p>The historian described Nalanda University as the Oxbridge of ancient India which attracted students from all over, including Korea and Japan. &nbsp;</p>

<p>"Nalanda - the oxbridge, the Ivy League, the NASA of ancient Asia - was visited not just by monks from China but monks from Nepal, Korea and Japan. Its library had science, mathematics, astronomy, everything was gathered in this extraordinary space. Look at the plan of different monasteries and university buildings in Nalanda, it is the same as we find in Oxbridge," he said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Sanskrit emerged as the language of diplomacy and culture, spanning from Kandahar to Bali, he said, adding that the Palava script formed the base for various Southeast Asian scripts such as Khmer and Thai.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/ptidpedg_william-dalrymple_625x300_21_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[William Dalrymple at NDTV World Summit]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/not-a-birkin-internet-reacts-to-israels-claim-of-yahya-sinwars-wifes-rs-26-lakh-hermes-bag-6841700]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Internet Reacts To Israel's Claim Of Yahya Sinwar's Wife's Rs 26 Lakh Bag]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/not-a-birkin-internet-reacts-to-israels-claim-of-yahya-sinwars-wifes-rs-26-lakh-hermes-bag-6841700]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 22:24:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In the clip, Sinwar's wife is seen holding a bag, which Israel claimed to be worth $32,000 (around Rs 26.90 lakh).]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Days after Yahya Sinwar was killed in an Israeli operation in southern Gaza, a video has surfaced showing the Hamas leader, along with his wife and children, moving through a tunnel the night before the October 7 attack on Israel last year.</p>

<p>The CCTV footage, released by the Israel Defense Forces (IDF), captures Sinwar and his group carrying various supplies, including pillows, mattresses, a television, and several bags, into the tunnel.</p>

<p>In the clip, Sinwar's wife is seen holding a bag, which Israel claimed to be worth $32,000 (around Rs 26.90 lakh).</p>

<p>"Sinwar's wife was caught on camera sneaking into the tunnels the night before October 7, clutching a $32,000 Hermes Birkin bag! While Gazans faced hardships under Hamas, Sinwar and his family shamelessly lived in luxury, indulging while sending others to fight," Israel stated.</p>

<p>Lieutenant Colonel Avichay Adraee, the IDF's Arabic language spokesperson, reiterated this claim, highlighting the contrast between the opulent lifestyle of Sinwar's family and the poverty experienced by most residents of Gaza, who "struggle to afford basic necessities."</p>

<p>However, internet users were quick to criticize these claims. Many on X pointed out that the bag was not a "Birkin," accusing Israel of spreading false information.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">They are not stupid, they know that's not a Birkin, but they're pandering to an audience of evil, delusional beings who are willing to believe anything Israel says so they can continue their support without feelings of guilt bc the ppl they're murdering somehow deserve it. <a href="https://t.co/GZXsm1hx9O">https://t.co/GZXsm1hx9O</a></p>
— Rebecca Sevilla (@rebeccasev7) <a href="https://twitter.com/rebeccasev7/status/1848038997437694034?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 20, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>A user wrote, "They are not stupid, they know that's not a Birkin, but they're pandering to an audience of evil, delusional beings who are willing to believe anything Israel says so they can continue their support without feelings of guilt bc the ppl they're murdering somehow deserve it."</p>

<p>Another user commented, "Even someone with zero fashion sense knows this bag ain't no Hermes, not even close. How's the official Israel account gonna mess that up? Y'all are embarrassing yourselves out here."</p>

<p>"Haha such a lame propaganda to come up with, The oceans of the world are gonna dry up but your lies are never ending," the third user remarked.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Desperately clutching at straws. It's not a Birkin. And it's hilarious to see this coming from an official state account. You're neck and neck with old Katzy for the weirdest official account propaganda posts prize," the fourth user commented.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Isn't it embarrassing when an official account representing a state posts desperate propaganda? The world is laughing at you," the fifth user wrote.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/4l1eba3_yahya-sinwars-wife_625x300_21_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Internet users were quick to criticize these claims.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-election-2024-important-dates-6841651]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Important Dates In US Presidential Election 2024]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-election-2024-important-dates-6841651]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 22:17:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Republican former President Donald Trump and Vice President Kamala Harris, a Democrat, will face each other in the November 5 US presidential election.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Republican former President Donald Trump and Vice President Kamala Harris, a Democrat, will face each other in the November 5 US presidential election.</p>

<p>Here is a timeline of events related to the election between now and Inauguration Day in January.</p>

<p>- November 5: Election Day</p>

<p>- Later in November: It could take days for the election result to be known, especially if it is close and mail-in ballots are a factor.</p>

<p>- November 26: Trump, the first sitting or former US president to be convicted of a crime, is due to be sentenced in a Manhattan hush money case where he was found guilty of falsifying documents to cover up a payment to silence a porn star. Trump has denied wrongdoing. Sentencing was originally due to take place on September 18.</p>

<p>- December 17: Electors, who together form the Electoral College, meet in their respective states and the District of Columbia to select the president and vice president.</p>

<p>- December 25: The electoral votes must be received by this date by the president of the Senate - a role held by the vice president, currently Harris - and the archivist.</p>

<p>2025</p>

<p>- January 6: The vice president presides over the Electoral College vote count at a joint session of Congress, announces the results and declares who has been elected.</p>

<p>Ahead of the count on January 6, 2021, then-President Trump lambasted his vice president, Mike Pence, for refusing to try to prevent Congress from certifying President Joe Biden's victory over Trump. On that day, the US Capitol was attacked by Trump supporters trying to stop the count. Biden's win was certified early the next day.</p>

<p>Congress has since passed the Electoral Count Reform and Presidential Transition Improvement Act of 2022, which requires approval of one-fifth of the House and Senate to consider a challenge to a state's results - a much higher bar than existed before, when at least one member each in the Senate and House of Representatives could together trigger a challenge.</p>

<p>- January 20: The inauguration of the election winner and their vice president takes place. At this ceremony, the victor and the vice president are officially sworn into office.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/at6bqpl_us-election-generic-reuters_625x300_16_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[It could take days for the election result to be known. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>