<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Jul 2024 10:56:17 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jd-vance-once-a-donald-trump-critic-now-his-vice-president-pick-5-facts-6115630]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[JD Vance, Once A Donald Trump Critic, Now His Vice President Pick: 5 Facts]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jd-vance-once-a-donald-trump-critic-now-his-vice-president-pick-5-facts-6115630]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Jul 2024 10:21:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former US President Donald Trump on Monday announced US Senator JD Vance of Ohio as his running mate for the November Presidential polls.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former US President Donald Trump on Monday announced US Senator JD Vance of Ohio as his running mate for the November Presidential polls. The announcement came ahead of the former president's surprise appearance at the Republican National Convention, just two days after he survived an attempt on his life at a Pennsylvania rally.</p>

<p>Vance, a Republican senator from Ohio, will join Trump on the ticket to challenge President Joe Biden and Vice President Kamala Harris in the upcoming election.</p>

<p><strong>Who is JD Vance?</strong><br />
<br />
1. JD Vance was born James David Bowman in Middletown, Ohio, to a mother struggling with addiction. His father left the family when Vance was a toddler. He grew up with his grandparents; his grandmother “Mamaw” was a “blue dog” Democrat and a devout Christian who owned 19 handguns.<br />
<br />
2. Vance served in the US Marine Corps after high school, including a tour in the Iraq War. He then pursued higher education, graduating from The Ohio State University and Yale Law School. Until 2017, he worked at a venture capital firm.<br />
<br />
3. Before entering politics, Vance gained national attention with his memoir <em>Hillbilly Elegy,</em> which was later adapted into a Netflix movie.<br />
<br />
4. JD Vance is married to Indian-origin Usha Chilukuri Vance. They met at Yale Law School and got married in Kentucky in 2014. In addition to a traditional ceremony, they had a separate Hindu ceremony conducted by a Hindu priest. They have three children.<br />
<br />
5. Vance was once a vocal critic of Donald Trump, calling him an “idiot” and “reprehensible” and comparing him to Hitler in earlier interviews in 2016. However, he has now transformed into one of Trump's steadfast allies, rarely missing an opportunity to defend him. Although his name was long mentioned as a potential political candidate, Vance seized the chance to run for Ohio's Senate seat in 2022 after Republican Senator Rob Portman decided not to seek re-election. His campaign struggled initially but gained momentum after receiving a $10 million donation from his former boss, Peter Thiel. Despite being in a predominantly Republican state, Vance's past criticism of Donald Trump posed a hurdle to his election. He managed to mend things with the former President for his previous remarks and secure Trump's endorsement.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ie6h2jc4_jd-vance_625x300_16_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[JD Vance was once a vocal critic of Donald Trump (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/these-men-are-loneliest-at-the-workplace-suggests-new-research-6115551]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[These Men Are Loneliest At The Workplace, Suggests New Research]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/these-men-are-loneliest-at-the-workplace-suggests-new-research-6115551]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Jul 2024 10:08:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Loneliness affects everyone at different times. Although it is well-documented that men are less likely than women to talk about feelings and to seek help, our research found men's work arrangements can be a significant contributor.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Loneliness affects everyone at different times. Although it is well-documented that men are less likely than women to talk about feelings and to <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC6560805/">seek help</a>, our <a href="https://bmcpublichealth.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12889-024-18770-w">research</a> found men's work arrangements can be a significant contributor.</p>

<p>We found loneliness was highest among men in their late 40s but it also occurred at other times, often shaped by how they perceived their careers and income.</p>

<p>This suggests the workplace and societal expectations around work are important in men's experiences of loneliness.</p>

<h2>Measuring loneliness</h2>

<p>Our findings are based on an analysis of yearly data from 12,117 Australian men, aged 15 to 98, collected for over 19 years for the Household, Income and Labour Dynamics in Australia (HILDA) <a href="https://melbourneinstitute.unimelb.edu.au/hilda">Survey</a>.</p>

<p>We measured loneliness by examining men's responses to a question asking whether they agreed with the statement: “I often feel very lonely”. The responses range from one (completely disagree) to seven (completely agree).</p>

<p>We then used statistical techniques to ensure we were measuring loneliness and not similar constructs, such as social isolation.</p>

<p>We also used methods that examined how much of men's loneliness was uniquely due to their social relationships (for example, their romantic relationships or friendships), versus other aspects of their lives, such as their living situation or their working arrangements.</p>

<h2>The role of work</h2>

<p>Given loneliness is a social problem, we were not surprised to find problems in men's social relationships, particularly their romantic relationships, friendships and family relationships were linked with loneliness. However, we were surprised to see work also played a significant role.</p>

<p>Men who were unemployed or in insecure jobs experienced more loneliness than those with stable employment. Job loss can impact a person's identity and <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0277953621006717">limits the social connections work typically provides</a>. Unemployment also limits income, making it harder to afford social activities. Insecure “gig” work, with its often unpredictable and long hours spent alone, <a href="https://theconversation.com/working-in-isolation-can-pose-mental-health-challenges-heres-what-anyone-can-learn-from-how-gig-workers-have-adapted-194712">disrupts work-life balance and can isolate people</a>.</p>

<p>Our research suggests societal expectations also worsen loneliness for some men. We measured the degree to which men agreed with the statement: “It is not good for a relationship if the woman earns more than the man”.</p>

<p>Men, particularly middle-aged men, who believed they should be the main breadwinners in a household were lonelier than those without this belief.</p>

<p>This suggests traditional views around work in the context of heteronormative relationships can be damaging to social connection.</p>

<p>This once mainstream view not only <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC8211126/">harms relationships</a> but is also unrealistic when surviving on a single income is increasingly difficult for many households.</p>

<figure class="align-right "><img alt="Woman scientist using a dropper to put fluid in a test tube" sizes="(min-width: 1466px) 754px, (max-width: 599px) 100vw, (min-width: 600px) 600px, 237px" src="https://images.theconversation.com/files/598261/original/file-20240604-17-pn7eiu.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=237&amp;fit=clip" srcset="https://images.theconversation.com/files/598261/original/file-20240604-17-pn7eiu.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=338&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=1 600w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/598261/original/file-20240604-17-pn7eiu.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=30&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=338&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=2 1200w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/598261/original/file-20240604-17-pn7eiu.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=15&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=338&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=3 1800w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/598261/original/file-20240604-17-pn7eiu.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=424&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=1 754w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/598261/original/file-20240604-17-pn7eiu.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=30&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=424&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=2 1508w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/598261/original/file-20240604-17-pn7eiu.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=15&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=424&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=3 2262w" />
<figcaption><span class="caption">Men who believed men, not women, should be the main breadwinner were more lonely.</span> <span class="attribution"><a class="source" href="https://www.shutterstock.com/image-photo/woman-white-coat-protective-goggles-face-1708180012">Marion Weyo/Shutterstock</a></span></figcaption>
</figure>

<p>Improving men's personal relationships is only one way to reduce male loneliness. The work sector and social pressures around work should also adapt.</p>

<h2>Shifting social norms</h2>

<p>Public stereotypes that make men feel solely responsible for household income need to shift. Public awareness and education campaigns <a href="https://www.cell.com/heliyon/pdf/S2405-8440(21)00763-5.pdf">can help shift gender norms and stereotypes</a> by building knowledge and awareness, and may therefore reduce loneliness.</p>

<p>Helping men attain better work-life balance <a href="https://theconversation.com/helping-men-get-work-life-balance-can-help-everyone-43000">can help everyone</a>. Such change, however, requires major cultural shifts which take time. A shorter term solution, particularly for men at retirement age, is volunteering.</p>

<p>Volunteering provides purpose and opportunities to socialise, although <a href="https://csrm.cass.anu.edu.au/sites/default/files/docs/2023/10/Ongoing_trends_in_volunteering_in_Australia.pdf">recent evidence</a> suggests volunteering has not returned to pre-COVID levels.</p>

<h2>How governments can help</h2>

<p>Increasing casualisation of the workplace and the growth of the gig economy offer flexibility but also decrease job security. Our research shows job insecurity or unemployment rates contribute to male loneliness.</p>

<p>Government amendments to the Fair Work Act should help reduce job insecurity by allowing the Fair Work Commission to set fair minimum standards, including access to dispute resolution for “employee-like” workers, such as Uber drivers, who work through a digital platform.</p>

<p>Governments can also support activities of interest to men by ensuring regular funding for programs like <a href="https://mensshed.org/">Men's Sheds</a> or opportunities to <a href="https://www.volunteeringaustralia.org/wp-content/uploads/Volunteering-Australia-%E2%80%93-Navigating-change-and-charting-a-new-course-volunteering-in-recent-times.pdf">work with animals</a>.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC10092430/">Social prescribing</a> – where a GP or other health worker links patients with resources and activities to improve health and reduce loneliness – can also involve men in roles which best fit their needs and interests.</p>

<h2>How employers can help</h2>

<p>Thankfully, workplaces can do a lot to reduce loneliness. A recent <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0007681323000010">review</a> suggests employers can:</p>

<p>1) Create opportunities for social connection, for example, dedicating time for non-work activities such as designing communal areas in offices to support connection.</p>

<figure class="align-right "><img alt="Work colleagues at a social function" sizes="(min-width: 1466px) 754px, (max-width: 599px) 100vw, (min-width: 600px) 600px, 237px" src="https://images.theconversation.com/files/597939/original/file-20240603-20-oowkcg.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=237&amp;fit=clip" srcset="https://images.theconversation.com/files/597939/original/file-20240603-20-oowkcg.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=401&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=1 600w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/597939/original/file-20240603-20-oowkcg.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=30&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=401&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=2 1200w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/597939/original/file-20240603-20-oowkcg.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=15&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=401&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=3 1800w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/597939/original/file-20240603-20-oowkcg.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=503&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=1 754w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/597939/original/file-20240603-20-oowkcg.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=30&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=503&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=2 1508w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/597939/original/file-20240603-20-oowkcg.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=15&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=503&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=3 2262w" />
<figcaption><span class="caption">Creating social opportunities for workers can help reduce loneliness.</span> <span class="attribution"><a class="source" href="https://www.pexels.com/photo/elegantly-dressed-people-talking-to-each-other-at-a-banquet-6762286/">Kampus Productions/Pexels</a></span></figcaption>
</figure>

<p>2) Support flexible and remote, potentially isolated workers by fostering workplace connections using virtual spaces such as online dinners, while still encouraging work-life balance.</p>

<p>3) Foster a people focused culture by building employee autonomy, tolerating mistakes and providing mentoring opportunities.</p>

<p>The relationship between managers and workers is <a href="https://academic.oup.com/occmed/article/73/9/557/7591258">especially important</a> for well-being, because managers can shape working conditions, model positive behaviour and improve staff knowledge, but few interventions target this area.<!-- Below is The Conversation's page counter tag. Please DO NOT REMOVE. --><img alt="The Conversation" height="1" referrerpolicy="no-referrer-when-downgrade" src="https://counter.theconversation.com/content/230535/count.gif?distributor=republish-lightbox-basic" style="border: none !important; box-shadow: none !important; margin: 0 !important; max-height: 1px !important; max-width: 1px !important; min-height: 1px !important; min-width: 1px !important; opacity: 0 !important; outline: none !important; padding: 0 !important" width="1" /><!-- End of code. If you don't see any code above, please get new code from the Advanced tab after you click the republish button. The page counter does not collect any personal data. More info: https://theconversation.com/republishing-guidelines --></p>

<p><em><span><strong>(Authors:</strong>&nbsp;<a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/marlee-bower-1000885">Marlee Bower</a>, Research Fellow, Matilda Centre for Research in Mental Health and Substance Use, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/university-of-sydney-841">University of Sydney</a>; <a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/ferdi-botha-1142770">Ferdi Botha</a>, Senior Research Fellow, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/the-university-of-melbourne-722">The University of Melbourne</a>, and <a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/mark-deady-966282">Mark Deady</a>, Senior Research Fellow, Black Dog Institute, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/unsw-sydney-1414">UNSW Sydney</a>)</span></em></p>

<p><em>(This article is republished from <a href="https://theconversation.com">The Conversation</a> under a Creative Commons license. Read the <a href="https://theconversation.com/loneliness-in-the-workplace-is-greatest-among-men-with-traditional-views-about-being-the-breadwinner-230535">original article</a>.)</em></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/refqbhn8_loneliness_625x300_16_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Representational Image]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trumps-running-mate-says-china-is-the-biggest-threat-to-us-6115403]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Biggest Threat To Our Country...": Trump Vice President Pick's First Comments]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trumps-running-mate-says-china-is-the-biggest-threat-to-us-6115403]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Jul 2024 09:39:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[JD Vance branded China the biggest threat to America in one of his first interviews since being named Donald Trump's running mate.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>JD Vance branded China the biggest threat to America in one of his first interviews since being named Donald Trump's running mate, underscoring the likely hawkish stance of their administration toward Beijing if elected.</p>

<p>The Ohio Senator made the remarks in an interview with Fox News' Sean Hannity on Monday local time. When asked about the war in Ukraine, Vance said Trump would negotiate with Moscow and Kyiv to "bring this thing to a rapid close so America can focus on the real issue, which is China."</p>

<p>Senator JD Vance, a Republican from Ohio and Republican vice-presidential nominee, during the Republican National Convention (RNC) at the Fiserv Forum in Milwaukee, Wisconsin, US, on Monday, July 15, 2024. The Republican National Convention in Milwaukee will go on as scheduled, despite an assassination attempt against former</p>

<p>"That's the biggest threat to our country and we are completely distracted from it," he said, shortly after joining the Republican presidential ticket.</p>

<p>President Joe Biden and his challenger Trump are jockeying to be seen as tough on China as they head toward an election rematch in November. Trump has promised to hike tariffs on China across the board if reelected, vowing a 60% tax on all Chinese imports. Biden has already announced a new 100% levy on electric cars from the world's No. 2 economy.</p>

<p>US spies believe that China has no clear preference between the two candidates, Bloomberg News previously reported.</p>

<p>Vance, 39, was tapped by Trump days after a failed assassination attempt on the former president upended what had already been a chaotic presidential contest.</p>

<p>It's not the first time Vance has criticized China. The venture capitalist-turned-senator previously called for "broad-based tariffs" on Chinese goods and advocated for bringing American manufacturing back home to reduce dependency on Beijing.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/tv9u9rfk_jd-vance_625x300_16_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Experts say China has no clear preference between the two candidates]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fact-check-did-the-simpsons-predict-trump-assassination-attempt-6115400]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Fact-Check: Did 'The Simpsons' Predict Trump Assassination Attempt?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fact-check-did-the-simpsons-predict-trump-assassination-attempt-6115400]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Jul 2024 09:38:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Misinformation and conspiracy theories were spreading online after an assassination attempt on former U.S. President Donald Trump at a campaign rally on Saturday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Misinformation and conspiracy theories were spreading online after an assassination attempt on former U.S. President Donald Trump at a campaign rally on Saturday.</p>

<p>Thomas Matthew Crooks, 20, was alleged to have shot at the Republican presidential candidate from a rooftop during the rally in Butler, Pennsylvania, wounding Trump's right ear. One spectator died and two others were injured.</p>

<p>Reuters has fact-checked some of the most widely shared narratives online.</p>

<p><strong>Misidentified shooters</strong></p>

<p>Within hours of the shooting, an image surfaced online of a man dressed in a black sweatshirt, hat and black sunglasses. Social media posts said the man was "Antifa extremist" Mark Violets and that he was named by local police as the suspect in the assassination attempt.</p>

<p>However, the man in the photograph is Marco Violi, who had nothing to do with the shooting. Violi is an Italian sports writer who shares content on the Italian soccer team AC Roma.</p>

<p>In a statement emailed to Reuters and shared on his social media, Violi said he was in Rome and had awoken at 2 a.m. to numerous messages, adding that he "categorically denied any involvement in the situation."</p>

<p>Violi was not the only individual to have been misidentified in the immediate aftermath of the shooting.</p>

<p>Viral posts also misidentified another man, Maxwell Yearick, as the shooter. In 2016, various media outlets reported that Yearick, who does not resemble Crooks, was arrested outside a Pittsburgh Trump rally after an altercation with police.</p>

<p><strong>Altered Images, False Claims Shooting Was Staged&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p>Doctored images of Trump and Secret Service agents smiling on stage surfaced in the immediate aftermath of the shooting. The fake images were shared to support claims that the assassination attempt had been "staged" as a ploy to boost Trump's popularity in November's election.</p>

<p>The original photographs were captured by an Associated Press photographer and show Trump and the agents with serious facial expressions.</p>

<p>The FBI on Sunday said Crooks acted alone and the agency had yet to identify a motive.</p>

<p><strong>Predictive Programming Conspiracy Theories</strong></p>

<p>Predictive programming is a conspiracy theory, often revived in the aftermath of a major news event, that suggests governments and powerful groups provide indications of planned events to the public by embedding predictions in books, TV shows and movies.</p>

<p>Within an hour of the attempted assassination, a fabricated screenshot resurfaced of a cartoon of Trump in a casket and was described as a scene from the TV series "The Simpsons."</p>

<p>But this image has made the rounds on social media since at least 2017.</p>

<p>Matt Selman, an executive producer for the show, told Reuters in an email that the screenshot never appeared on the show, adding that it is "all too easy to create fake Simpsons 'predictions' like these for the purpose of misleading people."</p>

<p>A spokesperson for Trump did not immediately respond to a request for comment.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/68fqh6to_trump-assassination-attempt-reuters_625x300_15_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Reuters has fact-checked some of the most widely shared narratives online. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/shut-up-and-follow-how-airbnb-ceo-helped-sam-altman-grow-open-ai-6115346]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Shut Up And Follow...": How Airbnb CEO Helped Sam Altman Grow Open AI]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/shut-up-and-follow-how-airbnb-ceo-helped-sam-altman-grow-open-ai-6115346]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Jul 2024 09:26:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Mr Altman shared that Mr Chesky instructed him on who to hire and how to "map" out the company's strategy.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sam Altman has acknowledged that he heavily relied on advice from his friend, Airbnb CEO Brian Chesky, to grow OpenAI after ChatGPT became a global sensation. In a joint interview with Mr Chesky at the Aspen Ideas Festival, the OpenAI CEO mentioned that while many people offered help once ChatGPT gained popularity in late 2022, Mr Chesky was the only one who truly pitched in, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.cnbc.com/2024/06/28/sam-altman-airbnb-ceo-gave-me-hours-of-advice-on-growing-openai.html"><em>CNBC Make It </em></a>reported.</p>

<p>"Everything just went crazy for me," Mr Altman said. "Brian would sit down with me for about three hours every other week and provide a list of things I needed to do. He'd point out where I was behind, what I was messing up, and what I needed to proactively consider."</p>

<p>Five days after ChatGPT launched to the public, it surpassed 1 million users. By January 2023, the platform had 100 million monthly active users, making it the fastest-growing consumer application in history, according to CNBC Make It. As the Microsoft-backed artificial intelligence company experienced rapid growth, Chesky became a close confidant, Altman noted. Mr Chesky was "almost always right," Altman added, saying, "I learned to just always shut up and follow the advice."</p>

<p>Elaborating on the impact of Mr Chesky's advice on OpenAI's business, Altman mentioned that his friend guided him on hiring decisions and how to "map" out the company's strategy.</p>

<p>Recently, Mr Chesky pointed out that Mr Altman was "probably not thinking enough about" the political consequences of the company's generative AI technology, the OpenAI CEO said.</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/326llad8_sam-altman-and-brian-chesky_625x300_16_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Five days after ChatGPT launched to the public, it surpassed 1 million users.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-backs-election-of-donald-trump-with-fund-worth-45million-a-month-6115339]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Musk's Big Bet On Donald Trump, Pledges $45 Million A Month To Elect Him]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-backs-election-of-donald-trump-with-fund-worth-45million-a-month-6115339]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Jul 2024 09:24:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Tech billionaire Elon Musk said he plans to commit roughly $45 million each month to a new fund backing Donald Trump for US president, the Wall Street Journal reported Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Tech billionaire Elon Musk said he plans to commit roughly $45 million each month to a new fund backing Donald Trump for US president, the Wall Street Journal reported Monday.</p>

<p>Musk's donations will go to a political group dubbed America PAC, which will focus on promoting voter registration, early voting and mail-in ballots among residents in swing states ahead of the November general election, the Journal reported, citing people familiar with the matter.</p>

<p>Musk is one of several major backers of the new fund, with others reportedly including Palantir co-founder Joe Lonsdale, former US ambassador to Canada Kelly Craft and cryptocurrency investors Tyler and Cameron Winklevoss.</p>

<p>The Tesla founder formally endorsed Trump's candidacy for US president on Saturday after the former president survived a shooting at a political rally in Butler, Pennsylvania.</p>

<p>"I fully endorse President Trump and hope for his rapid recovery," Musk wrote on the social media platform X, which he acquired in 2022.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">I fully endorse President Trump and hope for his rapid recovery <a href="https://t.co/ZdxkF63EqF">pic.twitter.com/ZdxkF63EqF</a></p>
— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1812256998588662068?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 13, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Musk, the wealthiest man in the world with an estimated net worth of $250 billion, has grown increasingly friendly with Trump over the course of the 2024 US election.</p>

<p>In March, the two met in person during a donor breakfast hosted at the Florida residence of billionaire Nelson Peltz.</p>

<p>Though individual campaign donations in the United States are capped at $3,300 per person, loopholes in the campaign finance system allow political mega-donors to contribute to funds known as political action committees or "PACs," which support candidates.</p>

<p>Trump previously decried mail and absentee voting, but has backtracked on his criticisms after it became clear Democrats had an edge among mail voters.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/fpd88p5s_elon-musk-donald-trump_625x300_30_May_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[In March, Elon Musk met Donald Trump at the Florida residence of billionaire Nelson Peltz.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/king-charles-and-queen-camilla-rushed-to-safety-due-to-security-scare-over-false-alarm-6115224]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[King Charles, Queen Camilla Rushed To Safety Over False Security Alarm]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/king-charles-and-queen-camilla-rushed-to-safety-due-to-security-scare-over-false-alarm-6115224]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Jul 2024 08:55:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[King Charles and Queen Camilla were swiftly escorted to safety during an event in Jersey due to a security scare that was later deemed a false alarm.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>King Charles and Queen Camilla were quickly taken away from an event in Jersey on Monday due to a security scare.</p>

<p>Queen Camilla was eating ice cream when a member of the royal staff whispered something to her. At the same time, King Charles was approached by his protection officer and informed that they needed to leave immediately.</p>

<p>Both Charles and Camilla were then escorted to the nearby Pomme d'Or hotel for safety.</p>

<p>Matt Taylor, founder of Jersey Sea Salt, told the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.mirror.co.uk/news/royals/breaking-king-charles-queen-camilla-33249399"><em>Daily Mirror </em></a>he was talking to the King before being approached by his security detail.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/former-boxers-single-punch-results-in-mans-permanent-brain-injury-6115035#pfrom=home-ndtv_lateststories"><strong>Also Read | Former Boxer's Single Punch Results In UK Man's Permanent Brain Injury</strong></a><br />
<br />
He said, "He stopped at the stall and said, 'Ooh, sea salt.' And I said, 'Come and have a chat, sir'. Then his security appeared and grabbed me and said, 'He has to go, now.'</p>

<p>"He didn't seem panicked, but he was quite stern. They just ushered him out. It's a shame, as he'd stopped to chat with us of his own accord."</p>

<p>A concern raised by a member of the visit team led to this security alert, which was later determined to be a false alarm after a full background check. The event resumed shortly afterward.</p>

<p>This false alarm occurred just days after an assassination attempt on former US President Donald Trump at a campaign rally in Butler, Pennsylvania. Trump was hit in the ear by a bullet and then swiftly taken to the ground by Secret Service agents, who returned fire and killed the gunman, Thomas Matthew Crooks.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-04/i48eb7do_camilla-will-be-crowned-alongside-the-king-18-years-after-the-couple-tied-the-knot_625x300_05_April_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The couple was taken to a hotel, and the event resumed after the alert was cleared.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trumps-first-public-appearance-since-rally-shooting-with-a-bandaged-ear-6115142]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump's First Public Appearance Since Rally Shooting With A Bandaged Ear]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trumps-first-public-appearance-since-rally-shooting-with-a-bandaged-ear-6115142]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Jul 2024 08:40:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump received a hero's welcome Monday at the Republican National Convention in Milwaukee, as he made his first public appearance since being wounded in an assassination attempt.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump received a hero's welcome Monday at the Republican National Convention in Milwaukee, as he made his first public appearance since being wounded in an assassination attempt.</p>

<p>Wearing a white bandage on his ear, the former US president waved at a packed arena and received a standing ovation from cheering supporters, two days after the botched attack at a Pennsylvania rally.</p>

<p>Trump, 78, made no remarks to the convention, which erupted in loud applause and chants of "USA! USA!" Instead, he stood alongside his newly announced running mate, Senator J.D. Vance, and soaked in the warm reception.</p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/C9d9KtCSWKl/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C9d9KtCSWKl/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C9d9KtCSWKl/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C9d9KtCSWKl/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by NDTV (@ndtv)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>

<p>After surveying the convention floor filled with more than 2,400 delegates, Trump took a seat next to Vance in a VIP box that also included House Republican Byron Donalds and Speaker of the House Mike Johnson.</p>

<p>Trump, wearing a blue suit and a trademark red tie, smiled and applauded as officials, guests and others took the stage to address the convention -- and to thank their party leader or praise his survival from a would-be assassin's attack.</p>

<p>Given Saturday's horrific events, "he has proven to be one tough S.O.B.," Sean O'Brien, president of the major International Brotherhood of Teamsters union, told the convention, drawing a huge roar from the crowd.</p>

<p>Trump is due on Thursday to formally accept his party's nomination as flagbearer to challenge President Joe Biden in the November 5 election.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/lgq0obi8_trump-at-convention-with-bandaged-ear-afp_625x300_16_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Wearing a white bandage on his ear, Donald Trump waved at a packed arena.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/yemens-houthis-attack-2-ships-in-red-sea-for-using-israeli-ports-6115070]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Yemen's Houthis Attack 2 Ships In Red Sea For Using Israeli Ports]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/yemens-houthis-attack-2-ships-in-red-sea-for-using-israeli-ports-6115070]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Jul 2024 08:19:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Yemen's Houthi rebels on Monday said they targeted two tankers in the Red Sea with missiles and drones after a British security agency reported several attacks in the troubled waterway.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yemen's Houthi rebels on Monday said they targeted two tankers in the Red Sea with missiles and drones after a British security agency reported several attacks in the troubled waterway.</p>

<p>In a statement on social media platform X, Houthi military spokesperson Yahya Saree identified the two ships as BENTLEY I, a Panama-flagged oil tanker, and the CHIOS LION, a Liberia-flagged crude oil tanker.</p>

<p>The BENTLEY I was attacked with "drone boats, unmanned aerial vehicles, and ballistic missiles", while the CHIOS LION was targeted with uncrewed surface vessels, Saree said.</p>

<p>They were targeted because their owners had used Israeli ports, according to the rebel spokesperson.</p>

<p>Earlier on Monday, the United Kingdom Maritime Trade Operations reported two separate incidents in the Red Sea.</p>

<p>A ship sailing southwest of the port city of Hodeidah came under attack from three small vessels, two of which had three people each on board, UKMTO said.</p>

<p>The third skiff was unmanned, according to the agency, which is run by Britain's Royal Navy.</p>

<p>The "unmanned small craft collided with the vessel twice and the two manned small craft fired at the vessel", UKMTO said.</p>

<p>"After 15 minutes, the small craft aborted the attack. The vessel and crew are reported safe and the vessel is proceeding to its next port of call."</p>

<p>The same ship later reported four missiles exploding in "close proximity", UKMTO said, adding that the strikes did not cause any injuries or damage.</p>

<p>British maritime security firm Ambrey also reported the attack, saying the merchant vessel had a private armed security team on board.</p>

<p>In a separate incident on Monday, an uncrewed surface vessel "impacted" a merchant vessel 97 nautical miles northwest of Hodeidah, UKMTO said.</p>

<p>The attack caused "some damage and light smoke", it said, adding that "the vessel and crew are reported safe and proceeding to next port of call".</p>

<p>Houthi drone and missile strikes have taken place despite the deployment of Western naval forces to protect ships in the Red Sea, a vital waterway for global trade.</p>

<p>Since January, the United States and Britain have carried out repeated retaliatory strikes on Houthi targets in Yemen.</p>

<p>On Sunday, the US military's Central Command (CENTCOM) said its forces destroyed several Houthi drones.</p>

<p>"These actions were taken to protect freedom of navigation and make international waters safer and more secure," it said in a post on social media platform X.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ej8s0nk8_yemen-houthi_625x300_16_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[File photo]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-says-new-republican-vice-president-jd-vance-is-clone-of-donald-trump-6115061]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Clone Of Trump": Biden On Republican Vice President Pick JD Vance]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-says-new-republican-vice-president-jd-vance-is-clone-of-donald-trump-6115061]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Jul 2024 08:10:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA["A clone of Trump on the issues," Joe Biden told reporters before flying to Nevada.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden on Monday dismissed Donald Trump's newly-picked running mate JD Vance as a "clone" of the Republican former president.</p>

<p>"A clone of Trump on the issues," Biden told reporters before flying to Nevada when asked about the Ohio senator. "I don't see any difference."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/fjskrtjc_jd-vance_625x300_16_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["I don't see any difference," said Joe Biden on Donald Trump's newly-picked running mate JD Vance]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/former-boxers-single-punch-results-in-mans-permanent-brain-injury-6115035]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Former Boxer's Single Punch Results In UK Man's Permanent Brain Injury]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/former-boxers-single-punch-results-in-mans-permanent-brain-injury-6115035]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Jul 2024 08:10:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Chris Harris, a father of three from Merthyr Tydfil, sustained a permanent brain injury from a single punch by former professional boxer Daniel Gerrard outside a pub in 2022.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Chris Harris, a 40-year-old Merthyr Tydfil resident and father of three, had a permanent brain injury from a single punch outside of a pub. He now faces a lengthy recovery process. The incident happened outside the Vulcan Inn in the wee hours of May 2, 2022.</p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://metro.co.uk/2024/07/15/man-left-permanent-brain-injury-single-punch-ex-boxer-21232132/">reports</a>, Harris was struck by former professional boxer Daniel Gerrard. This is not Gerrard's first offence; he has a prior conviction for manslaughter in 2012, resulting from a fatal punch during another pub brawl. The force of Gerrard's blow rendered Harris unconscious.</p>

<p>Harris sustained a serious head injury, including a two-inch skull fracture and bleeding on the brain. He woke up a day later at the University Hospital of Wales in Cardiff. The full extent of his recovery and the lasting effects of the brain injury remain unclear.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Describing the aftermath of the attack, Chris told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.walesonline.co.uk/news/wales-news/i-punched-outside-nightclub-changed-29531140"><em>WalesOnline: </em></a>“I was woken up by my wife Lynsey, and she told me I had a massive brain injury and what happened. They'd operated fast and drilled my skull to release the pressure. I just broke down in tears. I thought my life was done. I had an hour to live basically before they operated."</p>

<p>“Lynsey told me that when she went home while I was being operated on, she didn't know if I would survive. I woke up after the operation in so much pain that I was crying throughout. I remained on the critical care ward for three days. Only three days later was I able to look at the scar on my head. It had 23 staples for that injury, and I was shocked by it. I stopped eating and lost a stone and a half in weight. When you go through something like that, you just think, ‘Wow. I've got three kids.' I just didn't know how we'd cope.”</p>

<p>Detective Constable <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.south-wales.police.uk/news/south-wales/news/2023/med-sep/merthyr-man-jailed-for-unprovoked-assault/">Michael Snare commented</a>, "Our thorough &nbsp;investigation showed at no time did Gerrard act in self-defence. All four men he violently assaulted did not pose any threat to him at the time he attacked them. Gerrard caused significant harm to these innocent bystanders."</p>

<p>The third victim suffered significant injuries having to undergo lifesaving surgery for a bleed to the brain. The other victims had a lump to the side of his head, and the first victim sustained stiches to his eyes, a broken nose and bruising and swelling to his face."</p>

<p>Gerrard from the Gurnos was sentenced to a total of four years imprisonment, with an extended licence of one year. While Jason Cox received a 12-month suspended sentence.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/04dmcbng_daniel-gerrard_625x300_16_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Daniel Gerrard has been sentenced to four years in jail for an unprovoked assault.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-president-joe-biden-says-using-the-word-bullseye-against-donald-trump-was-a-mistake-6114855]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Joe Biden Says Using The Word "Bullseye" Against Donald Trump Was A Mistake]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-president-joe-biden-says-using-the-word-bullseye-against-donald-trump-was-a-mistake-6114855]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Jul 2024 07:11:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden on Monday said he was wrong to call for Donald Trump to be put in the "bullseye" in the race for the White House.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden on Monday said he was wrong to call for Donald Trump to be put in the "bullseye" in the race for the White House.</p>

<p>"It was a mistake to use the word," Biden told NBC when asked if he had gone too far with his rhetoric against the newly confirmed Republican nominee, who survived an attempted assassination Saturday at a campaign rally in Pennsylvania.</p>

<p>"I meant focus on him, focus on what he's doing. Focus on his policies, focus on the number of lies he told in the debate," said Biden.</p>

<p>The assassination attempt, in which Trump was grazed in one ear, shocked a nation already deeply polarized ahead of the November election.</p>

<p>Several prominent Republicans have since accused Biden of having responsibility for the assassination attempt because of his language against Trump.</p>

<p>"The central premise of the Biden campaign is that President Donald Trump is an authoritarian fascist who must be stopped at all costs," said J.D. Vance, who was announced on Monday as Trump's running mate for the 2024 ticket.</p>

<p>"That rhetoric led directly to President Trump's attempted assassination," wrote Vance on social media.</p>

<p>Biden had made the initial comments in a call to Democratic donors early last week.</p>

<p>"It's time to put Trump in the bullseye," the president said, in a call that was intended to galvanize supporters amid growing dissent over Biden's continued candidacy.</p>

<p>Those divisions emerged from Biden's disastrous debate performance last month, in which the president slurred his words, spoke incoherently at times and stood with mouth agape while Trump talked.</p>

<p>Biden's interview with NBC on Monday was the latest post-debate attempt by the White House to assuage growing fears over the 81-year-old president's age and mental state.</p>

<p>Speaking without the aid of a teleprompter, Biden told NBC's Lester Holt that his mental sharpness was "pretty damn good."</p>

<p>"I'm old," Biden told the US broadcaster, according to a transcript.</p>

<p>"But I'm only three years older than Trump, number one. And number two, my mental acuity has been pretty damn good."</p>

<p>He added: "I understand why people say, 'God, he's 81 years old. Whoa. What's he gonna be when he's 83 years old, 84 years?' It's a legitimate question to ask."</p>

<p>While accepting his language against Trump had been a "mistake," Biden said it was right to maintain focus on the threat posed by another Trump presidency.</p>

<p>"Look, I'm not the guy that said 'I want to be a dictator on day one,'" he said, referring to remarks by Trump that alarmed many people</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/dkviueqo_joe-biden-afp-_625x300_15_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Joe Biden had made the initial comments in a call to Democratic donors early last week.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-vice-president-pick-jd-vance-supports-big-tech-antitrust-crackdown-6114703]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Vice President Pick JD Vance Supports Big Tech Antitrust Crackdown]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-vice-president-pick-jd-vance-supports-big-tech-antitrust-crackdown-6114703]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Jul 2024 06:21:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Trump's vice presidential pick J.D. Vance has openly praised the work of Federal Trade Commission Chair Lina Khan, a sign that the agency's broad approach to antitrust enforcement could enjoy some level of support from a second Trump administration.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former U.S. President Donald Trump's vice presidential pick J.D. Vance has openly praised the work of Federal Trade Commission Chair Lina Khan, a sign that the agency's broad approach to antitrust enforcement could enjoy some level of support from a second Trump administration.</p>

<p>Vance, a Republican U.S. senator from Ohio, joined the presidential ticket on Monday at the Republican National Convention in Milwaukee, where Trump officially became the party's nominee.</p>

<p>Vance is one of several Republican lawmakers, including U.S. Senator Josh Hawley of Missouri and Florida U.S. Representative Matt Gaetz, called "Khanservatives" for their agreement with the FTC chair that U.S. antitrust law has a broader purpose than keeping prices down for consumers.</p>

<p>"She recognized there has to be a broader understanding of how we think about competition in the marketplace," Vance said at an event in Washington in February.</p>

<p>The comments reflect a tension in the conservative movement, between an impulse to shrink regulatory agencies and a willingness to use antitrust laws to challenge powerful corporations — especially in Big Tech, where some hope to tackle perceived censorship of conservatives online.</p>

<p>Joseph Coniglio, director of antitrust policy at the Information Technology and Innovation Foundation, said Vance is among the latter.</p>

<p>"I do think that picking Senator Vance as vice president certainly sends a signal in one direction," said Coniglio. His think tank receives funding from several major technology companies.</p>

<p>Scrutiny of Big Tech would not be a departure for Trump. The FTC and Department of Justice under Trump initiated investigations into Meta, Amazon, Apple and Google over alleged antitrust violations. All four companies were eventually sued, and have denied wrongdoing.</p>

<p>Vance is a Yale-educated lawyer and venture capitalist who worked at corporate law firm Sidley Austin and has helped Trump fundraise in Silicon Valley. He has also called for the breakup of one of its biggest companies.</p>

<p>"Long overdue, but it's time to break Google up," Vance tweeted in February, lamenting that "monopolistic control of information in our society resides with an explicitly progressive technology company."</p>

<p>It remains to be seen what a potential second Trump administration would focus on. The conservative Heritage Foundation's Project 2025 policy platform discusses ways conservative causes can be championed by antitrust enforcers, but also questions whether the FTC should continue to exist.</p>

<p>Business groups have criticized President Joe Biden's antitrust enforcers for going beyond traditional considerations of how competition affects prices to focus on issues including labor.</p>

<p>The U.S. Chamber of Commerce has sued to block the FTC's recent ban on employers requiring workers to sign agreements not to join rivals or launch competing businesses.</p>

<p>Vance said at the February event, hosted by Silicon Valley startup incubator Y Combinator, that his view of antitrust encompasses not only helping small firms compete, but also on workers and the quality of consumer goods.</p>

<p>He disagreed with what he described as some conservatives' view that corporations' behavior cannot be "tyrannical."</p>

<p>"I want people to live good lives in our country," he said. "I don't really care if the entity that is most threatening to that vision is a private entity or a public entity."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ie6h2jc4_jd-vance_625x300_16_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump chose senator JD Vance as his vice president pick on Monday.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/meet-india-origin-usha-chilukuri-vance-wife-of-trumps-vice-president-pick-6114615]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Meet Indian-Origin Usha Chilukuri Vance, Wife Of Trump's Vice President Pick]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/meet-india-origin-usha-chilukuri-vance-wife-of-trumps-vice-president-pick-6114615]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Jul 2024 05:54:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Usha Chilukuri Vance, the wife of JD Vance, whom Donald Trump declared as his running mate in the upcoming US presidential elections on Monday, brings a wealth of credentials and a deep connection to Indian values and culture.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Usha Chilukuri Vance, the wife of JD Vance, whom Donald Trump declared as his running mate in the upcoming US presidential elections on Monday, brings a wealth of credentials and a deep connection to Indian values and culture.</p>

<p>A litigator at a national firm, Usha Vance is the daughter of Indian immigrants and has an impressive academic background.</p>

<p>She holds a bachelor's degree in History from Yale University and a Master of Philosophy degree from the University of Cambridge, according to the New York Times.</p>

<p>Born Usha Chilukuri, she has carved out a distinguished career in the legal field, having clerked for Supreme Court Justices John Roberts and Brett Kavanaugh before Kavanaugh's nomination to the Court.</p>

<p>Raised in a suburb of San Diego, California, with a strong emphasis on education and hard work, Usha's academic achievements include serving as Managing Editor of the Yale Journal of Law &amp; Technology and Executive Development Editor of The Yale Law Journal, according to a biography from Munger, Tolles &amp; Olson law firm.</p>

<p>After four years of intense extracurricular activity at Yale, she continued her studies as a Gates fellow at Cambridge, where she engaged with left-wing and liberal groups. She was a registered Democrat in 2014.</p>

<p>Usha and JD Vance first met at Yale Law School and were married in Kentucky in 2014, with a Hindu priest presiding over a separate ceremony, according to the New York Times. The couple has three children together.</p>

<p>Usha Vance has played a subtle yet significant role in her husband's success. She assisted Vance in organizing his thoughts on the social decline in rural white America, which inspired his best-selling memoir, Hillbilly Elegy, which was adapted into a film directed by Ron Howard in 2020.</p>

<p>In the past, she has made some rare appearances with Vance as he sought the Ohio Senate seat.</p>

<p>As the US presidential elections draw near, former US President Donald Trump made his pick for Vice President, selecting JD Vance as his running mate on Monday. Trump confirmed Vance's candidature through a post on social media.</p>

<p>Speaking to ANI, a US-based global real estate investment advisor and a well-known entrepreneur, AI Mason said, "Usha Vance is a highly accomplished attorney and daughter of Indian immigrants -- and her husband brings youth and diversity to the Trump ticket."</p>

<p>"She knows the Indian culture and all about India. She can be a big help to her husband in navigating great ties between USA and India," the entrepreneur, who is also a friend of the Trump family, said.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, in an interview earlier with Fox &amp; Friends, Usha Chilukuri Vance and her Senator husband talked about the two having different faiths, and what are their views on the speculations of him becoming a pick for the Vice President of the US.</p>

<p>"I don't think people understand how hard he works and how creative he is. Everything he says and does is built on a foundation of so much thought. He's always trying to do better," Usha Vance said.</p>

<p>On being asked about the reason behind her support for JD Vance, as the US Presidential elections remain around the corner, Usha told Fox, "There are a few different reasons...One is that I grew up in a religious household. My parents are Hindu, and that was one of the things that made them such good parents, that makes them really very good people. And so I think I've seen that...the power of that in my own life, and I knew that JD was searching for something. This just felt right for him."</p>

<p>The interview was taken three weeks before the announcement of JD Vance as the running mate of Trump in the upcoming US presidential polls.</p>

<p>Vance was born James David Bowman in Middletown, Ohio, to a mother who struggled with addiction and a father who left the family when JD was a toddler. He was raised by his grandparents.</p>

<p>The Trump campaign says the former president, following his brush with death, will call for unity in the face of tragedy instead of criticising his political adversaries as he faces off with President Biden in a 2024 election rematch.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ritlupvk_usha-chilukuri-vance_625x300_16_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Usha Vance is the daughter of Indian immigrants and has an impressive academic background.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/unsinkable-trump-riding-wave-of-wins-6114502]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Unsinkable: Trump Riding Wave Of Wins]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/unsinkable-trump-riding-wave-of-wins-6114502]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Jul 2024 05:17:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[After dodging a bullet at a rally and seeing the US Supreme Court bolster his presidential immunity claims this month, Donald Trump was handed another gift Monday: the dismissal of his classified documents case.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After dodging a bullet at a rally and seeing the US Supreme Court bolster his presidential immunity claims this month, Donald Trump was handed another gift Monday: the dismissal of his classified documents case.</p>

<p>As the only president ever to be twice impeached -- and twice acquitted -- and the country's only ex-president convicted of criminal charges, the septuagenarian has often struggled to stay afloat.</p>

<p>His blunders, multitude of scandals and vitriolic statements have shocked millions of Americans. Many heads of state see him as a danger to global stability and the fight against global warming, and he has stood accused of indulging far-right groups and disparaging immigrants.</p>

<p>But each time he is said to be sunk, he roars back to the surface, and this week he is heading into Milwaukee riding very high.</p>

<p>On Thursday the Republican National Convention will overlook Trump's vows of vengeance against his political enemies and swat aside his various legal woes to formally nominate him as the party's flagbearer going into the November election against President Joe Biden.</p>

<p>Trump, the brash billionaire who burst onto the political landscape a decade ago as a super disruptor and champion of conservatives, appears unstoppable.</p>

<p>"It sure seems he's on a roll," Texas alternate delegate Orlando Dona, wearing Trump pins and a straw-colored cowboy hat, told AFP.</p>

<p>The 64-year-old Dona, like many conservatives, believes the various cases against Trump have been politically motivated, "and he is coming out of all this justified."</p>

<p>As for the shooting, some are chalking it up to divine intervention.</p>

<p>"I personally think it was the hand of God," Wisconsin former governor Scott Walker told AFP at the convention.</p>

<p>Walker, who ran for president against Trump briefly in 2016, said Trump the man has earned a reputation for taking on anything.</p>

<p>"He's never going to stop being a fighter," he said. "And I think people here realize he's fighting for them, and these wins are not just about wins for him, they're wins for the American people."</p>

<p><strong>- 'A lot of obstacles' -</strong></p>

<p>Trump earned the nickname "Teflon Don" for weathering a multitude of storms.</p>

<p>The #MeToo movement precipitated the downfall of dozens of powerful Americans. Not Trump, despite multiple accusations of sexual abuse, a 2023 civil trial finding of liability for the sexual assault of writer E. Jean Carroll, and an alleged affair with pornographic actress Stormy Daniels.</p>

<p>After an explosive "Access Hollywood" tape emerged in 2016 in which Trump makes degrading remarks about women and boasted about groping their genitals, some Republican heavyweights withdrew their support, and he was predicted to lose the female vote.</p>

<p>That collapse didn't happen, and he won the White House a month later.</p>

<p>Now, it appears he will pull off another miracle, avoiding three of the four lawsuits he had been facing before the election.</p>

<p>"If the story of even the last 18 months teaches us anything, there were a lot of obstacles that were put up to president Trump, and the fact that he's gotten through them shows, I think, part of what gives me faith in this country," businessman and former 2024 Vivek Ramaswamy told reporters at the convention.</p>

<p>"As Martin Luther King said, the arc of history is long but it bends towards justice," Ramaswamy said. "I believe that's exactly what it is doing in recent months, days, and over the last year of president Trump's journey as well."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/trbnmngo_donald-trump_625x300_02_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[On Monday, Republican Party officially nominated Donald Trump as their presidential nominee.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-says-his-mental-acuity-is-pretty-damn-good-amid-health-concerns-6114472]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden Says His Mental Acuity Is "Pretty Damn Good" Amid Health Concerns]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-says-his-mental-acuity-is-pretty-damn-good-amid-health-concerns-6114472]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Jul 2024 05:01:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Joe Biden defended his decision to stay in the US presidential race despite concerns about his age, saying Monday in an interview with NBC that his mental sharpness was "pretty damn good."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Joe <span class="markdjkwav29g" data-markjs="true" data-ogab="" data-ogac="" data-ogsb="" data-ogsc="" style="">Biden</span> defended his decision to stay in the US presidential race despite concerns about his age, saying Monday in an interview with NBC that his mental sharpness was "pretty damn good."</p>

<p>"I'm old," <span class="markdjkwav29g" data-markjs="true" data-ogab="" data-ogac="" data-ogsb="" data-ogsc="" style="">Biden</span> told the US broadcaster, according to a transcript. "But I'm only three years older than Trump, number one. And number two, my mental acuity has been pretty damn good."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/dkviueqo_joe-biden-afp-_625x300_15_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Joe Biden defended his decision to stay in the US presidential race despite concerns about his age.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/soldier-injured-in-paris-knife-attack-suspect-arrested-cops-6114118]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Soldier Injured In Paris Knife Attack, Suspect Arrested: Cops]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/soldier-injured-in-paris-knife-attack-suspect-arrested-cops-6114118]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Jul 2024 03:00:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A soldier guarding a major Parisian railway station on Monday was injured in a knife attack by a man who was then arrested, Interior Minister Gerald Darmanin said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A soldier guarding a major Parisian railway station on Monday was injured in a knife attack by a man who was then arrested, Interior Minister Gerald Darmanin said.</p>

<p>The soldier's life was not in danger, Darmanin said on X, while a police source told AFP that he had suffered a shoulder wound.</p>

<p>The attack at the Gare de l'Est station in northern Paris came less than two weeks before the start of the Olympic Games in the French capital.</p>

<p>"Thoughts to the soldier injured tonight at the Gare de l'Est," Armed Forces Minister Sebastien Lecornu wrote on X, paying tribute to the French troops protecting citizens.</p>

<p>He said the soldier was part of a special military operation to protect sensitive sites in Paris that was launched following the 2015 Islamist attacks on the satirical Charlie Hebdo newspaper.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/pkvd3pmo_paris-knife-attack_625x300_16_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A soldier guarding a major Parisian railway station on Monday was injured in a knife attack by a man.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-camp-slams-donald-trumps-extremist-vice-president-pick-6114005]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden Camp Slams Trump's "Extremist" Vice President Pick]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-camp-slams-donald-trumps-extremist-vice-president-pick-6114005]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Jul 2024 02:17:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden's campaign on Monday dismissed Donald Trump's newly-unveiled running mate J.D. Vance as a "far-right MAGA extremist."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden's campaign on Monday dismissed Donald Trump's newly-unveiled running mate J.D. Vance as a "far-right MAGA extremist."</p>

<p>"Vance is a 2020 election denier, supports a national abortion ban, and voted against IVF access," Biden's team said.</p>

<p>The president said Vance "talks a big game about working people. But now, he and Trump want to raise taxes on middle-class families while pushing more tax cuts for the rich."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/fjskrtjc_jd-vance_625x300_16_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump on Monday picked J.D. Vance as his running mate.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-officially-nominated-as-2024-republican-nominee-6113877]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Nominated Republican Nominee, Picks Old Critic As Running Mate]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-officially-nominated-as-2024-republican-nominee-6113877]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Jul 2024 01:39:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Republican Party on Monday formally confirmed Donald Trump as its nominee to take on President Joe Biden in November's election.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump won formal nomination Monday as the Republican presidential candidate and picked a right-wing loyalist for running mate, kicking off a triumphalist party convention in the wake of last weekend's failed assassination attempt.</p>

<p>Trump announced 39-year-old Ohio Senator J.D. Vance as his vice presidential pick, rewarding a one-time harsh critic who became one of his most reliable -- and uncompromising -- supporters in Congress.</p>

<p>Trump, 78, is guaranteed a hero's welcome at the convention in Milwaukee, where delegates delivered their formal nomination two days after the scandal-plagued former president survived an assassination attempt at a rally.</p>

<p>"As Vice President, J.D. will continue to fight for our Constitution, stand with our Troops, and will do everything he can to help me MAKE AMERICA GREAT AGAIN," Trump posted on Truth Social.</p>

<p>While Trump is increasingly confident of a shock return to the White House -- despite multiple legal problems and two impeachments during his first term -- President Joe Biden is reeling from weak polls and Democratic concerns over his health.</p>

<p>In the delegates count in Milwaukee, Eric Trump put his father over the threshold on behalf of the Florida delegation, calling him "the greatest president that ever lived."</p>

<p>Vance had been widely expected as Trump's pick. He will bolster the ticket on the right wing, but with less chance of expanding appeal to more moderate voters and women.</p>

<p>The standard-bearer for a new kind of populism that has come to the fore under Trump, Vance is also one of the least experienced VP picks in modern history.</p>

<p>But he embraces the ex-president's isolationist, anti-immigration America First movement. Vance is further to the right than his new boss on many issues including abortion, where he embraces calls for federal legislation.</p>

<p>He initially made his name with the 2016 memoir "Hillbilly Elegy," a best-selling account of his Appalachian family and modest Rust Belt upbringing, which gave a voice to rural, working-class resentment in left-behind America.</p>

<p>Turning his back on previous opposition to Trump, whom he once said might be "America's Hitler," Vance reinvented himself and ultimately won the ex-president's key endorsement in the 2022 Ohio Senate race, launching his meteoric rise.</p>

<p><strong>- 'Supposed to be dead' -</strong></p>

<p>Trump's convention comes as the country is still reeling from a botched attempt by a gunman to kill Trump at a rally in Pennsylvania Saturday.</p>

<p>Some 50,000 Republicans descended on the shores of Lake Michigan for the four-day gathering, four months before election day.</p>

<p>The attempted assassination -- in which one bystander was killed, two more wounded and Trump received a light wound in his ear -- was expected to dominate proceedings.</p>

<p>The Secret Service, which is battling criticism it failed to protect Trump from the shooter, said it was "fully prepared" to ensure security at the convention.</p>

<p>Leading in multiple polls, despite being convicted at his hush-money criminal case in New York, Trump is exuding confidence.</p>

<p>At 81, Biden is facing calls from his own side to quit the race over concerns around his age.</p>

<p>His campaign released a statement saying the Trump-Vance agenda would "take away Americans' rights, hurt the middle class, and make life more expensive -- all while benefiting the ultra-rich and greedy corporations."</p>

<p>Trump scored another victory Monday as a judge dismissed the criminal case against him over accusations he endangered national security by holding on to top secret documents after leaving the White House.</p>

<p>- Message of unity -</p>

<p>He immediately took to Truth Social to call for the dismissal of all legal cases against him, insisting again that he was being targeted for political reasons.</p>

<p>Trump told the New York Post he had "prepared an extremely tough speech" about Biden's "horrible administration" to deliver at the convention.</p>

<p>As some Republicans -- including Vance -- sought to blame Democrats' anti-Trump rhetoric for the attack, Trump also said he hopes to "unite our country."</p>

<p>Still, that would see him have to rein in the instinct to settle scores -- demonstrated by his cry for supporters to "fight" in the seconds after Saturday's attack.</p>

<p>The Milwaukee gathering is largely designed in Trump's image, with digital banners beaming out a message in the cavernous convention arena: "Make America Great Once Again."</p>

<p>The branding reflects his takeover of the party.</p>

<p>A diminished figure after his 2020 election loss and a subsequent riot at the Capitol by his supporters, Trump has spent much of the last four years reshaping Republican politics.</p>

<p>Installing loyalists including his daughter-in-law Lara Trump atop the Republican National Committee, the billionaire has effectively crushed dissent.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-01/vmosbodk_donald-trump-reuters_625x300_15_January_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Republican Party on Monday formally confirmed Donald Trump as its nominee for November's elecction.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-announces-jd-vance-as-vice-president-pick-6113749]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Selects Republican Ohio Senator JD Vance As Vice President Candidate]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-announces-jd-vance-as-vice-president-pick-6113749]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:50:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump selected J.D. Vance, a Republican U.S. senator from Ohio, as his running mate on Monday, elevating a politician who once criticized the former president in acid terms but has since become one of his most stalwart defenders.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump selected J.D. Vance, a Republican U.S. senator from Ohio, as his running mate on Monday, elevating a politician who once criticized the former president in acid terms but has since become one of his most stalwart defenders.</p>

<p>The news, carried on Trump's Truth Social media website, emerged at the start of the four-day Republican National Convention in Milwaukee to nominate the party's presidential ticket.</p>

<p>The selection of James David Vance, author of the bestselling memoir "Hillbilly Elegy," could increase the odds of Trump supporters turning out for the Nov. 5 election as the Ohio native is deeply popular with the Republican candidate's base.</p>

<p>A staunch conservative from a Republican state, Vance is unlikely to bring many new voters into Trump's corner, however, and may even alienate some moderates. Some Trump supporters had pushed him to select a woman or person of color as his No. 2 to expand a coalition that skews toward white men.</p>

<p>The former president, 78, survived an assassination attempt at a Pennsylvania campaign rally on Saturday by a gunman whose motive remains unknown.</p>

<p>Several of Trump's highest-profile backers - including former senior adviser Steve Bannon and Trump's eldest son, Donald Trump Jr. - have praised Vance for pushing the Republican Party to embrace a more hands-off foreign policy approach and for supporting trade barriers.</p>

<p>Vance has also delighted Trump supporters with his confrontational social media presence, a relative rarity in the Senate, where many lawmakers still try to maintain a sense of decorum and civility.</p>

<p>At 39, Vance will represent a younger generation in an election that features Trump and President Joe Biden, 81, bringing a counterweight to the Democratic ticket that also includes Vice President Kamala Harris, 59.</p>

<p>In selecting Vance, Trump passed over other possible contenders such including U.S. Senators Marco Rubio and Tim Scott and North Dakota Governor Doug Burgum.</p>

<p>Vance's rapid ascent has been unusual for American politics. After a troubled and impoverished childhood in southern Ohio, he served in the Marine Corps, won a scholarship to Yale Law School and later worked as a venture capitalist in San Francisco.</p>

<p>He rose to prominence after 2016 when he wrote "Hillbilly Elegy," in which he explored the socioeconomic problems confronting his hometown and the cycle of poverty that had entrapped Americans in the Appalachian Mountains, where his mother and her family had their origins.</p>

<p>The book criticized what Vance saw as a self-destructive culture in rural America and sought to explain Trump's popularity among impoverished white Americans.</p>

<p>Vance himself was harshly critical of Trump before and after Trump's 2016 election win against Democratic presidential nominee Hillary Clinton, calling him an "idiot" and "America's Hitler," among other epithets.</p>

<p>But as Vance geared up to run for the U.S. Senate in Ohio in 2022, he transformed into one of the former president's most consistent defenders, supporting Trump even when some Senate colleagues declined to do so.</p>

<p>Vance has played down the Jan. 6, 2021, attack on the U.S. Capitol. He said he "doubted" Mike Pence's life was in danger, despite violent protesters getting within yards of the former vice president as Secret Service agents rushed him out of the Capitol building. Vance has also echoed Trump's criticisms of the way the Justice Department has prosecuted Jan. 6 rioters, accusing the department of disregarding due process protections.</p>

<p>In February, he declined to criticize Trump for encouraging Russian President Vladimir Putin to attack America's NATO allies if they failed to increase their defense spending.</p>

<p>While the Republican Party historically stood for free markets and embraced foreign intervention as an important national security tool, Trump's 2016 election opened up significant rifts within the party. Vance has been one of the most vocal opponents of continued aid to Ukraine in the Senate, a stance at odds with many Republican legislative leaders.</p>

<p>On the campaign trail, the former venture capitalist has also served as a bridge between Trump associates and wealthy Silicon Valley donors, many of whom have opened their wallets to Trump this election.</p>

<p>Still, Vance's selection has its detractors among Trump associates, notably those who had wanted Trump to select a diverse vice presidential candidate. Though Trump and Biden are virtually tied in most national polls, Trump trails the Democratic president by significant margins among women and Black Americans.</p>

<p>Some Trump associates privately questioned whether it would be wise to take Vance out of the Senate with Democrats and Republicans vying for control of the upper chamber. Democrats hold a one-seat advantage, though they are likely to lose ground in the November election.</p>

<p>Ohio, while safely Republican in presidential elections, does occasionally elect Democrats in other races. Vance won his 2022 election by six percentage points.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/tv9u9rfk_jd-vance_625x300_16_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump selected J.D. Vance, a Republican U.S. senator from Ohio, as his running mate.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>