<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Thu, 21 Nov 2024 11:00:35 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/golden-visa-inquiries-from-us-citizens-soar-after-trump-win-7069133]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Golden Visa Inquiries From US Citizens Soar After Trump Win]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/golden-visa-inquiries-from-us-citizens-soar-after-trump-win-7069133]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 21 Nov 2024 11:00:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Affluent Americans are exploring golden visa programmes that allow foreign citizenship or residency through substantial investments.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Affluent Americans are exploring golden visa programmes that allow foreign citizenship or residency through substantial investments. The reason? The imminent arrival of Donald Trump as the US President. Henley &amp; Partners, a pioneer in citizenship-by-investment, noted a 400 per cent spike in inquiries from US citizens during election week, <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/11/20/business/golden-visas-americans-trump-election/index.html" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">CNN</a> reported.</p>

<p>Dominic Volek, head of private clients at Henley &amp; Partners, described the trend as a strategy for “optionality.” He said it was similar to “an insurance policy,” with most applicants seeking backup plans rather than permanent relocation.</p>

<p>Arton Capital, another consultancy, observed a fivefold increase in inquiries the day after the election result. CEO Armand Arton remarked, “A very small percentage of these people are actually relocating, but they all want to have the option as a Plan B.”</p>

<p>For those seeking golden visas, European countries are the most popular destinations. Portugal's Golden Residence Permit Programme stands out for its affordability and quick path to EU citizenship. With a minimum investment of €250,000 in cultural heritage, applicants can secure residency and, after five years, apply for citizenship.</p>

<p>The ultra-wealthy often favour Malta and Austria. Malta offers immediate citizenship for a €600,000 non-refundable payment, with additional investments in real estate and charitable donations. Austria requires investments of at least €3.5 million, typically in local businesses, in exchange for citizenship.</p>

<p>Historically, golden visa programmes attracted individuals from politically unstable countries, but US demand surged during the pandemic as travel restrictions affected wealthy families, according to Mr Volek.&nbsp;</p>

<p>While the golden visa trend is driven by the wealthy, many ordinary Americans are also considering a move abroad. For many, the motivation is not luxury but safety. Flannery Foster, an American living in Spain, helps others navigate the process of moving overseas. “I've been talking to people (whose) lives are at risk,” she said, pointing to women, Black individuals, and families with LGBTQ+ members.</p>

<p>These individuals often want to keep their US citizenship. Ms Foster explained, “There is a sense that, ‘I'm leaving because I have to, and I want to make sure that my vote still counts.'”</p>

<p>Social media discussions about relocating have also gained momentum, especially among those unable to afford golden visas. A <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Kt21MfW8wfs&amp;t=51s" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">YouTube video</a> titled “Countries for Americans Who Want to Leave the US” has over half a million views, with many commenting on their plans to live abroad.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2016-04/us-visa-generic_650x400_81460792605.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[For those seeking golden visas, European countries are the most popular destinations.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/byjus-founder-byju-raveendran-accused-of-trying-to-regain-firm-with-hidden-cash-7069055]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Byju's Founder Accused Of Trying To Regain Firm With Hidden Cash]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/byjus-founder-byju-raveendran-accused-of-trying-to-regain-firm-with-hidden-cash-7069055]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 21 Nov 2024 10:14:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The founder of bankrupt Indian tech firm Byju's tried to use loan proceeds that he allegedly hid from US lenders to secretly buy back a software company that was taken over by an American trustee, according to a new court filing.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The founder of bankrupt Indian tech firm Byju's tried to use loan proceeds that he allegedly hid from US lenders to secretly buy back a software company that was taken over by an American trustee, according to a new court filing.</p>

<p>Byju Raveendran has been trying to regain control his capsizing education technology empire, which is under court supervision in both India, where the parent is based, and the US, where some of its valuable units are located, according to a court declaration filed by Nebraska businessman William R. Hailer.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Raveendran allegedly recruited Hailer, who is a former political consultant, to try to buy out US creditors owed more than $1.2 billion under a loan, according to the filing with the US Bankruptcy Court in Delaware. Raveendran could then swap that debt, which was trading at about 0.24 cents on the dollar as of Wednesday evening, for ownership of Epic!, a education-software firm. The plan ultimately failed.</p>

<p>"Over the last several months I have been used as a pawn in Byju's manipulation of the law," Hailer wrote in his testimony. Hailer is set to testify in federal court on Thursday on behalf of a trustee, which is planning to sell Epic! in order to raise money for Byju's creditors, including US lenders.&nbsp;</p>

<p>A representative of Byju's and a lawyer for Raveendran did not return requests for comment.</p>

<p>Raveendran has denied wrongdoing in past responses to lender allegations, saying his actions were a justified response to overly aggressive tactics used by creditors who specialize in squeezing money out of distressed companies.&nbsp;</p>

<p>This summer, when Hailer began negotiating with lenders, Raveendran wired $11.25 million to a company that Hailer ran called Rose Lake Inc. Hailer was supposed to use the cash to prove to lenders that he was well funded. The money was then to be returned to Raveendran, Hailer said.</p>

<p>The money came from OCI Ltd., a UK-incorporated logistics firm that received hundreds of millions of dollars in loan proceeds that US lenders have been trying to reclaim, according Hailer's court filing.</p>

<p>Hailer said he tried unsuccessfully to gather proof that OCI was still holding money on behalf of Byju's, even though Raveendran has claimed all the cash has been spent. For several months, Hailer said he regularly spoke with Raveendran and other Indian business people involved in the Byju's empire. Hailer also visited Raveendran's family compound in Dubai for talks with investors who were allegedly backing Raveendran's effort to regain control of Byju's.</p>

<p>Lenders have been fighting Byju's in both US state and federal courts for more than a year. Lenders claim Raveendran hid $533 million in loan proceeds that should have been repaid to creditors. In India, Byju's is facing an insolvency proceeding, where a court-appointed professional has been tasked with raising money to repay lenders.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The case is Epic! Creations, Inc., 24-11161, US Bankruptcy Court, District of Delaware (Wilmington).</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/v318gbtg_byju-raveendran-bloomberg_625x300_21_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Byju Raveendran has denied wrongdoing in past responses to lender allegations]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sophia-park-us-teen-makes-history-becomes-youngest-to-pass-california-bar-exam-7068867]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Teen Makes History, Becomes Youngest To Pass California Bar Exam]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sophia-park-us-teen-makes-history-becomes-youngest-to-pass-california-bar-exam-7068867]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 21 Nov 2024 10:01:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 17-year-old prodigy has created history by becoming the youngest person to pass the California State Bar Exam, making her a practising lawyer in the state.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 17-year-old prodigy has created history by becoming the youngest person to pass the California State Bar Exam, making her a practising lawyer in the state. Sophia Park's achievement eclipses the record previously held by her older brother, Peter Park, by three months.</p>

<p>On November 8, 2024, Ms Park learned she passed the bar exam taken by over 8,000 candidates in July. She was 17 years and 8 months old when she sat for the exam, leaving her brother of 17 years and 11 months behind. “I am very happy and excited,” she said in a family-uploaded YouTube video.</p>

<p><br />
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="315" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6ouUV0kizhI?si=7KDW7zIfLaBEJ-f4" title="YouTube video player" width="560"></iframe></p>

<p>According to a <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/11/19/us/california-bar-exam-sophia-park.html" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">New York Times</a> report, the California State Bar Exam is known for its rigorous standards, with just under 54 per cent&nbsp;of the candidates who attempted the exam in July clearing it.<br />
<br />
Ms Park's achievement was also announced by her employer, the Tulare County District Attorney's Office. “Sophia's amazing accomplishments speak for themselves, and we could not be prouder as an office family,” said Tulare County District Attorney Tim Ward.<br />
<br />
Sophia Park completed high school, college and law school in an accelerated timeline of roughly four years, through advanced online courses. Beginning law school at 13 in 2020, Ms Park juggled her studies alongside attending junior high at Oxford Academy in Cypress, California. By 2022, she completed high school, having cleared the California High School Proficiency Exam (CHSPE). In 2024, she earned her law degree from Northwestern California University School of Law.<br />
<br />
According to the NYT&nbsp;report, Ms Park, like her brother, utilised a provision in California law permitting students to enter law school by passing College-Level Proficiency Exams (CLEP), bypassing traditional undergraduate requirements.<br />
<br />
At 16, Ms Park gained practical experience through a summer internship with the Los Angeles County District Attorney's Office. Since 2024, she has worked as a law clerk for the Tulare County District Attorney's Office.<br />
<br />
Ms Park will start as a practising attorney in March 2025, when she turns 18 and is sworn in as a licenced lawyer. She plans to join the Tulare County District Attorney's Office as a prosecutor, following in her brother's footsteps.<br />
<br />
“As a prosecutor, I will work to see justice served and ensure that victims' voices are heard,” she said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/cfsmn2so_sophia-parks_625x300_21_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sophia Park learned she passed the bar exam taken by over 8,000 candidates in July.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/thai-woman-gets-death-sentence-after-poisoning-14-friends-with-cyanide-7068810]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Thai Woman Gets Death Sentence After Poisoning 14 Friends With Cyanide]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/thai-woman-gets-death-sentence-after-poisoning-14-friends-with-cyanide-7068810]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 21 Nov 2024 09:32:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Authorities have since linked Sararat to a series of cyanide poisonings dating back to 2015.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Thai woman, accused of being one of the country's most prolific serial killers, has been sentenced to death for poisoning a friend with cyanide. This is the first of 14 murder trials involving Sararat Rangsiwuthaporn, 36, whose alleged crimes have shocked the nation, according to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2024/nov/20/thai-woman-sentenced-to-death-in-first-of-14-trials" rel="noindex,nofollow"><em>The Guardian</em></a>.</p>

<p>Sararat, described as an online gambling addict, is accused of swindling large sums of money from her victims before killing them with cyanide. <em>Thai media</em> reports that she borrowed thousands of dollars from her victims and later killed them to fund her gambling habit.</p>

<p>On Wednesday, a court in Bangkok convicted Sararat for the murder of her friend, Siriporn Khanwong. The two met near Bangkok in April 2022 to participate in a Buddhist ritual of releasing fish into the Mae Klong River. Shortly after the ritual, Siriporn collapsed and died. Investigators later found traces of cyanide in her body.</p>

<p>Authorities have since linked Sararat to a series of cyanide poisonings dating back to 2015. "The court's decision is just," said Siriporn's mother, Tongpin Kiatchanasiri, following the verdict. "I want to tell my daughter that I miss her deeply and justice has been done for her today."</p>

<p>Police revealed that Sararat borrowed as much as 300,000 baht from some victims, stealing their jewellery and mobile phones after killing them. She reportedly lured 15 people, of whom only one survived, to consume poisoned "herb capsules."</p>

<p>Deputy National Police Chief Surachate Hakparn explained Sararat's motives: "She asked people she knows for money because she has a lot of credit card debt ... and if they asked her for their money back, she started killing them."</p>

<p>Sararat faces charges for 13 additional murders and has been accused of around 80 offences in total. Her ex-husband, a police lieutenant-colonel, was sentenced to 16 months in prison, while her former lawyer received a two-year sentence for complicity in Siriporn's murder.</p>

<p>Thailand has witnessed several high-profile poisoning cases in the past, but Sararat's alleged crimes stand out for their scale and severity.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/5jqv74c8_sararat-rangsiwuthaporn_625x300_21_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sararat faces charges for 13 additional murders]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/comedian-banana-taped-to-a-wall-sells-for-6-2-million-in-new-york-7068764]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Comedian", Banana Taped To A Wall, Sells For $6.2 Million In New York]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/comedian-banana-taped-to-a-wall-sells-for-6-2-million-in-new-york-7068764]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 21 Nov 2024 09:24:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A fresh banana taped to a wall -- a provocative work of conceptual art by Italian artist Maurizio Cattelan -- was bought for $6.2 million on Wednesday by a cryptocurrency entrepreneur at a New York auction.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A fresh banana taped to a wall -- a provocative work of conceptual art by Italian artist Maurizio Cattelan -- was bought for $6.2 million on Wednesday by a cryptocurrency entrepreneur at a New York auction, Sotheby's announced in a statement.</p>

<p>The debut of the edible creation entitled "Comedian" at the Art Basel show in Miami Beach in 2019 sparked controversy and raised questions about whether it should be considered art -- Cattelan's stated aim.</p>

<p>Chinese-born crypto founder Justin Sun on Wednesday forked over more than six million for the fruit and its single strip of silver duct tape, which went on sale for 120,000 dollars five years ago.</p>

<p>"This is not just an artwork. It represents a cultural phenomenon that bridges the worlds of art, memes, and the cryptocurrency community," Sun was quoted as saying in the Sotheby's statement.</p>

<p>"I believe this piece will inspire more thought and discussion in the future and will become a part of history."</p>

<p>The sale featured seven potential buyers and smashed expectations, with the auction house issuing a guide price of $1-1.5 million before the bidding.</p>

<p>Given the shelf life of a banana, Sun is essentially buying a certificate of authenticity that the work was created by Cattelan as well as instructions about how to replace the fruit when it goes bad.</p>

<p>The installation auctioned on Wednesday was the third iteration -- with the first one eaten by performance artist David Datuna, who said he felt "hungry" while inspecting it at the Miami show.</p>

<p>Sun, who founded cryptomoney exahange Tron, said that he intended to eat his investment too.</p>

<p>"In the coming days, I will personally eat the banana as part of this unique artistic experience, honoring its place in both art history and popular culture," he said.</p>

<p>As well as his banana work, Cattelan is also known for producing an 18-carat, fully functioning gold toilet called "America" that he once offered on loan to Donald Trump during his first term in the White House.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/vgul12co_fresh-banana-taped-to-a-wall_625x300_21_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Italian visual artist Maurizio Cattelan's duct-taped Banana entitled Comedian.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/volcano-erupts-in-iceland-seventh-time-in-a-year-7068668]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Video: Red Lava Pours Out As Volcano Erupts 7th Time In A Year In Iceland]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/volcano-erupts-in-iceland-seventh-time-in-a-year-7068668]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 21 Nov 2024 09:04:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A volcano erupted late Wednesday on the Reykjanes Peninsula in southwest Iceland, the national weather service said, the seventh since last December.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A fishing village and tourist hot spot in southwest Iceland was evacuated late Wednesday after a volcano erupted in the region for the seventh time in a year, officials said.</p>

<p>The Icelandic Meteorological Office (IMO) reported an eruption of the Sundhnukagigar volcanic fissure outside the village of Grindavik on the Reykjanes Peninsula at 2314 GMT.</p>

<p>IMO specialist Benedikt Ofeigsson told public radio RAS2 that no infrastructure was currently threatened, but Grindavik -- a small fishing town known for its nearby Blue Lagoon hot spa -- was evacuated.</p>

<p>Volcanoes on the peninsula had not erupted for eight centuries until March 2021 when a period of heightened seismic activity began.</p>

<p>Images broadcast live showed red-orange lava gushing from a long fissure surrounded by thick smoke.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">?⚠️???A new <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/eruption?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#eruption</a> has just started in <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/iceland?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#iceland</a> at about 11PM local time with intense tremors on the ground, near <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/grindavik?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#grindavik</a> again.<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/volcano?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#volcano</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/reykijanes?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#reykijanes</a> <a href="https://t.co/RAsqsxNgWX">pic.twitter.com/RAsqsxNgWX</a></p>
— SatWorld (@or_bit_eye) <a href="https://twitter.com/or_bit_eye/status/1859391978557014116?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 21, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>The latest eruption is smaller than the last one, at the end of August, the IMO said in a statement.</p>

<p>"The outpourings are lower and the lava is not flowing as fast," added Ofeigsson.</p>

<p>Most of Grindavik's 4,000 residents were evacuated a year ago, shortly before the first volcanic eruption in the area.</p>

<p>Since then, almost all the houses have been sold to the state, and the residents departed.</p>

<p>"About fifty houses were occupied in recent nights," said the civil protection department.</p>

<p>In January, during another eruption, three houses in the village were engulfed by flames.</p>

<p>Volcanologists warned that volcanic activity in the region had entered a new era.</p>

<p>Iceland is home to 33 active volcanic systems, more than any other European country.</p>

<p>It is located on the Mid-Atlantic Ridge, a fault in the ocean floor that separates the Eurasian and North American tectonic plates and causes earthquakes and eruptions.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ffb37g5o_volcano-iceland_625x300_21_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Volcanic eruption took place at the Sundhnuksgigar volcanic fissure, outside Grindavik town.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bitcoin-hits-new-record-crosses-95-000-7068626]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bitcoin Hits New Record, Crosses $95,000]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bitcoin-hits-new-record-crosses-95-000-7068626]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 21 Nov 2024 08:55:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Bitcoin reached $95,004.50 in early Asian trade, with observers expecting it to soon reach $100,000.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bitcoin hit a record Thursday, topping $95,000 for the first time as it benefits from expectations that president-elect Donald Trump will push through measures to ease regulation of the unit.</p>

<p>The digital currency reached $95,004.50 in early Asian trade, with observers expecting it to soon reach $100,000.</p>

<p>Traders have been piling into the unit since Trump was elected at the start of the month, pushing it up almost 40 percent since the vote.</p>

<p>The tycoon pledged on the campaign trail to make the United States the "bitcoin and cryptocurrency capital of the world," and to put tech billionaire and right-wing conspiracy theorist Elon Musk in charge of a wide-ranging audit of governmental waste.</p>

<p>Stephen Innes at SPI Asset Management said the surge has been "driven by mounting confidence that President-elect Donald Trump's administration will usher in a crypto-friendly era. Speculators rally behind the narrative, fueling a frenzy as the digital asset edges toward an unprecedented valuation".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/78nudmn_bitcoin_625x300_06_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Bitcoin hit a record Thursday, topping $95,000 for the first time.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/google-ceo-sundar-pichai-dials-donald-trump-elon-musk-joins-the-call-7068432]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Google CEO Sundar Pichai Dials Donald Trump, Elon Musk Joins The Call]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/google-ceo-sundar-pichai-dials-donald-trump-elon-musk-joins-the-call-7068432]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 21 Nov 2024 08:06:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[When Google CEO Sundar Pichai dialed US-President elect Donald Trump, Elon Musk joined the call, according to a report.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Elon Musk has been a near-constant presence on the side of US President-elect Donald Trump. It was proven again when Google CEO Sundar Pichai dialed Trump and Musk joined the call, reported <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/musk-joined-call-between-trump-google-ceo" rel="nofollow,noindex">The Information</a>. Mr Pichai called Trump to congratulate him on his victory over Kamala Harris in the recently concluded US Presidential Election.</p>

<p>In the past, Musk has alleged biases in Google's search results, suggesting that upon searching for Trump, news related to Harris surfaced.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="qst">Wow <a href="https://t.co/9utMxHQCog">https://t.co/9utMxHQCog</a></p>
— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1817998077774483823?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 29, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>The Tesla and SpaceX CEO Musk has previously joined telephone calls with world leaders and dispensed advice on personnel choices.</p>

<p>It is because of his close ties with the President-elect, Musk is called the “<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-earns-key-position-in-donald-trumps-world-first-buddy-7016337">First Buddy</a>”.</p>

<p>Both have been spotted together at various events including the launch of the SpaceX Starship rocket and the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/feature/im-watching-myself-watch-this-elon-musk-reacts-to-his-viral-lol-moment-7047892">Ultimate Fighting Championship (UFC) heavyweight bout</a> on November 16.</p>

<p>Under Trump's cabinet, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-to-lead-us-government-efficiency-department-donald-trump-7006239">Musk will lead the 'Department of Government Efficiency'</a> - a position Trump hinted at during his campaign trail. Musk will head the department alongside Indian-American entrepreneur Vivek Ramaswamy. “Together, these two wonderful Americans will pave the way for my Administration to dismantle Government Bureaucracy, slash excess regulations, cut wasteful expenditures, and restructure Federal Agencies - Essential to the 'Save America' Movement,” Trump said in a statement.</p>

<p>Musk even found a mention in <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-election-results-live-thats-why-i-love-you-big-elon-musk-mention-in-donald-trumps-victory-speech-6955600">Trump's victory speech and was described as “an amazing guy”</a>.</p>

<p>“We have a new star, a star is born: Elon,” Trump told his supporters. “He's an amazing guy. We were sitting together tonight. You know, he spent two weeks in Philadelphia, in different parts of Pennsylvania, campaigning.”</p>

<p>The duo spent the election night at Trump's Florida estate, Mar-a-Lago, keeping a close watch on the results and Trump's return to the Oval Office after a four-year gap.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/77simq78_trump-musk-sundar-pichai_625x300_21_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Elon Musk has been a near-constant presence on the side of US President-elect Donald Trump.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/30-million-fine-for-flouting-australias-social-media-ban-for-under-16-7068425]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[$30 Million Fine For Flouting Australia's Social Media Ban For Under 16]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/30-million-fine-for-flouting-australias-social-media-ban-for-under-16-7068425]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 21 Nov 2024 08:01:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Social media companies could be fined more than US$30 million if they fail to keep children off their platforms, under new laws tabled before Australia's parliament Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Social media companies could be fined more than US$30 million if they fail to keep children off their platforms, under new laws tabled before Australia's parliament Thursday.</p>

<p>The legislation would force social media firms to take steps to prevent those under 16 years of age from accessing platforms such as X, TikTok, Facebook and Instagram.</p>

<p>Failing to do so would mean fines of up to Aus$50 million (US$32.5 million).</p>

<p>Australia is among the vanguard of nations trying to clean up social media, and the proposed age limit would be among the world's strictest measures aimed at children.</p>

<p>Details about how social media companies are expected to enforce the ban remain unclear.</p>

<p><strong>READ:&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/analysis-should-india-ban-social-media-for-under-16s-like-australia-7019678">Analysis: Should India Ban Social Media For Under-16s, Like Australia?</a></p>

<p>The proposed laws would also include robust privacy provisions that require tech platforms to delete any age-verification information collected.</p>

<p>Minister for Communications Michelle Rowland said Thursday that social media companies had a responsibility for the "safety and mental health" of Australians.</p>

<p>"The legislation places the onus on social media platforms, not parents or children, to ensure protections are in place," she said.</p>

<p>Some companies will be granted exemptions from the ban, such as YouTube, which teenagers may need to use for school work or other reasons.</p>

<p>Rowland said that messaging services -- such as WhatsApp -- and online gaming would also be exempt.</p>

<p>Once celebrated as a means of staying connected and informed, social media platforms have been tarnished by cyberbullying, the spread of illegal content, and election-meddling claims.</p>

<p>If the proposed law passes, tech platforms would be given a one-year grace period to figure out how to implement and enforce the ban.</p>

<p>Social media companies have said they will adhere to new legislation but have cautioned the government against acting too quickly and without adequate consultation.</p>

<p>Analysts have also expressed doubt it would be technically feasible to enforce a strict age ban.</p>

<p>Katie Maskiell from UNICEF Australia said Thursday the proposed legislation would not be a "solve-all" for protecting children and much more needed to be done.</p>

<p>She added the laws risked pushing young people onto "covert and unregulated online spaces".</p>

<p>Several other countries have been tightening children's access to social media platforms.</p>

<p>Spain passed a law in June banning social media access to under-16s.</p>

<p>And in the US state of Florida, children under 14 will be banned from opening social media accounts under a new law due to come into force in January.</p>

<p>In both cases, the age verification method has yet to be determined.</p>

<p><strong>READ:&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/can-social-media-ban-for-children-like-australias-work-evidence-suggests-6556305">Can Social Media Ban For Children Like Australia's Work? Evidence Suggests</a></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/6dlk0k38_social-media-banned-for-kids-in-australia_625x300_07_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Social media firms to prevent those under 16 from accessing platforms like X, TikTok, FB and IG.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/smear-campaign-india-slams-canada-media-report-on-nijjar-murder-plot-7068353]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India Slams Canada Report On Nijjar Murder Plot, Calls It "Ludicrous"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/smear-campaign-india-slams-canada-media-report-on-nijjar-murder-plot-7068353]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 21 Nov 2024 07:41:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[External Affairs Ministry spokesperson Randhir Jaiswal said a Canadian report claiming Prime Minister Narendra Modi was aware of the plot to kill Sikh separatist Hardeep Singh Nijjar was a "smear campaign".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Amid continuously deteriorating ties, External Affairs Ministry spokesperson Randhir Jaiswal said a Canadian report claiming Prime Minister Narendra Modi was aware of the plot to kill Sikh separatist Hardeep Singh Nijjar was a "smear campaign".</p>

<p>Canada's Globe and Mail newspaper report quoted unnamed Canadian officials to say Mr Modi was aware of plot to kill the Khalistani activist. The report claimed the Indian national security advisor and the external affairs minister were also in the loop of the plot.</p>

<p>In response, Mr Jaiswal said, "Such ludicrous statements made to a newspaper purportedly by a Canadian government source should be dismissed with the contempt they deserve. Smear campaigns like this only further damage our already strained ties."</p>

<p>Khalistani terrorist and Canadian citizen Hardeep Singh Nijjar was killed in Vancouver in June last year, kickstarting a diplomatic crisis after Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau accused "agents" of Delhi of being involved. He claimed "credible information" had been shared with intelligence partners, including the US.</p>

<p>Last month, Canada linked Indian High Commissioner Sanjay Verma and some other diplomats to the murder. The Canadian government had said the Indian diplomats were expelled from the country. In a tit-for-tat move, New Delhi expelled Canadian Charge d'Affaires Stewart Wheeler and five other diplomats.</p>

<p>"I think it is obvious the Government of India made a fundamental error in thinking they could engage in supporting criminal activity against Canadians, here on Canadian soil. Whether it be murders or extortion or other violent acts, it is absolutely unacceptable," Mr Trudeau said.</p>

<p>Nijjar - the mastermind behind banned terror outfit Khalistan Tiger Force - was on Delhi's list of 'most wanted' terrorists for multiple crimes, including the murder of Hindu priest in Punjab. Anti-terror agency NIA had offered a Rs 10 lakh reward for information leading to his capture.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/a6mni2rg_india-canada_625x300_21_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Last month, India and Canada expelled diplomats in tit-for-tat moves.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/migrants-depart-from-mexico-hoping-to-reach-us-before-trump-takes-office-7067953]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Migrants Depart From Mexico Hoping To Reach US Before Trump Takes Office]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/migrants-depart-from-mexico-hoping-to-reach-us-before-trump-takes-office-7067953]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 21 Nov 2024 05:31:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hundreds of migrants left the Mexican city of Tapachula on foot Wednesday, aiming to arrive at the US border before President-elect Donald Trump -- who has vowed massive deportations -- takes office in January.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hundreds of migrants left the Mexican city of Tapachula on foot Wednesday, aiming to arrive at the US border before President-elect Donald Trump -- who has vowed massive deportations -- takes office in January.</p>

<p>The group of about 1,500 people set out from Tapachula in southern Mexico in the early morning hours for a walk of some 2,600 kilometers (over 1,600 miles).</p>

<p>"My mentality is to get there, I want my (asylum) appointment before he (Trump) takes power," Colombian Yamel Enriquez told AFP.</p>

<p>"If I don't get the appointment before, I will give myself over to whatever God wants."</p>

<p>Venezuelan Zuleika Carreno joined the exodus with the same single-minded purpose.</p>

<p>She said she decided not to postpone her departure "for fear of getting stuck on this side" of the border, which would mean her laborious travels so far would have been "in vain."</p>

<p>Trump, who won an election in which illegal migration was a top issue, has vowed to declare a national emergency on border security and use the US military to carry out a mass deportation of undocumented migrants.</p>

<p>Authorities estimate that some 11 million people are living in the United States illegally, and Trump has stoked concerns by claiming an "invasion" is underway by migrants he says will rape and murder Americans.</p>

<p>On Wednesday, Mexican President Claudia Sheinbaum said her government was preparing a document highlighting the contribution of workers from her country to the US economy.</p>

<p>Migrants who amass in Mexico from a variety of troubled countries with a view to a better life in the United States frequently organize group movements known as "caravans" in a bid to pressure authorities into giving them temporary Mexican visas.</p>

<p>Sticking together also reduces the risk of criminal attacks, but the migrants groups usually disperse along the way.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2018-09/n2rnmlf8_us-immigration-generic_625x300_22_September_18.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Authorities estimate that some 11 million people are living in the US illegally. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/lempire-des-lumieres-at-121-million-rare-rene-magritte-painting-sets-world-record-for-surreal-work-of-art-7067870]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[At $121 Million, Rare Painting Sets "World Record" For Surreal Work Of Art]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/lempire-des-lumieres-at-121-million-rare-rene-magritte-painting-sets-world-record-for-surreal-work-of-art-7067870]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 21 Nov 2024 05:02:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A painting by the 'Master of Surrealism' Rene Magritte has smashed the auction record for any of his works by selling for an astonishing $121 million at a Christie's auction in New York on Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A painting by the 'Master of Surrealism' Rene Magritte has smashed the auction record for any of his works by selling for an astonishing $121 million at a Christie's auction in New York on Tuesday.</p>

<p>The piece of art, titled 'L'empire des lumieres' or 'The Empire of Light' brilliantly juxtaposes night and day. While Magritte depicts the skies above as a bright, sunny, spring-summer day, he paints a grim, damp, suspenseful, almost-eerie streetscape covered in inscrutable darkness and shadow; with a solitary street lamp lighting up the side facade of what seems like a traditional English manor and its reflection in a puddle of water left after a recent drizzle.</p>

<p>The longer and closer one looks at the painting, the more one gets drawn to its surreal nature - the artist's intricate play with lighting and the mysterious darkness that envelops the manor.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Photo Credit: christies.com" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/2hldndok_rene-magritte-painting-lempire-des-lumieres_625x300_21_November_24.jpg" title="Photo Credit: christies.com" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><small><em>Photo Credit: christies.com</em></small></p>
</div>

<p>The auction house - Christie's - called the artwork the "crown jewel" of its previous owner - late American interior designer Mica Ertegun. It also said that the 1954 oil-on-canvas painting sold for $121,160,000 - "setting a new world record for the artist and for a Surrealist work of art at any auction".</p>

<p>The piece of art - one of the largest paintings among 27 works, all titled 'L'empire des lumieres' - is renowned among 20th century art experts for its scale, condition and subtle details. The auction house said that the winning bid far exceeded the painting's $95 million estimate.</p>

<p>Some of the other paintings auctioned included two other works by Magritte "La cour d'amour" and "La Memoire," which sold for $10.53 million and $3.68 million, respectively. The auction also featured artworks by renowned artists Ed Ruscha and Max Ernst. Another sizeable bid - over $19 million - was made for the painting 'A Still Life' by 87-year-old British artist David Hockney.</p>

<p>According to Christie's, Rene Magritte (1898-1967) explored nocturnal landscapes bathed in daylight across 17 unique paintings throughout his career. The 1954 example from Mrs. Ertegun's collection reflects the artist's technical mastery and penchant for making the familiar uncanny. It is considered Magritte's finest work from the series and the first time he introduced a body of water into the mysterious street scene.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/3jea0m7k_christies-auction-house-rene-magritte-painting-auction_625x300_21_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Renowned artist and 'Master of Surrealism' Rene Magritte's L'empire des Lumieres auctioned]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-administration-moves-to-forgive-4-7-billion-in-us-loans-to-ukraine-7067784]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden Administration Moves To Forgive $4.7 Billion In US Loans To Ukraine]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-administration-moves-to-forgive-4-7-billion-in-us-loans-to-ukraine-7067784]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 21 Nov 2024 04:34:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Biden administration has moved to forgive about $4.7 billion in US loans to Ukraine, State Department spokesperson Matthew Miller said on Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Biden administration has moved to forgive about $4.7 billion in US loans to Ukraine, State Department spokesperson Matthew Miller said on Wednesday, as outgoing officials seek to do what they can before leaving office to bolster Ukraine in its war against Russia.</p>

<p>A funding bill passed by the US Congress in April included just over $9.4 billion of forgivable loans for economic and budgetary support to Ukraine's government, half of which the president could cancel after November 15. The bill appropriated a total of $61 billion to help Ukraine fight the full-scale invasion Moscow launched in February 2022.</p>

<p>"We have taken the step that was outlined in the law to cancel those loans," Miller told a press briefing, adding that the step was taken in recent days.</p>

<p>Congress could still block the move, Miller said.</p>

<p>The Senate is due to vote later on Wednesday on a motion of disapproval of loan forgiveness for Ukraine put forward by Republican Senator Rand Paul, a frequent critic of US support for Ukraine. The majority of senators from both parties support aid to Ukraine.</p>

<p>President Joe Biden has ordered officials to rush as much aid to Ukraine as possible before he leaves office on Jan. 20 amid concerns President-elect Donald Trump could limit US support.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-12/tjjj9r4s_biden-zelensky_625x300_13_December_23.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Joe Biden has ordered officials to rush as much aid to Ukraine as possible before he leaves office.(File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-parliament-approves-labour-partys-bill-to-renationalise-rail-services-7067726]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK Parliament Approves Bill To Renationalise Rail Services]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-parliament-approves-labour-partys-bill-to-renationalise-rail-services-7067726]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 21 Nov 2024 04:13:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Legislation put forward by the UK's new Labour government to renationalise the country's rail services, most of which are privately owned, was on Wednesday given the go-ahead by parliament.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Legislation put forward by the UK's new Labour government to renationalise the country's rail services, most of which are privately owned, was on Wednesday given the go-ahead by parliament.</p>

<p>The bill will bring rail operators into public ownership when the private companies' contracts expire -- or sooner in the event of poor management -- and will be managed by "Great British Railways".</p>

<p>The TSSA rail union hailed the law as a "landmark" after an attempt by the opposition Conservatives to amend the legislation was defeated in the House of Lords, the upper house of parliament, by 213 votes to 210.</p>

<p>"This really is a landmark moment paving the way for our railways to return to public hands, where they belong, as a vital service," said TSSA General Secretary Maryam Eslamdoust.</p>

<p>Labour triumphed over the Conservative party in elections on July 4, re-entering Downing Street after 14 years in opposition with promises to fix the country's ailing transport services.</p>

<p>The government has said it will be able to avoid having to pay compensation fees to rail operators, with all the current contracts set to expire by 2027.</p>

<p>The privatisation of rail operations took place in the mid-1990s under the Conservative prime minister John Major, but the rail network remained public, run by Network Rail.</p>

<p>Four of 14 operators in England have been taken over by the state in recent years because of poor performance, but this was meant to be a temporary fix before a return to the private sector.</p>

<p>The main rail operators in Scotland and Wales, where transport policy is handled by the devolved administrations in Edinburgh and Cardiff, are also state-owned.</p>

<p>British railways have faced a constant stream of strikes over pay and conditions in the last few years due to a cost-of-living crisis.</p>

<p>Train cancellations are commonplace and passengers regularly complain about high ticket prices.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2017-07/uk-train-station-reuters_650x400_81500915566.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Passengers regularly complain about high ticket prices. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/xi-jinping-calls-for-peace-in-ukraine-ceasefire-in-gaza-during-brazil-visit-7067467]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Xi Jinping Calls For Peace In Ukraine, Ceasefire In Gaza During Brazil Visit]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/xi-jinping-calls-for-peace-in-ukraine-ceasefire-in-gaza-during-brazil-visit-7067467]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 21 Nov 2024 02:40:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Chinese leader Xi Jinping urged "more voices" to end the Ukraine war and a ceasefire in Gaza, as he conducted a state visit to Brazil's capital, Chinese state media said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Chinese leader Xi Jinping urged "more voices" to end the Ukraine war and a ceasefire in Gaza, as he conducted a state visit to Brazil's capital, Chinese state media said.</p>

<p>Brazilian President Luiz Inacio Lula da Silva echoed those points as he met with Xi in a red-carpet welcome in Brasilia, and stressed a joint roadmap for peace in Ukraine that they are proposing.</p>

<p>"In a world plagued by armed conflicts and political strife, China and Brazil put peace, diplomacy and dialogue first," Lula said.</p>

<p>Xi said he wanted to see "more voices committed to peace to pave the way for a political solution to the Ukraine crisis," the Chinese state news agency Xinhua reported.</p>

<p>He also called for "a ceasefire and an end to the war at an early date" in Gaza, the agency said.</p>

<p>On Ukraine, the China-Brazil roadmap for mediating peace has been endorsed by Russia -- which is China's ally -- but rejected by Kyiv and its Western backers.</p>

<p>The Chinese president's appeal for a halt to fighting in Gaza -- where Israel is pressing an offensive against Hamas -- echoed one he and the other G20 leaders made during a summit held Monday and Tuesday in Rio.</p>

<p>That summit's joint statement called for a "comprehensive" ceasefire in both Gaza and Lebanon, where Israel is also waging an offensive against the Iran-backed Hezbollah group.</p>

<p>On Wednesday, the UN Security Council held a vote on a resolution calling for "an immediate, unconditional and permanent ceasefire" in Gaza, but it was vetoed by Israel's ally the United States.</p>

<p><strong>China filling 'vacuum'</strong></p>

<p>Xi's state visit to Brasilia showcased closer relations between the biggest economies in Asia and Latin America, which analysts said also reflected shrinking US influence.</p>

<p>The two leaders signed 35 cooperation accords on areas including agriculture, trade, technology and environmental protection.</p>

<p>Xi said China-Brazil relations "are at their best in history" and the two countries are now "reliable friends," according to Xinhua.</p>

<p>Lula said he believed the growing Brazil-China ties "will exceed all expectations and pave the way for a new phase of bilateral relations."</p>

<p>He added that he looked forward to welcoming Xi to Brazil again next July for a BRICS summit.</p>

<p>The Chinese leader figured prominently at the G20 summit, and at an APEC one held last week in Peru -- in contrast with outgoing US President Joe Biden, who cut a spectral figure.</p>

<p>Fellow leaders looked past Biden, politically, to the coming US presidency of Donald Trump, which starts January 20.</p>

<p>"Xi Jinping is clearly looking to fill the vacuum that will come following the election of Trump, who does not value multilateralism," Oliver Stuenkel, an international relations expert at Brazil's Getulio Vargas Foundation think tank, told AFP.</p>

<p><strong>'Synergies'&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p>China is Brazil's biggest trading partner, with two-way commerce exceeding $160 billion last year.</p>

<p>The South American agricultural power sends mainly soybeans and other primary commodities to China, while the Asian giant sells Brazil semiconductors, telephones, vehicles and medicines.</p>

<p>Since returning to power in early 2023, Lula has sought to balance efforts to improve ties with both China and the United States.</p>

<p>A visit to Beijing this year by Vice President Geraldo Alckmin was seen as paving the way for Brazil to potentially join China's Belt and Road Initiative to stimulate trade -- a central pillar of Xi's bid to expand China's clout overseas.</p>

<p>But there was no announcement in that direction during Xi's visit. Instead both leaders spoke of finding "synergies" between that Chinese program and Brazil's own infrastructure development program.</p>

<p>South American nations that have signed up to Beijing's initiative include Argentina, Chile, Bolivia, Ecuador, Peru, and Venezuela.</p>

<p>One of the accords signed Wednesday was on Brazil opening its market to a Chinese satellite company, SpaceSail, that competes with Starlink, founded and run by South African-born US billionaire Elon Musk, which already covers remote Brazilian regions.</p>

<p>Musk has a turbulent history with Brazil, whose courts forced his social media platform X to comply with national laws against disinformation.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/00gpup8_xi-jinping-g20_625x300_21_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[That summit's joint statement called for a "comprehensive" ceasefire in both Gaza and Lebanon. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-vivek-ramaswamy-plan-to-slash-us-federal-spending-and-regulation-7067416]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk, Vivek Ramaswamy Plan To Slash US Federal Spending And Regulation]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-vivek-ramaswamy-plan-to-slash-us-federal-spending-and-regulation-7067416]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 21 Nov 2024 02:28:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Elon Musk outlined plans Wednesday for his new role as "efficiency" czar -- signaling an assault on federal spending and staffing that would be backed by President-elect Donald Trump's executive powers and a conservative Supreme Court.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Elon Musk outlined plans Wednesday for his new role as "efficiency" czar -- signaling an assault on federal spending and staffing that would be backed by President-elect Donald Trump's executive powers and a conservative Supreme Court.</p>

<p>In the Wall Street Journal, the world's richest man said he was taking aim at hundreds of billions of dollars in government spending -- including funding for public broadcasting and abortion rights group Planned Parenthood -- as well as at bureaucracy that represents an "existential threat" to US democracy.</p>

<p>The Tesla and SpaceX CEO said that he, along with fellow businessman and Trump loyalist Vivek Ramaswamy, would work to slash federal regulations and make major administrative cuts and cost savings.</p>

<p>"We are entrepreneurs, not politicians. We will serve as outside volunteers, not federal officials or employees," Musk and Ramaswamy wrote in their most detailed remarks since Trump named them heads of a new Department of Government Efficiency.</p>

<p>Musk said DOGE -- a nod to Musk's support for a cryptocurrency -- will prepare a list of regulations issued by government agencies without Congress approval, which Trump could then invalidate by executive order.</p>

<p>"When the president nullifies thousands of such regulations, critics will allege executive overreach. In fact, it will be correcting the executive overreach of thousands of regulations enacted by administrative fiat that were never authorized by Congress," Musk said.</p>

<p>He added that a reduction in regulations would pave the way for "mass head-count reductions across the federal bureaucracy," and said DOGE would aim to cut more than $500 billion in government expenditures.</p>

<p>"With a decisive electoral mandate and a 6-3 conservative majority on the Supreme Court, DOGE has a historic opportunity for structural reductions in the federal government," Musk said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/hsb5uvqo_trump-elon-musk_625x300_19_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Musk said DOGE will prepare a list of regulations issued by government agencies. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-says-no-hostage-for-prisoner-swap-with-israel-unless-gaza-war-ends-7067381]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hamas Says No Hostage-For-Prisoner Swap With Israel Unless Gaza War Ends]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-says-no-hostage-for-prisoner-swap-with-israel-unless-gaza-war-ends-7067381]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 21 Nov 2024 02:15:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hamas' acting Gaza chief Khalil al-Hayya said in an interview with Al-Aqsa TV released on Wednesday that there would be no hostages-for-prisoners swap deal with Israel unless the war in the Palestinian enclave ended.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hamas' acting Gaza chief Khalil al-Hayya said in an interview with Al-Aqsa TV released on Wednesday that there would be no hostages-for-prisoners swap deal with Israel unless the war in the Palestinian enclave ended.</p>

<p>"Without an end to the war, there can be no prisoner swap," Hayya said in a televised interview with the group's Al-Aqsa television channel, reiterating the group's position on how to bring the war to an end.</p>

<p>"If the aggression is not ended, why would the resistance and in particular Hamas, return the prisoners (hostages)?" he said. "How would a sane or an insane person lose a strong card he owns while the war is continuing?"</p>

<p>Hayya, who led the group's negotiating team in talks with Qatari and Egyptian mediators, blamed the lack of progress on Israel's Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu, who in turn holds the Islamist group responsible for the stalled talks.</p>

<p>"There are contacts under way with some countries and mediators to revive this file (negotiation). We are ready to continue with those efforts but it is more important to see a real will on the side of the occupation to end the aggression," said Hayya.</p>

<p>"The reality proves that Netanyahu is the one who undermines it (negotiations)," he added.</p>

<p>Speaking during a visit to Gaza on Tuesday, Netanyahu said that Hamas would not rule the Palestinian enclave after the war had ended and that Israel had destroyed the Islamist group's military capabilities.</p>

<p>Netanyahu also said Israel had not given up trying to locate the 101 remaining hostages believed to be still in the enclave, and he offered a $5 million reward for the return of each one.</p>

<p>Hamas wants a deal that ends the war and sees the release of Israeli and foreign hostages held captive in Gaza as well as Palestinians jailed by Israel, while Netanyahu vowed the war can only end once Hamas is eradicated.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/m9qq4ic8_hamas_625x300_21_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hamas seeks a deal ending the war and the release of Israeli and foreign hostages in Gaza. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-slams-canadian-report-on-nijjar-murder-plot-calls-it-smear-campaign-7067116]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India Slams Canadian Report On Nijjar Murder Plot, Calls It "Smear Campaign"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-slams-canadian-report-on-nijjar-murder-plot-calls-it-smear-campaign-7067116]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 21 Nov 2024 00:59:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India on Wednesday strongly trashed as "smear campaign" a Canadian media report that claimed that the Indian prime minister was aware of the alleged plot to kill Sikh separatist Hardeep Singh Nijjar.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India on Wednesday strongly trashed as "smear campaign" a Canadian media report that claimed that the Indian prime minister was aware of the alleged plot to kill Sikh separatist Hardeep Singh Nijjar.</p>

<p>Referring to the report quoting an unnamed official, External Affairs Ministry spokesperson Randhir Jaiswal said such "ludicrous statements" should be dismissed with the contempt they deserve.</p>

<p>"We do not normally comment on media reports. However, such ludicrous statements made to a newspaper purportedly by a Canadian government source should be dismissed with the contempt they deserve," he said.</p>

<p>"Smear campaigns like this only further damage our already strained ties," he said.</p>

<p>Jaiswal was responding to media queries regarding the report in Canadian newspaper The Globe and Mail.</p>

<p>In the report, the newspaper cited inputs from a senior national security official.</p>

<p>The report claimed the Indian national security advisor and the external affairs minister were also in the loop of the plot.</p>

<p>Nijjar was gunned down on Canadian soil last year.</p>

<p>India-Canada ties nosedived last month after Canada linked Indian High Commissioner Sanjay Verma and some other diplomats to the murder.</p>

<p>India has strongly rejected all the allegations made by Ottawa in connection to the case and subsequently recalled the high commissioner. The Canadian government had said the Indian diplomats were expelled from the country.</p>

<p>New Delhi expelled Canadian Charge d'Affaires Stewart Wheeler and five other diplomats following Canada's allegations.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-09/122o7v0g_modi-trudeau-afp_625x300_23_September_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[India has strongly rejected all the allegations made by Ottawa in connection to the case. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/as-automaker-jaguar-rebrands-itself-with-new-logo-netizens-unimpressed-7067019]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[As Automaker Jaguar Rebrands Itself With New Logo, Netizens Unimpressed]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/as-automaker-jaguar-rebrands-itself-with-new-logo-netizens-unimpressed-7067019]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 21 Nov 2024 00:23:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prior to its relaunch as an electric-only brand, luxury car manufacturer Jaguar announced its 'new era ' by unveiling its new logo and branding.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prior to its relaunch as an electric-only brand, luxury car manufacturer Jaguar announced its 'new era ' by unveiling its new logo and branding. The Tata Motors-owned British vehicle maker on Tuesday revealed a new bespoke logo, written as JaGUar, alongside a new prancing "leaper" cat design and marketing slogans like ‘delete ordinary', ‘live vivid' and ‘copy nothing'.</p>

<p>The new logo emphasized the brand's posh English pronunciation “Jag-you-are" instead of the American “Jag-wahr." The company said the new branding "seamlessly blended upper and lower case characters in visual harmony."</p>

<p>The 102-year-old luxury automaker announced its transition to electric vehicles in 2021. The brand is reportedly set to launch three new electric cars by 2026 after it took new cars off-sale over a year ago to focus on reinventing itself.&nbsp;</p>

<p>“This is a reimagining that recaptures the essence of Jaguar, returning it to the values that once made it so loved, but making it relevant for a contemporary audience,” said Gerry McGovern, Jaguar Land Rover's chief creative officer, in a press release.</p>

<p>As per a report by Car and Driver, the pouncing cat logo called 'the Leaper', which has adorned Jaguar cars for decades, is being eliminated in favour of the badge.</p>

<p>Jaguar's Managing Director Rawdon Glover called the rebranding as the "biggest step change" in the company's history.</p>

<p>"A new era begins for Jaguar. This is an incredibly exciting time for the whole team. To re-imagine such a globally renowned brand really is a once-in-a-lifetime opportunity. Today, Jaguar unveils its new brand identity, recapturing its ethos to "Copy Nothing" that can trace its roots back to the words of our founder, Sir William Lyons," he posted on LinkedIn.&nbsp;</p>

<p>How the new branding will look on the cars will be unveiled at a Miami Art Week event on December 2.</p>

<p>"Watch out for the global unveiling of the first physical manifestation of our brand reinvention in Miami on December 2, where Jaguar will champion true originality, as a creator and advocate of artistic expression, in all its forms," Mr Glover said.</p>

<p>However, the social media reactions to the rebranding have not been very reassuring. Replying to the relaunch video posted by Jaguar on X, one internet user wrote: “Umm where are the cars in this ad? Is this for fashion?” To this, the brand replied, “Think of this as a declaration of intent.”&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Copy nothing. <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Jaguar?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Jaguar</a> <a href="https://t.co/BfVhc3l09B">pic.twitter.com/BfVhc3l09B</a></p>
— Jaguar (@Jaguar) <a href="https://twitter.com/Jaguar/status/1858800846646948155?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 19, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Another user wrote, "Jaguar took a year off for this? This is how companies fail." Replying to this, the brand said, "This is not the end. This is the new beginning."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Jaguar took a year off for this?<br />
<br />
This is how companies fail.</p>
— BitS (@BotintheShell) <a href="https://twitter.com/BotintheShell/status/1859021742783787277?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 19, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Tesla chief Elon Musk also joined the cacophony to express his confusion over the rebranding and wrote: “Do you sell cars?” To this, Jaguar's official X account responded: "Yes. We'd love to show you. Join us for a cuppa in Miami on 2nd December?"<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/67gomnq8_jaguar-twitter_625x300_21_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The new logo emphasized the brand's posh English pronunciation "Jag-you-are".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/google-told-employees-to-destroy-messages-to-avoid-antitrust-scrutiny-report-7066976]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Google Told Employees To Destroy Messages To Avoid Antitrust Suits: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/google-told-employees-to-destroy-messages-to-avoid-antitrust-scrutiny-report-7066976]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 21 Nov 2024 00:14:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Even as Google, the internet giant, stored the world's information, it kept a lid on its internal communications - telling employees to destroy messages, to not use certain words - to avoid antitrust suits, claimed a report.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Even as Google, the internet giant, stored the world's information, it kept a lid on its internal communications - telling employees to destroy messages and not use certain words - to avoid antitrust suits, claimed a report.</p>

<p>The company has been deploying such strategies since 2008, when it faced antitrust scrutiny over an advertising deal with its then-rival Yahoo and sent out a confidential memo to its employees, a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/11/20/technology/google-antitrust-employee-messages.html" rel="noindex,nofollow">New York Times report</a> said.</p>

<p>"Google said employees should refrain from speculation and sarcasm and think twice before writing one another about hot topics," said the report, adding that the employees were asked to not comment before they have "all the facts".</p>

<p>The technology, said the Times, was tweaked, too. "The setting for the company's instant messaging tool was changed to "off the record." An incautious phrase would be wiped the next day," it said.</p>

<p>"How Google developed this distrustful culture was pieced together from hundreds of documents and exhibits, as well as witness testimony, in three antitrust trials against the Silicon Valley company over the last year," said the report.</p>

<p>The testimony showed that Google took numerous steps to keep a lid on internal communication, it said.</p>

<p>"It encouraged employees to put 'attorney-client privileged' on documents and to always add a Google lawyer to the list of recipients, even if no legal questions were involved and the lawyer never responded," said the report.</p>

<p>Companies anticipating litigation are required to preserve documents, mandate the US laws. "But Google exempted instant messaging from automatic legal holds. If workers were involved in a lawsuit, it was up to them to turn their chat history on. From the evidence in the trials, few did," the report said.</p>

<p>Google has faced the broadest criticism for its actions, with the judges in all three antitrust cases chastising the company for its communications practices, said the report.</p>

<p>"Judge James Donato of the US District Court for the Northern District of California, who presided over the Epic (2020 Epic Games) case, said that there was 'an ingrained systemic culture of suppression of relevant evidence within Google' and that the company's behavior was 'a frontal assault on the fair administration of justice,'" the report said.</p>

<p>In another case involving the company's advertising technology, a district court judge in Virginia remarked that Google's document retention policies were designed in a way that an "awful lot of evidence has likely been destroyed".</p>

<p>Google produced 13 times as many emails as the average company per employee did before it was a decade old, Kent Walker, Google's top lawyer, testified in the Epic trial, said the report. Google felt overwhelmed, he said, and it was clear to the company that things would only become worse if changes weren't made, the report said quoting him.</p>

<p>The 2008 memo that said chat messages would be automatically purged was signed by Mr. Walker and Bill Coughran, an engineering executive.</p>

<p>Mr Walker, said the report, was asked to explain Google's behaviour to the judge. He denied that there was "a culture of concealment" but said one problem was Googlers unsure of the meaning of certain words, the report said.</p>

<p>"Last year, Google changed its procedures. The default became saving everything, including chats. Employees on litigation holds can no longer turn chat history off," the report said further.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-01/uspt4bmg_google-generic-reuters_625x300_20_January_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>