<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Sep 2024 12:33:43 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/prince-harry-and-meghan-markle-invited-to-spend-christmas-at-althorp-house-report-6530503]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Prince Harry, Meghan Markle Invited To Christmas At Princess DIana's House]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/prince-harry-and-meghan-markle-invited-to-spend-christmas-at-althorp-house-report-6530503]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Sep 2024 12:33:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prince Harry and Meghan Markle have reportedly been invited to spend Christmas at Althorp House, the childhood home of his late mother, Princess Diana.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prince Harry and Meghan Markle have reportedly been invited to spend Christmas at Althorp House, the childhood home of his late mother, Princess Diana. The invitation came from Harry's uncle, Charles Spencer, as the couple has not spent the festive season in the UK since 2018.</p>

<p>"Charles [Spencer] has invited Harry, Meghan, and the children to Althorp this Christmas. It's far too early to say whether they will take him up on it, but the offer is there if they want it,” a source revealed, according to <a href="https://www.express.co.uk/news/royal/1945837/meghan-markle-uk-return-date-revealed-prince-harry">The Express</a>.</p>

<p>If the Duke and Duchess of Sussex, along with their children – Prince Archie and Princess Lilibet – decide to travel from their California home to England, it would mark Meghan's first return since Queen Elizabeth II's funeral in 2022. The couple has also yet to receive an invitation from the royal family to celebrate Christmas at Sandringham. The source added that it is unlikely Harry and Meghan would attend even if invited.</p>

<p>Since stepping down from royal duties in 2020, Prince Harry has maintained close ties with his maternal family, the Spencers. His bond with them was evident when he attended his uncle, Lord Robert Fellowes' funeral last month. While both Harry and his brother Prince William were present, the estranged siblings sat separately, as per reports.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The trip also saw Harry staying at Althorp House, the final resting place of&nbsp;Princess Diana. Over the years, Harry has frequently visited the estate, which holds deep personal significance for him. Earlier this year, he reunited with Diana's brother Charles Spencer and sister Lady Jane Fellowes during the 10th anniversary of his Invictus Games.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to former BBC Royal correspondent Jennie Bond, Harry has <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/quietly-behind-scenes-prince-harry-secretly-in-contact-with-royal-family-6516545 ">kept in touch with his aunts and uncle</a>, Lady Sarah McCorquodale, Lady Jane Fellowes, and Charles Spencer, 9th Earl Spencer. The Spencer family has been a constant source of support for Harry, who has faced scrutiny and criticism since stepping back from royal duties.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/8h6aem6o_harry-diana-_625x300_10_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Over the years, Prince Harry has frequently visited the estate.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/rahul-gandhi-in-us-says-lok-sabha-elections-not-fought-on-level-playing-field-6530358]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Lok Sabha Elections Not Fought On Level Playing Field, Alleges Rahul Gandhi]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/rahul-gandhi-in-us-says-lok-sabha-elections-not-fought-on-level-playing-field-6530358]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Sep 2024 11:39:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Congress leader Rahul Gandhi has alleged the general elections in India this summer were not fought on a level playing field, asserting that the polls have destroyed the idea of Narendra Modi.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Congress leader Rahul Gandhi has alleged the general elections in India this summer were not fought on a level playing field, asserting that the polls have destroyed the idea of Narendra Modi.</p>

<p>The Leader of the Opposition in Lok Sabha, who is currently on a&nbsp;four-day visit to the United States, made the remarks at the prestigious Georgetown University here on Monday.</p>

<p>Addressing the event, Mr Gandhi said that the ruling coalition had collapsed and was broken "right down the middle".</p>

<p>“It's not just the prime minister, it's deeper than that. What has happened in India is that the coalition that brought Mr (Narendra) Modi to power has collapsed. It's broken right down the middle," Mr Gandhi said.</p>

<p>"So you'll see in these elections that they will struggle. Because the basic idea that Mr Modi is running a government for the people of India is gone,” he added.</p>

<p>Alleging that the Lok Sabha elections were not fought on the same footing, Mr Gandhi said, "I don't see it as a free election. I see it as a heavily controlled election." "I don't believe that in a fair election, the BJP would come anywhere near 240 seats. I would be surprised," he said, asserting that the party had a "huge financial advantage".</p>

<p>"The Election Commission was doing what they wanted. The entire campaign was structured so that Mr Modi could carry out his agenda across the country, with different designs for different states," Mr Gandhi claimed.</p>

<p>"The Congress party fought the elections with their bank accounts frozen and has basically destroyed the idea of Modi. You can see it because when you see the prime minister now in Parliament...he is psychologically trapped, and he basically cannot come to terms, he cannot understand how this has happened," he said.</p>

<p>Responding to a question, Mr Gandhi said that halfway through the campaign, Prime Minister Modi didn't think he would get anywhere near 300 or 400 seats.</p>

<p>“I think early on he realised that this thing's going wrong. We were getting inputs from regular sources...It was pretty clear that they were in trouble,” he said.</p>

<p>“So, there was this internal thing going on in the prime minister that I could see. And psychologically, how is this now happening? Because he's a person, as you know, he was in Gujarat for many years, never faced political adversity, then prime minister of India. Suddenly, this idea started to crack,” Mr Gandhi said.</p>

<p>“We knew. When he said that I speak directly to God, we knew that we had actually blown him apart. And that the psychology had gone. So people think that, well, this was the prime minister sort of saying that, look, 'I'm special, I'm unique, and I talk to God'. But that's not how we saw it. Internally, we saw it as a psychological collapse, what happened here? How is this thing not working?” he said.</p>

<p>"Now that idea has been replaced," he said.</p>

<p>Mr Gandhi, who arrived in the US on Saturday, interacted with members of the Indian diaspora and youths in Dallas, Texas. He also plans to meet lawmakers and senior officials of the US government in Washington DC.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/easgi2a8_rahul-gandhi-virginia-ani_625x300_10_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Rahul Gandhi said Congress party fought the elections with their bank accounts frozen.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/apophis-asteroid-isros-newest-headache-how-to-ward-off-egyptian-god-of-chaos-6530873]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Large Asteroid Hurtles Towards Earth, ISRO Warns Of "Worst Case Scenario"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/apophis-asteroid-isros-newest-headache-how-to-ward-off-egyptian-god-of-chaos-6530873]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Sep 2024 11:33:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Indian Space Research Organisation (ISRO) is monitoring a large asteroid called Apophis that is expected to come very close to Earth. The asteroid, which is named after the Egyptian God of Chaos, is hurtling towards the earth.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Indian Space Research Organisation (ISRO) is monitoring a large asteroid called Apophis that is expected to come very close to Earth. The asteroid, which is named after the Egyptian God of Chaos, is hurtling towards the earth and will have its closest encounter with Earth on April 13, 2029.</p>

<p>A new domain called planetary defense has been added to the portfolio of the Indian space agency and its job is to protect Earth from extra-terrestrial objects.</p>

<p>"A large asteroid strike is a real existential threat for humanity. ISRO is very alive to that threat and our Network for Space Objects Tracking and Analysis (NETRA) is monitoring Apophis very closely. After all we have only one Earth to live on. India will co-operate with all nations to ward off this and other such future threats," Dr S Somanath, Chairman of ISRO told NDTV.</p>

<p>Apophis was first discovered in 2004 and its periodicity, in which comes close to Earth, has been tracked very closely. The next encounter will be in 2029 and then in 2036. While there are concerns about its impact with Earth, some studies suggest that in 2029 it will be a fly by and may not hit Earth.</p>

<p>How close the encounter will be can be judged by the fact that India's geostationary satellites are in an orbit higher than the distance Apophis is likely to come close to.</p>

<p>At 32,000 kilometers above Earth, no other asteroid of this size has ever come so close to our planet.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/qgr83j98_apophis-asteroid_625x300_10_September_24.jpg?im=FitAndFill,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<h2><strong>"Continental scale devastation"</strong></h2>

<p>Asteroid Apophis is larger than India's largest aircraft carrier INS Vikramaditya and the largest cricket stadium, the Narendra Modi Stadium in Ahmedabad.</p>

<p>The asteroid has an estimated diameter of about 340 to 450 meters and any planetary body above a 140 meter diameter, passing close to Earth, is considered potentially hazardous.</p>

<p>ISRO estimates suggest that any asteroid larger than 300 meters can cause "continental scale devastation". In the worst-case scenario, if an asteroid larger than 10 kilometre in diameter hits Earth, it can cause "mass extinction"</p>

<p>Dr A K Anil Kumar, who heads ISRO's Network for Space Objects Tracking and Analysis (NETRA), said a collision with an asteroid that big can cause "global disruption".</p>

<p>"If it collides with Earth it can cause a catastrophe. It can cause local extinction. The dust thrown up by the collision can blanket the atmosphere causing global disruption," he said.</p>

<p>A meteor had hit India some 500,000 years ago at Lonar in Maharashtra. Today, a crater lake which is more than a square kilometer in area marks the site of collision.</p>

<p>"ISRO will surely study the Apophis asteroid on its closest approach in 2029. After all, we have a living example of the Lonar Crater Lake made by a meteor strike in Maharashtra," Dr Somanath said.</p>

<h2><strong>NASA plans mission to avert crisis</strong></h2>

<p>The world's leading space agencies are likely to launch several missions not only to study the asteroid's trajectory but also to understand its composition.</p>

<p>NASA's OSIRIS-REx was the first American spacecraft to return samples from an asteroid and now it is being retargeted to rendezvous with Apophis. Another mission by the European Space Agency named Rapid Apophis Mission for Security and Safety or RAMSES may be launched in 2028. Dr Somanath has said India may join this mission.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">This animation shows the distance between the Apophis asteroid and Earth at the time of the asteroid's closest approach. The blue dots are the many man-made satellites that orbit our planet, and the pink represents the International Space Station <a href="https://t.co/vY5x57y1FK">https://t.co/vY5x57y1FK</a> <a href="https://t.co/WKt8YiBjLh">pic.twitter.com/WKt8YiBjLh</a></p>
— Massimo (@Rainmaker1973) <a href="https://twitter.com/Rainmaker1973/status/1122935660053172224?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 29, 2019</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>There are ways to nudge the asteroid away from Earth which includes by impacting the asteroid by a space craft like NASA's Double Asteroid Redirection Test (DART), or more benign methods like using a gravity tractor to deflect the asteroid or using a high speed ion beam to change its direction, but the last step could always be using nuclear explosives to detonate on the asteroid.</p>

<p>Not the first asteroid to threaten Earth</p>

<p>Among the most recent asteroid hits was the February 5, 2013 hit at Oblast in Russia by a 20-meter diameter asteroid. About 1,500 people were injured and 7,200 buildings were damaged. In 1908, a 30-meter asteroid hit Tunguska in Russia and it is estimated that 80 million trees were destroyed.</p>

<p>The most devastating asteroid hit is estimated to have taken place 650 million years ago when a 10-15 kilometer diameter asteroid hit Mexico and led to the extinction of dinosaurs and almost 70% of all species.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/gg2ds54g_asteroid-apophis_625x300_10_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/spot-the-difference-the-subtle-changes-to-apples-latest-iphone-line-up-6530805]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Spot The Difference: The Subtle Changes To Apple's Latest iPhone Line-Up]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/spot-the-difference-the-subtle-changes-to-apples-latest-iphone-line-up-6530805]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Sep 2024 11:18:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[From the outside, Apple Inc.'s latest iPhones aren't strikingly different than last year's models - other than a small button nestled into the lower right side.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>From the outside, Apple Inc.'s latest iPhones aren't strikingly different than last year's models - other than a small button nestled into the lower right side.</p>

<p>This feature, the Camera Control button, is included in all four versions of the new iPhone 16 and looks like a slightly recessed groove. Pressing it once instantly brings up the camera launch screen, letting you fine-tune the shot. A second touch will take the photo.</p>

<p>The idea is to replicate the experience of using the shutter button on a digital single-lens reflex camera - better known as a DSLR. The process is pretty simple and works best with the phone held in your right hand, using your thumb on the button. It's possible to do it with your left hand, though it might require a bit more fiddling.</p>

<p>From there, it gets a little less intuitive. While doing a hands-on test of the technology at Apple's campus in Cupertino, California, it took time to get the hang of some of the button's other functions.</p>

<p>Beyond pressing down to take a shot or start a video, you can maintain your finger's contact with the button and double-tap lightly to toggle through camera options. You can also adjust the zoom level or - depending on the mode you've selected - change other settings by sliding the finger across the button.</p>

<p>This part didn't always go smoothly. A number of people testing the feature, as well as some Apple staff, struggled to activate the mode toggle the first time.</p>

<p>There are some other subtle changes to the iPhone lineup. The Pro versions now have slightly larger screen sizes, checking in at 6.3 and 6.9 inches depending on the model. They also have the tinniest borders of any Apple product, helping maximize that screen real estate.</p>

<p>Even so, many consumers might not notice the difference. The iPhone 16 Pro's 6.3-inch screen doesn't appear remarkably large when held up against its 6.1-inch predecessor.</p>

<p>More substantive changes will come in the form of software updates - most notably, a suite of AI tools called Apple Intelligence. But you'll have to be patient: A beta version of that technology will debut next month, well after the iPhones go on sale.</p>

<p>The early iteration of Apple Intelligence will center on text summarization, generating responses in email and other messages, and photo editing. Those capabilities were impressive during tests, but also in line with what's available through the likes of Adobe Inc. and Google.</p>

<p>The 16 Pro also has a 48-megapixel ultrawide-angle camera - something that does seem like a step up for the photography enthusiast.</p>

<p>Siri, the voice assistant, has a refreshed interface. When triggered, the feature lights up around the border of the phone. You also can pose questions to Siri voice-free by typing in a command bar.</p>

<p>The phones have more powerful processors, and this is evident when switching between between applications and handling other tasks. Apple also has described the new Pro Max phone as having the best iPhone battery life ever - something that seemed especially appealing after I drained my 15 Pro's battery during the event.</p>

<p>Apple kept the prices steady for the new lineup. The iPhone 16 starts at $799, with the Plus model priced at $899. The iPhone 16 Pro is $999, and the Pro Max begins at $1,199. Preorders begin Friday, with the phones shipping on Sept. 20.</p>

<p><br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/lnc5g2i_apple-iphone_625x300_10_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Pro versions now have slightly larger screen sizes.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/you-can-pre-order-new-iphone-16-and-buy-it-in-india-on-these-dates-6528656]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[You Can Pre-Order New iPhone 16 And Buy It In India On These Dates]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/you-can-pre-order-new-iphone-16-and-buy-it-in-india-on-these-dates-6528656]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Sep 2024 11:17:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Tech giant Apple on Monday introduced its much-anticipated iPhone 16 series with Apple Intelligence, larger display sizes, camera control, innovative pro-camera features and a big leap in battery life.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Tech giant Apple on Monday introduced its much-anticipated iPhone 16 series with Apple Intelligence, larger display sizes, camera control, innovative pro-camera features and a big leap in battery life.</p>

<p>Powered by the A18 Pro chip, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/apple-looks-to-entice-iphone-16-shoppers-with-not-quite-ready-ai-6530677">iPhone 16 Pro and iPhone 16 Pro Max</a> feature a new 48MP Fusion camera with a faster quad-pixel sensor that enables 4K120 fps video recording in Dolby Vision, the company said in a statement.</p>

<p>iPhone 16 Pro and iPhone 16 Pro Max will be available in black titanium, natural titanium, white titanium and desert titanium colours, in 128GB, 256GB, 512GB, and 1TB storage capacities. iPhone 16 Pro starts at Rs 119,900 and iPhone 16 Pro Max starts at Rs 144,900.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.gadgets360.com/mobiles/news/iphone-16-pro-max-price-in-india-japan-us-uae-uk-pre-order-sale-date-6530224">Customers in India</a> will be able to pre-order iPhone 16 Pro and iPhone 16 Pro Max beginning this Friday (September 13), with availability beginning September 20.</p>

<p>“Customers who are looking for the best possible iPhone will be able to take advantage of this huge step forward, whether they're applying edits to a photo without lifting a finger, rewriting meeting notes for a more professional tone, or using the advanced camera system to capture their next masterpiece in 4K120 fps in Dolby Vision,” said Greg Joswiak, Apple's senior vice president of Worldwide Marketing.</p>

<p>iPhone 16 and iPhone 16 Plus will be available in ultramarine, teal, pink, white, and black in 128GB, 256GB, and 512GB storage capacities. iPhone 16 starts at Rs 79,900 and iPhone 16 Plus starts at Rs 89.900. Pre-orders will begin on September 13, with availability beginning September 20, said the company.</p>

<p>The tech giant unveiled <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/apple-event-2024-sleep-apnoea-tool-arrives-on-apple-watch-hearing-health-on-airpods-pro-2-6530554">Apple Watch</a> Series 10, featuring a refined design and new capabilities. It also features new sleep apnea notifications, faster charging, water depth and temperature sensing and new health and fitness insights and intelligence in watchOS 11.</p>

<p>Apple Watch Series 10 is available in both aluminum and titanium, in an array of stunning colors and finishes. Jet black is a new polished aluminum finish that is distinctively reflective and sleek, while new titanium cases — available in natural, gold, and slate — have a spectacular jewellery-like shine.</p>

<p>The users in India can now pre-order Apple Watch Series 10, with availability in stores beginning September 20. Apple Watch Series 10 starts at Rs 46,900 and Watch SE is available starting at Rs 24,900.</p>

<p>Apple Watch Series 10 is nearly 10 per cent thinner than Apple Watch Series 7, Series 8, and Series 9.</p>

<p>The company also introduced Apple Watch Ultra 2 in a new black titanium finish and enhanced with features in watchOS 11 that make the most rugged and capable Apple Watch even better.</p>

<p>Apple Watch Ultra 2 features most accurate GPS in a sports watch, the brightest display of any Apple product, and up to 36 hours of battery life with regular use or up to 72 hours in Low Power Mode.</p>

<p>Customers can also pre-order AirPods 4 for Rs 12,900, with availability beginning September 20. They can also pre-order AirPods 4 with Active Noise Cancellation for Rs 17,900. AirPods Pro 2 are available for Rs 24,900, said the company. They can also pre-order AirPods Max with USB-C charging for Rs 59,900, with availability beginning September 20.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/are57q5_iphone-16-afp_625x300_10_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[iPhone 16 In India: Pre-orders will begin on September 13, with availability beginning September 20]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/apple-event-2024-sleep-apnoea-tool-arrives-on-apple-watch-hearing-health-on-airpods-pro-2-6530554]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Sleep Apnoea Tool Arrives On Apple Watch, Hearing Health On AirPods Pro 2]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/apple-event-2024-sleep-apnoea-tool-arrives-on-apple-watch-hearing-health-on-airpods-pro-2-6530554]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Sep 2024 11:00:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The new iPhone maker has added groundbreaking health features to its newly launched Apple Watch which will deliver sleep apnoea notifications, while its AirPods Pro 2 will feature the world's first all-in-one hearing health experience.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The new iPhone maker has added groundbreaking health features to its newly launched Apple Watch which will deliver sleep apnoea notifications, while its AirPods Pro 2 will feature the world's first all-in-one hearing health experience.</p>

<p>Apple Watch Series 10 and <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.gadgets360.com/wearables/news/airpods-4-pro-launch-sale-date-specifications-features-6527644">AirPods Pro 2</a> were launched globally at <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/apple-looks-to-entice-iphone-16-shoppers-with-not-quite-ready-ai-6530677">Apple's “Its Glowtime” event</a> on Monday at Apple Park, California.</p>

<p>“With Apple Watch, we continue to offer our users the ability to uncover important health conditions with new sleep apnoea notifications. And on AirPods Pro, powerful features put users' hearing health front and centre, bringing new ways to help test for and receive assistance for hearing loss,” said Sumbul Desai, MD, Apple's vice president of Health, in a statement.</p>

<p>The sleep apnoea detection feature is a first for the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.gadgets360.com/mobiles/features/apple-event-2024-launch-iphone-16-pro-max-plus-watch-airpods-glowtime-6526944">Apple Watch</a>, beginning with the Series 10 model. It will be supported on Apple Watch Series 9, Apple Watch Series 10, and Apple Watch Ultra 2.</p>

<p>The Cupertino-based company said the new sleep notification algorithm was developed using advanced machine learning and an extensive data set of clinical-grade sleep apnoea tests. The innovative breathing disturbances metric will track users' sleep, analyse sleep patterns and notify them in the event of an apnoea -- a serious sleep disorder where breathing repeatedly stops and starts.</p>

<p>The breathing disturbances metric uses the accelerometer to detect small movements at the wrist associated with interruptions to normal respiratory patterns during sleep, and then notify users if it shows consistent signs of moderate to severe sleep apnoea.</p>

<p>Apple noted that the sleep apnoea feature will roll out in 150 countries once it receives approval from the US Food and Drug Administration (FDA) in the next few months. Other standard health features like the Afib alerts, cardio fitness, and the ECG app, from the previous Apple Watch models are also present in the latest model.</p>

<p>The newly launched smartwatch is slimmer than its predecessor and features a larger display.</p>

<p>Further, Apple's AirPods Pro comes with active Loud Sound Reduction -- a clinically validated hearing test feature -- and an over-the-counter hearing aid feature.</p>

<p>The first-of-its-kind software-based hearing aid feature helps make access to hearing assistance easier than ever at an approachable price point. The hearing test and hearing aid features are expected to receive marketing authorisation from global health authorities soon and will be available this year in more than 100 countries and regions.</p>

<p>Since launching the Health app in 2014, Apple has introduced meaningful features that focus on 18 areas of health and fitness across Apple Watch, AirPods, iPhone, and iPad.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/igbvi0go_apple-watch-afp_625x300_10_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The sleep apnoea detection feature is a first for the Apple Watch.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/apple-looks-to-entice-iphone-16-shoppers-with-not-quite-ready-ai-6530677]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Apple Looks To Entice iPhone 16 Shoppers With Not-Quite-Ready AI]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/apple-looks-to-entice-iphone-16-shoppers-with-not-quite-ready-ai-6530677]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Sep 2024 10:54:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Apple Inc. introduced the latest version of its flagship device, the iPhone 16, betting it can entice consumers with modest hardware upgrades and AI technology that's still on the horizon.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Apple Inc. introduced the latest version of its flagship device, the iPhone 16, betting it can entice consumers with modest hardware upgrades and AI technology that's still on the horizon.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Chief Executive Officer Tim Cook unveiled the smartphone - alongside new watches and AirPods earbuds - at an event Monday that was infused with the promise of artificial intelligence. The iPhone 16 was built for AI "from the ground up," he said, though the capabilities will only be gradually added to the device via software updates.&nbsp;</p>

<p>It's a gambit for the tech titan, which has been racing to develop a suite of tools called Apple Intelligence. Though Apple has been touting the technology since its developers conference in June, the software won't be included in the initial versions of the new iPhones. They're set to go on sale Friday, with the product reaching stores on Sept. 20.</p>

<p>"This is just the beginning," Apple software chief Craig Federighi said during the presentation. The first set of tools will be released as part of a beta test in October, he said, "with more features rolling out in the months to come."</p>

<p>The media could not be loaded, either because the server or network failed or because the format is not supported. As part of the event, Apple unveiled a version of its smartwatch with a bigger screen and the ability to detect sleep apnea. And it touted new software that can turn AirPods into hearing aids.</p>

<p>The iPhone debut was the centerpiece of the presentation, though the company only made relatively minor changes to the device's look and hardware features. The iPhone 16 and 16 Plus will be available in new colors and get a customizable Action button that had only been available on higher-end models. There's also a more powerful chip and new Camera Control button that lets users snap pictures and access camera functions.</p>

<p>New Pro models, meanwhile, will get slightly larger displays and thinner borders. They will run an A18 Pro processor with an upgraded neural engine - the part of the chip designed to handle AI tasks. The phones have more powerful camera components and video features, letting them capture higher-resolution photos and more cinematic slow-motion clips.</p>

<p>Apple is playing catch-up in the world of generative artificial intelligence, where tech peers like Alphabet Inc.'s Google and Microsoft Corp. have made strides. Monday's presentation was partly a pitch to consumers - and Wall Street - that Apple should be taken seriously in AI.&nbsp;</p>

<p>But the Cupertino, California-based company's AI technology is still in early stages. The Apple Intelligence tools have faced numerous delays, and many key features won't arrive until next year. For now, the technology is focused on summarizing messages and notifications, rather than matching the gee-whiz capabilities of rival systems.</p>

<p>Apple shares slipped more than 1.5% during the event, though they rebounded later. That kind of ho-hum reaction is fairly typical during Apple presentations. Most new features are reported ahead of time, and there were few surprises during Monday's presentation.</p>

<p>AI was a major theme of the event, which kicked off at 10 a.m. local time. The company hopes to use the Apple Intelligence software to entice consumers to buy upgraded devices, since customers will need a recent iPhone to handle the capabilities.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Apple Intelligence will include an upgraded Siri digital assistant and the ability to create custom emoji with text prompts. The event's "It's Glowtime" theme was a reference to the look of Siri's new interface.</p>

<p>But much of the technology won't be ready right away, potentially limiting its impact on iPhone sales. Even when Apple Intelligence debuts in October, it will be a beta test - an early version for more adventurous consumers.</p>

<p>That "indicates a lot of the features are still being fine-tuned for release and not ready for prime time," eMarketer analyst Gadjo Sevilla said in a note. "The focus on security and privacy is a likely reason for feature delays."</p>

<p>The entry-level iPhone will continue to start at $799, with the Plus model selling for $899. The iPhone 16 Pro is $999, while the larger Pro Max version is $1,199.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The new Apple Watch - the Series 10 edition - has 30% more screen area, even with a thinner design. The sleep apnea feature will be available in more than 150 regions, the company said.</p>

<p>The new watch is about 10% thinner than the Series 9 version. It also comes in a new titanium chassis that's lighter than aluminum models. The device starts at $399 and will be released Sept. 20. A new version of the higher-end Ultra version also was announced, and it goes on sale that day for $799.</p>

<p>The event included an updated version of the standard $129 AirPods, which shrinks the size of the case and adds a USB-C charger. A $179 version also will be available - a midrange product - with noise cancellation. That used to only be available on the higher-end AirPods Pro.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The company introduced a new line of $549 AirPods Max headphones in fresh colors, also with USB-C charging. Like the other products, the devices will be released on Sept. 20. Apple didn't debut a new version of its AirPods Pro, but introduced features such as a hearing test and the ability to act as a hearing aid. Those capabilities will be offered as a software update this fall.</p>

<p>The iPhone debut is usually Apple's most important announcement of the year. The device accounts for roughly half of the company's annual revenue, and it helps fuel additional sales in the form of accessories and services.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Apple doesn't typically hold its iPhone launch on a Monday, but the earlier timing let the company get out ahead of an eventful Tuesday: A US presidential debate is scheduled for that day, and there should a resolution in a European Commission case over whether Apple has to pay $14 billion in taxes.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/kc4lbg0o_apple-launch-event_625x300_09_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The iPhone debut was the centerpiece of the presentation.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/rahul-gandhi-in-us-rahul-gandhi-shares-reaction-to-congress-accounts-being-sealed-before-polls-6529912]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Rahul Gandhi Shares Reaction To Congress Accounts Being Sealed Before Polls]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/rahul-gandhi-in-us-rahul-gandhi-shares-reaction-to-congress-accounts-being-sealed-before-polls-6529912]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Sep 2024 10:31:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Congress MP Rahul Gandhi addressing an event in Washington DC metro area said that just months ahead of the general elections in India the bank accounts of his party were sealed leaving it without funds for advertising or campaigning.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lok Sabha Leader of Opposition and Congress MP Rahul Gandhi addressing an event in Washington DC metro area said that just months ahead of the general elections in India the bank accounts of his party were sealed leaving it without funds for advertising or campaigning.</p>

<p>"Three months before elections our bank accounts were all sealed... We were discussing that now what to do...I said '<em>Dekhi Jayegi</em>', let's see what we can do .. and we went into the elections..." <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/rahul-gandhi-pm-narendra-modi-i-dont-hate-mr-modi-rahul-gandhis-latest-at-us-university-chat-6530361">Mr Gandhi said</a>.</p>

<p>"We had no money for advertising or campaigning we had no money to transport our leaders. I remember discussing with Mallikarjun Kharge and the treasurer "unki toh, hawa likal gayi thi (lost his confidence) about what to do next.</p>

<p>The <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/rahul-gandhi-on-indians-in-us-says-youre-bridge-between-two-nations-6529750">Congress leader</a> recounted that he had fought multiple elections-2004, 2009, assembly elections.</p>

<p>"This is the first time in my life all the bank accounts were sealed. I said, '<em>dekhi jayegi, dekhte hain kya hota hai</em>' (We'll see, let's see what happens) and that was the spirit with which we fought the election," said Rahul Gandhi said while addressing an Indian diaspora event in Virginia's Herndon in US on Monday (local time).</p>

<p>"You have to understand what this fight is about. It's not just about politics, that's superficial," Mr Gandhi said adding that the the real issue is whether a person will still be allowed to wear his turban as a Sikh.</p>

<p>"The fight (in India) is about whether a Sikh, is going to be allowed to wear a turban in India...whether a Sikh will be allowed to wear a kada in India or will be able to go to the Gurudwara...that's what the fight is about, and it is not just for Sikh, it is for all the religion..." the Congress leader said.</p>

<p>Further he continued his tirade against the ruling Bharatiya Janata Party claiming that the "fear of Prime Minister Narendra Modi" among people had vanished after Lok Sabha elections 2024 results were declared.</p>

<p>"Something has changed after the elections. PM Modi tried to create an environment of fear. Various agencies, media, income tax department tried to spread fear, even among small and medium-sized businesses. But, nothing worked. The fear vanished in one second. The spread of fear took years and consumed a lot of money, but it vanished. You can see it in parliament right upfront... And I can tell you that the idea of PM Modi, 56 inch chest, direct connection with God. That's all gone. It's history now. He, his partners in government and India, the three or four senior ministers in his government realise it." he said.</p>

<p>Earlier on February 16, Congress national president Mallikarjun Kharge came down heavily on the Prime Minister Narendra Modi-led central government after the alleged freezing of the grand old party's bank accounts by the Income Tax department.</p>

<p>"Power drunk Modi Govt has frozen the accounts of the country's largest Opposition party - the Indian National Congress - just before the Lok Sabha elections," Mr Kharge said in a post on X.</p>

<p>"This is a deep assault on India's Democracy! The UNCONSTITUTIONAL money collected by the BJP would be utilised by them for elections, but the money collected by us through CROWDFUNDING shall be sealed!" he added.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/epcuqhdg_rahul-gandhi-twitter-ani_625x300_10_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Rahul Gandhi said months ahead of general elections the bank accounts of his party were sealed]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/harvey-weinstein-undergoes-emergency-heart-surgery-after-chest-pain-in-jail-6530303]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Harvey Weinstein Undergoes Emergency Heart Surgery After Chest Pain In Jail]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/harvey-weinstein-undergoes-emergency-heart-surgery-after-chest-pain-in-jail-6530303]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Sep 2024 09:46:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Disgraced film producer Harvey Weinstein was rushed from Rikers Island jail to Bellevue Hospital in New York City on Sunday for emergency heart surgery.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">Disgraced film producer Harvey Weinstein was rushed from Rikers Island jail to Bellevue Hospital in New York City on Sunday for emergency heart surgery after experiencing severe chest pains.&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">The news was confirmed by his representatives, Craig Rothfeld and Juda Engelmayer, who issued a <a href="https://abcnews.go.com/US/harvey-weinstein-rushed-hospital-emergency-heart-surgery-sources/story?id=113527737">statement</a> saying, “Mr Weinstein was rushed to Bellevue Hospital last night due to several medical conditions.” No further details were provided.&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">Weinstein's lawyer, Arthur Aidala, revealed that the request for Weinstein's immediate transfer to the hospital was made following his complaints of chest pains. Mr Aidala reportedly warned jail officials, “This guy is going to die on your watch if you don't do something,” as per The Guardian.&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">The 72-year-old has a history of serious health issues. In July, he was hospitalised for treatment of COVID-19, pneumonia, diabetes, high blood pressure and other conditions. His health problems have been recurrent, leading to multiple hospital visits over the years, including in 2020 when he had surgery to open a blocked artery.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Currently, Weinstein is awaiting a retrial for rape and sexual assault charges after New York's top court overturned his 2020 conviction earlier this year. The court ruled that the original trial allowed testimony from women whose accusations were not part of the case, thus stating that he did not receive a fair trial.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Despite the reversal, Weinstein faces the prospect of a new indictment in New York, with the Manhattan district attorney's office investigating additional sexual assault allegations. Furthermore, Weinstein has been sentenced to 16 years in prison in a separate rape trial in California, which he is appealing.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Over 100 people have made allegations of rape and misconduct against Weinstein, dating back to the late 1970s. His case has been a significant moment in the #MeToo movement against sexual abuse by powerful men. Despite the overwhelming accusations, Weinstein has consistently maintained his innocence, claiming he was the victim of a “set-up.”</p>

<p dir="ltr">Once a prominent figure in the film industry, Weinstein co-founded the Miramax film studio and produced some of Hollywood's most iconic films, including&nbsp;<em>Pulp Fiction</em>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<em>Shakespeare in Love.&nbsp;</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/qrgmo9p_harvey-weinstein_625x300_26_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iranian-dissident-gang-raped-in-germany-by-tehran-loyalists-report-6530310]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iranian Dissident Gang-Raped In Germany By Tehran Loyalists: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iranian-dissident-gang-raped-in-germany-by-tehran-loyalists-report-6530310]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Sep 2024 09:45:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 30-year-old Iranian dissident was gang-raped in Germany by four men believed to be loyalists of Iran's Islamic Republic, a report said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 30-year-old Iranian dissident was gang-raped in Germany by four men believed to be loyalists of Iran's Islamic Republic, a report said. The assault, which took place on Saturday night at an abandoned brewery in the town of Iserlohn in North Rhine-Westphalia is being treated as a politically motivated crime, according to reports from <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.spiegel.de/panorama/sexualdelikt-in-iserlohn-mutmassliche-taeter-sind-offenbar-regimetreue-iraner-a-9eb13a1f-a2ac-42f4-a71f-c03fcab97c1b">Der Spiegel </a>and other German media outlets.</p>

<p>The attackers, aged 24 to 46, were arrested shortly after the incident by local law enforcement, who deployed helicopters and multiple patrol units in a swift search of a nearby forest. One of the suspects sustained injuries while trying to escape capture. According to local media, witnesses had alerted authorities after hearing the victim's screams, leading to the discovery of the man in a severely abused state, tied up and in need of medical care.</p>

<p>German investigators have confirmed that the attack was not only violent but carried a specific political message. The victim, an Iranian refugee known for his opposition to Tehran's regime, was targeted with the intention of "sexual humiliation."</p>

<p>The attackers are reported to be staunch supporters of Iran's Islamic Republic.&nbsp;</p>

<p>This latest attack follows a trend of Iranian dissidents being targeted on foreign soil. Earlier this year, an Iranian dissident in the Netherlands narrowly escaped an assassination attempt. Other incidents include the stabbing of Iran International presenter Pouria Zeraati in London and threats against Iranian journalists in the UK.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-07/48i2lvj8_germany-police-reuters_625x300_20_July_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The attackers, aged 24 to 46, were arrested shortly after the incident by local law enforcement.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mass-deportations-end-of-ukraine-war-donald-trumps-5-step-plan-for-presidency-6530073]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Mass Deportations, End Of Ukraine War: Trump's 5-Step Plan For Presidency]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mass-deportations-end-of-ukraine-war-donald-trumps-5-step-plan-for-presidency-6530073]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Sep 2024 08:50:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Mass expulsions? Political revenge? World peace? A new golden age? As Donald Trump vies for another term in the White House, the country is abuzz with speculation over how life might look with the ex-president back at the helm.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Mass expulsions? Political revenge? World peace? A new golden age? As Donald Trump vies for another term in the White House, the country is abuzz with speculation over how life might look with the ex-president back at the helm.</p>

<p>Here are Trump's plans for the United States and the world, in five emblematic measures.</p>

<h2>Mass deportations</h2>

<p>Vice President Kamala Harris's rival in November's election has pledged to launch the biggest deportation operation of illegal migrants in US history on his first day in office.</p>

<p>"We're going to get them out as fast as we can," he has said, accusing undocumented migrants of "poisoning the blood of our country."</p>

<p>The 78-year-old, known for his unfinished US-Mexico border wall project, has said he would be happy to "use the military" as part of the effort and would open detention camps to process targets for expulsion.</p>

<p>"On day one of my new term in office, I will sign an executive order making clear to federal agencies that under the correct interpretation of the law, going forward the future children of illegal aliens will not receive automatic US citizenship," he said in a campaign video.</p>

<p>He has confirmed he also plans to reinstate his ban on entries from several Muslim-majority countries, as a means of "keeping terrorists the hell out of our country."</p>

<h2>'Drill, baby, drill!'</h2>

<p>Trump slammed the door on the 2015 Paris climate accords during his first term, and his campaign has said he intends to end US participation again if reelected.</p>

<p>He told supporters at a rally earlier in the summer that he would "stop Biden's wasteful spending and rapidly terminate the green new scam" -- a reference to the funding committed by his successor to mitigating climate change.</p>

<p>"I will repeal crooked Joe Biden's insane electric vehicle mandate and we will 'drill, baby, drill,'" Trump said in Wisconsin, using an old Republican slogan.</p>

<p>"Energy costs will come down very quickly," he vowed. "In many cases we'll be cutting your energy costs in half."</p>

<h2>Crypto-a-go-go</h2>

<p>Trump has pledged to make the United States the "Bitcoin and cryptocurrency capital of the world," and to put tech billionaire and right-wing conspiracy theorist Elon Musk in charge of a wide-ranging audit of governmental waste.</p>

<p>Trump also envisages tariffs of "more than 10 percent" on all imports. US companies -- and eventually their customers -- pay for import tariffs, not the companies exporting the goods.</p>

<p>He insists that the revenue collected will finance a "middle class, upper class, lower class, business class big tax cut."</p>

<p>Having waged a fierce trade war with China during his first term, he also plans to revoke the Asian giant's "most favored nation" status, granted to promote trade.</p>

<h2>Abortion ambiguity</h2>

<p>Trump never misses an opportunity to point out that it is partly thanks to him -- and his three conservative Supreme Court appointments -- that abortion rights have been considerably weakened in the United States.</p>

<p>But he is more ambiguous about the future of access to reproductive health care.</p>

<p>Insisting it should be an issue for the individual states, the Republican has balked at pushing a nationwide abortion ban, a commitment that would win him support from the religious right.</p>

<p>"You must follow your heart on this issue but remember, you must also win elections," he has said.</p>

<p>And he promised: "My Administration will be great for women and their reproductive rights."</p>

<h2>Ukraine war 'plan'</h2>

<p>Trump has been saying for months he could end the war in Ukraine within "24 hours," without explaining how.</p>

<p>Critics suggest his plan would involve pressuring Kyiv to cede territory illegally occupied by Russia in both 2014 and 2022.</p>

<p>"I have a very exacting plan how to stop Ukraine and Russia, And I have a certain idea -- maybe not a plan, but an idea -- for China," he said in an interview.</p>

<p>"But I can't give you those plans, because if I give you those plans, I'm not going to be able to use them, they'll be very unsuccessful. You know, part of it's surprise, right?"</p>

<p>Trump presented himself as an unconditional defender of Israel when the war with Hamas broke out. But he has since appeared more critical in his comments about the US ally's military offensive in Gaza, saying: "I'm not sure that I'm loving the way they're doing it."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/q5p67c08_donald-trump-reuters_625x300_06_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/13-years-after-tsunami-nuclear-debris-removed-from-fukushima-reactor-6530043]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[13 Years After Tsunami, Nuclear Debris Removed From Fukushima Reactor]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/13-years-after-tsunami-nuclear-debris-removed-from-fukushima-reactor-6530043]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Sep 2024 08:43:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A difficult operation to remove a small amount of radioactive debris from Japan's stricken Fukushima nuclear plant began Tuesday, after technical issues suspended an earlier attempt.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A difficult operation to remove a small amount of radioactive debris from Japan's stricken Fukushima nuclear plant began Tuesday, after technical issues suspended an earlier attempt. Tokyo Electric Power Company (TEPCO) said in a statement that its "pilot extraction operation" had started. It will take about two weeks, according to the company.</p>

<p>The tiny sample will be studied for clues about conditions inside the reactors -- a crucial step towards decommissioning the Fukushima Daiichi plant.</p>

<p>Around 880 tons of extremely hazardous material remain 13 years after a tsunami caused by a 9.0-magnitude earthquake triggered one of the world's worst nuclear accidents.</p>

<p>Removing the debris from the reactors is regarded as the most daunting challenge in the decades-long decommissioning project.</p>

<p>TEPCO originally planned to start its first trial removal on August 22, aiming to collect just three grams (0.1 ounces) for analysis -- if the extraction process is successful.</p>

<p>But the company had to stop the work at a preliminary stage after detecting a problem involving the installation of the necessary equipment.</p>

<p>Three of the Fukushima plant's six reactors were operating when the tsunami hit on March 11, 2011, sending them into meltdown.</p>

<p>The debris within has radiation levels so high that TEPCO had to develop specialised robots able to function inside.</p>

<p>TEPCO deployed two mini-drones and a "snake-shaped robot" into one of the three nuclear reactors in February, as part of the preparations for the removal task.</p>

<p>Separately, last year Japan began releasing treated wastewater from the Fukushima plant into the Pacific Ocean, sparking a diplomatic row with China and Russia.</p>

<p>Both countries have banned Japanese seafood imports, although Tokyo insists the discharge is safe, a view backed by the UN atomic agency.</p>

<p>And in a TEPCO initiative to promote food from the Fukushima area, swanky London department store Harrods on Saturday began selling peaches that were grown in the region.</p>

<p>Fukushima peaches are renowned for their juicy, sweet taste -- but they aren't cheap, with one box of three reportedly going for 80 pounds ($100).</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-08/r7p1sqbg_japan-fukushima-plant-reuters-_625x300_24_August_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/ambassador-parvathaneni-harish-assures-antonio-guterres-about-indias-commitment-to-revitalise-un-6530014]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India Committed To Revitalisation Of UN: Ambassador Harish To Antonio Guterres]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/ambassador-parvathaneni-harish-assures-antonio-guterres-about-indias-commitment-to-revitalise-un-6530014]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Sep 2024 08:39:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Assuring Secretary-General Antonio Guterres of India's commitment to revitalising the global organisation, Ambassador Parvathaneni Harish presented his credentials to take over as the Permanent Representative.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Assuring Secretary-General Antonio Guterres of India's commitment to revitalising the global organisation, Ambassador Parvathaneni Harish presented his credentials to take over as the Permanent Representative.</p>

<p>Ambassador Harish hit the ground running, making the case before the Security Council soon after the ceremony on Monday for major troop-contributing countries to be actively involved in the decision-making process of peacekeeping operations.</p>

<p>Earlier, prepping for the assignment ahead which takes off with the summit starting on September 22 with Prime Minister Narendra Modi's participation, he had made a round of consultations with several diplomats on cooperating on issues that India shared with their countries.</p>

<p>In posts on X after presenting his credentials, Mr Harish wrote that he and&nbsp; Mr Guterres “agreed on the need to strengthen and reform multilateralism in both its political and economic dimensions to deal with contemporary challenges and harness new opportunities”.</p>

<p>He added that he assured him of India's commitment under PM Modi's “leadership to reformed multilateralism and revitalisation of the UN”.</p>

<p>Mr Harish met with Philemon Yang, who will become the president of the General Assembly this month. He assured the former prime minister of Cameroon of India's support in his new role.</p>

<p>Coming from his latest assignment as the ambassador to Germany, Mr Harish brings 34 years of diplomatic experience having represented India from Southeast Asia through the Middle East and Europe to the US.</p>

<p>He has special expertise in the issue currently consuming the UN, Gaza, as he served as India's representative to the Palestine Authority based in Gaza City and had also been deputed to work for the UN Relief and Works Agency for Palestine.</p>

<p>His assignments included ambassador to Vietnam and postings in Houston, Riyadh, and Cairo, where he studied Arabic.</p>

<p>Mr Harish started at the UN on Thursday with a floral tribute to Mahatma Gandhi at his statue on the UN campus.</p>

<p>He followed that with meetings with General Assembly President Dennis Francis and Amandeep Singh Gill, the secretary-general's envoy on technology.</p>

<p>Francis posted on X that he was “grateful for India's continued support throughout my presidency”.</p>

<p>The next day, India's mission said he discussed “Special Strategic and Global Partnership” with Yamazaki Kazuyuki, the permanent representative of Japan, a member of G4, the group that advocates for expanding the Security Council's permanent membership.</p>

<p>He met Sergio Franca, the permanent representative of another G4 member, Brazil, who took over the presidency of the G20 group from India last year.</p>

<p>Osama Abdelkhalek, the permanent representative of Egypt which has a role in the Gaza peace process, also had a meeting with Harish and they “agreed to work closely in the UN”, according to an Indian Mission post on X.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/p0oocisg_parvathaneni-harish-antonio-guterres-twitter_625x300_10_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/rahul-gandhi-in-us-rahul-gandhis-thali-chawal-dal-sabji-attack-on-rss-in-us-6530003]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Rahul Gandhi's "Thali, Chawal, Dal, Sabji" Attack On RSS In US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/rahul-gandhi-in-us-rahul-gandhis-thali-chawal-dal-sabji-attack-on-rss-in-us-6530003]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Sep 2024 08:34:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Rahul Gandhi, took a jibe at the Bharatiya Janata Party with a veiled reference to the Rashtriya Swayamsevak Sangh (RSS) stating that the ruling party doesn't understand that the country is for everyone.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Congress leader and Leader of Opposition in Lok Sabha, Rahul Gandhi, took a jibe at the Bharatiya Janata Party with a veiled reference to the Rashtriya Swayamsevak Sangh (RSS) stating that the ruling party doesn't understand that the country is for everyone, whereas for them whose headquarters are in Nagpur, only one ideology is important.</p>

<p>Interacting with the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/rahul-gandhi-pm-narendra-modi-i-dont-hate-mr-modi-rahul-gandhis-latest-at-us-university-chat-6530361">Indian diaspora at an event</a> in Herndon, Virginia, the Congress leader made a reference to the different dishes on a food plate to highlight India's diversity. The LoP reiterated that India is a "union of states," adding that it means a union of different traditions and histories.</p>

<p>"In India, everything works together...if someone sits in front of Thali and says chawal (rice) is more important than Dal (pulses) and sabji (vegetable) is the least important, then what will happen? That's what BJP does," Rahul Gandhi said.</p>

<p>"BJP doesn't understand that this country is of everyone...India is a union. In the Constitution, it is written clearly... India that is Bharat is a union state. It means it is a union of languages, it's a union of traditions, a union of histories, music and dance...they (BJP) say it is not a union, it is different Only one ideology is important and its headquarters are in Nagpur. That is what the fight is about," he added.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/rahul-gandhi-on-indians-in-us-says-youre-bridge-between-two-nations-6529750">Rahul Gandhi further alleged that the RSS</a> believes that certain states and communities are inferior to others.</p>

<p>"The RSS is saying that certain states, languages, religions and communities are inferior to others. This is what the fight is about. We are of the opinion that... all of you have your history, tradition and language. Every single one of them is as important as any other one. What would you do if somebody told you that you cannot speak Tamil? How would you feel? How would you react? That is the ideology of the RSS -- That Tamil, Marathi, Bengali, Manipuri- are all inferior languages," he said.</p>

<p>The Congress leader said, "It ends up in the polling booth, Lok Sabha and Vidhan Sabha. But the fight is about what type of India we are going to have. Are we going to have an India where people are allowed to believe what they want to believe?... Or we are going to have an India where only few people can decide what is going to happen."</p>

<p>Rahul Gandhi is on a three-day visit to the US. In his speech at Dallas, he termed the Indian diaspora in the US a "vital bridge" between two nations and stated that Dallas has provided a "fantastic start" to his US visit.</p>

<p>Mr Gandhi, who arrived in Dallas on Sunday, interacted with students and teachers at the University of Texas. He also addressed the members of the Indian diaspora in Dallas. He also visited Washington DC.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/easgi2a8_rahul-gandhi-virginia-ani_625x300_10_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Rahul Gandhi says BJP doesn't understand that this country is of everyone.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-narendra-modis-russia-visit-former-us-secretary-of-state-says-cant-hold-loyalty-test-for-india-every-5-minutes-6529822]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[On PM Modi's Russia Trip, US Ex-Diplomat's "Can't Hold Loyalty Test" Remark]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-narendra-modis-russia-visit-former-us-secretary-of-state-says-cant-hold-loyalty-test-for-india-every-5-minutes-6529822]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Sep 2024 07:37:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former US Secretary of State Condoleezza Rice has dismissed concerns around Prime Minister Narendra Modi's Russia visit, saying that the US can't hold India to a loyalty test every five minutes.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former US Secretary of State Condoleezza Rice has dismissed concerns around Prime Minister Narendra Modi's Russia visit, saying that the US can't hold India to a loyalty test every five minutes.</p>

<p>Speaking at Indus X (India-United States Defence Acceleration Ecosystem), she categorised the India-US ties as enduring and bipartisan and stressed that whoever comes to the White House knows the importance of the relationship.</p>

<p>"Countries wish to, as India says, have strategic autonomy and I have no problem with that. But it is our (US and India's) deep interests that will ultimately lead to a stronger partnership," she added.</p>

<p>Rice, Director at the Hoover Institute at Stanford, called Russian military equipment "junk" and said PM Modi's Moscow visit won't lead to much on the defence side. This even as she indicated that the US believes it has been slow on stepping up military cooperation with India and lost some vital time and opportunity.</p>

<p>She also added that PM Modi was aware of the no-limits relationship between Chinese President Xi Jinping and his Russian counterpart Vladimir Putin and that it could pose a huge challenge to India.</p>

<p>Describing China as formidable rival for the US, Rice said the situation is graver than the Cold War since Moscow was a military giant but a technological and economic midget, whereas China has leveraged technology and is so well integrated into the global networks and supply chains that it is a tough situation to deal with.</p>

<p>Rice was instrumental in getting the Indo-US civil nuclear deal going under the George W Bush administration.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi visited both Russia and Ukraine in the last three months. He also spoke to Putin on August 27, shortly after his trip to Ukraine where he met President Volodymyr Zelensky.</p>

<p>India has asserted it will support any <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/india-to-support-any-feasible-mutually-acceptable-solution-mea-on-russia-ukraine-war-6456803">feasible and mutually acceptable solution</a> or format that could restore peace between the two warring countries. Sources have said National Security Advisor <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/nsa-ajit-doval-to-visit-moscow-for-russia-ukraine-peace-talks-sources-6516112">Ajit Doval will visit Moscow</a> this week to hold discussions aimed at resolving the Russia-Ukraine conflict.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/2ie9ca7g_pm-modi-putin_625x300_18_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/40-killed-60-injured-in-humanitarian-zone-attack-gaza-civil-defence-6529584]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[40 Killed, 60 Injured In Gaza After Israel Strikes Humanitarian Zone]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/40-killed-60-injured-in-humanitarian-zone-attack-gaza-civil-defence-6529584]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Sep 2024 07:34:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Gaza civil defence official told AFP early Tuesday that "40 martyrs and 60 injured were recovered and transferred" to nearby hospitals following an attack inside the Al-Mawasi humanitarian zone in Khan Yunis.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Gaza's civil defence agency said Tuesday that an Israeli strike on a humanitarian zone in the south of the Palestinian territory killed 40 people and wounded 60 others, with the Israeli army saying it had targeted a Hamas command centre in the area.</p>

<p>The strike hit Al-Mawasi -- in Gaza's main southern city of Khan Yunis -- which was designated a safe zone by the Israeli military early in the war, with tens of thousands of displaced Palestinians seeking refuge there.</p>

<p>However, Israel's military has occasionally carried out operations in and around the area, including a strike in July that it said killed Hamas military chief Mohammed Deif, and which Gaza health authorities said killed more than 90 people.</p>

<p>Gaza civil defence official Mohammed Al-Mughair told AFP early Tuesday that "40 martyrs and 60 injured were recovered and transferred" to nearby hospitals following the overnight strike.</p>

<p>"Our crews are still working to recover 15 missing people as a result of targeting the tents of the displaced in Mawasi, Khan Yunis," Mughair added.</p>

<p>In a separate statement, civil defence spokesman Mahmoud Basal said that people sheltering in the camp had not been warned of the strike, adding a shortage of tools and equipment was hindering rescue operations.</p>

<p>"More than 20 to 40 tents were completely damaged," he said, adding the strike left behind "three deep craters".</p>

<p>"There are entire families who disappeared under the sand in the Mawasi Khan Yunis massacre."</p>

<p>The Israeli military said in a statement early Tuesday that its aircraft had "struck significant Hamas terrorists who were operating within a command and control center embedded inside the Humanitarian Area in Khan Yunis".</p>

<p>"The terrorist organizations in the Gaza Strip continue to systematically abuse civilian and humanitarian infrastructure, including the designated Humanitarian Area, to carry out terrorist activity against the State of Israel and IDF troops," it added.</p>

<p>Hamas said in a statement on Tuesday that claims its fighters were present at the scene of the strike were "a blatant lie".</p>

<p>Over the course of the war, Israel has repeatedly accused Hamas of using civilians as human shields, an accusation the group denies.</p>

<h2><strong>Shrinking safe zone</strong></h2>

<p>Hamas's October 7 attack on Israel that sparked the war in Gaza resulted in the deaths of 1,205 people, mostly civilians, including some hostages killed in captivity, official Israeli figures show.</p>

<p>Militants seized 251 hostages during the attack, 97 of whom are still held in Gaza, including 33 the Israeli military says are dead.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory offensive in the Gaza Strip has so far killed at least 40,988 people, according to the health ministry in the Hamas-run territory.</p>

<p>The UN human rights office says most of the dead are women and children.</p>

<p>The vast majority of Gaza's 2.4 million people have been displaced at least once during nearly a year of war, according to the United Nations.</p>

<p>From 1,200 inhabitants per square kilometre before the war, the Al-Mawasi humanitarian zone now houses "between 30,000 and 34,000 people per square kilometre", and its protected area shrank from 50 square kilometres to 41, the UN has calculated.</p>

<p>The United States, Qatar and Egypt have been mediating in efforts to forge a ceasefire and hostage-prisoner exchange deal between Israel and Hamas, but talks remain stalled.</p>

<p>Hamas is demanding a complete Israeli withdrawal from Gaza as part of any deal, but Israel insists troops must remain along the Gaza-Egypt border.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/v02fk4vo_khan-yunis_625x300_08_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[More than 40,000 people have been killed in Gaza since war began between Israel and Hamas.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/rahul-gandhi-on-indians-in-us-says-youre-bridge-between-two-nations-6529750]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["These People Don't Understand India": Rahul Gandhi Attacks RSS In US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/rahul-gandhi-on-indians-in-us-says-youre-bridge-between-two-nations-6529750]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Sep 2024 07:24:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Speaking at Washington DC metro area on Monday (local time), Congress leader Rahul Gandhi said that the Indians in the US are the bridge between the two countries.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Speaking at Washington DC metro area on Monday (local time), Congress leader Rahul Gandhi said that the Indians in the US are the bridge between the two countries.</p>

<p>The Congress leader said that the Indian diaspora has two identities- that of the US and India. They can transfer the US and Indian ideas back and forth.</p>

<p>"You are the bridge between these two great unions of states. And you make us very proud because we understand that what it meant for you to come here. We understand the difficulties and struggles you faced. But when you came here, you came with humility, respect and affection... You did not say that United States is inferior to us, or that you hate the United States... You are proud of India and proud of the United States," he said.</p>

<p>The Leader of Opposition in Lok Sabha said that the Congress's message is to spread love, not hatred.</p>

<p>"As per the BJP, you cannot have two identities. You cannot be an Indian, and at the same time an American. That is what the fight is about... We are saying that don't spread hatred, spread love. Don't be arrogant, be humble. Don't disrespect people, communities, religions, traditions, languages... If you don't do this, you will never be successful... You will take American ideas and values back home and will bring Indian values, traditions and ideas to the United States. You will help both states by doing this," he said.</p>

<p>He alleged that the RSS does not understand India.</p>

<p>"And the problem is, these people don't understand India... India is called a union of states. In the Constitution it is written clearly- India, that is Bharat, is a union of states. It means it is a union of languages, traditions, histories, music, or dance," he said.</p>

<p>Rahul Gandhi alleged that the RSS believes that certain states and communities are inferior to others.</p>

<p>"The RSS is saying that certain states, languages, religions and communities are inferior to others. This is what the fight is about. We are of the opinion that... all of you have your history, tradition and language. Every single one of them is as important as any other one. What would you do if somebody told you that you cannot speak Tamil? How would you feel? How would you react? That is the ideology of the RSS- That Tamil, Marathi, Bengali, Manipuri- are all inferior languages. It ends up in the polling booth, Lok Sabha and Vidhan Sabha. But the fight is about what type of India we are going to have. Are we going to have an India where people are allowed to believe what they want to believe?... Or we are going to have an India where only few people can decide what is going to happen," the Congress leader said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/lskl7er_rahul-gandhi-us-ani_625x300_10_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Rahul Gandhi said that the Congress's message is to spread love, not hatred.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/marie-alvarado-gil-chad-condit-us-senator-who-forced-aide-to-perform-oral-sex-rallied-against-sexual-abuse-6529782]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["End Sexual Violence," Said US Senator Accused Of Forcing Aide Into Oral Sex]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/marie-alvarado-gil-chad-condit-us-senator-who-forced-aide-to-perform-oral-sex-rallied-against-sexual-abuse-6529782]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Sep 2024 07:22:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A US woman senator, who has been accused of forcing her former chief of staff to perform sexual acts on her, had introduced a bill against sexual assault in the California Senate just months after firing him for allegedly refusing her advances.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A US woman senator, who has been accused of forcing her former chief of staff to perform sexual acts on her, had introduced a bill against sexual assault in the California Senate just months after firing him for allegedly refusing her advances.</p>

<p>In a video posted on X, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/california-state-senator-used-her-male-chief-of-staff-as-sex-slave-claims-lawsuit-6526899">Senator Marie Alvarado-Gil </a>talked of the prevalence of sexual assault and violence in the US while seeking support for her bill.</p>

<p>"April is National #SexualAssaultAwarenessMonth, and I am leading the charge with Senate Bill 268 - my bill will address a critical gap in the state's criminal justice system by reclassifying the rape of an intoxicated person as a violent felony," she wrote.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">April is National <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/SexualAssaultAwarenessMonth?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#SexualAssaultAwarenessMonth</a>, and I am leading the charge with Senate Bill 268 – my bill will address a critical gap in the state's criminal justice system by reclassifying the rape of an intoxicated person as a violent felony. DETAILS: <a href="https://t.co/5jKLIaXlYG">https://t.co/5jKLIaXlYG</a> <a href="https://t.co/p5pNC92PXS">pic.twitter.com/p5pNC92PXS</a></p>
— Senator Marie Alvarado-Gil (@AlvaradoGilSD4) <a href="https://twitter.com/AlvaradoGilSD4/status/1778826051487207653?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 12, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>In the video, Alvarado-Gil said an American is sexually assaulted every 73 seconds and the crime affects people of all genders and sexuality.</p>

<p>"If you or someone you know has been sexually assaulted, please know that it is not your fault," she said in the video, asking citizens to help "end sexual violence".</p>

<p>The bill which sought to make rape of an intoxicated person a violent felony and sought stricter punishment for sex crimes was passed in the senate on August 31.</p>

<h2><strong>"Sexual quid pro quo"</strong></h2>

<p>Alvarado-Gil's former chief of staff, Chad Condit, has alleged that she maintained a "sexual quid pro quo relationship" with him that left him injured in the back and hip.</p>

<p>Mr Condit started working for Alvarado-Gil when she contested for Senate in 2022 and was appointed chief of staff when she was elected.</p>

<p>He alleged that the senator pressured him into performing sex acts on her while they went on work trips over the years to protect his job.</p>

<p>On one such occasion last year, Condit alleges, he suffered a severe back injury when he was forced to "twist and contort" as he performed oral sex on her in a car. The act left him with three herniated discs and a collapsed hip, the suit alleges.</p>

<p>When Alvarado-Gil continued to seek sexual favours, he used the back injury as an excuse to reject her advances which made her retaliate, he alleges. She issued a disciplinary letter that accused him of inappropriate behavior.</p>

<h2><strong>"Erratic, controlling" boss</strong></h2>

<p>After he repeatedly turned down her sexual advances, Condit alleges he was fired in December. He told her he was undergoing back surgery for the injuries he sustained, he added.</p>

<p>"This was a sex-based quid pro quo relationship of unwelcome advances and sexual behaviors coupled with punishment and flexing of power," he says in the lawsuit.</p>

<p>In the lawsuit, Mr Condit details his harrowing ordeal trying to navigate a professional relationship marred by "sexually dominating abuse of authority and power" by an "erratic" and "controlling" boss.</p>

<p>Alvardo-Gil's lawyer has rubbished the allegations and hit back at the former aide, calling him "disgruntled".</p>

<p>"A disgruntled former employee has fabricated an outlandish story, presented without evidence, to get a payday. We expect that the senator will be fully cleared of any wrongdoing of these bogus, financially motivated claims," he told the New York Post.</p>

<p>Alvarado-Gil made the switch from her Democratic party to the Republican party last month after claiming that the party had become unrecognisable under its current leadership.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/s4m22ubo_marie-alvaradogil_625x300_10_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hollywood-mourns-actor-james-earl-jones-voice-of-darth-vader-6529723]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["RIP Dad": Hollywood Mourns James Earl Jones, Voice Of 'Darth Vader']]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hollywood-mourns-actor-james-earl-jones-voice-of-darth-vader-6529723]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Sep 2024 06:42:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Stars of the screen are mourning the death of James Earl Jones, the voice of "Star Wars" villain Darth Vader, on Monday at the age of 93.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Stars of the screen are mourning the death of James Earl Jones, the voice of "Star Wars" villain Darth Vader, on Monday at the age of 93.</p>

<p>Jones, who also voiced King Mufasa in Disney's animated feature "The Lion King," had a prolific and varied career.</p>

<p>Over six decades he worked with some of the greatest figures in cinema and theater, including Stanley Kubrick in his 1964 Cold War satire "Dr Strangelove."</p>

<p>He also had roles in the Arnold Schwarzenegger film "Conan The Barbarian" and the 1989 Kevin Costner movie "Field of Dreams."</p>

<p>But it was for his role as one of cinema's most famous villains that he became most widely known.</p>

<p>While Darth Vader's immense physicality was the result of the towering British actor David Prowse, the sinister voice that appeared to emanate from inside the reconstructed man-in-a-mask was that of Jones.</p>

<p>And it was Jones who gave the "Star Wars" franchise some of its most memorable lines, including when he reveals to Luke Skywalker –- played by a young Mark Hamill -– "I am your father."</p>

<p>Hamill took to social media on Monday to share news of Jones' death, writing simply: "#RIP dad" with a broken heart emoji.</p>

<p>"Rustin" star Coleman Domingo wrote on social media that Jones was "a master of our craft."</p>

<p>"We stand on your shoulders. Rest now. You gave us your best."</p>

<p>Lydia Cornell, whose 1982 debut "Bloodtide," was opposite Jones, said: "Oh no!! I can't believe it!! I thought he was going to live forever."</p>

<p>"Adored working with him. Such a generous spirit, and so humble. Taught me the power of stillness and using my voice."</p>

<p>"Selma" Director Ava DuVernay posted images of Jones, accompanied by a heartfelt message.</p>

<p>"Thank you for showing us ourselves. Our complicated selves, our dignified selves, our smiles, our pain. A job well done. A gift beautifully shared. Bless you as you journey on."</p>

<p>Alongside a clip of Jones' 1974 film, "Claudine," she urged fans to seek it out if they have never seen it.</p>

<p>"Mr. Jones crying in a scene of this film is one of the most exquisite cinematic images of a Black man I've ever seen. Don't miss it. He gave us so much," she wrote.</p>

<p>"The Help" star Octavia Spencer posted a black and white photograph of Jones, alongside a tribute that nodded to his indelible role in "Star Wars."</p>

<p>"Legendary doesn't even begin to describe his iconic roles and impact on cinema forever," she wrote.</p>

<p>"His voice and talent will be remembered always. Sending love to his family, friends and countless fans in all the galaxies, far, far away."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/gom709sc_james-earl_625x300_10_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Over six decades James Earl Jones worked with some of the greatest figures in cinema and theater.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/james-earl-jones-voice-of-darth-vader-king-mufasa-dies-at-93-6529696]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[James Earl Jones, Voice Of 'Darth Vader', 'King Mufasa', Dies At 93]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/james-earl-jones-voice-of-darth-vader-king-mufasa-dies-at-93-6529696]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Sep 2024 06:35:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[James Earl Jones, the actor whose rich baritone provided the voice for "Star Wars" villain Darth Vader, has died at age 93, his representatives said Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>James Earl Jones, the actor whose rich baritone provided the voice for "Star Wars" villain Darth Vader, has died at age 93, his representatives said Monday.</p>

<p>Jones, who also voiced King Mufasa in Disney's animated feature "The Lion King," had a prolific and varied career.</p>

<p>Over six decades he worked with some of the greatest figures in cinema and theater, including Stanley Kubrick in his 1964 Cold War satire "Dr Strangelove."</p>

<p>He also had roles in the Arnold Schwarzenegger film "Conan The Barbarian" and the 1989 Kevin Costner movie "Field of Dreams."</p>

<p>But it was for his role as one of cinema's most famous villains that he became most widely known.</p>

<p>While Darth Vader's immense physicality was the result of the towering British actor David Prowse, the sinister voice that appeared to emanate from inside the reconstructed man-in-a-mask was Jones.</p>

<p>And it was Jones who gave the "Star Wars" franchise some of its most memorable lines, including when he reveals to Luke Skywalker –- played by a young Mark Hamill -– "I am your father."</p>

<p>Hamill took to social media on Monday to share news of Jones' death, writing simply: " #Rip dad" with a broken heart emoji.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/6o6ek94s_james-earl_625x300_10_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[James Earl Jones has died at age 93.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>