<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 20:18:14 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/reuven-azar-israel-hamas-hezbollah-ndtv-world-summit-right-and-duty-to-retaliate-says-israeli-envoy-on-irans-attack-6840842]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Right And Duty To Retaliate": Israeli Envoy To India On Iran's Attack]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/reuven-azar-israel-hamas-hezbollah-ndtv-world-summit-right-and-duty-to-retaliate-says-israeli-envoy-on-irans-attack-6840842]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 20:18:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel has a right and duty to retaliate after Iran fired at least 180 missiles at it on October 1, the country's Ambassador to India, Reuven Azar, has said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel has a right and duty to retaliate after Iran fired at least 180 missiles at it on October 1, the country's Ambassador to India, Reuven Azar, has said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In an interview during the NDTV World Summit on Monday, Mr Azar said Israel is keen on peace and stability in the region but it cannot have a situation where Iran is free to attack whenever it likes.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Mr Azar also said that, as a rising power, India has a substantial role to play in the Middle East and its importance will only increase every year.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Asked about reports stating that Israel could respond to the Iranian attack before elections are held in the US - which is its most important ally -&nbsp; on November 5, the ambassador said, "The US elections are not a factor. What is a factor is that we have not only a right but a duty to retaliate. Imagine a situation in which a country like Iran is capable of threatening any country in the region without any repercussions... this is completely unacceptable."</p>

<p>Mr Azar said Israel wants to promote stability in the region and it is doing that with its peace agreements with Jordan and Egypt, the Abraham Accords with the UAE, Bahrain, Morocco and Sudan, and dialogue with Saudi Arabia.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"We have proved after the attack by Iran that we are capable of defending the skies of the Middle East from the Iranian threat, but we cannot be in a situation in which the Iranians feel free to attack us at any point. This is why the security building block has to be complemented by our retaliation," he said.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>'Neutralised Missile Threat'</strong></p>

<p>On the killing of leaders like Hamas chief Yahya Sinwar and the fact that the outfit has regrouped in the past, Mr Azar said the situation is very different now.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"What we have managed to achieve in the Gaza Strip right now is that we have defeated the terrorist army of Hamas in a way that they cannot pose a missile threat to Israel. We have destroyed their missile factories. We have sealed the border between the Gaza Strip and the Sinai, so it will be much more difficult to re-arm," he said.</p>

<p>The ambassador admitted that they have not been able to bring back all the hostages from the October 7, 2023, attack and remove Hamas from government. The latter, he said, is being worked on by finding a way to distribute assistance to the population in Gaza so that Hamas cannot hold them hostage.</p>

<p>The balance, the ambassador claimed, is changing in Israel's favour in its conflicts with Hamas and Hezbollah.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Indian Century</strong></p>

<p>Asked about India's role in West Asia and in ending the conflicts, Mr Azar said the country will contribute a lot to the region and the world.</p>

<p>"India is a rising power. I was looking at the data and I saw that in the next year, when India grows by seven per cent, it will grow by $260 billion... our (Israel's) economy is $600 billion. So what India has to contribute to the world is huge. It is going to be a powerhouse, a manufacturing hub, and it needs to be connected to the world. It has a lot to offer to countries in West Asia. I have seen how India is increasing its links with the UAE," he noted.</p>

<p>The envoy added, "When all this infrastructure of connectivity is set, we are going to see an incredible role of India in our region. It won't be just about merchandise, it will be about manufacturing... We depend on the goodwill of India, on the investments of India, on our cooperation with India and that role is going to increase every year."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/1qec30h_reuven-azar_625x300_21_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mr Azar also said India has a substantial role to play in the Middle East.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/truly-historic-egypt-certified-malaria-free-by-who-after-100-year-effort-6840771]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Truly Historic": Egypt Certified Malaria-Free By WHO After 100-Year Effort]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/truly-historic-egypt-certified-malaria-free-by-who-after-100-year-effort-6840771]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 20:09:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In the 1940s, malaria cases in Egypt surged to over three million due to population displacement during World War II.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Egypt has officially been declared malaria-free, with the World Health Organization (WHO) hailing the achievement as "truly historic" after nearly a century of dedicated efforts to eradicate the disease, the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cm2yl8pjgn2o" rel="nofollow, noindex"><em>BBC </em></a>reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Malaria is as old as Egyptian civilization itself, but the disease that plagued the pharaohs now belongs to its history," said WHO Director-General Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus.</p>

<p>Egypt began its fight against the mosquito-borne infectious disease almost 100 years ago. Certification is awarded when a country can prove it has interrupted the transmission of malaria for at least three consecutive years. Malaria still claims the lives of at least 600,000 people annually, the vast majority of whom are in Africa.</p>

<p>In its statement, the WHO commended "the Egyptian government and people" for their successful efforts to "end a disease that has been present in the country since ancient times."</p>

<p>Egypt is now the third country in the WHO's Eastern Mediterranean Region to receive this certification, following the United Arab Emirates and Morocco. Globally, a total of 44 countries and one territory have reached this milestone.</p>

<p>The WHO emphasized that this certification marks "the beginning of a new phase," urging Egypt to remain vigilant in order to maintain its malaria-free status.</p>

<p>For certification, a country must demonstrate its ability to prevent the re-establishment of malaria transmission. The WHO highlighted that Egypt's initial attempts to reduce human-mosquito contact began in the 1920s by restricting rice cultivation and other agricultural crops near residential areas.</p>

<p>Malaria, caused by a parasite transmitted through mosquito bites, has seen progress in control efforts, with vaccines now being deployed in some regions. However, monitoring the disease and preventing mosquito bites remain the most effective preventive measures.</p>

<p>"Receiving the malaria elimination certificate today is not the end of the journey but the beginning of a new phase," said Egypt's Health Minister, Khaled Abdel Ghaffar. "We must now work tirelessly and vigilantly to sustain our achievement through maintaining the highest standards for surveillance, diagnosis, and treatment."</p>

<p>In the 1940s, malaria cases in Egypt surged to over three million due to population displacement during World War II. The construction of the Aswan Dam in the 1960s also increased malaria risks by creating mosquito breeding grounds through standing water. However, by 2001, Egypt had brought malaria "firmly under control," according to the WHO.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Nigeria continues to bear the highest malaria burden, accounting for more than a quarter of all malaria deaths globally, followed by the Democratic Republic of Congo, Uganda, and Mozambique.<br />
&nbsp;</p>

<p><br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/k7qbgqbg_mosquito-_625x300_21_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Egypt is now the third country in the WHO's Eastern Mediterranean Region]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-woman-jailed-for-fatally-poisoning-boyfriend-over-false-30-million-inheritance-6840453]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Woman Jailed For Poisoning Boyfriend Over False $30 Million Inheritance]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-woman-jailed-for-fatally-poisoning-boyfriend-over-false-30-million-inheritance-6840453]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 19:21:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[State District Judge Richard Hagar sentenced Kenoyer to 25 years in prison last Wednesday after she pleaded guilty in May.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A North Dakota woman, Ina Thea Kenoyer, 48, has been sentenced to 25 years in prison for poisoning her boyfriend, Steven Riley Jr., 51, after mistakenly believing he had inherited $30 million and planned to break up with her. Riley died last year from ethylene glycol poisoning, a toxic substance commonly found in antifreeze, the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/10/20/us-news/woman-sentenced-to-25-years-for-poisoning-boyfriend-when-thinking-she-inherited-30-million/" rel="nofollow, noindex"><em>New York Post </em></a>reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>During the court hearing in Minot, Stephanie Gonzalez, Riley's sister, confronted Kenoyer, telling her she was fortunate to receive such a lenient sentence, as reported by <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.kxnet.com/video/ina-kenoyer-sentencing/10137085/" rel="nofollow, noindex"><em>KXMB</em></a>. "As so many other families of victims often feel, the punishment should fit the crime," Gonzalez said to Kenoyer. "But lucky for you, the Department of Corrections doesn't serve antifreeze in your iced tea."</p>

<p>State District Judge Richard Hagar sentenced Kenoyer to 25 years in prison last Wednesday after she pleaded guilty in May. In addition to her prison term, Kenoyer received 10 years of supervised probation and was ordered to pay $3,455 in restitution to Riley's family, according to court records.</p>

<p>However, it appears there was never any inheritance at all. Officials revealed that Kenoyer poisoned Riley just hours after discovering an email he had received, claiming he would inherit $30 million.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Ryan Riley, the victim's 21-year-old son, later told The Post that both his father and Kenoyer had fallen victim to an online scam, and no such inheritance actually existed.</p>

<p>On September 3, 2023, while meeting with the supposed estate lawyer, Riley began to feel unwell. Paramedics were called to his home the next day, where they found him unresponsive. He was pronounced dead on September 5.</p>

<p>Kenoyer initially told police that Riley had been drinking heavily and suffered from heat stroke in the days leading up to his death, according to the affidavit. She also claimed that she planned to split Riley's alleged inheritance with his son, asserting that she was entitled to a share as his common-law wife. However, North Dakota does not recognize common-law marriages.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/qk4mhsj8_ina-thea-kenoyer_625x300_21_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kenoyer initially told police that Riley had been drinking heavily]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/idea-of-giving-back-to-society-dates-back-to-ancient-times-m3ms-payal-kanodiya-6840402]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA['Idea Of Giving Back To Society Dates Back To Ancient Times': M3M's Payal Kanodiya]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/idea-of-giving-back-to-society-dates-back-to-ancient-times-m3ms-payal-kanodiya-6840402]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 19:14:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The idea of giving back to society dates back to ancient times, M3M Foundation'sChairperson and TrusteePayal Kanodia said while listing the various initiatives undertaken by her organisation.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The idea of giving back to society dates back to ancient times, M3M Foundation's&nbsp;Chairperson and Trustee&nbsp;Payal Kanodia said while listing the various initiatives undertaken by her organisation.</p>

<p>Speaking at NDTV World Summit 2024, Ms Kanodia said Sarvodaya, a program that looks at integrated village development, covers 82 villages in Haryana's Nuh. It looks at building smart villages, holding people responsible for developing their areas and starting initiatives. She also listed other programs that look at holistic development of underprivileged families, education, art, literature, sports and&nbsp;scholarships to children who want to establish enterprises in social sector.</p>

<p>Another initiative Van Jeevan was developed with the aim of protecting an entire ecosystem.&nbsp;The first project started at Tipeshwar santuary near Nagpur, when local people were roped in to install solar water pumps after reports of tigers suffering in the heat. It then expanded to&nbsp;Koluchur near to Jim Corbett and will now be taken to Pilibhit.</p>

<p>Ms Kanodia said her organisation designs projects that empowers communities to lead. She added that more public-private partnership is needed to allow best use of government initiatives.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/r4oa6ido_payal-kanodiya_625x300_21_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/believe-in-economic-policies-of-this-government-pernod-ricard-india-official-prasanna-mohile-to-ndtv-6840216]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Believe In Economic Policies Of This Government": Pernod Ricard India Official To NDTV]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/believe-in-economic-policies-of-this-government-pernod-ricard-india-official-prasanna-mohile-to-ndtv-6840216]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 18:49:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Pernod Ricard India has faith in the economic policies of the government led by Narendra Modi and that is why it is going ahead with its expansion and investment plans here, its top official told NDTV.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pernod Ricard India, which began its operations three decades ago in the country, has faith in the economic policies of the government led by Narendra Modi and that is why it is going ahead with its expansion and investment plans here, its top official told NDTV on Monday.</p>

<p>"We have partnered with Indian growth story for last three decades. And we have grown right after the liberalisation era began. Out of these 30 years, last 10 years we have seen a quite stable policies of the government. There was stability in economic policies," said Prasanna Mohile, National Head, Corporate Affairs, Pernod Ricard India, speaking at NDTV World Summit.</p>

<p>Pernod India is known for its scotch brand 100 Pipers and Indian-made foreign liquor brands Blenders Pride and Royal Stag.</p>

<p>"Today we have 25 manufacturing facilities across India, and we have been exporting to 50 plus countries. We also have plans to invest further in this country looking at the way the economy of this country is growing. For Pernod, India is the second largest market after the US in the world," said Mr Mohile.</p>

<p>"We believe in the economic policies of this government and that is why we are going ahead with &nbsp;all our expansion and investment plans," said Mr Mohile.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Underlining that sustainability is at the company's core and its values and operations, Mr Mohile said it sticks to the mantra of 3Ts: Talent, training and transformation.</p>

<p>"Until and unless we don't touch the roots of rural India, and the corporates do not take this responsibility, the real Viksit Bharat will not come through. That is also one of the initiatives of Pernod. We decided that we will go to remotest areas, teach them sustainable farming, we upskill them with the required skills. My plan is we might tomorrow think of farmers' federation there from where we can have the entire supply chain," said Mr Mohile, adding that the company will establish a malt distillery and maturation facility in Nagpur in Maharashtra.</p>

<p>"We always have this glocal approach wherein we basically try and blend the thing with the local resources," said Mr Mohile.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/18r8jnmg_prasanna-mohile-_625x300_21_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Prasanna Mohile, National Head, Corporate Affairs, Pernod Ricard India, at NDTV World Summit]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-china-ties-no-direct-flights-ban-on-apps-areas-hit-by-indias-strained-ties-with-china-6840004]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[No Direct Flights, Ban On Apps: Areas Hit By India-China's Strained Ties]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-china-ties-no-direct-flights-ban-on-apps-areas-hit-by-indias-strained-ties-with-china-6840004]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 18:26:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India and China have reached a deal on patrolling their disputed Himalayan frontier, aiming to resolve a fouryear military standoff, Indian Foreign Secretary Vikram Misri said]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India and China have reached a deal on patrolling the Himalayan frontier, aiming to resolve a four-year military stand-off, Indian Foreign Secretary Vikram Misri said on Monday.</p>

<p>The two nuclear-armed neighbours have had tense relations since their troops clashed in 2020.</p>

<p>Here are some areas affected by India's strained ties with China since then:</p>

<p><strong>NO DIRECT FLIGHTS</strong></p>

<p>The two countries have not had any direct flights for four years. China has been pressing India to restart direct passenger flights and India's aviation minister said last month the two countries discussed an early resumption of scheduled passenger flights.</p>

<p><strong>VISA RULES FOR CHINESE TECHNICIANS</strong></p>

<p>India increased scrutiny for visa applications from Chinese citizens in the wake of the border clashes. This hurt some of India's key manufacturing firms as stricter visa rules meant specialised engineers from China could not enter the country, leading to production losses.</p>

<p>After industry complaints, India recently decided to speed up processing of visas for Chinese technicians.</p>

<p><strong>NEW INVESTMENT VETTING RULES</strong></p>

<p>In 2020, India stepped up scrutiny of investments from companies based in neighbouring countries by adding an extra layer of vetting and security clearances, in what was widely seen as a move to stave off takeovers and investments by Chinese firms.&nbsp;</p>

<p>It has led to billions of dollars in proposed investment getting stuck in the approval process over the last four years, including the stalling or shelving of investment worth billions from companies like BYD and Great Wall Motor.</p>

<p><strong>MOBILE APPS BAN</strong></p>

<p>Citing data and privacy issues, India has banned about 300 Chinese mobile apps including popular ones such as the battle-royale format game from Krafton Inc, a South Korean company backed by China's Tencent.</p>

<p><strong>XIAOMI ASSET FREEZE</strong></p>

<p>Indian authorities last year accused Chinese smartphone company Vivo Communication Technology of breaching some visa rules and alleged it siphoned $13 billion in funds.</p>

<p>India has frozen more than $600 million in Xiaomi assets for alleged illegal remittances to foreign entities, accusing the company of passing them off as royalty payments.</p>

<p>Both Chinese companies deny any wrongdoing.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2018-04/india-china-flags_650x400_61523324939.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[China and India have not had any direct flights for four years. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ndtv-world-summit-s-jaishankar-explains-why-russia-will-remain-indias-strategic-partner-6839984]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[S Jaishankar Explains Why Russia Will Remain India's Strategic Partner]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ndtv-world-summit-s-jaishankar-explains-why-russia-will-remain-indias-strategic-partner-6839984]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 18:23:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[S Jaishankar today spoke about 'The India Century' at the NDTV World Summit in New Delhi. During the interaction Mr Jaishankar gave a detailed overview on India's foreign policy and how it is playing an increasingly global role.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar today spoke about 'The India Century' at the NDTV World Summit in New Delhi. During the interaction Mr Jaishankar gave a detailed overview on India's foreign policy and how it is playing an increasingly global role.</p>

<p>Speaking exclusively to NDTV World, Mr Jaishankar discussed the entire gamut of ties - from the US and China to Russia and India's neighbourhood. He even spoke a few lines about Pakistan.</p>

<p>When asked about the Russia relationship, the foreign minister made it absolutely clear that India's relationship with Russia is time-tested and among the most important. Explaining his point he said, "I'll put it to you very simply. If you look at our history with the Soviet Union and subsequently Russia since Independence in 1947, I can say with confidence and knowing that nobody in this room can contradict it, that Russia has never done anything to impact India's interest negatively," adding that in geopolitics, "that is a big statement to make because there are not many major countries in the world for whom such a statement can be made."</p>

<p>He further told NDTV World that "Today, Russia's situation is different and Russia's relationship with the West has broken down. We now have a Russia which is turning much more towards Asia (than Europe and the West), so we must ask ourselves that if Russia is looking more at Asia, should Russia not have multiple options in Asia? And as an Asian country, should we (India) not do in Asia that which is in our national interest?"</p>

<p>"Clearly, Russia as a major natural resources power has a complementarity with India at this stage of development when we are big resource consumers. People talk about Russian oil, but it isn;t just about oil. It could be about fertilizers, metal, coal, etc. So, there is a big economic logic to it as well," Mr Jaishankar added.</p>

<p>Mr Jaishankar went on to say that besides an economic relationship, there is also a strategic one. He explained that "There is a basic strategic logic - that if you look at the Eurasian landmass, there are 3 big countries (Russia, China and India). It is a one-o-one in international relations, that a country will always maintain the balance in relationship with the country which is your immediate neighbour's neighbour - and do so in very good stead."</p>

<p>"So, there is a strategic logic, there is an economic fit, and the relationship overall has had a very positive history, so that is how it is viewed," Mr Jaishankar reiterated.</p>

<h2><strong>BREAKTHROUGH WITH CHINA</strong></h2>

<p>Mr Jaishankar today added to what India's foreign secretary said earlier in the day about a "positive outcome" emerging from the standoff with China along the Line of Actual Control, saying Indian and Chinese soldiers will be able to resume patrolling in the way they had been doing before the border face-off began in May 2020.</p>

<p>Foreign Secretary Vikram Misri announced India and China have arrived on a patrolling arrangement along the Line of Actual Control (LAC) in the Himalayas, and it can lead to disengagement and resolution of tension.</p>

<p>"We reached an agreement on patrolling, and we have gone back to the 2020 position. With that we can say the disengagement with China has been completed. Details will come out in due course," Mr Jaishankar told NDTV World.</p>

<p>"There are areas which for various reasons after 2020, they blocked us, we blocked them. We have now reached an understanding which will allow patrolling as we had been doing till 2020," Mr Jaishankar explained.</p>

<p>The breakthrough came ahead of Prime Minister Narendra Modi's visit to Russia to attend the BRICS summit tomorrow.</p>

<h3><strong>INDIA'S NEIGHBOURHOOD FIRST POLICY</strong></h3>

<p>Speaking about how India's highest priority has always been about fostering good relations with its neighbours, Mr Jaishanakr emphasised that New Delhi has always played a positive and friendly part towards its neighbours.</p>

<p>Citing the examples of Sri Lanka, Bhutan, and even Maldives and Bangladesh, the foreign minister gave examples of how India has always tried to build a neighbourhood of cooperation and camaraderie.</p>

<p>Explaining this, Mr Jaishankar said "Our neighbourhood is democratic which means that political changes will keep on happening. We will often be the subject of their politics. We have to factor in that in our policies. If we can create a record of being a country which is a reliable friend in any trouble, if they understand that there's this country India which is generous, which is large, if we create that record and which I feel we have. During Sri Lanka crisis, we stepped up. Today in Sri Lanka, we have seen a very big change," said S Jaishankar.</p>

<p>"Bhutan had the wisdom to collaborate on electricity. This is a lesson which everyone should learn," he said praising the country.</p>

<h3><strong>THE 'JUSTIN TRUDEAU' PROBLEM</strong></h3>

<p>Speaking about ties with Canada, Mr Jaishankar said the Justin Trudeau government seems to have a problem with Indian diplomats trying to find out about what is happening there in relation to India.</p>

<p>Highlighting the Trudeau government's "double standards" and stressing that saying so is an understatement, Mr Jaishankar said they seem to have different standards for how they behave domestically and how they behave globally.</p>

<p>"Canada has asked us to subject our High Commissioner to a police inquiry and we chose to withdraw our High Commissioner... They seem to have a problem with our diplomats trying to find out about what is happening in Canada which directly pertain to their welfare and security," he said.</p>

<p>On the other hand, the license they give themselves is "totally different from the restrictions they impose on diplomats in Canada," he said. "Canadian diplomats have no problem going around on our military or our police, profiling people, targeting people to be stopped in Canada," he added.</p>

<p>"When we tell them that you have people openly threatening Indian leaders and diplomats, their response is freedom of speech... If you threaten the Indian High Commissioner, he is supposed to accept it as freedom of speech but if an Indian journalist says the Canadian High Commissioner walked out of the South Block looking very grumpy, it is apparently foreign interference," he added.</p>

<h3><strong>VISIT TO PAKISTAN</strong></h3>

<p>Towards the end of his interaction at the NDTV World Summit, Mr Jaishankar spoke a line about Pakistan. "India is a good SCO member. We were very supportive of Pakistan's presidency this year and wanted the proceeding to be smooth. Haath milaya aur aa gaye wapis (shook hands and came back)," he said summing up his visit to Islamabad.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/38l4dd4_s-jaishankar_625x300_21_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[S Jaishankar today spoke about India's foreign policy at the NDTV World Summit in New Delhi]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jennifer-garner-julia-roberts-hollywood-stars-support-kamala-harris-6839773]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Jennifer Garner, Julia Roberts - Hollywood Stars Support Kamala Harris]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jennifer-garner-julia-roberts-hollywood-stars-support-kamala-harris-6839773]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 17:59:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Actor Jennifer Garner had a warning for a crowd of "Moms for Harris" gathered at a tearoom in Tucson, Arizona: Be prepared to see more Hollywood stars visiting your state to talk about the November 5 election.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Actor Jennifer Garner had a warning for a crowd of "Moms for Harris" gathered at a tearoom in Tucson, Arizona: Be prepared to see more Hollywood stars visiting your state to talk about the November 5 election.</p>

<p>"Jessica Alba, Kerry Washington - my colleagues and friends - will be here tomorrow. We're all just going to barnstorm you and drive you nuts," Garner said with a smile.</p>

<p>"I'm sure everything is a nightmare. You don't even want to turn on the TV," Garner said to laughter. "That being said, it really is that important."</p>

<p>The "Alias" star was acknowledging the text messages, TV ads, canvassing and other efforts in one of the seven battleground states that will decide whether Democrat Kamala Harris or Republican Donald Trump becomes the next US president.</p>

<p>Celebrity endorsers such as Garner are part of the down-to-the-wire blitz to mobilize voters ahead of Election Day on November 5. A week after her Arizona stop, Garner stumped for Vice President Harris in Pennsylvania and had plans to visit Nevada.</p>

<p>When stars want to campaign, political strategists urge them to visit places where they have a personal connection and to talk about issues they have worked on. They also are pairing them with political heavyweights.</p>

<p>In Garner's case, she joined former policy adviser and Ambassador Susan Rice, and the actor talked about how her parents met in Arizona. A board member for Save the Children, Garner touted Harris' support for child tax credits and higher pay for child-care workers.</p>

<p>Julia Roberts, meanwhile, visited her home state of Georgia and was introduced by former state Representative Stacey Abrams.</p>

<p>Actor Jane Fonda, an advocate for action on climate change, knocked on doors in Michigan to tout Harris and other "climate champions." The Oscar winner and longtime political activist said she had never campaigned door-to-door for a president before.</p>

<p>"I'm doing everything I can," Fonda told one potential voter. "We have to get them elected."</p>

<p>While Hollywood has a reputation for being liberal, some stars are working to turn out the vote for former President Trump. Dennis Quaid, who starred in a recent movie as Republican icon Ronald Reagan, spoke at a Trump rally in California.</p>

<p>"I'm here to tell you that it's time to pick a side," Quaid said to applause.</p>

<p>Other Trump supporters from the entertainment world include musicians Ted Nugent and Kid Rock, and wrestler Hulk Hogan, who spoke at this summer's Republican National Convention.</p>

<p><strong>HELPING OR HURTING?</strong></p>

<p>Will Garner, Quaid or any other movie star make a difference?</p>

<p>Celebrity appearances do amplify messages about voting, said Christian Grose, a political science professor and academic director at the University of Southern California's Schwarzenegger Institute.</p>

<p>If a non-famous person knocks on a door, it affects only that voter. When a celebrity does, it generates media coverage and social media posts that reach beyond that home, Grose said.</p>

<p>Whether that translates into higher turnout depends on the celebrity and the circumstances.</p>

<p>Megastars such as Oprah Winfrey can make a meaningful impact. Winfrey's 2007 endorsement of Barack Obama was credited with driving 1 million votes during the Democratic primary.</p>

<p>And pop megastar Taylor Swift stimulated thousands of new voter registrations with a nonpartisan call for people to register in 2023, according to the nonprofit group Vote.org.</p>

<p>This September, Swift went a step further and endorsed Harris via an Instagram post, which has now received more than 11 million likes.</p>

<p>While the Harris campaign welcomed Swift's support, it may not turn out to be a blessing, according to Mark Harvey, author of "Celebrity Influence: Politics, Persuasion, and Issue-Based Advocacy," published in 2018.</p>

<p>Harvey and other researchers surveyed 1,000 people in August, before Swift's endorsement. Half were shown a photo of Swift with a generic message urging people to vote and half were shown the same image urging votes for Democrats.</p>

<p>In the study, the singer was most influential with undecided voters who were Swift fans. Swifties who saw the general message reported a high likelihood of heading to the polls. The intent to vote declined, however, among the Swift fans who saw the singer calling for ballots for Democrats.</p>

<p>"I think there are a lot people who don't want to mix their entertainment with their politics," said Harvey, an associate professor at the University of Saint Mary in Kansas.</p>

<p>And outside of the elite sphere of the biggest celebrities, studies suggest celebrity endorsements have "no effect to marginal effect" on turnout, Grose said.</p>

<p>Still, it is possible that the presidential race, and some races for the U.S. Congress could be decided by hundreds or thousands of votes.</p>

<p>"I wouldn't put it up there as the most critical part of the campaign," Grose said, "but you certainly can mobilize people with enthusiasm and excitement and a little bit of Hollywood pizzazz showing up in places you wouldn't expect."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/vkefagb_us-election-julia-robers_625x300_21_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Julia Roberts speaks virtually during a campaign event for Kamala Harris. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/have-to-protect-society-from-ai-sunil-bharti-mittal-at-ndtv-world-summit-6839752]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Have To Protect Society From AI": Sunil Bharti Mittal At NDTV World Summit]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/have-to-protect-society-from-ai-sunil-bharti-mittal-at-ndtv-world-summit-6839752]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 17:56:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence (AI) will be among the most important drivers of the world economy and geopolitics in times to come, Bharti Group Chairman Sunil Mittal said on Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Artificial Intelligence (AI) will be among the most important drivers of the world economy and geopolitics in times to come, Bharti Group Chairman Sunil Mittal said on Monday but cautioned that the new technology will pose new challenges, including potential for misuse and hence require greater vigilance and guardrails.</p>

<p>Speaking at the NDTV World Summit, the telecom doyen who helms India's second-largest telco Bharti Airtel, cited a personal anecdote on how a senior finance official stationed in Dubai received a fraudulent call that seemed to mimic Mittal's voice and tone and directed a large fund transfer.</p>

<p>The official who was vigilant and "sensible" immediately detected the fraud. Mittal admitted that when he heard the voice recording himself he was "stunned" as "it was perfectly articulated as I would speak".</p>

<p>"And anyone who would not have been vigilant may have done something about it," he said and warned that in the future misuse of technology will enable fraudsters to go a step ahead and use digital signatures, even faces on Zoom calls to perpetrate such acts.</p>

<p>"We'll have to protect our societies from the evils of AI, and yet we have to use the goodness of AI because those companies, and nations that will not adopt AI will be left behind. So this is a conundrum for every time you get a new technology into place, there are pluses and minuses. I remain very optimistic about the benefit of AI that the human race will achieve and be able to do jobs which are otherwise very difficult to perform," Mittal said.</p>

<p>Asked about the use cases he has found for AI in his own business and whether technology has indeed replaced jobs, Mittal asserted that routine, mundane, repetitive jobs are certainly going to be under "straight threat".</p>

<p>"And we are already seeing in our company, that we are making huge efficiency through the adoption of AI, which means reduction of people. But equally, new jobs are coming through," he said.</p>

<p>Elaborating, he said AI is bringing <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ndtv-world-summit-some-jobs-reduced-due-to-ai-but-sunil-bharti-mittal-at-ndtv-world-summit-6837440">changes</a> in call centre and workforce management.</p>

<p>"Just 10 years back, every time a customer had to be onboarded onto a mobile phone, there was a physical form to be filled out. There were runners on scooters and more bikes who would take those forms to a different centre. From there, they would fax it to another place...in 10 years' time, it seems like a joke today.</p>

<p>"Similarly, if you go 10 years forward, some of these repetitive jobs will disappear. But have we suffered on account of the earlier adoption of electronic media? We have not. We've added more jobs in different spaces, different parts," he said.</p>

<p>Mittal said he is hopeful there will be new ideas and new thoughts with the advent of AI, and it will create new businesses and new jobs.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2017-09/sunil-mittal-ndtv_650x400_41506497896.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sunil Mittal said at the NDTV World Summit that competitive jobs are going to be under threat.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/alexei-navalnys-yulia-navalnaya-wife-plans-political-run-after-putin-regimes-fall-report-6839670]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Alexei Navalny's Wife Plans Political Run After Putin Regime's Fall: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/alexei-navalnys-yulia-navalnaya-wife-plans-political-run-after-putin-regimes-fall-report-6839670]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 17:47:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Yulia Navalnaya, the widow of late Russian opposition leader Alexei Navalny, will return to Russia and run for political office once Vladimir Putin is no longer leader, she told the BBC in an interview aired Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yulia Navalnaya, the widow of late Russian opposition leader Alexei Navalny, will return to Russia and run for political office once Vladimir Putin is no longer leader, she told the BBC in an interview aired Monday.</p>

<p>Navalnaya, whose husband died in an Arctic prison in unclear circumstances in February following years as Putin's top political opponent, also vowed to keep up her husband's work.</p>

<p>But she said she would not be returning to Russia to do so.</p>

<p>"I want to live in Russia. I was born in Moscow, our children were born in Moscow... of course, it's not possible while Putin is in power, but I hope one day all this regime will fall and I will come back," Navalnaya said.</p>

<p>"If I will come back to Russia I will participate in the elections as a candidate," she added.</p>

<p>"My political opponent is Vladimir Putin and I'm trying to do and I will do everything to make his regime fall as soon as possible."</p>

<p>Navalnaya, 48, called the international community's response to her husband's death "a joke" and urged them to be "a little less afraid" of Putin.</p>

<p>Russia added Navalnaya, who has been based for several years in Germany, to its list of "terrorists" and "extremists" in July.</p>

<p>Her late husband's posthumous memoir "Patriot" will be released on Tuesday, chronicling his 2020 nerve agent poisoning and life in a brutal Russian prison camp.</p>

<p>The key opponent of the Russian president died in February in a penal colony, where he had been held in harsh conditions, sparking worldwide condemnation.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/jqn8gv8g_yulia-navalnaya_625x300_21_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Yulia Navalnaya will participate in elections as a candidate if she returned to Russia. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gurpatwant-singh-pannun-air-india-threat-s-jaishankar-ndtv-world-summit-what-s-jaishankar-said-on-khalistani-terrorist-pannuns-threat-to-air-india-6839667]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What S Jaishankar Said On Khalistani Terrorist Pannun's Threat To Air India]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gurpatwant-singh-pannun-air-india-threat-s-jaishankar-ndtv-world-summit-what-s-jaishankar-said-on-khalistani-terrorist-pannuns-threat-to-air-india-6839667]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 17:47:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Indian government is "not aware" of any specific threat against Air India and its passengers - made by Khalistani terrorist Gurpatwant Pannun - External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar said Monday evening at the NDTV World Summit.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Indian government is "not aware" of any specific threat against Air India and its passengers, External Affairs Minister <a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/topic/s-jaishankar" target="_blank">S Jaishankar</a> said Monday evening at the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ndtv-world-summit-2024-india-century-live-updates-pm-narendra-modi-david-cameron-s-jaishankar-to-speak-6830644" target="_blank">NDTV World Summit</a>.</p>

<p>Mr Jaishankar's remark came hours after Khalistani terrorist <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/topic/gurpatwant-singh-pannun" target="_blank">Gurpatwant Singh Pannun</a> - whom the United States believes was the subject of <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ndtv-explains-gurpatwant-singh-pannun-murder-for-hire-case-ex-spy-vikash-yadav-drug-smuggler-nikhil-gupta-plot-to-kill-khalistani-terrorist-6816220" target="_blank">a murder-for-hire plot involving ex-Indian spy Vikas Yadav</a> - released a video statement online warning people not to fly Air India between November 1 and 19.</p>

<p>The threat follows a worrying flood of bomb threats against Indian passenger jets, including those operated by Air India and Air India Xpress; <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/want-to-put-culprits-on-no-fly-list-aviation-minister-on-hoax-bomb-calls-6837808" target="_blank">over 100 such threats have been made in the past week</a>.</p>

<p>"I am not aware of any specific threat today... but we have seen threats, in the past, to our airlines, to our Parliament, to our diplomats and High Commissions, and our leaders," Mr Jaishankar said.</p>

<p>"And all that is a source of concern..." he said.</p>

<h3><strong>Jaishankar Jabs Canada</strong></h3>

<p>Mr Jaishankar may have sidestepped the question on the threat, but took the opportunity to take more sharp digs at the Canadian government amid a tense diplomatic stand-off over the killing of another Khalistani terrorist - <a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/topic/hardeep-nijjar" target="_blank">Hardeep Singh Nijjar</a>, a Canadian citizen - in Vancouver in June last year.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ndtv-explains-hardeep-singh-nijjar-killing-lawrence-bishnoi-gang-trade-talks-how-india-canada-relations-soured-6793249" target="_blank">Nijjar Killing, Bishnoi Gang, Trade Talks: How India-Canada Relations Soured</a></p>

<p>"These threats are cleverly worded... they (the Canadian government) calls this 'freedom of speech'. But my question to them is - if you receive these threats would you take them lightly?"</p>

<p>"If it was your airline being threatened, your Parliament, your diplomats... this is exactly the kind of problem with which we started this conversation," Mr Jaishankar told NDTV.</p>

<p>Earlier in the interview with NDTV's Sanjay Pugalia, he also spoke of 'double standards' in the way Canada treats Indian diplomats and the 'license' their officials allowed themselves while in India.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/difficult-to-imagine-current-state-of-relations-s-jaishankar-on-canada-ties-6839070#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">"Difficult To Imagine Current State...": S Jaishankar On Canada Ties</a></p>

<p>The Indian government has been fiercely critical of its Canadian counterpart giving space - physical and political - to individuals it considers terrorists with designs against India's sovereignty.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/political-agenda-of-trudeau-government-indias-full-statement-slamming-canada-6785786" target="_blank">"Political Agenda Of Trudeau Govt": India Slams Canada On Nijjar Killing</a></p>

<p>Last week - after Canadian federal police claimed top Indian diplomats in that country were working with organised criminal gangs, such as the Lawrence Bishnoi outfit - Delhi pointed out Ottawa had "consciously provided space to violent extremists and terrorists to harass, threaten and intimidate Indian diplomats". This, Delhi complained, had been "justified in the name of freedom of speech".</p>

<p><em>NDTV is now available on WhatsApp channels. <a href="https://www.whatsapp.com/channel/0029Va4lixw7z4kcvZI9JM12">Click on the link</a> to get all the latest updates from NDTV on your chat. </em></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-10/l8063v1o_gurpatwant-singh-pannun-twitter_625x300_12_October_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/shook-hands-came-back-s-jaishankar-on-pakistan-visit-for-sco-summit-6839492]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Haath Milaya, Aa Gaye Wapis": S Jaishankar On Pakistan Visit For SCO Summit]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/shook-hands-came-back-s-jaishankar-on-pakistan-visit-for-sco-summit-6839492]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 17:25:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar denied meeting Pakistan Prime Minister Shehbaz Sharif in a personal capacity at the recently-concluded Shanghai Cooperation Organisation Summit in Islanabad.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar on Monday denied meeting former Pakistan Prime Minister Nawaz Sharif at the recently-concluded Shanghai Cooperation Organisation (SCO) Summit in Islamabad.</p>

<p>"I am a good SCO member. We were very supportive and wanted the proceeding to be smooth. <em>Haath milaya aur aa gaye wapis</em> (shook hands and came back)," he said at the NDTV World Summit 2024.</p>

<p>S Jaishankar was referring to a brief interaction with Mr Sharif at an official dinner held for all the summit attendees.&nbsp;The two leaders shook hands and exchanged a courtesy greeting as Mr Sharif welcomed Mr Jaishankar for the official dinner for SCO leaders. Few words were spoken during the interaction that lasted less than twenty seconds.</p>

<p>The Union Minister's Pakistan visit for the&nbsp;first by an Indian minister in nearly ten years. The last visit by an Indian foreign minister was by Sushma Swaraj.</p>

<p>At his speech at the&nbsp;meeting of the Heads of Government, S Jaishankar flagged concerns over terrorism and extremism. In a veiled message to Pakistan, he said that cooperation in areas like trade is unlikely to flourish if cross-border activities are characterised by terrorism.</p>

<p>Mr Jaishankar also said Indian and Chinese soldiers will be able to resume patrolling in the way they had been doing before the border face-off began in May 2020.&nbsp;His statement came hours after Foreign Secretary Vikram Misri announced India and China have arrived on a patrolling arrangement along the Line of Actual Control (LAC) in the Himalayas, and it can lead to disengagement and resolution of tension.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/pudbeva_jaishankar-at-ndtv_625x300_21_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-has-never-s-jaishankar-spells-out-mantra-in-delhi-moscow-ties-6839431]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Russia Has Never...": S Jaishankar Spells Out Mantra In Delhi-Moscow Ties]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-has-never-s-jaishankar-spells-out-mantra-in-delhi-moscow-ties-6839431]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 17:20:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russia has never done anything to impact India's interests negatively, and there is an economic and strategic logic behind New Delhi maintaining strong ties with Moscow, External Affairs Minister Dr S Jaishankar said at the NDTV World Summit today.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russia has never done anything to impact India's interests negatively, and there is an economic and strategic logic behind New Delhi maintaining strong ties with Moscow, External Affairs Minister Dr S Jaishankar said at the NDTV World Summit today.</p>

<p>During an interaction with NDTV Editor-in-Chief Sanjay Pugalia, the veteran diplomat was asked how India-Russia ties would develop in the coming years.</p>

<p>"The Prime Minister is going to Russia tomorrow, so this is a timely question. If you look at our history with Russia after Independence, Russia has never done anything to impact our interests negatively. Among the major countries, there are not many about who we can say this. Today Russia's situation is different, I think Russia's relationship with the West has broken down, so you have a Russia which is turning much more towards Asia. Should Russia not have multiple options in Asia? Should we not take what is good for us in national interests?"</p>

<p>"And clearly, Russia as a major natural resources power has a complementarity with India at this stage of development where we are big resource consumers. It isn't just Russian oil, it could be fertilisers, metals, coal. There is a whole economic logic to it. There is also a basic strategic logic, if you look at the Eurasian landmass, there are three big countries. You always keep a balance, a relationship," the minister said.</p>

<p>New Delhi's ties with Moscow have been a key geopolitical talking point over the past few years, especially after the Ukraine War began. With the West siding with Ukraine and imposing sanctions on Russia, India's decision to buy Russian oil had come under scrutiny.</p>

<p>India has consistently refused to take sides in the conflict and said it is on the side of peace. This was also reflected in Prime Minister Narendra Modi's recent visits to both Kyiv and Moscow.</p>

<p>Earlier, articulating the Indian position over the decision to procure Russian oil, Dr Jaishankar had said New Delhi has a right to prioritise the interests of its people.</p>

<p>"I understand that there is a conflict situation (in Ukraine). I also understand that Europe has a point of view and Europe will make the choices it will make that is Europe's right. But for Europe to make choices which prioritises its energy needs and then ask India to do something else..," he had said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/au1beqqo_jaishankar-ndtv-summit-_625x300_21_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar at the NDTV World Summit today]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-will-become-leader-in-semiconductor-production-investor-mark-mobius-at-ndtv-world-summit-6839409]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["India Will Become Leader In Semiconductor Production": Investor Mark Mobius]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-will-become-leader-in-semiconductor-production-investor-mark-mobius-at-ndtv-world-summit-6839409]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 17:16:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India has outperformed the US markets and emerging markets are, on average, growing at double the rate of developed economies, ace investor Mark Mobius has said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India has outperformed the US markets and emerging markets are, on average, growing at double the rate of developed economies, ace investor Mark Mobius has said.</p>

<p>In a conversation with investor Ramesh Damani at the NDTV World Summit on Monday, Mr Mobius said Prime Minister Narendra Modi's thrust on digital infrastructure and the opening up of the economy has been key to India's growth.</p>

<p>Mr Mobius, who is the founder of Mobius Capital Partners LLP and is known as the 'Indiana Jones of emerging market investing', said, "I always think of India as the United States of India, because there are different states. It's mind-boggling - you are one nation but you are speaking different languages and even the written languages are different. The first thing he (PM Modi) did was unify the tax system. This is an incredible accomplishment. This is something that probably would have taken a century."</p>

<p>The investor said India's diversity results in incredible creativity and the future belongs to those who are creative.</p>

<p>"I definitely think India is going to become a leader or the leader in semiconductor production in the future. One reason I say that is the demand - you have got a market here that is one of the biggest in the world. Secondly, it is a relatively open economy, so you are going to be able to take technology from Taiwan, China, the United States, wherever. Thirdly, you have got an incredible software industry already, you are the largest exporter of software in the world," Mr Mobius said, adding that many large semiconductor companies already have software bases in India.</p>

<p>The investor said semiconductor fabrication will happen in India because the country has the labour force.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"I remember I was meeting an Indian friend of mine a few years ago and I said India will become a big semiconductor manufacturer. He said Indians are not as patient and not so good with small things like the Chinese are and I asked him if he had seen the places where they are polishing these tiny diamonds in India. They will do a very good job here, no questions about it. But it will require a huge amount of capital," he added.</p>

<p>In terms of return on capital, it's "India, China and the US", Mr Mobius said, adding that India still presents plenty of opportunities despite stock prices climbing.&nbsp;</p>

<p>As the conversation moved to lighter topics, the investor said he likes the 'Baahubali' movies and also had a picture taken with a statue of the villain from the movies in Hyderabad. &nbsp;&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/d6oiigag_mark-mobius-ndtv-summit_625x300_21_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mr Mobius said India's diversity results in incredible creativity.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/no-other-country-deserves-german-envoy-advocates-unsc-seat-for-india-6839205]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA['No Other Country Deserves..': German Envoy Advocates UNSC Seat For India]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/no-other-country-deserves-german-envoy-advocates-unsc-seat-for-india-6839205]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 16:50:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India deserves more than any other country to have a permanent seat on the United Nations Security Council, Dr Philipp Ackermann, Ambassador of Germany to India and Bhutan, said at the NDTV World Summit.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India deserves more than any other country to have a permanent seat on the United Nations Security Council, Dr Philipp Ackermann, Ambassador of Germany to India and Bhutan, said at the NDTV World Summit on Monday.</p>

<p>Dr Ackermann emphasised that India is an important part of equations and should become one of the main actors globally. "The G20 declaration would not have been possible without India. Despite Russia and the west, India secured a satisfactory result, showing the weight it carries," he said.</p>

<p>In a session titled 'Geo-Political Disruptions: Emerging Powers Vs Existing Powers', former permanent representative at the UN Syed Akbaruddin also raised the West Asia matter, where non-state actors are challenging state actors. In a reference to the Israel-Hamas-Hezbollah conflict, he said the changing fault lines are going to have tremendous repercussions.</p>

<p>Ashok Malik, partner at The Asia Group, said given India's economic and political interests, diaspora across the globe and factors like energy prices, West Asia also becomes New Delhi's problem. To this, Akbaruddin added, "The challenge will be of resetting the global order. Challenges will come not just from the state, but also from climate, Artificial Intelligence and space. The solution for these will only come through partnerships."</p>

<p>Speaking on the ongoing India-Canada diplomatic row, Mr Malik asked if a prime ministerial press conference was needed, when countries usually engage diplomats to resolve similar issues "behind closed doors".</p>

<p>Meanwhile, in the move from brown to green energy, protecting the environment in the short term and not just the long term should be priority, Ambassador of Brazil to India Kenneth H da Nobrega said.</p>

<p>Praising the Indian private sector's work in the renewables segment, Ackermann said any climate fight is futile without Indian involvement. Further, Akbaruddin warned that climate transition is difficult and complex, with various countries facing different issues in their fight to preserve the environment.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/l0h6gpto_ndtv-world-summit_625x300_21_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/we-will-be-able-to-go-back-to-2020-patrolling-s-jaishankar-on-lac-border-row-6839082]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Back To 2020 Patrolling": S Jaishankar To NDTV On India, China Pact]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/we-will-be-able-to-go-back-to-2020-patrolling-s-jaishankar-on-lac-border-row-6839082]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 16:38:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Indian and Chinese soldiers will be able to resume patrolling in the way they had been doing before the border face-off began in May 2020, External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar said today at the NDTV World Summit.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Indian and Chinese soldiers will be able to resume patrolling in the way they had been doing before the border face-off began in May 2020, External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar said today at the NDTV World Summit.</p>

<p>Earlier today, Foreign Secretary Vikram Misri announced India and China have arrived on a patrolling arrangement along the Line of Actual Control (LAC) in the Himalayas, and it can lead to disengagement and resolution of tension.</p>

<p>The breakthrough came ahead of Prime Minister Narendra Modi's visit to Russia to attend the BRICS summit tomorrow.</p>

<p>"We reached an agreement on patrolling, and we have gone back to the 2020 position. With that we can say the disengagement with China has been completed. Details will come out in due course," Mr Jaishankar told NDTV Editor-in-Chief Sanjay Pugalia.</p>

<p>"There are areas which for various reasons after 2020, they blocked us, we blocked them. We have now reached an understanding which will allow patrolling as we had been doing till 2020," Mr Jaishankar said.</p>

<p>The External Affairs Minister said the LAC breakthrough is a good development that happened due to "patient and persevering diplomacy".</p>

<p><strong>READ</strong> |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/india-china-agree-on-patrolling-agreement-along-lac-leads-to-disengagement-6838489">India To Resume Patrolling In Ladakh After Big Breakthrough With China</a></p>

<p>"... At various points of time people almost gave up. We have always maintained on the one hand we obviously had to do counter deployment, and we have been negotiating since September 2020. It has been a very patient process, though more complicated than how it should have been," Mr Jaishankar told NDTV.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-09/qcr6vjes_ladakh-generic_625x300_10_September_20.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>"The important thing is if we have reached an understanding, I think what it does is it creates a basis for peace and tranquillity along the border, which were there before 2020. That was a major concern. If there is no peace and tranquillity, how can other areas of bilateral ties improve?" Mr Jaishankar said.</p>

<p>While he agreed people may speculate on the LAC development, the External Affairs Minister said he would use "caution" in responding on whether this positive development would spread to trade ties.</p>

<p>"It (LAC breakthrough) has just happened. I would not go so fast at the moment," Mr Jaishankar said, referring to trade.</p>

<p>The last meeting of the working mechanism for consultation and coordination on India-China border affairs was held on August 29 in Beijing. The two sides then had a frank, constructive and forward-looking exchange of views on the situation along the LAC to narrow down differences and find early resolution of outstanding issues.</p>

<p>It was agreed that restoration of peace and tranquillity, and respect for the LAC are the essential basis for restoration of normalcy in bilateral relations.</p>

<p>Earlier this month, Indian Army chief General Upendra Dwivedi had said the two sides have resolved the "low-hanging fruits" and now need to address difficult situations, adding there was "positive signalling" from the diplomatic side and execution on the ground was dependent on military commanders of the two countries.</p>

<p>Indian and Chinese military commanders too had been meeting regularly seeking complete disengagement in the remaining areas along the LAC in eastern Ladakh as an essential basis for restoration of peace and tranquillity in the India-China border areas.</p>

<p>Some areas still remained to be de-escalated after Indian and Chinese troops withdrew from Gogra-Hot Springs in Ladakh in September 2022. The Chinese forces in this area had returned to pre-2020 positions. Even then, Chinese soldiers were still believed to hold large swathes of Indian territory to the north in the Depsang plains.</p>

<p>Fierce clashes between soldiers of both sides took place in eastern Ladakh's Galwan in June 2020, in which 20 Indian soldiers were killed in action. Over 40 Chinese soldiers were killed or injured.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/d4l91abg_s-jaishankar-ndtv-summit-_625x300_21_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar said today at the NDTV World Summit]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistan-empowers-parliament-to-pick-supreme-court-chief-justice-6839076]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Pakistan Empowers Parliament To Pick Supreme Court Chief Justice]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistan-empowers-parliament-to-pick-supreme-court-chief-justice-6839076]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 16:34:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Pakistan approved changes to the constitution on Monday, which included empowering parliament to pick the Supreme Court's chief justice, drawing criticism from opposition parties who said it was an attempt to subvert the judiciary.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pakistan approved changes to the constitution on Monday, which included empowering parliament to pick the Supreme Court's chief justice, drawing criticism from opposition parties who said it was an attempt to subvert the judiciary.</p>

<p>Pakistan's top court has become a battleground between the government and jailed former Prime Minister Imran Khan, ruling on issues ranging from a controversial national election to a potential military court trial for Khan and his supporters.</p>

<p>The constitutional changes were approved in an extraordinary session of parliament which was assembled on Sunday, a public holiday, and ran all night, concluding close to dawn on Monday.</p>

<p>"The Chief Justice of Pakistan shall be nominated by the Special Parliamentary Committee...from amongst the three most senior Judges of the Supreme Court," the text of amendment bill, which had a host of other procedural changes, read.</p>

<p>Previously, the Supreme Court's second-most senior judge automatically became the chief justice when the top judge retired at age 65.</p>

<p>"It has been settled that parliament is supreme," Prime Minister Shehbaz Sharif said after his ruling coalition garnered the required two-thirds majority of parliament to amend the constitution for the 26th time since it was passed in 1973.</p>

<p>Pakistani politicians have long complained about judicial overreach into matters of governance, stoking tensions between the judiciary and legislature.</p>

<p>Sharif defended the amendments, saying past verdicts had resulted in the sackings of sitting prime ministers, endorsements of military dictatorships, and the undermining of democracy and parliament.</p>

<p>The current Chief Justice Qazi Faez Isa is due to retire this Friday. There had been concern in government circles that senior judges below him and in the high courts had shown leniency to Khan in a number of cases, analysts say.</p>

<p>Former cricket star Khan, 71, has been in jail for over a year. His 2022 removal from office and subsequent clashes with the military have triggered Pakistan's worst political turmoil in decades.</p>

<p>"It is a black day in our constitutional history and for judicial independence," Gohar Ali Khan, chairman of Khan's Pakistan Tehreek-e-Insaf (PTI), said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/9uatkdjo_pakistan-supreme-court-building_625x300_21_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Supreme Court of Pakistan building, in Islamabad, Pakistan. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/difficult-to-imagine-current-state-of-relations-s-jaishankar-on-canada-ties-6839070]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Double Standards A Very Mild Word For It": S Jaishankar On Canada Stance]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/difficult-to-imagine-current-state-of-relations-s-jaishankar-on-canada-ties-6839070]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 16:34:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Canadians seem to have a problem with Indian diplomats trying to find out about what is happening there in relation to India, Foreign Minister S Jaishankar said today at the NDTV World Summit.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Canadians seem to have a problem with Indian diplomats trying to find out about what is happening there in relation to India, Foreign Minister S Jaishankar said today at the NDTV World Summit. &nbsp;In an exclusive interview with Editor-in-Chief Sanjay Pugalia, Mr Jaishankar spoke of the different standards -- "double standards is a very mild word for it" -- &nbsp;that seem to exist between how Canada treats other diplomats and the "license' their diplomats allow themselves while in India.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Speaking on the backdrop of the Canada-India political ties that have nosedived following Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau's allegations about Indian involvement in the murder of Khalistani terrorist Hardeep Singh Nijjar, who was also a Canadian citizen, Mr Jaishankar attributed it to several reasons.&nbsp;</p>

<p>One of these, he said, was the changing world order where the western world is still struggling to adjust to developing nations that surged ahead and stand on an equal platform. Besides this 'big picture" reason are conditions that are specific to Canada-India ties.</p>

<p>While the relations are extremely strong in terms of trade or people-to-people connection, politically, things changed just when the two nations have emerged from the shadow of the 1985 bombing of Kanishka, the Air India 182 flight from Montreal. &nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p>Speaking of the lowest point of that relationship -- tit-for-tat expulsions of diplomats -- Mr Jaishankar said: "Canada has asked us to subject our High Commissioner to a police inquiry and we chose to withdraw our High Commissioner... They seem to have a problem with our diplomats trying to find out about what is happening in Canada which directly pertain to their welfare and security."</p>

<p>On the other hand, the license they give themselves is "totally different from the restrictions they impose on diplomats in Canada," he said. "Canadian diplomats have no problem going around on our military or our police, profiling people, targeting people to be stopped in Canada," he added.</p>

<p>"When we tell them that you have people openly threatening Indian leaders and diplomats, their response is freedom of speech... If you threaten the Indian High Commissioner, he is supposed to accept it as freedom of speech but if an Indian journalist says the Canadian High Commissioner walked out of the South Block looking very grumpy, it is apparently foreign interference," he added.</p>

<p>Ties between India and Canada -- on a downward spiral since Mr Trudeau's allegations in September last year -- have plummeted after the series of fresh allegations against the Indian envoy.</p>

<p>The Foreign Ministry slammed Ottawa for its allegations against Sanjay Kumar Verma -- one of the country's senior-most diplomats who served in Japan, Sudan, Italy, Turkey, Vietnam and China.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The allegations, India said, were "ludicrous" and deserved to be treated with contempt. New Delhi said it has "no faith in the current Canadian Government's commitment to ensure their security". The ministry had also recalled the diplomats, after which Canada formally expelled them. &nbsp;India reiterated by ordering out six Canadian diplomats. &nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p>Last week, in a startling admission during a public inquiry, Mr Trudeau had admitted that Canada had no "hard evidentiary proof" in 2023 to support allegations linking Indian government agents to the killing of Hardeep Singh Nijjar. His claims, Mr Trudeau admitted, were based on intelligence rather than hard evidence.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"I was briefed on the fact that there was intelligence from Canada, and possibly from Five Eyes allies that made it fairly clear, incredibly clear, that India was involved in this... Agents of the government of India were involved in the killing of a Canadian on Canadian soil," he said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/gv1i0t28_s-jaishankar_625x300_21_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-palestine-conflict-israeli-forces-tighten-siege-in-gaza-target-schools-and-shelters-6838928]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israeli Forces Tighten Siege In Gaza, Target Schools And Shelters]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-palestine-conflict-israeli-forces-tighten-siege-in-gaza-target-schools-and-shelters-6838928]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 16:16:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli forces blew up homes and besieged schools and shelters for displaced people on Monday as they deepened their operations in Jabalia in the northern Gaza Strip, residents and medics said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli forces blew up homes and besieged schools and shelters for displaced people on Monday as they deepened their operations in Jabalia in the northern Gaza Strip, residents and medics said.</p>

<p>They also rounded up men and ordered women to leave the camp, they said.</p>

<p>Medics at the Indonesian Hospital told Reuters that Israeli troops marched a school and detained the men before setting the facility ablaze. The fire reached the hospital generators and caused a power outage, they added.</p>

<p>Health officials said they refused orders by the Israeli army, which began a new incursion into the north of the Palestinian territory over two weeks ago, to evacuate the three hospitals in the area or leave the patients unattended.</p>

<p>Troops remained outside the hospital but did not enter, they said. Medics at a second hospital, Kamal Adwan, reported heavy Israeli fire near the hospital at night.</p>

<p>"The army is burning the schools next to the hospital, and no one can enter or leave the hospital," said one nurse at the Indonesian Hospital, who asked not to be named.</p>

<p>Palestinian health officials said 18 people had been killed in Jabalia and eight elsewhere in Gaza in Israeli strikes.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said troops were continuing ground operations across the Gaza Strip. It said in a statement that over the past day, troops had dismantled infrastructure and tunnel shafts of operators and killed fighters in the Jabaliya area. It did not comment on the immediate situation regarding the hospitals and camps.</p>

<p>Israel has intensified its campaigns both in Gaza and Lebanon days after the killing of Hamas leader Yahya Sinwar raised hopes of an opening for ceasefire talks to end more than a year of conflict.</p>

<p>Israel has vowed to eradicate the Hamas operators who formerly controlled Gaza, but in doing so has laid waste to much of the territory and killed tens of thousands of people. More than 1.9 million people have been left homeless amid a humanitarian crisis.</p>

<p>RUNNING OUT</p>

<p>Hadeel Obeid, a supervisor nurse at the Indonesian hospital, where 32 patients are currently being treated, said they were running out of medical supplies.</p>

<p>"Sterile gauze is going to finish and there are no medications to give them," she told Reuters via a chat app.</p>

<p>Obeid said the water supply has been cut off and there was no food for the fourth consecutive day. She appealed to international organizations to take action to save the wounded.</p>

<p>The United Nations said it had been unable to reach the three hospitals in northern Gaza. It demand access to allow aid into northern Gaza areas.</p>

<p>The UN Human Rights Office said it was "increasingly concerned that the manner in which the Israeli military is conducting hostilities in North Gaza, along with unlawful interference with humanitarian assistance and orders that are leading to forced displacement, may be causing the destruction of the Palestinian population in Gaza's northernmost governate through death and displacement".</p>

<p>Israel says it is getting large quantities of humanitarian supplies into Gaza with land deliveries and airdrops. It also says it has facilitated the evacuation of patients from the Kamal Adwan Hospital.</p>

<p>Palestinians say no aid entered northern Gaza areas where the operation is active.</p>

<p>Residents and medics said Israeli forces had tightened their siege on Jabalia, the largest of the enclave's eight historic refugee camps, which it encircled by sending tanks to the nearby towns of Beit Hanoun and Beit Lahiya and issuing evacuation orders to residents.</p>

<p>"We are facing death by bombs, by thirst and hunger," said Raed, a resident of Jabalia camp. "Jabalia is being wiped out and there is no witness to the crime, the world is blinding its eyes,"</p>

<p>Israeli officials said evacuation orders were aimed at separating Hamas fighters from civilians and denied there was any systematic plan to clear civilians out of Jabalia or other northern areas. It said forces operating in northern Gaza killed scores of Hamas gunmen and dismantled infrastructure</p>

<p>Hamas accused Israel of carrying out acts of "genocide and ethnic cleansing" against the people of northern Gaza to force them to leave.</p>

<p>The Hamas armed wing said fighters attacked forces there with anti-tank rockets and mortar fire, and detonated already planted bombs against troops inside tanks and stationed in houses.</p>

<p>Elsewhere in the enclave, Israeli strikes killed at least five people in Rafah in the southern Gaza Strip and four in two separate strikes in Gaza City, medics said.</p>

<p>Sinwar was one of the masterminds of the October 7, 2003, cross-border attack on Israeli communities that killed around 1,200 people, with another 253 taken back to Gaza as hostages, according to Israeli tallies.</p>

<p>Israel's subsequent war has devastated Gaza, killing more than 42,500 Palestinians, with another 10,000 uncounted dead thought to lie under the rubble, Gaza health authorities say.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/pdjfj2h_israeli-forces_625x300_21_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israeli soldiers look on from atop a military vehicle near the Israel-Gaza border.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fethullah-gulen-accused-of-2016-coup-in-turkey-dies-in-exile-aged-83-6838803]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Fethullah Gulen, Accused Of 2016 Coup In Turkey, Dies In Exile Aged 83]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fethullah-gulen-accused-of-2016-coup-in-turkey-dies-in-exile-aged-83-6838803]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 16:00:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US-based Muslim cleric Fethullah Gulen, who was accused by Ankara of organising a failed 2016 coup, has died in exile in the United States aged 83, his movement and the Turkish government said Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US-based Muslim cleric Fethullah Gulen, who was accused by Ankara of organising a failed 2016 coup, has died in exile in the United States aged 83, his movement and the Turkish government said Monday.</p>

<p>Gulen, who lived in the United States since 1999, was the bete noire of Turkish President Recep Tayyip Erdogan who accused him of heading a "terror organisation".</p>

<p>"Our intelligence sources confirm the death of the leader of the FETO organisation," Foreign Minister Hakan Fidan told a press conference, using Turkey's term for Gulen's influential Hizmet movement of schools, businesses and charities.</p>

<p>Turkey's TRT public television said the preacher, who had lived in Pennsylvania for a quarter of a century and was stripped of his Turkish nationality in 2017, died in hospital overnight.</p>

<p>The news was first posted on X by Herkul, Gulen's website which is banned in Turkey, saying he died on "October 20".</p>

<p>"The honourable Fethullah Gulen, who spent every moment of his life serving the blessed religion of Islam and humanity, passed away today," the post said, pledging to share details of his funeral.</p>

<p>Gulen moved to live in the United States in 1999, ostensibly for heath reasons. From there he ran Hizmet, a movement which has a sprawling network of public schools on every continent.</p>

<p>But the organisation has long been blacklisted by the Turkish authorities who refer to it as FETO, the Fethullah Terror Organisation (FETO).</p>

<p>"This organisation has become a threat rarely seen in the history of our nation," Fidan said, accusing its followers of "being used as a weapon against their own country".</p>

<p>And Justice Minister Yilmaz Tunc said Turkey's fight against the movement would continue, despite Gulen's death.</p>

<p>"The fight against this organisation, which poses a national security problem to our country... will continue," he wrote on X.</p>

<p><strong>Ally turned enemy</strong></p>

<p>Once an ally who helped Erdogan when he became prime minister the early 2000s, Gulen became persona non grata after a 2013 corruption scandal engulfed the Turkish premier's inner circle.</p>

<p>Erdogan blamed Gulen and later began accusing him of terror links, denouncing his Hizmet movement as the "FETO terrorist organisation".</p>

<p>Gulen repeatedly insisted his influential movement was merely a network of charitable and business institutions.</p>

<p>Things worsened in 2016 when Erdogan blamed him for masterminding a botched coup, triggering a massive crackdown.</p>

<p>During that purge, some 700,000 people were prosecuted and some 3,000 Gulen followers were jailed for life for what the authorities said was involvement in the putsch.</p>

<p>Another 125,000 people were sacked from public institutions, including 24,000 soldiers and thousands of judges with the authorities shuttering private educational establishments, media outlets and publishing houses.</p>

<p>Turkey still regularly rounds up Gulen followers at home and demands their extradition from countries where his network is active.</p>

<p>Turkish security sources quoted by the private NTV broadcaster, said very few people were expected to attend Gulen's funeral and that his body would likely be buried in the US at a location which would be kept secret.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2016-02/turkish-islamic-preacher-fethullah-gulen-ap_650x400_51454393596.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Fethullah Gulen became persona non grata after a 2013 corruption scandal. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>