<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Wed, 31 Jul 2024 04:46:40 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-says-it-killed-top-hezbollah-commander-fuad-shukr-in-beirut-strike-6227253]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Says It Killed Top Hezbollah Commander Fuad Shukr In Beirut Strike]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-says-it-killed-top-hezbollah-commander-fuad-shukr-in-beirut-strike-6227253]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 31 Jul 2024 04:45:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Israeli military said its fighter jets "eliminated" Hezbollah military commander Fuad Shukr in the area of Beirut on Tuesday, accusing him of being responsible for a rocket strike on the annexed Golan Heights.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Israeli military said its fighter jets "eliminated" Hezbollah military commander Fuad Shukr in the area of Beirut on Tuesday, accusing him of being responsible for a rocket strike on the annexed Golan Heights.</p>

<p>"Israeli air force fighter jets eliminated the Hezbollah terrorist organisation's most senior military commander and the head of its strategic unit, Fuad Shukr, in the area of Beirut," the military said in a statement.</p>

<p>"Fuad Shukr was the commander responsible for the Majdal Shams massacre, in which 12 children were murdered after Hezbollah fired an Iranian Falaq-1 rocket directly at a soccer field in northern Israel on Saturday evening," military spokesman Rear Admiral Daniel Hagari said in a separate video statement.</p>

<p>"Fuad Shukr was the right-hand man to Hassan Nasrallah, Hezbollah's leader and his advisor in planning and directing attacks and operations."</p>

<p>Hagari said Shukr was a "senior terrorist who has the blood of Israelis and many others on his hands".</p>

<p>Since the start of the Gaza war, Shukr directed Hezbollah's attacks on Israel, the military said.</p>

<p>He was responsible for the majority of Hezbollah's most advanced weaponry, including precise-guided missiles, cruise missiles, anti-ship missiles, long-range rockets and UAVs, it added.</p>

<p>The military said that in the 1990s the Hezbollah commander was "directly involved" in the abduction of the bodies of three Israeli soldiers -- Benyamin Avraham, Adi Avitan and Omar Sawaid.</p>

<p>The three were killed by Hezbollah while patrolling the security fence adjacent to Har Dov, the military said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Since then, he has planned and directed numerous terror attacks against innocent civilians," it said.</p>

<p>While Israel wanted to end hostilities without any wider war with Hezbollah, its forces were ready for "any scenario," Hagari said.</p>

<p>"Hezbollah's ongoing aggression and brutal attacks are dragging the people of Lebanon and the entire Middle East into a wider escalation," he said.</p>

<p>"While we prefer to resolve hostilities without a wider war, the IDF (Israeli army) is fully prepared for any scenario."&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/3eouetvo_fuad-shukr-killed_625x300_31_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[uad Shukr was the right-hand man to Hassan Nasrallah, Israel said.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-gaining-ground-on-donald-trump-in-6-of-7-swing-states-report-6227053]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris Gaining Ground On Trump In 6 Of 7 Swing States: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-gaining-ground-on-donald-trump-in-6-of-7-swing-states-report-6227053]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 31 Jul 2024 03:38:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Democratic U.S. Vice President Kamala Harris has gained ground against Republican Donald Trump in six of the seven swing states since President Joe Biden dropped out of the presidential race, according to a Bloomberg News/Morning Consult poll.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Democratic U.S. Vice President Kamala Harris has gained ground against Republican Donald Trump in six of the seven swing states since President Joe Biden dropped out of the presidential race, according to a Bloomberg News/Morning Consult poll of registered voters published on Tuesday.</p>

<p>The poll - conducted online from July 24-28 - shows Harris leading Trump in Michigan by 11 percentage points, while in Arizona, Wisconsin and Nevada, she has a 2-point advantage. Trump is ahead of Harris in Pennsylvania by 4 points and in North Carolina by 2 points. They are on equal footing in Georgia.</p>

<p>Wisconsin is the only state of the seven where Trump has narrowed his deficit with Harris in comparison to Biden's performance in a previous poll.</p>

<p>Tuesday's poll has a margin of error of 3 percentage points in Arizona, Georgia and Pennsylvania, 4 percentage points in Michigan, North Carolina and Wisconsin, and 5 percentage points in Nevada.</p>

<p>In a Bloomberg/Morning Consult poll conducted July 1-5, Trump was ahead of Biden in Arizona by 3 percentage points; in Georgia by 1 point; in Nevada by 3 points; in North Carolina by 3 points; and in Pennsylvania by 7 points. Biden led in Michigan by 5 points and in Wisconsin by 3 points, the poll showed.</p>

<p>The margin of error in the July 1-5 poll was 3 percentage points in Georgia and Pennsylvania; 4 percentage points in Arizona, Michigan, North Carolina, and Wisconsin, and 5 percentage points in Nevada.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/bqfnk8go_kamala-harris_625x300_25_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kamala Harris is gaining ground since Joe Biden dropped out of the US presidential race.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-expected-to-announce-her-running-mate-as-early-as-monday-6226989]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris Expected To Announce Her Running Mate As Early As Monday]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-expected-to-announce-her-running-mate-as-early-as-monday-6226989]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 31 Jul 2024 03:15:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kamala Harris will announce her vice presidential pick as early as Monday before embarking on a multi-state battleground tour with her new running mate later in the week, two sources familiar with the planning said on Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Vice President Kamala Harris will announce her vice presidential pick as early as Monday before embarking on a multi-state battleground tour with her new running mate later in the week, two sources familiar with the planning said on Tuesday.</p>

<p>The high-stakes decision on who will run with Harris has taken center stage since she became the Democratic frontrunner for the Nov. 5 election after U.S. President Joe Biden ended his White House bid just over a week ago.</p>

<p>Harris will announce her vice presidential pick before next week's tour of states that could swing to Republicans or Democrats in November, one of the sources said.</p>

<p>Harris' campaign did not immediately respond to requests for comment.</p>

<p>The short list of candidates under consideration include Kentucky Governor Andy Beshear, Pennsylvania Governor Josh Shapiro, U.S. Senator Mark Kelly of Arizona, Minnesota Governor Tim Walz and Secretary of Transportation Pete Buttigieg.</p>

<p>On Monday, North Carolina Governor Roy Cooper and Michigan Governor Gretchen Whitmer both indicated they were out of the VP sweepstakes.</p>

<p>A handful of U.S. states, often called battlegrounds, have decided the presidential election in recent years, including Michigan, Pennsylvania and Wisconsin.</p>

<p>"There has been no date confirmed for VP Harris to announce her running mate," a campaign spokesperson told Reuters.</p>

<p>Typically, campaigns begin thinking about their vice-presidential pick after the primary race ends in the spring, giving them months to vet candidates and make a decision on who the candidate meshes with best personally and politically.</p>

<p>Harris is being forced to select her running mate on a highly compressed timeline. She faces an Aug. 7 deadline set by the Democratic National Committee, but the decision is likely to come sooner, according to the sources.</p>

<p>Eric Holder Jr., the former attorney general who led the vice-presidential vetting process for Barack Obama in 2008, is vetting Harris' picks through his law firm, Covington &amp; Burling.</p>

<p>The candidates are informally auditioning for the job, hitting the airwaves and campaign stops to showcase what they would bring to the Harris ticket.</p>

<p>Shapiro, for example, delivered a rousing testimonial about Harris in the Philadelphia suburbs on Monday.</p>

<p>"She's not only ready, she's damned ready," he said to a cheering crowd. "And you know who else knows she's ready? Donald Trump knows she's ready."</p>

<p>Walz, the governor of Minnesota, is credited with pushing the Democrats' new criticism of Trump and his running mate J.D. Vance - that they are "weird."</p>

<p>"The fascists depend on us going back, but we're not afraid of weird people," Walz said on Saturday of the Republican ticket. "We're a little bit creeped out, but we're not afraid."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/f31c6agc_kamala-harris-reuters_625x300_29_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kamala Harris will announce her new running mate later in the week.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-hezbollah-commander-fuad-shukr-targeted-by-israel-in-beirut-6226900]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Who Is Hezbollah Commander Fuad Shukr Targeted By Israel In Beirut?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-hezbollah-commander-fuad-shukr-targeted-by-israel-in-beirut-6226900]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 31 Jul 2024 02:42:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Fuad Shukr, a Hezbollah commander whom Israel believes it killed in an airstrike in Beirut on Tuesday, has been one of the group's leading military figures since it was established by Iran's Revolutionary Guards more than four decades ago.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Fuad Shukr, a Hezbollah commander whom Israel believes it killed in an airstrike in Beirut on Tuesday, has been one of the group's leading military figures since it was established by Iran's Revolutionary Guards more than four decades ago.</p>

<p>Part of the generation of Lebanese Shi'ites who founded Hezbollah during the Israeli invasion of Lebanon in 1982, Shukr was a friend of the group's late military commander Imad Mughniyeh, who was assassinated in Damascus in 2008, Hezbollah sources said.</p>

<p>The United States says Shukr, believed to be in his 60s, played a central role in the 1983 bombing of the U.S. Marine barracks in Beirut, which killed 241 U.S. military personnel, and had put a bounty of up to $5 million on his head, according to the U.S. government's Rewards for Justice website.</p>

<p>He was hit in what the Israeli army has said was a targeted strike against the Hezbollah commander responsible for an attack in the Israeli-occupied Golan Heights that killed 12 children and teenagers at the weekend. Hezbollah denied any role.</p>

<p>An Israel broadcast report said the commander was killed.</p>

<p>Two security sources in Lebanon earlier named the target as Shukr, describing him as head of Hezbollah's operations centre. They said he was critically injured in the attack around Hezbollah's Shura Council in the Haret Hreik neighbourhood.</p>

<p>Also known as Al-Hajj Mohsin, Hezbollah sources said Shukr is a special adviser to Hezbollah leader Sayyed Hassan Nasrallah and a member of the Shura Council, a decision-making body.</p>

<p>The sources said he became more prominent in Hezbollah after the assassination of Mughniyeh - a shadowy figure remembered in Hezbollah as a military mastermind who was on the U.S. list of most wanted terrorists, accused of plotting attacks on Western interests including the Marines barracks.</p>

<p>Referring to those attacks and hostage-taking in Lebanon in the 1980s, Hezbollah leader Nasrallah said in a 2022 interview with an Arabic broadcaster they were carried out by small groups not linked to Hezbollah.</p>

<p>The Hezbollah sources said Shukr fought Israeli troops during Israel's 1982 invasion alongside both Mughniyeh and Mustafa Badreddine, another of Hezbollah's veteran commanders who was killed in Syria in 2016.</p>

<p>Announcing the bounty on his head in 2017, the U.S. Rewards for Justice program said he was a senior Hezbollah military commander of the group's forces in southern Lebanon and a member of Hezbollah's highest military body, the Jihad Council.</p>

<p>It also said he played a key role in its military operations in Syria, where Hezbollah deployed fighters in support of President Bashar al-Assad in the early years of the Syrian civil war.</p>

<p>Hezbollah at the time dismissed the accusations against Shukr and another Hezbollah operative for whom a bounty was offered, Talal Hamiyah, saying they were "rejected and void".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/rdv6rkj8_fuad-shukr_625x300_31_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[An Israel broadcast report said the commander was killed.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gross-violation-of-international-law-russia-on-israeli-strike-on-lebanon-6226515]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Gross Violation Of International Law": Russia On Israeli Strike On Lebanon]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gross-violation-of-international-law-russia-on-israeli-strike-on-lebanon-6226515]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 31 Jul 2024 00:58:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russia accused Israel on Tuesday of violating international law after it struck a Hezbollah stronghold in the Lebanese capital Beirut.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russia accused Israel on Tuesday of violating international law after it struck a Hezbollah stronghold in the Lebanese capital Beirut.</p>

<p>"This is a gross violation of international law," Russia's foreign ministry told state news agencies. Israel said the strike targeted a commander responsible for a Saturday rocket attack on the annexed Golan Heights that killed 12 children.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/heo7ka68_israeli-strike-on-lebanon_625x300_31_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Top floors of a building destroyed in Israeli strike in Beirut on Tuesday.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/2-killed-in-israeli-strike-on-lebanon-suburbs-report-6226189]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[2 Killed In Israeli Strike On Lebanon Suburbs: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/2-killed-in-israeli-strike-on-lebanon-suburbs-report-6226189]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 30 Jul 2024 23:42:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel struck Hezbollah's stronghold in southern Beirut on Tuesday in retaliation for rocket fire from Lebanon that killed 12 children over the weekend, saying it had targeted the commander responsible for the attack.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel struck Hezbollah's stronghold in southern Beirut on Tuesday in retaliation for rocket fire from Lebanon that killed 12 children over the weekend, saying it had targeted the commander responsible for the attack.</p>

<p>"The IDF (army) carried out a targeted strike in Beirut on the commander responsible for the murder of the children in Majdal Shams and the killing of numerous additional Israeli civilians," the military said in a statement, referring to the Druze Arab town in the annexed Golan Heights where the children were killed on Saturday.</p>

<p>A source close to the Iran-backed rebel group confirmed that "a leading commander" was the target of the strike, which hit near the group's decision making body, the Shura Council.</p>

<p>The source added that two people were killed in the strike, but was unable to confirm if the commander was among them.</p>

<p>Minutes after the explosions rocked Beirut, Israeli Defence Minister Yoav Gallant posted on social media site X that "Hezbollah crossed the red line".</p>

<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu had on Monday threatened a "severe response" to the attack which Israel and the United States have blamed on Hezbollah, though the group denies responsibility.</p>

<p>Following Saturday's strike, the international community had raced to head off any escalation that might tip the two into a first all-out conflict since 2006.</p>

<p>Lebanon's Foreign Minister Abdallah Bou Habib said on Monday he had received assurances from international diplomats that there would be only a limited response.</p>

<p>"Israel will escalate in a limited way and Hezbollah will respond in a limited way... These are the assurances we've received," Bou Habib said in an interview with local broadcaster Al-Jadeed.</p>

<p>Analysts told AFP that they also expected Israel to temper its actions, with its leaders wary of having to fight a second war while its troops are still engaged in the Gaza Strip.</p>

<h3><strong>'Constant anxiety'</strong></h3>

<p>At least 531 people have been killed on the Lebanese side of the near daily cross-border exchanges, according to an AFP tally. Most have been fighters, but the toll includes at least 105 civilians.</p>

<p>The violence has so far killed 22 soldiers and 25 civilians on the Israeli side, including in the Golan Heights, according to army figures.</p>

<p>There was further deadly violence earlier on Tuesday, with Israeli medics saying a 30-year-old civilian had been killed in the northern kibbutz of HaGoshrim. The military said it had killed a Hezbollah fighter during overnight strikes.</p>

<p>Druze residents of the Majdal Shams -- the vast majority of whom have rejected Israeli citizenship and identify as Syrians -- had opposed threats of retaliation for the deadly strike.</p>

<p>Scores of residents had come out to protest Netanyahu's visit after the burial of the last of the victims of the rocket strike.</p>

<p>A paramedic from Majdal Shams, Nabih Abu Saleh, told AFP his community was "against any Israeli response", and asked: "Who will we strike? Our people in Syria and Lebanon?"</p>

<p>A French diplomat told AFP earlier that Paris "alongside other partners, notably the United States, is making all-out efforts to call on the parties to exercise restraint and not to be drawn into spiralling violence".</p>

<p>Multiple international airlines suspended flights to Beirut ahead of Israel's retaliation, although the chairman of Lebanon's Middle East Airlines, Mohammed al-Hout, said Beirut airport, its only international facility, "is not exposed to any threat, it is supposed to be a neutral place", state media reported.</p>

<p>The Lebanese public, meanwhile, has been gripped by worry, with mother of two Cosette Beshara describing living "in a state of constant anxiety".</p>

<p>"I'm always thinking about how I will escape with my children if war breaks out," said the 40-year-old, adding that "life goes on in Lebanon... but always with a looming state of anxiety."</p>

<h3><strong>Khan Yunis operation</strong></h3>

<p>Hezbollah has said its attacks on northern Israel are in solidarity with Hamas and the people of Gaza, who have been under siege by Israel since October 7.</p>

<p>The Hamas attack on southern Israel that started the war resulted in the deaths of 1,197 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on official Israeli figures.</p>

<p>Hamas also seized 251 hostages, 111 of whom are still held captive in Gaza, including 39 the military says are dead.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory military campaign in Gaza has killed at least 39,400 people, according to the health ministry in the Hamas-run territory, which does not provide details on civilian and operative deaths.</p>

<p>Fighting has raged on unabated in the Gaza Strip, with the territory's civil defence agency saying on Tuesday that around 300 people had been killed in the southern city of Khan Yunis during an Israeli operation there that began on July 22.</p>

<p>"Since the beginning of the Israeli ground invasion of the eastern part of Khan Yunis province, the civil defence and medical teams have recovered approximately 300 bodies of martyrs, many of them decomposed," agency spokesman Mahmud Bassal told AFP.</p>

<p>The military meanwhile said it had completed its operation in the Khan Yunis area, which had seen heavy fighting earlier this year, and had killed "over 150 terrorists".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/amn3ob9o_beirut-strike_625x300_30_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The strike came days after Israel vowed to retaliate over deadly attack on annexed Golan Heights]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-security-was-unaware-of-gunman-until-shots-fired-secret-service-6226143]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Security Was Unaware Of Gunman Until Shots Fired: Secret Service]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-security-was-unaware-of-gunman-until-shots-fired-secret-service-6226143]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 30 Jul 2024 23:33:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump's security detail and a sniper team were not aware there was a gunman on a roof until he opened fire on the former president, the acting Secret Service director said Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump's security detail and a sniper team were not aware there was a gunman on a roof until he opened fire on the former president, the acting Secret Service director said Tuesday.</p>

<p>Local law enforcement identified the gunman, Thomas Matthew Crooks, as a "suspicious person" about 90 minutes before the July 13 attack at a Trump campaign rally in Butler, Pennsylvania, according to FBI officials.</p>

<p>Since the assassination attempt, questions have been raised about when the Secret Service became aware of the presence of the gunman on the roof of a building that overlooked the campaign event.</p>

<p>"Based on what I know right now, neither the Secret Service counter-sniper teams nor members of the former president's security detail had any knowledge that there was a man on the AGR roof with a firearm," acting Secret Service chief Ronald Rowe told a joint Senate committee.</p>

<p>"The only thing we had was that locals were working an issue at the three o'clock, which would have been the former president's right-hand side, which is where the shots came from," Rowe said.</p>

<p>"Nothing about man on the roof, nothing about man with a gun," he said.</p>

<p>FBI special agent Kevin Rojek said Monday that a police officer was boosted on to the roof by another officer at 6:11 pm.</p>

<p>Crooks pointed his rifle at the officer, who "immediately dropped to the ground."</p>

<p>"Approximately 25 to 30 seconds after this encounter, the subject fired eight rounds before being successfully neutralized," Rojek said.</p>

<p>Rowe said Crooks was shot dead by a Secret Service sniper "within 15.5 seconds" of firing the first shot.</p>

<p>The Republican presidential candidate was wounded in the right ear, while two rally attendees were injured and a Pennsylvania firefighter was killed.</p>

<h3><strong>'Ashamed'</strong></h3>

<p>Rowe said he "cannot defend" why the rooftop where Crooks fired from was not better secured, and said he was "ashamed" about the security lapses.</p>

<p>He said local law enforcement had been tasked with securing the rooftop. "We assumed that the state and locals had it," he said.</p>

<p>Asked why Trump was allowed to take the stage, Rowe said Crooks had not been identified as a threat but only as suspicious.</p>

<p>"We did not have anything beyond suspicious person that was communicated to us," he said. "Suspicion had not risen to the level of threat or imminent harm."</p>

<p>Rowe said communications failures between local law enforcement and the Secret Service contributed to what he called a "failure on multiple levels."</p>

<p>The Secret Service had "technical difficulties" with its counter-drone capabilities on the day of the attack and they were not "operational until after five o'clock," he said.</p>

<p>Crooks flew a drone near the rally site for 11 minutes about two hours before the attack, according to the FBI.</p>

<p>FBI deputy director Paul Abbate also addressed the committee hearing and said the authorities still have not established a motive.</p>

<p>He said they have identified a social media account believed to be associated with Crooks.</p>

<p>"In about the 2019, 2020 timeframe there were over 700 comments posted from this account," Abbate said. "Some of these comments, if ultimately attributable to the shooter, appear to reflect anti-Semitic and anti-immigration themes, to espouse political violence and are described as extreme in nature."</p>

<p>Secret Service Director Kimberly Cheatle resigned last week after acknowledging that the agency had failed in its mission to prevent the assassination attempt.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/rgcrhcv_donald-trump-shooting-afp_625x300_17_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-senate-passes-first-major-child-online-safety-bills-in-years-6226036]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Senate Passes First Major Child Online Safety Bills In Years]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-senate-passes-first-major-child-online-safety-bills-in-years-6226036]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 30 Jul 2024 23:12:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The US Senate passed a sweeping social media safety package Tuesday that would force tech companies to do more to protect children -- the first major legislation targeting Silicon Valley in a generation.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The US Senate passed a sweeping social media safety package Tuesday that would force tech companies to do more to protect children -- the first major legislation targeting Silicon Valley in a generation.</p>

<p>Social media giants like Meta and X have been confronting a torrent of political anger for not putting in guardrails to thwart online dangers for children, including from sexual predators and teen suicide.</p>

<p>A rare sign of cross-party unity in an increasingly rancorous election year, the Kids Online Safety Act (KOSA) and the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) were passed in an overwhelmingly bipartisan vote with just three dissenters.</p>

<p>But the bills face an uncertain path through the House of Representatives, where Republican Speaker Mike Johnson has spoken broadly in favor of the package but has not scheduled a vote.</p>

<p>"I'm proud to say today, the Senate keeps its promise to every parent who's lost a child because of the risks of social media... KOSA and COPPA will be perhaps the most important updates to federal laws protecting kids on the internet in decades, and it's a very good first step," said Senate Majority Leader Chuck Schumer.</p>

<p>The legislation was drawn up in consultation with parents of teens who had been bullied or sexually exploited but has been opposed by some free speech groups worried that it could lead to censorship.</p>

<h3><strong>'Duty of care'</strong></h3>

<p>While there is widespread agreement in a politically divided Congress on curbing the negative impacts of social media, there has never been a united path on how to go about doing so.</p>

<p>House members are on their summer recess and will almost certainly be focusing on averting a looming government shutdown when they return in September.</p>

<p>But Schumer called on the lower chamber to pass the bills immediately on its return, urging lawmakers to "seize the opportunity to send them to the president's desk."</p>

<p>The KOSA bill would establish a "duty of care" obligation on the online platforms that would demand that special provisions are in place to shield minors from toxic content.</p>

<p>Supported by Microsoft, X and Snap, the company that owns Snapchat, the legislation would require companies to give users a dedicated page to report harmful content -- including sexual exploitation, online bullying, the promotion of suicide and eating disorders.</p>

<p>Meta CEO Mark Zuckerberg gave a public apology to the families of victims at the Senate Judiciary Committee in January as hostile lawmakers grilled tech CEOs over the dangers that children face on social media.</p>

<p>"I'm sorry for everything you have all been through," he said. "No one should go through the things that your families have suffered."</p>

<h3><strong>Censorship fears</strong></h3>

<p>Seven LGBTQ advocacy groups withdrew initial opposition based on updates to the bill they said mitigated concerns that teens would be limited in accessing information about gender identity, sexuality and reproductive health.</p>

<p>But free speech groups including the American Civil Liberties Union have argued that the definition of harm is too broad and that it could lead to censorship.</p>

<p>COPPA would beef up privacy standards for Americans aged under 17, and outlaw advertising targeted at children and teens -- requiring companies to allow users to delete personal information.</p>

<p>"Too many kids experience relentless promotion of suicide or substance abuse material. Too many kids have their personal data collected and then used nefariously," Schumer said.</p>

<p>"With studies showing that kids today spend more time on social media than ever before, now is the moment to pass KOSA, pass COPPA, and instill guardrails that protect kids from these risks."</p>

<p>But Oregan Democrat Ron Wyden posted on X that the tweaks to KOSA "remain insufficient" and voiced fears that a hard-right future Republican administration could "still use this bill to pressure companies to censor gay, trans and reproductive health information."</p>

<p></p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2017-06/us-senate-reuters-650_650x400_51498171179.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gaza-health-ministry-declares-palestinian-territory-polio-epidemic-area-6225989]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Gaza Health Ministry Declares Palestinian Territory "Polio Epidemic Area"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gaza-health-ministry-declares-palestinian-territory-polio-epidemic-area-6225989]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 30 Jul 2024 23:02:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The health ministry in Hamas-run Gaza has declared the Palestinian territory a "polio epidemic area," accusing Israel's military campaign of destroying health infrastructure, which it says led to the recurrence of the virus.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The health ministry in Hamas-run Gaza has declared the Palestinian territory a "polio epidemic area," accusing Israel's military campaign of destroying health infrastructure, which it says led to the recurrence of the virus.</p>

<p>The CPV2 strain of the virus has been detected in sewage samples collected from the southern Khan Yunis area and central governorates, the ministry said.</p>

<p>It did not say if any human cases had been detected, but said the presence of the virus "constitutes a health threat to the residents of the Gaza Strip and neighbouring countries and a setback to the global polio eradication program".</p>

<p>The wild version of the virus is now endemic only in Afghanistan and Pakistan, but a type of vaccine that contains small amounts of weakened but live polio still causes occasional outbreaks elsewhere.</p>

<p>United Nations agencies said recently that such vaccine-derived type-2 poliovirus had been detected in samples collected from sewage.</p>

<p>"The brutal Israeli aggression that deprived the people of usable water, the destruction of the sanitation infrastructure, the accumulation of tonnes of garbage and a lack of food security" had led to the recurrence of the virus, the ministry said.</p>

<p>On Tuesday, the World Health Organisation said it was "looking at a very problematic situation".</p>

<p>"Having vaccine-derived poliovirus in the sewage very likely means that it's out there somewhere in people," WHO spokesman Christian Lindmeier told journalists.</p>

<p>"But again, about 75 percent of people infected by polio don't even show any symptoms.</p>

<p>"That means it most likely is in the population but it doesn't necessarily mean that we see an outbreak of cases."</p>

<p>He said a campaign to distribute vaccines across the Gaza Strip was needed.</p>

<p>"It's not enough just to get it (the vaccine) into Ben Gurion airport and then hopefully get it into Gaza. It needs to reach people," Lindmeier said.</p>

<p>Israel's bombardments and ground assault has devastated swathes of Gaza, displacing the vast majority of its 2.4 million population.</p>

<p>The war in Gaza began after Hamas attacked Israel on October 7, which resulted in the death of 1,197 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on official Israeli figures.</p>

<p>Hamas also seized 251 people, 111 still held captive in Gaza, including 39 who the military says are dead.</p>

<p>Israel's campaign has killed 39,400 people so far in Gaza, according to the health ministry in the Hamas-run territory, which does not provide details of civilian and operative deaths.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/1k6ecrdo_israel-gaza-war_625x300_06_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/loud-blast-heard-in-lebanese-capital-beirut-amid-tensions-with-israel-report-6225848]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Targets Senior Hezbollah Commander In Lebanese Capital Air Strike]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/loud-blast-heard-in-lebanese-capital-beirut-amid-tensions-with-israel-report-6225848]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 30 Jul 2024 22:31:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An Israeli air strike targeted a senior Hezbollah commander in Beirut's southern suburbs late on Tuesday in what the Israeli military said was retaliation for a cross-border rocket attack three days before that killed 12 children and teenagers.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An Israeli air strike targeted a senior Hezbollah commander in Beirut's southern suburbs late on Tuesday in what the Israeli military said was retaliation for a cross-border rocket attack three days before that killed 12 children and teenagers.</p>

<p>A loud blast was heard and a plume of smoke could be seen rising above the southern suburbs - a stronghold of the Iran-backed Lebanese armed group Hezbollah - at around 7:40 p.m. (1640 GMT), a Reuters witness said.</p>

<p>A senior Lebanese security source said a senior Hezbollah commander had been the target of the air strike and his fate remained unclear.</p>

<p>Lebanon's state-run national news agency said an Israeli air strike had targeted the area around Hezbollah's Shura Council in the Haret Hreik neighbourhood of the capital.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Initial report- the IDF carried out a targeted strike in Beirut, on the commander responsible for the murder of the children in Majdal Shams and the killing of numerous additional Israeli civilians. At the moment, there are no changes in the Home Front Command defensive… <a href="https://t.co/ja9PRE0cZM">pic.twitter.com/ja9PRE0cZM</a></p>
— Israel Defense Forces (@IDF) <a href="https://twitter.com/IDF/status/1818333771260690783?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 30, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Beirut has been on edge for days ahead of an anticipated Israeli attack in reprisal for the rocket strike on the Israeli-occupied Golan Heights on Saturday that killed the 12 youngsters in a football field in a Druze village.</p>

<p>Hezbollah has denied involvement in that attack.</p>

<p>In a statement, the Israeli military said it had conducted "a targeted strike in Beirut on the commander responsible for the murder of the children in Majdal Shams and the killing of numerous additional Israeli civilians". Details would follow.</p>

<p>Earlier on Tuesday, more rocket fire from south Lebanon killed a civilian in a kibbutz in northern Israel, medics said.</p>

<p>Shortly before the explosion in south Beirut, the Israeli military said 15 projectiles had been fired across the Lebanese border within the past few hours, with impacts in parts of the Upper Galilee region. No injuries were reported.</p>

<p>Israel's air force had just hit a Hezbollah observation post and "terror infrastructure" in south Lebanon, it added.</p>

<h3><strong>Concerns About Escalation</strong></h3>

<p>As diplomats sought to contain the fallout, U.S. Defense Secretary Lloyd Austin said he did not believe a fight was inevitable between Hezbollah and Israel, though he remained concerned about the potential for escalation.</p>

<p>Hezbollah and Israel, which last fought each other in a major war in 2006, have been trading fire since the eruption of the Gaza war in October, after Hezbollah began firing at Israeli targets in what it says is solidarity with the Palestinians.</p>

<p>The hostilities have mostly been limited to the frontier region and both sides have previously indicated they do not seek a wider confrontation even as the conflict has prompted worry about the risk of a slide towards war.</p>

<p>In the latest exchanges of fire on Tuesday, the Israeli military said 10 rockets had been fired from Lebanon and one hit Kibbutz Hagoshrim, causing one casualty. Israel's ambulance service said the 30-year-old male died of shrapnel wounds.</p>

<p>Israel said it hit some 10 Hezbollah targets in south Lebanon overnight and killed one Hezbollah fighter - attacks which appeared to be in keeping with the pattern of the last nine months. Hezbollah confirmed one of its fighters was killed.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/8d5c7ck8_beirut-blast_625x300_30_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Beirut is a stronghold of Lebanese armed group Hezbollah]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/air-canada-flight-cancelled-after-staff-members-meltdown-over-passengers-blanket-request-6225773]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Air Canada Flight Cancelled After Staff's Meltdown Over Blanket Request]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/air-canada-flight-cancelled-after-staff-members-meltdown-over-passengers-blanket-request-6225773]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 30 Jul 2024 22:20:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The altercation occurred when a passenger requested a blanket due to excessive air conditioning, which enraged the flight attendant.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An Air Canada flight from Morocco to Montreal was cancelled on Friday morning following an altercation between a passenger and a flight attendant. According to the <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/07/29/world-news/air-canada-flight-canceled-after-flight-attendant-goes-berserk-when-passenger-asks-for-blanket/">New York Post</a></em>, the argument occurred when a passenger requested a blanket due to excessive air conditioning, which enraged the flight attendant. She yelled at the passenger, called the police, and asked the passenger to disembark.</p>

<p>The flight attendant was heard shouting in French, ''You will behave or we will get off! I'll tell the captain right away. Yes or no?''&nbsp;</p>

<p>When a passenger asked the flight attendant to call the captain, she refused and said, ''I don't want any bullying against my crew.'' She then stormed up the aisle, turned around and shouted, ''Everyone behaves! Be quiet … or you're getting off.''</p>

<p>In support of the passenger, other passengers onboard also left the flight, leading to the cancellation.&nbsp;<a auto-tracked="true" data-evt="click" data-evt-typ="click" data-evt-val="{&quot;control_fields&quot;: {&quot;mparticle&quot;: {&quot;keys&quot;: {&quot;click_source_type&quot;: &quot;click_source_type&quot;, &quot;anchor_text&quot;: &quot;anchor_text&quot;, &quot;target_url&quot;: &quot;target_url&quot;, &quot;layout_section&quot;: &quot;layout_section&quot;}, &quot;mp_event_type&quot;: &quot;Navigation&quot;, &quot;extra_keys&quot;: [&quot;click_vertical_position_percentage&quot;, &quot;click_vertical_position_pixels&quot;]}}, &quot;click_source_type&quot;: &quot;in-page link&quot;, &quot;anchor_text&quot;: &quot;Flight radar data&quot;, &quot;target_url&quot;: &quot;https://www.flightradar24.com/data/flights/ac73#3655510e&quot;, &quot;layout_section&quot;: &quot;in-page-link&quot;}" href="https://www.flightradar24.com/data/flights/ac73#3655510e" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Flight radar data</a>&nbsp;shows that flight AC73 was taxiing to the runway before returning to the terminal.</p>

<p><strong>Here's the video:</strong></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Stress levels are quite high in the sky these days : An Air Canada flight from Casablanca (CMN) to Montreal (YUL) was canceled due to the inappropriate behavior of a flight attendant on July 26, 2024.<br />
<br />
The Airbus A330-343 aircraft (C-GHLM) did the taxi aiming a departure while… <a href="https://t.co/h3s4fbGF5A">pic.twitter.com/h3s4fbGF5A</a></p>
— FL360aero (@fl360aero) <a href="https://twitter.com/fl360aero/status/1817249195960455420?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 27, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>Air Canada confirmed that the flight was cancelled, with a different crew brought in to take the passengers to their destination on Sunday.&nbsp;The airline stated that they are taking the incident seriously and will take appropriate action. They also apologised to their customers and offered compensation for the inconvenience.</p>

<p>A representative for Air Canada added, ''We take this issue extremely seriously. It is being reviewed, and we will take the right action. We apologize to our customers and deeply regret that their experience today fell far short of what they have come to expect when flying with Air Canada.''</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/lh5n53i8_air-canada-flight-_625x300_30_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A different crew was brought in to take the passengers to their destination]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-shooter-thomas-crooks-posted-violent-content-online-as-teen-says-fbi-officer-6225737]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Shooter Posted Violent Content Online As Teen, Says FBI Officer]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-shooter-thomas-crooks-posted-violent-content-online-as-teen-says-fbi-officer-6225737]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 30 Jul 2024 22:16:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The man who tried to assassinate Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump appears to have posted violent antisemitic and anti-immigration content online as a teenager, a senior FBI official told a U.S. Senate hearing on Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The man who tried to assassinate Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump appears to have posted violent antisemitic and anti-immigration content online as a teenager, a senior FBI official told a U.S. Senate hearing on Tuesday.</p>

<p>FBI Deputy Director Paul Abbate at the hearing revealed the existence of the social media account, which dated to 2019-2020 - when Thomas Crooks, who authorities have identified as the shooter, would have been 15 or 16 years old. It is some of the first evidence to become public about a potential motive in the July 13 attack at a campaign rally in western Pennsylvania.</p>

<p>"Something just very recently uncovered that I want to share is a social media account which is believed to be associated with the shooter in about the 2019-2020 time frame," Abbate told lawmakers, adding that more than 700 comments were posted by the account.</p>

<p>"Some of these comments, if ultimately attributable to the shooter, appear to reflect antisemitic and anti-immigration themes to espouse political violence and are described as extreme in nature," Abbate said.</p>

<p>Crooks, who was 20, shot at Trump with an AR-15-style rifle during the rally in Butler, Pennsylvania, wounding the former president's ear, killing one rally attendee and wounding two others. Secret Service snipers killed Crooks after he opened fire.</p>

<p>Investigators have described Crooks as a loner with no close friends and a social network limited mainly to immediate family members.</p>

<p>The first shooting of a U.S. president or major party candidate in more than four decades was a glaring security lapse that led last week to former Secret Service Director Kimberly Cheatle's resignation under bipartisan congressional pressure.</p>

<p>Her immediate successor, Acting Secret Service Director Ronald Rowe, told lawmakers that he visited the outdoor rally site in Butler and climbed onto the roof of a nearby building from which Crooks fired.</p>

<p>"What I saw made me ashamed," Rowe told a joint hearing of the Senate Homeland Security and Judiciary Committees. "As a career law enforcement officer, and a 25-year veteran with the Secret Service, I cannot defend why that roof was not better secured."</p>

<p>Rowe sought to assure lawmakers that he has since taken steps to prevent similar lapses from occurring amid concerns among both Democrats and Republicans about further political violence as the campaign intensifies ahead of the Nov. 5 U.S. election.</p>

<p>Crooks flew a drone near the rally site ahead of his assassination attempt, a flight that officials failed to detect because a system designed to detect drones was not working properly due to problems with cellular network bandwidth, Rowe said.</p>

<p>The Secret Service, a federal law enforcement agency whose duties including protecting the president and certain other top political figures, has added six people to its protection list since July 13, including Republican vice presidential candidate JD Vance and his family and independent presidential candidate Robert F. Kennedy, while reinforcing security details, Rowe said.</p>

<p>"This attack was a shocking reminder that the threat of political violence is alive and well in our country. By all accounts, this was inexcusable security, and planning failure," Democratic Senate Homeland Security Chairman Gary Peters said, adding that his panel is working on reforms to strengthen security protocols for the Secret Service.</p>

<p>Senator Rand Paul, the committee's top Republican, said his staff had found communication gaps between local police who first noticed Crooks and the Secret Service.</p>

<p>Rowe said that Secret Service counter snipers and members of the Trump security detail had no knowledge that there was a man with a firearm on the roof of a nearby building.</p>

<p>The attempted assassination is the topic of multiple investigations by House and Senate committees, as well as a new bipartisan task force</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/9ckehas_thomas-matthew-crooks-thomas-crooks_625x300_15_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Thomas Crooks shot at Trump with an AR-15-style rifle during the rally in Butler]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-army-stops-paying-wages-to-soldier-gordon-black-imprisoned-in-russia-heres-why-6225670]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Army Stops Paying Wages To Soldier Imprisoned In Russia. Here's Why]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-army-stops-paying-wages-to-soldier-gordon-black-imprisoned-in-russia-heres-why-6225670]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 30 Jul 2024 22:04:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Army has stopped paying wages and allowances to a U.S. soldier sentenced last month to nearly four years in a Russian penal colony and may prosecute him if he returns to the United States, U.S. officials said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Army has stopped paying wages and allowances to a U.S. soldier sentenced last month to nearly four years in a Russian penal colony and may prosecute him if he returns to the United States, U.S. officials said.</p>

<p>Gordon Black, a 34-year-old staff sergeant, was convicted in Russia of theft and threatening murder. But he broke a series of Army rules first, traveling to Russia without U.S. military authorization, and flying through China to get there.</p>

<p>He was also having an extramarital affair - prohibited in the U.S. military - with a Russian woman named Alexandra Vashchuk, who he met during a deployment in South Korea. During leave from the military, Black followed her to Russia's far eastern city of Vladivostok, where she reported him to the police after an argument.</p>

<p>A senior U.S. defense official, speaking on condition of anonymity, drew a comparison to the case of U.S. Army Private Travis King, who last year ran into North Korea and was taken into custody there. Once the United States secured his release, King was charged in October by the Army with crimes including desertion.</p>

<p>"When Black is back in the United States, there will be probably consequences, just as Private King is experiencing consequences for essentially unacceptable behavior," the official said.</p>

<p>"So the Army is going to do the right thing in terms of punishing bad behavior."</p>

<p>Black's case created another headache for U.S. officials already coping with several high-profile detentions in Russia, including Wall Street Journal reporter Evan Gershkovich and former U.S. Marine Paul Whelan.</p>

<p>Russia's Foreign Ministry has said the case was not political and the U.S. military has not weighed in on the substance of the charges against Black in Russia.</p>

<p>Black was arrested in Vladivostok in May after he and Vashchuk had an argument, and on June 19 a Russian judge found Black guilty of stealing $10,000 rubles ($116) from his girlfriend's purse and threatening to kill her. He pleaded not guilty to threatening to kill Vashchuk but admitted he took the money and said he did so out of necessity.</p>

<p>His defense lawyer in Russia, who has said she will appeal the verdict, was not immediately reachable for comment.</p>

<p>The violations of Army rules present a quandary for the U.S. military, given the high-profile nature of Black's arrest and the fact he has a wife and daughter near Fort Cavazos in Texas who depended on benefits, including a portion of his housing allowance.</p>

<p>In May, the military quietly decided to stop paying Black his wages and housing allowance, Army officials told Reuters.</p>

<h3><strong>Controversial Decision</strong></h3>

<p>An Army spokesperson told Reuters Black's status was now CCA, or "Confined Civilian Authority," and that he is being kept on active duty without pay or allowances. The Army is maintaining medical benefits and base privileges for Black's family members.</p>

<p>Franklin Rosenblatt, an associate professor at Mississippi College School of Law and former Army Judge Advocate General, suggested the decision to change Black's status to CCA would be routine, if he were detained in the United States.</p>

<p>But assigning that status to him in Russia could be controversial, Rosenblatt said.</p>

<p>"There's a concern here that we may be giving legitimacy to the proceedings conducted in Russia with how we reflect his duty and pay status," he said, when informed by Reuters about Black's CCA status.</p>

<p>The U.S. military is not providing Black with any special military counsel, the Army has said.</p>

<p>Black's wife and mother, in interviews with Reuters, have portrayed a sometimes violent relationship between Black and his girlfriend.</p>

<p>His wife Megan recounted a time that Black's girlfriend stabbed him during a drunken video-call from Seoul with his daughter back in Texas.</p>

<p>Black's mother, Melody Jones, said he had followed his girlfriend to Russia even though they "fought like cats and dogs."</p>

<p>In Russia, prosecutors said that during an argument at Vashchuk's apartment, Black had grabbed her by the neck before taking her money. Black argued that Vashchuk had drunk half a bottle of vodka that day, was aggressive and had struck him.</p>

<p>Rosenblatt said while the Army might want to prosecute him now, it may opt against doing so if Black were to end up serving his entire sentence of three years and nine months in a Russian penal colony.</p>

<p>"What happened to him there (Russia) and serving that sentence, it does not entitle him automatically to confinement credit, but ... that may be a strong reason to grant leniency," he said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/3i7lvnag_gordon-black_625x300_30_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Gordon Black, a 34-year-old staff sergeant, was convicted in Russia of theft and threatening murder]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hezbollah-exchange-deadly-fire-amid-calls-for-restraint-after-golan-attack-6225391]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel, Hezbollah Exchange Fire Amid Calls For Restraint After Golan Attack]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hezbollah-exchange-deadly-fire-amid-calls-for-restraint-after-golan-attack-6225391]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 30 Jul 2024 21:22:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel and Hezbollah exchanged deadly fire on Tuesday, following a rocket attack from Lebanon on the Golan Heights that killed 12 children over the weekend and sent regional tensions soaring.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel and Hezbollah exchanged deadly fire on Tuesday, following a rocket attack from Lebanon on the Golan Heights that killed 12 children over the weekend and sent regional tensions soaring.</p>

<p>The strike on the Druze Arab town of Majdal Shams in the Israeli-annexed Golan Heights on Saturday, whose victims were aged between 10 and 16, was blamed by Israel and the United States on Lebanon's Hezbollah, but the Iran-backed group has denied any connection to the attack.</p>

<p>During a visit Monday to Majdal Shams, Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu vowed a "severe response", raising fears yet again that the Gaza war could spill over into a wider regional conflagration, despite international appeals for calm.</p>

<p>Israeli medics on Tuesday said one civilian, a 30-year-old man, was killed following a rocket attack on the northern kibbutz of HaGoshrim.</p>

<p>The Israeli army meanwhile reported its forces were "striking the sources of fire", which were in Lebanon.</p>

<p>It had said earlier that it struck around 10 Hezbollah targets overnight in seven different areas of south Lebanon, killing one fighter from the Iran-backed group.</p>

<p>Hezbollah said on Tuesday that it had fired a salvo of Katyusha rockets at a military headquarters in the village of Beit Hillel, in response to "the Israeli enemy's attack on the town of Jibchit, which resulted in civilian casualties".</p>

<p>Lebanon's official National News Agency had reported a strike in the Jibchit area that caused "major damage".</p>

<h3><strong>'Constant anxiety'</strong></h3>

<p>Hezbollah has been exchanging near-daily fire with Israel in solidarity with its ally Hamas since war erupted in Gaza in October.</p>

<p>At least 531 people have been killed on the Lebanese side, according to an AFP tally. Most have been fighters, but the toll includes at least 105 civilians.</p>

<p>The violence has so far killed 22 soldiers and 25 civilians on the Israeli side, including in the Golan Heights, according to army figures.</p>

<p>Lebanon has been bracing for major retaliatory strikes following the Golan attack, amid international efforts to defuse tensions.</p>

<p>But Druze residents of the town -- the vast majority of whom have rejected Israeli citizenship and identify as Syrians -- have rejected threats of retaliation for the deadly strike.</p>

<p>Scores of Majdal Shams residents had come out to protest Netanyahu's visit after the burial of the last of the victims of the rocket strike.</p>

<p>A paramedic from Majdal Shams, Nabih Abu Saleh, told AFP his community was "against any Israeli response", and asked: "Who will we strike? Our people in Syria and Lebanon?"</p>

<p>A French diplomat told AFP that Paris "alongside other partners, notably the United States, is making all-out efforts to call on the parties to exercise restraint and not to be drawn into spiralling violence".</p>

<p>Lebanon's Middle East Airlines chairman Mohammed al-Hout said Beirut airport, its only international facility, "is not exposed to any threat, it is supposed to be a neutral place", state media reported.</p>

<p>Multiple international airlines have suspended flights to Beirut amid Israel's promises of retaliation.</p>

<p>The Lebanese public, meanwhile, has been gripped by worry, with mother of two Cosette Beshara describing living "in a state of constant anxiety".</p>

<p>"I'm always thinking about how I will escape with my children if war breaks out," said the 40-year-old, adding that "life goes on in Lebanon... but always with a looming state of anxiety."</p>

<h3><strong>Khan Younis operation</strong></h3>

<p>The Hamas attack on southern Israel that started the war resulted in the deaths of 1,197 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on official Israeli figures.</p>

<p>Operatives also seized 251 hostages, 111 of whom are still held captive in Gaza, including 39 the military says are dead.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory military campaign in Gaza has killed at least 39,400 people, according to the health ministry in the Hamas-run territory, which does not provide details on civilian and operatives deaths.</p>

<p>Fighting has meanwhile raged on unabated in the besieged Gaza Strip, with the territory's civil defence agency saying on Tuesday that around 300 people had been killed in the southern city of Khan Younis during an Israeli operation there that began on July 22.</p>

<p>"Since the beginning of the Israeli ground invasion of the eastern part of Khan Younis province, the civil defence and medical teams have recovered approximately 300 bodies of martyrs, many of them decomposed," agency spokesman Mahmud Bassal told AFP.</p>

<p>The military meanwhile said it had completed its operation in the Khan Younis area, which had seen heavy fighting earlier this year, and had killed "over 150 terrorists".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/5husnh3_israel-lebanon_625x300_27_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hezbollah has been exchanging near-daily fire with Israel]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/irans-reformist-president-masoud-pezeshkian-sworn-in-at-parliament-6225052]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iran President Sworn In With Chants Of 'Death To America, Israel']]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/irans-reformist-president-masoud-pezeshkian-sworn-in-at-parliament-6225052]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 30 Jul 2024 20:37:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iranian reformist president Masoud Pezeshkian was sworn before parliament on Tuesday as the Islamic republic's ninth president at a ceremony attended by foreign dignitaries.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Iranian reformist president Masoud Pezeshkian was sworn before parliament on Tuesday as the Islamic republic's ninth president at a ceremony attended by foreign dignitaries.</p>

<p>Pezeshkian won a runoff race against ultraconservative Saeed Jalili on July 5 to replace president Ebrahim Raisi who died in a helicopter crash in May.</p>

<p>Tuesday's ceremony came two days after Iran's supreme leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei officially endorsed Pezeshkian and gave the 69-year-old heart surgeon presidential powers.</p>

<p>"I as the president, in front of the Holy Koran and the people of Iran, swear to almighty God to be the guardian of the official religion and the Islamic Republic system and the constitution of the country," Pezeshkian said at the ceremony which was broadcast live on state TV.</p>

<p>Pezeshkian, who is expected to unveil his government within two weeks, had secured more than 16 million votes during the runoff, or about 54 percent of the roughly 30 million ballots cast.</p>

<p>Iran's presidential election took place against a backdrop of heightened regional tensions since the Gaza war began in early October, disputes with Western powers over Iran's nuclear programme and domestic discontent over the state of the sanctions-hit economy.</p>

<p>Tuesday's ceremony was attended by senior officials from several countries including Armenia, Tajikistan, Egypt, Sudan, Iraq, Turkey, Saudi Arabia, Azerbaijan, Cuba and Brazil.</p>

<p>European Union envoy Enrique Mora was also present.</p>

<p>Regional Iran-backed allies were also in attendance, namely Hamas leader Ismail Haniyeh and the head of the Islamic Jihad Ziyad al-Nakhalah.</p>

<p>Lebanon's Hezbollah movement was represented by the group's deputy secretary general Naim Qassem while the Yemen's Huthi rebels sent spokesman Mohammed Abdulsalam.</p>

<h3><strong>'Death to Israel'</strong></h3>

<p>Haniyeh and Nakhalah, whose groups have been fighting Israel in the Gaza Strip since Hamas's October 7 attack on Israel, met with Khamenei and Pezeshkian.</p>

<p>"Supporting the cause of the oppressed Palestinian nation will continue with strength, and no factor can disrupt our will in this direction," said Pezeshkian in a Monday statement.</p>

<p>Tuesday's swearing-in ceremony came amid concerns of war between Israel and Lebanon's Hezbollah following a rocket attack from Lebanon Saturday on the Israeli-annexed Golan Heights.</p>

<p>Israel has accused Hezbollah of responsibility for the attack that killed 12 children but the Iran-backed Lebanese group has denied any involvement.</p>

<p>During Tuesday's ceremony, parliament speaker Mohammad Bagher Ghalibaf gave a speech lambasting what he called Israel's "crimes" in Gaza.</p>

<p>Some Iranians present in parliament chanted: "Death to Israel, Death to America."</p>

<p>Iran has made support for the Palestinian cause a centrepiece of its foreign policy since the 1979 Islamic revolution, and hailed Hamas's October 7 attack on Israel.</p>

<p>Iran's president is not head of state, and the ultimate authority rests with the supreme leader -- a post held by Khamenei for the last 35 years.</p>

<p>On Monday, Pezeshkian warned Israel against attacking Lebanon, saying such an act would have "heavy consequences".</p>

<p>Since his election, Iran's new president has reaffirmed support for the so-called "axis of resistance", Tehran-aligned groups such as Hezbollah and the Huthis, that support Hamas against arch-foe Israel.</p>

<p>Pezeshkian was the only candidate representing Iran's reformist camp allowed to stand in Iran's presidential election, for which all contenders were approved by the conservative-dominated Guardian Council.</p>

<p>During his campaign, the former health minister, had vowed to try and revive a 2015 nuclear deal with world powers which collapsed in 2018 after the United States unilaterally withdrew from agreement.</p>

<p>The deal had given Iran sanctions relief in return for curbs on its nuclear activity.</p>

<p>Pezeshkian has recently called for "constructive relations" with European countries, even though he accused them of reneging on commitments to mitigate the impact of renewed US sanctions.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/gc3222b4_masoud-pezeshkian_625x300_09_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Pezeshkian is expected to unveil his government within two weeks]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fresh-demonstrations-loom-in-venezuela-after-4-dead-in-anti-maduro-protests-6225021]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Fresh Demonstrations Loom In Venezuela After 4 Dead In Anti-Maduro Protests]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fresh-demonstrations-loom-in-venezuela-after-4-dead-in-anti-maduro-protests-6225021]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 30 Jul 2024 20:31:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[New demonstrations were expected in Venezuela on Tuesday, after four people died and dozens were injured when the authorities broke up protests against President Nicolas Maduro's claim of victory in a hotly disputed election.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>New demonstrations were expected in Venezuela on Tuesday, after four people died and dozens were injured when the authorities broke up protests against President Nicolas Maduro's claim of victory in a hotly disputed election.</p>

<p>Security forces fired tear gas and rubber bullets Monday at angry protesters challenging the official results, which were questioned by the opposition and neighboring countries.</p>

<p>Thousands of people flooded the streets of several neighborhoods in the capital Caracas, chanting "Freedom, freedom!" and "This government is going to fall!"</p>

<p>Some ripped down and burned Maduro campaign posters while at least two statues of Hugo Chavez -- the late authoritarian socialist who led Venezuela for more than a decade and handpicked Maduro as his successor -- were knocked down by protesters.</p>

<p>In addition to the deaths, 44 were reported injured, according to the National Hospital Survey, a network that monitors crises in the country's hospitals</p>

<p>Two of the dead were in the state of Aragua and one in Caracas, the network said. The NGO Foro Penal meanwhile reported one more dead in the northwestern state of Yaracuy.</p>

<p>Amid growing fears of violence, a leading figure in the opposition coalition, Freddy Superlano, was "kidnapped" by black-clad officials, his Voluntad Popular said on X.</p>

<h3><strong>Fears of fraud</strong></h3>

<p>The elections were held amid widespread fears of fraud by the government and a campaign tainted by accusations of political intimidation.</p>

<p>The National Electoral Council (CNE) certified the reelection of Maduro, 61, to another six-year term until 2031, with the president winning 51.2 percent of votes cast compared to 44.2 percent for Edmundo Gonzalez Urrutia.</p>

<p>But opposition leader Maria Corina Machado told reporters that a review of available voting records clearly showed that the next president "will be Edmundo Gonzalez Urrutia," who replaced her on the ballot after she was barred from running by Maduro-aligned courts.</p>

<p>The records showed a "mathematically irreversible" lead for Gonzalez Urrutia, she said, with 6.27 million votes to Maduro's 2.75 million.</p>

<p>The Organization of American States, a regional body, charged Tuesday there was "exceptional manipulation" of the election results that handed Maduro his win.</p>

<p>Machado called for families to turn out Tuesday for "popular assemblies" nationwide to show support for a peaceful transition of power.</p>

<p>Maduro's campaign manager Jorge Rodriguez, also called on X for "large marches starting this Tuesday to celebrate the victory."</p>

<p>In Caracas on Monday, AFP observed members of the national guard firing tear gas and rubber bullets at protesters, some wearing motorbike helmets and bandanas tied over their faces. Some responded by throwing rocks.</p>

<p>Protests were reported even in poor areas of Caracas that had been bastions of support for Maduro. Shots were heard in some areas.</p>

<p>The United Nations, United States, European Union and several Latin American countries called for a "transparent" process, while allies including China, Russia and Cuba congratulated Maduro.</p>

<p>Nine Latin American countries called in a joint statement for a "complete review of the results with the presence of independent electoral observers." Chile's president said the outcome was "hard to believe."</p>

<p>Amid the tensions, Peru recalled its ambassador and Panama said it was suspending relations with Venezuela. Caracas meanwhile said it was withdrawing diplomatic staff from Argentina, Chile, Costa Rica, Panama, Peru, the Dominican Republic and Uruguay.</p>

<h3><strong>'Bloodbath' warning</strong></h3>

<p>Independent polls had predicted Maduro would lose Sunday's vote.</p>

<p>He has been at the helm of the once-wealthy oil-rich country since 2013. Amid US sanctions and economic mismanagement, the past decade has seen GDP drop by 80 percent, pushing more than seven million of Venezuela's 30 million citizens to emigrate.</p>

<p>Maduro is accused of locking up critics and harassing the opposition in a climate of rising authoritarianism.</p>

<p>In the run-up to the election, he warned of a "bloodbath" if he lost.</p>

<p>Sunday's election was the product of a deal reached last year between the government and opposition.</p>

<p>That agreement led the United States to temporarily ease sanctions imposed after Maduro's 2018 reelection, rejected as a sham by dozens of Latin American and other countries.</p>

<p>Sanctions were snapped back after Maduro reneged on agreed conditions.</p>

<p>Venezuela boasts the world's largest oil reserves but production capacity has been severely diminished in recent years.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/o5rmthp8_venezuela-protests_625x300_30_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The elections were held amid widespread fears of fraud by the government]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/absurd-kremlin-on-charges-it-is-trying-to-meddle-in-us-presidential-poll-6224621]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Absurd": Kremlin On Charges It Is Trying To Meddle In US Poll]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/absurd-kremlin-on-charges-it-is-trying-to-meddle-in-us-presidential-poll-6224621]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 30 Jul 2024 19:42:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Kremlin on Tuesday dismissed as absurd U.S. intelligence assertions that Russia is seeking to meddle in the presidential election and said that U.S. spies were intent on casting Russia as an enemy.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Kremlin on Tuesday dismissed as absurd U.S. intelligence assertions that Russia is seeking to meddle in the presidential election and said that U.S. spies were intent on casting Russia as an enemy.</p>

<p>U.S. intelligence officials have said that Russia is seeking to influence the November election, and that Moscow has used Russia-based influence-for-hire companies to shape U.S. public opinion.</p>

<p>"As for these accusations, they are absurd, and we strongly reject them," Kremlin spokesman Dmitry Peskov said when asked about the reports from Washington.</p>

<p>"There will be a lot of such statements as the U.S. elections approach because Russia and the head of the Russian state personally are essentially significant factors that both Republicans and Democrats exploit during their political struggle, especially in the election campaign," said Peskov.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/pqsvmrc_vladimir-putin-afp-_625x300_28_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/european-union-approves-humanitarian-aid-to-india-due-to-recent-floods-6224560]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[European Union Approves Humanitarian Aid To India Due To Recent Floods]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/european-union-approves-humanitarian-aid-to-india-due-to-recent-floods-6224560]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 30 Jul 2024 19:38:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The European Union has approved Euro 2.4 million in humanitarian aid to help the most affected population in the recent floods in India, northern Bangladesh and the Philippines.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The European Union has approved Euro 2.4 million in humanitarian aid to help the most affected population in the recent floods in India, northern Bangladesh and the Philippines.</p>

<p>The funding will help provide cash assistance, food, access to clean water and sanitation, and other essential services in the hardest-hit areas.</p>

<p>Ambassador of the European Union to India, Herve Delphin, posted on X, "EU provides EUR2.4 million in humanitarian response to floods in India, Bangladesh, and the Philippines."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">❗️News ? EU provides €2.4 million in humanitarian response to floods in India, Bangladesh, and the Philippines <a href="https://t.co/8rDyoqoZg3">https://t.co/8rDyoqoZg3</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/PIB_India?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@PIB_India</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/EU_in_India?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@EU_in_India</a></p>
— Hervé Delphin (@EUAmbIndia) <a href="https://twitter.com/EUAmbIndia/status/1818245614095753300?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 30, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Commissioner for Crisis Management, Janez Lenarcic, stated that as the beginning of this year's monsoon has been affecting these regions, the EU is stepping up its assistance to the affected population.</p>

<p>"The beginning of this year's monsoon season is proving very hard for people in the north of Bangladesh, India and the Philippines. The EU is stepping up its assistance to the most affected populations, so they can receive much needed relief," the Commissioner for Crisis Management said.</p>

<p>In Bangladesh and India, an allocation of Euro 1.2 million will support the most affected communities.</p>

<p>Earlier in May, the European Union provided over 22.6 million rupees in response to a hailstorm and heavy rain that hit Manipur. The humanitarian aid was provided for crucial assistance to those most-affected in some of the worst-hit areas.</p>

<p>Moreover, combined with the effects of cyclone Remal that hit the country in May, nearly one-third of Bangladesh has been impacted by floods.</p>

<p>The funding comes in addition to the over Euro 30 million already allocated to Bangladesh earlier this year, mainly in support of the Rohingya refugees living in Cox's Bazar as well as in response to other recent emergencies, including heatwaves and cyclone Remal.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, in the Philippines, Euro 1.2 million will help the communities in Mindanao, where monsoon rains have caused massive flooding, intensified by typhoons Prapiroon and Gaemi.</p>

<p>This new funding comes in addition to the Euro 3.1 million already allocated to the Philippines this year, mostly in response to the protracted crises in Mindanao but also to previous floods.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/uv657p4_assam-floods_625x300_18_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[In Bangladesh and India, an allocation of Euro 1.2 million will support the most affected communities.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/meta-to-pay-1-4-billion-to-settle-texas-lawsuit-over-facial-recognition-data-6224549]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Meta To Pay $1.4 Billion To Settle Lawsuit Over Facial Recognition Data]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/meta-to-pay-1-4-billion-to-settle-texas-lawsuit-over-facial-recognition-data-6224549]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 30 Jul 2024 19:36:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Meta Platforms has agreed to pay $1.4 billion to Texas to resolve the state's lawsuit accusing the Facebook parent of illegally using facial-recognition technology to collect biometric data of millions of Texans without their consent.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Meta Platforms has agreed to pay $1.4 billion to Texas to resolve the state's lawsuit accusing the Facebook parent of illegally using facial-recognition technology to collect biometric data of millions of Texans without their consent.</p>

<p>The terms of the settlement, disclosed on Tuesday, marks the largest accord ever by any single state, according to the lawyers for Texas, whose legal team included the plaintiffs firm Keller Postman.</p>

<p>The lawsuit, filed in 2022, was the first major case to be brought under Texas' 2009 biometric privacy law, according to law firms tracking the litigation. A provision of the law provides damages of up to $25,000 per violation.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-05/m24k7rio_meta-generic_625x300_25_May_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-secret-service-acting-director-ashamed-about-trump-shooting-incident-6224518]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Secret Service Acting Director "Ashamed" About Trump Shooting Incident]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-secret-service-acting-director-ashamed-about-trump-shooting-incident-6224518]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 30 Jul 2024 19:32:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The U.S. Secret Service's new acting director said in prepared congressional testimony on Tuesday he was "ashamed" of a major security lapse that preceded the July 13 attempted assassination of Republican presidential nominee Donald Trump at a Pennsy]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The U.S. Secret Service's new acting director said in prepared congressional testimony on Tuesday he was "ashamed" of a major security lapse that preceded the July 13 attempted assassination of Republican presidential nominee Donald Trump at a Pennsylvania campaign rally.</p>

<p>In testimony released before addressing two Senate committees, Acting Secret Service Director Ronald Rowe said he visited the outdoor rally site in Butler and climbed onto the roof of a nearby building from which 20-year-old Thomas Crooks fired shots that wounded Trump's right ear, killed one rally attendee and wounded two others, with an AR-15-style rifle.</p>

<p>"What I saw made me ashamed," Rowe said in the prepared testimony for a joint hearing of the Senate Homeland Security and Judiciary Committees. "As a career law enforcement officer, and a 25-year veteran with the Secret Service, I cannot defend why that roof was not better secured."</p>

<p>Rowe's admission of a glaring security lapse came a week after former Secret Service Director Kimberly Cheatle resigned under bipartisan congressional pressure after refusing to detail security shortfalls in testimony before a House of Representatives panel.</p>

<p>Rowe sought to assure lawmakers that he has since taken steps to prevent similar lapses from occurring amid concerns among both Democrats and Republicans about further political violence as the campaign intensifies ahead of the Nov. 5 U.S. election.</p>

<p>"I directed our personnel to ensure every event site security plan is thoroughly vetted by multiple experienced supervisors before it is implemented," Rowe said.</p>

<p>The Secret Service, a federal law enforcement agency whose duties including protecting the president and certain other top political figures, has added six people to its protection list since July 13, including Republican vice presidential candidate JD Vance and his family and independent presidential candidate Robert F. Kennedy, while reinforcing security details, Rowe said.</p>

<p>Rowe was due to testify alongside Paul Abbate, deputy director of the FBI, which is due to interview Trump on Thursday as part of its investigation into the shooting.</p>

<p>The attempted assassination is the topic of multiple investigations by House and Senate committees, as well as a new bipartisan task force established by Republican House Speaker Mike Johnson and House Democratic leader Hakeem Jeffries.</p>

<p>Investigators have been unable to determine a clear motive for Crooks, who they have described as a loner with no close friends and a social network limited mainly to immediate family members. Much interest revolves around the timeline from when law enforcement officials first noticed Crooks to when Secret Service snipers killed him after he opened fire.</p>

<p>The FBI said on Monday that Crooks first came to the attention of police more than an hour before he fired at least eight shots at the former president.</p>

<p>A local officer took a photo of Crooks and sent it to other law enforcement officials at the scene. About 30 minutes later, SWAT team members saw Crooks using a rangefinder and browsing news sites, the FBI said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/rgcrhcv_donald-trump-shooting-afp_625x300_17_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>