<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Tue, 20 Aug 2024 09:57:24 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/democratic-national-convention-2024-joe-biden-calls-donald-trump-loser-in-fiery-convention-speech-6375202]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Who Does He Think He Is?" Joe Biden Blasts Donald Trump In Fiery Speech]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/democratic-national-convention-2024-joe-biden-calls-donald-trump-loser-in-fiery-convention-speech-6375202]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 20 Aug 2024 09:27:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In a charged and emotional farewell speech at the Democratic National Convention in Chicago, President Joe Biden delivered a scathing critique of former President Donald Trump, labelling him a "loser" and vigorously defending his own legacy.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a charged and emotional farewell speech at the Democratic National Convention in Chicago, President Joe Biden delivered a scathing critique of former President Donald Trump, labelling him a "loser" and vigorously defending his own legacy.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Mr Biden, who recently announced his decision to step aside from the 2024 presidential race, received a thunderous ovation from the crowd, which chanted "We love you, Joe," in a show of solidarity.</p>

<p>"Donald Trump says we are losing, but he is the loser," Mr Biden declared, drawing a stark contrast between his administration's achievements and what he described as the failures of the Trump presidency. "He is dead wrong. Name a country in the world that does not think we are the leading nation in the world. Who could lead the world if not us?"</p>

<p>The 81-year-old Biden, visibly moved, spoke at length about the challenges he faced and the progress made during his presidency. His speech was punctuated by moments of reflection on the state of American democracy and the stakes of the upcoming election. "We are in a battle for the very soul of America," Mr Biden said.</p>

<p>Kamala Harris, America's first female, Black, and South Asian vice president, has taken a lead over Mr Trump in the polls.</p>

<p>In her brief but powerful remarks, Ms Harris expressed gratitude to Mr Biden, saying, "We are forever grateful to you." She praised his leadership and commitment to the country, setting the stage for her own formal acceptance of the party's nomination later in the week. With Beyonce's "Freedom" blaring from loudspeakers during her entrance on stage, Ms Harris said, "I want to kick us off by celebrating our incredible president Joe Biden."&nbsp;<br />
&nbsp;</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/5dek1g9g_joe-biden-afp_625x300_20_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-2024-joe-biden-wins-huge-ovation-at-democratic-convention-farewell-6375158]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Tearful Biden Gets Huge Ovation At Democratic Convention Farewell]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-2024-joe-biden-wins-huge-ovation-at-democratic-convention-farewell-6375158]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 20 Aug 2024 09:17:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden won a huge ovation as he took to the stage Monday at the Democratic National Convention in Chicago.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An emotional Joe Biden won a huge ovation as he gave a farewell speech at the Democratic National Convention in Chicago on Monday after Kamala Harris made a surprise appearance to thank him for being an "incredible" president.</p>

<p>"I love you," the tearful 81-year-old president told the crowd to deafening cheers, less than a month after dropping out of the White House race against Donald Trump and passing the torch to his vice president.</p>

<p>Biden took to the stage to chants of "We love you Joe" from the same party which had pushed him out over concerns about his age, in one of the biggest political shocks in US political history.</p>

<p>"We both know we have more to do, but we're moving in the right direction," he said, referring to himself and the 59-year-old Harris, who, in the space of a few breathtaking weeks, has turned the presidential race upside down.</p>

<p>America's first female, Black and South Asian vice president has quickly breathed new life into the Democratic Party and wiped out Republican rival Donald Trump's lead in the polls.</p>

<p>She heaped lavish tribute to Biden at what must be one of the toughest moments of his career, even breaking with tradition to speak on the first night of the convention in praise of her boss.</p>

<p>"I want to kick us off by celebrating our incredible president Joe Biden," said Harris, who was wearing a tan suit and took to the stage to Beyonce's "Freedom."</p>

<p>"We are forever grateful to you."</p>

<p>As he has been so often in his five-decade-long political journey, Biden was surrounded by family, with wife Jill Biden and their daughter Ashley introducing him.</p>

<p>"Joe and I have been together for almost 50 years. And still, there are moments when I fall in love with him all over again," the first lady said.</p>

<h3><strong>'Something is happening'&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>The Democrats are in an exuberant mood in Chicago, daring to hope for victory in November that seemed inconceivable just weeks ago after Biden's disastrous debate against Trump.</p>

<p>But Monday's first night of the convention was an emotional one on many levels, and for many of the key players.</p>

<p>Hillary Clinton, who lost against Trump in 2016 in her own bid to become America's first woman president, backed Harris to finally break the glass ceiling.</p>

<p>"Something is happening in America, you can feel it -- something we've worked for and dreamed of for a long time," the former secretary of state and first lady said.</p>

<p>The crowd also chanted "lock him up" as she recalled Trump's recent conviction in a porn star hush money trial -- an ironic echo of when Trump led similar chants for Clinton to be jailed in a row over deleted emails.</p>

<p>Harris will formally accept the party's nomination on the final day Thursday, in her biggest chance yet to define her candidacy in front of a huge audience of tens of millions of American voters.</p>

<p>Her star turn will cap a week where the biggest names from the party's past will endorse her as its future, with former president Barack Obama speaking on Tuesday, and ex-president Bill Clinton introducing Harris's running mate Tim Walz on Wednesday.</p>

<h3><strong>'Craziness'&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>For Biden, he is suddenly the convention's warm-up act instead of its headliner, and he reportedly still feels frustration at the way he was pushed aside despite feeling that he could still beat Trump.</p>

<p>But he has insisted he is at peace with his decision.</p>

<p>"I am," Biden told reporters earlier when asked if he was ready to pass the torch to Harris.</p>

<p>Protests against Israel's war in Gaza had earlier shadowed the opening of the convention, underscoring what remains a potential vote-loser for Democrats among left-wingers and Arab Americans.</p>

<p>A group of demonstrators broke through the outer security fence of the convention after splitting off from a larger protest of thousands of people.</p>

<p>Police in blue helmets with shields and carrying black batons prevented them from getting to the inner cordon.</p>

<p>Trump, meanwhile, has been sent into a tailspin by the sudden change at the top of the Democratic ticket.</p>

<p>While Democrats are in Chicago, the Republicans will spend the week crisscrossing the country.</p>

<p>In the battleground state of Pennsylvania on Monday, he highlighted what he called Harris's "craziness" and said she "has no idea what the hell she's doing" on the economy.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/1bo7m2k_tearful-biden-at-convention-afp-_625x300_20_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Joe Biden won a huge ovation as he took to the stage for his farewell speech.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/willing-to-serve-elon-musk-responds-to-donald-trumps-adviser-offer-6374980]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk's Response After Trump Says He Would Make Him Adviser]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/willing-to-serve-elon-musk-responds-to-donald-trumps-adviser-offer-6374980]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 20 Aug 2024 08:31:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[After US Presidential candidate Donald Trump said that he might consider offering Tesla and SpaceX CEO Elon Musk an advisory role within his administration, the latter responded with a social media post that read, "I am willing to serve."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After US Presidential candidate Donald Trump said that he might consider offering Tesla and SpaceX CEO Elon Musk an advisory role within his administration, the latter responded with a social media post that read, "I am willing to serve."</p>

<p>The post features Mr Musk standing in front of a podium emblazoned with the words "Department of Government Efficiency (DOGE)." The acronym is a playful nod to Dogecoin, the popular cryptocurrency that originated as a meme.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">I am willing to serve <a href="https://t.co/BJhGbcA2e0">pic.twitter.com/BJhGbcA2e0</a></p>
— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1825723913051000851?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 20, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>Mr Musk's post came in the wake of an offer from Mr Trump, the Republican frontrunner in the upcoming US presidential race. On Monday, Mr Trump mentioned that, if elected, he would consider appointing Musk to a cabinet position or an advisory role within his administration. Mr Trump's comments followed his critique of the $7,500 tax credit for electric vehicle (EV) purchases, a measure he suggested he might abolish if he returns to the White House.</p>

<p>"Tax credits and tax incentives are not generally a very good thing," Mr Trump said after a campaign event in Pennsylvania. When asked specifically about the possibility of naming Mr Musk to a particular role in his administration, Mr Trump was unequivocal: "He's a very smart guy. I certainly would, if he would do it, I certainly would. He's a brilliant guy."</p>

<p>Mr Musk, who last month publicly endorsed Trump for the presidency, has not yet commented directly on whether he would accept such an offer. However, his post on X has sparked speculation about his potential involvement in a future Trump administration.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/d89c4me8_elon-musk-donald-trump-_625x300_20_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Elon Musk last month publicly endorsed Donald Trump for the US presidency.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hillary-clinton-praises-kamala-harris-joe-biden-at-2024-democratic-convention-slams-donald-trump-6374851]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Kamala Harris Won't Rest, Trump Slept At His Trial": Hillary Clinton]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hillary-clinton-praises-kamala-harris-joe-biden-at-2024-democratic-convention-slams-donald-trump-6374851]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 20 Aug 2024 07:56:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hillary Clinton, who became the first woman to secure a major US party's presidential nomination, addressed the Democratic convention in Chicago today and praised her party's new presidential nominee Kamala Harris.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hillary Clinton, who became the first woman to secure a major US party's presidential nomination, addressed the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-democratic-convention-live-updates-us-democratic-national-convention-to-kick-start-in-chicago-6373201" target="_blank">Democratic convention</a> in Chicago today and praised her party's&nbsp;new presidential nominee Kamala Harris, and attacked Republican candidate Donald Trump.</p>

<p>Thousands have gathered in Chicago for the Democratic Convention to show their support for Kamala Harris as officially nominated democratic party candidate against <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-says-he-may-end-ev-tax-credit-is-open-to-having-elon-musk-as-adviser-6374360#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">Donald Trump</a> in the 2024 US presidential elections.</p>

<p>“As president, she (Kamala Harris) will always have our backs and she will be a fighter for us. She will fight to lower costs for hard-working families, open the doors wide for good paying jobs and, yes, she will restore abortion rights nationwide,” Clinton said.</p>

<p>Attacking Trump, who she lost in the 2016 US elections, Clinton said he "only thinks about himself".</p>

<p>"Donald Trump fell asleep at his own trial, and when he woke up, he made his own kind of history, the first person to run for president with 34 felony convictions," she said.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">.<a href="https://twitter.com/HillaryClinton?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@HillaryClinton</a>: Kamala will never rest in defense of our freedom and safety. Donald Trump fell asleep at his own trial <a href="https://t.co/30gaMgk7n3">pic.twitter.com/30gaMgk7n3</a></p>
— Kamala HQ (@KamalaHQ) <a href="https://twitter.com/KamalaHQ/status/1825717636275335453?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 20, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Clinton, who lost the party's nomination to Barrack Obama in 2008, also praised US President Joe Biden,&nbsp;saying he has been the "champion of Democracy, at home and abroad."</p>

<p>"And now, we are writing a new chapter in America's story," Clinton said, adding Kamala has the "character, experience and vision to lead us forward."</p>

<h3><strong>Kamala Harris' Surprise Appearance</strong></h3>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-forever-grateful-to-you-kamala-harris-at-democratic-convention-6374653#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">Kamala Harris</a> also made a surprise appearance at the party's national convention and vowed to defeat her Republican rival Donald Trump in the November election.</p>

<p>"Let us fight for the ideals we hold dear and let us always remember, when we fight we win!" she said in brief remarks.</p>

<p>She also praised Biden and said, "Joe, thank you for your historic leadership, for your lifetime of service to our nation."</p>

<p>"We are forever grateful," she told Biden.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/4qqb4nso_hillary-clinton-kamala-harris_625x300_20_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hillary Clinton addressed the Democratic convention in Chicago today]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nothing-ceo-ends-work-from-home-suggests-leaving-to-those-who-disagree-6374721]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Nothing CEO Ends Work From Home, Suggests Leaving To Those Who Disagree]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nothing-ceo-ends-work-from-home-suggests-leaving-to-those-who-disagree-6374721]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 20 Aug 2024 07:13:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The CEO also advised staff members who were unable to work five days a week to find alternative jobs.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Nothing, a British smartphone startup aiming to challenge Apple's dominance in the industry, is bringing its staff back to the office full-time in pursuit of growth. CEO of Nothing Carl Pei defended in a long email the necessity for his 450 workers to report to work five days a week, refuting a workplace policy that has supported remote work from the company's founding four years ago.</p>

<p>"We've come a long way in a short space of time. We are the only company to have established a smartphone business in the last 10 years. We are the fastest-growing smartphone brand in India at 567% YoY. Yet, we are at 0.1% of our potential. With the solid start we've made, we really have the chance to create a generational tech company that can change the world. This is an incredibly exciting opportunity that we've earned together, and now it's time to double down," he said in the email to staff.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Last Friday, we made an important decision to work 5 days a week in-office in London.<br />
<br />
This is the email I sent to everyone on the <a href="https://twitter.com/nothing?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@nothing</a> team.<br />
<br />
—————<br />
<br />
We've come a long way in a short space of time. We are the only company to have established a smartphone business in the last…</p>
— Carl Pei (@getpeid) <a href="https://twitter.com/getpeid/status/1825451734442922202?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 19, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Mr Pei stated that although remote or hybrid work environments have proven successful for certain companies, they do not support the high standards of ambition and speed necessary for Nothing to meet its goals. He identified three primary reasons for the change- the company's goal to become a tech company that defines a generation; the necessity of close cooperation in the production of physical goods; and the significance of creativity and innovation in outperforming more established rivals.</p>

<p>"First of all, we make physical products where design, engineering, manufacturing and quality have to collaborate closely together to deliver products to our users. This does not work well remotely," he said.</p>

<p>The CEO added, "We are not looking to create a good business that gets acquired by a big company, we are looking to realize our full potential of becoming a generation-defining company. And we're really serious about moving fast. Remote work is not compatible with a high ambition level plus high speed."</p>

<p>Mr Pei's email also mentioned that the new mandate will go into effect in two months and that he plans to host a town hall in London to address any concerns raised by staff members.</p>

<p>The CEO also advised staff members who were unable to work five days a week to find alternative jobs. "We know it's not the right type of setup for everybody, and that's okay. We should look for a mutual fit. You should find an environment where you thrive, and we need to find people who want to go the full mile with us in the decades ahead," he concluded.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-02/1djstmbo_carl-pei_625x300_18_February_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mr Pei's email mentioned that the new mandate will go into effect in two months.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-forever-grateful-to-you-kamala-harris-at-democratic-convention-6374653]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris Thanks Biden In Surprise Speech On Day 1 Of Democratic Event]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-forever-grateful-to-you-kamala-harris-at-democratic-convention-6374653]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 20 Aug 2024 06:53:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US Vice President and Democratic nominee Kamal Harris has thanked US President Joe Biden for his "lifetime of service" to the nation. The Indian-origin leader addressed the opening of the Democratic National Convention in Chicago.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US Vice President and Democratic nominee Kamal Harris has thanked US President Joe Biden for his "lifetime of service" to the nation. Addressing the opening of the Democratic National Convention in Chicago, the Indian-origin leader said the country was "forever grateful" to the 81-year-old for his leadership.</p>

<p>"I want to kick us off by celebrating our incredible president, Joe Biden. Joe, thank you for your historic leadership, for your lifetime of service to our nation. We are forever grateful to you," she said in a surprise speech on the first day of the party's convention.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Usually, the presidential nominees deliver their remarks on the final day of the convention. But Harris broke tradition and was greeted by loud cheers from the crowd.</p>

<p>The 59-year-old leader is expected to officially accept her nomination for the November US elections at the convention.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"People from every corner of our country and every walk of life are here and this November we will come together and declare with one voice that we are moving forward. Let us always remember -- when we fight, we win," she said.</p>

<p>At the end of the four-day convention, which concludes on August 22, Harris and her running mate Minnesota Governor Tim Walz will be nominated as the Democratic candidates for US' president and vice president.</p>

<p>Biden is expected to deliver a 'swan song' address and endorse his deputy against Donald Trump, the former US President.</p>

<p>Former US presidents Barack Obama and Bill Clinton are also expected to speak. The Democrats will also honour Hilary Clinton, their official candidate who lost to Donald Trump in the 2016 US Presidential Elections.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/8li8p3d_kamala-harris-at-dnc_625x300_20_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mpox-death-count-crosses-570-as-congo-awaits-vaccines-6374625]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Mpox Death Count Crosses 570 As Congo Awaits Vaccines]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mpox-death-count-crosses-570-as-congo-awaits-vaccines-6374625]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 20 Aug 2024 06:49:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Mpox cases and deaths are rising in the Democratic Republic of Congo (DRC) as the central African country awaits vaccines from the United States and Japan, the health minister said on Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Mpox cases and deaths are rising in the Democratic Republic of Congo (DRC) as the central African country awaits vaccines from the United States and Japan, the health minister said on Monday.</p>

<p>The count this year has risen in a few days from 16,000 cases and 548 deaths to 16,700 cases and "a little more than 570" deaths, Health Minister Samuel-Roger Kamba said.</p>

<p>"We are talking about a continental emergency," Kamba told a press briefing as the World Health Organisation (WHO) called on affected countries to step up vaccination programmes to counter a more deadly strain of mpox.</p>

<p>The WHO on Wednesday declared the mpox surge in Africa a global public health emergency. Outbreaks have been reported in Burundi, Kenya, Rwanda and Uganda since July. A case of the new strain has also been detected in Sweden.</p>

<p>The United States has promised 50,000 vaccine doses for DRC, while Japan on Monday agreed Monday to send 3.5 million doses, "only for children," a medical source, who spoke on condition of anonymity, told AFP.</p>

<p>The source said that DRC "plans to vaccinate four million people including 3.5 million children".</p>

<p>"I hope by the next week we will already be able to see the vaccines arriving," Kamba said.</p>

<p>"The vaccine is a solution to our problems," he added, urging people to get jabbed.</p>

<p>"Our strategic vaccination plan is ready. We are just waiting for the vaccines to arrive."</p>

<h3><strong>WHO calls for vaccines&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Cases have now surfaced in all 26 provinces in the country of around 100 million people.</p>

<p>The WHO has declared the outbreak "a public health emergency of international concern" -- its highest alert category.</p>

<p>On Monday it released updated guidelines on countering the surge, including by "the agile adaptation of immunization strategies and plans to concerned areas".</p>

<p>It called on countries to "scale up efforts to thoroughly investigate cases and outbreaks of mpox disease" to understand its transmission and prevent the spread "to household members and communities".</p>

<p>Health authorities must report new cases on a weekly basis and "identify, monitor and support the contacts of people with mpox to prevent onward transmission," it said.</p>

<p>It added that countries had to be ready to provide food and other support for mpox patients "including, as warranted and possible, isolation in care centres and guidance for home-based care".</p>

<p>The WHO said there has to be greater "cross-border collaboration" to monitor and handle suspected mpox cases "without resorting to general travel and trade restrictions unnecessarily impacting local, regional or national economies".</p>

<p>While mpox has been known for decades, a new more deadly and more transmissible strain -- clade 1b -- causes death in about 3.6 per cent of cases, with children more at risk, according to the WHO.</p>

<p>Kamba said that mpox is reaching "more and more young people" in DRC and there are a lot of children under 15 who have been affected.</p>

<p>A total of 18,737 suspected or confirmed cases of mpox were reported in Africa since the beginning of the year, including 1,200 cases in one week, the African Union health agency said Saturday.</p>

<p>Formerly called monkeypox, the virus was discovered in 1958 in Denmark, in monkeys kept for research.</p>

<p>It was first discovered in humans in 1970 in what is now the DRC.</p>

<p>Mpox is caused by a virus transmitted to humans by infected animals but can also be passed from human to human through close physical contact.</p>

<p>The disease causes fever, muscular aches and large boil-like skin lesions.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/sb4ndo5g_mpox-reuters_625x300_20_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mpox is caused by a virus transmitted to humans by infected animals (representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/former-congressman-george-santos-pleads-guilty-to-fraud-6374415]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Former Congressman George Santos Pleads Guilty To Fraud]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/former-congressman-george-santos-pleads-guilty-to-fraud-6374415]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 20 Aug 2024 05:35:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Disgraced former Republican lawmaker George Santos, who was expelled from the US Congress for using stolen donor cash to bankroll a lavish lifestyle, pleaded guilty on Monday to wire fraud and identity theft.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Disgraced former Republican lawmaker George Santos, who was expelled from the US Congress for using stolen donor cash to bankroll a lavish lifestyle, pleaded guilty on Monday to wire fraud and identity theft.</p>

<p>Judge Joanna Seybert ordered Santos to pay more than $370,000 in restitution during a court hearing in Central Islip and set sentencing for February 7.</p>

<p>Santos, 36, faces at least two years in prison and a maximum of 22 years.</p>

<p>"After years of telling lies, George Santos stood in the courthouse right behind me and finally, under oath, told the truth," Breon Peace, US attorney for the Eastern District of New York, told reporters.</p>

<p>"And that truth is that he is a criminal," Peace said. "He lied, he stole and he conned people."</p>

<p>An emotional Santos, speaking to reporters after entering his guilty plea, apologized to his former constituents and said he had allowed "ambition to cloud my judgment," leading him to make "decisions that were unethical."</p>

<p>"This plea is not just an admission of guilt but an acknowledgement that I need to be held accountable like any other American that breaks the law," he said through tears.</p>

<p>The downfall of the congressman from Long Island came after it was revealed he had fabricated almost his entire backstory including his education, religion and work history.</p>

<p>Santos was elected to the US House of Representatives in 2022 and indicted the following year for stealing from campaign donors and engaging in credit card fraud, money laundering and identity theft.</p>

<p>Santos used donor money for Botox treatments and the OnlyFans porn website, as well as luxury Italian goods and vacations to the Hamptons and Las Vegas, according to an investigation by a congressional ethics committee.</p>

<p>He had been scheduled to go on trial on September 9 on some two dozen charges but opted instead to enter a guilty plea to wire fraud and identity theft.</p>

<p>Santos's bizarre biographical fabrications included claiming to have worked for Goldman Sachs, being Jewish and having been a college volleyball star.</p>

<p>He was ultimately doomed by the congressional probe that found overwhelming evidence of misconduct and accused him of seeking to "fraudulently exploit every aspect of his House candidacy."</p>

<p>Santos was expelled from the House last year, becoming only the third person to be ejected as a US lawmaker since the Civil War, a rebuke previously reserved for traitors and convicted criminals.</p>

<p>In February, voters in his suburban New York district picked Democrat Tom Suozzi to replace him.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/r5m5l0rg_george-santos_625x300_20_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Santos, 36, faces at least two years in prison and a maximum of 22 years.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-bidens-son-hunter-loses-bid-to-toss-tax-evasion-case-6374389]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Joe Biden's Son Hunter Loses Bid To Toss Tax Evasion Case]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-bidens-son-hunter-loses-bid-to-toss-tax-evasion-case-6374389]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 20 Aug 2024 05:23:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A judge on Monday denied a bid by U.S. President Joe Biden's son, Hunter, to dismiss a federal tax evasion case brought against him in California.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A judge on Monday denied a bid by U.S. President Joe Biden's son, Hunter, to dismiss a federal tax evasion case brought against him in California.</p>

<p>Hunter Biden was convicted in Delaware in June for lying about his illegal drug use to buy a gun, and is scheduled to go to trial in September in the tax evasion case.</p>

<p>Biden, who has pleaded not guilty to the tax charges, had argued that David Weiss, the special counsel leading both prosecutions, was illegally appointed.</p>

<p>The president's son had relied on a federal judge's decision dismissing a criminal case accusing former President Donald Trump of illegally retaining classified documents after leaving office.</p>

<p>Florida-based U.S. District Judge Aileen Cannon found the appointment of the special counsel in that case, Jack Smith, violated the U.S. Constitution because Congress had not given him the authority to pursue the case. Smith's office is appealing.</p>

<p>But U.S. District Judge Mark Scarsi in Los Angeles said on Monday there was no valid basis to reconsider a prior order denying Hunter Biden's bid to throw out the tax evasion indictment.</p>

<p>"The court declines to reach the merits of the motion because there is no valid basis for reconsideration of the court's order denying Mr. Biden's motion to dismiss," the judge wrote.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-12/7odfp46s_hunter-biden-afp_625x300_10_December_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hunter Biden is scheduled to go to trial in September in the tax evasion case.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-says-he-may-end-ev-tax-credit-is-open-to-having-elon-musk-as-adviser-6374360]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Says May Appoint Elon Musk As Adviser If He Defeats Kamala Harris]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-says-he-may-end-ev-tax-credit-is-open-to-having-elon-musk-as-adviser-6374360]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 20 Aug 2024 05:16:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump said on Monday that if elected he would consider ending a $7,500 tax credit for electric-vehicle purchases and that he would be open to naming Tesla CEO Elon Musk to a cabinet or advisory role.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump said on Monday that if elected he would consider ending a $7,500 tax credit for electric-vehicle purchases and that he would be open to naming Tesla CEO Elon Musk to a cabinet or advisory role.</p>

<p>"Tax credits and tax incentives are not generally a very good thing," Trump told Reuters in an interview after a campaign event in York, Pennsylvania, when asked about the EV credit.</p>

<p>Asked if he would consider naming Musk to an advisory role or cabinet job, Trump said he would. "He's a very smart guy. I certainly would, if he would do it, I certainly would. He's a brilliant guy," Trump said.</p>

<p>Musk last month publicly endorsed Trump in the U.S. presidential race. Tesla did not immediately respond to a request for comment.</p>

<p>If elected, Trump could take steps to reverse Treasury Department rules that have made it easier for automakers to take advantage of the $7,500 credit or could ask the U.S. Congress to repeal it entirely. While president, Trump sought to repeal the EV tax credit which was later expanded by President Joe Biden in 2022.</p>

<p>"I'm not making any final decisions on it," Trump said of the EV tax credit. "I'm a big fan of electric cars, but I'm a fan of gasoline-propelled cars, and also hybrids and whatever else happens to come along."</p>

<p>He added that he would rescind the Biden administration rules that will prod automakers to build more EVs and plug-in hybrids to meet stricter emissions standards and said he sees a "much smaller market" for EVs because of cost and battery range issues.</p>

<p>Trump also said on Monday he would take steps to discourage exports of vehicles produced by the Detroit Three automakers and others from Mexico for U.S consumers by imposing new tariffs and would prevent Chinese automakers from building new plants in Mexico for U.S. market vehicles. He made similar threats during his presidency.</p>

<p>"If you put tariffs on those cars, they're going to make it here" Trump said. "It's very simple. It's not complicated. If you tell Mexico, 'look, you're stealing our car industry,' which they're doing now."</p>

<p>But Trump is open to Chinese and other automakers building vehicles in the United States. "We're going to give incentives, and if China and other countries want to come here and sell the cars, they're going to build plants here, and they're going to hire our workers," Trump said. "We will make our own cars. I want to make our own cars."</p>

<p>Separately, Trump harshly criticized Alphabet's Google but declined to say if he thought the technology company should be broken up after a judge ruled this month that Google was an illegal monopoly.</p>

<p>"They're almost like the Wild West," Trump said of Google, without elaborating on what penalty it should face. "They're going to have to pay a great price."</p>

<p>Trump has previously said he would prevent short video app TikTok from being banned despite a law approved in April that sets a deadline of Jan. 19, 2025, for Chinese owner ByteDance to divest TikTok's U.S. assets. Asked if he could accept continued Chinese ownership of TikTok, Trump did not directly answer but said ByteDance might sell.</p>

<p>"It's very hard to ban something like that, because you're talking about free speech," Trump said. "You're talking about a lot of different things go into that equation, but TikTok has treated me very well."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/map7l9ho_trump-musk_650x400_13_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Elon Musk last month publicly endorsed Trump in the U.S. presidential race.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-intelligence-officials-say-iran-responsible-for-trump-campaign-hack-6374219]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Intelligence Officials Say Iran Responsible For Trump Campaign Hack]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-intelligence-officials-say-iran-responsible-for-trump-campaign-hack-6374219]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 20 Aug 2024 04:20:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US intelligence officials said on Monday that they considered Iran to be responsible for a recent hack of Donald Trump's presidential campaign, according to a statement, adding that it was part of ongoing cyber attacks by Tehran.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Iran was behind a recent hack targeting Donald Trump's presidential campaign, US security agencies said on Monday, accusing Tehran of seeking to influence the 2024 election.</p>

<p>The statement from the Office of the Director of National Intelligence (ODNI), the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI), and the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA) confirmed the Trump campaign claim from earlier this month that it had been targeted, potentially by Iran.</p>

<p>"We have observed increasingly aggressive Iranian activity during this election cycle, specifically involving influence operations targeting the American public and cyber operations targeting presidential campaigns," the security agencies said.</p>

<p>"This includes the recently reported activities to compromise former President Trump's campaign, which the (intelligence community) attributes to Iran," they said.</p>

<p>The intelligence community "is confident that the Iranians have through social engineering and other efforts sought access to individuals with direct access to the presidential campaigns of both political parties. Such activity, including thefts and disclosures, are intended to influence the US election process."</p>

<p>Trump's campaign said on August 10 that it had been hacked, blaming "foreign sources" for distributing internal communications and a dossier on running mate J.D. Vance.</p>

<p>"These documents were obtained illegally from foreign sources hostile to the United States, intended to interfere with the 2024 election and sow chaos throughout our Democratic process," Trump campaign spokesman Steven Cheung said in a statement.</p>

<p>Trump's campaign implied Iran was behind the move as news outlet Politico reported it had received emails with the campaign material from a source who refused to identify themselves.</p>

<p>Cheung cited a report from Microsoft this week that said Iranian hackers "sent a spear phishing email in June to a high-ranking official on a presidential campaign."</p>

<p>The materials received by Politico included research on vetting Vance, Trump's vice presidential pick.</p>

<p>In 2016, a hack of Democratic National Committee emails -- blamed on Russians -- exposed internal party communications, including about candidate Hillary Clinton.</p>

<p>Trump, who would go on to win the election, was criticized for encouraging the hack.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/15cb3sdo_donald-trump_625x300_18_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US intelligence officials said that Iran to be responsible for a hack of Trump's presidential campaign.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistan-ex-pm-imran-khan-applies-to-be-oxford-chancellor-from-jail-6374166]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Pakistan Ex-PM Imran Khan Applies To Be Oxford Chancellor From Jail]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistan-ex-pm-imran-khan-applies-to-be-oxford-chancellor-from-jail-6374166]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 20 Aug 2024 04:05:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Pakistan's jailed former prime minister Imran Khan has applied to become the next chancellor of Britain's prestigious University of Oxford, his party said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pakistan's jailed former prime minister Imran Khan has applied to become the next chancellor of Britain's prestigious University of Oxford, his party said.</p>

<p>Khan, prime minister from 2018 to 2022, has just marked one year in prison on various charges from corruption to inciting violence that he said are politically motivated and designed to keep him from power.</p>

<p>"Imran Khan had given instructions that he would like to submit his application and now the application scrutiny will take place," Sayed Zulfikar Bukhari, the London-based spokesman for Khan's Pakistan Tehreek-e-Insaf (PTI) party, told AFP.</p>

<p>"It's a ceremonial post but one with utmost prestige and importance and Imran Khan, being one of the larger or more popular names coming out of Oxford, it would be brilliant to see him as chancellor," he said.</p>

<p>Conservative peer Chris Patten, the last British governor of Hong Kong, announced in February he was stepping down as Oxford chancellor.</p>

<p>The list of candidates for the 10-year term will not be made public until October, according to the university's website, with voting taking place at the end of the month.</p>

<p>Khan graduated from Oxford in 1975 after studying philosophy, politics, and economics.</p>

<p>He led a playboy lifestyle during his career as one of Pakistan's greatest cricket players, regularly gracing the pages of Britain's gossip magazines.</p>

<p>Married three times, including to British socialite and filmmaker Jemima Goldsmith, he later turned to philanthropy and politics.</p>

<p>He faced a backlash from women's rights groups while prime minister for linking Pakistan's high rates of sexual violence to the clothes that women wear.</p>

<p>Khan was ousted in 2022 and then launched a comeback campaign in which he criticised Pakistan's powerful military, whose leading generals had once backed him, and drew massive crowds onto the nation's streets.</p>

<p>"If he does become the chancellor, he would be the first of Asian descent. It wouldn't be something only for Pakistan, but it would be a great achievement for all of Asia and the rest of the world," Bukhari said.</p>

<p>Other prominent applicants and Oxford alumni include former foreign secretary William Hague and former EU trade commissioner Peter Mandelson, according to British media reports.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/jbg3lne_imran-khan-reuters_625x300_04_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Imran Khan graduated from Oxford in 1975 after studying philosophy, politics, and economics.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-democratic-convention-live-updates-us-democratic-national-convention-to-kick-start-in-chicago-6373201]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Live: "I've Been Determined To Keep America Moving Forward," Says Biden]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-democratic-convention-live-updates-us-democratic-national-convention-to-kick-start-in-chicago-6373201]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 20 Aug 2024 03:51:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Thousands have gathered in Chicago for the four-day Democratic Convention to show their support for Kamala Harris as officially nominated democratic party candidate for the US presidential polls 2024.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Thousands have gathered in Chicago for the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/democrats-cheer-joe-biden-and-kamala-harris-in-chicago-convention-amid-protester-march-6368883" target="_blank">Democratic Convention</a> to show their support for <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-to-pass-torch-to-kamala-harris-at-democratic-convention-10-points-6373095#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">Kamala Harris</a> as officially nominated democratic party candidate against Republican rival <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-shows-doctored-pictures-showing-taylor-swifts-support-6373114" target="_blank">Donald Trump</a> in the 2024 US presidential elections.</p>

<p>The convention will also mark the official nomination of Harris' running mate and Minnesota Governor Tim Walz.&nbsp;</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-forever-grateful-to-you-kamala-harris-at-democratic-convention-6374653" target="_blank">Joe Biden</a>, who quit the US presidential race last month, also made his farewell speech at the convention and said he has been "determined to keep America moving forward, not going back" as the US President.</p>

<h2><strong>Here are live updates on Democratic Convention:</strong></h2>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/jk296p78_joe-biden_625x300_20_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Joe Biden, who quit the US presidential race last month, speaking at the convention]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/we-dont-need-hamas-criticises-us-gaza-truce-deal-6374113]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["We Don't Need...": Hamas Criticises US' Gaza Truce Deal]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/we-dont-need-hamas-criticises-us-gaza-truce-deal-6374113]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 20 Aug 2024 03:49:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hamas senior official Osama Hamdan criticized U.S. Secretary of State Antony Blinken's statement on Monday that Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu accepted an updated proposal.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;Hamas senior official Osama Hamdan criticized U.S. Secretary of State Antony Blinken's statement on Monday that Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu accepted an updated proposal, saying it "raises many ambiguities" because it is "not what was presented to us nor what we agreed on."</p>

<p>Hamdan told Reuters that Hamas has already confirmed to mediators that "we don't need new Gaza ceasefire negotiations, we need to agree on an implementation mechanism."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/4dmff0tg_israel-hamas-war_625x300_31_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US Secretary of State Antony Blinken said that Israel has accepted US proposal for Gaza truce.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-to-pass-torch-to-kamala-harris-at-democratic-convention-10-points-6373095]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden To Pass Torch To Kamala Harris At Democratic Convention: 10 Points]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-to-pass-torch-to-kamala-harris-at-democratic-convention-10-points-6373095]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 20 Aug 2024 02:59:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The 2024 Democratic National Convention will officially declare US Vice President Kamala Harris as its official nomination for the Presidential election today, replacing incumbent Joe Biden, who withdrew from the race last month.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<ol>
	<li>The four-day event, which will end on August 22, will officially nominate Kamala Harris's Vice President pick, Minnesota Governor Tim Walz, in the presidential elections.</li>
	<li>Former US Presidents Barack Obama and Bill Clinton are expected to speak at the National Convention and bid adieu to Joe Biden. The Democrats will also honour Hilary Clinton, their official candidate who lost to Donald Trump in the 2016 US Presidential Elections.</li>
	<li>Last month, Mr Biden dropped out of the Presidential race just 100 days before the election, an unprecedented move in modern US political history. Concerns over the 81-year-old's health surrounded the Presidential campaigns, with rival Republicans targeting the Democrats over the issue. The concerns were aggravated after Biden's presidential debate with Trump in June.</li>
	<li>To designate a formal nominee, delegates chosen from 50 US states, the US capital and overseas territories attend their party's nominating convention to officially anoint the candidate. Biden backed Kamala Harris as the candidate which was later endorsed by several leaders including former US President Barack Obama.</li>
	<li>Joe Biden will give a prime-time address and make a case for his incumbent deputy, Kamala Harris, who is up against Donald Trump, the former US President, with multiple court cases and survivor of an assassination attempt.</li>
	<li>In the Primary Election, a poll where parties select their candidates for the general election, Joe Biden won overwhelmingly with 87.1 per cent votes. The 26th Democratic National Convention will serve as a farewell for Mr Biden as he hangs up his boots. In 1968, President Lyndon B Johnson declared in the middle of the Vietnam War that he would not run for re-election.</li>
	<li>Kamala Harris, the first Black and South Asian US Vice President, is expected to share the stage with Mr Biden. Kamala Harris, who considers herself an "underdog" in the race against Trump, earlier said, "A lot of work has to be done to earn the vote of the American people,"</li>
	<li>Security has been increased near the convention centre in Chicago after an array of possible threats, including tens of thousands of protesters opposing Biden's support for Israel's actions in Gaza. They are expected to march through the city outside the security perimeter.</li>
	<li>The Secret Service, FBI and the local police reportedly spent a year formulating a security plan and cordoning off areas near the United Center Arena where the convention will take place. Musicians and Hollywood celebrities are expected to attend the event.</li>
	<li>Last week, Biden and Harris had put up a show of unity in Maryland when they made their first joint trip since the change of the Democratic Party's plans for the Presidential Elections.</li>
</ol>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-10/90qr96k8_kamala-harris-joe-biden-birthday-wish-tweet-_625x300_21_October_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The four-day event will end on August 22 (File photo)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-approves-3-5-billion-sale-of-military-helicopters-to-south-korea-6373961]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Approves $3.5 Billion Sale Of Military Helicopters To South Korea]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-approves-3-5-billion-sale-of-military-helicopters-to-south-korea-6373961]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 20 Aug 2024 02:55:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United States on Monday announced its approval of a $3.5-billion sale to South Korea of up to 36 AH-64E Apache attack helicopters and related equipment, including missiles.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United States on Monday announced its approval of a $3.5-billion sale to South Korea of up to 36 AH-64E Apache attack helicopters and related equipment, including missiles.</p>

<p>"The proposed sale will improve the Republic of Korea's capability to meet current and future threats by providing a credible force capable of deterring adversaries and participating in regional operations," the Defense Security Cooperation Agency (DSCA) said in a statement.</p>

<p>The sale will improve "the security of a major ally that is a force for political stability and economic progress in the Indo-Pacific region," the statement said, using the US foreign policy term for the Asia Pacific region.</p>

<p>The State Department approved the possible sale of the helicopters to South Korea, and the DSCA on Monday provided the required notification to Congress, which still needs to sign off on the transaction.</p>

<p>The principal contractors for the deal will be Boeing and Lockheed Martin, the DSCA said.</p>

<p>The announcement came on the same day that Washington and Seoul began major annual joint military drills, with new exercises aimed at containing the nuclear-armed North.</p>

<p>The Ulchi Freedom Shield exercise runs until August 29 and will involve thousands of military personnel.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-02/em685c0s_us-south-korea-reuters-650_625x300_19_February_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The principal contractors for the deal will be Boeing and Lockheed Martin, the Department said.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistan-confirms-mpox-case-detected-last-week-not-new-strain-6373415]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Pakistan Confirms Mpox Case Detected Last Week Not New Strain]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistan-confirms-mpox-case-detected-last-week-not-new-strain-6373415]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 20 Aug 2024 00:02:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A case of mpox in Pakistan announced last week was not the new strain spreading through Africa, health officials said Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A case of mpox in Pakistan announced last week was not the new strain spreading through Africa, health officials said Monday.</p>

<p>The mpox diagnosis in a 34-year-old man recently returned from a Gulf country was declared by health officials on Friday, while testing over the exact strain was carried out.</p>

<p>"The virus has been classified as Clade 2b," the health ministry said in a statement on Monday.</p>

<p>"Currently, the ongoing outbreak in the Democratic Republic of the Congo (DRC) is primarily associated with Clade 1b. Notably, as of now, there have been no reported cases of Clade 1b in Pakistan."</p>

<p>Mpox infections surged worldwide in May 2022, mostly affecting gay and bisexual men due to the Clade 2b subclade, but cases have largely subsided.</p>

<p>The World Health Organization declared last week the rapid spread of the new Clade 1b strain in Africa a public health emergency of international concern -- the highest alarm it can sound.</p>

<p>Sweden's Public Health Agency said Thursday that it had registered a case of the Clade 1b subclade, the first to be diagnosed out of Africa.</p>

<p>Around 16,000 cases have been recorded in the Democratic Republic of Congo, the epicentre of the epidemic which has killed 548 people in the country so far.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-07/fcd7k5c_monkeypox-afp_650x400_23_July_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["The virus has been classified as Clade 2b," Pak health ministry said. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/as-polio-reemerges-in-gaza-a-mother-fears-for-her-childs-health-6373369]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[As Polio Reemerges In Gaza, A Mother Fears For Her Child's Health]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/as-polio-reemerges-in-gaza-a-mother-fears-for-her-childs-health-6373369]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 19 Aug 2024 23:57:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In Gaza, a mother worries that her month-old son, Mohammed, could be infected with polio after the Palestinian health ministry confirmed the first case in the enclave on Friday, ending a 25 year period in which the Strip was polio-free.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In Gaza, a mother worries that her month-old son, Mohammed, could be infected with polio after the Palestinian health ministry confirmed the first case in the enclave on Friday, ending a 25 year period in which the Strip was polio-free.</p>

<p>Just three days after his birth, Ghada al-Ghandour's son Mohammed started developing skin rashes.</p>

<p>"He had skin rashes as if he was burnt," she said.</p>

<p>A doctor told her there were no creams to treat her child.</p>

<p>She later brought him to Al-Aqsa Martyrs Hospital in Deir al-Balah in central Gaza to seek a diagnosis and treatment.</p>

<p>The rash fueled his mother's fears that other symptoms and diseases could follow due to a lack of hygiene and medical supplies in Gaza after more than 10 months of conflict.</p>

<p>In a statement, the Palestinian health ministry confirmed the first case of polio in the city of Deir al-Balah had been detected in a 10-month-old baby who had not been vaccinated.</p>

<p>Likewise, Mohammed has not received a polio vaccine.</p>

<p>"My son was deprived of the first vaccine in his first month," his mother said.</p>

<p>Polio was detected in sewage in Gaza's Deir al-Balah and Khan Younis governorates, Dr. Hamid Jafari, a polio specialist at the World Health Organization (WHO), said on Aug. 7, adding it was possible the virus had been circulating since September.</p>

<p><strong>'YET ANOTHER THREAT TO CHILDREN'</strong></p>

<p>Poliomyelitis, which is spread mainly through the fecal-oral route, is a highly infectious virus that can invade the nervous system and cause paralysis.</p>

<p>Children under 5 are most at risk from the viral disease, and especially infants under 2 since normal vaccination regimens have been disrupted by the war.</p>

<p>"If the occupation (Israeli forces) continues to close the (border) crossing and denies access to vaccines, it will lead to a health disaster," said Khalil al-Daqran, spokesperson of Al-Aqsa Martyrs Hospital.</p>

<p>Israel announced on Sunday that it would facilitate the transfer into Gaza of polio vaccines for around one million children.</p>

<p>More than 43,000 vials of the vaccine were expected to arrive in Israel in the coming weeks and would be sent to Gaza, according to a statement from COGAT, the Israeli defence agency that coordinated civilian matters with the Palestinians. This would be enough for two rounds of doses for over a million children, it said.</p>

<p>But Al-Daqran of Al-Aqsa Martyrs Hospital said a vaccination campaign could not happen without a pause in fighting.</p>

<p>The reemergence of polio "represents yet another threat to the children in the Gaza Strip and neighbouring countries," the WHO said on Aug. 16.</p>

<p>Nearly half of Gaza's 2.3 million population are under the age of 18 and around 15% are children under the age of 5, according to the Palestinian Central Bureau of Statistics.</p>

<p>Aside from the resurgence of polio and the threat of other diseases, Palestinians face a humanitarian crisis with shortages of food, fuel and water inflicting suffering every day.</p>

<p>The war in Gaza started after Hamas attacked southern Israel, killing 1,200 people and taking over 250 hostage, according to Israeli tallies. The death count of Palestinians killed by the Israeli military campaign has exceeded 40,000, according to Gaza authorities.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/id5us9h_gaza-polio-scare_625x300_19_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Children under 5 are most at risk from polio]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-islamic-jihad-claim-responsibility-for-bomb-blast-in-tel-aviv-6373359]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hamas, Islamic Jihad Claim Responsibility For Bomb Blast In Tel Aviv]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-islamic-jihad-claim-responsibility-for-bomb-blast-in-tel-aviv-6373359]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 19 Aug 2024 23:52:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The armed wings of Hamas and Islamic Jihad claimed responsibility on Monday for a bomb blast near a synagogue in Tel Aviv that Israeli police and the Shin Bet intelligence agency described as a terrorist attack.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The armed wings of Hamas and Islamic Jihad claimed responsibility on Monday for a bomb blast near a synagogue in Tel Aviv that Israeli police and the Shin Bet intelligence agency described as a terrorist attack.</p>

<p>A man who was carrying the bomb was killed and a passerby was injured in the incident late on Sunday, according to police at the scene in Israel's commercial capital.</p>

<p>Israeli government spokesperson David Mencer said the man was carrying a backpack loaded with explosives that detonated "before he managed to reach a more heavily populated area".</p>

<p>In a joint statement, the two Palestinian groups said their "martyrdom operations" inside Israel would return to the forefront as long as the "occupation's massacres and assassination policy continue". This was an allusion to Israel's offensive in Gaza and the July 31 killing of Hamas leader Ismail Haniyeh in Tehran.</p>

<p>Israel has neither claimed nor denied responsibility for Haniyeh's death in the Iranian capital.</p>

<p>The war in Gaza began on Oct. 7 last year when Hamas gunmen entered across the border into Israeli communities, killing around 1,200 people and abducting about 250 hostages according to Israeli tallies.</p>

<p>Israel's military campaign has since levelled wide swathes of the Gaza Strip and killed at least 40,000 people, according to the enclave's health authorities.</p>

<p>Sunday's explosion in Tel Aviv came about an hour after U.S. Secretary of State Antony Blinken arrived in Tel Aviv to push for a ceasefire in Gaza to end the 10-month-old war between Israel and Hamas.</p>

<p>There has been increased urgency to reach a ceasefire deal amid fears of an escalation across the wider region. Iran has threatened to retaliate against Israel after the assassination of Haniyeh.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/qpvr6jso_tel-aviv-bomb-blast_625x300_19_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sunday's explosion in Tel Aviv came about an hour after Blinken arrived in Tel Aviv]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/blinken-says-israel-accepts-gaza-truce-proposal-ball-now-in-hamas-court-6373320]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Blinken Says Israel "Accepts" Gaza Truce Proposal, Ball Now In Hamas' Court]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/blinken-says-israel-accepts-gaza-truce-proposal-ball-now-in-hamas-court-6373320]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 19 Aug 2024 23:47:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Secretary of State Antony Blinken on Monday urged Hamas to accept a US bridging proposal for a Gaza ceasefire and hostage release deal after what he said was a "very constructive" meeting with Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Secretary of State Antony Blinken on Monday urged Hamas to accept a US bridging proposal for a Gaza ceasefire and hostage release deal after what he said was a "very constructive" meeting with Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu.</p>

<p>He had earlier said the latest push for a deal was probably the best and possibly last opportunity, urging both sides towards agreement.</p>

<p>Talks in Qatar last week paused without a breakthrough, but the negotiations are expected to resume this week based on the US proposal to bridge the gaps between Israel and Hamas.</p>

<p>However, with the Palestinian Islamist group announcing a resumption of suicide bombing inside Israel after many years, and medics saying Israeli military strikes killed at least 30 Palestinians across the Gaza Strip on Monday, there are few signs of conciliation on the ground.</p>

<p>"In a very constructive meeting with Prime Minister Netanyahu today, he confirmed to me that Israel accepts the bridging proposal - that he supports it," Blinken told reporters in Tel Aviv.</p>

<p>"It's now incumbent on Hamas to do the same, and then the parties, with the help of the mediators - the United States, Egypt and Qatar - have to come together and complete the process of reaching clear understandings about how they'll implement the commitments that they've made under this agreement."</p>

<p>Despite US expressions of optimism and Netanyahu's office describing the meeting as positive, both Israel and Hamas have signalled that any deal will be difficult.</p>

<p>Hamas accused Netanyahu on Sunday of "thwarting the mediators' efforts" and Turkey said Hamas envoys had told it that US officials were "painting an overly optimistic picture".</p>

<p>Months of on-off talks have circled the same issues, with Israel saying the war can only end with the destruction of Hamas as a military and political force and Hamas saying it will only accept a permanent, and not a temporary, ceasefire.</p>

<p>There are disagreements over Israel's continued military presence inside Gaza, particularly along the border with Egypt, over the free movement of Palestinians inside the territory, and over the identity and number of prisoners to be freed in a swap.</p>

<p>The current war in Gaza began on October 7 last year when Hamas gunmen rushed across the border into Israeli communities, killing around 1,200 people and abducting about 250 hostages according to Israeli tallies.</p>

<p>Israel's military campaign has since levelled swathes of Gaza, driving nearly all of its 2.3 million people from their homes, giving rise to deadly hunger and disease and killing at least 40,000 people according to Palestinian health authorities.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/iq5k0vlg_-gaza-strip_625x300_12_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The current war in Gaza began on October 7 last year (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>