<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Jul 2024 09:31:17 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/amid-health-concerns-biden-to-make-announcement-on-re-election-bid-report-6137554]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Amid Health Concerns, Biden To Make Announcement On Re-Election Bid: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/amid-health-concerns-biden-to-make-announcement-on-re-election-bid-report-6137554]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Jul 2024 09:31:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden is expected to make a major announcement on his re-election bid, with several senior Democratic leaders suggesting that he leave the race following his disastrous debate performance.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden is expected to make a major announcement on his re-election bid, with several senior Democratic leaders suggesting that he leave the race following his disastrous debate performance, a failed assassination attempt on his rival Donald Trump, his poor health, and falling poll numbers, according to media reports.</p>

<p>“Several people close to President Biden said on Thursday that they believe he has begun to accept the idea that he may not be able to win in November and may have to drop out of the race, bowing to the growing demands of many anxious members of his party,” The New York Times reported.</p>

<p>Biden, 81, is spending time at his Delaware residence in isolation after he was tested positive for COVID-19. Media reports said that top leaders of the Democratic party, including former president Barack Obama, former House Speaker Nancy Pelosi, and Senate Majority Leader Chuck Schumer, have asked him to leave the presidential race, in the absence of which the party risks losing the White House, the Senate and the House of Representatives.</p>

<p>“People close to top Democrats said Thursday that it now appeared it was a matter of when—not if—Biden bows out of the presidential race. In the past day or so, former President Barack Obama has told friends who have called him that Biden's path to victory is narrow, according to people familiar with the calls,” The NYT report said.</p>

<p>The Washington Post reported Thursday night that Pelosi has stepped up her behind-the-scenes role in working to persuade the president to bow out of campaign. Obama has said that he has a very slight chance of winning the race.</p>

<p>According to The Hill, Vice President Kamala Harris has started looking for options for her running mate. The three being talked about right now are Senator Mark Kelly, Kentucky Governor Andy Beshear and North Carolina Governor Roy Cooper.</p>

<p>Most of the media reports said that Biden's announcement on his re-election bid might come after the conclusion of the Republican National Convention in Milwaukee.</p>

<p>“One of the people close to him warned that the president had not yet made up his mind to leave the race after three weeks of insisting that almost nothing would drive him out. But another said that 'reality is setting in', and that it would not be a surprise if Mr Biden made an announcement soon endorsing Vice President Kamala Harris as his replacement,” The NYT reported. PTI LKJ SCY SCY</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/81g72018_joe-biden_625x300_19_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-trumps-unique-tribute-to-firefighter-who-died-in-pennsylvania-shooting-6138003]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Video: Trump's Unique Tribute To Firefighter Who Died In Pennsylvania Shooting]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-trumps-unique-tribute-to-firefighter-who-died-in-pennsylvania-shooting-6138003]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Jul 2024 09:28:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump, in his acceptance speech for the Republican presidential nomination at the Republican convention in Milwaukee today, paid tribute to the man who lost his life during a shooting at his rally in Pennsylvania.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump, in his acceptance speech for the Republican presidential nomination at the Republican convention in Milwaukee today, paid tribute to the man who lost his life during a shooting at his rally in Pennsylvania.</p>

<p>In his first public address since surviving an assassination attempt, Trump honoured Corey Comperatore, the firefighter who was killed by the shooter. He solemnly presented the man's helmet and uniform, kissing them in homage. Trump hailed Corey as a "highly respected former fire chief" and recounted how he "lost his life selflessly acting as a human shield to protect others."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Tragically, the shooter claimed the life of one of our fellow Americans, Corey Comperatore, and seriously wounded two other great warriors, David Dutch and James Copenhaver.<br />
<br />
- President Donald J. Trump <a href="https://t.co/6W04vbXSKA">pic.twitter.com/6W04vbXSKA</a></p>
— Team Trump (Text TRUMP to 88022) (@TeamTrump) <a href="https://twitter.com/TeamTrump/status/1814137280287686983?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 19, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>Trump also expressed his respects to those injured in the attack, referring to them as "dedicated Trumpsters."</p>

<p>Last week, during a campaign rally in Butler, Pennsylvania, the former US President was struck near the ear in what appeared to be an assassination attempt by a gunman.</p>

<p>Agents from the Secret Service, the law enforcement agency responsible for protecting US political leaders, swiftly intervened, rushing to the stage and escorting him quickly to a nearby vehicle.</p>

<p>The gunman and a bystander were killed, and two spectators were critically injured. The deceased spectator was a 50-year-old firefighter.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/1g3q1uf8_donald-trump-afp_625x300_19_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump solemnly presented the man's helmet and uniform, kissing them in homage.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chile-earthquake-7-4-magnitude-earthquake-hits-northern-chile-6137944]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[7.4- Magnitude Earthquake Hits Northern Chile]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chile-earthquake-7-4-magnitude-earthquake-hits-northern-chile-6137944]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Jul 2024 09:22:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A major magnitude 7.4 earthquake struck northern Chile on Thursday, the United States Geological Survey said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A major magnitude 7.4 earthquake struck northern Chile on Thursday, the United States Geological Survey said.</p>

<p>The epicenter of the tremor was located 164 miles (265 kilometers) east of the coastal city of Antofagasta, at a depth of 78.5 miles (126 kilometers).</p>

<p>"So far there are no reports of injuries or major damage, but teams are gathering information," Chilean President Gabriel Boric wrote on X.</p>

<p>Chile is situated along the Pacific "Ring of Fire", an arc of intense seismic activity that stretches from Japan through Southeast Asia and across the Pacific basin.</p>

<p>In 2010, an 8.8-magnitude quake unleashed a tsunami that swept away entire villages in the south and center of the country, leaving about 520 people dead.</p>

<p>Bordered by the Pacific Ocean to the west and the Andes mountain range to the east, Chile is also one of the most seismically active countries in the world.</p>

<p>The epicenter of Thursday's earthquake was located about 50 miles from Chile's border with Argentina, and less than 20 miles from its border with Bolivia.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2017-09/earthquake-generic_650x400_71505899871.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Chile Earthquake: The epicenter was located 164 miles east of Antofagasta.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-gop-must-not-criminalise-dissent-trump-slams-witch-hunt-by-democrats-6137939]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Must Not Criminalise Dissent": Trump Slams "Witch-Hunt" By Democrats]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-gop-must-not-criminalise-dissent-trump-slams-witch-hunt-by-democrats-6137939]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Jul 2024 09:11:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Six days after he narrowly survived an assassination attempt, former US President Donald Trump today said the ruling Democrats must stop "weaponising the justice system" and labelling their political opponent an "enemy of democracy".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Six days after he narrowly survived an assassination attempt, former US President Donald Trump today said the ruling Democrats must stop "weaponising the justice system" and labelling their political opponent an "enemy of democracy".</p>

<p>"In an age where our politics too often divide us, now is the time to remember that we are fellow citizens, we are one nation under God, indivisible with liberty and justice for all," Trump said after accepting the Republican Party's nomination for the Presidential polls due later this year.</p>

<p>"We must not criminalise dissent and demonise political disagreement, which is what has been happening at a level that nobody has ever seen before. In that spirit, the Democrat party should immediately stop weaponising the justice system and labelling their political opponent as the enemy of democracy," he said. "In fact, I am the one saving democracy for the people of our country," the former President told the gathering in Milwaukee.</p>

<p>"They should drop these partisan witch hunts which I have been going through for approximately eight years, and they should do that without delay," he said, referring to the criminal cases against him.</p>

<p>"If they would use that genius to help our country, we will have a much stronger and better country," Trump said.</p>

<p>Thanking his family members for their support, he said "they got subpoenaed more than any people probably in the history of the United States". "Every week, they get another subpoena from the Democrats, crazy Nancy Pelosi and the whole thing just boom, boom, boom. They have got to stop that because they are destroying our country. We have to work on Making America Great Again," he said.</p>

<p>Ms Pelosi is a senior Democratic leader who has earlier served as a Speaker of the House of Representatives</p>

<p>Seeking the Americans' support, the 78-year-old leader said, "Tonight, I ask for your partnership, for your support, and I am humbly asking for your vote. Every day, I will strive to honour the trust you have placed in me, and I will never let you down." In a unity pitch, he also said he was "running for full America and not just half of America".</p>

<p>Doubling down on his stand on immigrants, he said the US is in "decline" with an immigrant "invasion".</p>

<p>"We have an illegal immigration crisis that's taking place right now as we sit here in this beautiful arena. It's a massive invasion at our southern border that has spread misery, crime, poverty, disease, and destruction to communities all across our land."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/18d9bodo_donald-trump-_625x300_19_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump was addressing a gathering at Milwaukee]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/near-naked-image-of-trump-and-biden-on-new-york-magazine-cover-sparks-controversy-6137859]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Controversial Image Of Trump and Biden On A Magazine Cover Sparks Outrage]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/near-naked-image-of-trump-and-biden-on-new-york-magazine-cover-sparks-controversy-6137859]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Jul 2024 08:53:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The magazine's latest Health Issue cover, featuring a Photoshopped image of Donald Trump and Joe Biden in shorts on medical scales, has faced backlash.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The cover of <em>New York magazine's</em> latest Health Issue included a Photoshopped picture of former president Donald Trump and President Joe Biden in their shorts, which sparked a flurry of criticism. The image, which compares the two political rivals on medical scales, has drawn criticism for being improper and immoral.</p>

<p>The magazine defended the cover, arguing that it was a statement on the candidates' ages and health-a subject that the public is becoming more interested in. Social media users and critics have, however, voiced anger over the photograph, denouncing it as exploitative and insulting.</p>

<p><em>New York Magazine's</em> Instagram post featuring the controversial cover image garnered thousands of likes and comments, with a majority of social media users expressing outrage and labelling it as immoral.</p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/C9irqNHOpfx/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C9irqNHOpfx/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C9irqNHOpfx/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C9irqNHOpfx/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by New York Magazine (@nymag)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p>"What a disgusting decision to make this a cover. We can now point to the media's contribution to making the U.S. a joke to the world," commented a user.</p>

<p>"I'd just like to note that if a publication photoshopped a woman's head onto a body in underwear and posted it, then the comments would be different. This is such a weird thing to do to anyone," wrote another user.</p>

<p>"What a disgusting decision to make this a cover. We can now point to the media's contribution to making the US a joke to the world," commented a third user.</p>

<p>"We had already been thinking about how to address the fact that this health issue would drop in the middle of the presidential campaign, when the presidential debate put the health and age of the candidates in the centre of the national conversation," <em>New York</em>'s executive editor, Genevieve Smith, said of the cover <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nymag.com/press/article/the-health-issue-july-15-2024.html"><em>in a press release.</em></a></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-11/2o4jj8m_trump-biden-split_625x300_04_November_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Critics argue the cover is exploitative, while the magazine defends it.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/not-running-for-just-half-of-america-donald-trumps-pitch-ahead-of-polls-6137669]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Not Running For Just Half Of America": Donald Trump's Pitch Ahead Of Polls]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/not-running-for-just-half-of-america-donald-trumps-pitch-ahead-of-polls-6137669]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Jul 2024 08:10:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump was addressing the Republican National Convention in Milwaukee.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump today made a "unity" pitch as he said he was "running for full America and not just half of America".</p>

<p>The 78-year-old was addressing the Republican National Convention in Milwaukee, hoping to build momentum toward a November victory over US President <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/obama-tells-allies-biden-needs-to-reconsider-re-election-bid-report-6135482#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">Joe Biden</a> and a second term in the White House.</p>

<p>"We will have an incredible victory, and we will begin the four greatest years in the history of our country," Trump said in his first speech since a 20-year-old man shot at him, causing a slight injury to his right ear, and killing a bystander, during a rally last week.</p>

<p>"Four months from now, we will have an incredible victory... I am running to be president for all of America, not half of America because there is no victory in winning for half of America," he said.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">President Trump: “Four months from now, we will have an incredible victory...I am running to be president for ALL of America, not half of America, because there is no victory in winning for half of America.” <a href="https://t.co/GnqUBrwEIo">pic.twitter.com/GnqUBrwEIo</a></p>
— MAGA War Room (@MAGAIncWarRoom) <a href="https://twitter.com/MAGAIncWarRoom/status/1814127407676191137?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 19, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>He also spoke about the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/too-painful-wont-narrate-again-donald-trump-recounts-being-shot-at-6137658" target="_blank">assassination attempt</a> on him during his campaign rally in Pennsylvania on Saturday and said he instantly knew he was "under attack".</p>

<p>"I immediately knew it was very serious, that we were under attack," he told the Republican National Convention with his family in attendance. "I felt very safe because I had God on my side."</p>

<p>"The assassin's bullet came within a quarter of an inch of taking my life. So many people have asked me what happened, and therefore, I'll tell you what happened, and you'll never hear it from me a second time, because it's too painful," Trump said.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">President Trump: “As you already know, the assassin's bullet came within a quarter of an inch of taking my life. So many people have asked me what happened, and therefore, I'll tell you what happened, and you'll never hear it from me a second time, because it's too painful..." <a href="https://t.co/DPC4CUG32l">pic.twitter.com/DPC4CUG32l</a></p>
— MAGA War Room (@MAGAIncWarRoom) <a href="https://twitter.com/MAGAIncWarRoom/status/1814129233569931362?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 19, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Trump also held a moment of silence for <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-rally-victim-corey-comperatore-was-a-firefighter-father-of-2-died-shielding-his-family-6106855" target="_blank">Corey Comperatore</a>, a 50-year-old firefighter and father of two, who died in the shooting at the Pennsylvania rally&nbsp;</p>

<p>Trump's wife Melania, who has been mostly absent throughout the campaign, arrived to applause but did not speak.</p>

<p>Trump's address comes when team Biden is in full crisis mode as pressure from within the incumbent's Democratic Party builds for him to end his reelection bid.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/49nv71cg_donald-trump_625x300_19_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump at the Republican National Convention in Milwaukee]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-soul-searching-about-dropping-reelection-campaign-against-donald-trump-6137660]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Joe Biden "Soul Searching" About Dropping Reelection Campaign: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-soul-searching-about-dropping-reelection-campaign-against-donald-trump-6137660]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Jul 2024 08:10:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[President Joe Biden was "soul searching" about dropping his Democratic reelection campaign, a source said, while Donald Trump prepared to accept the Republican presidential nomination in what aides said would be an unusually reflective speech.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>President Joe Biden was "soul searching" about dropping his Democratic reelection campaign, a source said, while Donald Trump prepared to accept the Republican presidential nomination in what aides said would be an unusually reflective speech.</p>

<p>The fortunes of the two candidates appeared to be on opposite trajectories on Thursday in the run-up to the November 5 election.</p>

<p>Biden, 81, was isolating at his Delaware home after contracting COVID-19, while facing a growing revolt from Democrats who urged him to step aside to avert a landslide defeat. His doctor said he was experiencing mild symptoms.</p>

<p>Trump, 78, has basked all week in adulation at the Republican National convention in Milwaukee after surviving a weekend assassination attempt at a Pennsylvania rally.</p>

<p>For the fourth consecutive night, Trump made a grand entrance into the arena during the program, still wearing a bandage over the ear that was wounded on Saturday and drawing huge applause.</p>

<p>Trump's acceptance speech, scheduled for 10 p.m. Eastern Time (0200 GMT on Friday), offers a chance to lay out his vision for a second White House term before a primetime national television audience.</p>

<p>Among the speakers on Thursday were the conservative commentator Tucker Carlson, former pro wrestler Hulk Hogan and mixed martial arts impresario Dana White.</p>

<p>The head pro at Trump's Florida golf club, John Nieporte, praised Trump's skills on the course and claimed the former president had won 21 club championships.</p>

<p>"Joe Biden? Zero," he said, evoking the surreal moment from the June 27 presidential debate when Trump and Biden argued over which of the two candidates had a better golf game.</p>

<p>Biden has faced increasing pressure from heavyweights in his party to cede his position at the top of the ticket after his erratic performance on debate night. Former House of Representatives Speaker Nancy Pelosi is among those who have told him he cannot win in November, according to a White House source familiar with the matter.</p>

<p>After weeks of insisting that he will remain in the race, Biden is now taking calls to step aside seriously and multiple Democratic officials think an exit is a matter of time, according to sources familiar with the matter.</p>

<p>People close to the president told the New York Times on Thursday that they believe he has begun to accept the idea that he may have to drop out.</p>

<p>Democratic leaders in the House and Senate - Hakeem Jeffries and Chuck Schumer - have told Biden directly that he will not only lose the White House but also endanger their effort to win back the House, according to reports in multiple news outlets.</p>

<p>Opinion polls show four of the seven most competitive states looking increasingly out of reach for Biden. The Trump campaign, meanwhile, said it believes it is now competitive in Democratic-leaning states including Minnesota, New Hampshire, and Virginia.</p>

<p>Senator Jon Tester, who faces a challenging reelection battle in Montana this year, on Thursday became the 21st congressional Democrat and the second senator to publicly call on Biden to drop out.</p>

<p>Some lawmakers say Biden may now be more open to stepping aside.</p>

<p>"He's done what's best for America ... I think he'll keep doing so," Democratic U.S. Senator John Hickenlooper told Reuters. "He's working towards that."</p>

<p>Hickenlooper declined to say whether he believed Biden should step aside as a candidate.</p>

<p>Former President Barack Obama has told others that Biden, who was Obama's vice president, should rethink his candidacy, the Washington Post reported, citing anonymous sources.</p>

<h3><strong>REPUBLICAN UNITY</strong></h3>

<p>Trump will cap the four-day Republican convention with his first public address since the assassination attempt.</p>

<p>Lara Trump, the nominee's daughter-in-law who serves as Republican National Committee co-chair, said the attack had prompted him to revise his acceptance speech and emphasize unity.</p>

<p>"I don't think you can go through what he went through on Saturday, really a near-death experience, and not come out on the other side impacted," Lara Trump said.</p>

<p>Vice President Kamala Harris, who could vie for the Democratic nomination should Biden pull out, said Trump's call for unity would have little credibility, given his persistent refusal to acknowledge his 2020 election defeat.</p>

<p>"We're too busy watching what you're doing to hear what you're saying," she said at a campaign rally in Fayetteville, North Carolina.</p>

<p>With most dissent quelled and his grip on the Republican Party never tighter, Trump will be in a much stronger position than in his 2017-2021 term to follow through on his agenda if he wins the election.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/81g72018_joe-biden_625x300_19_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Biden, 81, was isolating at his Delaware home after contracting COVID-19 (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/too-painful-wont-narrate-again-donald-trump-recounts-being-shot-at-6137658]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Had God On My Side": Donald Trump Recounts Being Shot At During Rally]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/too-painful-wont-narrate-again-donald-trump-recounts-being-shot-at-6137658]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Jul 2024 08:07:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former US President Donald Trump recounted the assassination attempt on him during a campaign rally on Saturday while addressing the Republican National Convention (RNC).]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Speaking at the Republican National Convention, former US President Donald Trump recounted the assassination attempt on him during a campaign rally last week, stating that he felt safe during the attack as "God was on my side".</p>

<p>After accepting his nomination as the official Republican presidential candidate, Trump narrated how the attack unfolded during his rally in Pennsylvania.&nbsp;"I am not supposed to be here tonight. I am not supposed to be here," he told the crowd who chanted "Yes, you are".</p>

<p>"I stand before you in this arena only by the grace of almighty God," he said, adding that many have described the moment as "divine intervention".</p>

<p>Trump said the bullet missed him as he leaned forward, seconds before the assassin fired the shot, to look at a screen displaying immigration data. "In order to see the chart and I started to turned to my right. I began to turn a little bit further which I am very lucky I did not do," he said.</p>

<p>"If I had not moved my head at the very last instant, the assassin's bullet would have perfectly hit its mark, and I would not be with you tonight."</p>

<p>The bullet that missed him by a few inches, grazed his ear as the 78-year-old Republican nominee hid behind the podium and was quickly whisked off the stage by Secret Service agents.</p>

<p>Trump said he heard "a loud whizzing sound and felt something hit me very, very hard on my right ear".</p>

<p>“I said to myself, ‘Wow, what was that - it can only be a bullet' - and moved my right hand to my ear, brought it down, and my hand was covered with blood," he said, adding that he knew immediately that he was under attack.</p>

<p>"There was blood pouring everywhere, and yet, in a certain way I felt very safe, because I had&nbsp;<br />
God on my side,” Trump said, as he continued to describe the attack.</p>

<p>Trump, who first shared his reaction to the attack on a Truth Social post, said the attack was "too painful to tell" and he would not narrate how it occurred again.</p>

<p>The shooter, a 20-year old nursing aide named Thomas Matthew Crooks, was shot dead by Secret Service snipers. The motive behind his attack is not known yet.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/hlqtumco_donald-trump-ear-bandaged-afp_625x300_18_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Trump said the bullet missed him as he leaned forward, seconds before the assassin fired the shot]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/journalist-told-to-pay-5000-euros-for-mocking-italy-pm-giorgia-melonis-height-6137418]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Journalist Fined Rs 4.5 Lakh For Posting A Joke On Giorgia Meloni's Height]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/journalist-told-to-pay-5000-euros-for-mocking-italy-pm-giorgia-melonis-height-6137418]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Jul 2024 07:14:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Milan court has ordered a journalist to pay Italian Prime Minister Giorgia Meloni damages of 5000 euros for making fun of her in a social media post, news agency ANSA and other local media reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Milan court has ordered a journalist to pay Italian Prime Minister Giorgia Meloni damages of 5,000 euros ($5,465) for making fun of her in a social media post, news agency ANSA and other local media reported.</p>

<p>The journalist, Giulia Cortese, was also given a suspended fine of 1,200 euros for a jibe on Twitter, now named X, in Oct. 2021 about Meloni's height, which was defined as "body shaming".</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Italy's government has a serious problem with freedom of expression and journalistic dissent. This country seems to get closer to Orbán's Hungary: these are bad times for independent Journalists and opinion leaders. Let's hope for better days ahead. We won't give up!<a href="https://twitter.com/Reuters?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Reuters</a> <a href="https://t.co/sWojOlMJz1">https://t.co/sWojOlMJz1</a></p>
— Giulia Cortese (@GiuliaCortese1) <a href="https://twitter.com/GiuliaCortese1/status/1813896664396284190?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 18, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>In a response to a Reuters story on the verdict, Cortese wrote on X on Thursday: "Italy's government has a serious problem with freedom of expression and journalistic dissent."</p>

<p>Meloni had launched legal action against the journalist after the two women clashed on social media three years ago.</p>

<p>Meloni, whose far-right Brothers of Italy party was in opposition at the time, took exception when Cortese published a mocked-up photo of her with a picture of the late fascist leader Benito Mussolini in the background.</p>

<p>Cortese responded with further tweets including one that translates as "you don't scare me, Giorgia Meloni. After all, you're only 1.2 metres (4 feet) tall. I can't even see you."</p>

<p>Meloni's height is given as between 1.58 m and 1.63 m on various media websites.</p>

<p>Cortese can appeal against the sentence, and Meloni's lawyer said the prime minister would donate to charity any damages she eventually receives.</p>

<p>Writing in English on X on Thursday, Cortese said it was a tough time for independent journalists in Italy.</p>

<p>"Let's hope for better days ahead. We won't give up!" she added.</p>

<p>A high number of lawsuits brought against journalists was cited this year by Reporters Without Borders, which relegated Italy five places to 46th in its 2024 World Press Freedom Index.</p>

<p>Meloni is not new to taking journalists to court. Last year a Rome court fined best-selling author Roberto Saviano 1,000 euros plus legal expenses after he insulted her on television in 2021 over her hardline stance on illegal immigration.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/h5pmfd3_giorgia-meloni-reuters-_625x300_19_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Italian Prime Minister Giorgia Meloni is not new to taking journalists to court.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-nears-crunch-point-as-pressure-grows-to-drop-out-of-white-house-race-6137454]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden Nears Crunch Point As Pressure Grows To Drop Out Of White House Race]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-nears-crunch-point-as-pressure-grows-to-drop-out-of-white-house-race-6137454]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Jul 2024 07:08:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden was reportedly coming closer to dropping out of the White House race Friday as allies including Barack Obama were said to have expressed concerns that he can no longer win the 2024 election.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden was reportedly coming closer to dropping out of the White House race Friday as allies including Barack Obama were said to have expressed concerns that he can no longer win the 2024 election.</p>

<p>The 81-year-old Democrat was holed up at his beach house with Covid as multiple US media reports said he was considering the future of his reelection bid amid mounting opposition within his party.</p>

<p>The New York Times cited several people close to Biden as saying they believe he has begun to accept that he may lose in November to Republican rival Donald Trump and may have to drop out, with one quoted as saying: "Reality is setting in."</p>

<p>It quoted the person as saying it would not be a surprise if Biden soon endorsed Vice President Kamala Harris to replace him as the Democratic candidate.</p>

<p>Former president Obama meanwhile had reportedly told allies that Biden should "seriously consider the viability of his candidacy," the Washington Post reported. His office did not comment.</p>

<p>The Axios news outlet separately quoted party figures as saying that Biden could drop out as soon as this weekend, while broadcaster NBC quoted a person close to Biden as saying: "We're close to the end."</p>

<p>Biden's candidacy has been in peril for three weeks since a disastrous television debate against Trump.</p>

<p>His campaign however denied the reports and insisted he was staying in.</p>

<p>"He's running for reelection. Baseless conjecture from anonymous sources isn't a scoop," campaign official T.J. Ducklo said on X.</p>

<p>Harris made no comment on the crisis in a speech in the battleground state of North Carolina but praised the president, saying the "contrast between Joe Biden and Donald Trump it's like night and day."</p>

<p>She also lashed out Trump's new running mate J.D. Vance and said it was the "most existential, consequential and important election of our lifetime."</p>

<p><strong>- Covid symptoms -</strong><br />
While rival Trump prepares for his star turn at the Republican National Convention in Milwaukee later Thursday, Biden finds himself in both personal and political isolation.</p>

<p>His personal doctor, Kevin O'Connor, said Thursday that Biden was still experiencing mild Covid symptoms and was taking the drug Paxlovid, but that his vital signs remain normal.</p>

<p>"He will continue to conduct the business of the American people," O'Connor said in a letter released by the White House.</p>

<p>His Covid diagnosis came at the worst possible time for his campaign, forcing him to cut short a trip to Las Vegas and isolate at his holiday home in Rehoboth Beach, Delaware.</p>

<p>Biden told reporters on Wednesday that he was "doing well" but was later seen looking frail as he slowly descended the steps of Air Force One.</p>

<p>The drumbeat of Democrats coming out against Biden is growing, with 20 members of the House of Representatives having openly called on him to quit.</p>

<p>The top Democrats in Congress, Senate Majority Leader Chuck Schumer and House Minority Leader Hakeem Jeffries, both reportedly met with Biden in recent days to warn that his candidacy threatens his party's prospects in November's election.</p>

<p>Influential former House speaker Nancy Pelosi added to his woes by privately telling Biden he cannot win and could harm Democrats' chances of recapturing the lower chamber, CNN and the New York Times reported.</p>

<p>White House National Security spokesman John Kirby meanwhile said Biden was being "kept up to speed" by his team despite the political turmoil and his illness.</p>

<p>However the split-screen with Donald Trump could not be more stark, with Trump set to formally accept the Republican nomination in Milwaukee as Biden hunkers down.</p>

<p>Republicans find themselves newly unified after former president Trump, who at 78 is just three years younger than Biden, survived an assassination attempt on Saturday that left him with a bandaged ear.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/oh8gta3g_joe-biden_625x300_09_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Several people close to Biden as saying they believe he has begun to accept that he may lose in November.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/tulsi-gabbard-slams-kamala-harris-over-her-remarks-against-jd-vance-6136502]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Tulsi Gabbard Slams Kamala Harris Over Her Remarks Against JD Vance]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/tulsi-gabbard-slams-kamala-harris-over-her-remarks-against-jd-vance-6136502]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Jul 2024 07:03:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former US Congresswoman Tulsi Gabbard has slammed the US Vice President over her remarks against former US President Donald Trump's running mate, JD Vance, calling Kamala Harris a "self-serving politician who should not be in office."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former US Congresswoman Tulsi Gabbard has slammed the US Vice President over her remarks against former US President Donald Trump's running mate, JD Vance, calling Kamala Harris a "self-serving politician who should not be in office."</p>

<p>Criticising the US Vice President over her warning to Americans that JD Vance will only be loyal to Trump and not the US, Gabbard said that Kamala Harris is driven by her own political ambition.</p>

<p>Gabbard stated that JD Vance enlisted himself in the Marine Corps after the 9/11 attacks and was deployed to Iraq in 2005. She asked, "Was Kamala Harris willing to put her own life on the line in service to our country at any time in the past?"</p>

<p>In a video posted on X, Tulsi Gabbard stated, "Shortly after President Trump announced that J.D. Vance is gonna be his running mate in this election, Kamala Harris issued this scathing warning to the American people, saying, make no mistake, JD Vance will be loyal only to Trump, not to our country. The audacity that she has to say this is off the charts. She's talking about JD Vance, someone who enlisted in the Marine Corps after the terrorist attack on 9/11."</p>

<p>"Someone who deployed to Iraq in 2005, the same year that I was there, during the height of that war, putting his own life on the line in service to our country. Was Kamala Harris willing to put her own life on the line in service to our country at any time in the past? Is she now? No. Kamala Harris is driven by her own political ambition. She's a self-serving politician who should not be in office," she added.</p>

<p>The former Hawaii congresswoman's statement comes after Kamala Harris said on Wednesday that JD Vance will act as a "rubber stamp" for Donald Trump and his "extreme" agenda.</p>

<p>While sharing the video on X, Tulsi Gabbard stated, "Kamala Harris claims 'JD Vance will be loyal only to Trump, not to our country.' @JDVance1 enlisted in the Marine Corps after 9/11 and deployed to Iraq in 2005, the same year I was there during the height of the war. He put his life on the line in service to our country. Was Kamala Harris ready to sacrifice her life for our country? Of course not. Once again, Kamala exposes her hypocrisy."</p>

<p>Kamala Harris criticised Vance for saying he would not have certified the election results of 2020. Harris even compared Vance to former US Vice President Mike Pence, saying that Vance "would have carried out Trump's plan to overturn the 2020 election."</p>

<p>In a video released on Wednesday, Harris said, "Donald Trump has picked his new running mate: JD Vance. Trump looked for someone he knew would be a rubber stamp for his extreme agenda." She further said, "Make no mistake: JD Vance will be loyal only to Trump, not to our country," ABC News reported.</p>

<p>The US Vice President also called him out for backing the national abortion ban and for voting against protections for IVF in the Senate, according to ABC News report.</p>

<p>She said, "And if elected, he will help implement the extreme Project 2025 plan for a second Trump term, which would target critical programs like Head Start and Medicare." "But we are not going to let that happen," she added.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, JD Vance officially accepted his vice presidential nomination on Wednesday. The 39-year-old lawmaker, during his acceptance speech, called on Americans to send Trump back to the White House and introduced himself to voters across the country.</p>

<p>Talking about his journey from "poverty to the vice presidential nomination," he described himself as a "working-class boy."</p>

<p>"I pledge to every American, no matter your party, that I will give everything I have to serve you and to make this country a place where every dream you have for yourself, your family and your country will be possible," Vance said.</p>

<p>Vance's speech portrayed "Trump as America's last best hope--to restore what is lost--which, if lost, may never be found, again."</p>

<p>"From Iraq to Afghanistan, from the financial crisis to the Great Recession, from open borders to strengthening wages, the people who govern this country have failed and failed again," Vance said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-10/a2ijf6no_tulsi-gabbard_650x400_12_October_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Tulsi Gabbard said that Kamala Harris is driven by her own political ambition.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/working-with-donald-trump-would-be-hard-if-he-wins-says-ukraine-president-volodymyr-zelensky-6137354]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Working With Trump "Would Be Hard" If He Wins, Says Zelensky]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/working-with-donald-trump-would-be-hard-if-he-wins-says-ukraine-president-volodymyr-zelensky-6137354]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Jul 2024 06:37:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[President Volodymyr Zelenskiy acknowledged in an interview published on Thursday that a victory for Donald Trump in the U.S. election in November would be difficult for his country but Ukrainians were prepared.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>President Volodymyr Zelenskiy acknowledged in an interview published on Thursday that a victory for Donald Trump in the U.S. election in November would be difficult for his country but Ukrainians were prepared.</p>

<p>Trump's choice of Senator J.D. Vance as his running mate has underscored how Washington's stand on Ukraine, locked in a 28-month-old war with Russia, could change if he won the election. Vance is on record in an interview as saying "I don't really care what happens to Ukraine one way or the other."</p>

<p>Zelenskiy, speaking to the BBC while attending the European Political Community meeting in London, noted the comment, but added: "Maybe he really doesn't care, but we have to work with the United States."</p>

<p>Trump's election, he said in remarks on the BBC website, would be "hard work, but we are hard workers".</p>

<p>The administration of Joe Biden has provided weapons and supplies throughout the conflict, though the flow of assistance was halted for months by disputes within the U.S. Congress.</p>

<p>Trump has said during the campaign that, once elected, he would bring the conflict to an end even before taking office by securing a deal at the negotiating table. He said there would have been no conflict at all had he been in office when Moscow sent troops into Ukraine in February 2022.</p>

<p>In other comments to the BBC, Zelenskiy said Ukraine was thankful for pledges from its partners to supply F-16 fighter jets, most likely this summer, though they had not yet arrived.</p>

<p>"It's been 18 months and the planes have not reached us," Zelenskiy told the BBC.</p>

<p>The planes, he said, were essential to help Ukrainians resist Russia's aerial dominance and "unblock the skies".</p>

<p>He said he anticipated no change in Britain's support for Ukraine, but hoped new Prime Minister Keir Starmer would "become special - speaking about international politics, about defending world security, about the war in Ukraine."</p>

<p>Ukraine, he said, "doesn't just need a new page, we need power to turn this leaf".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-01/kkg64p4o_volodymyr-zelensky_625x300_29_January_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Volodymyr Zelensky said that Trump's election would be "hard work, but we are hard workers".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/netanyahu-vows-to-maintain-israels-control-of-rafah-crossing-6137300]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Netanyahu Vows To Keep Control Of Rafah Crossing Even After Ceasefire Deal]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/netanyahu-vows-to-maintain-israels-control-of-rafah-crossing-6137300]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Jul 2024 06:12:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu has made a surprise visit to Gaza's Rafah, pledging to uphold Israeli control over the Rafah crossing and the entire Gaza-Egypt border.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu has made a surprise visit to Gaza's Rafah, pledging to uphold Israeli control over the Rafah crossing and the entire Gaza-Egypt border, even if a ceasefire-hostage agreement is reached.</p>

<p>Netanyahu on Thursday received briefings from commanders in Rafah, which Israeli ground forces have seized since early May, and observed the "Philadelphia Corridor", the border area between Gaza and Egypt, Xinhua news agency reported.</p>

<p>"I got here stronger in the understanding that our control of the Philadelphia Corridor and the Rafah crossing is essential for the future," Netanyahu said in a video statement, surrounded by soldiers.</p>

<p>He noted that next week he will travel to Washington to address the US Congress, adding that he will present the "righteousness" of the controversial ongoing Israeli onslaught in Gaza.</p>

<p>Netanyahu made the statement as an Israeli delegation was in Cairo for more talks on the agreement. The control over the Rafah crossing and "the Philadelphia Corridor" is a major sticking point in the talks. Israeli officials, including Defence Minister Yoav Gallant, have said that Israel would agree to withdraw from the area under a deal that would secure the release of about 120 hostages still held in Gaza.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/1pl02qt_rafah-border-_625x300_27_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/no-change-to-donald-trump-campaign-if-joe-biden-drops-out-tells-advisor-6137219]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[No Change To Trump Campaign If Biden Drops Out, Tells Advisor]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/no-change-to-donald-trump-campaign-if-joe-biden-drops-out-tells-advisor-6137219]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Jul 2024 05:41:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A senior advisor to Donald Trump said Thursday that the Republican's White House campaign will not fundamentally change should US President Joe Biden bow to Democratic pressure and end his reelection bid.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A senior advisor to Donald Trump said Thursday that the Republican's White House campaign will not fundamentally change should US President Joe Biden bow to Democratic pressure and end his reelection bid.</p>

<p>Jason Miller, one of Trump's closest advisors, spoke to AFP on the sidelines of the Republican National Convention in Milwaukee, where Trump was set to formally accept the party's presidential nomination in a Thursday night address.</p>

<p><strong>- How might a Biden withdrawal impact Trump's White House bid? -</strong></p>

<p>"Nothing fundamentally changes," said Miller, who has worked closely on the Republican's presidential campaigns since 2016.</p>

<p>"And the fact of the matter is whether it's Joe Biden or (Vice President) Kamala Harris, or any other radical liberal Democrats, they all share responsibility for the failure of destroying our economy and ruining our borders."</p>

<p><strong>- Has Biden crisis prompted a Trump speech rewrite? -</strong></p>

<p>Trump's much-anticipated address, coming just days after he survived an assassination attempt at a campaign rally, is "not about Joe Biden," Miller said. "It's about president Trump and his vision for the country."</p>

<p><strong>- What can we expect to hear? -</strong></p>

<p>"It will be very exciting," Miller said.</p>

<p>"President Trump's going to offer his vision for how we heal America and make the country more affordable and safe for its citizens."</p>

<p>Trump "will also offer a very personal reflection of what happened on Saturday," when a gunman on a roof fired shots at the former president, wounding him and killing a rally attendee.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/smgpnocg_donald-trump-afp_625x300_14_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Trump's much-anticipated address, coming just days after he survived an assassination attempt at a rally.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-koreas-kim-jong-un-hosts-russia-military-delegation-after-putin-visit-6137168]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kim Jong Un Hosts Russia Military Delegation After Putin Visit]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-koreas-kim-jong-un-hosts-russia-military-delegation-after-putin-visit-6137168]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Jul 2024 05:30:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Propelled by the popularity of titles such as "Heeramandi: The Diamond Bazaar", "The Great Indian Kapil Show" and "Amar Singh Chamkila", India has emerged as the third country in revenue per cent growth for streaming service Netflix in its second qua]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>North Korean leader Kim Jong Un hosted a Russian military delegation led by Vice Defence Minister Aleksey Krivoruchko to discuss the "importance and necessity" of bilateral defence cooperation, state media said Friday.</p>

<p>Thursday's meeting in Pyongyang came roughly a month after Russian President Vladimir Putin's visit to the North Korean capital, during which the two countries signed a mutual defence agreement that raised hackles in Seoul and Washington.</p>

<p>North Korea and Russia have been allies since the North's founding after World War II and have drawn even closer since Moscow's 2022 invasion of Ukraine.</p>

<p>Kim emphasised the need for the countries' armies to "get united more firmly to dynamically lead the DPRK-Russia relations in the new era and play an important part in defending regional and global peace," the official Korean Central News Agency reported.</p>

<p>The United States and its allies have accused North Korea of providing ammunition and missiles to Russia for its war in Ukraine, and the treaty has fuelled concerns of more deliveries.</p>

<p>After leaving Pyongyang, Putin further fanned the flames by saying he "does not rule out" sending weapons to North Korea.</p>

<p>The North has been under a UN sanctions regime since 2006 over its weapons programmes.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/r50bt4a4_kim-jong-un_625x300_19_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[North Korea and Russia have been allies since the North's founding after World War II.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-benjamin-netanyahu-expected-to-meet-next-week-white-house-6137109]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden, Netanyahu Expected To Meet Next Week: White House]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-benjamin-netanyahu-expected-to-meet-next-week-white-house-6137109]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Jul 2024 05:09:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden is still expected to meet with Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu when he visits Washington next week but it will depend on his recovery from Covid, the White House said Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden is still expected to meet with Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu when he visits Washington next week but it will depend on his recovery from Covid, the White House said Thursday.</p>

<p>"We have every expectation that the two leaders will have a chance to see each other while Prime Minister Netanyahu is in town," National Security Council spokesman John Kirby told reporters in a briefing.</p>

<p>Netanyahu is set to address the US Congress on Wednesday and Israeli media had reported a meeting with Biden on Monday, but Kirby said, "I can't tell you at this point what that exactly is going to look like."</p>

<p>"We need to make sure that the president's health and his recovery from Covid takes priority and if and how that might affect a discussion with the prime minister."</p>

<p>Israel's war in Gaza will be top of the agenda for the meeting, with Biden pressing for a peace deal with Hamas.</p>

<p>Ahead of Netanyahu's visit, Israeli lawmakers passed a symbolic resolution opposing the creation of a Palestinian state -- a move criticized by the United Nations and one that clashes with US ambitions for the region.</p>

<p>"I think the best way I can respond to that is to just reiterate our firm belief in the power and the promise of the two-state solution," said Kirby when asked about Thursday's vote.</p>

<p>"And that is not something that President Biden is going to give up on," he added.</p>

<p>"We're going to keep doing everything we can to try to achieve that outcome."</p>

<p>Biden was suffering from mild symptoms after testing positive for Covid on Wednesday, Kirby said, taking him off the campaign trail just as he fights mounting calls from Democrats to quit his reelection bid.</p>

<p>Kirby said that neither the political turmoil nor illness had affected Biden's duties.</p>

<p>"While he's certainly focused on getting better, as anyone who has Covid would want to do, he's being kept up to speed as appropriate by his leadership team and certainly that includes on the national security front," he said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-10/dh45inf8_joe-biden-netanyahu_625x300_27_October_23.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Netanyahu is set to address the US Congress on Wednesday.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/comedy-legend-bob-newhart-dead-at-94-publicist-6136608]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[American Comedy Legend Bob Newhart Dies At 94: Publicist]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/comedy-legend-bob-newhart-dead-at-94-publicist-6136608]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Jul 2024 02:05:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Bob Newhart, the American stand-up performer whose comedy made him one of the top TV stars of his era, has died, his publicist announced Thursday. He was 94 years old.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bob Newhart, the American stand-up performer whose comedy made him one of the top TV stars of his era, has died, his publicist announced Thursday. He was 94 years old.</p>

<p>The decorated Chicago icon was an accountant before striking gold with comedy, acclaimed for his dry, deadpan delivery.</p>

<p>He died at his Los Angeles home after a series of short illnesses, his longtime publicist Jerry Digney said in a statement.</p>

<p>Born September 5, 1929 in suburban Illinois, Newhart studied business management before being drafted into the US army, and served in the Korean War.</p>

<p>He briefly studied law before quitting and getting work as an accountant while moonlighting as a comedy performer and writer.</p>

<p>He eventually was signed to Warner Bros. Records, and "The Button-Down Mind of Bob Newhart" became the music industry's first comedy album to hit the top of the sales charts.</p>

<p>It earned him prestigious Grammys for Best New Artist and Best Album, and helped launch his career in television.</p>

<p>He starred in two long-running sitcoms in the 1970s and 1980s, and made guest star appearances into his 90s.</p>

<p>Newhart featured as a recurring guest on "The Big Bang Theory," and also starred as Papa Elf in the Christmas film "Elf.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/1fk4j2k_bob-newhart_625x300_19_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Bob Newhart featured as a recurring guest on "The Big Bang Theory".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-strike-kills-field-commander-in-elite-hezbollah-unit-report-6136534]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israeli Strike Kills Field Commander In Elite Hezbollah Unit: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-strike-kills-field-commander-in-elite-hezbollah-unit-report-6136534]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Jul 2024 01:45:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A field commander in Hezbollah's elite Radwan forces was killed in an Israeli strike on south Lebanon, two security sources said on Thursday, the latest senior member of the group to be killed in months of tit-for-tat fighting with Israel.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A field commander in Hezbollah's elite Radwan forces was killed in an Israeli strike on south Lebanon, two security sources said on Thursday, the latest senior member of the group to be killed in months of tit-for-tat fighting with Israel.</p>

<p>Habib Maatouk had replaced another commander in the elite unit who was killed earlier this year in an Israeli strike, the security sources said.</p>

<p>Maatouk was killed in one of several strikes on the neighbouring border villages of Safad El Batikh and Jmaijmeh, the sources said.</p>

<p>After the strikes, 18 wounded people arrived in nearby Tebnin government hospital, two in critical condition, hospital director Mohammed Hamadi told Reuters.</p>

<p>Israel and Hezbollah have been trading fire since Hezbollah announced a "support front" with Palestinians shortly after its ally Hamas attacked southern Israeli border communities on Oct. 7, triggering Israel's military offensive in Gaza.</p>

<p>The fighting in Lebanon has killed more than 100 civilians and more than 300 Hezbollah fighters, according to a Reuters tally, and led to levels of destruction in Lebanese border towns and villages not seen since the 2006 Israel-Lebanon war.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/t0borbr4_hezbollah_625x300_28_June_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[After the strikes, 18 wounded people arrived in nearby Tebnin government hospital.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/cop-injured-in-attack-in-central-paris-says-french-minister-6136057]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Cop Injured In Attack In Central Paris, Says French Minister]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/cop-injured-in-attack-in-central-paris-says-french-minister-6136057]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 18 Jul 2024 23:34:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[One police officer was injured in an attack in central Paris on Thursday, French Interior Minister Gerald Darmanin said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>One police officer was injured in an attack in central Paris on Thursday, French Interior Minister Gerald Darmanin said.</p>

<p>The attacker was incapacitated by police while the area where the incident occurred was cordoned off, Darmanin said.</p>

<p>Paris police did not immediately reply to a request for comment.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-12/dsgt4ipo_french-police-generic_625x300_03_December_23.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Paris police did not immediately reply to a request for comment. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-owns-republicans-now-critics-wary-of-unchecked-quest-for-power-6136038]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump 'Owns Republicans' Now, Critics Wary Of Unchecked Quest For Power]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-owns-republicans-now-critics-wary-of-unchecked-quest-for-power-6136038]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 18 Jul 2024 23:33:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Five days after narrowly escaping assassination, Donald Trump will accept his presidential nomination on Thursday before an adoring crowd of supporters, the final act in his transformation of the Republican Party into the party of Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Five days after narrowly escaping assassination, Donald Trump will accept his presidential nomination on Thursday before an adoring crowd of supporters, the final act in his transformation of the Republican Party into the party of Trump.</p>

<p>His brush with death has fueled the growing quasi-religious fervor among the party faithful, elevating him from political leader to a man they believe is protected by God.</p>

<p>"Trump, Trump, Trump," attendees roared at the Republican National Convention in Milwaukee when he appeared each night this week, his right ear bandaged, to listen to speaker after speaker intone reverentially about him and reference God's hand in his survival from a would-be assassin's bullet.</p>

<p>Republicans are uniting behind him this week. With most dissent quelled and his grip on the party never tighter, Trump will be in a much stronger position than in his 2017-2021 term to follow through on his agenda if he wins the Nov. 5 election.</p>

<p>Untrammeled by the internal divisions that sometimes stymied him in his first term, Trump would be freer to pursue hard-edged policies that include mass deportations as part of a crackdown on illegal migration, aggressive trade policies, and dismissing government officials seen as insufficiently loyal.</p>

<p>Even if Trump retakes the White House, Republicans take control of both houses of Congress, and conservatives go on holding a Supreme Court super majority, there would still be institutional checks on a second Trump term.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Add image caption here" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ot8nkhj_trump-reuters_625x300_18_July_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Add image caption here" /></div>

<p></p>
</div>

<p>&nbsp;</p>

<p>He could be kept in check by Congress, the courts, and a public that elects a new Congress every two years and a president every four years, constitutional experts say.</p>

<p>Nevertheless, many Trump supporters want to see a powerful president.</p>

<p>"You need a strong leader at the top," said Bill Dowd, a 79-year-old lumber business owner who was a guest of the Colorado delegation in Milwaukee.</p>

<p>"I'm a very, very big Ronald Reagan fan. Ronald Reagan pulled the party together also," Dowd said.</p>

<p>Dowd acknowledged that some of his Republican friends feared that Trump might try to abuse his power. He said while he did not share that fear he believed that dissent should not be stifled in any party.</p>

<p>For Trump's critics and political opponents, this is a dark and disturbing moment: they see the modern Republican Party as a cult of personality, a base from which Trump could pursue extreme policies and create America's first truly imperial presidency, threatening the future of its democratic norms.</p>

<p>"Donald Trump has called for the 'termination' of the Constitution, promised to be a 'dictator' 'on day one,' and now his Supreme Court justices say he can rule without any checks on his power," said Ammar Moussa, campaign spokesman for incumbent President Joe Biden, Trump's Democratic rival.</p>

<p>"Trump is a liar, but we believe him when he says he will rule as a dictator," Moussa said.</p>

<p>Trump campaign spokesman Steven Cheung said Democratic assertions that Trump threatens American democracy and could become an autocrat if reelected were "fear-mongering" and a "blatant effort to deceive the American people."</p>

<p><strong>An Unrestricted Trump</strong></p>

<p>In Milwaukee, nearly all of the 30 delegates, guests, and elected Republicans interviewed by Reuters for this story acknowledged that their party had become the party of Trump but dismissed any suggestion that it had become cult-like.</p>

<p>"I believe that President Trump is a transformational figure, a man of destiny who God providentially saved from death on Saturday," Louisiana delegate Ed Tarpley said. "He's been given a special mission in our country. God's providential hand has elevated Donald Trump to a different status."</p>

<p>Those interviewed said they wanted a President Trump who was not constrained by bureaucracy or Congress to execute his agenda. They were in favor of a more expansive use of executive action - decisions made by a president that do not need congressional approval.</p>

<p>They want nothing to stand in the way of his plans to deport millions of people in the country illegally and to reduce the size of the federal bureaucracy. In his first term Trump often complained of "deep state" bureaucrats he said were seeking to thwart him.</p>

<p>"The president... must be allowed to implement his policies free of a bureaucracy resistant to them and unelected officials who do not agree with them," Tarpley said.</p>

<p>There are constitutional limits to what Trump can do through the power of his office, however, and any policies could still face lawsuits.</p>

<p>"I think the fears of critics are overblown, in the sense that they're more worried about the substance of his likely policies than the possibility that they'll be adopted through unilateral executive action," Stewart Baker, a former general counsel for the U.S. National Security Agency, said.</p>

<p>If Trump goes too far, his opponents say, they may still be able to count on federal courts to check him.</p>

<p>"We are mindful of the fact that we have a very conservative Supreme Court. But what we have found is that even Trump-appointed judges have ruled against his policies and found them illegal," said Kica Matos, president of the National Immigration Law Center.</p>

<p>Half of Republican respondents to a Reuters/Ipsos poll this week said they agreed with the statement that "the country is in a crisis and needs a strong president who should be allowed to rule without too much interference from the courts and Congress."</p>

<p>That was substantially higher than the 35% of Democrats and 33% of independents who agreed with the sentiment.</p>

<p>Only one convention attendee interviewed by Reuters, a senior Republican from a southern state, said he was worried about a second Trump administration. He said he feared Trump would become an autocrat, fill government agencies with yes men, and seek revenge on his political enemies.</p>

<p>Referring to Trump's pledge to supporters that he will be their "retribution," the Republican, who asked to remain anonymous, said: "That effort will be horrendous."</p>

<p>Trump was widely criticized for saying during the campaign that should he win, he will be a "dictator" - if only for a day, a comment he later said was a joke.</p>

<p>Democrats have rebuked him for promising to pardon his supporters imprisoned for the deadly Jan. 6, 2021, insurrection at the U.S. Capitol that was triggered by his refusal to accept his 2020 election loss.</p>

<p>Trump, who was convicted of making hush money payments to a former porn star and faces charges related to his efforts to overturn Biden's victory, has threatened to use the Justice Department to pursue opponents, including Biden. Trump has pleaded not guilty to the charges.</p>

<p>Former Republican presidential candidate Asa Hutchinson said he was concerned about the lack of constraints on Trump in a second term.</p>

<p>"The Department of Justice is probably the perfect example of that. Clearly, a President Trump would have a close hand at directing the activities of the Justice Department," Hutchinson, a former governor of Arkansas, told Reuters.</p>

<p><strong>Making 'Nixon Blush'</strong></p>

<p>The implications of a second Trump term are profoundly disturbing for America and the world, said presidential historian Timothy Naftali, a former director at the presidential library of Richard Nixon, who resigned from office in disgrace in 1974 after the Watergate scandal.</p>

<p>Naftali said a recent Supreme Court decision granting sweeping immunity to a president for most acts while in office, combined with a pliant Republican Party, means there are limited constraints on Trump should he act maliciously and exploit the office for his own personal power and political retribution.</p>

<p>"He can gut the Justice Department and engage in a revenge tour that would make Nixon blush," Naftali said.</p>

<p>To be sure, Trump would not be the first president to test the limits of executive power. Leaders including former Democratic presidents Franklin Roosevelt and Barack Obama have taken an expansive view of their authority.</p>

<p>Even with the July 1 ruling by the high court on presidential immunity, Trump ostensibly would still be bound by the U.S. Constitution's separation of powers that reserves key functions to Congress and the judiciary.</p>

<p>Lara Trump, the Republican National Committee co-chair, and Trump's daughter-in-law acknowledged this week that governance by executive action - which can be overturned in the courts or by a successor - was not ideal. That's why it was crucial for Republicans to hold onto the House of Representatives in November and take the Senate from Democrats, she said, "so we don't have to rely on executive actions and we can actually see some lasting change."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/tif74i68_donald-trump-reuters_625x300_23_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>