<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Mon, 28 Oct 2024 11:08:52 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-from-immigration-to-abortion-5-issues-at-stake-in-the-us-election-6890136]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[From Immigration To Abortion: 5 Issues At Stake In The US Election]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-from-immigration-to-abortion-5-issues-at-stake-in-the-us-election-6890136]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 28 Oct 2024 11:11:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[From taxes, to immigration, to abortion -- here are the five key issues which are at stake as Donald Trump and Kamala Harris enter a final sprint in the race for the White House.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Tax breaks for families with children? Supporting Ukraine? Drilling for oil?</p>

<p>From taxes, to immigration, to abortion -- here are the five key issues which are at stake as Donald Trump and Kamala Harris enter a final sprint in the race for the White House.</p>

<p><strong>Economy</strong></p>

<p>Trump, who cut taxes for businesses and the wealthy during his 2017-2021 presidency, plans to impose tariffs of more than 10 percent on all US imports, which he says will enable him to lower taxes for Americans. &nbsp;</p>

<p>The Republican has also vowed to make the United States the "crypto capital of the planet," and launched his own cryptocurrency platform with his sons in September.</p>

<p>Democrat Harris, meanwhile, is appealing to the middle class with her promise to create an "opportunity economy," while pitching moderate tax hikes for the richest people.</p>

<p>The 60-year-old has also promoted child tax credits, support for first-time homebuyers, and help for small businesses.</p>

<p><strong>Immigration</strong></p>

<p>Trump has taken a hard-line approach on immigration, saying that he will order mass deportations of millions of undocumented migrants if reelected.</p>

<p>The former president, who in 2016 promised to build a wall along the US-Mexico border, has accused immigrants of "poisoning the blood of our country."</p>

<p>For her part, Harris has pledged a tough stance and warned of "consequences" for people who enter the country illegally.&nbsp;</p>

<p>She has supported President Joe Biden's plan to tighten up immigration policy, notably by investing in physical barriers on the border.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Abortion</strong></p>

<p>Reproductive rights are a big issue for some US voters after the federal right to abortion was removed in 2022 with the overturning of Roe v Wade, resulting in total abortion bans in some states.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Trump has often boasted of his role in appointing the Supreme Court justices who scrapped the 1973 decision, and has further hinted that he may restrict access to drugs used in medical abortions if reelected.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The 78-year-old, who was found liable last year for sexually assaulting writer E. Jean Carroll, has nonetheless promised to be "great for women."</p>

<p>Harris wants to pass a federal law to reinstate nationwide abortion rights, making the issue a key part of her presidential campaign.&nbsp;</p>

<p>On November 5, voters in 10 states will decide whether to adopt constitutional amendments that could shape the future of abortion access in their states. &nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Foreign politics</strong></p>

<p>With wars raging in the Middle East and in Ukraine, Trump has promised to quickly resolve both conflicts -- though without explaining how.&nbsp;</p>

<p>He has denounced the huge amount of US funding for Kyiv since it was invaded by Russia in 2022.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Harris has pledged her enduring support for Ukraine if reelected.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Both Trump and Harris offer continued backing for Israel, though the vice president has drawn more attention to the suffering of Palestinians.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Climate</strong></p>

<p>The United States is the world's second-biggest greenhouse gas emitter behind China, but neither candidate has outlined a comprehensive platform on the issue.</p>

<p>Trump, who has long denounced climate change as a "hoax" despite overwhelming scientific evidence, plans to cut subsidies for renewable energies and electric vehicles, which he says harm businesses.</p>

<p>The Republican has vowed to "drill, baby, drill" for oil, and to again remove the United States from the Paris climate agreement.</p>

<p>Harris has promoted the "Inflation Reduction Act" of President Joe Biden, which has driven investment in green energy.</p>

<p>She "is committed to continuing and building upon the United States' international climate leadership," according to her campaign website.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/7v0s9c6o_donald-trump-and-kamala-harris-in-second-presidential-debate_625x300_11_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kamala Harris wants to pass a federal law to reinstate nationwide abortion rights.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-what-if-donald-trump-loses-6890092]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What If Donald Trump Loses US Elections]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-what-if-donald-trump-loses-6890092]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 28 Oct 2024 11:05:00 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Much of the outside world's focus during the 2024 US election has been on what victory for Donald Trump might look like, but many Americans are fretting about the opposite outcome -- including some of his most vocal opponents.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Much of the outside world's focus during the 2024 US election has been on what victory for Donald Trump might look like, but many Americans are fretting about the opposite outcome -- including some of his most vocal opponents.</p>

<p>The Republican ex-president, who is in a dead heat with Democrat Kamala Harris in the race for the White House, has never acknowledged the legitimacy of his election defeats -- from the 2016 Iowa primary to his presidential contest in 2020.</p>

<p>His denialism deeply polarized the country last time around, and his continued attempts to sow distrust in US democracy have sparked fears of a repeat of the violence seen during the 2021 storming of the US Capitol.</p>

<p>"Should he lose this year, I have no doubt that he will claim fraud, leave no stone unturned to reverse the results, and refuse to attend Harris's inauguration," said Donald Nieman, a political analyst at Binghamton University in New York state.</p>

<p>"He's not only a sore loser, he's someone who will never admit he lost."</p>

<p>Trump's rap sheet demonstrates that it is not beyond him to try to cheat in elections.</p>

<p>He has 34 felony convictions for a scandal involving covered-up payments to silence a porn star he feared was about to wreck his 2016 campaign with a salacious story about a sexual encounter.</p>

<p>And he has been indicted twice and impeached twice over alleged efforts to steal or otherwise cheat in the 2020 election, which he still has not conceded.</p>

<p>Rejected by the American people four years ago, Trump and his allies flooded the zone with bogus claims of irregularities and fraud.</p>

<p><strong>Deadly riot</strong></p>

<p>Trump's critics worry about a repeat of the violence that resulted from those lies -- a deadly riot by an angry mob summoned to Washington by Trump, pumped up by his claims of voter fraud and sent marching on the Capitol.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Especially since he's at it again.</p>

<p>"If I lose, I'll tell you what, it's possible because they cheat. That's the only way we're going to lose -- because they cheat," the 78-year-old told rally-goers in Michigan last month.</p>

<p>Trump has been dusting off the same baseless concerns over the legitimacy of vote counts, foreigners voting, the reliability of mail-in ballots and much else.</p>

<p>The ex-president and his allies set the stage for the 2021 riot through legal means -- more than 60 lawsuits largely complaining about the way state and local authorities had changed voting rules to take account of a raging pandemic.&nbsp;</p>

<p>But they lost every substantive case, with judges ruling that objections to election organization should have been lodged long before the first ballot was cast.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Republicans hit the ground running this time around, filing more than 100 lawsuits before early voting began about every aspect of the election, from how Americans register and cast ballots to who can vote.</p>

<p>Many of the suits seek to limit access to the polls and most will be unresolved by Election Day, but experts say this plays into distrust over vote-counting that Trump and other conspiracy theorists have spent years exacerbating.</p>

<p><strong>'Sporadic violence'</strong></p>

<p>"The legal skirmishes might drag on for weeks, and depending on their intensity, could lead to protests or even sporadic violence in certain areas," said political analyst Adrienne Uthe, the founder of Utah-based PR firm Kronus Communications.</p>

<p>Almost two-thirds of Americans are anticipating post-election violence, a Scripps News/Ipsos poll out Thursday found, and most support using the military to quell unrest after polls open on November 5.</p>

<p>More than a quarter believe that civil war could break out, according to a new YouGov poll, with 12 percent saying they know someone who might take up arms if they thought Trump had been cheated.</p>

<p>The intelligence community raised concerns about the potential for bloodshed in a report on election threats from foreign actors that was declassified, redacted and released last week by the Office of the Director of National Intelligence.</p>

<p>"Foreign-driven or -amplified violent protests, violence, or physical threats... could challenge state and local officials' ability to conduct elements of the certification and Electoral College process," it said.</p>

<p>Security measures have been beefed up in Washington in anticipation of potential unrest, although analysts contacted by AFP saw a repeat of the 2021 insurrection in the capital as unlikely, with hundreds of subsequent prosecutions acting as a potent deterrent.</p>

<p>But they warned of the potential for violence in the battleground states during and after the election.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"My biggest fear is violence in Madison, Wisconsin; Lansing, Michigan; or Harrisburg, Pennsylvania by armed Trump supporters designed to prevent electors from casting their votes," said Nieman.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/6tjcj0g_donald-trump-afp_625x300_13_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump's rap sheet demonstrates that it is not beyond him to try to cheat in elections.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/wall-street-tech-royalty-head-to-saudi-crown-princes-event-amid-war-6890077]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Wall Street, Tech Royalty Head To Saudi Crown Prince's Event Amid War]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/wall-street-tech-royalty-head-to-saudi-crown-princes-event-amid-war-6890077]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 28 Oct 2024 11:00:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Saudi Arabia will host the biggest names in finance and technology this coming week in a test of investor appetite for the kingdom's ambitions of transforming itself into a global hub at a time of widening regional conflict.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Saudi Arabia will host the biggest names in finance and technology this coming week in a test of investor appetite for the kingdom's ambitions of transforming itself into a global hub at a time of widening regional conflict.</p>

<p>International executives will have to contend with a region rocked by geopolitical tensions, with the threat of further military confrontation between Israel and Iran at the highest levels in decades. And they will land in a country that is increasingly facing up to the fact that even its vast oil wealth has limits.</p>

<p>But those arriving at the Future Investment Initiative - often dubbed Davos in the desert - seem undeterred, sensing an opportunity to plug into Crown Prince Mohammed bin Salman's trillion-dollar Vision 2030 economic remake. Goldman Sachs Group Inc.'s David Solomon, Citigroup Inc.'s Jane Fraser and BlackRock Inc.'s Larry Fink have become regulars at the Riyadh summit and are set to return this year.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Reflecting Saudi Arabia's focus on technology and artificial intelligence, they'll be joined by prominent names in those industries. Alphabet Inc. President Ruth Porat and TikTok Inc. Chief Executive Officer Shou Chew are set to speak at the summit for the first time. Benjamin Horowitz, tech entrepreneur and co-founder of venture capital giant Andreessen Horowitz, is also making an appearance.</p>

<p>Wall Street and Silicon Valley have increasingly turned to the oil-rich Middle East as liquidity gets tighter in other parts of the world, especially China. Saudi Arabia itself commands nearly $1 trillion in sovereign wealth, though the Crown Prince wants titans of industry to stop deploying that money overseas and instead help support his domestic ambitions.</p>

<p>Yet the backdrop is one of increasing uncertainty.</p>

<p>Saudi foreign policy has recently focused on lowering regional tensions in the hope that a more stable region will bring in foreign capital and technological know-how. But events of the past year have served as a reminder of how unstable the region can be.</p>

<p>"The impact of regional instability on the prospects for foreign investment is completely negative, with the possible exception of the defense industry," said Gregory Gause, Professor of International Affairs at Texas A&amp;M University. Capital is "not attracted to conflict regions, even if the country is not an immediate participant in the conflict."</p>

<p>To be sure, Saudi Arabia is still pushing ahead with its big development plans. Deals worth more than $28 billion are likely to be announced over the next week by executives from around the world, according to Richard Attias, CEO of the FII Institute.</p>

<p>Some of these will focus on AI, including potentially a new fund with Andreessen Horowitz that could grow to as large as $40 billion. The kingdom is also expected to announce a new company that will invest at least $10 billion in making Saudi Arabia a top global producer of hydrogen - a low carbon fuel that could be key to the world's transition away from burning fossil fuels.</p>

<p>Ahead of the event, General Atlantic said it's opening its first office in the Middle East - in Saudi Arabia - to scout for more deals in the region.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Two exchange-traded funds will make their trading debuts in Riyadh, giving Saudi investors access to Hong Kong stocks - a reflection of the kingdom's growing ties with China as it looks to boost investment flows with its biggest trading partner. Hong Kong Financial Secretary Paul Chan, and the Commissioner for the Belt and Road, Nicholas Ho, will speak at FII as some of the highest profile speakers from Asia.</p>

<p>Still, the regional conflict is undoubtedly weighing on global investor sentiment in the Middle East. Saudi Arabia, the biggest Gulf economy, is feeling some of that.</p>

<p>The number of actively-managed emerging market funds with Saudi exposure had been rising sharply until earlier this year, but stalled at around 56% as tensions between Israel and Iran escalated, according to Copley Fund Research. The data show that the number of funds invested in the Saudi stock market fell slightly between March and September this year and that the country is the third-biggest underweight after Taiwan and India.</p>

<p>Coupled with that, Crown Prince Mohammed has had to come to terms with the limits of even Saudi Arabia's vast financial resources to pay for his ambitions. The government, which is forecasting deficits out to at least 2027, has said some projects will be need to be delayed.</p>

<p>At the same time, the Public Investment Fund, the kingdom's powerful sovereign fund that the de-facto ruler chairs, is becoming a tougher place for foreign firms to get money out of. An increased focus on domestic projects like the $1.5 trillion Neom has global asset managers fretting that the PIF will have less cash to spend abroad.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The FII has always been designed as a mechanism for investment into Saudi, however in reality it has been an opportunity for foreign execs to extract financing from the Kingdom," said Zaid Belbagi, managing partner of political risk consultancy Hardcastle Advisory. "Sold-out hotels at $500-1000 per night are indicative of sustained international interest."</p>

<p>The organizers of the Riyadh jamboree remain confident, and about 7,000 people have registered to attend this year's event. That's higher than the numbers for last year's summit, which took place days after the current conflict in the region started.</p>

<p>When asked what attendees were speaking about ahead of the event, FII Institute's Attias said the US election was front of mind. There are many executives that feel developments in the Middle East hinge on the outcome of the vote, he said on a Bloomberg television interview on Monday.</p>

<p>Even so, investors are coming "despite what is happening in the world," Attias said. "The show must go on."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/1c5ghek_saudi-crown-prince-bloomberg_625x300_28_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Crown Prince has had to come to terms with the limits of even Saudi Arabia's vast financial resources]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mcdonalds-rules-out-beef-caused-e-coli-to-resume-quarter-pounder-sales-6889923]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[McDonald's Rules Out Beef Caused E. Coli. To Resume Quarter Pounder Sales]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mcdonalds-rules-out-beef-caused-e-coli-to-resume-quarter-pounder-sales-6889923]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 28 Oct 2024 10:55:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Beef patties have been ruled out as the source of the E. coli outbreak, McDonald's said on Sunday, adding the fast-food giant will soon resume sales of its quarter-pounder hamburgers.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Beef patties have been ruled out as the source of the E. coli outbreak, McDonald's said on Sunday, adding the fast-food giant will soon resume sales of its quarter-pounder hamburgers. The US Food and Drug Administration (FDA) maintains that the contamination is most likely linked to slivered onions sourced from a specific supplier, McDonald's said. The company plans to reintroduce the quarter pounder but without slivered onions within a week, reported <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/retail-consumer/mcdonalds-rules-out-beef-patties-source-e-coli-outbreak-2024-10-27/" rel="nofollow,noindex">Reuters</a>.</p>

<p>McDonald's had pulled out the quarter pounder from around 20 per cent&nbsp;of its US outlets, specifically in states such as Colorado, Kansas, Utah, Wyoming&nbsp;and parts of Idaho, Iowa, Missouri, Montana, Nebraska, Nevada, New Mexico, and Oklahoma.</p>

<p>According to Reuters, Cesar Pina, the chief supply chain officer for McDonald's, reassured the public, stating, “We remain very confident that any contaminated product related to this outbreak has been removed from our supply chain and is out of all McDonald's restaurants.”</p>

<p>The Colorado Department of Agriculture conducted detailed testing, confirming all subsamples from various batches of McDonald's fresh and frozen beef patties returned negative results for E. coli. The department also indicated that it concluded its beef testing and did not foresee the need for additional samples.</p>

<p>The E. coli outbreak in the US has caused at least one death in Colorado and sickened nearly 75 others across multiple states in the US.</p>

<p>Authorities had been probing the potential involvement of McDonald's beef patties in the outbreak, which raised concerns among consumers and health officials alike.</p>

<p>In response to the outbreak, various fast-food chains across the US removed fresh onions from their menus after the vegetable was believed to be a potential source of contamination.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/gsf8fkqo_mcdonalds_625x300_23_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[McDonald's had pulled out the quarter pounder from around 20 per centof its US outlets.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-a-melting-iceberg-a-68-is-reshaping-marine-ecosystems-6889746]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How A Melting Iceberg Is Reshaping Marine Ecosystems]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-a-melting-iceberg-a-68-is-reshaping-marine-ecosystems-6889746]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 28 Oct 2024 10:20:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A massive iceberg, A-68, which broke off from Antarctica's Larsen C Ice Shelf in 2017, has created a distinctive marine environment during its four-year drift, according to recent scientific analyses.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A massive iceberg, A-68, which broke off from Antarctica's Larsen C Ice Shelf in 2017, has created a distinctive marine environment during its four-year drift, according to recent scientific analyses. In July 2017, the massive iceberg, later named A-68, broke off in an event called ‘calving,' and began a journey across the Southern Ocean. It became the largest iceberg adrift at the time.</p>

<p>Initially covering over 2,200 square miles (over 5,698 km) — more than twice the size of the European country Luxembourg — the iceberg captured global attention as it drifted north, propelled by ocean currents and winds.</p>

<p>Concerns rose in late 2020 when A-68 neared South Georgia Island, a critical breeding ground for threatened species. “South Georgia is an incredibly rich, dynamic marine ecosystem,” Geraint Tarling, a polar ecologist at the British Antarctic Survey in Cambridge, UK, told the <a href="https://www.bbc.com/future/article/20241025-how-mega-icebergs-change-the-ocean" rel="nofollow,noindex">BBC</a>. The island's nutrient-rich waters support phytoplankton, krill and larger marine animals. Its shores are home to breeding colonies of threatened species, including king penguins and wandering albatrosses.</p>

<p>But the iceberg avoided a catastrophic collision with the island. It began to collapse in December 2020 and gradually broke apart and melted into smaller fragments over the course of 2021.</p>

<p>As it dissolved, A-68 released billions of tons of freshwater into the ocean, significantly altering the surrounding marine habitat. The iceberg created conditions that scientists say supported diverse ecosystems, functioning as a temporary sanctuary for various species.</p>

<p>Nutrient levels in the surrounding waters rose, drawing in ice-associated algae, which created temporary micro-ecosystems teeming with life. Zooplankton flocked to feed on the algae, and Tarling speculated larger animals like baleen whales would likely have followed.</p>

<p>“You have this sort of halo effect,” he said, as algae bloomed around the iceberg fragments.</p>

<p>"Everything was happening so fast it just completely changed the whole dynamic of that," Tarling added. “What was happening is that huge dumps of water were coming in.” The weight of the freshwater pushed down the underlying layers, causing conditions that would typically exist at 164 feet to occur at depths of 328 feet instead.</p>

<p>Any food particles drifting in the water were also forced downward. “This deepening of the water masses is creating an effect that we've never seen before, taking all this particulate material down with it,” he said.</p>

<p>This phenomenon may have actually increased the amount of carbon buried at the bottom of the Southern Ocean. Typically, organic material descends slowly through the water, with some being consumed, so only a small portion reaches the seabed to be trapped there. However, the immense weight of the freshwater from A-68a as it melted might have accelerated the descent of carbon-based material to depths where it is less likely to be consumed.</p>

<p>“No one's ever reported this,” Tarling said. This suggests that large icebergs like A-68 could play a role in driving carbon deep into the ocean, potentially reducing greenhouse gas concentrations in the atmosphere.</p>

<p>During its journey after breaking away from the Antarctic ice shelf, A-68 shed a staggering 802 billion tonnes of ice. Between late 2020 and early 2021, it released around 152 billion tonnes of freshwater into the ocean — equivalent to nearly 61 million Olympic-sized swimming pools.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-11/68r8qejs_icebergs_625x300_13_November_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The iceberg created conditions that scientists say supported diverse ecosystems.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-uk-couples-fight-against-google-cost-the-tech-giant-2-billion-pounds-6889657]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How UK Couple's Fight Against Google Cost The Tech Giant 2 Billion Pounds]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-uk-couples-fight-against-google-cost-the-tech-giant-2-billion-pounds-6889657]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 28 Oct 2024 10:17:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A UK couple has won a 15-year-long legal battle against Google, with the tech giant facing a record 2.4 billion pound fine for market abuse.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A UK couple has won a 15-year-long legal battle against Google, with the tech giant facing a record 2.4 billion pound fine for market abuse. Shivaun and Adam Raff, founders of the price comparison website ‘Foundem', launched their business in 2006. Soon after going live, they noticed a dramatic drop in their website's visibility on Google searches for key terms such as “price comparison” and “shopping.”</p>

<p>The unexpected drop was caused by a search penalty from Google's automated spam filters that ranked their site much lower than expected. This penalty affected Foundem's ability to generate revenue after users couldn't access the site through Google's search results.</p>

<p>"We were monitoring our pages and how they were ranking, and then we saw them all plummet almost immediately," Mr Adam told the <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cjr431lr72jo " rel="nofollow,noindex">BBC</a>. Initially, the couple assumed the dip in visibility was an error. "We just assumed we had to escalate to the right place and it would be overturned," Ms Shivaun explained. Even after two years and despite many attempts, Google didn't lift the penalty. Foundem's traffic continued to suffer, while other search engines ranked it normally.</p>

<p>In 2010, their case gained traction after they approached the European Commission. A lengthy antitrust investigation found Google unfairly promoted its own shopping service over competitors like Foundem. The Commission ultimately ruled, in 2017, that Google abused its market dominance, imposing a fine of 2.4 billion pounds.</p>

<p>However, Google appealed, sparking seven years of legal battles. In 2024, the European Court of Justice upheld the fine, rejecting Google's appeals.</p>

<p>For Shivaun and Adam Raff, the conclusion felt long overdue. "We've both been brought up maybe under the delusion that we can make a difference, and we really don't like bullies," said Ms Shivaun.</p>

<p>Google maintains the fine addresses practices that ended in 2017. A spokesperson told BBC, “The changes we made in 2017 to comply with the European Commission's Shopping decision have worked successfully for more than seven years, generating billions of clicks for more than 800 comparison shopping services.”</p>

<p>The Raffs are pursuing a civil damages claim against Google, set for trial in 2026, though Foundem was forced to close in 2016. "If we had known it would take this long, we might have thought twice," said Mr Adam, acknowledging the toll of their 15-year battle.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-05/k86n0d7s_google-logo_625x300_14_May_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Google maintains the fine addresses practices that ended in 2017.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/a-for-abortion-b-for-border-us-election-vocabulary-explained-6889651]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[A For Abortion, B For Border: US Election Vocabulary Explained]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/a-for-abortion-b-for-border-us-election-vocabulary-explained-6889651]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 28 Oct 2024 09:46:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Struggling to understand the US presidential election? Here's an A-Z dictionary to guide you through the battle between Kamala Harris and Donald Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Struggling to understand the US presidential election? Here's an A-Z dictionary to guide you through the battle between Kamala Harris and Donald Trump.</p>

<p>A - Abortion. A hot button issue that Democrats hope will be Trump's Achilles heel, given his role as president in ending the federal right to the procedure.</p>

<p>B - Border. A weakness for Vice President Harris, through her association with President Joe Biden, amid charges that under their watch the frontier with Mexico was crossed by millions of undocumented migrants.</p>

<p>C - California. The liberal home state of Harris, a circumstance that has prompted her to try to look more centrist and moderate as she woos independent and Republican voters.</p>

<p>D - Debate. A catastrophic performance by Biden in June led to him abandoning his campaign. Trump was bested by Harris in their debate and he has refused a rematch before Election Day.</p>

<p>E - Elon, as in Musk. The tech mogul that has put his mouth, money and media platform at the service of Trump.</p>

<p>F - Fundraising. After replacing Biden, Harris stunned America by attracting vast sums in donations from suddenly jubilant supporters.</p>

<p><strong>Eating dogs and cats?</strong></p>

<p>G - Genitalia. The anatomical feature of the late golf great Arnold Palmer that Trump saw fit to address at a campaign rally.</p>

<p>H - Haitian. The nationality of some immigrants living in Ohio that Trump, his running mate JD Vance and other Republicans have alleged, falsely, are eating people's dogs and cats.</p>

<p>I - Information (see dis- and mis-). A mist of bogus and often ridiculous claims permeating the campaign, like the pet-eating Haitians and this gem from Republican lawmaker Marjorie Taylor Greene: the Biden administration is controlling the weather.</p>

<p>J - January 6. The date of the 2021 Capitol insurrection by violent Trump supporters bent on keeping him in power after he lost to Biden in the 2020 election. Trump recently called the uprising "a day of love."</p>

<p>K - Kamala. What's in a name? If elected, she would be America's first female president and the first one of South Asian heritage -- both historic achievements that are reflected in her name.</p>

<p>L - Ladies, ones with cats but no kids. A demographic defined by Vance years ago which came back to haunt him.</p>

<p>M - Media. Harris was accused of avoiding one-on-one interviews, reinforcing the impression that Americans simply did not know much about her.</p>

<p><strong>'Most beautiful word'</strong></p>

<p>N - National security. Trump says he will bolster it while Harris says he is a threat to it.</p>

<p>O - Old. Biden, 81, bowed out because of the impression he was too worn out for another term. Trump at 78, is now the oldest US candidate ever. At 60, Harris by comparison comes across as young.</p>

<p>P - Project 2025. A prominent think tank's blueprint for authoritarian rule under Trump.</p>

<p>Q - Quit, for Biden's departure from the race. The political earthquake this July of an incumbent president stepping aside and yielding to Harris rejuvenated Democrats who had been increasingly resigned to another Trump term.</p>

<p>R - Refusal. Trump refuses to promise he will accept a loss in November, raising the specter of another January 6 type insurrection.</p>

<p>S - Swing states. The seven states that can go either way and are seen as determining the election.</p>

<p>T - Tariffs. The levies Trump says he will slap on all imports into the US. "It's the most beautiful word in the dictionary," he has said.</p>

<p>U - "Unfit" and "unstable." How Harris describes Trump.</p>

<p>V - Vague. Harris has faced charges of leaving her policy positions intentionally ambiguous so as not to alienate potential voters.</p>

<p>W - Weird. Harris's running mate Tim Walz coined this way of describing Trump, Vance and others in their orbit, much to the delight of Democrats.</p>

<p>X - (E)xhausted. A term that a Trump aide has been quoted as using to describe the Republican in the grueling homestretch.</p>

<p>Y - Yes men. The people, it is feared, that Trump would surround himself with in a second term, meaning no guard rails against rash or dangerous behavior.</p>

<p>Z - Zelensky, Volodymyr. The Ukrainian president who is surely fretting over Trump's affinity for Putin, who ordered the 2022 invasion.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/59fkr768_us-elections_625x300_28_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US Elections 2024: Donald Trump vs Kamala Harris.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/earths-biodiversity-crisis-1-million-species-face-extinction-6889562]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Earth's Biodiversity Crisis: 1 Million Species Face Extinction]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/earths-biodiversity-crisis-1-million-species-face-extinction-6889562]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 28 Oct 2024 09:25:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Over a quarter of plants and animals assessed on the International Union for Conservation of Nature's Red List of threatened species risk extinction.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The experts' assessment is clear: humans are the major threat to Earth's land, seas and all the living things they shelter, including ourselves.</p>

<p>The COP16 biodiversity summit in Cali, Colombia, enters its second week Monday to assess, and ramp up, progress towards achieving 23 targets agreed in Canada two years ago to halt and reverse nature destruction by 2030.</p>

<p>The science in numbers:</p>

<p><strong>2/3 of oceans degraded</strong></p>

<p>Three-quarters of Earth's surface has already been significantly altered and two-thirds of oceans degraded by humankind's rapacious consumption, according to the IPBES intergovernmental science and policy body on biodiversity.</p>

<p>Globally, over a third of inland wetlands declined from 1970 to 2015 -- a rate three times that of forest loss.</p>

<p>"Land degradation through human activities is undermining the well-being of at least 3.2 billion people," according to the IPBES's latest report.</p>

<p>But it highlights that not all is lost, and the benefits of restoration would be 10 times higher than the costs.</p>

<p>One of the 23 targets of the so-called Kunming-Montreal Global Biodiversity Framework is for 30 percent of degraded land, inland water, marine and coastal ecosystems to be under "effective restoration" by 2030.</p>

<p><strong>A million species threatened</strong></p>

<p>Over a quarter of plants and animals assessed on the International Union for Conservation of Nature's Red List of threatened species risk extinction.</p>

<p>According to the IPBES, about a million species are at risk.</p>

<p>Pollinators, essential to the reproduction of plants and three-quarters of crops that feed humanity, are at the forefront, dying off fast.</p>

<p>Corals -- on which the food and labor of some 850 million people depend -- are another striking example.</p>

<p>These animals, whose reefs provide feeding and spawning grounds for a multitude of creatures, could all but disappear in a world 2 degrees Celsius (3.6 degrees Fahrenheit) warmer than pre-industrial levels.</p>

<p>This is the upper limit of average planet warming the world is seeking not to exceed under the 2015 Paris Agreement on curbing Earth-warming greenhouse gases.</p>

<p><strong>Five horsemen of the apocalypse</strong></p>

<p>For the UN, the biodiversity crisis has five causes, all human-induced and nicknamed the "Five Horsemen of the Apocalypse."</p>

<p>They are habitat destruction (for agriculture or human infrastructure), over-exploitation of resources such as water, climate change, pollution and the spread of invasive species.</p>

<p>Climate change is likely to become the main driver of biodiversity destruction by 2050, experts say.</p>

<p><strong>Half of GDP</strong></p>

<p>More than half (55%) of the world's gross domestic product, some $58 trillion, depends "heavily or moderately" on nature and its services, according to auditing giant PwC.</p>

<p>Agriculture, forestry, fisheries and aquaculture, the food and beverage industry and construction are the sectors most exposed to nature loss.</p>

<p>Pollination services, safe water, and disease control are other, nigh-incalculable, benefits derived from nature.</p>

<p>Indian economist Pavan Sukhdev, who led a research project entitled The Economics of Ecosystems and Biodiversity (TEEB) had estimated that biodiversity loss comes at a cost of between 1.35 trillion and 3.1 trillion euros ($1.75 trillion and $4 trillion) per year.</p>

<p><strong>$2.6 billion in subsidies</strong></p>

<p>A report in September by the Earth Track monitor said environmentally harmful subsidies to industries were worth at least $2.6 trillion, equivalent to 2.5 percent of global GDP.</p>

<p>This dwarfs the Kunming-Montreal framework's target of mobilizing $200 billion per year by 2030 for nature protection.</p>

<p>Harmful industries that benefit from subsidies include fisheries, agriculture and fossil fuel producers.</p>

<p>Another target of the biodiversity framework is to reduce harmful subsidies and tax benefits by "at least $500 billion per year" by 2030.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-06/lflm0p18_biodiversity-park_625x300_05_June_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Humans are the major threat to Earth's land, seas and all the living things they shelter, warn experts.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mossad-chief-heads-to-qatar-israel-continues-multi-front-war-10-facts-6889471]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Mossad Chief Heads To Qatar, Israel Continues Multi-Front War: 10 Facts]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mossad-chief-heads-to-qatar-israel-continues-multi-front-war-10-facts-6889471]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 28 Oct 2024 09:06:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel's Mossad chief is set to visit Qatar to discuss the release of hostages in Gaza, even as Egypt proposed a two-day truce in the Palestinian enclave, as regional tensions simmered.

Here are today's top developments in the multi-front war:]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="CetSht_cn">
<ol class="CetSht_ol">
	<li class="CetSht_li">Chief of Israel's Mossad intelligence agency David Barnea will head to Qatar's Doha on Sunday to discuss the release of hostages in Gaza, the office of Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said. Barnea will meet with US Central Intelligence Agency Director William Burns and Qatari Prime Minister Sheikh Mohammed bin Abdulrahman bin Jassim Al Thani, against the background of the latest developments.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Egyptian President Abdel Fattah al-Sisi announced a proposed two-day truce and limited hostage exchange in Gaza aimed at securing "a complete ceasefire" after more than a year of war between Israel and Hamas. The proposal includes exchanging four Israeli hostages held in Gaza for Palestinian prisoners in Israeli jails, and would be followed by more negotiations within 10 days, Sisi said at a news conference in Cairo.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">An emergency UN Security Council meeting will take place on Monday at Iran's request, with Tehran calling for it to condemn the strikes that killed four soldiers.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">A truck crashed into a crowd of people at a bus stop in central Israel, killing one man and injuring more than two dozen people. Police did not immediately say whether the incident, near the Mossad spy agency's headquarters and other Israeli intelligence sites, was an attack or an accident.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">The Hebrew language account opened by Iran's leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei on social media platform X has been suspended after just two posts, as per Jerusalem Post. The latest post from Sunday read, "The Zionist regime made a mistake, and erred in its calculation regarding Iran. We will make it understand what power, ability, initiative and desire the Iranian nation has."</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Heavy bombing continued in Gaza. The Israeli military said it had killed another 40 militants in the territory. United Nations Secretary-General Antonio Guterres expressed deep concern for the fate of Gaza's civilians. "The plight of Palestinian civilians trapped in north Gaza is unbearable," Guterres's spokesman said.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Iran's Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei has said that Israel's airstrikes on Iran should not be magnified nor downplayed. While Israel would like to amplify the impacts of its actions against Iran, Khamenei said, adding it would also not be right for Iran to dismiss the strikes as insignificant, CNN reported. "They still haven't been able to correctly understand the power, capability, ingenuity, and determination of the Iranian people. We need to make them understand these things," he said.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Lebanon continued to receive donations from different countries to support the Lebanese government amid the escalation of the Hezbollah-Israeli conflict. Lebanon received a second airplane from Pakistan carrying 17 tons of food and medical supplies, according to the Lebanese official National News Agency (NNA). It also received from Saudi Arabia the 14th airplane carrying relief aid, including food, shelter, and medical supplies, and two planes carrying humanitarian aid provided by Jordan and the first shipment of the second fuel grant provided by Qatar.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Iran's Foreign Minister Abbas Araghchi said he had "received indications" hours before Israel launched an attack on military sites. "We had received indications since the evening about the possibility of an attack that night," Araghchi told reporters without specifying the nature of the indications. Araghchi said the "necessary measures" were taken when the attack unfolded, adding that he had been in contact with military officials and that "messages were also exchanged with different parties" whom he did not name.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Oil prices tumbled with markets relieved by various factors, among them that Israel's strikes on Iran had avoided the country's energy infrastructure. Oil prices fell as much as five percent in early trade before paring some of their losses.</li>
</ol>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/1sfjlmgg_mossad-chief_625x300_28_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mossad chief David Barnea attends a ceremony marking the anniversary of the October 7 Hamas attack]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/georgia-polls-opposition-calls-for-protest-eu-demands-investigation-into-irregularities-6889434]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Georgian Opposition Calls For Protest, EU Demands Investigation]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/georgia-polls-opposition-calls-for-protest-eu-demands-investigation-into-irregularities-6889434]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 28 Oct 2024 09:00:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Georgian opposition called for protests on Monday and the European Union demanded an investigation into "irregularities" after a disputed legislative vote that showed a win for the ruling party accused of moving towards Russia's orbit.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Georgian opposition called for protests on Monday and the European Union demanded an investigation into "irregularities" after a disputed legislative vote that showed a win for the ruling party accused of moving towards Russia's orbit.</p>

<p>Pro-Western President Salome Zurabishvili on Sunday accused Moscow of orchestrating election fraud, calling it a "Russian special operation".</p>

<p>Amid angry opposition claims over the result, Zurabishvili called for a rally on Monday. Jailed former president Mikheil Saakashvili also called for mass protests.</p>

<p>The European Union had warned that Saturday's vote, seen as a crucial test of democracy in the Caucasus country, could determine Tbilisi's chances of joining the bloc.</p>

<p>EU council president Charles Michel wrote on social media that Georgian authorities should "swiftly, transparently and independently investigate and adjudicate electoral irregularities and allegations thereof."</p>

<p>"These alleged irregularities must be seriously clarified and addressed," he said.</p>

<p>US Secretary of State Antony Blinken also said he supported calls for investigations into "election-related violations", citing reports from international and local observers of "vote buying and voter intimidation".</p>

<p>After meeting with opposition leaders in Tbilisi, Zurabishvili said there had been a "total falsification of the election".</p>

<p>"We are witnesses and victims of a Russian special operation, a modern form of hybrid war against the Georgian people," she said.</p>

<p>International observers said Saturday's election was "marred by an uneven playing field, pressure and tension".</p>

<p>An EU parliament mission also expressed concern about "democratic backsliding", saying it had seen instances of "ballot box stuffing" and the "physical assault" of observers.</p>

<p><strong>'Fighting for freedom'</strong></p>

<p>Saakashvili, who spearheaded the bloodless Rose Revolution in 2003, said on Facebook that opposition lawmakers should renounce their parliamentary seats.</p>

<p>"Now is the time for mass protests. We must show the world that we are fighting for freedom and that we are a people who will not tolerate injustice," he said.</p>

<p>Official tallies from more than 99 percent of precincts showed the ruling Georgian Dream party winning 54 percent of the vote, with the main pro-Western opposition coalition on 37.5 percent.</p>

<p>The result gives Georgian Dream 91 seats in the 150-member parliament -- enough to govern but short of the supermajority it had sought to pass a constitutional ban on all main opposition parties.</p>

<p>"Our victory is impressive," Prime Minister Irakli Kobakhidze said in a statement, accusing the opposition of "undermining the country's constitutional order" by questioning his party's victory.</p>

<p>The government said that Hungarian Prime Minister Viktor Orban, an ally of the ruling party and current holder of the EU's rotating presidency, would visit Georgia on Monday and Tuesday.</p>

<p>Orban rushed to congratulate Georgian Dream for an "overwhelming victory" on Saturday after one exit poll showed the government in the lead and before preliminary results had been published.</p>

<p>Another exit poll by US pollster Edison Research had projected an opposition victory by an 11-percent margin.</p>

<p><strong>EU hopes 'dimmed'</strong></p>

<p>Opposition parties lined up to denounce the vote.</p>

<p>"This is an attempt to steal Georgia's future," said Tina Bokuchava, leader of Saakashvili's United National Movement (UNM).</p>

<p>Nika Gvaramia, leader of the liberal Akhali party, called the way the vote was held "a constitutional coup" by the government.</p>

<p>Analyst Gela Vasadze of the Georgian Strategic Analysis Centre said the country was plunging "into political instability for an indefinite period" and that its EU hopes had "dimmed".</p>

<p>He said, however, that the opposition lacked "charismatic leaders who could channel popular anger into a protest wave capable of bringing about political change."</p>

<p><strong>'Global war party'</strong></p>

<p>Georgia was gripped by mass demonstrations this year against what the opposition saw as government attempts to curtail democratic freedoms and steer the country of four million off its pro-Western course and towards Russia.</p>

<p>In power since 2012, Georgian Dream initially pursued a liberal pro-Western policy agenda.</p>

<p>But it has reversed course over the last two years.</p>

<p>Its campaign centred on a conspiracy theory about a "global war party" that controls Western institutions and is seeking to drag Georgia into the Russia-Ukraine war.</p>

<p>In a country scarred by Russia's 2008 invasion, the party has offered voters bogeyman stories about an imminent threat of war, which only Georgian Dream could prevent.</p>

<p>Georgian Dream's controversial "foreign influence" law which targeted civil society sparked weeks of street protests and was criticised as a Kremlin-style measure to silence dissent.</p>

<p>The move prompted Brussels to freeze Georgia's EU accession process, while Washington imposed sanctions on dozens of Georgian officials.</p>

<p>In a campaign against sexual minorities, the ruling party has adopted measures that ban LGBTQ "propaganda", nullify same-sex marriages conducted abroad, and outlaw gender reassignment.</p>

<p><strong>READ |</strong>&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bidzina-ivanishvili-secretive-billionaire-called-georgias-puppet-master-6889122">Bidzina Ivanishvili, Secretive Billionaire Called Georgia's "Puppet Master"</a></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/ii920tto_georgia-elections_625x300_28_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Supporters and members of the ruling Georgian Dream party attend a gathering at the party's headquarters.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/wiped-off-the-face-of-the-earth-how-russia-erased-a-ukrainian-city-6889218]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Wiped Off The Face Of The Earth": How Russia Erased A Ukrainian City]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/wiped-off-the-face-of-the-earth-how-russia-erased-a-ukrainian-city-6889218]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 28 Oct 2024 07:52:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Vovchansk had a population of about 20,000 before the war. It now lives only in the memories of the survivors who managed to flee.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>"It barely exists anymore," said the mayor of Vovchansk, an industrial town razed by a Russian onslaught shocking even for the killing fields of eastern Ukraine.</p>

<p>Vovchansk has no great history but its geography could not be more tragic. Just five kilometres (three miles) from the Russian border, drone footage from the Ukrainian military this summer shows a lunar landscape of ruins stretching for miles.</p>

<p>And it has got worse since.</p>

<p>"Ninety percent of the centre is flattened," said mayor Tamaz Gambarashvili, a towering man in uniform, who runs what is left of Vovchansk from the regional capital of Kharkiv, an hour and a half's drive away.</p>

<p>"The enemy continues its massive shelling," he added.</p>

<p>Six out of 10 of Vovchansk's buildings have been totally destroyed, with 18 percent partially ruined, according to analysis of satellite images by the independent open-source intelligence collective Bellingcat. But the destruction is much worse in the city centre, which has been levelled north of the Vovcha River.</p>

<p>AFP and Bellingcat joined forces to tell how, building by building, an entire city was wiped off the map in just a few weeks -- and to show the human toll it has taken.</p>

<p>The sheer pace of the destruction dwarfed that of even Bakhmut, the "meatgrinder" Donbas region city where some of the most brutal killing of the war has been done, a Ukrainian officer who fought in both cities told AFP.</p>

<p>"I was in Bakhmut, so I know how the battles unfolded there," Lieutenant Denys Yaroslavsky insisted.</p>

<p>"What took two or three months in Bakhmut happened in just two or three weeks in Vovchansk."</p>

<p><strong>Invaded, then freed</strong></p>

<p>Vovchansk had a population of about 20,000 before the war. It now lives only in the memories of the survivors who managed to flee.</p>

<p>Beyond its factories, the city had a "medical school, a technical college, seven schools and numerous kindergartens," Nelia Stryzhakova, the head of its library, told AFP in Kharkiv.</p>

<p>It even had a workshop that made "carriages for period films. We were even interesting, in our own way," insisted Stryzhakova, 61.</p>

<p>Add to that a regional hospital, rebuilt in 2017 with nearly 10 million euros ($10.8 million) of German aid, a church packed for religious feasts, and a vast hydraulic machinery plant. Once the town's economic lifeblood, its ruins are now being fought over by both armies.</p>

<p>Vovchansk was quickly occupied by the Russian army after it invaded Ukraine in February 2022, but was then retaken by Kyiv in a lightning counter attack that autumn.</p>

<p>Despite enduring regular Russian bombardment, it was relatively calm. Then something very different happened on May 10.</p>

<p><strong>Badly defended</strong></p>

<p>Exhausted after weeks of hard fighting 100 kilometres to the south, the Ukrainian 57th Brigade was regrouping near Vovchansk when one of its reconnaissance units noticed something strange.</p>

<p>"We spotted two Russian armoured troop carriers that had just crossed the border," recalled Lieutenant Yaroslavsky, who was leading the unit.</p>

<p>They were the advance guard of one of the most intense Russian offensives since the beginning of the war, with Moscow throwing several thousand soldiers at the city.</p>

<p>"There were no fortifications, no mines" to slow down their advance, Yaroslavsky said, still furious at the "negligence or corruption" that allowed this to happen.</p>

<p>Some "17,000 people lost their homes. Why? Because someone didn't build fortifications," fumed the 42-year-old officer.</p>

<p>"We control the city today, but what we control is a pile of rubble," he added bitterly.</p>

<p>President Volodymyr Zelensky cancelled an overseas trip to rush to Kharkiv, admitting that the Russian army had pushed between five and 10 kilometres into Ukraine.</p>

<p>The people of Vovchansk, meanwhile, were living a nightmare.</p>

<p><strong>'Drones like mosquitoes'</strong></p>

<p>"The Russians started bombing," said Galyna Zharova, who lived at 16A Stepova Street -- an apartment building now reduced to ruins, as images analysed by Bellingcat and AFP confirmed.</p>

<p>"We were right on the front line. No one could come and get us out," added the 50-year-old, who now lives with her family in a university dormitory in Kharkiv.</p>

<p>"We went down to the cellar. All the buildings were burning. We were crammed into basements (for nearly four weeks) until June 3," her husband Viktor, 65, added.</p>

<p>Eventually, the couple decided to flee on foot. "Drones were flying around us like wasps, like mosquitoes," Galyna remembered. They walked for several kilometres before being rescued by Ukrainian volunteers.</p>

<p>"The city was beautiful. The people were beautiful. We had everything," sighed librarian Stryzhakova. "No one could have imagined that in just five days, we would be wiped off the face of the Earth."</p>

<p>The 125,000 books in the library she had run at 8 Tokhova Street went up in smoke.</p>

<p>More than half of the families in eastern Ukraine have relatives in Russia. In Vovchansk, before the war in the Donbas region began in 2014, people crossed the border daily to shop, with Russians flocking to the city's markets.</p>

<p>"There are many mixed families," said Stryzhakova. "Parents, children, we're all connected. And now we've become enemies. There's no other way to put it."</p>

<p>The Russian defence ministry did not respond to AFP's questions asking for its account of what happened in the city.</p>

<p>Mayor Gambarashvili, who was hit in the leg by shrapnel as he oversaw the city's evacuation, shook his head when asked to estimate the number of civilian casualties.</p>

<p>Dozens, no doubt. Perhaps more. There were still around 4,000 people in Vovchansk on May 10, mostly older people, since most families with children had been evacuated months earlier.</p>

<p><strong>Families divided by war</strong></p>

<p>Kira Dzhafarova, 57, believes her mother, Valentina Radionova, who had lived at 40 Dukhovna Street in a small house with a charming garden, is likely dead.</p>

<p>Their last phone conversation was on May 17. "At 85, I'm not going anywhere," her mother insisted. Satellite images and witnesses have since confirmed that the house was completely destroyed.</p>

<p>"Since then I know it's over," sighed Kira, who provided DNA for identification, if and when the fighting ends.</p>

<p>In a particularly cruel irony, her mother, a Russian national, had moved to Vovchansk so she could be equidistant between her two children, who had fallen out.</p>

<p>Kira has lived in Kharkiv for 35 years and became officially Ukrainian two years ago. Her older brother, who she believes supports Russian President Vladimir Putin, remained in Belgorod, the family's hometown and the first big Russian city on the other side of the border.</p>

<p>Kira, a psychiatrist, now only refers to him as her "former brother".</p>

<p>AFP was unable to contact him directly.</p>

<p>Volodymyr Zymovsky, 70, is also missing. On May 16, he decided to flee the bombardment in a car with his 83-year-old mother, his wife Raisa, and a neighbour. Zymovsky and his mother were both shot dead, "most likely by a Russian sniper", Raisa said.</p>

<p>Amid the hail of bullets, the 59-year-old paediatric nurse had barely got out of the car when she was grabbed by Russian soldiers and held for two days. She managed to escape, hid in a neighbour's cellar for a night, and eventually fled through the forest.</p>

<p>She recounted her harrowing odyssey in a calm, measured voice. One thing alone seems to matter to her now: finding the bodies of her husband and mother-in-law and giving them a proper burial.</p>

<p><strong>'They took my son'</strong></p>

<p>A rumour has circulated among the survivors that the bodies that littered the streets of Vovchansk for days were thrown into a mass grave. Where and by whom, no one knows.</p>

<p>A handful of civilians still remain in Vovchansk. Oleksandre Garlychev, 70, claims to have seen at least three when he returned to his former apartment on a bicycle in mid-September to retrieve belongings.</p>

<p>Garlychev lived at 10A Rubezhanskaya Street, in a southern part of the city that was relatively spared. He only left on August 10.</p>

<p>Vovchansk's survivors -- and even a few of its officials -- quietly wonder whether it will ever be rebuilt given its proximity to the border, regardless of how the war ends.</p>

<p>Asked whether she could ever forgive her husband's killer, Raisa Zymovska fell silent for a long time. Then, in a whisper, she replied: "I don't know, I really don't. As a Christian, yes, but as a human being... What can I say?"</p>

<p>As for the librarian Stryzhakova, she can no longer bring herself to open a Russian book, even the classics, since her only son Pavlo was killed in the Battle of Bakhmut.</p>

<p>"I know that literature is not to blame, but Russia, all of it disgusts me. They took my son, it's personal."</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/d4h8mtj8_vovchansk-ukraine_625x300_28_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Tamaz Gambarashvili, Mayor of Vovchansk shows the emblem of Vovchansk city.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bidzina-ivanishvili-secretive-billionaire-called-georgias-puppet-master-6889122]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bidzina Ivanishvili, Secretive Billionaire Called Georgia's "Puppet Master"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bidzina-ivanishvili-secretive-billionaire-called-georgias-puppet-master-6889122]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 28 Oct 2024 07:29:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[When Georgia's richest man first burst into politics 12 years ago, he vowed to "astonish Europe" with the democracy he would bring to the Black Sea nation.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When Georgia's richest man first burst into politics 12 years ago, he vowed to "astonish Europe" with the democracy he would bring to the Black Sea nation.</p>

<p>But Bidzina Ivanishvili, the billionaire founder of Tbilisi's ruling party, has done what many critics say is the opposite: led the country into international isolation while curbing the power of his political opponents.</p>

<p>This month, the European Parliament called for sanctions against the powerful tycoon, accusing him of "undermining democracy" with the aim of pulling Georgia away from the West towards Russia's orbit.</p>

<p>As the Caucasus nation gears up for crunch parliamentary elections Saturday, all eyes will be on what the reclusive 68-year-old oligarch does if his Georgian Dream party, in power since 2012, wins again.</p>

<p><strong>'Absolute power'</strong></p>

<p>Born into poverty in the village of Chorvila in western Georgia, Ivanishvili made his fortune in Russia during the cutthroat 1990s, amassing huge wealth as state-owned Soviet assets were privatised.</p>

<p>He is now worth $4.9 billion, according to Forbes magazine -- just under a sixth of Georgia's GDP -- and holds dual Georgian and French citizenship.</p>

<p>In 2012, he became Georgia's prime minister after founding his own political party, serving for just over a year before officially retiring from politics.</p>

<p>In 2023, he returned to become Georgian Dream's honorary chairman, assuming the role of a kingmaker who nominates prime ministers from among his loyal lieutenants.</p>

<p>After initially pursuing a liberal pro-Western agenda, his party has over the last two years intensified its anti-Western and anti-liberal positions.</p>

<p>Under his de-facto rule, Georgian Dream has "managed to gradually capture all branches of power and independent institutions in the country," the Georgian branch of the Transparency International rights group said in May.</p>

<p>"The arrangement allows Ivanishvili to have near absolute power without any formal accountability," it added.</p>

<p>He maintains control by placing close associates, such as personal bodyguards, ex-CEOs of his companies, personal assistants and family doctors in charge of state institutions, "with law enforcement and security services being the key", it said.</p>

<p><strong>Modern art, sharks, baobabs</strong></p>

<p>"He thinks of the country as his personal property, as a private corporation," said political analyst Gia Khukhashvili, Ivanishvili's former adviser and one-time close confidant.</p>

<p>The billionaire is "detached from reality" and surrounded by a small circle of "sycophantic favourites", he added.</p>

<p>Giorgi Bachiashvili, the former head of Ivanishvili's Co-Investment Fund who used to be the tycoon's right-hand man, called him a "power-drunk criminal" who "is trading away the future of our country."</p>

<p>Ivanishvili has also faced accusations of having ties with Russia, a charge his party has rejected.</p>

<p>In addition to property and land in Georgia worth hundreds of millions of dollars, Ivanishvili owns luxury real estate in New York and Paris through a complex web of offshore companies and trusts.</p>

<p>His Georgian Co-Investment Fund is registered in Luxembourg and operates 25 projects in Georgia, including shopping malls, cement factories, and luxury hotels.</p>

<p>He is also the founder of a charity fund that has failed to publish financial reports for the last four years and faced accusations of vote-buying.</p>

<p>Now sporting a splash of grey in his neatly coiffed hair, Ivanishvili lives in a lavish glass-and-steel mansion overlooking the capital Tbilisi, where he keeps a priceless collection of contemporary paintings.</p>

<p>Among his possessions is a private zoo with exotic animals, a huge aquarium with sharks and a collection of giant baobab trees transported from Africa by boat in a journey that cost millions of dollars.</p>

<p><strong>'Global war party'</strong></p>

<p>In recent weeks, Ivanishvili has attracted ridicule on social media for appearing at campaign rallies inside a bulletproof glass booth and for canned applause being played at his speeches.</p>

<p>He says his party is seeking to win a supermajority in the new parliament to enable a constitutional ban on pro-Western opposition parties.</p>

<p>His campaign has focused on a conspiracy theory about a mysterious "global war party" that controls Western institutions and seeks to drag Georgia into the Russia-Ukraine war.</p>

<p>Opposition parties, he said, "are trying to seize power by opening a second front (against Russia) in Georgia" with the help of their foreign partners.</p>

<p>"On October 26, we must once again save the country and choose between slavery and freedom, submission to foreign powers and sovereignty, war and peace," he told a campaign rally in the Black Sea city of Batumi.</p>

<p>In spring, Georgian Dream lawmakers passed a Russian-style "foreign influence" law that targeted civil society and sparked weeks of unprecedented street protests, prompting Brussels to halt Tbilisi's European Union integration process.</p>

<p>Recent opinion polls suggest that four leading opposition alliances are poised to garner enough votes to form a coalition government in the upcoming ballot.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/1mcq7q38_bidzina-ivanishvili_625x300_28_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-man-finds-20-on-ground-buys-lottery-ticket-and-wins-1-million-6889090]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Man Finds $20 On Ground, Buys Lottery Ticket And Wins $1 Million]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-man-finds-20-on-ground-buys-lottery-ticket-and-wins-1-million-6889090]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 28 Oct 2024 07:18:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[When Jerry Hicks, a master carpenter from Banner Elk was headed to a convenience store, he found a $20 bill lying on the ground and then he won a lottery.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A $20 bill lying on the ground, outside a convenience store, became the road to a $1 million lottery for a North Carolina man. On October 22, when Jerry Hicks, a master carpenter from Banner Elk was headed to a convenience store, he found a $20 bill lying on the ground.</p>

<p>“I found $20 in the parking lot outside the Speedway,” Hicks recalled, as per the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nclottery.com/News/2024/10/25/Avery-County-man-finds-20-on-ground-and-uses-it-to-win-1-million-" rel="nofollow,noindex">press release</a>. “I used that to buy the ticket.”</p>

<p>He picked it up, walked into the Speedway on N.C. 105 in Boone, and bought an Extreme Cash scratch-off.</p>

<p>“They actually didn't have the ticket I was looking for so I bought that one instead,” he laughed.</p>

<p>He hit the jackpot with a $1 million lottery.</p>

<p>The winner had two options to claim his prize money - receive the prize as an annuity of $50,000 over 20 years or a lump sum of $600,000. He chose the latter and took $429,007 after required state and federal tax withholdings.</p>

<p>Hicks has plans for the family. He wants to use the winning amount to help out his children and retire after working as a carpenter for 56 years.</p>

<p>When asked, what is the first thing he would do to celebrate the big win, he said, “We are going to head straight to Golden Corral and eat everything they've got.”</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/a7qj1b2o_us-nc-education-lottery_625x300_28_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Jerry Hicks is a master carpenter from Banner Elk]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-supreme-leaders-hebrew-x-account-suspended-last-post-was-6889056]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iran Supreme Leader's Hebrew X Account Suspended, Last Post Was...]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-supreme-leaders-hebrew-x-account-suspended-last-post-was-6889056]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 28 Oct 2024 07:06:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Hebrew language account opened by Iran's leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei on social media platform X has been suspended after just two posts, as per Jerusalem Post.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Hebrew language account opened by Iran's leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei on social media platform X has been suspended after just two posts, as per Jerusalem Post.</p>

<p>The latest post from Sunday read, "The Zionist regime made a mistake, and erred in its calculation regarding Iran. We will make it understand what power, ability, initiative and desire the Iranian nation has."</p>

<p>The first Hebrew language post came on Saturday, reading, "In the name of Allah the merciful." Both posts came after Israel's strikes on Iran's military targets last week.</p>

<p>On his main X account, Khamenei often posts in Hebrew,&nbsp;often using strong language against Israel.</p>

<p>Khamenei had said that Israel's airstrikes on Iran should not be magnified nor downplayed. While Israel would like to amplify the impacts of its actions against Iran, Khamenei said on Sunday, adding it would also not be right for Iran to dismiss the strikes as insignificant, CNN reported.</p>

<p>"They're making a miscalculation concerning Iran," he said in comments published on his website. "They still haven't been able to correctly understand the power, capability, ingenuity, and determination of the Iranian people. We need to make them understand these things."</p>

<p>Iran said Israeli air strikes targeting its military sites killed two soldiers on Saturday, after Israel simultaneously struck missile manufacturing facilities, surface-to-air missile arrays and other "aerial capabilities".</p>

<p>It said later that the air attack had "concluded" its response to Iran's October 1 missile attack, saying its warplanes had returned safely and the mission was "fulfilled".&nbsp;Iran's air force confirmed strikes on military bases in Tehran, Khuzestan and Ilam provinces that "caused limited damage".</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-11/b3d2u2tg_ayatollah-ali-khamenei_625x300_01_November_23.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/man-dials-911-claiming-a-bear-is-chasing-him-hes-now-a-key-murder-suspect-6889023]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Man Dials 911 Claiming A Bear Is Chasing Him. He's Now A Murder Suspect]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/man-dials-911-claiming-a-bear-is-chasing-him-hes-now-a-key-murder-suspect-6889023]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 28 Oct 2024 06:59:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The man called 911 and said that he had fallen off of a cliff while running from a bear and that he was injured and partially in the water, leading first responders to a dead body.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A man in the US is wanted for murder after he called the emergency number 911, claiming he had been chased by a bear, and leading first responders to a dead body.</p>

<p>According to a news release from the Monroe County Tennessee Sheriff's Office, 911 received a call about a "distressed hiker" on October 18 who claimed to be Brandon Andrade. He told the dispatcher that he had fallen off of a cliff while running from a bear and that he was injured and partially in the water.&nbsp;</p>

<p>When officials conducted a search in Tellico Plains, the area where they received the call from, a body of a man was recovered with an identification of Brandon Kristopher Andrade.&nbsp;</p>

<p>After investigation, the officials found that Brandon Andrade was not the victim and that the identification had been "stolen and used" on multiple occasions.</p>

<p>"A male that was using the stolen identification of Mr Andrade, was discovered to be a Nicholas Wayne Hamlett, who was wanted out of the State of Alabama on a parole violation," the press release said.</p>

<p><iframe allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="true" frameborder="0" height="250" scrolling="no" src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/post.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2Fphoto.php%3Ffbid%3D1044339974374056%26set%3Da.284744377000290%26type%3D3&amp;show_text=true&amp;width=500" style="border:none;overflow:hidden" width="500"></iframe></p>

<p>Hamlett had used a false name when speaking with law enforcement after the distressed hiker call.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Before his real identity had been verified, he is believed to have fled from his Tennessee residence, the Sheriff's Office said.</p>

<p>The victim has so far not been identified, and an arrest warrant has been issued for Hamlett, who is considered "armed and dangerous", for First Degree Murder.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/86npog38_nicholas-wayne-hamlett_625x300_28_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The man has been identified as Nicholas Wayne Hamlett]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korea-blames-souths-military-for-drone-intrusion-6888603]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[North Korea Blames South's Military For Drone Intrusion]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korea-blames-souths-military-for-drone-intrusion-6888603]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 28 Oct 2024 04:38:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[North Korea's defence ministry blamed South Korea's military for sending drones into its territory for political purposes, calling it an infringement upon the country's sovereignty]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>North Korea's defence ministry blamed South Korea's military for sending drones into its territory for political purposes, calling it an infringement upon the country's sovereignty, state media KCNA said on Monday.</p>

<p>The ministry announced final results of its investigation after claiming that South Korean drones flew over Pyongyang at least three times this month to distribute anti-North leaflets. KCNA has also published photos of what it described as a crashed South Korean military drone.</p>

<p>During an analysis of the drone's flight control programme, North Korean authorities said they uncovered more than 230 flight plans and flight logs since June 2023, including a plan to scatter "political motivational rubbish."</p>

<p>An Oct. 8 record showed that the drone had departed the South's border island of Baengnyeongdo late at night and released leaflets over the foreign and defence ministry buildings in Pyongyang a few hours later.</p>

<p>Seoul's defence ministry did not immediately have comment but has said Pyongyang's unilateral claims were "not worth verifying or a response."</p>

<p>A North Korean spokesperson warned that the country would respond with "merciless offensive" if such a case recurs, KCNA said.</p>

<p>Tensions between the Koreas have rekindled since the North began flying balloons carrying trash into the South in late May, prompting the South to restart loudspeaker propaganda broadcasts.</p>

<p>Seoul and Washington have said North Korea has sent 3,000 troops to Russia for possible deployment in Ukraine, which could mean a significant escalation in their conflict. Pyongyang said on Friday that any move to send its troops to support Russia would be in line with international law.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/fst13ff8_north-korea-_625x300_16_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[North Korean authorities said they uncovered more than 230 flight plans and flight logs since June 2023.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/egypt-proposes-2-day-truce-in-gaza-with-limited-hostage-prisoner-exchange-6887823]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Egypt Proposes 2-Day Truce In Gaza With Limited Hostage-Prisoner Exchange]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/egypt-proposes-2-day-truce-in-gaza-with-limited-hostage-prisoner-exchange-6887823]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:05:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Egypt has proposed an initial two-day ceasefire in Gaza to exchange four Israeli hostages of Hamas for some Palestinian prisoners, Egypt's president said on Sunday as Israeli military strikes killed 45 Palestinians across the enclave.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Egypt has proposed an initial two-day ceasefire in Gaza to exchange four Israeli hostages of Hamas for some Palestinian prisoners, Egypt's president said on Sunday as Israeli military strikes killed 45 Palestinians across the enclave.</p>

<p>Egyptian leader Abdel Fattah al-Sisi made the announcement as efforts to defuse the devastating, more than year-long war resumed in Qatar with the directors of the CIA and Israel's Mossad intelligence agency taking part.</p>

<p>Speaking alongside Algerian President Abdelmadjid Tebboune during a press conference in Cairo, Sisi also said that talks should resume within 10 days of implementing the temporary ceasefire in efforts to reach a permanent one.</p>

<p>There was no immediate comment from Israel or Hamas but a Palestinian official close to the mediation effort told Reuters: "I expect Hamas would listen to the new offers, but it remains determined that any agreement must end the war and get Israeli forces out of Gaza."</p>

<p>Israel has said the war cannot end until Hamas has been wiped out as a military force and governing entity in Gaza.</p>

<p>The US, Qatar and Egypt have been spearheading negotiations to end the war that erupted after Hamas fighters entered southern Israel on October 7 last year, killing 1,200 people and taking more than 250 hostages, by Israeli tallies.</p>

<p>The death count from Israel's retaliatory air and ground onslaught in Gaza is approaching 43,000, Gaza health officials say, with the densely populated enclave in ruins.</p>

<p>An official briefed on the talks told Reuters earlier on Sunday that negotiations in Doha will seek a short-term ceasefire and the release of some hostages being held by Hamas in exchange for Israel's release of Palestinian prisoners.</p>

<p>The objective, still elusive after multiple mediation attempts, is to get Israel and Hamas to agree to a halt in fighting for less than a month in the hope this would lead to a more permanent ceasefire.</p>

<p>At least 43 of those killed in Gaza on Sunday were in the north of the enclave, where Israeli troops have returned to root out Hamas fighters who it says have regrouped there.</p>

<p><strong>'UNBEARABLE' CONDITIONS IN NORTH GAZA</strong></p>

<p>The United Nations said the plight of Palestinian civilians in northern Gaza was "unbearable" and the conflict was being "waged with little regard for the requirements of international humanitarian law".</p>

<p>"The Secretary-General (Antonio Guterres) is shocked by the harrowing levels of death, injury and destruction in the north, with civilians trapped under rubble, the sick and wounded going without life-saving health care, and families lacking food and shelter, amid reports of families being separated and many people detained," U.N. spokesperson Stephane Dujarric said in a statement.</p>

<p>Israeli authorities were hampering efforts to deliver food, medicine and other essential humanitarian supplies, putting lives at risk, he said. The devastation and deprivation resulting from Israeli military operations in the north were making life there untenable.</p>

<p>Israel says its forces operate in accordance with international law. It says it targets Hamas operatives who conceal themselves among the civilian population which they use as human shields, a charge Hamas denies.</p>

<p>It denies blocking humanitarian aid to Gaza, blaming international organisations for problems distributing it and accusing Hamas of stealing from aid convoys.</p>

<p><strong>JABALIA IN FOCUS</strong></p>

<p>Earlier on Sunday, 20 people were killed following an airstrike on houses in Jabalia, the largest of the Gaza Strip's eight historic refugee camps, which has been the focus of an Israeli military offensive for more than three weeks, medics and the Palestinian official news agency WAFA said.</p>

<p>Another Israeli airstrike on a school sheltering displaced Palestinian families in Shati camp in Gaza City, killed nine people and wounded 20 others, with many in critical condition, medics said.</p>

<p>Footage circulated on Palestinian media, which Reuters could not immediately verify, showed people rushing to the bomb site to help evacuate the casualties. Bodies were scattered on the ground, while some carried wounded children in their arms before loading them in a vehicle.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said it was looking into the report on the strike on the school.</p>

<p>Three local journalists were among those killed at the school in Shati - Saed Radwan, head of digital media at Hamas Al-Aqsa television, Hanin Baroud, and Hamza Abu Selmeya, according to Hamas media.</p>

<p>On Sunday, Israel's military said it had killed more than 40 militants in the Jabalia area in the past 24 hours, as well as dismantling infrastructure and locating large quantities of military equipment.</p>

<p>Israeli military strikes on the towns of Jabalia, Beit Hanoun and Beit Lahiya in northern Gaza have so far killed around 800 people during a three-week offensive, the Gaza health ministry said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/1qvfgfig_gaza-reuters_625x300_28_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[There was no immediate comment from Israel or Hamas (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-army-says-5-soldiers-killed-in-combat-in-south-lebanon-6886902]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Army Says 5 Soldiers Killed In "Combat" In South Lebanon]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-army-says-5-soldiers-killed-in-combat-in-south-lebanon-6886902]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 27 Oct 2024 21:01:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Israeli military on Sunday said five soldiers were killed in southern Lebanon, bringing to 37 the death toll for soldiers fighting there since the start of ground operations on September 30.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Israeli military on Sunday said five soldiers were killed in southern Lebanon, bringing to 37 the death count for soldiers fighting there since the start of ground operations on September 30.</p>

<p>The soldiers "fell during combat in southern Lebanon," the army said in a statement, adding that they were killed on Saturday.</p>

<p>Hezbollah began launching rockets at Israel on October 8, 2023, in support of Hamas after the Palestinian group launched its unprecedented attack on Israel the previous day.</p>

<p>Israel dramatically escalated its air strikes on Lebanon late last month before launching ground operations in southern Lebanon.</p>

<p>The war has left at least 1,615 people dead in Lebanon since September 23, according to an AFP tally based on official figures, though the real number is likely to be higher due to gaps in the data.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/psho2ggg_lebanon-afp_625x300_27_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel dramatically escalated its air strikes on Lebanon late last month (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/king-charles-to-continue-foreign-tours-after-being-diagnosed-with-cancer-6886851]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[King Charles To Continue Foreign Tours After Being Diagnosed With Cancer]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/king-charles-to-continue-foreign-tours-after-being-diagnosed-with-cancer-6886851]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 27 Oct 2024 20:55:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[King Charles III's cancer diagnosis will not prevent him flying abroad next year for foreign visits, a Buckingham Palace official said, as the monarch wrapped up a tour of Australia and Samoa.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>King Charles III's cancer diagnosis will not prevent him flying abroad next year for foreign visits, a Buckingham Palace official said, as the monarch wrapped up a tour of Australia and Samoa.</p>

<p>"We're now working on a pretty normal looking full overseas tour programme for next year, which is a high for us to end on, to know that we can be thinking in those terms," the official said late Saturday.</p>

<p>King Charles was diagnosed with an undisclosed cancer earlier this year but doctors agreed he could pause his treatment to allow him to travel to Australia and Samoa.</p>

<p>The palace announced in April that he would make a limited return to public duties, as doctors were "very encouraged" by his progress.</p>

<p>The official added that the king had "thrived" on the tour's programme which had lifted "his spirits, his mood and his recovery".</p>

<p>"In that sense, the tour, despite its demands, has been the perfect tonic," he added.</p>

<p>The tour was King Charles' first to Australia, where he is also head of state, since he became king following the death of Queen Elizabeth II in September 2022.</p>

<p>King Charles and Queen Camilla left Samoa Saturday after the marathon 11-day tour that saw the king carry out more than 30 engagements.</p>

<p>The royal couple visited Sydney, Canberra and the Samoan capital Apia, where King Charles attended a meeting of Commonwealth nations.</p>

<p>The 56-nation bloc -- made up mostly of British ex-colonies -- had hoped to focus on a future threatened by climate change, but instead bickered over a troubled past marked by slavery and colonisation.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/svej0b98_king-charles_625x300_27_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[King Charles was diagnosed with an undisclosed cancer earlier this year (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-man-sues-alaska-airlines-after-his-dog-dies-during-flight-6886850]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Man Sues Alaska Airlines After His Dog Dies During Flight]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-man-sues-alaska-airlines-after-his-dog-dies-during-flight-6886850]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 27 Oct 2024 20:55:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The sudden relocation caused significant distress to Ash, who began exhibiting signs of respiratory distress, including heavy panting and gasping for air.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A lawsuit filed against Alaska Airlines alleges negligence in the death of a French bulldog during a flight from New York to San Francisco. Michael Contillo, a San Francisco resident, claims that his beloved pet, Ash, died due to the airline's mishandling, the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.independent.co.uk/travel/news-and-advice/alaska-airlines-dog-dies-flight-first-class-coach-b2634145.html" rel="nofollow, noindex"><em>Independent</em></a> reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Mr Contillo and his father had purchased first-class tickets to ensure ample space and comfort for their two French bulldogs, Ash and Kora. Before the flight, both dogs were examined by a veterinarian and declared fit to fly. However, Alaska Airlines staff insisted on moving the passengers and their pets further back in the plane, citing safety concerns.</p>

<p>The sudden relocation caused significant distress to Ash, who began exhibiting signs of respiratory distress, including heavy panting and gasping for air. Mr Contillo was unable to monitor his pet during takeoff and landing due to airline regulations. Upon arriving at San Francisco International Airport, Mr Contillo discovered that Ash had died.</p>

<p><strong>The lawsuit highlights several key allegations against Alaska Airlines:</strong></p>

<ul>
	<li>Negligence in Handling Brachycephalic Breeds: The airline allegedly failed to consider the specific needs of brachycephalic breeds like French bulldogs, which are particularly vulnerable to respiratory problems during air travel.</li>
	<li>Breach of Contract: The lawsuit claims that Alaska Airlines breached the contract by downgrading the passengers from first class without a valid reason.</li>
	<li>Inadequate Staff Training: Mr Contillo alleges that the airline's staff lacked proper training in handling animals, especially those with specific health concerns.</li>
</ul>

<p>In addition to seeking financial compensation, Mr Contillo is also seeking punitive damages to hold Alaska Airlines accountable for its negligence. The lawsuit emphasizes the emotional distress caused by the loss of his pet and the airline's lack of empathy following the incident.</p>

<p>The American Veterinary Medical Association has warned that brachycephalic breeds are at a higher risk of respiratory issues during air travel. The organization recommends that these breeds should be kept in the passenger cabin and not transported as cargo or in confined areas.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-01/l5q13kco_alaska-airlines-boeing-737-max-9-afp_625x300_25_January_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The lawsuit highlights several key allegations against Alaska Airlines]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>