<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Sun, 22 Sep 2024 12:45:02 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-shuts-schools-caps-gatherings-as-hezbollah-launches-rockets-at-military-targets-6622397]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Caps Gatherings As Hezbollah Launches Rockets At Military Facilities]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-shuts-schools-caps-gatherings-as-hezbollah-launches-rockets-at-military-targets-6622397]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 22 Sep 2024 12:26:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel closed schools and restricted gatherings in many northern areas of the country and the Israeli-occupied Golan Heights early on Sunday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel and Lebanon exchanged heavy fire into Sunday, with Israeli warplanes carrying out the most intense bombardment in almost a year of war across Lebanon's south, while Hezbollah claimed rocket attacks on military targets in Israel's north. The Israeli military said it struck around 290 targets on Saturday including thousands of Hezbollah rocket launcher barrels and said it would continue to strike targets of the Iran-backed movement.</p>

<p>Israel closed schools and restricted gatherings in many northern areas of the country and the Israeli-occupied Golan Heights early on Sunday.</p>

<p>Sirens sounded all night as multiple rockets and missiles were fired from Lebanon and Iraq, most of which were intercepted by Israeli aerial defence systems, the military said.</p>

<p>Israeli media reported that a number of buildings were hit directly or by falling missile debris, and ambulance services said they treated some lightly injured people. No serious casualties were reported.</p>

<p>Hezbollah said it targeted the Israeli Ramat David Airbase with dozens of missiles in response to "repeated Israeli attacks on Lebanon", the group posted on its Telegram channel early on Sunday.</p>

<p>The successive barrages of rocket attacks launched by Hezbollah at Ramat David are the deepest strikes it has claimed since hostilities began.</p>

<p>Iran-backed Iraqi militants in a statement also claimed an explosive drone attack on Israel early on Sunday.</p>

<h3><strong>ESCALATING ATTACKS</strong></h3>

<p>The escalating attacks come less than 48 hours after an Israeli airstrike targeting Hezbollah commanders killed at least 37 people in a suburb of the Lebanese capital, according to authorities.</p>

<p>Hezbollah, a powerful Iran-backed group, said 16 members including senior leader Ibrahim Aqil and another commander, Ahmed Wahbi, were among those killed on Friday in the deadliest strike in nearly a year of conflict with Israel.</p>

<p>Israel's army said it hit an underground gathering of Aqil and leaders of Hezbollah's elite Radwan forces, and had almost completely dismantled its military chain of command.</p>

<p>The attack levelled a multi-story residential building in the crowded suburb and damaged a nursery next door, a security source said. Three children and seven women were among those killed, according to Lebanon's health ministry.</p>

<p>Friday's strike sharply escalated the conflict and inflicted another blow on Hezbollah after two days of attacks in which pagers and walkie-talkies used by its members exploded.</p>

<p>The death count in those attacks, widely believed to have been carried out by Israel, has risen to 39 with more than 3,000 injured. Israel has neither confirmed nor denied involvement.</p>

<p>In what it said was the initial retaliation for the attacks with the exploding devices, Hezbollah on Sunday posted on its Telegram channel that it had launched rockets at Israeli military-industry facilities.</p>

<p>Israel quickly responded, striking Hezbollah targets in Lebanon, the military said in a statement.</p>

<p>U.S. national security adviser Jake Sullivan said he was worried about escalation but that the Israeli killing of a top Hezbollah leader brought justice to the group, which Washington designates a terrorist organization.</p>

<p>"While the risk of escalation is real, we actually believe there is also a distinct avenue to getting to a cessation of hostilities and a durable solution that makes people on both sides of the border feel secure," Sullivan told reporters.</p>

<p>Lebanese Prime Minister Najib Mikati cancelled a planned trip to the U.N. General Assembly in New York.</p>

<h3><strong>ISRAEL BRACES FOR RETALIATION</strong></h3>

<p>Hezbollah has said it would keep fighting Israel until it agrees to a ceasefire in its war against Hamas in the Palestinian enclave of Gaza - triggered by a Hamas-led rampage in southern Israel on Oct. 7.</p>

<p>U.S. officials say that is unlikely anytime soon. Israel wants Hezbollah to cease fire and withdraw forces from the border region, adhering to a U.N. resolution signed with Israel in 2006, irrespective of any Gaza deal.</p>

<p>Anticipating retaliation, the Israeli military restricted gatherings and raised the alert level for residents of northern communities. The alert went as far south as the coastal city of Haifa, signalling Israel thought Hezbollah could strike deeper than it had since the war with Hamas began.</p>

<p>In southern Lebanon on Saturday, people described huge explosions that lit up the night sky and shook the ground as Israel carried out its latest strikes.</p>

<p>Israeli Defence Minister Yoav Gallant, who said last week Israel was launching a new phase of war on the northern border, posted on X: "The sequence of actions in the new phase will continue until our goal is achieved: the safe return of the residents of the north to their homes."</p>

<p>Tens of thousands of people have left their homes on both sides of the Israel-Lebanon border since Hezbollah began firing rockets at Israel in October in sympathy with Palestinians in Gaza.</p>

<p>A communique from a U.S. summit hosted by President Joe Biden with the leaders of Japan, India and Australia stressed the need to prevent the Gaza war "from escalating and spilling over in the region" but did not specifically mention the Israel-Hezbollah conflict.</p>

<p>With at least 70 people killed in Lebanon over the past week, the conflict toll in the country since October has surpassed 740 during the worst Israel-Hezbollah flare-up since a 2006 war.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/h7okrmro_israel-hezbollah_625x300_22_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israeli media reported that a number of buildings were hit directly]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-refuses-kamala-harris-call-for-another-presidential-debate-on-cnn-too-late-voting-already-started-6622140]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Too Late": Donald Trump Refuses Kamala Harris' Call For Another Debate]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-refuses-kamala-harris-call-for-another-presidential-debate-on-cnn-too-late-voting-already-started-6622140]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 22 Sep 2024 11:38:00 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kamala Harris's campaign said she had accepted an invitation from broadcaster CNN to participate in a debate on October 23.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump on Saturday rejected a second debate against Kamala Harris before the November 5 election, saying it was "too late" with early voting already underway in some states. Earlier on Saturday, Harris's campaign said she had accepted an invitation from broadcaster CNN to participate in a debate on October 23. It would have been the candidates' second debate, after a September 10 encounter that most pundits said she had won.</p>

<p>"The American people deserve another opportunity to see Vice President Kamala Harris and Donald Trump debate before they cast their ballots," her campaign chair Jen O'Malley Dillon said in a statement.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"I hope (Trump) will join me," Harris posted on X.</p>

<p>Trump claimed during a campaign rally in the battleground state of North Carolina that he would like to debate -- calling it "good entertainment value" -- but the start of early voting in some states had taken the air out of the idea.</p>

<p>"It's just too late, voting has already started," he said.</p>

<p>He added, to a large and enthusiastic crowd of supporters, that while CNN had been "very fair" when he debated President Joe Biden in June, "they won't be fair again."&nbsp;</p>

<p>Vice President Harris replaced her boss at the top of the Democratic ticket after the 81-year-old Biden's disastrous performance against Trump.</p>

<p>His exit from the race left Trump, 78, now the oldest-ever presidential nominee, against a much younger Harris, 59.</p>

<h3><strong>Voting underway</strong></h3>

<p>Saturday's announcement came as some states have already begun early voting in what is an agonizingly close race.</p>

<p>The result is expected to hinge on seven battleground states, including North Carolina.</p>

<p>Trump addressed the crowd in the port city of Wilmington from behind bulletproof glass, following an apparent second assassination attempt against him.</p>

<p>A gunman was discovered on his golf course in Florida last Sunday, with security agents foiling any plan to harm the former president.</p>

<p>In July, Trump was struck on the ear by a bullet at a rally in Butler, Pennsylvania, after a gunman opened fire from a nearby rooftop. The US Secret Service -- tasked with protecting the candidate -- on Friday admitted to "deficiencies" and "complacency" in the shocking security breach.</p>

<h3><strong>Anti-immigrant rhetoric</strong></h3>

<p>Trump won North Carolina in the 2020 election against Biden.&nbsp;</p>

<p>But Harris is aiming to flip the southeastern state for Democrats, on the strength of her support from African Americans and young voters.</p>

<p>Trump's speech on Saturday reinforced the hardline anti-immigrant rhetoric that has become a centerpiece of his campaign, falsely claiming migrants were "attacking villages and cities all throughout the Midwest."</p>

<p>He also promised the crowd that the United States would "reach Mars before the end of my term."</p>

<p>The former president was facing a new challenge in North Carolina after a bombshell report on Thursday revealed that Mark Robinson, the Republican candidate for governor whom Trump has endorsed, had called himself a "Black Nazi" and made other incendiary comments on a porn website message board more than a decade ago.</p>

<p>Robinson has denounced the CNN report as "salacious tabloid lies."</p>

<p>The presidential race remains neck-and-neck and every vote will count in the election, whose result Trump has once again refused to say he will accept if he loses.</p>

<p>Trump faces criminal charges for allegedly trying to overturn the 2020 result, after which his supporters violently stormed the US Capitol on January 6, 2021.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/b64vd7go_donald-trump-kamala-harris_625x300_22_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-narendra-modi-gifts-joe-biden-a-silver-hand-engraved-train-model-jill-biden-a-pashmina-shawl-6621947]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[PM Modi's Silver Train Model, Pashmina Shawl Gifts To Joe And Jill Biden]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-narendra-modi-gifts-joe-biden-a-silver-hand-engraved-train-model-jill-biden-a-pashmina-shawl-6621947]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 22 Sep 2024 10:58:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Narendra Modi today gifted an antique silver hand-engraved train model to US President Joe Biden.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi today gifted an antique silver hand-engraved train model to US President Joe Biden. The Prime Minister, who is in the US for a three-day trip, met Mr Biden in his hometown Wilmington, Delaware, ahead of the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/quad-summit-2024-pm-narendra-modi-joe-biden-cancer-moonshot-to-sea-observer-mission-key-takeaways-from-wilmington-summit-6621531" target="_blank">Quad Leaders' Summit</a>.</p>

<p>The train model was customised by inscribing "DELHI-DELAWARE" on the sides of the main carriage and "INDIAN RAILWAYS" on the sides of the engine in English and Hindi based on the standard format used on passenger trains in India.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/vfp8gag8_modi-biden-gifts_625x300_22_September_24.jpeg?im=FitAndFill,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/sfumm58o_modi-biden-gifts_625x300_22_September_24.jpeg?im=FitAndFill,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Crafted by artisans from Maharashtra, which is renowned for its rich heritage in silver craftsmanship, the model is made of 92.5% silver, officials said.</p>

<p>PM Modi also gifted a Kashmiri pashmina shawl to First Lady Jill Biden.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/p8b0uqco_modi-biden-gifts_625x300_22_September_24.jpeg?im=FitAndFill,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Earlier in the day, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-narendra-modi-joe-biden-quad-security-council-to-space-tech-key-takeaways-of-modi-biden-meet-in-us-6621683#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">PM Modi said he held an "extremely fruitful" meeting with Mr Biden</a> during which the two leaders discussed ways to further enhance bilateral cooperation in areas of mutual interest and exchanged views on global and regional issues including the Indo-Pacific region and beyond.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/talks-were-extreme-fruitful-pm-modi-meets-president-biden-in-us-6620160" target="_blank">PM Modi was welcomed by Mr Biden</a> at his residence in Greenville, Delaware, where the two leaders hugged each other. The US President held PM Modi's hand as he led him into the house where the bilateral talks took place.</p>

<p>"I thank President Biden for hosting me at his residence in Greenville, Delaware. Our talks were extremely fruitful. We had the opportunity to discuss regional and global issues during the meeting," PM Modi posted on X after the meeting which lasted more than an hour.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">I thank President Biden for hosting me at his residence in Greenville, Delaware. Our talks were extremely fruitful. We had the opportunity to discuss regional and global issues during the meeting. <a href="https://twitter.com/JoeBiden?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@JoeBiden</a> <a href="https://t.co/WzWW3fudTn">pic.twitter.com/WzWW3fudTn</a></p>
— Narendra Modi (@narendramodi) <a href="https://twitter.com/narendramodi/status/1837580216492798096?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 21, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Mr Biden also took to X and said the United States' partnership with India is "stronger, closer, and more dynamic than any time in history".</p>

<p>"Prime Minister Modi, each time we sit down, I'm struck by our ability to find new areas of cooperation. Today was no different," he wrote.</p>

<p>A joint statement issued after the bilateral meeting said the India-US partnership is "decisively delivering on an ambitious agenda that serves the global good", calling it the "defining partnership of the 21st century".</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/3dd2k9ag_modi-gifts_625x300_22_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The train model was customised by inscribing "DELHI-DELAWARE" on the sides of the main carriage]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-narendra-modi-joe-biden-quad-security-council-to-space-tech-key-takeaways-of-modi-biden-meet-in-us-6621683]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Security Council To Space Tech: Key Takeaways From Modi-Biden Meet In US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-narendra-modi-joe-biden-quad-security-council-to-space-tech-key-takeaways-of-modi-biden-meet-in-us-6621683]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 22 Sep 2024 09:55:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden commended Prime Minister Narendra Modi for his historic visit to Ukraine and his message of peace amid the war with Russia. The US also backed permanent membership for India in the UN Security Council.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden commended Prime Minister Narendra Modi for his historic visit to Ukraine and his message of peace amid the war with Russia. The US also backed permanent membership for India in the UN Security Council.</p>

<p><strong>Here Are Some Of The Key Takeaways From The Bilateral Meet</strong></p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/each-time-we-sit-down-biden-posts-pics-of-meeting-pm-modi-6619870">READ: "Each Time We Sit Down...": Biden Posts Pics Of Meeting PM Modi</a></p>

<p><strong>Boost For India-US Ties</strong></p>

<p>The Prime Minister met the US president at his home in Wilmington, North Carolina. At the meeting, the Prime Minister conveyed his appreciation for President Biden's unparalleled contributions in giving impetus to the India-US partnership, the Ministry of External Affairs said. Recalling his earlier visit to the US last year and President Biden's India trip for the G20 summit, the Prime Minister noted that visits have led to greater dynamism and depth in the India-US partnership.</p>

<p>The Prime Minister emphasised that India and the US now enjoy a comprehensive global strategic partnership that covers all areas of human endeavour, driven by shared democratic values, convergence of interests and vibrant people-to-people ties, the MEA said. It added that the two leaders discussed ways to enhance bilateral cooperation in areas of mutual interest and exchanged views on global and regional issues, including the Indo-Pacific region and beyond.</p>

<p><strong>India's Global Role</strong></p>

<p>President Biden expressed appreciation for India's leadership on the world stage, particularly Prime Minister Modi's leadership in the G20 and the Global South, a White House statement said. The US President also praised the Prime Minister's commitment to strengthen the Quad to ensure a free, open, and prosperous Indo-Pacific.</p>

<p>"India is at the forefront of efforts to seek solutions to the most pressing challenges, from supporting the global response to the COVID-19 pandemic to addressing the devastating consequences of conflicts around the world," the White House said.</p>

<p>President Biden, it said, commended Prime Minister Modi for his historic visits to Poland and Ukraine, the first by an Indian Prime Minister in decades, and his message of peace and ongoing humanitarian support for Ukraine. The statement was silent on the Prime Minister's visit to Russia.</p>

<p>President Biden told Prime Minister Modi that the US supports initiatives to reform global institutions to "reflect India's important voice". The US also backed permanent membership for India in a reformed UN Security Council.</p>

<p><strong>Space To Semiconductors</strong></p>

<p>The White House has said that the two leaders cheered the success of the Initiative on Critical and Emerging Technology (iCET) in deepening and expanding strategic cooperation across key technology sectors, including space, semiconductors, and advanced telecommunications.</p>

<p>"Both Leaders committed to enhance regular engagements to improve the momentum of collaboration in fields such as artificial intelligence, quantum, biotechnology, and clean energy. They highlighted ongoing efforts to strengthen collaboration with like-minded partners, including through the Quad and a U.S.-India-ROK Trilateral Technology initiative launched earlier this year to build more secure and resilient supply chains for critical industries and ensure we collectively remain at the leading edge of innovation," the statement said. The leaders, it said, also endorsed new mechanisms for deeper cyberspace cooperation through the bilateral cybersecurity dialogue.</p>

<p>"President Biden and Prime Minister Modi hailed a watershed arrangement to establish a new semiconductor fabrication plant focused on advanced sensing, communication, and power electronics for national security, next generation telecommunications, and green energy applications," the White House said, adding that the two leaders praised combined efforts to facilitate resilient, secure, and sustainable semiconductor supply chains.</p>

<p>In the space technology sector, the two leaders welcomed the progress towards the first joint effort by NASA and ISRO to conduct scientific research onboard the International Space Station in 2025.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-modi-us-visit-as-pm-narendra-modi-and-joe-biden-hold-bilateral-talks-a-mega-drone-deal-firms-up-6620448">READ:&nbsp;As PM Modi And Joe Biden Hold Bilateral Talks, A Mega Drone Deal Firms Up</a></p>

<p><strong>Impetus To Defence Ties</strong></p>

<p>The US president welcomed the progress in India completing the procurement of 31 General Atomics MQ-9B (16 Sky Guardian and 15 Sea Guardian) remotely piloted aircraft and their associated equipment, the White House said, adding that these will enhance the intelligence, surveillance and reconnaissance capabilities of India's armed forces.</p>

<p>The two leaders recognised the progress under the US-India Defense Industrial Cooperation Roadmap, including ongoing collaboration to advance priority co-production arrangements for jet engines, munitions, and ground mobility systems. Prime Minister Modi and President Biden also welcomed efforts to expand defence industrial partnerships.</p>

<p>"President Biden welcomed India's decision to set a uniform Goods and Services Tax (GST) of 5 per cent on the maintenance, repair, and overhaul (MRO) sector, including on all aircraft and aircraft engine parts thereby simplifying the tax structure and paving the way for building a strong ecosystem for MRO services in India. The Leaders also encouraged the industry to foster collaboration and drive innovation to support India's efforts to become a leading aviation hub," the White House said.</p>

<p>"The Leaders hailed the teaming agreement on the C-130J Super Hercules aircraft recently signed between Lockheed Martin and Tata Advanced Systems Limited, the two companies that co-chair the U.S.-India CEO Forum. Building on longstanding industry cooperation, this agreement will establish a new Maintenance, Repair and Overhaul (MRO) facility in India to support the readiness of the Indian fleet and global partners who operate the C-130 Super Hercules aircraft," it said, adding that this marks a significant step in US-India cooperation in the defence and aerospace sector.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-us-to-elevate-bilateral-ties-to-expand-clean-energy-supply-chains-6621420">READ: India, US To Elevate Bilateral Ties To Expand Clean Energy Supply Chains</a></p>

<p><strong>Clean Energy</strong></p>

<p>Prime Minister Modi and President Biden welcomed the joint efforts to accelerate the expansion of safe and secure clean energy supply chains through US and Indian manufacturing of clean energy technologies and components. "In its initial phase, the U.S. and India would work together to unlock $1 billion of multilateral financing to support projects across the clean energy value chain for renewable energy, energy storage, power grid and transmission technologies, high efficiency cooling systems, zero emission vehicles, and other emerging clean technologies," the White House said.</p>

<p>"The Leaders also highlighted the U.S. International Development Finance Corporation (DFC)'s partnership with India's private sector to expand clean energy manufacturing and diversify supply chains. To date, DFC has extended a $250 million loan to Tata Power Solar to construct a solar cell manufacturing facility and a $500 million loan to First Solar to construct and operate a solar module manufacturing facility in India," it added.</p>

<p>The two leaders welcomed the India-US collaboration on a new National Center for Hydrogen Safety in India and affirmed their intent to utilise the new Renewable Energy Technology Action Platform (RETAP) to enhance collaboration on clean energy manufacturing and global supply chains.</p>

<p>"The Leaders welcomed the progress made on joint efforts since 2023 for India to work toward IEA membership in accordance with the provisions of the Agreement on an International Energy Program.</p>

<p>The two Leaders reaffirmed their commitment to accelerating the manufacturing and deployment of renewable energy, battery storage and emerging clean technology in India," the White House said.</p>

<p><strong>Promoting Global Health and Development</strong></p>

<p>The two leaders celebrated the new US-India Drug Policy Framework, which will deepen the collaboration to disrupt the illicit production and international trafficking of synthetic drugs and precursor chemicals, and deepen a holistic public health partnership.</p>

<p>"The Leaders applauded the first-ever U.S.-India Cancer Dialogue held in August 2024, which brought together experts from both countries to increase research and development to accelerate the rate of progress against cancer," the White House said.</p>

<p>"The leaders welcomed the signing of Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) between the Ministry of Micro, Small and Medium Enterprises and Small Business Administration for promoting cooperation between U.S. and Indian small and medium-size enterprises by improving their participation in the global market place through capacity building workshops in areas such as trade and export finance, technology and digital trade, green economy and trade facilitation," it said.</p>

<p>"The Leaders welcomed enhanced cooperation on agriculture between the U.S. Department of Agriculture and India's Ministry of Agriculture and Farmers Welfare, in areas such as climate-smart agriculture, agriculture productivity growth, agriculture innovation, and sharing best practices related to crop risk protection and agriculture credit. The two sides will also enhance cooperation with the private sector through discussions on regulatory issues and innovation to enhance bilateral trade," the White House said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/gp6g6l_modi-biden-afp_625x300_22_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Prime Minister Modi met US president Joe Biden at his home in Wilmington, North Carolina]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/quad-summit-2024-pm-narendra-modi-joe-biden-cancer-moonshot-to-sea-observer-mission-key-takeaways-from-wilmington-summit-6621531]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Cancer Moonshot To Sea Observer Mission: Key Takeaways From Quad Summit]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/quad-summit-2024-pm-narendra-modi-joe-biden-cancer-moonshot-to-sea-observer-mission-key-takeaways-from-wilmington-summit-6621531]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 22 Sep 2024 09:18:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[PM Narendra Modi, US President Joe Biden, Japan PM Kishida Fumio, and Australia's Anthony Albanese held the fourth in-person Quad Leaders Summit in Wilmington on Saturday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi, US President Joe Biden, Japan PM Kishida Fumio, and Australia's Anthony Albanese - met for the fourth in-person <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-modis-opening-remarks-at-quad-summit-free-open-indo-pacific-is-our-shared-priority-6620348#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">Quad Leaders Summit</a> in Wilmington, Delaware on Saturday. In a joint statement, they said the four-member Quad is a "force for good" and is "more strategically aligned" than ever before.</p>

<p>"Four years since elevating the Quad to a leader-level format, the Quad is more strategically aligned than ever before and is a force for good that delivers real, positive, and enduring impact for the Indo-Pacific. We celebrate the fact that over just four years, Quad countries have built a vital and enduring regional grouping that will buttress the Indo-Pacific for decades to come," the Wilmington Declaration joint statement said.</p>

<h2><strong>Key Takeaways From Quad Summit:</strong></h2>

<h3><strong>Quad Cancer Moonshot</strong></h3>

<p>The four leaders have launched a Quad Cancer Moonshot in a bid to reduce the number of lives lost to cancer in the Indo-Pacific, with an initial focus on cervical cancer.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Prime Minister Narendra Modi, US President Joe Biden, Australias Prime Minister Anthony Albanese and Japans Prime Minister Fumio Kishida during the Quad leaders summit" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/68nfp4c8_quad-summit_625x300_22_September_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Prime Minister Narendra Modi, US President Joe Biden, Australias Prime Minister Anthony Albanese and Japans Prime Minister Fumio Kishida during the Quad leaders summit" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">Prime Minister Narendra Modi, US President Joe Biden, Australia's Prime Minister Anthony Albanese and Japan's Prime Minister Fumio Kishida during the Quad leaders summit</p>
</div>

<p>According to the statement, the Quad Cancer Moonshot is projected to save hundreds of thousands of lives over the coming decades.</p>

<h3><strong>Quad-at-Sea Ship Observer Mission</strong></h3>

<p>They also announced the first-ever "Quad-at-Sea Ship Observer Mission" in 2025, which they said will improve interoperability and advance maritime safety between the Indian Coast Guard and its US, Japan, and Australian counterparts.</p>

<h3><strong>Indo-Pacific Logistics Network</strong></h3>

<p>A Quad Indo-Pacific Logistics Network pilot project was also launched today to support civilian response to natural disasters more rapidly and efficiently across the Indo-Pacific region.</p>

<h3><strong>Quad Ports</strong></h3>

<p>The "Quad Ports of the Future Partnership" was also announced to support sustainable and resilient port infrastructure development across the Indo-Pacific.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="PM Narendra Modi, Joe Biden, Anthony Albanese and Fumio Kishida meet at the Quad leaders summit at Archmere Academy in Claymont" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/fl9o7su_quad-summit_625x300_22_September_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="PM Narendra Modi, Joe Biden, Anthony Albanese and Fumio Kishida meet at the Quad leaders summit at Archmere Academy in Claymont" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">PM Narendra Modi, Joe Biden, Anthony Albanese and Fumio Kishida meet at the Quad leaders summit at Archmere Academy in Claymont<br />
<span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: PTI</span></p>
</div>

<p>Through this new partnership, Quad partners intend to coordinate, exchange information, share best practices with partners in the region, and leverage resources to mobilize government and private sector investments in quality port infrastructure across the Indo-Pacific region.</p>

<h3><strong>Semiconductors</strong></h3>

<p>The <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/watch-will-quad-survive-beyond-november-bidens-gesture-pm-modi-by-his-side-6620503#pfrom=home-ndtv_topstories" target="_blank">Quad leaders</a> also announced the finalization of a Memorandum of Cooperation for the Semiconductor Supply Chains Contingency Network to facilitate collaboration in addressing semiconductor supply chain risks.</p>

<h3><strong>Reform UN Security Council</strong></h3>

<p>The four leaders also agreed to reform the UN Security Council and recognised the urgent need to make it "more "representative, inclusive, transparent, efficient, effective, democratic, and accountable" through expansion in permanent and non-permanent categories of membership of the UNSC.</p>

<p>At a bilateral meeting, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/quad-summit-us-supports-indias-push-for-permanent-seat-in-un-security-council-6621150#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">Joe Biden also told PM Modi</a> that the US supports initiatives to "reform global institutions to reflect India's important voice, including permanent membership for India in a reformed UN Security Council".</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Prime Minister Narendra Modi speaks as US President Joe Biden looks on at the Quad Leaders Summit" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/925jqd_pm-modi-biden_625x300_22_September_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Prime Minister Narendra Modi speaks as US President Joe Biden looks on at the Quad Leaders Summit" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">Prime Minister Narendra Modi speaks as US President Joe Biden looks on at the Quad Leaders Summit<br />
<span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: PTI</span></p>
</div>

<h3><strong>Quad's MAITRI</strong></h3>

<p>Quad partners also agreed to launch a "Maritime Initiative for Training in the Indo-Pacific" (MAITRI) to monitor and secure their waters, enforce their laws, and deter "unlawful behavior". India will host the inaugural MAITRI workshop during its Quad Presidency in 2025</p>

<h3><strong>Quad Scholarship</strong></h3>

<p>India announced a new initiative to award fifty Quad scholarships, worth $5,00,000, to students from the Indo-Pacific to pursue a 4-year undergraduate engineering program at a Government of India-funded technical institution.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/soo946v_quad-summit_625x300_22_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[PM Narendra Modi with other Quad leaders during the summit at the Archmere Academy in Claymont, Delaware]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-us-to-elevate-bilateral-ties-to-expand-clean-energy-supply-chains-6621420]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India, US To Elevate Bilateral Ties To Expand Clean Energy Supply Chains]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-us-to-elevate-bilateral-ties-to-expand-clean-energy-supply-chains-6621420]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 22 Sep 2024 08:49:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The US and India plan to elevate bilateral technical, financial, and policy support to expand complementary manufacturing capacity for building on existing clean energy cooperation between the two nations, according to the White House.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The US and India plan to elevate bilateral technical, financial, and policy support to expand complementary manufacturing capacity for building on existing clean energy cooperation between the two nations, according to the White House.</p>

<p>The announcement on Saturday came after the meeting of Prime Minister Narendra Modi and US President Joe Biden at Greenville, Delaware.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Modi is in the US on a three-day visit.</p>

<p>To launch the partnership for establishing a "shared, resilient, and cutting-edge techno-industrial base" centred on innovative clean energy manufacturing techniques, the US and India are "working to unlock USD 1 billion in new multilateral finance through the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development (IBRD) for projects, including catalysing India's domestic clean energy supply chain buildout", the White House said in a statement.</p>

<p>The partnership will look to expand complementary US and Indian manufacturing capacity for clean energy technologies and components and lay the groundwork for enhanced cooperation in third countries, with a focus on partnerships in Africa.</p>

<p>This effort will build on existing clean energy cooperation between the US and India, including clean energy initiatives launched during Prime Minister Modi's visit to the US in 2023, and the Strategic Clean Energy Partnership led by the US Department of Energy and Government of India ministries, among other initiatives.</p>

<p>The US-India partnership "sets a strong example for the world and positions our countries to lead clean economic development in the 21st century," the statement said.</p>

<p>"The United States and India share an enduring commitment to deepen our collaboration on issues of shared national and economic security. As an important aspect of our economic growth agendas, we are committed to working together to capture the benefits of the clean energy transition, including the creation of high-quality jobs for our populations, acceleration of clean energy deployment globally, and achievement of global climate goals," it said.</p>

<p>"Over time, we seek to mobilise additional financing into priority clean energy manufacturing sectors that harness public and private financial tools and pioneer innovative financial vehicles to meet the rapid demand for flexible climate finance solutions," said the White House.</p>

<p>Noting that the United States and India intend to work with relevant government agencies, civil society and the private sector to identify a package of pilot projects across the clean energy value chain, it said that the two nations also pledge to work with industry leaders on the following lines of effort to launch and eventually scale this new partnership.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/3np6h8eo_pm-modi-joe-biden-ani-_625x300_22_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Prime Minister Modi is in the US on a three-day visit.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hezbollah-lebanon-israel-bombards-lebanon-as-hezbollah-launches-rocket-attacks-10-facts-6621312]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Bombards Lebanon As Hezbollah Launches Rocket Attacks: 10 Facts]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hezbollah-lebanon-israel-bombards-lebanon-as-hezbollah-launches-rocket-attacks-10-facts-6621312]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 22 Sep 2024 08:13:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hezbollah on Saturday launched a series of rocket attacks from Lebanon into northern Israel, marking one of the most intense cross-border confrontations since the war began in October.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<ol>
	<li>On Saturday night, Hezbollah fired at least 10 missiles into northern towns and cities of Israel's Jezreel Valley, the Times of Israel reported. This was the deepest incursion by Hezbollah rockets into Israeli territory since the conflict began in early October. The Israel Defense Forces (IDF) intercepted most of the missiles, but one man in his 60s suffered minor injuries from shrapnel.</li>
	<li>Hezbollah claimed responsibility for the missile barrage and stated that it had aimed at the Ramat David Airbase. Located 50 km from the Lebanon border, the airbase is a key strategic site for the Israeli Air Force.&nbsp;</li>
	<li>In response, Israeli jets carried out a series of retaliatory strikes across southern Lebanon. The IDF reported that its airstrikes targeted at least 110 Hezbollah positions, including rocket launchers and operational facilities. The IDF claims it successfully disrupted Hezbollah's preparations for further rocket launches.</li>
	<li>The IDF stated that their Saturday afternoon air raids hit approximately 290 Hezbollah sites, including thousands of rocket launcher barrels, as part of their strategy to dismantle Hezbollah's rocket-firing capabilities. These preemptive strikes were launched to degrade Hezbollah's ability to launch large-scale attacks on Israeli territory.</li>
	<li>The intensification of Israeli airstrikes follows Hezbollah's earlier attack on Israeli military targets, including seven positions in northern Israel and the Golan Heights. Israel's military reported that Hezbollah had fired about 90 rockets at Israeli forces during these engagements.</li>
	<li>In addition to military targets, Israel conducted an airstrike on southern Beirut, killing senior Hezbollah commanders. According to Lebanon's Health Ministry, the strike left 37 people dead. Among those killed were three children and seven women. Hezbollah confirmed that Ibrahim Aqil, the head of its elite Radwan Force, and other high-ranking commanders were among the dead.&nbsp;</li>
	<li>Following the loss of its commanders, Hezbollah vowed retaliation. Ahmed Mahmud Wahbi, another high-ranking Hezbollah commander, was also killed in the same Israeli strike. Hezbollah leader Hassan Nasrallah condemned the attack, calling it an act of war, and promised retribution against Israel.</li>
	<li>The United Nations has expressed concern over the situation, calling for "maximum restraint" from all parties. Germany and other nations have urged an immediate de-escalation. International mediators, particularly from the United States, are working to prevent the Israel-Hezbollah conflict from spiralling into a regional war.</li>
	<li>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu announced an expansion of the country's war objectives, including the return of northern Israeli residents, who have been forced to evacuate due to Hezbollah's attacks. Netanyahu said the military's focus was on dismantling Hezbollah's ability to pose a threat to Israel's northern borders, stating that the country's actions speak for themselves.</li>
	<li>Amid the heightened conflict, the US State Department has issued an advisory for American citizens in Lebanon, urging them to leave the country while commercial flights are still available. The US raised its travel advisory for Lebanon in July following another Israeli strike that killed a Hezbollah commander in Beirut.</li>
</ol>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/s466bit_israel-lebanon-strike-afp-_625x300_22_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The IDF stated that their air raids hit approximately 290 Hezbollah sites.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-man-22-arrested-in-the-murder-of-his-father-stepmother-and-stepbrother-6621298]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Man Arrested In The Murder Of His Father, Stepmother And Stepbrother]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-man-22-arrested-in-the-murder-of-his-father-stepmother-and-stepbrother-6621298]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 22 Sep 2024 08:10:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Brian Crossman Jr., 22, now faces three counts of aggravated murder for the fatal shootings of his father, stepmother, and stepbrother.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 22-year-old man has been arrested for the murder of his father, stepmother, and teenage stepbrother, who were found shot to death in their Vermont home, police announced on Friday. The triple homicide was discovered early Sunday morning., the<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://abcnews.go.com/US/pawlet-vermont-triple-homicide-arrest-murder/story?id=113880592" rel="nofollow, noindex"><em> ABC News</em></a> reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://vtstatepolice.blogspot.com/2024/09/update-no-3-suspect-arrested-on-murder.html?utm_source=dlvr.it&amp;utm_medium=twitter" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>Vermont State Police</em></a> responded to a report of a "suspicious person" and the investigation led officers to a residence in Pawlet, Vermont. Inside, they found the bodies of Brian Crossman Sr., 46, a Pawlet government official; his wife, Erica Crossman, 41; and her son, Colin Taft, 13, who was also Crossman Sr.'s stepson. According to police, they were killed sometime early Sunday morning in their home.</p>

<p>Brian Crossman Jr., 22, from Granville, New York, now faces three counts of aggravated murder for the fatal shootings of his father, stepmother, and stepbrother, Vermont State Police said.</p>

<p>"The Vermont State Police investigation identified significant evidence linking Crossman Jr. to the murders, including digital data, statements, injuries, and interviews," the police statement said.</p>

<p>Authorities have not yet disclosed a motive for the killings.</p>

<p>New York State Police apprehended Crossman Jr. and took him into custody. On Friday afternoon, he appeared in court in Lake George, New York, on a charge of being a fugitive from justice. This charge is connected to an arrest warrant obtained by Vermont State Police for the aggravated murder charges, police said.</p>

<p>He is being held without bail and is awaiting another hearing in New York next week. Attorney information for Crossman Jr. was not immediately available, and his extradition to Vermont is still being arranged.</p>

<p>The Vermont Chief Medical Examiner's Office ruled all three deaths as homicides, confirming that each victim died from gunshot wounds. Brian Crossman Sr. was shot in the head and torso, Erica Crossman was shot in the head, and Colin Taft suffered multiple gunshot wounds.</p>

<p>Brian Crossman Sr., who had recently joined the Pawlet Select Board, was remembered by the board's chair, Mike Beecher, as a "friend and neighbour" and a "hardworking community member."</p>

<p>"This tragedy that struck him and his family has also hit our community hard, and we are shaken and grieving," Beecher said in a statement on Tuesday. "Our hearts go out to everyone affected by this devastating loss. The town of Pawlet will get through this, as we always do in hard times-by supporting each other and carrying on."</p>

<p>Pawlet, a town of about 1,400 residents, is located along the New York state border in western Vermont.</p>

<p><br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/q0ta9n6g_brian-crossman-jr_625x300_22_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Vermont Chief Medical Examiner's Office ruled all three deaths as homicides]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/quad-summit-us-supports-indias-push-for-permanent-seat-in-un-security-council-6621150]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Supports India's Push For Permanent Seat In UN Security Council]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/quad-summit-us-supports-indias-push-for-permanent-seat-in-un-security-council-6621150]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 22 Sep 2024 07:47:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden has told Prime Minister Narendra Modi that the United States supports initiatives to reform global institutions to reflect India's important voice, including permanent membership for India in a "reformed" UNSC.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden has told Prime Minister Narendra Modi that the United States supports initiatives to reform global institutions to reflect India's important voice, including permanent membership for India in a "reformed" United Nations Security Council (UNSC). President Biden's statement came during the Quad Leaders Summit attended by PM Modi, Japan's PM Fumio Kishida and Australia's Anthony Albanese on Sunday.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Quad leaders vowed support to reform the UNSC through expansion in permanent and non-permanent categories of membership. <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2024/09/21/joint-fact-sheet-the-united-states-and-india-continue-to-expand-comprehensive-and-global-strategic-partnership/">In a joint statement</a>, the leaders said that the India-US partnership "is vital to the success of efforts to build a cleaner, inclusive, more secure, and more prosperous future for the planet."&nbsp;</p>

<p>President Biden commended India's leadership, particularly PM Modi's role in the G-20 and the Global South and acknowledged the PM's recent visits to Poland and Ukraine. The discussion around India's potential inclusion as a permanent member of the UNSC is part of a larger conversation about reforming global institutions to reflect current geopolitical realities. India, with its large population, expanding economy, and active role in international peacekeeping and diplomacy, has long advocated for such reforms.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The Leaders reaffirmed their support for the freedom of navigation and the protection of commerce, including critical maritime routes in the Middle East where India will assume co-lead in 2025 of the Combined Task Force 150 to work with Combined Maritime Forces to secure sea lanes in the Arabian Sea," the joint statement added.</p>

<p>During the Quad summit, PM Modi reiterated the importance of a "free, open, inclusive, and prosperous Indo-Pacific." PM Modi highlighted several initiatives, including collaborations in health security, emerging technologies, and climate change, aimed at addressing global challenges. He described the Quad as a "force for global good," committed to fostering cooperation for the benefit of all.</p>

<p>The US and India are working together to expand clean energy manufacturing and strengthen their technological and industrial bases. The Biden administration has announced plans to unlock $1 billion in new multilateral financing through the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development (IBRD) for clean energy projects in India.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Prime Minister Modi announced a $7.5 million grant for cancer testing, screening, and diagnostics in the Indo-Pacific region. The grant forms part of India's broader 'One Earth, One Health' vision, which seeks to share India's expertise in healthcare and provide assistance in areas such as radiotherapy and capacity building.</p>

<p>The US and India also announced advancements in technology and defence cooperation. The Initiative on Critical and Emerging Technology (iCET) continues to strengthen strategic ties between the two nations in key technology sectors, including semiconductors. A new semiconductor fabrication plant will be established, supported by India's Semiconductor Mission and a partnership with US companies like Bharat Semi and 3rdiTech.</p>

<p>In defence, the two countries have deepened industrial cooperation, with projects such as the co-development of unmanned surface vehicle systems by Liquid Robotics and Sagar Defence Engineering.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/670ocu7o_pm-modi-quad-summit-_625x300_22_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[President Biden's statement came during the Quad Leaders Summit attended by PM Modi.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sri-lankas-marxist-politician-anura-kumara-dissanayake-leads-presidential-elections-vote-6621214]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Sri Lanka's Marxist Politician Anura Dissanayake Leads Presidential Vote]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sri-lankas-marxist-politician-anura-kumara-dissanayake-leads-presidential-elections-vote-6621214]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 22 Sep 2024 07:43:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Sri Lanka's Marxist-leaning leader, Anura Kumara Dissanayake, grabbed a commanding early lead on Sunday in his bid to become the next president of the debt-ridden country seeking to elect a leader to bolster its fragile economic recovery.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sri Lanka's Marxist-leaning leader, Anura Kumara Dissanayake, grabbed a commanding early lead on Sunday in his bid to become the next president of the debt-ridden country seeking to elect a leader to bolster its fragile economic recovery. Dissanayake won about 53% of a million votes counted so far in the election, Sri Lanka's Election Commission data showed.</p>

<p>Opposition leader Sajith Premadasa was second at 22%, ahead of President Ranil Wickremesinghe in third place.</p>

<p>About 75% of the eligible 17 million people in the Indian Ocean island nation cast their votes in Saturday's election, according to the poll body.</p>

<p>Dissanayake contested as candidate for the National People's Power (NPP) alliance, which includes his Marxist-leaning Janatha Vimukthi Peremuna (JVP) party that has traditionally backed stronger state intervention, lower taxes &nbsp;and more closed market economic policies.</p>

<p>Although JVP party has just three seats in parliament, the 55-year-old Dissanayake has been boosted by his promises of tough anti-corruption measures and more pro-poor policies.</p>

<p>He presented himself as the candidate of change, promising to dissolve parliament within 45 days of coming to power in order to seek a fresh mandate for his policies in the general elections.</p>

<p>"After a long and arduous campaign, the results of the election are now clear," Foreign Minister Ali Sabry said on X.</p>

<p>"Though I heavily campaigned for President Ranil Wickremasinghe, the people of Sri Lanka have made their decision, and I fully respect their mandate for Anura Kumara Dissanayake."</p>

<p>This was Sri Lanka's first election since the economy buckled in 2022 under a severe foreign exchange shortage, leaving the country unable to pay for imports of essentials including fuel, medicine and cooking gas.</p>

<p>Thousands of protesters marched in Colombo in 2022 and occupied the president's office and residence, forcing then-President Gotabaya Rajapaksa to flee and later resign.</p>

<p>Buttressed by a $2.9 billion bailout programme from the International Monetary Fund (IMF), the economy has posted a tentative recovery but the high cost of living was still a critical issue for many voters.</p>

<p>Although inflation cooled to 0.5% last month from a crisis high of 70%, and the economy is forecast to grow in 2024 for the first time in three years, millions remain mired in poverty, with many pinning hopes of a better future on the next leader.</p>

<p>The winner will have to ensure Sri Lanka sticks with the IMF programme until 2027 to get its economy on a stable growth path, reassure markets, repay debt, attract investors and help a quarter of its people climb out of poverty.</p>

<p>In his manifesto, Dissanayake, known for his ability to deliver stirring speeches, has pledged to slash taxes that would impact fiscal targets, leaving investors and market participants worried about his economic policies.</p>

<p>However, during campaign speeches he has taken a more conciliatory approach, saying any changes would be undertaken in consultation with the IMF and that he is committed to ensuring repayment of debt.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/n0jg6u7_anura-kumara-dissanayake_625x300_22_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-testing-us-on-several-fronts-joe-biden-to-quad-leaders-6621181]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["China Testing Us On Several Fronts": Joe Biden To Quad Leaders]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-testing-us-on-several-fronts-joe-biden-to-quad-leaders-6621181]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 22 Sep 2024 07:33:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden was caught on a hot mic telling leaders of the Quad nations that China was testing them, thus reflecting upon the American seriousness of the emerging Chinese threat.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden was caught on a hot mic telling leaders of the Quad nations that China was testing them, thus reflecting upon the American seriousness of the emerging Chinese threat.</p>

<p>Biden's remark came during the Quad Leaders' Summit on Saturday, which was attended by Prime Minister Narendra Modi, Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese and Japanese Prime Minister Fumio Kishida.</p>

<p>"We believe Xi Jinping is looking to focus on domestic economic challenges and minimise the turbulence in China," Biden told the leaders at the Summit.</p>

<p>His opening remarks were caught on the hot mic as pool reporters were leaving the Summit venue. Biden was heard saying that Chinese President Xi Jinping is "looking to buy himself some diplomatic space, in my view, to aggressively pursue China's interest." Biden added that China continues to "behave aggressively, testing us all across the region on several fronts, including on economic and technology issues".</p>

<p>"At the same time, we believe intense competition requires intense diplomacy," he said.</p>

<p>Later a senior administration official tried to downplay the error.</p>

<p>"I don't think I have much to elaborate on that. It's consistent with what has been said before, and I don't think it'll be much of a surprise that our inside voice matches our outside voice," the official said.</p>

<p>"I think it's not surprising that China would have been on the agenda. It's an Indo-Pacific convening. This is an Indo-Pacific partnership. China is a major country in the Indo-Pacific. But I think it's also fair to say that there were a number of other topics on the agenda," said the official.</p>

<p>China is engaged in hotly contested territorial disputes in both the South China Sea and the East China Sea.</p>

<p>It claims sovereignty over all of the South China Sea. Vietnam, Malaysia, the Philippines, Brunei and Taiwan have counterclaims.</p>

<p>The four-member Quad, or the Quadrilateral Security Dialogue, advocates upholding a free, open, and inclusive Indo-Pacific. China claims that the grouping aims to contain its rise.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/ofrrpqv8_joe-biden-afp_625x300_08_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Joe Biden's remark came during the Quad Leaders' Summit on Saturday]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-testing-us-on-several-fronts-joe-biden-to-quad-leaders-6621149]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["China Testing Us On Several Fronts": Joe Biden To Quad Leaders]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-testing-us-on-several-fronts-joe-biden-to-quad-leaders-6621149]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 22 Sep 2024 07:24:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden was caught on a hot mic telling leaders of the Quad nations that China was testing them, thus reflecting upon the American seriousness of the emerging Chinese threat.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden was caught on a hot mic telling leaders of the Quad nations that China was testing them, thus reflecting upon the American seriousness of the emerging Chinese threat.</p>

<p>Biden's remark came during the Quad Leaders' Summit on Saturday, which was attended by Prime Minister Narendra Modi, Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese and Japanese Prime Minister Fumio Kishida.</p>

<p>"We believe Xi Jinping is looking to focus on domestic economic challenges and minimise the turbulence in China," Biden told the leaders at the Summit.</p>

<p>His opening remarks were caught on the hot mic as pool reporters were leaving the Summit venue. Biden was heard saying that Chinese President Xi Jinping is "looking to buy himself some diplomatic space, in my view, to aggressively pursue China's interest." Biden added that China continues to "behave aggressively, testing us all across the region on several fronts, including on economic and technology issues".</p>

<p>"At the same time, we believe intense competition requires intense diplomacy," he said.</p>

<p>Later a senior administration official tried to downplay the error.</p>

<p>"I don't think I have much to elaborate on that. It's consistent with what has been said before, and I don't think it'll be much of a surprise that our inside voice matches our outside voice," the official said.</p>

<p>"I think it's not surprising that China would have been on the agenda. It's an Indo-Pacific convening. This is an Indo-Pacific partnership. China is a major country in the Indo-Pacific. But I think it's also fair to say that there were a number of other topics on the agenda," said the official.</p>

<p>China is engaged in hotly contested territorial disputes in both the South China Sea and the East China Sea.</p>

<p>It claims sovereignty over all of the South China Sea. Vietnam, Malaysia, the Philippines, Brunei and Taiwan have counterclaims.</p>

<p>The four-member Quad, or the Quadrilateral Security Dialogue, advocates upholding a free, open, and inclusive Indo-Pacific. China claims that the grouping aims to contain its rise.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/ofrrpqv8_joe-biden-afp_625x300_08_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Joe Biden's remark came during the Quad Leaders' Summit on Saturday]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-forces-raid-al-jazeeras-ramallah-west-bank-office-order-45-day-closure-6621089]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Take All Cameras And Leave": Israel Raids Al Jazeera's West Bank Office]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-forces-raid-al-jazeeras-ramallah-west-bank-office-order-45-day-closure-6621089]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 22 Sep 2024 07:08:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA["Heavily armed and masked Israeli soldiers" entered the building and handed the closure order to Qatari broadcaster's West Bank bureau chief, Al Jazeera reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Qatari broadcaster Al Jazeera today said that Israeli forces raided its office in Ramallah in the occupied West Bank and issued a 45-day closure order.</p>

<p>"Heavily armed and masked Israeli soldiers entered the building and handed the closure order to the network's West Bank bureau chief Walid al-Omari early on Sunday. They did not provide a reason for the decision," Al Jazeera reported.</p>

<p>"There is a court ruling for closing down Al Jazeera for 45 days," an Israeli soldier told journalist Walid al-Omari, Al Jazeera reported, citing the conversation which was broadcast live.</p>

<p>"I ask you to take all the cameras and leave the office at this moment," the soldier said in Arabic.</p>

<p>The raid comes months after <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/will-pursue-legal-action-until-the-end-says-al-jazeera-after-israel-ban-5609359" target="_blank">Israel banned Al Jazeera</a> from operating inside the country in May, saying it threatened national security.</p>

<p>In May, Israeli authorities also raided a Jerusalem hotel room used by <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-extends-al-jazeera-ban-for-another-45-days-cites-security-threat-5852595" target="_blank">Al Jazeera</a> as its office.</p>

<p>Al Jazeera had condemned the ban, calling it a "criminal act that violates human rights and the basic right to access of information".</p>

<p>"Israel's ongoing suppression of the free press, seen as an effort to conceal its actions in the Gaza Strip, stands in contravention of international and humanitarian law," the network said in a statement.</p>

<h3><strong>Israel Kills Al Jazeera Journalist</strong></h3>

<p>Israel last month said it had killed <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-kills-al-jazeera-journalist-claims-he-was-vital-part-of-hamas-military-activity-6250941" target="_blank">Al Jazeera journalist Ismail Al-Ghoul</a> in an airstrike in Gaza, saying he was a Hamas operative who had taken part in the October 7 attack on Israel.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said Al-Ghoul was a member of the elite Nukhba unit who took part in the October 7 attack and instructed Hamas operatives on how to record operations. It also said he was involved in recording and publicizing attacks on Israeli troops.</p>

<p>"His activities in the field were a vital part of Hamas' military activity," the Israeli military said in a statement on August 1.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-gaza-benjamin-netanyahu-rejects-gaza-truce-talks-shuts-down-al-jazeeras-israel-office-5597845" target="_blank">Al Jazeera</a>, however, had dismissed what it said were "baseless allegations" which it said were an attempt to justify the deliberate killing of its journalists.</p>

<p>"The network condemns the accusations against its correspondent Ismail Al-Ghoul, without providing any proof, documentation or video," it said in a statement, adding that it reserved the right to take legal action against those responsible.</p>

<p>The Qatari broadcaster said that Al-Ghoul and cameraman Ramy El Rify were killed in an Israeli strike on Gaza City while on an assignment to film near the house of Ismail Haniyeh, the Hamas chief killed in Iran.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/602lmr9_aljazeera_625x300_22_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Representational Image]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/watch-will-quad-survive-beyond-november-bidens-gesture-pm-modi-by-his-side-6620503]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Watch: Will Quad Survive Beyond Nov? Biden's Gesture. PM Modi By His Side]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/watch-will-quad-survive-beyond-november-bidens-gesture-pm-modi-by-his-side-6620503]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 22 Sep 2024 03:43:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden, one of the architects of the Quad grouping, was asked ahead of the Quad summit in Delaware if it would survive beyond November elections.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden, one of the architects of the Quad grouping, was asked ahead of the Quad summit in Delaware if it would survive beyond November elections. The question was posed at the outgoing President - who is not seeking re-election - as he posed for a photo with Prime Minister Narendra Modi and his Australian and Japanese counterparts, Anthony Albanese and Fumio Kishida.</p>

<p>The four leaders represent the four member countries of the Quad, a security and strategic grouping committed to a free and open Indo-Pacific.</p>

<p>Responding to the question on Quad's future, Biden turned around and placed a hand across PM Modi's shoulder and said, "(It will survive) way beyond November."</p>

<p>The Quad summit is being held in Biden's hometown of Wilmington, Delaware.</p>

<p>The US elections this November will see a Kamala Harris versus Donald Trump fight with Biden not returning to the ring. Japan's Kishida too has announced he won't seek re-election. This implies both the US and Japan are set to be represented by new leaders at its next Quad summit.</p>

<p>In his opening remarks, PM Modi offered to host the Quad Leaders' summit in India in 2025. He also highlighted that a free, open and inclusive Indo-Pacific is a shared priority and shared commitment of the Quad.</p>

<p>"We are meeting at a time when the world is surrounded by tensions and conflicts. At such a time, it is important for all of humanity that the members of the Quad move forward based on shared democratic values," he told the Quad leaders.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/8t8f5l48_biden-modi_625x300_22_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Quad summit is being held in Biden's hometown of Wilmington, Delaware.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-modi-us-visit-as-pm-narendra-modi-and-joe-biden-hold-bilateral-talks-a-mega-drone-deal-firms-up-6620448]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[As PM Modi And Joe Biden Hold Bilateral Talks, A Mega Drone Deal Firms Up]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-modi-us-visit-as-pm-narendra-modi-and-joe-biden-hold-bilateral-talks-a-mega-drone-deal-firms-up-6620448]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 22 Sep 2024 03:29:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India and the United States today firmed up multi-billion dollar drone deal as PM Modi met Joe Biden on the first day of his three-day visit to the US.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India and the United States today firmed up multi-billion dollar drone deal as PM Modi met Joe Biden on the first day of his three-day visit to the US. PM Modi held bilateral talks with US President Joe Biden and the two leaders discussed a range of issues to further strengthen India-US ties.</p>

<p>The drone deal was also discussed in detail by both leaders.</p>

<p>India is in the process of procuring 31 MQ-9B Sky Guardian and Sea Guardian drones from the United States. The cost to acquire these drones is nearly $3 billion. India aims to heighten the surveillance apparatus of the armed forces, especially along the frontier with China.</p>

<p>The talks for this deal have been on for well over a year now. In June last year, the Defence Ministry approved the procurement of the MQ-9B Sky Guardian and Sea Guardian armed drones with air-to-surface missiles and laser-guided bombs from the US under a government-to-government framework.</p>

<p>Apart from purchasing the drones, the Indian Navy is also looking to conclude two other major defence deals this financial year - 3 more Scorpene submarines and 26 Rafale-M fighter aircraft.</p>

<h2><strong>THE MQ-9B SKY GUARDIAN AND SEA GUARDIAN DRONES</strong></h2>

<p>The MQ-9B drone is a high-altitude long-endurance remotely-piloted unmanned aircraft manufactures and sold by US defence firm General Atomics. It is known for delivering persistent intelligence, surveillance, and reconnaissance (ISR).</p>

<p>It is designed to fly over the horizon via satellite for up to 40+ hours in all types of weather and safely integrate into civil airspace, enabling joint forces and civil authorities to deliver real-time situational awareness anywhere in the world—day or night.</p>

<p>According to General Atomics, the drone can be configured to conduct a number of ISR operations, including but not limited to:</p>

<ol>
	<li>Humanitarian Assistance/Disaster Relief</li>
	<li>Search and Rescue</li>
	<li>Maritime domain awareness</li>
	<li>Anti-surface warfare</li>
	<li>Anti-submarine warfare</li>
	<li>Airborne mine countermeasures</li>
	<li>Airborne early warning</li>
	<li>Electronic warfare</li>
	<li>Long-range strategic ISR</li>
	<li>Over-the-horizon targeting</li>
</ol>

<p>The Predator drone has an impressive and proven record in West Asia as well as in Afghanistan. It is valued for its precision bombing capabilities and eliminating high-value targets.</p>

<p>The Predator drone is a variant of the MQ-9 "Reaper", which was used to launch a modified version of the Hellfire missile that killed Al Qaeda leader Ayman al-Zawahiri in the heart of Kabul in July 2022.</p>

<h3><strong>INDIAN ARMED FORCES - WHO GETS WHAT</strong></h3>

<p>The 31 drones that will be purchased from General Atomics will be divided between the Indian Navy, Indian Air Force and Indian Army. 16 of the MQ-9B drones will be allocated to the Indian Navy to increase its surveillance in the Indian Ocean region, eight will be given to the Indian Army for use along the Line of Actual Control with China and Line of Control with Pakistan, and the remaining eight will be assigned to the Indian Air Force for precision, targeted missions across borders.</p>

<p>The drone deal must be agreed upon and signed by both India and the United States before October 31, 2024, after which the approximately $3 billion price will be up for revision on part of the manufacturer - General Atomics, as per talks between both governments.</p>

<p>Defence Minister Rajnath Singh and his delegation was given a detailed brief on the capability and other specifics of the drone during his official visit to the US in August.</p>

<p>With PM Modi visiting the US, both nations will prioritise the deal and want to make progress before the October 31 date lapses.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/p00a3994_mq-9b-sky-guardian-drone-general-atomics_625x300_22_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[India and US are in talks for New Delhi to purchase 31 MQ-9B Sky Guardian and Sea Guardian drones]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-modis-opening-remarks-at-quad-summit-free-open-indo-pacific-is-our-shared-priority-6620348]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Free, Open Indo-Pacific Is Our Shared Priority": PM Modi At Quad Summit]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-modis-opening-remarks-at-quad-summit-free-open-indo-pacific-is-our-shared-priority-6620348]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 22 Sep 2024 02:50:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A free, open, and inclusive Indo-Pacific is the shared priority and commitment of the Quad countries, said Prime Minister Narendra Modi at the Quad summit on Saturday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A free, open, and inclusive Indo-Pacific is the shared priority and commitment of the Quad countries, said Prime Minister Narendra Modi at the Quad summit on Saturday. Joe Biden, Australian PM Anthony Albanese, and Japan PM Fumio Kishida were also present at the meeting being held at the US President's hometown of Wilmington.</p>

<p>In his opening remarks, PM Modi pointed out the Quad summit is being held at a time when the world is surrounded by tensions and conflicts.</p>

<p>"At such a time, it is important for all of humanity that the members of the Quad move forward based on shared democratic values. We are not against anybody. All of us support rules-based international order, respect for sovereignty and territorial integrity, and peaceful resolution of all disputes. A free, open, inclusive, and prosperous Indo-Pacific is our shared priority and shared commitment," he told the Quad leaders.</p>

<p>The Quad has taken several positive and inclusive initiatives in areas such as health security, critical and emerging technologies, climate change, and capacity building, PM Modi pointed out.</p>

<p>"Our message is clear - the Quad is here to stay, to assist, to partner, and to complement," he said and offered to organise the Quad Leaders' Summit in India in 2025.</p>

<p><strong>Read |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/talks-were-extreme-fruitful-pm-modi-meets-president-biden-in-us-6620160">"Talks Were Extreme Fruitful": PM Modi Meets President Biden In US</a></p>

<p>PM Modi also noted that the first Quad summit was held under Biden's leadership and praised his role in enhancing cooperation in every sphere in an unprecedented way.</p>

<p>"I express my heartfelt gratitude to you (Biden) for your firm commitment, leadership, and contribution towards the Quad," said the Prime Minister.</p>

<p>PM Modi arrived in the US hours earlier on a three-day visit and held bilateral talks with President Biden at his Delaware home. The talks were extremely fruitful, he said in an online post after the meeting.</p>

<p>During his visit, the Prime Minister will also address the Summit of the Future at the UN General Assembly in New York and interact with Indian expatriates and American business leaders.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/8onpgf0g_pm-modi-at-quad_625x300_22_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Quad is here to stay, said PM Modi.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/talks-were-extreme-fruitful-pm-modi-meets-president-biden-in-us-6620160]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Talks Were Extreme Fruitful": PM Modi Meets President Biden In US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/talks-were-extreme-fruitful-pm-modi-meets-president-biden-in-us-6620160]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 22 Sep 2024 01:58:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Narendra Modi said his talks with US President Joe Biden ahead of the Quad summit were extremely fruitful. The two leaders discussed regional and global issues during their bilateral meeting held at the US President's Delaware home.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi said his talks with US President Joe Biden ahead of the Quad summit were extremely fruitful. The two leaders discussed regional and global issues during their bilateral meeting held at the US President's Delaware home on Saturday.</p>

<p>"I thank President Biden for hosting me at his residence in Greenville, Delaware. Our talks were extremely fruitful. We had the opportunity to discuss regional and global issues during the meeting," said PM Modi in a statement posted online.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">I thank President Biden for hosting me at his residence in Greenville, Delaware. Our talks were extremely fruitful. We had the opportunity to discuss regional and global issues during the meeting. <a href="https://twitter.com/JoeBiden?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@JoeBiden</a> <a href="https://t.co/WzWW3fudTn">pic.twitter.com/WzWW3fudTn</a></p>
— Narendra Modi (@narendramodi) <a href="https://twitter.com/narendramodi/status/1837580216492798096?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 21, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>PM Modi, who is on a three-day visit to the US, received a warm welcome as he touched down in Philadelphia earlier in the day. President Biden received PM Modi at his house and led him inside holding his hand.</p>

<p>Posting photos of their meeting, the US President said he is struck by PM Modi's ability to find new areas of cooperation every time he meets him.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">The United States' partnership with India is stronger, closer, and more dynamic than any time in history.<br />
<br />
Prime Minister Modi, each time we sit down, I'm struck by our ability to find new areas of cooperation. Today was no different. <a href="https://t.co/TdcIpF23mV">pic.twitter.com/TdcIpF23mV</a></p>
— President Biden (@POTUS) <a href="https://twitter.com/POTUS/status/1837561205025653025?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 21, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>"The United States' partnership with India is stronger, closer, and more dynamic than any time in history. Prime Minister Modi, each time we sit down, I'm struck by our ability to find new areas of cooperation. Today was no different," President Biden said in a post on X.</p>

<p>PM Modi's US visit is accompanied by Foreign Minister S Jaishankar, Foreign Secretary Vikram Misri, and Ambassador of India to the US Vinay Mohan Kwatra.</p>

<p>The US team present in the meeting included Secretary of State Antony Blinken, Assistant to the President for National Security Affairs Jake Sullivan, and Ambassador of the US to India Eric Garcetti.</p>

<p>PM Modi will also hold separate bilateral meetings with Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese and Japanese Prime Minister Fumio Kishida, who are in the US for the Quad Summit.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/8f2vsqag_modi-biden_625x300_22_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[PM Modi met Biden at his Delaware home on Saturday.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/each-time-we-sit-down-biden-posts-pics-of-meeting-pm-modi-6619870]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Each Time We Sit Down...": Biden Posts Pics Of Meeting PM Modi]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/each-time-we-sit-down-biden-posts-pics-of-meeting-pm-modi-6619870]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 22 Sep 2024 00:28:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Narendra Modi today met US President Joe Biden on the margins of the Quad summit. PM Modi was welcomed by Mr Biden at his residence, where the two leaders hugged each other. Mr Biden held PM Modi's hand as he led him into the house.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi today met US President Joe Biden on the margins of the Quad summit. PM Modi was welcomed by Mr Biden at his residence, where the two leaders hugged each other. Mr Biden held PM Modi's hand as he led him into the house.</p>

<p>"The United States' partnership with India is stronger, closer, and more dynamic than any time in history. Prime Minister Modi, each time we sit down, I'm struck by our ability to find new areas of cooperation. Today was no different," President Biden said in a post on X.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">The United States' partnership with India is stronger, closer, and more dynamic than any time in history.<br />
<br />
Prime Minister Modi, each time we sit down, I'm struck by our ability to find new areas of cooperation. Today was no different. <a href="https://t.co/TdcIpF23mV">pic.twitter.com/TdcIpF23mV</a></p>
— President Biden (@POTUS) <a href="https://twitter.com/POTUS/status/1837561205025653025?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 21, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>PM Modi's US visit is accompanied by External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar, Foreign Secretary Vikram Misri and Ambassador of India to the US Vinay Mohan Kwatra. The US team included Secretary of State Antony Blinken, Assistant to the President for National Security Affairs TH Jake Sullivan and Ambassador of the US to India Eric Garcetti.</p>

<p>PM Modi, who is on a three-day visit, will also hold separate bilateral meetings with Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese and Japanese Prime Minister Fumio Kishida, who are in the US for the Quad Summit.</p>

<p>The annual Quad summit being hosted by President Biden in his hometown Wilmington is expected to roll out a series of new initiatives to boost cooperation in the Indo-Pacific and explore ways to find peaceful solutions to the conflicts in Ukraine and Gaza.</p>

<p>The four-member Quad, or the Quadrilateral Security Dialogue, advocates upholding a free, open, and inclusive Indo-Pacific. Beijing sees it as an anti-China grouping.</p>

<p>In his departure statement in New Delhi, PM Modi said he looked forward to joining his colleagues President Biden, Prime Minister Albanese and Prime Minister Kishida for the Quad Summit.</p>

<p>"The forum has emerged as a key group of like-minded countries to work for peace, progress and prosperity in the Indo-Pacific region," he added.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/d0498958_narendra-modi-joe-biden_625x300_22_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[President Joe Biden meets PM Narendra Modi ahead of the Quad Summit]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-ukraine-discussion-on-agenda-as-pm-modi-joe-biden-hold-talks-6619766]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russia-Ukraine Discussion On Agenda As PM Modi, Joe Biden Hold Talks]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-ukraine-discussion-on-agenda-as-pm-modi-joe-biden-hold-talks-6619766]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 22 Sep 2024 00:00:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Narendra Modi on Saturday met US President Joe Biden on the margins of the Quad summit here and the two leaders were expected to discuss a range of issues, including the Russia-Ukraine conflict.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi on Saturday met US President Joe Biden on the margins of the Quad summit here and the two leaders were expected to discuss a range of issues, including the Russia-Ukraine conflict.</p>

<p>"A special start to a significant visit. @POTUS @JoeBiden warmly received PM @narendramodi at his residence in Greenville, Delaware," the prime minister's office said in a post on X.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">A special start to a significant visit.<a href="https://twitter.com/POTUS?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@POTUS</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/JoeBiden?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@JoeBiden</a> warmly received PM <a href="https://twitter.com/narendramodi?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@narendramodi</a> at his residence in Greenville, Delaware. <a href="https://t.co/zsvBWsGCe3">pic.twitter.com/zsvBWsGCe3</a></p>
— PMO India (@PMOIndia) <a href="https://twitter.com/PMOIndia/status/1837555978557866328?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 21, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>During the meeting, the two leaders were set to "review and identify new pathways to further deepen India-US Comprehensive Global Strategic Partnership".</p>

<p>PM Modi was welcomed by Biden at his residence, where the two leaders hugged each other. Biden held PM Modi's hand as he led him into the house.</p>

<p>"A warm and special beginning to an important visit. In a special gesture @POTUS Joe Biden hosts PM @narendramodi at his residence. PM @narendramodi warmly received by @POTUS Joe Biden at Greenville, Delaware ahead of their bilateral meeting," Ministry of External Affairs spokesperson Randhir Jaiswal said in a post on X.</p>

<p>The Ukraine war and PM Modi's recent visit to Kyiv is expected to figure prominently in the bilateral meeting, US National Security Adviser Jake Sullivan earlier said.</p>

<p>"My meeting with President Biden will allow us to review and identify new pathways to further deepen India-US Comprehensive Global Strategic Partnership for the benefit of our people and the global good," PM Modi had said in his departure statement in New Delhi.</p>

<p>PM Modi was accompanied by External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar, Foreign Secretary Vikram Misri and Ambassador of India to the US Vinay Mohan Kwatra. The US team included Secretary of State Antony Blinken, Assistant to the President for National Security Affairs T H Jake Sullivan and Ambassador of the US to India Eric Garcetti.</p>

<p>PM Modi, who is here as part of his three-day visit to the United States, will also hold separate bilateral meetings with Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese and Japanese Prime Minister Fumio Kishida, who are here for the Quad Summit.</p>

<p>The annual Quad summit being hosted by President Biden in his hometown Wilmington is expected to roll out a series of new initiatives to boost cooperation in the Indo-Pacific and explore ways to find peaceful solutions to the conflicts in Ukraine and Gaza.</p>

<p>The four-member Quad, or the Quadrilateral Security Dialogue, advocates upholding a free, open, and inclusive Indo-Pacific. Beijing sees it as an anti-China grouping.</p>

<p>In his departure statement in New Delhi, PM Modi said he looked forward to joining his colleagues President Biden, Prime Minister Albanese and Prime Minister Kishida for the Quad Summit.</p>

<p>"The forum has emerged as a key group of like-minded countries to work for peace, progress and prosperity in the Indo-Pacific region," he added.</p>

<p>The Quad leaders are also set to unveil a "milestone" initiative to prevent, detect, treat and alleviate the impact of cancer on patients and their families.</p>

<p>Earlier, a large group of the Indian diaspora greeted PM Modi upon his arrival at the Philadelphia International Airport, from where he travelled to Wilmington.</p>

<p>PM Modi greeted a group of people dressed in traditional attire, with many of them holding the Indian tri-colour. He walked along the fenced area, signed autographs for some of them and shook hands with some others.</p>

<p>"An energetic welcome in Philadelphia! Our diaspora's blessings are greatly cherished," PM Modi said in another post on X.</p>

<p>"The Indian community has distinguished itself in the USA, making a positive impact across diverse sectors. It's always a delight to interact with them," the prime minister said. "Let's celebrate the bonds that connect our nations!" From Wilmington, PM Modi will travel to New York to attend an Indian community event at Long Island on September 22 and address the Summit of the Future at the UN General Assembly the next day.</p>

<p>The prime minister's other engagements include joining an Indian diaspora event at Long Island and participating in a round table with CEOs of American firms working on cutting-edge technologies such as AI, quantum computing and semiconductors.</p>

<p>"I am eagerly looking forward to engaging with the Indian diaspora and important American business leaders, who are the key stakeholders and provide vibrancy to the unique partnership between the largest and the oldest democracies of the world," PM Modi said.</p>

<p>"The Summit of the Future is an opportunity for the global community to chart the road ahead for the betterment of humanity. I will share the views of one-sixth of humanity as their stakes in a peaceful and secure future are among the highest in the world," the prime minister said.</p>

<p>The 'Summit of the Future' will bring leaders from various countries to forge a new international consensus on how to deliver a "better present and safeguard the future," according to the UN.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/ib8rd9rg_modi-biden_625x300_22_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[PM Modi was welcomed by Biden at his residence]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/french-president-macron-announces-new-government-led-by-pm-michel-barnier-6619722]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[French President Macron Announces New Government Led By PM Michel Barnier]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/french-president-macron-announces-new-government-led-by-pm-michel-barnier-6619722]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 21 Sep 2024 23:49:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[President Emmanuel Macron named a new government led by Prime Minister Michel Barnier Saturday, his office said, marked by a shift to the right 11 weeks after an inconclusive parliamentary election.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>President Emmanuel Macron named a new government led by Prime Minister Michel Barnier Saturday, his office said, marked by a shift to the right 11 weeks after an inconclusive parliamentary election.</p>

<p>The first major task for Barnier, appointed just over two weeks ago, will be to submit a 2025 budget plan addressing France's financial situation, which the prime minister this week called "very serious".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/nq5bd4ug_emmanuel-macron_625x300_21_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[French PM Michel Barnier was appointed just over two weeks ago. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>