<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Wed, 10 Jul 2024 17:20:29 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-gaza-palestine-explained-how-accurate-are-gaza-death-figures-does-hamas-control-them-6075524]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: How Accurate Are Gaza Death Figures, Does Hamas Control Them?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-gaza-palestine-explained-how-accurate-are-gaza-death-figures-does-hamas-control-them-6075524]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 10 Jul 2024 16:46:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Palestinian health authorities say Israel's ground and air campaign in Gaza has killed more than 38,000 people, mostly civilians, and driven most of the enclave's 2.3 million people from their homes.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Palestinian health authorities say Israel's ground and air campaign in Gaza has killed more than 38,000 people, mostly civilians, and driven most of the enclave's 2.3 million people from their homes.</p>

<p>The war began on Oct. 7 when Hamas operatives rushed across the border into Israeli communities. Israel says the operatives killed more than 1,200 people, mostly civilians, and dragged 253 into captivity in Gaza.</p>

<p>This explainer examines how the Palestinian death count is calculated, how reliable it is, the breakdown of civilians and fighters killed and what each side says.</p>

<p><strong>HOW DO GAZA HEALTH AUTHORITIES CALCULATE THE DEATH COUNT?</strong></p>

<p>In the first months of the war, death counts were calculated entirely from counting bodies that arrived in hospitals and data included names and identity numbers for most of those killed.</p>

<p>As the conflict ground on, and fewer hospitals and morgues continued to operate, the authorities adopted other methods too.</p>

<p>From early May, the Health Ministry updated its breakdown of total fatalities to include unidentified bodies which account for nearly a third of the overall deaths. Omar Hussein Ali, head of the ministry's emergency operations centre in the Israeli-occupied West Bank, said these were bodies that had arrived at hospitals or medical centres without personal data such as identity numbers or full names.</p>

<p>It also began including deaths reported online by family members who had to input information including identity numbers.</p>

<p><strong>IS THE GAZA DEATH COUNT COMPREHENSIVE?</strong></p>

<p>The numbers "do not necessarily reflect all victims due to the fact that many victims are still missing under the rubble", the Palestinian Health Ministry says. In May it estimated that some 10,000 bodies were uncounted in this way.</p>

<p>The Lancet medical journal published a letter from three academics on July 5 estimating that indirect deaths, caused by factors such as disease, might mean the death count is several times higher than official Palestinian estimates.</p>

<p>The letter said it was "not implausible to estimate that up to 186,000 or even more deaths could be attributable to the current conflict in Gaza".</p>

<p>The authors said the figure, which made global headlines, was based on what they said was the conservative estimate of four indirect deaths to one direct death based on trends from prior conflicts.</p>

<p>The U.N. human rights office and the Humanitarian Research Lab at the Yale School of Public Health have also said during the conflict that the true figures are likely higher than those published, without giving specifics.</p>

<p><strong>HOW CREDIBLE IS THE GAZA DEATH COUNT?</strong></p>

<p>Pre-war Gaza had robust population statistics and better health information systems than in most Middle East countries, public health experts told Reuters.</p>

<p>A spokesperson for the World Health Organisation said the ministry has "good capacity in data collection/analysis and its previous reporting has been considered credible".</p>

<p>The United Nations regularly cites the ministry's death count figures, while naming the ministry as the source.</p>

<p>Early in the conflict, after U.S. President Joe Biden cast doubt on casualty figures, the health ministry published a detailed list of the 7,028 deaths that had been registered by that point.</p>

<p>Academics looking at details of listed casualties said in a peer-reviewed article in the Lancet medical journal in November that it was implausible that the patterns shown in the list could be the result of fabrication.</p>

<p>However, there are specific questions over the inclusion of 471 people said to have been killed in an Oct. 17 blast at al-Ahli al-Arab hospital in Gaza City. An unclassified U.S. intelligence report estimated that death count "at the low end of the 100 to 300 spectrum".</p>

<p><strong>DOES HAMAS CONTROL THE FIGURES?</strong></p>

<p>While Hamas has run Gaza since 2007, the enclave's Health Ministry also answers to the overall Palestinian Authority ministry in Ramallah in the West Bank.</p>

<p>Gaza's Hamas-run government has paid the salaries of all those hired in public departments since 2007, including in the Health Ministry. The Palestinian Authority still pays the salaries of those hired before then.</p>

<p>The extent of Hamas control in Gaza now is difficult to assess with Israeli forces occupying most of the territory, including around locations of major hospitals that provide casualty figures, and with fighting ongoing.</p>

<p><strong>WHAT DOES ISRAEL SAY?</strong></p>

<p>Israeli officials have said the figures are suspect because of Hamas' control over government in Gaza. Foreign Ministry spokesperson Oren Mamorstein said the numbers were manipulated and "do not reflect the reality on the ground".</p>

<p>However, Israel's military has also accepted in briefings that the overall Gaza casualty numbers are broadly reliable.</p>

<p>In May, Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said 14,000 Hamas fighters and 16,000 Palestinian civilians had been killed in the war.</p>

<p><strong>HOW MANY CIVILIANS HAVE BEEN KILLED?</strong></p>

<p>The Health Ministry figures do not differentiate between civilians and Hamas combatants, who do not wear formal uniform or carry separate identification.</p>

<p>Israel periodically provides estimates of how many Hamas fighters it believes have been killed. The most recent was Netanyahu's estimate of 14,000.</p>

<p>Israeli security officials say such estimates are reached through a combination of counting bodies on the battlefield, intercepts of Hamas communications and intelligence assessments of personnel in targets that were destroyed.</p>

<p>Hamas has said Israeli estimates for its losses are exaggerated but has not said how many of its fighters have been killed.</p>

<p>The Palestinian Health Ministry says more than 70% of the dead are women and children. For most of the conflict its figures showed children as representing slightly over 40% of all those killed.</p>

<p>However, conditions in hospitals compiling figures have worsened amid the fighting and many of those killed may not be identifiable due to their injuries.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/4e11d1u8_gaza-school-attack_625x300_09_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Palestinian Health Ministry says more than 70% of the dead are women and children. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-gaza-palestine-israeli-army-urges-everyone-in-gaza-city-to-leave-amid-offensive-6075223]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israeli Army Urges "Everyone In Gaza City" To Leave Amid Offensive]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-gaza-palestine-israeli-army-urges-everyone-in-gaza-city-to-leave-amid-offensive-6075223]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 10 Jul 2024 16:07:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Israeli army on Wednesday dropped thousand of leaflets on Gaza City urging all residents to leave amid an intensified military offensive on the Palestinian territory's main city, an AFP journalist said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p>

<p>The Israeli army on Wednesday dropped thousand of leaflets on Gaza City urging all residents to leave amid an intensified military offensive on the Palestinian territory's main city, an AFP journalist said.</p>

<p>The leaflets, addressed to "everyone in Gaza City", set out routes out of the city to designated safe areas further south and warned the urban area would "remain a dangerous combat zone" as the army hits Hamas targets.</p>

<p>Israel issued a first formal evacuation order for part of the city on June 27, and two more in following days.</p>

<p>In the leaflet drop, the army said residents would be able to take two safe roads "quickly and without inspection from Gaza City to shelters in Deir Al-Balah and Al-Zawiya".</p>

<p>Following the October 7 Hamas attacks, Israel said in January that it had "dismantled" the group's "military structure" in the northern city.</p>

<p>Tens of thousands more residents have already fled Gaza City since troops launched the latest offensive in the city's eastern Shujaiya district and ground battles have since raged.</p>

<p>The two latest orders covered central and western districts where tanks and troops have move in this week.</p>

<p>The army also said its forces had attacked operatives inside Gaza City's vacated headquarters of the UN agency for Palestinians, UNRWA.</p>

<p>Strikes have also hit Deir Al-Balah, an area where Palestinians have been urged to move to for safety.</p>

<p>The United Nations on Tuesday expressed alarm at Israel's evacuation orders, saying they tell Palestinians to go to zones where there is fighting.</p>

<p>The October 7 Hamas attack on southern Israel resulted in the deaths of 1,195 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli figures.</p>

<p>The operatives also seized 251 hostages, 116 of whom remain in Gaza, including 42 the military says are dead.</p>

<p>Israel's military offensive has killed at least 38,243 people in Gaza, also mostly civilians, according to figures released Tuesday by the Hamas-run territory's health ministry.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/2225v5kg_israel-army_625x300_10_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The October 7 Hamas attack on southern Israel resulted in the deaths of 1,195 people. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/relationship-of-trust-began-in-1950s-austrian-chancellor-on-ties-with-india-6075048]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bond Of Trust Began In 1950s: Austrian Chancellor On Ties With India]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/relationship-of-trust-began-in-1950s-austrian-chancellor-on-ties-with-india-6075048]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 10 Jul 2024 15:45:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[PM Modi Austria Visit: Praising the ties shared between Austria and India, Austrian Chancellor Karl Nehammer on Wednesday emphasised that it is a relationship of trust that began in the 1950s.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Praising the ties shared between Austria and India, Austrian Chancellor Karl Nehammer on Wednesday emphasised that it is a relationship of trust that began in the 1950s. He stated that it is the "concern over the development of the geopolitical situation" that united both nations.</p>

<p>Delivering his remarks at the joint press conference with Prime Minister Narendra Modi in Vienna, the Austrian Chancellor said, "There is a very good relationship between India and Austria. It's a relationship of trust which began in the 1950s...India helped Austria and in 1955, the negotiations came to a positive conclusion with the Austrian State Treaty."</p>

<p>"What unites India and Austria is concern over the development of the geopolitical situation," he underlined.</p>

<p>The Austrian Chancellor also highlighted his talks with PM Modi and stated that the two of them "had very intensive talks" about the aggression of Russia against Ukraine in the ongoing conflict.</p>

<p>"Last night and this morning, we had very intensive talks about the Russian war of aggression against Ukraine. For me, as the Federal Chancellor of Austria, it is particularly important to get to know India's assessment and to understand it and familiarise India with European concerns and worries," the Austrian Chancellor Karl said.</p>

<p>"Moreover, the conflict in the Middle East was a major topic and in addition to this challenging geopolitical situation, we also referred to the positive aspects of our cooperation..." he added.</p>

<p>Notably, this is the first time an Indian Prime Minister has visited Austria in 41 years. Indira Gandhi was the last PM to visit Austria in 1983.</p>

<p>PM Modi's visit to Austria comes after his two-day official visit to Russia, where he met Russian President Vladimir Putin. PM Modi arrived in Austria on Wednesday (local time).</p>

<p>Upon his arrival here, the Indian Prime Minister was welcomed by Austrian Foreign Minister Alexander Schallenberg. Indian Ambassador to Austria, Shambhu Kumaran was also present at the airport.</p>

<p>On Tuesday, PM Modi joined a dinner hosted by Austria Chancellor Karl Nehammer.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Welcome to Vienna, PM <a href="https://twitter.com/narendramodi?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@narendramodi</a> ! It is a pleasure and honour to welcome you to Austria. Austria and India are friends and partners. I look forward to our political and economic discussions during your visit! ?? ?? <a href="https://t.co/e2YJZR1PRs">pic.twitter.com/e2YJZR1PRs</a></p>
— Karl Nehammer (@karlnehammer) <a href="https://twitter.com/karlnehammer/status/1810769299696668774?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 9, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>In a post on X, Nehammar stated, "Welcome to Vienna, PM @narendramodi! It is a pleasure and honour to welcome you to Austria. Austria and India are friends and partners. I look forward to our political and economic discussions during your visit!"</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/n1oqtou8_pm-modi-in-austria_625x300_10_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[PM Modi's visit to Austria comes after his two-day official visit to Russia]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/india-to-remain-strategic-partner-despite-concerns-over-its-russia-ties-us-6074183]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India To Remain Strategic Partner Despite Concerns Over Its Russia Ties: US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/india-to-remain-strategic-partner-despite-concerns-over-its-russia-ties-us-6074183]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 10 Jul 2024 15:13:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India will continue to be a strategic partner for the US despite concerns over its ties with Russia, the Biden Administration has said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India will continue to be a strategic partner for the US despite concerns over its ties with Russia, the Biden Administration has said.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi was in Russia for two days for the 22nd India-Russia annual summit that has been watched closely by the West amidst the Ukraine conflict.</p>

<p>During his talks with President Putin on Tuesday, Prime Minister Modi told President Putin that a solution to the Ukraine conflict is not possible on the battlefield and peace efforts do not succeed amid bombs and bullets.</p>

<p>On Tuesday, spokespersons of the Pentagon and the State Department reacted separately to questions on India's relationship with Russia and PM Modi's visit to Moscow.</p>

<p>"India and Russia have had a relationship for a very long time. From a US perspective, India is a strategic partner with whom we continue to engage in full and frank dialogue to include their relationship with Russia. As it relates to the NATO summit being this week, of course, like you, the world is focused on that," Pentagon Press Secretary Major General Pat Ryder told reporters at a news conference.</p>

<p>On the other hand, US State Department Spokesperson Matthew Miller told reporters at his daily news conference that the US has been quite clear about its "concerns about India's relationship with Russia."</p>

<p>"We have expressed those privately directly to the Indian government, and continue to do so. And that has not changed," Mr Miller told reporters at his daily news conference.</p>

<p>India has been open its "special and privileged strategic partnership" with Russia and maintained the momentum in the ties.</p>

<p>India has not condemned Russia's invasion of Ukraine in 2022 but has consistently pitched for a resolution of the conflict through dialogue and diplomacy.</p>

<p>Maj Gen Ryder said: "I do not think anybody will be surprised if (Russian) President (Vladimir) Putin tries to represent this visit in a way that seeks to somehow show that he is not isolated from the rest of the world. And the fact of the matter is President Putin's war of choice has isolated Russia from the rest of the world, and it has come at great cost. Their war of aggression has come at great cost, and the facts bear that out," he said.</p>

<p>"So we will continue to view India as a strategic partner. We will continue to have a robust dialogue with them," Maj Gen Ryder said.</p>

<p>"He (Putin) is not looking so isolated with the head of the world's largest democracy being in Moscow, embracing him right now," a reporter asked.</p>

<p>Maj Gen Ryder responded by saying that Prime Minister Modi also met recently with the Ukrainian president Volodymyr Zelenskyy and offered his assurances that India will continue to do everything within its means to support a peaceful solution to the war in Ukraine.</p>

<p>"I think that we trust that India will support efforts to realise an enduring and just peace for Ukraine and will convey to Mr Putin the importance of adhering to the UN charter and the principles of sovereignty and territorial integrity," he added.</p>

<p>Mr Miller said the US continues to "urge India to support efforts to realise an enduring and just peace in Ukraine, based on the principles of the UN charter based on upholding Ukraine's territorial integrity and its sovereignty. And that will continue to be what we will engage with India about."<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-09/mu6n27j_modi-biden-delhi_650x400_08_September_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Biden Administration said today that "We will continue to view India as a strategic partner"]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/2-us-school-employees-arrested-for-allegedly-having-sex-with-students-6074654]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[2 US School Employees Arrested For Allegedly Having Sex With Students]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/2-us-school-employees-arrested-for-allegedly-having-sex-with-students-6074654]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 10 Jul 2024 14:55:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Greeson is accused of having sexual relations with two male students, while Shuler is accused of having sexual relations with one male student.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Two school employees in a Georgia school district have been accused of engaging in sexual relationships with students during 2021 and 2022.</p>

<p>Railey Greeson and Brooklyn Shuler were indicted in Gordon County, Georgia, on Thursday, June 28, on charges of sexual contact by an employee or agent in the first degree, as reported by<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.11alive.com/article/news/crime/two-calhoun-teachers-indicted-inappropriate-relations-with-students/85-65a6c42f-a17c-44fc-8bfc-6418fed0d8c6"><em> 11 Alive,</em></a> WSB TV, and FOX 5 Atlanta citing the indictment.</p>

<p>According to the indictment, Greeson is accused of having sexual relations with two male students, while Shuler is accused of having sexual relations with one male student between October 2021 and January 2022.</p>

<p>"I'm not trying to stereotype, but you could look at them and tell they were trouble," said Audrey Decker, whose stepdaughter attends the school.</p>

<p>"They just seemed boy-crazy. And everyone in the school knew it and joked about it."</p>

<p>Another parent agreed. "Ugh, they were flirts," said the mom of a sophomore.</p>

<p>"You should have seen them with any attractive parents who came to the school. They would flirt with any of the dads."</p>

<p>"You know: laughing too loud, getting too close, that type of thing," continued the mom.</p>

<p>"Flirting. Trying to be cute. They were shameless."</p>

<p>Greeson faces two counts of the offence, while Shuler has been indicted on one count, according to the indictment.</p>

<p>Although the indictment did not specify the school district involved, WSB TV identified it as the City of Calhoun School District.</p>

<p>According to reports from 11 Alive, FOX 5 Atlanta, and WSB TV, the ages of the students involved have not been disclosed. However, the indictment stated that the women "reasonably should have known" that the alleged victims were enrolled as students.</p>

<p>It remains unclear whether either of the suspects has entered pleas or retained attorneys to represent them.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/101dcrqo_brooklyn-shuler-and-railey-greeson_625x300_10_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Greeson faces two counts of the offence, while Shuler has been indicted on one count]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/massive-125-million-year-old-herbivorous-dinosaurs-fossil-found-in-england-6074585]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Massive 125-Million-Year-Old Herbivorous Dinosaur's Fossil Found In England]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/massive-125-million-year-old-herbivorous-dinosaurs-fossil-found-in-england-6074585]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 10 Jul 2024 14:48:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The fossil remains of a plant-eating dinosaur estimated to have roamed the earth some 125 million years ago have been discovered on England's Isle of Wight.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The fossil remains of a plant-eating dinosaur estimated to have roamed the earth some 125 million years ago have been discovered on England's Isle of Wight, with scientists believing it to be the most complete new specimen found in Britain in a century.</p>

<p>Weighing roughly the same as a large male American bison at about 900 kilogrammes (1990 lbs), the herbivorous species was likely a herding animal, Jeremy Lockwood, a PhD student at the University of Portsmouth who helped with the excavation, said in a statement.</p>

<p>The dinosaur, made up of 149 bones, was found in the cliffs of Compton Bay on the Isle of Wight, off the southern coast of England, in 2013 by late fossil collector Nick Chase.</p>

<p>It was named "Comptonatus chasei" as a tribute to Chase.</p>

<p>"Nick had a phenomenal nose for finding dinosaur bones ... This really is a remarkable find," Lockwood said.</p>

<p>"It helps us understand more about the different types of dinosaurs that lived in England in the Early Cretaceous," said Lockwood, also the lead author of a new paper describing the species published in the Journal of Systematic Palaeontology.</p>

<p>The remains of a meat-eating dinosaur belonging to an ancient predator bigger than anything known from the whole of Europe were discovered on the island in 2022. It was also from the Cretaceous Period.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/d8p9hp1o_dinosaur-fossil-_625x300_10_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The dinosaur, made up of 149 bones, was found in the cliffs of Compton Bay on the Isle of Wight.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/muchu-chhish-the-mountain-in-karakoram-range-that-was-never-climbed-summited-by-3-men-6074322]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Muchu Chhish, The Mountain That Was Never Climbed, Summited By 3 Men]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/muchu-chhish-the-mountain-in-karakoram-range-that-was-never-climbed-summited-by-3-men-6074322]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 10 Jul 2024 14:01:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Muchu Chhish, a 7,453-meter mountain in the Karakoram Range that was never climbed before, has finally been summited by three men, ExplorersWeb reported on Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Muchu Chhish, a 7,453-meter mountain in the Karakoram Range that was never climbed before, has finally been summited by three men, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://explorersweb.com/muchu-chhish-finally-summited/" target="_blank">ExplorersWeb</a> reported on Tuesday.</p>

<p>A Czech team of Zdenek Hak, Radoslav Groh, and Jaroslav Bansky took six days to climb the highest unclimbed peak in the world.</p>

<p>Climbers from the Czech Republic have reportedly tried to reach the summit thrice in the past four years and Groh was one of last year's members.</p>

<p>"We started on July 1 after the acclimatization. We climbed via the south ridge to the main ridge, and then we continued westward to the summit. We stood on top on July 5 at 10:20 am and took one more day for the descent. [We] finally re-entered Base Camp on July 6 at 6 pm," Zdenek Hak told ExplorersWeb, which covers environment adventure news online.</p>

<p>He said they climbed some 8-10 hours a day and made four bivouacs, a temporary camp without tents or cover used especially by mountaineers.</p>

<p>"The total length of the route from Base Camp was 20 km and 3,687 vertical meters. The length from Camp 1 to the top was 14.29 km, and the altitude gain was 2,300 m," Haq said.</p>

<p>The Czech climbers have previously tried to climb Muchu Chhish, which hides in Asia's Western Karakoram range, in 2020, 2022, 2023.</p>

<p>Last year, a team of Pavel Korinek, Pavel Bem, Radoslav Groh, and Tomas Petrecek nearly reached the summit before bad weather trapped them at 7,200 m at the bottom of a final rock pyramid.</p>

<p>They, however, retreated after running out of supplies and fuel.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/m0jvo8r8_muchu-chhish_625x300_10_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A Czech team of Zdenek Hak, Radoslav Groh, and Jaroslav Bansky took six days to climb Muchu Chhish]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/microsoft-and-apple-exit-observer-roles-on-openai-board-6073867]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Microsoft And Apple Exit Observer Roles On OpenAI Board]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/microsoft-and-apple-exit-observer-roles-on-openai-board-6073867]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 10 Jul 2024 13:50:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In a move reflecting shifting dynamics in the tech industry, both Microsoft and Apple have decided to relinquish their observer seats on the board of OpenAI, reported UK-based 'The Financial Times'.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a move reflecting shifting dynamics in the tech industry, both Microsoft and Apple have decided to relinquish their observer seats on the board of OpenAI, reported UK-based 'The Financial Times'. The move comes amidst reports of increased regulatory scrutiny over the involvement of tech giants in AI startups.</p>

<p>Microsoft, which had invested significantly in OpenAI, including a substantial USD 13 billion investment in its generative AI technology, ChatGPT, has announced its immediate withdrawal from its observer role on OpenAI's board.</p>

<p>The decision was communicated via a letter to OpenAI, citing the company's satisfaction with the progress made by the newly formed board.</p>

<p>Similarly, Apple, which was expected to take up a similar observer role as part of an agreement to integrate ChatGPT into its devices, has opted not to do so.</p>

<p>Although Apple declined to comment on the matter, sources familiar with the situation indicate that the tech giant will not be taking an observer position on OpenAI's board.</p>

<p>In response to these developments, OpenAI has announced a revised strategy for engaging with its strategic partners and investors.</p>

<p>According to the FT report, the organization plans to hold regular meetings with partners like Microsoft and Apple, along with investors such as Thrive Capital and Khosla Ventures.</p>

<p>This shift, as explained by an OpenAI spokesperson, aims to foster a more inclusive and collaborative approach to governance and strategic decision-making.</p>

<p>The board of OpenAI recently saw the addition of Phil Schiller, Apple's former marketing chief, as an observer, which was reported just days before these withdrawals.</p>

<p>However, Schiller will no longer be observing OpenAI's operations, highlighting the fluidity and perhaps underlying tensions within the organization's boardroom dynamics.</p>

<p>Analysts speculate that the decision by Microsoft and Apple to step back from their observer roles could be linked to strategic considerations or internal dynamics within OpenAI.</p>

<p>While some suggest possible concerns over antitrust scrutiny or strategic disagreements, the exact motivations behind these decisions remain unclear.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/10qmcdao_openai-afp_625x300_31_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Microsoft and Apple have exited the status of observer for OpenAI.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/man-in-china-tries-to-smuggle-over-100-live-snakes-in-his-trousers-6073882]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Chinese Man Tries To Smuggle Over 100 Live Snakes In His Trousers, Arrested]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/man-in-china-tries-to-smuggle-over-100-live-snakes-in-his-trousers-6073882]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 10 Jul 2024 12:54:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A man has been caught trying to smuggle over 100 live snakes into mainland China by cramming them into his trousers, according to the country's customs authority.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A man has been caught trying to smuggle over 100 live snakes into mainland China by cramming them into his trousers, according to the country's customs authority.</p>

<p>The unnamed traveller was stopped by customs officers as he sought to slip out of semi-autonomous Hong Kong and into the border city of Shenzhen, China Customs said in a statement on Tuesday.</p>

<p>"Upon inspection, customs officers discovered that the pockets of the trousers the passenger was wearing were packed with six canvas drawstring bags and sealed with tape," the statement said.</p>

<p>"Once opened, each bag was found to contain living snakes in all kinds of shapes, sizes and colours," it added.</p>

<p>The statement said officers seized 104 of the scaly reptiles, including milk snakes and corn snakes, many of which were non-native species.</p>

<p>An accompanying video showed two border agents peering into transparent plastic bags filled with squirming red, pink and white snakes.</p>

<p>China is one of the world's biggest animal trafficking hubs, but authorities have cracked down on the illicit trade in recent years.</p>

<p>The country's biosecurity and disease control laws forbid people from bringing in non-native species without permission.</p>

<p>"Those who break the rules will be... held liable in accordance with the law," the customs authority said, without specifying the man's punishment.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2019-08/rdmgnvu_snake-generic-pixabay_625x300_14_August_19.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[China is one of the world's biggest animal trafficking hubs (representational).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-attacks-kamala-harris-questions-her-competence-6073040]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump Attacks Kamala Harris, Questions Her Competence]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-attacks-kamala-harris-questions-her-competence-6073040]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 10 Jul 2024 12:37:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump, the former US president and presumptive presidential nominee of the Republican Party, attacked Vice President Kamala Harris, raising questions on her competence and describing her as an "insurance policy" for President Joe Biden.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump, the former US president and presumptive presidential nominee of the Republican Party, has attacked Vice President Kamala Harris, raising questions on her competence and describing her as an "insurance policy" for incumbent President Joe Biden.</p>

<p>His attack against Kamala Harris, who is of Indian and African heritage, came amid chatter in the Democratic Party about whether President Biden should remain the nominee in the November 5 presidential election.</p>

<p>Joe Biden, 81, has faced calls from some Democrats to step aside as the nominee following his disastrous performance during a June 27 debate with Trump in which he struggled to complete sentences or land any significant blows against his opponent.</p>

<p>"Whatever else can be said about crooked Joe Biden, you have to give him credit for one brilliant decision, probably the smartest decision he ever made. He picked Kamala Harris as his vice president. No, it was brilliant. Because it was an insurance policy. Maybe the best insurance policy I've ever seen," Donald Trump, 78, told his supporters in Florida.</p>

<p>"If Joe had picked someone even halfway competent, they would have bounced him from office years ago, but they can't because she's gotta be their second choice," he said as he repeatedly mispronounced her name.</p>

<p>Trump said as vice president, Harris was given two very important tasks - border security and to deter Russia from attacking Ukraine.</p>

<p>"First, she was put in charge of the U.S. border security. She never showed up. She's never gone. She never went there once. And the border is the worst border in the history of the world," he alleged.</p>

<p>"We have the best border in history because she has the worst border in the history of the world. Then, she was sent to Europe to deter Russia from attacking Ukraine. How did that work out? Not too good. Both times, the result was a deadly failure. Since Kamala was made border czar, the Biden-Harris administration has lost track of an estimated 150,000 children, many of whom have undoubtedly been raped, trafficked, killed, or horribly abused," Trump said.</p>

<p>Trump accused Harris, 59, of being a socialist.</p>

<p>"I don't think Kamala Harris' California socialism is going to go down well with the people of Doral, the people of Miami, or the people of Florida. Because in Florida, we don't like socialism. We want our freedom, right? We want our freedom," he said.</p>

<p>"Joe, Kamala and the entire Democrat establishment have been caught red-handed in the thick of the biggest scandal and the biggest coverup…it's a cover-up. It's the biggest cover-up in political history. As you know, they are all co-conspirators in the sinister plot to defraud the American public about the cognitive abilities of the man in the Oval Office," alleged Trump.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/t1djlno_kamala-harris-ians_625x300_10_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump has questioned the competence of US Vice Presdent Kamala Harris.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-to-serve-full-second-term-if-re-elected-white-house-6073724]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Joe Biden To Serve Full Second Term If Re-Elected: White House]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-to-serve-full-second-term-if-re-elected-white-house-6073724]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 10 Jul 2024 12:32:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden is committed to serving a full second term if reelected in November, the White House said Tuesday, as the 81-year-old fights for political survival as concerns mount over his age and fitness.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden is committed to serving a full second term if reelected in November, the White House said Tuesday, as the 81-year-old fights for political survival as concerns mount over his age and fitness.</p>

<p>"Yes," White House press secretary Karine Jean-Pierre said when asked during a daily briefing if the Democrat pledged to serve another four years should he beat Donald Trump in the 2024 election.</p>

<p>The spokeswoman said she believed Democrats were now "absolutely" united behind Biden, as the party's lawmakers held critical talks on whether he should step aside as candidate in November.</p>

<p>"We do want to turn the page... We want to get to the other side of this," Jean-Pierre said when asked if Biden now believed the crisis was behind him.</p>

<p>"He wants to move forward, unite the party," she said. "The president's going to move forward."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/gbfd0cv8_joe-biden_625x300_07_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Joe Biden, 81, is fighting for political survival as concerns mount over his age]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/look-up-a-once-in-a-lifetime-explosion-is-about-to-create-a-new-star-in-the-sky-6073593]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Look Up! A Once-In-A-Lifetime Explosion Is About To Create A 'New' Star]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/look-up-a-once-in-a-lifetime-explosion-is-about-to-create-a-new-star-in-the-sky-6073593]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 10 Jul 2024 12:10:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Any night now, a "new star" or nova will appear in the night sky. While it wont set the sky ablaze, its a special opportunity to see a rare event thats usually difficult to predict in advance.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Any night now, a “new star” or nova will appear in the night sky. While it won't set the sky ablaze, it's a special opportunity to see a rare event that's usually difficult to predict in advance.</p>

<p>The star in question is T Coronae Borealis (<a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2308.13668">T CrB</a>, pronounced “T Cor Bor”). It lies in the constellation of the <a href="https://earthsky.org/tonight/corona-borealis-the-northern-crown-2/">northern crown</a>, prominent in the Northern Hemisphere but also visible in the northern sky from Australia and Aotearoa New Zealand over the next few months.</p>

<p>Most of the time T CrB, which is 3,000 light years away, is much too faint to be seen. But once every 80 years or so, it brightly erupts.</p>

<p>A brand new star suddenly seems to appear, although not for long. Just a few nights later it will have rapidly faded, disappearing back into the darkness.</p>

<h2>A burst of life</h2>

<p>During the prime of their lives, stars are powered by nuclear fusion reactions deep inside their cores. Most commonly, hydrogen is turned into helium creating enough energy to keep the star stable and shining for billions of years.</p>

<p>But T CrB is well past its prime and is now a stellar remnant known as a <a href="https://esahubble.org/wordbank/white-dwarf/">white dwarf</a>. Its internal nuclear fire has been quenched, allowing gravity to dramatically compress the dead star.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="A white dwarf is about the same size as Earth but around 300,000 times more massive, generating a mighty gravitational field. ESA/NASA." id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/0up7bk4o_white-dwarf-esanasa_625x300_10_July_24.jpg" title="A white dwarf is about the same size as Earth but around 300,000 times more massive, generating a mighty gravitational field. ESA/NASA." /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">A white dwarf is about the same size as Earth but around 300,000 times more massive, generating a mighty gravitational field. ESA/NASA.</p>
</div>

<p>T CrB also has a stellar companion – a red giant that has puffed up as it enters old age. The white dwarf mops up the swollen red giant's gas, and this forms what's known as an accretion disc around the dead star.</p>

<p>The matter keeps piling up on a star that's already compressed to its limit, forcing a continual rise in pressure and temperature. Conditions become so extreme, they mimic what once would've been found inside the star's core. Its surface ignites in a runaway thermonuclear reaction.</p>

<p>When this happens, the energy released makes T CrB shine 1,500 times brighter than usual. Here on Earth, it briefly appears in the night sky. With this dramatic reset, the star has then expelled the gas and the cycle can begin all over again.</p>

<figure><iframe allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="400" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/CIRx5F6lfJI?wmode=transparent&amp;start=0" width="650"></iframe>

<figcaption><span class="caption">Animation of a nova erupting as thermonuclear reactions ignite on the smaller white dwarf star. Credit: NASA/Conceptual Image Lab/Goddard Space Flight Center.</span></figcaption>
</figure>

<h2>How do we know it's due?</h2>

<p>T CrB is the brightest of a rare class of <a href="https://adsabs.harvard.edu/full/2013IAUS..281..154A">recurrent novae</a> that repeat within a hundred years – a time scale that allows astronomers to detect their recurrent nature.</p>

<p>Only ten recurrent novae are currently known, although more novae may be recurrent – just on much greater timescales that aren't as easily tracked.</p>

<p>The earliest known date of T CrB erupting is from the year 1217, based on observations recorded in a <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2308.13668">medieval monastic chronicle</a>. It's remarkable that astronomers can now predict its eruptions so precisely as long as the nova follows its usual pattern.</p>

<p>The star's two most recent eruptions – in 1866 and 1946 – showed the exact same features. About ten years prior to the eruption, T CrB's brightness increased a little (known as a high state) followed by a short fading or dip about a year out from the explosion.</p>

<p>T CrB entered its high state in 2015 and the pre-eruption dip was spotted in March 2023, setting astronomers on alert. What causes these phenomena are just some of the current mysteries surrounding T CrB.</p>

<h2>How can I see it?</h2>

<p>Start stargazing now! It's a good idea to get used to seeing <a href="https://earthsky.org/tonight/corona-borealis-the-northern-crown-2/">Corona Borealis</a> as it is now, so that you get the full impact of the “new” star.</p>

<p>Corona Borealis currently reaches its best observing position (known as a <a href="https://astronomy.swin.edu.au/cosmos/M/Meridian+Transit">meridian transit</a>) around 8:30pm to 9pm local time across Australia and Aotearoa. The farther north you are located, the higher the constellation will be in the sky.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="The farther north you are located, the higher Corona Borealis will appear in the northern sky. The new star will be about as bright as Alphecca in Corona Borealis or the nearby Rasalhague in Ophiuchus. Museums Victoria/Stellarium." id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/es2c95g4_the-conversation-story_625x300_10_July_24.jpg" title="The farther north you are located, the higher Corona Borealis will appear in the northern sky. The new star will be about as bright as Alphecca in Corona Borealis or the nearby Rasalhague in Ophiuchus. Museums Victoria/Stellarium." /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">The farther north you are located, the higher Corona Borealis will appear in the northern sky. The new star will be about as bright as Alphecca in Corona Borealis or the nearby Rasalhague in Ophiuchus. Museums Victoria/Stellarium.</p>
</div>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Whereas down south in Hobart, Corona Borealis stays low in the north. The bright star Arcturus acts as a good guide. Museums Victoria/Stellarium." id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/pnhnkvms_the-conversation-story_625x300_10_July_24.jpg" title="Whereas down south in Hobart, Corona Borealis stays low in the north. The bright star Arcturus acts as a good guide. Museums Victoria/Stellarium." /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">Whereas down south in Hobart, Corona Borealis stays low in the north. The bright star Arcturus acts as a good guide. Museums Victoria/Stellarium.</p>
</div>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Across Aotearoa, T CrB is best seen around 9pm throughout July. Additional constellations are shown for reference. Museums Victoria/Stellarium." id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/qucnph3k_the-conversation-story_625x300_10_July_24.jpg" title="Across Aotearoa, T CrB is best seen around 9pm throughout July. Additional constellations are shown for reference. Museums Victoria/Stellarium." /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">Across Aotearoa, T CrB is best seen around 9pm throughout July. Additional constellations are shown for reference. Museums Victoria/Stellarium.</p>
</div>

<p>The nova is expected to be a reasonable brightness (magnitude 2.5): about as bright as Imai (<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Delta_Crucis">Delta Crucis</a>), the fourth brightest star in the <a href="https://earthsky.org/constellations/crux-the-southern-cross-jewel-box/">Southern Cross</a>. So it will be easy to see even from a city location, if you know where to look.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="During July evenings, the Southern Crux can be found on its side, high in the southwest from Australia and Aotearoa. Museums Victoria/Stellarium." id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/hj72dcec_the-conversation-story_625x300_10_July_24.jpg" title="During July evenings, the Southern Crux can be found on its side, high in the southwest from Australia and Aotearoa. Museums Victoria/Stellarium." /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">During July evenings, the Southern Crux can be found on its side, high in the southwest from Australia and Aotearoa. Museums Victoria/Stellarium.</p>
</div>

<h2>We won't have much time</h2>

<p>We won't have long once it goes off. The maximum brightness will only last a few hours; within a week T CrB will have faded and you'll need binoculars to see it.</p>

<p>It almost certainly will be an amateur astronomer that alerts the professional community to the moment when T CrB outbursts.</p>

<p>These dedicated and knowledgeable people routinely monitor stars from their backyards on the chance of “what if” and therefore fill an important gap in night sky observations.</p>

<p>The American Association of Variable Star Observing (<a href="https://www.aavso.org/">AAVSO</a>) has a log of over 270,000 submitted observations on T CrB alone. Amateur astronomers are collaborating here and around the world to continually monitor T CrB for the first signs of eruption.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="By September, Corona Borealis will be moving lower into the northwest sky and best seen between 7:30pm to 8pm local time. Museums Victoria/Stellarium." id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/nl58ncag_the-conversation-story_625x300_10_July_24.jpg" title="By September, Corona Borealis will be moving lower into the northwest sky and best seen between 7:30pm to 8pm local time. Museums Victoria/Stellarium." /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">By September, Corona Borealis will be moving lower into the northwest sky and best seen between 7:30pm to 8pm local time. Museums Victoria/Stellarium.</p>
</div>

<p>Hopefully the nova will erupt as expected sometime before October, because after that Corona Borealis leaves our evening sky in the Southern Hemisphere.<!-- Below is The Conversation's page counter tag. Please DO NOT REMOVE. --><img alt="The Conversation" height="1" referrerpolicy="no-referrer-when-downgrade" src="https://counter.theconversation.com/content/233884/count.gif?distributor=republish-lightbox-basic" style="border: none !important; box-shadow: none !important; margin: 0 !important; max-height: 1px !important; max-width: 1px !important; min-height: 1px !important; min-width: 1px !important; opacity: 0 !important; outline: none !important; padding: 0 !important" width="1" /><!-- End of code. If you don't see any code above, please get new code from the Advanced tab after you click the republish button. The page counter does not collect any personal data. More info: https://theconversation.com/republishing-guidelines --></p>

<p><em><span>(<strong>Authors:</strong> <a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/tanya-hill-121214">Tanya Hill</a>, Senior Curator (Astronomy), Museums Victoria and Honorary Fellow at University of Melbourne, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/museums-victoria-research-institute-1116">Museums Victoria Research Institute</a> and <a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/amanda-karakas-1545654">Amanda Karakas</a>, Associate Professor, School of Physics and Astronomy, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/monash-university-1065">Monash University</a></span>)</em></p>

<p><em>(<strong>Disclosure Statement:</strong> Amanda Karakas receives funding from the Australian Research Council. Tanya Hill does not work for, consult, own shares in or receive funding from any company or organisation that would benefit from this article, and has disclosed no relevant affiliations beyond their academic appointment)</em></p>

<p><em>This article is republished from <a href="https://theconversation.com">The Conversation</a> under a Creative Commons license. Read the <a href="https://theconversation.com/look-up-a-once-in-a-lifetime-explosion-is-about-to-create-a-new-star-in-the-sky-233884">original article</a>.</em><br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/mgv141bg_the-conversation-story_625x300_10_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Stellarium Web Online Star Map.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/playground-fights-to-white-house-bids-a-look-at-stubborn-joe-bidens-life-6073283]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Playground Fights To White House Bids, A Look At "Stubborn" Biden's Life]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/playground-fights-to-white-house-bids-a-look-at-stubborn-joe-bidens-life-6073283]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 10 Jul 2024 11:22:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Anyone expecting Joe Biden to step aside from the US presidential race without a fight had not fully considered the life story of a proud but often stubborn man.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Anyone expecting Joe Biden to step aside from the US presidential race without a fight had not fully considered the life story of a proud but often stubborn man.</p>

<p>From playground punch-ups to terrible tragedies and multiple White House bids, Biden has long seen his life as a series of comebacks against impossible odds.</p>

<p>And as a Democratic revolt over his debate debacle against Donald Trump appears to sputter for now, the 81-year-old seems determined to win the fight of his political life.</p>

<p>Unless a major shift occurs, it will likely fall to US voters to decide whether Biden stages another turnup for the books -- or whether hubris condemns him and his party to a historic defeat by Trump.</p>

<p>Biden has repeatedly returned to the image of himself as an underdog since the debate, repeating his family's mantra that "when you get knocked down, you get back up."</p>

<p>"What we've seen the last 10 to 12 days is certainly fundamental to the Joe Biden story," his spokeswoman Karine Jean-Pierre said from the White House podium on Tuesday.</p>

<p>"He is someone that is certainly counted out many, many times in his career. People tend to knock him down, and you hear him say he gets back up.</p>

<p>"This is the story of him standing up for himself, standing up for millions of Americans."</p>

<h3><strong>'Punch the guy'&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>That outlook was formed by a hardscrabble childhood in the American rust-belt, as part of a close-knit Irish Catholic family known for its intense pride.</p>

<p>His mother Jean told the young Joey and his siblings every day that "nobody was better than a Biden," Ben Cramer wrote in his book "What It Takes," about the 1988 US election campaign.</p>

<p>He was also known for never backing down.</p>

<p>"Most guys who got into a fight, they'd square off... Joey didn't do that," Cramer wrote. "He decided to fight... BANGO -- he'd punch the guy in the face."</p>

<p>One affliction Biden famously had to battle was a childhood stutter.</p>

<p>Repeatedly humiliated at school, the young Biden ended up teaching himself how to speak smoothly by sheer determination, repeating phrases again and again into the mirror.</p>

<p>But Biden's biggest test was yet to come.</p>

<p>In 1972, he was only 29 and had just been elected senator for Delaware when his wife Neilia and their one-year-old daughter Naomi were killed in a car crash, while their young sons Beau and Hunter were left badly injured.</p>

<p>Tragedy struck again in 2015 when Beau died of brain cancer aged 46.</p>

<p>Biden also had to deal with the agony of Hunter's severe drug addiction and legal problems.</p>

<p>"Sometimes I marvel at Joe's strength. His life has been marked by cruel losses," First Lady Jill Biden, whom Biden married in 1977, said in her memoir "Where the Light Enters."</p>

<p><strong>'Psychological prison'&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p>With his family close around him, Biden has also ridden out a series of political humiliations.</p>

<p>In 1988 he was forced to abandon his first presidential bid following a plagiarism scandal.</p>

<p>His next bid in 2008 ended in heavy defeat in the Democratic primaries, before Barack Obama picked him as his running mate.</p>

<p>Yet in the current crisis over Biden's age and health, the very things that have previously brought Biden strength could also bring about his downfall.</p>

<p>It's common knowledge that he will only really listen to family members and a few aides he's known for decades, but as he ages that bubble has become increasingly insular.</p>

<p>His long-standing belief that he's been underestimated and mocked by the media means he's even less likely to listen to outside voices.</p>

<p>Moreover, Biden's lifelong image as someone who always bounces back means he may not be able to envisage a graceful exit this time around.</p>

<p>Franklin Foer, author of a book on the early Biden presidency, wrote recently in The Atlantic magazine that "humiliation -- and its transcendence -- is Biden's origin story."</p>

<p>"Right now it is his psychological prison, a mental habit that might doom American democracy."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/f6nmtplg_joe-biden-file-afp_625x300_17_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Joe Biden's lifelong image has been as someone who always bounces back.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-mass-shooter-nikolas-cruz-agrees-to-donate-brain-to-science-in-unique-settlement-6073237]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Mass Shooter Agrees To Donate Brain To Science In Unique Settlement]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-mass-shooter-nikolas-cruz-agrees-to-donate-brain-to-science-in-unique-settlement-6073237]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 10 Jul 2024 11:14:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The unusual condition was proposed by an attorney representing Anthony Borges, 21, who was shot five times during the attack.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Nikolas Cruz, the Florida mass shooter, has agreed to donate his brain to science as part of a "unique" civil settlement with one of his victims, according to court documents and experts. Cruz used an AR-15 assault rifle to kill 17 students and staff members at Marjory Stoneman Douglas High School in Parkland on February 14, 2018, one of the deadliest mass shootings in U.S. history.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The unusual condition was proposed by an attorney representing Anthony Borges, 21, who was shot five times during the attack, the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/07/09/us-news/parkland-shooter-nikolas-cruz-agrees-to-donate-his-brain-to-science-in-shocking-settlement/"><em>New York Post</em></a> reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"I figured if scientists studied his brain they might be able to figure out what created this monster," Borges' lawyer, Alex Arreaza, told<em> Fox News Digital.</em> "Maybe there was some kind of imbalance that caused this that we can prevent in the future."</p>

<p>Scott Herndon, a Berkeley-based attorney who has represented victims of mass shootings, described the settlement as unprecedented.</p>

<p>"I've never heard of anything like this before. It's pretty unique," he told Fox News Digital. "It underscores the feeling of those left behind that whatever can be done to avoid these massacres in the future should be done."</p>

<p>The new settlement agreement also grants Borges the right to use Cruz's name in movies, books, and other media. The 25-year-old murderer, currently serving a life sentence, is prohibited from profiting from his crime and must obtain Borges' permission before participating in any interviews.</p>

<p>"We didn't want him to be able to continue torturing the families," said Arreaza, referencing O.J. Simpson's book "If I Did It" as a cautionary tale.</p>

<p>Herndon mentioned that it is not unusual for a perpetrator to give up the rights to their name as part of a settlement. The agreement was finalized during a Zoom meeting involving Borges' father, Rory Borges, Cruz, and Arreaza. Anthony Borges, who is dealing with PTSD, did not feel comfortable participating in the discussions, according to Arreaza.</p>

<p>"You could see what a psychopath he is," Arreaza noted. "He looked at Rory when we were all done and asked if he could apologize, and Nikolas apologized to him like they had been in a car accident together. It was just very cold and weird."</p>

<p>At 15, Borges was among the 17 victims who narrowly survived the brutal attack. He used his body to barricade a door, preventing Cruz from entering the classroom where he and other terrified students were hiding.</p>

<p>The former promising soccer player sustained severe injuries to his legs and torso, requiring over a dozen surgeries.</p>

<p>The settlement also allocates $430,000 to Anthony Borges, which Cruz is expected to receive from a relative's life insurance policy.</p>

<p>Previously, the Broward County Public School District paid $26 million to the victims of the shooting, with $1.25 million going to Borges. Additionally, Borges received an undisclosed settlement from the FBI for their failure to prevent Cruz's rampage.</p>

<p>Borges, along with other victims, has pending lawsuits against School Resource Officer Scot Peterson and the Broward County Sheriff's Office, the New York Post reported.</p>

<p>The shooting continues to haunt the young man, who's happy the site of the massacre is being torn down. "Every time he drove by there, it brought back memories," Arreaza told the media outlet.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/2i15ph4o_nikolas-cruz_625x300_10_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Cruz used an AR-15 assault rifle to kill 17 students and staff members]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/miss-universe-singapore-now-open-for-mothers-married-divorced-women-6072972]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Miss Universe Singapore Now Open For Mothers, Married, Divorced Women]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/miss-universe-singapore-now-open-for-mothers-married-divorced-women-6072972]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 10 Jul 2024 10:35:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Miss Universe Singapore beauty pageant is now open to all Singaporean women above 18 years of age, irrespective of their marital status. The upper age limit has  also been removed by the organization.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Miss Universe Singapore beauty pageant is now open to all Singaporean women above 18 years of age, irrespective of their marital status. The upper age limit has also been removed by the organization, making the renowned beauty pageant more inclusive than before.</p>

<p>By introducing the latest changes in eligibility criteria in terms of marital status, Miss Universe Singapore is also breaking free from the idea that only certain codes of conventional femininity is entertained and encouraged in beauty pageants across the world.</p>

<p>Miss Universe Malaysia 2003, and Miss Universe Singapore's national director Ms. Elaine Daly said in a statement: "This competition is more than just a crown. It's a platform to inspire and advocate for causes close to your heart."</p>

<p>Their latest Instagram post reads, "Calling all ambitious, intelligent and confidently beautiful women of Singapore!"</p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/C9LzSLavGu4/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C9LzSLavGu4/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C9LzSLavGu4/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C9LzSLavGu4/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by Miss Universe Singapore (@missuniversesingapore.official)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p>According to the specifications on their official website, any legally recognized adult female who has been residing in Singapore for at least six months before September 1, 2024, can apply for the competition.</p>

<p>The contest is now open to women who are either single, or married, or even divorced, or with children.</p>

<p>Miss Universe 2023 was open to women aged between 18 and 28 who were single and unmarried, irrespective of any specific height requirements. This time, however, a height criterion has been introduced among the other changes, which makes only women at least 168cm in height or above eligible for the pageant.</p>

<p>Miss Universe Singapore 2024 is organised by Beyond Entity, a Malaysian company, in collaboration with King Kong Media Production, headed by Singaporean actor Mark Lee.</p>

<p>The winner will get to represent Singapore on the international stage of the Miss Universe pageant to be held in Mexico in September. She will also be receiving $10,000 as a prize.</p>

<p>Entrepreneur Priyanka Annuncia was crowned Miss Universe Singapore last year.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/2qb3q46o_miss-universe-singapore-crown-instagram_625x300_10_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Miss Universe Singapore is now more inclusive than before with its reformed eligibility criteria.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/make-no-mistake-russia-failing-in-ukraine-war-joe-biden-slams-vladimir-putin-6072234]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Make No Mistake, Russia Failing In This War": Biden Slams Putin]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/make-no-mistake-russia-failing-in-ukraine-war-joe-biden-slams-vladimir-putin-6072234]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 10 Jul 2024 07:57:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden on Tuesday announced a historic donation of air-defence equipment for Ukraine and said Russia is failing in this war.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden on Tuesday announced a historic donation of air-defence equipment for Ukraine and said Russia is failing in this war.</p>

<p>Welcoming leaders of NATO member countries for the historic summit on the occasion of its 75th anniversary, Biden said the United States, Germany, the Netherlands, Romania and Italy will provide Ukraine with the equipment for five additional strategic air-defence systems.</p>

<p>In the coming months, the US and its partners intend to provide Ukraine with dozens of additional tactical air-defence systems, he said, adding that the US will make sure that when "we export critical air-defence interceptors, Ukraine goes to the front of the line".</p>

<p>"They will get this assistance before anyone else gets it. All told, Ukraine will receive hundreds of additional interceptors over the next year, helping protect Ukrainian cities against Russian missile and Ukrainian troops facing air attacks on their front lines," Biden said.</p>

<p>"Make no mistake, Russia is failing in this war.&nbsp; More than two years into (Russian President Vladimir) Putin's war of choice, his losses are staggering. More than 350,000 Russian troops dead or wounded, nearly one million (10 lakh) Russians, many of them young people, have left Russia because they no longer see a future in Russia," he said.</p>

<p>"Kiev, remember fellas and ladies, was supposed to fall in five days? Remember? Well, it is still standing two and a half years later and will continue to stand. All of the allies knew that before this war, Putin thought NATO would break. Today, NATO is stronger than it has ever been in its history. When this senseless war began, Ukraine was a free country. Today, it is still a free country," the US president said.</p>

<p>Reiterating that Putin's war of aggression against Ukraine continues, he said the Russian president wants nothing less than Ukraine's total subjugation to end that country's democracy, to destroy its culture and to wipe it off the map.</p>

<p>"We know Putin will not stop at Ukraine, but make no mistake, Ukraine can and will stop Putin," Biden said.</p>

<p>He said the war will end with Ukraine remaining a free and independent country. "Russia will not prevail. Ukraine will prevail. Ladies and gentlemen, this is a pivotal moment for Europe, for the transatlantic community and I might add, for the world. Let us remember, the fact that NATO remains the bulwark of global security did not happen by accident," he said.</p>

<p>"NATO is stronger, smarter and more energised than when you began. And a billion people across Europe or North America, indeed the whole world, will reap the rewards of your labour for years to come in the form of security, opportunity and greater freedom," the president said.</p>

<p>In his remarks, NATO Secretary General Jens Stoltenberg said there are no cost-free options with an aggressive Russia as a neighbour.</p>

<p>"There are no risk-free options in a war. And remember -- the biggest cost and the greatest risk will be if Russia wins in Ukraine. We cannot let that happen. Not only would it embolden President Putin, it would also embolden other authoritarian leaders in Iran, North Korea and China," he said.</p>

<p>He acknowledged that NATO's enduring success has never been a given, but is rather "the result of deliberate choices and difficult decisions" -- from the alliance's creation to arms control negotiations, and from NATO's enlargement at the end of the Cold War to its support to Ukraine today.</p>

<p>"The time to stand for freedom and democracy is now, the place is Ukraine," he said.</p>

<p>Stoltenberg concluded by saying that the alliance will continue to face difficult questions in the future, but that "we are stronger and safer together in NATO".</p>

<p>Biden presented Stoltenberg with the Presidential Medal of Freedom, the United States' highest civilian honour, in recognition of his decade of service at the helm of the alliance.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/o44j52qo_joe-biden_625x300_03_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["Ukraine can and will stop Putin," US President Joe Biden said.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/days-after-india-visit-bangladesh-pm-sheikh-hasina-in-china-to-hold-talks-with-xi-jinping-li-qiang-6072228]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Days After India Visit, Bangladesh PM In China To Hold Talks With Xi Jinping]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/days-after-india-visit-bangladesh-pm-sheikh-hasina-in-china-to-hold-talks-with-xi-jinping-li-qiang-6072228]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 10 Jul 2024 07:54:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Bangladesh Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina arrived here on Tuesday on a four-day visit for talks with China's top leadership, including President Xi Jinping and Premier Li Qiang to further cement the bilateral strategic ties.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bangladesh Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina arrived here on Tuesday on a four-day visit for talks with China's top leadership, including President Xi Jinping and Premier Li Qiang to further cement the bilateral strategic ties.</p>

<p>In her separate meetings with Xi and Li on Wednesday, the entire gamut of the bilateral relations alongside the regional and international matters will come for discussion, the official BSS news agency reported.</p>

<p>This visit of the Bangladesh premier to China is taking place within 15 days after her last visit to India from June 21 to 22, the Bangladeshi news agency reported.</p>

<p>Hasina had her last discussions with President Xi in a recent meeting on the sidelines of the 15th BRICS Summit in Johannesburg, South Africa.</p>

<p>Hasina will also hold a delegation-level bilateral meeting with her Chinese counterpart Li Qiang at the Great Hall of the People. Following the meeting, Bangladesh and China are likely to sign and renew 20 to 22 Memorandums of Understanding (MoUs), the report said.</p>

<p>"The MoUs on cooperation in the economic and banking sector, trade and investment, digital economy, infrastructure development, assistance in disaster management, construction of 6th and 9th Bangladesh-China friendship bridges, export of agricultural products from Bangladesh and people to people connectivity are likely to be signed," Foreign Minister Dr Hasan Mahmud said on Sunday at a curtain raiser press conference at the Foreign Ministry in Bangladesh.</p>

<p>During the visit, Dr Hasan said the inauguration of several projects of the two countries will also be announced.</p>

<p>The issues like Rohingya, and cooperation on business, trade, commerce and development will dominate the discussions.</p>

<p>This is Hasina's fourth visit to China and the trip is expected to elevate the relations between Bangladesh and China to "comprehensive strategic cooperative partnership" from "strategic partnership", the report said.</p>

<p>The two countries would celebrate the golden jubilee of their diplomatic relations next year.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, China's top political advisor Wang Huning met with Prime Minister Hasina on Tuesday in Beijing.</p>

<p>Wang, chairman of the National Committee of the Chinese People's Political Consultative Conference (CPPCC), said that under the strategic guidance of the two countries' leaders, China and Bangladesh have respected and treated each other with equality, setting a good example of friendly coexistence and mutually beneficial cooperation between countries.</p>

<p>China is ready to deepen practical cooperation with Bangladesh in various fields, and push the strategic cooperative partnership between the two countries to a new height, to better benefit the two peoples, Wang was quoted as saying by the official Xinhua news agency.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/hn6ntrho_sheikh-hasina-_625x300_10_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Bangladesh and China are likely to sign and renew 20 to 22 MoUs]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-not-competent-kamala-harris-would-be-disaster-for-america-nikki-haley-praises-donald-trump-6072192]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Biden Not Competent, Kamala Harris Would Be Disaster For US": Nikki Haley]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-not-competent-kamala-harris-would-be-disaster-for-america-nikki-haley-praises-donald-trump-6072192]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 10 Jul 2024 07:46:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Indian American Republican leader Nikki Haley also released the several dozen delegates she had won during the party's presidential primaries early this year for the presumptive nominee, Donald Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Indian American Republican leader Nikki Haley on Tuesday released the several dozen delegates she had won during the party's presidential primaries early this year for the presumptive nominee, Donald Trump.</p>

<p>The move by Haley comes ahead of the Republican National Convention (RNC) in Milwaukee, Wisconsin wherein Trump would formally be nominated as the party's presidential candidate for the November 5 general election.</p>

<p>"The nominating convention is a time for Republican unity. Joe Biden is not competent to serve a second term and Kamala Harris would be a disaster for America. We need a president who will hold our enemies to account, secure our border, cut our debt and get our economy back on track. I encourage my delegates to support Donald Trump next week in Milwaukee," Haley said in a statement.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">The nominating convention is a time for Republican unity. Joe Biden is not competent to serve a second term and Kamala Harris would be a disaster for America. We need a president who will hold our enemies to account, secure our border, cut our debt, and get our economy back on…</p>
— Nikki Haley (@NikkiHaley) <a href="https://twitter.com/NikkiHaley/status/1810803750908613015?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 9, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Haley had won 97 delegates, as against Biden's 2,265. A candidate needs 1,215 delegates to win the GOP's presidential nomination. She had suspended her campaign in March.</p>

<p>The former US ambassador to the United Nations and South Carolina governor is not attending the RNC.</p>

<p>"She was not invited and she is fine with that. Trump deserves the convention he wants. She has made it clear she is voting for him and wishes him the best," Haley's spokesperson Chaney Denton said.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/4sen0cuo_nikki-haley_625x300_10_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[File photo]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-ukraine-war-how-doctors-at-ukraine-hospital-saved-5-month-old-baby-during-russian-airstrike-6072191]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How Doctors Saved 5-Month-Old Baby During Airstrike At Ukraine Hospital]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-ukraine-war-how-doctors-at-ukraine-hospital-saved-5-month-old-baby-during-russian-airstrike-6072191]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 10 Jul 2024 07:46:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Oleh Holubchenko's team was in the middle of surgery on five-month-old Taras when an explosive wave sent the medics flying across the room.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Oleh Holubchenko's team was in the middle of surgery on five-month-old Taras when an explosive wave sent the medics flying across the room.</p>

<p>Shards of glass tore into Holubchenko's back and his colleague Ihor Kolodka's face. The baby remained in place on the table, surrounded by shattered equipment and five bleeding adults.</p>

<p>"Is everyone alive?" Holubchenko recalls shouting.</p>

<p>Anaesthesiologist Yaroslav Ivanov grabbed the manual resuscitator to keep the baby breathing after the ventilator broke. Worried the ceiling would collapse, some members of the team ran to the basement with Taras.</p>

<p>These were the dramatic moments after a missile struck Okhmatdyt Children's Hospital in central Kyiv on Monday, an assault that shocked Ukrainians and prompted angry condemnation from Kyiv and its Western allies.</p>

<p>The U.N. said on Tuesday there was a "high likelihood" the hospital took a direct hit from a Russian missile during a series of airstrikes on Ukrainian cities that have killed at least 44 people. The Kremlin has said, without providing evidence, that it was Ukrainian anti-missile fire, not Russia, that hit the hospital, large parts of which were reduced to rubble.</p>

<p>Two adults were killed at Okhmatdyt and dozens were wounded. Many patients, relatives and staff had fled to basements in time to avoid the worst of the blast.</p>

<p>"For me, Okhmatdyt was the safest place for kids and adults. On that day, I realized there are no safe spaces left anywhere," Ivanov, 39, told Reuters over the telephone on Tuesday as he recovered from concussion and cuts.</p>

<p>When they reached the basement, Ivanov and his colleagues found a room free of smoke and away from the screams of the injured.</p>

<p>There they brought the baby back to consciousness and handed him over to a team of doctors to continue the surgery at another hospital.</p>

<h3><strong>STRAIGHT BACK TO WORK</strong></h3>

<p>As Holubchenko and Ivanov took care of Taras, Kolodka took out shards of glass from his face and then rushed outside to see how he could help. He saw that the toxicology department had been flattened.</p>

<p>"Since I was not bleeding anymore, I went outside to keep helping the injured and deal with the aftermath of the missile strike," Kolodka said.</p>

<p>"In the moment, we didn't think about whether it was easy or difficult - we were just doing our job and trying to help."</p>

<p>After helping rescue workers and soldiers sift through the rubble for the rest of the day in the dust and heat, he returned home to find there was no power. Electricity outages are now common across the country as Russia targets the energy system.</p>

<p>Kolodka woke up at 5 a.m. to take a shower before heading back to work. Holubchenko also returned to the hospital on Tuesday.</p>

<p>"I had to go because there was a meeting with colleagues, to see what was happening with the department and check all the equipment," Holubchenko said. "I ... connected with colleagues from the other hospital to ask about the state of the baby."</p>

<p>Taras was doing fine after his surgery, he was told.</p>

<p>The team was heartened by support and gratitude from patients and the broader community as they battled exhaustion.</p>

<p>Work to repair the hospital was underway within hours of the blast as hundreds of volunteers joined the effort to clear broken glass, rubble and damaged equipment.</p>

<p>"It is nice to see how united our people are," said Kolodka.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/5t7n0b4o_kyiv-hospital-strike-reuters-_625x300_10_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Two adults were killed after a missile struck Okhmatdyt Children's Hospital]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/canadian-government-sued-over-harsh-migrant-detentions-6072132]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Canada Accused Of Keeping Migrants In Chains, Strip-Searching Them]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/canadian-government-sued-over-harsh-migrant-detentions-6072132]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 10 Jul 2024 07:25:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Canadian government is being sued for allegedly violating migrants' rights by detaining them alongside criminal suspects while awaiting processing of their status, lawyers for the migrants said Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Canadian government is being sued for allegedly violating migrants' rights by detaining them alongside criminal suspects while awaiting processing of their status, lawyers for the migrants said Tuesday.</p>

<p>One of the migrants described his time in detention as a "living hell." Another described a traumatic atmosphere in prison, with drug use and fights among inmates.</p>

<p>Migrants were at times shackled and subjected to strip searches, the lawyers said.</p>

<p>"Immigration detention is administrative detention and should not be punitive in nature," said the plaintiffs' lawyers, who are seeking C$100 million ($73.4 million) in damages.</p>

<p>These allegations of harsh treatment are contained in a ruling handed down Friday by the Superior Court of Ontario province, which authorized a class action suit by 8,360 people detained by the Canada Border Services Agency (CBSA) between 2016 and 2023 in 87 prisons.</p>

<p>Foreign nationals -- including asylum seekers -- who were not accused of a crime "encountered the same conditions as criminal inmates, including co-mingling with violent offenders, use of restraints such as shackles and handcuffs, strip searches, and severe restrictions on contact and movement," wrote Justice Benjamin Glustein.</p>

<p>Border agents can detain migrants if there is fear that they will not show up for an immigration hearing, if their identity is in doubt or if they pose a danger to public safety.</p>

<p>But having them held in provincial jails instead of immigration facilities violates their rights, the lawsuit claims.</p>

<p>One party to the suit with the surname Garcia Paez, who was incarcerated for 13 days in 2021, described his time in jail in a sworn statement as traumatic, with a violent atmosphere, drug use and physical assaults involving other detainees.</p>

<p>The Canadian government, which can still appeal, has said it has not yet decided its next step.</p>

<p>"It was important to me to bring this lawsuit not just for myself but for the thousands of other immigration detainees who, like me, were incarcerated in provincial prisons and treated as if they were criminals despite not even being accused of a crime," said another of the plaintiffs, Tyron Richard.</p>

<p>"I felt an overwhelming sense of helplessness during the 18 months I spent in a maximum-security prison. It was a living hell. I am proud that I am now able to stand up and fight back."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2018-01/prison-generic-unsplash-650_650x400_61515061532.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[One of the migrants described his time in detention as a "living hell" (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>