<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 14:51:16 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/study-shows-how-cancer-cells-may-be-using-lipids-to-hide-from-immune-system-6592758]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Study Shows How Cancer Cells May Be Using Lipids To Hide From Immune System]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/study-shows-how-cancer-cells-may-be-using-lipids-to-hide-from-immune-system-6592758]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 14:51:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Scientists have long known that cancer cells alter lipid metabolism, but it was generally assumed that cancer cells were gobbling up these lipids for energy.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Cancer cells rarely begin stealthily. Quite the contrary, they alert the immune system to their presence by displaying chemical red flags on their membranes. When detected, the body's defences can swoop in and destroy renegade cells before they can do significant damage. Lipids, fatty molecules traditionally thought to be largely a fuel supply for developing tumours, are at the heart of this early detection system.</p>

<p>However, a new study in Nature shows that one specific lipid type is essential for cancer immune evasion -- so much so that certain cancer cells cannot reproduce without it. The findings validate long-held assumptions that not only is this lipid a crucial factor in cancer biology (and thus a key therapeutic target).</p>

<p>"Cancer cells are altering how this lipid is metabolized, which in turn distorts the 'eat me' signals that malignant cells usually produce," says first author Mariluz Soula, a former graduate student in the laboratory of Kivanc Birsoy, and now a scientist Lime Therapeutics. "This paints a very different picture of the role lipids play in cancer growth."</p>

<p>Scientists have long known that cancer cells alter lipid metabolism, but it was generally assumed that cancer cells were gobbling up these lipids for energy--consuming the fatty molecules to help the tumor grow and spread far beyond that of healthy cells.</p>

<p>"We knew from the literature that elevated lipid levels correlate with severity of cancer growth and metastasis, but it was unclear how," Soula says. The Birsoy lab, in conjunction with the laboratory of Gabriel D. Victoria, set out to answer this question by screening the genes involved in this process. They then implanted a series of cancer cells, each missing a different such gene, into mice with and without immune systems--thereby revealing which lipids a cancer cannot live without.</p>

<p>The result: so-called "sphingolipids." Discovered in the late 1800s by German chemist Johann Ludwig Wilhelm Thudichum, sphingolipids were named after the enigmatic Sphinx of Greek lore because of their puzzling structure and function. Two centuries later, sphingolipids are less of a mystery. "We know that sphingolipids aren't really used for energy," Soula says. "They're mainly in the cell membrane to create scaffolding for signaling proteins."</p>

<p>This finding raised an intriguing possibility. Was lipid metabolism in cancer cells really just the story of hungry cells trying to consume more energy? Or was it a key part of the cancer cell's efforts to subtly manipulate cell signaling and dodge the immune system?</p>

<p>To test how sphingolipids were driving cancer growth, the team turned to an FDA-approved drug used to treat Gaucher disease--a genetic disorder characterized by an impaired ability to break down lipids. The drug essentially blocks glycosphingolipid synthesis, and the team found that this impaired tumor growth in pancreatic, lung, and colorectal cancer models.</p>

<p>They also found that depleting glycosphingolipids prevented the formation of the "lipid nanodomains" that bunch signalizing molecules together on the membrane, impacting the cell's surface receptors on the cell surface in a way that made them more sensitive to an immune response. These findings suggest that cancer cells hoard glycosphingolipids in order to obscure inflammatory signals, and that disrupting glycosphingolipid production can leave cancer cells vulnerable to the immune system.</p>

<p>"Everyone thought of elevated lipid levels as an energy source for cancer cells to consume," Soula says. "We discovered that it's far more nuanced. Lipids are not just fuel, but a protection mechanism for cancer cells that modulates how they communicate with the immune system."</p>

<p>Future work will determine whether this holds true for multiple cancers. The team tested a variety of types, but found this mechanism at work in KRAS-dependent cancers (so named for the mutated oncogene that drives them). Still, the initial results could have significant clinical impact, given how aggressive many KRAS-dependent cancers, such as pancreatic cancer, tend to be. Based on their findings, the team suggests that drug and dietary interventions that stunt sphingolipid production may help increase the efficacy of existing immunotherapies.</p>

<p>"Diets may impact many aspects of cancer biology," Birsoy says. "We believe modulating dietary lipids may be an interesting avenue to target cancer cells' ability to evade immune cells."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/tlop50jo_surgery_625x300_13_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Representational Image]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pager-attacks-hezbollah-mass-murder-iran-slams-israel-after-9-killed-envoy-injured-in-lebanon-6592621]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Mass Murder": Iran Slams Israel After 9 Killed In Pager Attack In Lebanon]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pager-attacks-hezbollah-mass-murder-iran-slams-israel-after-9-killed-envoy-injured-in-lebanon-6592621]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 14:35:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Among those wounded in the pager attacks on Tuesday was Iran's ambassador to Lebanon Mojtaba Amani, with Iranian media reporting he suffered injuries "to the hand and the face."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Iran accused Israel on Wednesday of "mass murder" after <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-how-pagers-turned-bombs-and-why-israel-is-being-blamed-6592100#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll">pager devices</a> belonging to the Tehran-aligned Hezbollah group in Lebanon exploded, killing nine people and wounding nearly 3,000 others.&nbsp;Foreign ministry spokesman Nasser Kanani said in a statement he "condemned the terrorist act of the Zionist regime... as an example of mass murder".</p>

<p>Among those wounded in the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-israel-lebanon-pager-attacks-what-is-a-pager-and-why-hezbollah-still-relies-on-this-outdated-device-6590890#pfrom=home-ndtv_topstories">pager blasts</a> on Tuesday was Iran's ambassador to Lebanon Mojtaba Amani, with Iranian media reporting he suffered injuries "to the hand and the face."&nbsp;</p>

<p>State television said that Amani was only lightly injured.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Iranian Red Crescent said on Wednesday it had dispatched "rescue teams and eye surgeons" to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hezbollah-inside-lebanon-politics-hezbollah-iran-and-a-larger-battle-for-hegemony-6588884#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll">Lebanon</a> to treat the wounded.</p>

<p>There was no immediate comment from Israel on the wave of explosions that killed nine people, including the 10-year-old daughter of a Hezbollah member, and wounded around 2,800 others.</p>

<p>The blasts came just hours after Israel announced it was broadening the aims of the war sparked by Hamas's October 7 attacks to include its fight against the group's ally <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hezbollah-inside-lebanon-politics-hezbollah-iran-and-a-larger-battle-for-hegemony-6588884#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll">Hezbollah</a> along the country's border with Lebanon.</p>

<p>In his statement, Kanani expressed solidarity with the families of those killed and wounded in the explosions including the Iranian ambassador.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Combating the terrorist acts of the (Israeli) regime and the threats arising from them is an obvious necessity," said Kanani.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"It is necessary for the international community to act quickly in order to counter the impunity of the Zionist criminal authorities."&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/4s1csfh8_pager-attack_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Pager attacks in Lebanon also injured nearly 3,000 others.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-cups-of-coffee-a-day-may-lower-risk-of-developing-heart-condition-study-6592540]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[3 Cups Of Coffee A Day May Lower Risk Of Developing Heart Condition: Study]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-cups-of-coffee-a-day-may-lower-risk-of-developing-heart-condition-study-6592540]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 14:28:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Three cups of coffee a day could lower one's risk of developing multiple metabolic conditions, including diabetes, and those related to heart, by 40 per cent to almost 50 per cent, a new research has found.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Three cups of coffee a day could lower one's risk of developing multiple metabolic conditions, including diabetes, and those related to heart, by 40 per cent to almost 50 per cent, a new research has found.</p>

<p>Researchers said that as populations age globally, there is an increase in number of people with at least two cardiometabolic diseases -- referred to as 'cardiometabolic multimorbidity' -- which is becoming a public health concern.</p>

<p>Using data from the UK Biobank, the researchers from Suzhou Medical College of Soochow University, China, analysed information of over 1.72 lakh people taking caffeine with that of 1.88 lakh people consuming coffee and tea. The participants were free of cardiometabolic conditions at the study's start.</p>

<p>While coffee and tea are well-known to contain caffeine, the stimulant is also present in chocolates, aerated and energy drinks, and snack bars, all of which count as caffeine intake.</p>

<p>The authors found that people consuming moderate amounts -- three cups of coffee or 200-300 milligrams of caffeine a day -- had a 40-48 per cent lower risk of developing cardiometablic comorbidity, compared to those not consuming or taking under 100 milligrams of caffeine a day. The results are published in the Journal of Clinical Endocrinology &amp; Metabolism.</p>

<p>"Consuming three cups of coffee, or 200-300 mg caffeine, per day might help to reduce the risk of developing cardiometabolic multimorbidity in individuals without any cardiometabolic disease," lead author Chaofu Ke from the School of Public Health at Suzhou Medical College of Soochow University said.</p>

<p>While the protective effects of coffee and tea beverages in people having one cardiometabolic disease have been detailed in numerous studies, the researchers said the potential effects of these beverages in the onset of more than one such condition is largely unknown.</p>

<p>Even though all levels of coffee and caffeine intake were found to be conversely related with the risk of onset of more than one cardiometabolic disorder -- higher the intake, lower the risk -- those reporting moderate levels of coffee or caffeine intake were found to have the lowest risk.</p>

<p>"The findings highlight that promoting moderate amounts of coffee or caffeine intake as a dietary habit to healthy people might have far-reaching benefits for the prevention of cardiometabolic comorbidity," Ke said.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2019-04/480ih3a8_coffee-generic-istock_625x300_12_April_19.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kate-middleton-makes-tentative-return-to-work-week-after-finishing-chemotherapy-6592564]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kate Middleton Makes Tentative Return To Work After Finishing Chemotherapy]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kate-middleton-makes-tentative-return-to-work-week-after-finishing-chemotherapy-6592564]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 14:27:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kate Middleton held a meeting at Windsor Castle, west of London, with staff from the Royal Foundation Centre for Early Childhood.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Britain's Princess of Wales has taken a first step towards returning to her work on the early-years development of children, a week after announcing she had completed chemotherapy. Catherine, 42, also known as <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kate-middleton-finishes-chemotherapy-course-says-cant-tell-what-a-relief-6527477">Kate Middleton</a>, held a meeting at Windsor Castle, west of London, with staff from the Royal Foundation Centre for Early Childhood, the organisation she established, on Tuesday.</p>

<p>The meeting was listed in the Court Circular, the official record of engagements carried out by members of the royal family, which was published in The Times newspaper on Wednesday.</p>

<p>The issue of childrens' early development has been described as mother-of-three Catherine's life's work by aides.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/groundbreaking-how-people-reacted-to-kate-middletons-chemo-announcement-6535556">Catherine</a>, a future queen who is married to heir to the throne Prince William, has appeared in public on only a few occasions since the start of the year, when it was announced that she was due to have abdominal surgery.</p>

<p>That announcement was followed in March with the shock revelation that she was undergoing a course of "preventative chemotherapy" for an undisclosed cancer.</p>

<p>She said last week she had finished the treatment and was "looking forward to being back at work and undertaking a few more public engagements in the coming months when I can".</p>

<p>The announcement in a highly emotional video came after her father-in-law, King Charles III, 75, was given the light to resume public duties in April after his own cancer treatment.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/jj55v3mo_kate-middleton_625x300_14_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[File photo]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/google-wins-challenge-against-brussels-1-66-billion-antitrust-fine-6592492]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Google Wins Challenge Against Brussels' $1.66 Billion Antitrust Fine]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/google-wins-challenge-against-brussels-1-66-billion-antitrust-fine-6592492]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 14:16:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The ruling will be a relief for Google after the EU's highest court last week upheld a 2017 fine worth 2.42 billion euros for abusing its dominance by favouring its own comparison shopping service.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An EU court on Wednesday scrapped a 1.49-billion euro ($1.65 billion) fine imposed by Brussels against Google for an abuse of dominance over online advertising. "The General Court annuls the (European) Commission's decision in its entirety," the Luxembourg-based court said in a statement, adding that the "institution committed errors in its assessment".</p>

<p>Brussels "failed to take into consideration all the relevant circumstances in its assessment of the duration of the contract clauses that the commission had deemed abusive", the court said.</p>

<p>The commission, the EU's influential competition regulator, said it "takes note" and would "carefully study the judgment and reflect on possible next steps" -- which could include an appeal.</p>

<p>The ruling will be a relief for Google after the EU's highest court last week upheld a 2017 fine worth 2.42 billion euros for abusing its dominance by favouring its own comparison shopping service.</p>

<p>As part of a major push to target big tech abuses, the EU slapped Google with fines worth a total of 8.2 billion euros between 2017 and 2019 over antitrust violations.</p>

<p>The 1.49-billion euro fine is the third of those penalties, focused on Google's AdSense service.</p>

<p>But the long-running legal battles between Google and the EU do not end there.</p>

<p>Google is also challenging a 4.3-billion-euro penalty Brussels levied on it for putting restrictions on Android smartphones to boost its internet search business.</p>

<p>The 2018 fine remains the EU's largest-ever antitrust penalty.</p>

<p>The General Court in 2022 slightly reduced the fine to 4.1 billion euros, but mainly supported the commission's argument that Google had imposed illegal restrictions.</p>

<p>The legal saga continues in that case after Google appealed the latest decision before the higher European Court of Justice.</p>

<p>The EU has since armed itself with a more powerful legal weapon known as the Digital Markets Act (DMA), to rein in tech giants including Google.</p>

<p>Rather than regulators discovering egregious antitrust violations after probes lasting many years, the DMA gives businesses a list of what they can and cannot do online.</p>

<p>The aim is that tech titans change their ways before the need for deterrent fines.</p>

<p>Google is already the subject of one investigation under the DMA alongside Facebook owner Meta and Apple.</p>

<p>Google is in the US regulators' crosshairs as well.</p>

<p>Last week, the tech titan faced its second major antitrust trial in less than a year with the US government accusing Google of a monopoly in ad technology -- the complex system determining which online ads people see and their cost.</p>

<p>It comes after a US judge in August found Google's search business to be an illegal monopoly, a ruling which threatens a possible break-up for the tech behemoth.</p>

<p>Ad tech is at the centre of multiple probes by regulators around the world.</p>

<p>British regulators earlier this month said in provisional findings that Google abused its dominance in the market.</p>

<p>The EU similarly concluded last year that Google is distorting competition in the market and recommended that the company be forced to divest its ad tech business.</p>

<p>Google has the right to respond in the British and EU cases before the regulators reach final conclusions.</p>

<p>Parent company Alphabet in July said revenue from online ad searches climbed to $48.5 billion in the second quarter of this year.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/subjtm5_google_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Representational Image]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/stone-age-people-drove-dwarf-hippos-elephants-to-extinction-on-cyprus-study-says-6592447]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Stone Age People Drove Dwarf Hippos To Extinction On Cyprus? Study Says...]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/stone-age-people-drove-dwarf-hippos-elephants-to-extinction-on-cyprus-study-says-6592447]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 14:10:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Cyprus wasnt the only Mediterranean island with dwarf wildlife. In fact, Crete, Malta, Sicily, Sardinia and many other islands had their own dwarf elephants and hippos.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Imagine growing up beside the eastern Mediterranean Sea 14,000 years ago. You're an accomplished sailor of the small watercraft you and your fellow villagers make, and you live off both the sea and the land. But times have been difficult — there just isn't the same amount of game or fish around as when you were a child. Maybe it's time to look elsewhere for food.</p>

<p>Now imagine <a href="https://doi.org/10.3390/heritage5040160">going farther</a> than ever before in your <a href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0299765">little boat</a>, accompanied maybe by a few others, when suddenly you spot something on the horizon. Is that an island?</p>

<h2><strong>An island of tiny elephants and hippos</strong></h2>

<p>Welcome to <a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/D6LAmqHQic4oNJjz7">Cyprus</a> as the world emerges from the <a href="https://www.livescience.com/40311-pleistocene-epoch.html">last ice age</a>. You are the first human to set your eyes on this huge, <a href="http://doi.org/10.4000/paleorient.2565">heavily forested island</a> teeming with food.</p>

<p>When you beach your boat to have a look around, you can't believe what you're seeing — tiny boar-sized hippos and horse-sized elephants that look like babies to your eyes. There are so many of them, and you're hungry after the long journey.</p>

<p>The diminutive beasts don't seem to show any fear. You easily kill a few and preserve the meat as best you can for the long journey back.</p>

<p>When you get home, you are excited to let everyone in the village know what you've found. Soon enough, you organise a major expedition back to the island.</p>

<p>Of course, we'll never know if this kind of scenario took place, but it's a plausible story of how and when the <a href="https://cosmosmagazine.com/history/archaeology/cyprus-stone-age-settlement/">first humans managed to get to Cyprus</a>. It also illustrates how they might have quickly brought about the demise of the <a href="https://uchytel.com/Hippopotamus-minor">tiny hippopotamus</a> <em>Phanourios minor</em>, as well as the <a href="https://uchytel.com/Palaeoloxodon-cypriotes">dwarf elephant</a> <em>Palaeoloxodon cypriotes</em>.</p>

<h2><strong>Dwarf ‘giants'</strong></h2>

<p>Cyprus wasn't the only Mediterranean island with dwarf wildlife. In fact, Crete, Malta, Sicily, Sardinia and many other islands had their own <a href="https://www.theextinctions.com/articles-1/elephants-of-the-aegean-dwarfs-and-giants-of-the-ancient-sea">dwarf elephants</a> and <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/2017/jan/25/sun-sea-and-fossils-the-mediterranean-is-a-surprising-palaeontological-paradise">hippos</a>.</p>

<p><iframe class="tc-infographic-datawrapper" frameborder="0" height="400px" id="tWIqa" scrolling="no" src="https://datawrapper.dwcdn.net/tWIqa/2/" style="border: 0;" width="100%"></iframe></p>

<p><a href="https://www.sapiens.org/biology/island-dwarfism/">Island dwarfism</a> — the process in which a once large, mainland species evolves to become smaller in response to fewer resources and predators — is in fact quite common. Unfortunately, the process also makes such species <a href="https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.add8606">more vulnerable to rapid environmental change</a>, including the arrival of new predators such as humans.</p>

<figure class="align-right zoomable"><a href="https://images.theconversation.com/files/619365/original/file-20240914-16-rpx5vp.jpeg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=1000&amp;fit=clip"><img alt="Photo of a museum display of the skeleton of a dwarf hippo and an illustration of what it may have looked like in life." sizes="(min-width: 1466px) 754px, (max-width: 599px) 100vw, (min-width: 600px) 600px, 237px" src="https://images.theconversation.com/files/619365/original/file-20240914-16-rpx5vp.jpeg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=237&amp;fit=clip" srcset="https://images.theconversation.com/files/619365/original/file-20240914-16-rpx5vp.jpeg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=825&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=1 600w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/619365/original/file-20240914-16-rpx5vp.jpeg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=30&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=825&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=2 1200w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/619365/original/file-20240914-16-rpx5vp.jpeg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=15&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=825&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=3 1800w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/619365/original/file-20240914-16-rpx5vp.jpeg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=1037&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=1 754w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/619365/original/file-20240914-16-rpx5vp.jpeg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=30&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=1037&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=2 1508w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/619365/original/file-20240914-16-rpx5vp.jpeg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=15&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=1037&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=3 2262w" /></a>

<figcaption><span class="caption">Skeleton of a dwarf hippo (<em>Phanourios minor</em>) and artist's reconstruction of the animal displayed at the Akamas Geology and Palaeontology Information Centre in Pano Arodes, western Cyprus.</span> <span class="attribution"><a class="source" href="https://panoarodes.com/akamas-geology-and-paleontology-information-center/">CJA Bradshaw / Flinders University</a></span></figcaption>
</figure>

<p>The Cypriot dwarf hippopotamus was the <a href="http://doi.org/10.1016/j.palaeo.2019.05.032">smallest dwarf hippo</a> in the Mediterranean region. Genetic data suggest <a href="http://doi.org/10.1093/zoolinnean/zlab089">it diverged</a> from the <a href="https://www.awf.org/wildlife-conservation/hippopotamus">common hippopotamus</a> (<em>Hippopotamus amphibius</em>) roughly 1.5 million years ago.</p>

<p>The Cypriot dwarf elephant was less than 10% of the size of its mainland ancestor, <a href="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/237394736_Palaeloxodon_cypriotes_the_dwarf_elephant_of_Cyprus_Size_and_scaling_comparisons_with_P_falconeri_Sicily-Malta_and_mainland_P_antiquus">the straight-tusked elephant</a> (<em>Palaeoloxodon antiquus</em>) that inhabited Europe and Western Asia during the Middle and Late Pleistocene.</p>

<h2><strong>An extinction controversy</strong></h2>

<p>For a long time, many <a href="https://ibdigital.uib.es/greenstone/collect/monografiesHistoriaNatural/index/assoc/Monograf/iesSHNB_/2005vol0/12p193.dir/MonografiesSHNB_2005vol012p193.pdf">archaeologists</a> and <a href="https://doi.org/10.1371%2Fjournal.pone.0134429">palaeontologists</a> didn't believe humans had anything to do with the extinction of these two “<a href="https://rewilding.academy/what-is-megafauna-2/">megafauna</a>” species on Cyprus.</p>

<p>The doubters assumed that either people arrived well after the extinctions, or the earliest humans were too few to be able to kill off entire species.</p>

<p>Earlier this year we showed that <a href="https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2318293121">people came to Cyprus between 14,000 and 13,000 years ago</a>, well before hippos and elephants went extinct. We also showed that the human population likely grew to several thousand within a few hundred years of arrival. But we didn't know whether this human population was large enough to drive the dwarf hippos and elephants to extinction.</p>

<p>Our new <a href="https://doi.org/10.1098/rspb.2024.0967">research published today</a> answers this question with a combination of several different types of mathematical models.</p>

<h2><strong>Could a small human population cause extinction?</strong></h2>

<p>Even though these animals are long extinct, we can draw some conclusions about their likely population because we can estimate their weights from palaeontological information. The dwarf hippo weighed around 130kg, and the dwarf elephant came in at just over 500kg.</p>

<p>We also know how to translate weights to estimates of population size, longevity, survival and fertility. We can even use data collected from related species still living today, such as the <a href="https://taronga.org.au/animals/pygmy-hippopotamus">pygmy hippo</a> and the <a href="https://www.worldwildlife.org/species/african-elephant">African elephant</a>, to estimate how fast they would have grown.</p>

<p>With this information, we built computer models of what would have happened to the two mini-megafauna species on Cyprus when human hunters arrived. We estimated how efficient human hunters would be, how long it would take them to process each carcass, and how much energy hunter-gatherers need to survive.</p>

<p>We also estimated how much of the human diet included these species, and how this proportion might have changed as the dwarf hippo and elephant numbers dwindled.</p>

<p>We found that even a small human population, numbering between 3,000 and 7,000, could have easily driven first dwarf hippos, and then dwarf elephants, to extinction. Our model showed the process would have taken less than 1,000 years. This prediction matches the sequence of extinction inferred from the palaeontological record.</p>

<p>Our results provide strong evidence that palaeolithic peoples in Cyprus were at least partially, if not entirely, responsible for megafauna extinctions during the Late Pleistocene and early Holocene.</p>

<p>Cyprus was the perfect place to test our models because the island offers an ideal set of conditions to examine whether the arrival of humans ultimately led to the extinction of its megafauna. This is because Cyprus was a relatively simple test case – a small island of around 11,000 square kilometres at the time, with only two species of megafauna.</p>

<p>Our research therefore improves our understanding of how even small human populations can disrupt ecosystems and cause major extinctions, particularly in times of rapid environmental change.<!-- Below is The Conversation's page counter tag. Please DO NOT REMOVE. --><img alt="The Conversation" height="1" referrerpolicy="no-referrer-when-downgrade" src="https://counter.theconversation.com/content/238999/count.gif?distributor=republish-lightbox-basic" style="border: none !important; box-shadow: none !important; margin: 0 !important; max-height: 1px !important; max-width: 1px !important; min-height: 1px !important; min-width: 1px !important; opacity: 0 !important; outline: none !important; padding: 0 !important" width="1" /><!-- End of code. If you don't see any code above, please get new code from the Advanced tab after you click the republish button. The page counter does not collect any personal data. More info: https://theconversation.com/republishing-guidelines --></p>

<p><span>(<strong>Authors:&nbsp;</strong><a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/corey-j-a-bradshaw-9183">Corey J. A. Bradshaw</a>, Matthew Flinders Professor of Global Ecology and Node Leader in the ARC Centre of Excellence for Indigenous and Environmental Histories and Futures, <em><a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/flinders-university-972">Flinders University</a></em>; <a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/christian-reepmeyer-1527424">Christian Reepmeyer</a>, Deputy Director - Oceania, <em><a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/deutsches-archaologisches-institut-german-archaeological-institute-6198">Deutsches Archäologisches Institut - German Archaeological Institute</a></em>, and <a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/theodora-moutsiou-1527770">Theodora Moutsiou</a>, Special Scientist, <em><a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/university-of-cyprus-1426">University of Cyprus</a>)</em></span></p>

<p>(This article is republished from <a href="https://theconversation.com">The Conversation</a> under a Creative Commons license. Read the <a href="https://theconversation.com/small-populations-of-stone-age-people-drove-dwarf-hippos-and-elephants-to-extinction-on-cyprus-238999">original article</a>.)</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/924tc87g_dwarf-hippos_625x300_18_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Representational Image]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trumps-plan-continue-golf-comes-as-a-bogey-for-the-us-secret-sevice-6592416]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump's Plan To Continue Golf Comes As A 'Bogey' For The US Secret Service]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trumps-plan-continue-golf-comes-as-a-bogey-for-the-us-secret-sevice-6592416]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 14:04:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The head of the Secret Service told Donald Trump in a private meeting that significant new security arrangements will be needed if he wants to keep playing golf, The New York Times reported on Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The head of the Secret Service told Donald Trump in a private meeting that significant new security arrangements will be needed if he wants to keep playing golf, The New York Times reported on Tuesday.</p>

<p>Trump asked Ronald Rowe, the Secret Service's acting director, in a meeting on Monday whether it was safe for him to continue playing, the newspaper said. Rowe said the Secret Service views the golf course at Joint Base Andrews in Maryland as easier to secure because it is a military course.</p>

<p>That meeting occurred a day after the Secret Service thwarted a second apparent assassination attempt on Trump in less than two months. On Sunday, Secret Service agents fired on Ryan Wesley Routh, the apparent would-be assassin, when they saw the barrel of his gun poking through the fenceline at Trump's golf course in West Palm Beach, Florida, and local police officers later arrested him.</p>

<p>The incident has raised questions within Trump's orbit and among lawmakers about whether Trump's protection is sufficient.</p>

<p>"Former President Trump is receiving the highest level of protection that the U.S. Secret Service can provide, and we will continue to evaluate and adjust our specific protective measures and methodology based on each location and situation," Secret Service spokesperson Melissa McKenzie said on Tuesday.</p>

<p>Trump on Tuesday told Fox News "we've long requested more people" and that additional Secret Service protection was forthcoming.</p>

<p>"I think we are getting it now. Somebody told me that they will be providing more people now," Trump told interviewer Sean Hannity by telephone.</p>

<p>Still, West Palm Beach Sheriff Ric Bradshaw told reporters on Sunday that Trump's security detail was not as tight as that of a sitting president.</p>

<p>Since the incident, both Democrats and Republicans have accused each other of using overheated rhetoric that is inspiring political violence.</p>

<p>White House press secretary Karine Jean-Pierre said in a press briefing on Tuesday that Republican vice presidential candidate JD Vance's comments about Vice President Kamala Harris not having faced an assassination attempt are dangerous.</p>

<p>"The big difference between conservatives and liberals is that ... no one has tried to kill Kamala Harris in the last couple of months," Vance said on Monday.</p>

<p>Jean-Pierre said that language could put Harris in danger.</p>

<p>"When you make comments like that, all it does is ... opens an opportunity for people to listen to you and potentially take you very seriously, and so it's dangerous to have that type of rhetoric out there," she said.</p>

<p>Trump was due to speak at a campaign event in Michigan on Tuesday evening in his first public political event since the apparent assassination attempt over the weekend.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-08/rl6jcufk_donald-trump-golf-ndtv-file-photo_625x300_18_August_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Significant new security arrangements will be needed if Donald Trump wants to keep playing golf]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/opinion-a-smartphone-epidemic-is-destroying-europes-new-generation-6592345]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: 'We Lost Her': A Smartphone Epidemic Is Ruining Europe's New Generation]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/opinion-a-smartphone-epidemic-is-destroying-europes-new-generation-6592345]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 13:55:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Parent-led movements are pushing for stricter screen time regulations, and even bans in schools, calling for comprehensive policies to protect the next generation's future.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2017-07/mobile-phone_650x400_81501483347.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>"We lost her, and she lost her childhood." These were the words of Amanda Miller, the mother of a 15-year-old girl who has been in the hospital for a year, undergoing treatment for acute mental health problems. Smartphone addiction has torn the teenager's world apart. Amanda now campaigns to ban the device for children in British schools. The Labour government is currently considering a ban on smartphones for children under 16 in schools.</p>

<p>In an interview with a TV channel, Amanda revealed that she reluctantly bought her daughter a smartphone for her 10th birthday, a decision she now regrets. Her daughter quickly became obsessed with the device. "She would come home from school and lock herself in her room with her phone. We completely lost her. Her mental health deteriorated-she started self-harming, became depressed, and suicidal to the point where she stopped eating. Eventually, she ended up in the hospital."</p>

<p>Amanda pleads with the UK Government to pass a law to help parents "bring their children back".</p>

<h2><strong>A Continental Epidemic&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p>Like Amanda, millions of parents across Europe are increasingly vocal about the damaging effects of smartphones on their children. Parent-led movements are pushing for stricter screen time regulations, and even bans in schools, calling for comprehensive policies to protect the next generation's future. More than 10,000 mothers with young children in Spain have created a WhatsApp group to inform one another of the state of their children's mental health and exchange tips on dealing with smartphone addiction. They want help from their government and demand legislation to ban smartphone use in schools.</p>

<p>This growing concern has sparked intense debates across Europe about how to address screen addiction among children. Movements advocating for phone-free schools are gaining momentum. In the absence of any legislation, some schools have started implementing smartphone-free classes and some others have completely banned phones in schools.</p>

<h2><strong>A Crisis In India</strong></h2>

<p>India's smartphone market has exploded in recent years, with no signs of slowing down. The youth, in particular, spend countless hours on their devices. Deloitte predicts that by 2026, India will be the second-largest smartphone market, surpassing one billion users, with rural areas driving sales<br />
Indian youth are consumed by social media and smartphones, which have been linked to mental health problems like depression, anxiety, and social isolation. A Boston Consulting Group (BCG) study reveals that half of Indian consumers pick up their phones out of habit, often without purpose.</p>

<p>Researchers in India warn that more comprehensive studies are needed to understand the full impact of smartphones on children.</p>

<p>In response, both central and state governments have set up de-addiction and research centres focused on phone addiction. While the Indian government has taken steps to encourage responsible usage, more action is needed. In 2015, the Modi government introduced the Prevention of Addiction of Technological Gadgets Bill in the Rajya Sabha, but it's unclear whether it was ever passed into law.<br />
Can we expect teenagers to resist what adults cannot?</p>

<p>Like millions of others, I rely on my smartphone for nearly every aspect of life-reading, writing, social media, internet browsing, and communication. I use it for payments, watching TV, and listening to music. With multiple OTT subscriptions, I have more content at my fingertips than I could ever use.<br />
So, is it fair to expect teenagers to limit their screen time and curb their dependence on smartphones? Some experts argue that banning smartphones in schools is ineffective and anti-technology. Instead, they believe students should be educated on responsible usage. Others warn that a ban might lead to covert smartphone use or smuggling of devices into classrooms. The focus, they say, should be on teaching children the benefits of responsible use and the dangers of overuse.</p>

<h2><strong>The Scale Of The Problem</strong></h2>

<p>Amanda Miller believes smartphones are "killing our children, killing their youth, destroying their mental health". According to a study by the UK's broadcasting and telecommunications regulatory authority, Ofcom, "by the age of 12, 97% of children have their own mobile phones". Studies have shown that increased screen time negatively impacts mental health, academic performance, and social skills. Adolescents, in particular, are at risk of anxiety, depression, and sleep problems due to excessive smartphone use.</p>

<p>By 2022, as much as 68% of the global population used smartphones, and over 60% of people in many countries admitted to being addicted to their devices.</p>

<p>Smartphones have fuelled the rise of social media platforms, allowing celebrities to connect with their young fans. Cristiano Ronaldo, for instance, reached one billion followers across social media platforms in September, with a large portion of his fanbase being young adults. Other youth icons, such as Selena Gomez, Justin Bieber, and Taylor Swift, also have millions of followers, reinforcing the hold smartphones have over young people.</p>

<p>While smartphones offer practical benefits like communication and education, those opposing a ban argue that implementing it could brand Europe as anti-technology. However, the device's addictive nature, similar to gaming addiction, raises concerns. Last year, UNESCO called for a ban on smartphones in schools, and France has already enforced one. The UK is seriously considering banning smartphones for children aged five to 16 in schools, in addition to guidelines issued earlier this year supporting head teachers who prohibit mobile phones.</p>

<p>Some British schools have already banned smartphones with great success, seeing improvements in academic performance and reduced distractions.</p>

<h2><strong>An Experiment That Gives Hope</strong></h2>

<p>Recently, 10 teenagers from a Manchester school participated in a five-day experiment, swapping their smartphones for basic mobile phones that only allowed calls and texts. These boys and girls, aged 14 to 16, previously spent over 12 hours a day on their devices. While one participant demanded his smartphone back, the other nine completed the experiment. One boy reported better sleep and another girl shared that her relationship with her father improved as they spent more time talking. Though a small sample, the experiment suggested that life without smartphones is possible for even the most dependent teens.&nbsp;</p>

<p>While the British government contemplates the ban a school trust in England with 35,000 pupils has just announced it is banning smartphones in all its 42 schools in England. The trust hopes that the ban will lead to higher academic achievement and improve the mental health of its pupils.</p>

<p><em>(Syed Zubair Ahmed is a London-based senior Indian journalist with three decades of experience with the Western media)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2017-07/mobile-phone_650x400_81501483347.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-2011-hit-and-run-is-fake-news-spread-by-russia-microsoft-6592237]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris' '2011 Hit-And-Run' Is Fake News Spread By Russia: Microsoft]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-2011-hit-and-run-is-fake-news-spread-by-russia-microsoft-6592237]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 13:35:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A false claim circulating on social media that Kamala Harris left a 13-year-old girl paralysed after an alleged hit-and-run in San Francisco in 2011 is the work of a covert Russian disinformation operation, according to new research by Microsoft.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A false claim circulating on social media that Democratic presidential candidate Kamala Harris left a 13-year-old girl paralysed after an alleged hit-and-run in San Francisco in 2011 is the work of a covert Russian disinformation operation, according to new research by Microsoft.</p>

<p>Researchers found that the operation created a video, paid an actor to appear as the alleged victim, and spread the claim through a fake website for a non-existent San Francisco news outlet named "KBSF-TV". The Russian group responsible, which Microsoft dubs Storm-1516, is described as a Kremlin-aligned troll farm.</p>

<p>The discovery is a sign of Russia ramping up its foreign influence efforts ahead of the Nov. 5 presidential election, Microsoft said.</p>

<p>A spokesperson for the Russian embassy in Washington did not respond to a request for comment.</p>

<p>"Russian influence operations initially struggled to pivot operations aimed at the Democratic campaign following President Biden's departure from the U.S. 2024 presidential race," a blog published on Tuesday by Microsoft said.</p>

<p>"In late August, however, elements of prolific Russian actor Storm-1516 began producing content implicating Vice President Harris and Governor Walz in outlandish fake conspiracy theories," Microsoft said, referring to Harris' running mate, Tim Walz.</p>

<p>Storm-1516 is known for producing misleading videos featuring on-screen or voice actors who impersonate whistleblowers or journalists that share false, scandalous information, experts say.</p>

<p>A website for KBSF-TV was created shortly before publishing its first related article about the alleged driving incident, according to online registration records. The claim was circulated on social media platforms, including X.com, using the hashtag #HitAndRunKamala.</p>

<p>The video was also shared on Sept. 3 on X.com by Aussie Cossack, who describes himself as a "Registered foreign agent for Sputnik News," with the message "make this go viral MAGA folks." In total, it is estimated the video has been viewed more than 2.7 million times.</p>

<p>"Many entities within the pro-Russian ecosystem advanced the video and its claims," said Microsoft's Threat Analysis Center. "Storm-1516 relies on some of these personalities, such as Aussie Cossack, to drive amplification of its videos."</p>

<p>Cossack did not immediately respond to a request for comment.</p>

<p>Earlier this month the U.S. Justice Department filed money-laundering charges against two employees of Russian state media network RT for what officials said was a scheme to hire an American company to produce online content to influence the election.</p>

<p>US officials say Russia's goal is to exacerbate US political divisions and weaken public support for American military aid to Ukraine. Harris says if elected she will continue supporting Ukraine in its defence against Russia's invasion.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/pq4qlj0o_kamala-harris-reuters_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Social media claims about Kamala Harris' "hit-and-run" is fake news, a Microsoft research shows.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/over-3-600-food-packaging-chemicals-found-in-human-bodies-in-new-study-6592181]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Over 3,600 Food Packaging Chemicals Found In Human Bodies In New Study]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/over-3-600-food-packaging-chemicals-found-in-human-bodies-in-new-study-6592181]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 13:30:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Around 100 of these chemicals are considered to be of "high concern" to human health, said lead study author Birgit Geueke.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>More than 3,600 chemicals used in food packaging or preparation have been detected in human bodies, some of which are hazardous to health, while little is known about others, a study published on Tuesday said. Around 100 of these chemicals are considered to be of "high concern" to human health, said lead study author Birgit Geueke from the Food Packaging Forum Foundation, a Zurich-based NGO.</p>

<p>Some of these chemicals are relatively well-studied and have already been found in human bodies, such as PFAS and bisphenol A -- both of which are the target of bans.</p>

<p>But little is known about the health effects of others, Geueke told AFP, calling for more research into how chemicals used in packaging end up being swallowed along with food.</p>

<p>The researchers had previously catalogued around 14,000 food contact chemicals (FCCs), which are capable of "migrating" into food from packaging made of plastic, paper, glass, metal or other materials.&nbsp;</p>

<p>They can also come from other parts of the food-making process, such as from conveyer belts or kitchen utensils.</p>

<p>The researchers then searched for these chemicals in existing biomonitoring databases, which track chemicals in human samples.</p>

<p>The team was expecting to find a few hundred FCCs, Geueke said. Instead, they were surprised to find 3,601 -- a quarter of all the known FCCs.</p>

<p>Geueke emphasised that this study could not show that all these chemicals necessarily ended up in bodies from food packaging, as "other exposure sources are possible".&nbsp;</p>

<p>Among the "high concern" chemicals were numerous PFAS, also known as forever chemicals, which have been detected in many parts of the human body in recent years and linked to a range of health problems.</p>

<p>Also detected was bisphenol A, a hormone-disrupting chemical used to make plastics that has already been banned from baby bottles in many countries.</p>

<p>Another hormone-disrupting chemical was phthalates, which has been linked to infertility.</p>

<p>Less is known about oligomers, which are also byproducts of plastic production.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"There is almost no evidence on the health effects of these chemicals," Geueke said.</p>

<p>When it comes to toxicology, an old saying is that "the dose makes the poison".</p>

<p>A limitation of the study was that it could not say whether there were particularly high concentrations of any of the chemicals, Geueke acknowledged.</p>

<p>But she warned that these chemicals can interact with each other, pointing to a single sample that had up to 30 different PFAS.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Geueke recommended that people reduce their contact time with packaging -- and to avoid heating up food in the packaging it came in.</p>

<p>Duane Mellor, an expert in evidence-based medicine at the UK's Aston University and not involved in the research, praised the "very thorough piece of work".</p>

<p>"However, it does not cover how much of these chemicals we are exposed to and hints at other sources of these chemicals in our environment," he told AFP.</p>

<p>Rather than being "unduly alarmed", Mellor suggested that people "demand better data and minimise unnecessary exposure to chemicals which may ultimately impact our health".</p>

<p>Some of the chemicals are also already facing bans.</p>

<p>The European Union is in the final stages of banning the use of PFAS in food packaging. The EU has also proposed a similar ban for bisphenol A from the end of this year.</p>

<p>The study was published in the Journal of Exposure Science and Environmental Epidemiology.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/55a8ckv_food-packaging-chemicals-_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Representational Image]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-how-pagers-turned-bombs-and-why-israel-is-being-blamed-6592100]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: How Pagers Turned Bombs And Why Israel Is Being Blamed]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-how-pagers-turned-bombs-and-why-israel-is-being-blamed-6592100]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 13:19:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Thousands of pagers exploded within seconds across the Lebanon yesterday in a synchronized attack targeting the US-designated terror group Hezbollah.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Thousands of pagers exploded within seconds across the Lebanon yesterday in a synchronized attack targeting the US-designated terror group Hezbollah. The explosions killed at least nine and injured 2,800 individuals in the country that has been caught up in the Israel-Palestine tensions in its backyard.</p>

<p>Hezbollah, the political force running Lebanon, has blamed Israel for the attack. Throughout Gaza war, it supported Hamas and exchanged fire across its southern border with Israel in support for its Palestinian group.</p>

<p>No country or group has claimed responsibility for the attack yet. But fingers pointing at Israel raise a big question over the capabilities of Mossad, the Israeli spy agency known for carrying out targeted attacks on foreign soils.</p>

<h2><strong>Pager bombs - a reality?</strong></h2>

<p>Pagers are wireless low-tech means of communication that lost popularity in the nineties with the emergence of mobile phones. They can display text messages but not relay voice calls. Hezbollah uses pagers to avoid location-tracking by Israel.</p>

<p>The ones used that exploded yesterday came fitted with explosives from Taiwan, reported the New York Times. Gold Apollo, a Taiwanese firm, had placed the order and the pagers were tampered by Israeli agents before they arrived in Lebanon, the US-based newspaper said citing unnamed officials.</p>

<p>Some 3,000 pagers were part of a recent order for Gold Apollo that included mostly its AR-924 model, reported the NYT.</p>

<p>Israeli intelligence infiltrated the production process of the pagers and fitted the explosives that could be triggered remotely without any suspicion, said news agency AFP citing a Brussel-based security analyst.</p>

<p><strong>Read |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hezbollah-inside-lebanon-politics-hezbollah-iran-and-a-larger-battle-for-hegemony-6588884">Inside Lebanon Politics: Hezbollah, Iran And A Larger Battle For Hegemony</a></p>

<p>Mossad had been planning the attack for months, according to Reuters. They fitted the Taiwan-made devices with up to 3 grams of explosives that went unnoticed by Hezbollah, it reported cited Lebanese sources.</p>

<p>The trigger was activated and about 3,000 pagers exploded when a codeword was sent to them, the news agency reported.</p>

<p>Gold Apollo founder Hsu Ching-Kuang has denied making the pagers. He said a Hungarian firm named BAC that had the right to use his company's brand name were the original makers.</p>

<h2><strong>Why Israel Is Being Blamed</strong></h2>

<p>Early Tuesday morning, Israeli PMO released a statement that the safe return of residents evacuated from northern Israel - which borders southern Lebanon - was among its war goals.</p>

<p>Hours later, blasts rocked Lebanon.</p>

<p>Mossad, which has a long history of carrying out sophisticated remote attacks on foreign soil, came under question though Israel never claims responsibility for such covert operations.</p>

<p><strong>Read |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-grams-of-explosives-per-pager-israel-complex-op-to-hurt-hezbollah-6590229">3 Grams Of Explosives Per Pager: Israel's Complex Op To Hurt Hezbollah</a></p>

<p>The latest such incident that was linked to Israel was the killing of a top Hamas commander in Iran. Ismail Haniyeh's assassination in a blast at a high-security VIP compound in a posh Tehran locality was carried out by Mossad, The Telegraph (UK) reported. The bomb was smuggled in months ago, the NYT had said, and was triggered remotely after Haniyeh entered that particular room.</p>

<p>Mossad also played a big role in the 'Operation Wrath of God', codenamed Bayonet, which was activated to avenge the murders of 11 Israeli athletes by Palestinian operatives at the 1972 Olympics in Munich.</p>

<p>During the operation, they used telephones not only to track their enemies but to kill them. A top leader of the Palestine Liberation Organization (PLO) was killed in Paris in a blast that occurred after he answered a telephone call. This marked the emergence of what came to be known as telephone bombs.</p>

<p>Mobile phones were the next target as technology evolved. A bomb-making expert of the Hamas was killed in 1996 after his mobile phone blasted when he answered a call.</p>

<p>Linked or not, attacks on Palestinians and their allies using telephone, mobile phone, and now pagers complete a cycle of using communication means as weapons.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/iuermu3_pagers-reuters_625x300_18_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Pagers are wireless low-tech means of communication that lost popularity in the nineties. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/justin-trudeaus-liberal-party-loses-canadas-closely-watched-montreal-by-election-6592098]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Justin Trudeau's Party Loses Closely-Watched Montreal By-Election]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/justin-trudeaus-liberal-party-loses-canadas-closely-watched-montreal-by-election-6592098]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 13:18:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Canada's ruling Liberal Party lost a long-held parliamentary seat in Montreal on Tuesday, a sign of mounting trouble for Prime Minister Justin Trudeau.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Canada's ruling Liberal Party lost a long-held parliamentary seat in Montreal on Tuesday, a sign of mounting trouble for Prime Minister Justin Trudeau.</p>

<p>The loss marks the second high-profile defeat for Trudeau, who has held the top elected office in Canada since 2015, after a Conservative party candidate won a June by-election in the Toronto area.</p>

<p>Monday's election in the LaSalle-Emard-Verdun district of Montreal was won by Bloc Quebecois candidate Louis-Philippe Sauve, who received 28% of the votes compared to 27.2% cast for Liberal Party candidate Laura Palestini, according to Elections Canada.</p>

<p>"Obviously, it would have been nicer to be able to win and hold Verdun, but there's more work to do and we're going to stay focused on doing it," Trudeau said to reporters Tuesday in response to the election results.</p>

<p>The election was notable for having 91 candidates on the ballot, although most were not running serious campaigns; rather, they signed up for the race as a show of protest for the Longest Ballot Committee, an activist group which seeks electoral reforms in Canada.</p>

<p>Trudeau and the Liberal Party face all-time low popularity after nine years in power, with Conservative party leader Pierre Poilievre leading Trudeau in polls.</p>

<p>According to a Leger poll conducted last week, Conservatives lead Liberals in voting intention 45% to 25%.</p>

<p>Elections must be called by October of next year.</p>

<p>Trudeau's government suffered a major setback this month when a minority leftwing party ended its coalition agreement with the Liberal Party, putting the latter at risk of losing confidence votes.</p>

<p>Despite the upheaval, experts believe elections will not be called in Canada until next spring instead of the upcoming fall or winter.</p>

<p>Trudeau said on Tuesday he plans to remain in office, saying there's "work we're going to continue to do."<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/5segqcpc_justin-trudeau-reuters_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Justin Trudeau's ruling Liberal Party has lost a long-held parliamentary seat in Montreal, Canada.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/robert-roberson-author-john-grisham-joins-bid-to-save-man-on-death-row-for-daughters-death-6591920]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Author John Grisham Joins Bid To Save Man On Death Row For Daughter's Death]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/robert-roberson-author-john-grisham-joins-bid-to-save-man-on-death-row-for-daughters-death-6591920]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 12:51:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Lawmakers in Texas, medical experts and the best-selling novelist John Grisham are pushing to save an autistic death row inmate whose daughter died in 2002 in a tragedy blamed on shaken baby syndrome.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lawmakers in Texas, medical experts and the best-selling novelist John Grisham are pushing to save an autistic death row inmate whose daughter died in 2002 in a tragedy blamed on shaken baby syndrome. Robert Roberson, 57, is scheduled to be executed on October 17 for the death of his two-year-old daughter Nikki in 2002.</p>

<p>Roberson took the girl to a hospital with severe head trauma and the child died the next day.</p>

<p>Lawyers for Roberson filed papers Tuesday with Texas Governor Greg Abbott and the Texas Board of Pardons and Paroles seeking clemency, or failing that, a 180-day stay of execution.</p>

<p>They argued that the diagnosis of shaken baby syndrome, made at the hospital where the child died, was erroneous.</p>

<p>In a letter to Texas officials, 34 doctors argued that the cause of death was in fact severe pneumonia, aggravated by the little girl's being prescribed the wrong medication.</p>

<p>The appeal also argues that Roberson's autism, which was not officially diagnosed until 2018, was misconstrued at the time as showing indifference to the death of the toddler and that this perception weighed heavily in his conviction.</p>

<p>"What's amazing about Robert's case is that there was no crime," Grisham, author of best-selling thrillers such as "The Firm" and "A Time to Kill," told a news conference. Grisham is a former lawyer who has been active in fighting cases of wrongful conviction.</p>

<p>"When you get into wrongful convictions you realize how many innocent people are in prison and how we could stop it, if we had the political gumption to do so. These cases really keep me awake at night," he said.</p>

<p>Roberson's attorney, Gretchen Sween, said "the state of Texas is preparing, in essence, to execute Forrest Gump." She was alluding to the gentle, mildly disabled character played by Tom Hanks in the 1994 film of the same name.</p>

<p>Sween argued that during the medical crisis involving his daughter, Roberson "shut down, and his external lack of affect was judged as a lack of caring."</p>

<p>Former police officer Brian Wharton, who led the investigation at the time, said the diagnosis of shaken baby syndrome "led the investigation from that point forward to the exclusion of all other possibilities."</p>

<p>"Knowing everything that I know now, I am firmly convinced that Robert is an innocent man," said Wharton, who is now a Methodist minister.</p>

<p>Wharton said that for the rest of his life he will regret his role in Roberson's arrest and prosecution.</p>

<p>Eighty-four Texas lawmakers signed a letter in support of the request for clemency for Roberson, more than a third of them Republicans.</p>

<p>These legislators said they are acting out of "grave concern that Texas may put him to death for a crime that did not occur, as new evidence suggests."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/t9q9t8og_robert-roberson_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Robert Roberson's daughter died in 2002 in a tragedy blamed on shaken baby syndrome]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joachim-de-bellay-tomb-an-excavation-may-solve-centuries-old-mystery-at-notre-dame-in-paris-6591872]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[An Excavation May Solve Centuries-Old Mystery At Notre Dame In Paris]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joachim-de-bellay-tomb-an-excavation-may-solve-centuries-old-mystery-at-notre-dame-in-paris-6591872]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 12:46:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A centuries-old mystery surrounding a poet buried in Notre Dame in Paris could be close to being solved thanks to archaeological digs at the world-famous cathedral, researchers said on Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A centuries-old mystery surrounding a poet buried in Notre Dame in Paris could be close to being solved thanks to archaeological digs at the world-famous cathedral, researchers said on Tuesday. The exact whereabouts of the tomb of Joachim de Bellay, a French Renaissance poet, has puzzled researchers for many years.</p>

<p>De Bellay, a member of a literary group known as La Pleiade, died aged 37 in 1560. His family asked for him to be buried in Notre Dame's Saint-Crepin chapel. But when the site was renovated in 1758, no trace of his remains could be found.</p>

<p>His remains' precise location was shrouded in mystery until 2022 when archaeologists, sifting through the site in the aftermath of the 2019 fire that destroyed much of Notre Dame, found two tombs at the cathedral's crossing.</p>

<p>The scientists, working for the national institute for preventative archaeology, rapidly identified one of them as that of Antoine de La Porte, a cleric who died in the early 1700s.</p>

<p>But they could not immediately figure out who was buried in the other one.</p>

<p>Using modern methods of analysis, the researchers began to find clues as to his possibly identity. All pointed to de Bellay.</p>

<p>A deformation of his iliac bone told them that he did a lot of horse-riding.</p>

<p>De Bellay "was a skilled rider, he went from Paris to Rome on horseback", Eric Cubrezy, a doctor and archaeologist, told reporters.</p>

<p>In addition, an incision made by a saw in the corpse's skull, as well as a broken sternum, suggested the body had undergone an autopsy before being embalmed -- just like de Bellay.</p>

<p>The final, and most telling, clue was traces of a rare illness, a bone tuberculosis leading to chronic meningitis, consistent with the poet's medical history.</p>

<p>French daily Le Monde, describing the mystery around the missing corpse as "a cold case", said the latest find was the "most spectacular result" of the Notre Dame digs launched after the 2019 catastrophic fire.</p>

<p>The archaeologists themselves preferred to remain cautious.</p>

<p>"There are still some doubts," said Christophe Besnier, one of the scientists in charge of the excavation site.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/mrknfbd_notre-dames-dead-poet-mystery-_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Joachim de Bellay's remains' precise location was shrouded in mystery until 2022]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/study-of-craters-suggests-earth-once-had-saturn-like-rings-6591771]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Study Of Craters Suggests Earth Once Had Saturn-Like Rings]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/study-of-craters-suggests-earth-once-had-saturn-like-rings-6591771]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 12:30:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The study said that the asteroid belt was formed due to the break-up of an asteroid passing within Earth's Roche limit.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Earth has had a long history, but millions of years ago, the planet even had Saturn-like ring of debris around it. Surprised? A new study by Andy Tomkins and his colleagues at Monash University in Melbourne has suggested that the rings lasted for tens of millions of years, and may have affected the planet's climate. The study is based on the assessment of 21 asteroid craters from the 'Ordovician impact spike' period 466 million years ago. The researchers said these crater sites were caused by larger objects in a previously unidentified ring being pulled out of orbit and crashing into Earth.</p>

<p>The study has been published in <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0012821X24004230?via%3Dihub"><em>Earth and Planetary Science Letters</em></a>. The team noticed the asteroids that the craters were located in a narrow band of land close to the equator.</p>

<p>Asteroids normally strike at random locations, but looking at this pattern, researchers feel that it happened after Earth's close encounter with a large asteroid millions of years ago.</p>

<p>They have theorised in the study that the asteroid broke apart due to tidal forces and formed a debris ring around our planet, similar to the rings seen around Saturn.</p>

<p>"Over millions of years, material from this ring gradually fell to Earth, creating the spike in meteorite impacts observed in the geological record," Mr Tomkins was quoted as saying by <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.independent.co.uk/space/earth-asteroid-saturn-ring-hidden-craters-b2614683.html"><em>The Independent</em></a>.</p>

<p>"We also see that layers in sedimentary rocks from this period contain extraordinary amounts of meteorite debris," he explained.</p>

<p>But how did the craters emerge so close to the equator? Mr Tomkins and his team point to the movement of continents due to plate tectonics. They say at that time, all the sites would have been located close to the equator.</p>

<p>The team also relied on previous research having identified a consistent meteorite signature in a number of limestone deposits, also from that time and also once close to the equator.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/1aie6a3_earth-saturn-like-rings_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The asteroid belt existed around Earth more than 450 million years ago.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kristina-khorram-once-diddys-right-hand-now-his-manipulator-in-chief-in-sex-trafficking-case-6591462]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Rappers' Trusted Aide Linked To Sex Trafficking In Ongoing Investigation]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kristina-khorram-once-diddys-right-hand-now-his-manipulator-in-chief-in-sex-trafficking-case-6591462]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 12:02:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hip-hop mogul Sean Diddy' Combs' chief of staff, Kristina Khorram, who was once described as his "right hand", is now considered a "manipulator in chief", sources close to the federal sex trafficking investigation have said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hip-hop mogul Sean ‘Diddy' Combs' chief of staff, Kristina Khorram, who was once described as his “right hand”, is now considered a “manipulator in chief”, sources close to the federal sex trafficking investigation have said.</p>

<p>Combs, 54, was indicted on Tuesday on three federal counts: sex trafficking, racketeering, and transportation to engage in prostitution. Despite pleading not guilty, Combs remains in custody after a judge rejected his $50 million bail request, reported the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/09/17/entertainment/sean-diddy-combs-manipulator-in-chief-kristina-khorram/ " rel="nofollow,noindex">NY Post</a>.</p>

<p>The federal indictment accuses Combs of orchestrating a sex trafficking operation with the help of “certain employees”, including high-ranking supervisors. These employees allegedly facilitated sexual performances, referred to as “Freak Offs,” that involved sex workers and were organised to include “controlled substances, baby oil lubricant, extra linens, and lighting.”&nbsp;</p>

<p>While the indictment does not name specific individuals, sources suggest Kristina Khorram, who has not been charged with any crime, may hold vital information about the operation. "If anybody is the gatekeeper, Kristina would know everything," a source told the NY Post.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Earlier this year, federal raids at Combs' mansions uncovered narcotics and over 1,000 bottles of baby oil and lubricant. Investigators have reportedly obtained key evidence, including text messages and recordings, some allegedly implicating Khorram.</p>

<p>In 2021, Diddy publicly praised Khorram, <a href="https://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=10159056349829697&amp;id=23291809696&amp;set=a.408569254696&amp;locale=sl_SI ">posting on Facebook</a> that the 37-year-old has been his “right hand for the last 8 years” and has “consistently proven to execute and get s**t done”. “Don't know how I'd function without her,” he wrote.</p>

<p>However, allegations against Kristina Khorram have surfaced in a separate lawsuit filed by rapper Lil Rod (real name Rodney Jones) in February 2024. In his suit, Khorram is compared to Ghislaine Maxwell, the notorious aide of sex offender Jeffrey Epstein, and is accused of “ordering sex workers and prostitutes” for Combs.</p>

<p>The lawsuit also claims Khorram required Combs' household staff to carry a “fanny pack” filled with various drugs, including cocaine, GHB and ecstasy, to satisfy the hip-hop star's drug habits.</p>

<p>Lil Rod's lawsuit also states that Khorram “knowingly and intentionally participated in, perpetrated, assisted and facilitated a sex-trafficking venture,” and alleges she was instrumental in organising Combs' alleged “Freak Off” events. According to the suit, another employee, Stevie J, was recruited to help find sex workers for these parties.</p>

<p>Diddy's legal team has denied all allegations, dismissing Lil Rod's claims as fabrications. A source suggested that Khorram might choose to cooperate with federal authorities. “At least if she's smart, she will be,” the source added.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/mo9uurjg_kristina-khorram-facebook_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kristina Khorram has not been charged with any crime.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/the-long-road-to-1600-pennsylvania-avenue-joe-bidens-five-decade-political-career-6591534]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[The Long Road To White House: Joe Biden's Five-Decade Political Career]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/the-long-road-to-1600-pennsylvania-avenue-joe-bidens-five-decade-political-career-6591534]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 11:56:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[As the 46th President of the United States, Joe Biden's leadership has been marked by several challenges. But his steady hand and experience have allowed Mr Biden to push forward.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Joseph Robinette Biden Jr, the 46th and current President of the United States, has led a five-decade-long political career during which he faced several challenges, but overcame all of them to reach the pinnacle of power in the United States. His road to 1600 Pennsylvania Avenue in Washington, DC (the official address of the White House), has been marked by personal tragedy, political triumphs and a life-long commitment to public service.</p>

<h3><strong>Early Life and Background</strong></h3>

<p>Joe Biden was born on November 20, 1942, in Scranton, Pennsylvania into a working-class family. During his childhood, Mr Biden saw a country that was still recovering from the impact of the war. His father, Joseph Biden Sr, struggled with financial difficulties, working as a car salesman after his earlier business drowned. His mother, Catherine Eugenia Finnegan Biden, was a homemaker who played a significant role in shaping his strong moral values and sense of responsibility.</p>

<p>The Biden family moved to Claymont, Delaware, a few years later where he attended Archmere Academy, a private Catholic school. Joe Biden was an active student, participating in sports and developing leadership skills that would serve him in his political future. Mr Biden graduated from the University of Delaware in 1965 with a degree in history and political science, followed by a law degree from Syracuse University in 1968.</p>

<h3><strong>Family Life: Tragedy And Resilience</strong></h3>

<p>Mr Biden has seen deep loss and personal tragedies, including the death of his son that nearly ended his political career. These events also shaped his character and approach in public life. In 1966, Mr Biden married Neilia Hunter, and the couple had three children: Beau, Hunter and Naomi. However, in 1972, just weeks after Mr Biden was elected as a senator from Delaware, Neilia and one-year-old Naomi were tragically killed in a car accident. His sons, Beau and Hunter, survived but were severely injured.</p>

<p>Mr Biden seriously considered stepping down from his newly won Senate seat to care for his sons but was persuaded to continue by colleagues.</p>

<p>In 1977, Mr Biden married Jill Jacobs, an educator with a doctorate in education, who has stood by his side through the highs and lows of his career. Together, they have a daughter, Ashley Biden, who is a social worker and activist.</p>

<p>Tragedy struck Mr Biden again when his eldest son, Beau Biden, who had served as Delaware's attorney general and was considered a rising star in Democratic politics, died from brain cancer in 2015. Beau's death was a crushing blow for Mr Biden, and he often speaks of his son's legacy as a major influence in his decision to run for President.</p>

<h3><strong>Political Career: From Senator To Vice President</strong></h3>

<p>After graduating from law school, Mr Biden went back to Delaware to work as an attorney but turned towards politics. He was elected to the US Senate in 1972 at the age of 30, becoming the fifth-youngest Senator in US history, as per Encyclopaedia Britannica. He won the re-election six times, becoming Delaware's longest serving senator. As a senator, Mr Biden focused on foreign policy, criminal law and drug policy.</p>

<p>During his time in the Senate, Mr Biden chaired both the Senate Committee on Judiciary and the Senate Foreign Relations Committee. He played a pivotal role in shaping US foreign policy, particularly in the Balkans during the 1990s and in the lead-up to the Iraq War in 2003. His support for the 1994 Crime Bill, which increased penalties for certain crimes and expanded the prison system, has been both lauded and criticised in later years, especially as the conversation around criminal justice reform has evolved.</p>

<p>In 2008, Mr Biden was selected as Barack Obama's running mate. As Vice President, Biden helped steer the country through the 2008 financial crisis and played a key role in passing the Affordable Care Act. He also led initiatives related to foreign policy, particularly with respect to Iraq and Ukraine, and domestic efforts on cancer research, mental health, and violence against women.</p>

<h3><strong>2020 Presidential Campaign And Victory</strong></h3>

<p>Joe Biden's path to the presidency was far from smooth. After two unsuccessful runs in 1988 and 2008, Mr Biden entered the 2020 Democratic primary initially as a moderate candidate in a crowded field. His experience, moderate positions and perceived electability against then-President Donald Trump helped him secure the Democratic nomination.</p>

<p>The 2020 election was one of the most contentious in US history, held amid a global pandemic, widespread economic uncertainty and social unrest following the murder of George Floyd. Mr Biden ran on a platform focused on unifying the country, combating the COVID-19 pandemic and addressing systemic racism. His choice of Senator Kamala Harris as his running mate also made history, as she became the first woman, the first Black woman, and the first South Asian American to serve as Vice President. She is now running for President.</p>

<p>On November 7, 2020, Mr Biden was declared the winner of the presidential election, securing 306 electoral votes to Trump's 232. Despite challenges to the results and the Capitol insurrection on January 6, 2021, he was inaugurated on January 20, 2021, as the 46th President of the United States.</p>

<h3><strong>Age And Experience</strong></h3>

<p>At 78 years old, Joe Biden became the oldest president in US history at the time of his inauguration. His age became a topic of both concern and admiration with critics questioning his cognitive abilities, which ultimately led him to drop off the race and support Ms Harris.</p>

<p>The concerns around Mr Biden's age became more profound since his disastrous performance in a television debate against Donald Trump in June this year. Mr Biden's confused answers and body language led to calls that the 81-year-old was too old for the job. He ultimately dropped out of the race on July 21.</p>

<h3><strong>Policies And Achievements As President</strong></h3>

<p>Since taking office, Joe Biden's presidency has been defined by his handling of the COVID-19 pandemic, economic recovery, and his push for large-scale infrastructure investment. His administration passed the $1.9 trillion American Rescue Plan, which provided financial relief to millions of Americans affected by the pandemic, expanded unemployment benefits and accelerated vaccine distribution.</p>

<p>In November 2021, Mr Biden signed the $1.2 trillion Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act, which aimed to modernise America's roads, bridges and public transit systems, and expand broadband internet access. The legislation was seen as a major bipartisan victory for Mr Biden, who had campaigned on his ability to work across party lines.</p>

<p>The Democrat leader has also focused on issues like climate change, proposing ambitious goals to reduce carbon emissions and promote clean energy. His administration rejoined the Paris Agreement and committed to making the US a leader in the global fight against climate change.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/ofrrpqv8_joe-biden-afp_625x300_08_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Joe Biden dropped out of US presidential race in July this year.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sri-lanka-polls-frontrunners-whats-at-stake-implications-for-india-6591362]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Sri Lanka Polls: Frontrunners, What's At Stake, Implications For India]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sri-lanka-polls-frontrunners-whats-at-stake-implications-for-india-6591362]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 11:28:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The political landscape in Sri Lanka is set to change as its citizens elect a new President on Saturday. Sri Lanka's 17 million voters will choose from among 39 candidates.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The political landscape in Sri Lanka is set to change as its citizens elect a new President on Saturday. Sri Lanka's 17 million voters will choose from among 39 candidates in the country's first election after the people's uprising of 2022, which led to then President Gotabaya Rajapaksa's ouster.</p>

<p>This year's election is dominated by two major alliances, the SJB (Samagi Jana Balawegaya) and the NPP (National People's Power), apart from various smaller parties and independent candidates.</p>

<p>President Ranil Wickremesinghe of the UNP (United National Party) is contesting as an independent. Wickremesinghe, popularly known as RW, is being supported by many rebel legislators of the SLPP (Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna) headed by former president Mahinda Rajapaksa. Also in the contest are opposition leader Sajith Premadasa from the SJB alliance; leftist leader Anura Kumara Dissanayake of the JVP (Janatha Vimukthi Peramuna) - the presidential candidate of NPP - and Mahinda's son, Namal Rajapaksa, as the SLPP candidate.</p>

<p>Poll surveys and experts suggest that Lankan voters are prioritising issues such as economy, education, health, law, and security. Matters of corruption and wrongdoing among politicians, which dominated the electoral narrative, have receded into the background after the 2022 unrest. Since most governments in the past didn't solve the corruption issue, people feel it's better to talk about development. They hope to elect a leader who can pull them out of dire poverty.</p>

<h2><strong>Gloomy past</strong></h2>

<p>In the last election, held after the Easter bombings on April 21, 2019, Gotabaya Rajapaksa of SLPP (Namal's uncle) won a decisive victory and Sajith Premadasa came second. However, three years later, the world saw Sri Lankans oust President Gotabaya Rajapaksa, having endured a steady economic slide. The flawed economic and monetary policies of Gotabaya, along with the COVID-19 pandemic that dented tourism - a chunk of the economy - resulted in an unsustainable debt level. In April 2022, Sri Lanka defaulted on its debt and asked the International Monetary Fund (IMF) for assistance. The Russia-Ukraine war further aggravated the crisis with rising food, medicine and fuel prices resulting in mass protests never seen before in the country's history.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Sri Lankas Samagi Jana Balawegaya party leader Sajith Premadasa waves to supporters." id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/oaet1ah_sajith-premadasa-afp_625x300_18_September_24.jpg" title="Sri Lankas Samagi Jana Balawegaya party leader Sajith Premadasa waves to supporters." /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">Sri Lanka's Samagi Jana Balawegaya party leader Sajith Premadasa waves to supporters.</p>
</div>

<p>The uprising was given the name of '<em>Janatha Aragalaya</em>' (a Sinhala term). Then Prime Minister Mahinda Rajapaksa resigned and subsequently, his brother Gotabaya Rajapaksa quit as President and fled. Ranil Wickremesinghe, a former minister, became Prime Minister. In July 2022, Ranil took over as president through a parliamentary vote with the support of the Rajapaksas' party SLPP, which still has the majority in the legislature. Ranil Wickremesinghe adopted severe austerity measures, with support from the IMF.</p>

<h2><strong>New leaders</strong></h2>

<p>Gotabaya Rajapaksa's inept governance and his decision to leave the country tarred the image of the Rajapaksa clan and the SLPP the most. Most SLPP MPs are supporting either Ranil or Sajith in this election. Namal Rajapaksa, they say, is just a symbolic candidate to keep the SLPP alive.</p>

<p>Sajith's SJB has the support of the Tamil and Muslim minorities, who form 11% and 9% of the population.</p>

<p>Though Tamil parties have fielded a common candidate, the largest party ITAK (Ilankai Tamil Arasu Kachchi) has extended its support to Sajith Premadasa. In 2019 also, Tamils had voted for Sajith but there was an unprecedented consolidation of Sinhala votes behind Gotabhaya Rajapaksa after the Easter bombings, which helped him win the election.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="National Peoples Power (NPP) presidential candidate Anura Kumara Dissanayaka gestures during an election rally." id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/jcgsatu_anura-kumara-dissanayaka-afp_625x300_18_September_24.jpg" title="National Peoples Power (NPP) presidential candidate Anura Kumara Dissanayaka gestures during an election rally." /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">National People's Power (NPP) presidential candidate Anura Kumara Dissanayaka gestures during an election rally.</p>
</div>

<p>The political space created by Rajapaksas' dismissal was filled by Anura Kumara Dissanayake and the JVP, who urged Sri Lankans to go for a broader change. Once in the margins, the party has emerged as a credible, major political force.</p>

<p>As far as Ranil Wickremesinghe is concerned, most members of his party UNP are now with Sajith, though he has support from some legislators of the SLPP like state Defence Minister Premitha Bandara Tennakoon. Ranil is banking on his handling of the economic crisis to fetch him votes.</p>

<p>"People want change this time. They don't want to vote for the same party and old candidates. The new voters, especially on social media, are rooting for Anura Dissanayake. However, on the ground Sajith has a lot of support base, especially in the rural areas," says Thushara Gooneratne, editor-in-chief, Mawrata News.</p>

<p>"Most people think of Sajith as pro-poor just like his father, former President R Premadasa."</p>

<h2><strong>India's Stake</strong></h2>

<p>In recent times, anti-India sentiment has surged in the neighbourhood, because of various reasons. Be it Nepal, Maldives, Sri Lanka or Bangladesh, politicians have been successful in diverting the people's ire towards India.</p>

<p>For India, the sorry plight of the Tamil population in the north and east of Sri Lanka has been a concern for a long time. Successive Lankan governments have failed to implement the 13th Amendment signed as part of India-Sri Lanka agreement in 1987, which provided for devolution of powers to local governments in the north and the east. India, in fact, raised the Sri Lankan Tamil issue at the 51st session of the United Nations Human Rights Council in Geneva in 2022. With the new government, India would like to push for the restoration of provincial councils, which would give a measure of autonomy to Lankan Tamils.</p>

<p>India has stakes in a stable and peaceful Sri Lanka. It wants to restrict China's growing interference in the country because of its geo-strategic location in the Indo-Pacific. The 99-year lease of Hambantota port to China in 2017, feeding the debt-trap narrative, has exacerbated India's concerns.</p>

<p>Anura Dissanayake's party has often been seen as close to China, India's principal geopolitical rival. But for some time now, Dissanayake has enjoyed a different kind of authority within Sri Lankan politics, which has in turn earned him recognition as a rising political force even from India's point of view. As a reflection of this, New Delhi invited Dissanayake in February to engage with him.</p>

<p>"Whoever wins this time will engage with India. Sajith is pro-India. But even Dissanayake, who was known to be anti-India before. India is important for Sri Lanka's growth and stability," says Thushara.</p>

<p>India needs all the goodwill it can command in order to navigate the increasing complexities in the neighbourhood, The escalating regional conflicts and a continuous shift in the global economic order. A friendly, stable neighbourhood is a good start.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/8ougknao_sri-lanka-polls_625x300_18_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sri Lanka's 17 million voters will choose from among 39 candidates.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-how-instagrams-teen-accounts-will-protect-underage-users-6591169]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: How Instagram's "Teen Accounts" Will Protect Underage Users]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-how-instagrams-teen-accounts-will-protect-underage-users-6591169]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 10:58:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Instagram has introduced new safety measures to better protect underage users from online harm.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Instagram has introduced new safety measures to better protect underage users from online harm. The key change is the creation of "Teen Accounts," designed to shield users aged 13 to 17 from the mental health challenges often linked to social media use.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>Why the update?</strong></h2>

<p>Experts and authorities have long criticised Instagram for its role in worsening mental health problems such as anxiety, addiction, cyberbullying, eating disorders and low self-esteem, among teens. Governments and advocacy groups around the world have called for stronger safeguards. Some, like in the US and Australia, are setting age restrictions for social media use.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Meta, Instagram's parent company, response is this significant update that defaults teens' accounts to private, limits who can contact them, and controls what content they are exposed to.</p>

<h2><strong>Features of "Teen Accounts"</strong></h2>

<ul>
	<li>Private accounts - Teens aged 13 to 17 will have their accounts set to private by default, making it harder for strangers to view or interact with their profiles.</li>
	<li>Messaging restrictions - Direct messaging (DM) will have tighter controls, allowing teens to receive messages only from people they follow. This reduces the chances of contact with unwanted or harmful individuals.</li>
	<li>Sensitive content restrictions - Teens will have limited exposure to potentially harmful or inappropriate content.</li>
	<li>Limited interactions - Interaction with adult accounts that do not follow them back will be limited, reducing risks like unsolicited DMs or predatory behaviour.</li>
	<li>Time limit reminders - Teens will receive notifications encouraging them to set time limits on how long they use the app. This will promote healthier usage habits.</li>
</ul>

<h2><strong>Parental supervision</strong></h2>

<p>Meta is also introducing a 'Parents' Supervision Feature', providing parents with more control over their teen's Instagram activity:</p>

<ul>
	<li>Parents can set maximum daily screen time for their children.</li>
	<li>They can see what topics their teen is viewing and monitor who they are chatting with.</li>
	<li>Parents can block access to the app during certain hours to help regulate screen time.</li>
</ul>

<h2><strong>Age Verification: How it works</strong></h2>

<p>Instagram will use new technology to verify user ages:</p>

<ul>
	<li>Partnering with Yoti, Instagram will allow teens to verify their age through a video selfie.</li>
	<li>Teens can also ask their mutual friends to verify their age if required.</li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-02/qqv8pi2_instagram-generic-unsplash_625x300_23_February_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The new Instagram update defaults teenagers' accounts to private.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/tupperware-files-for-bankruptcy-after-years-long-sales-struggle-6591096]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Tupperware Files For Bankruptcy After Years-Long Sales Struggle]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/tupperware-files-for-bankruptcy-after-years-long-sales-struggle-6591096]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 10:41:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Tupperware Brands Corp. filed for bankruptcy following a years-long struggle with sales declines and growing competition.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Tupperware Brands Corp. filed for bankruptcy following a years-long struggle with sales declines and growing competition.</p>

<p>Publicly-traded Tupperware filed for Chapter 11 bankruptcy protection, listing assets of between $500 million to $1 billion and liabilities of $1 billion to $10 billion, according to its court filing. The company will seek court approval to facilitate a sale process of the business and to continue operating during bankruptcy proceedings, it said in a separate statement.</p>

<p>The kitchenware company, which for decades dominated the world of food storage, since 2020 had warned of doubt in its ability to stay in business. As of June of this year, it planned to close its only US factory and lay off almost 150 employees.</p>

<p>The bankruptcy filing in Delaware follows months-long negotiations between Tupperware and its lenders over how to manage more than $700 million in loans. The creditors had agreed to give it some breathing room on that debt, but the business continued to deteriorate.</p>

<p>Tupperware founder Earl Tupper in 1946 introduced its plastic products to the public, and subsequently patented their flexible airtight seal. The brand's goods later flooded into American homes, largely by way of independent sales parties hosted in suburban homes.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/6as4m1f8_tupperware-bloodmberg_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Publicly-traded Tupperware filed for Chapter 11 bankruptcy protection. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>