<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Sat, 20 Jul 2024 06:37:00 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/conspiracy-theories-take-off-after-global-it-crash-6145046]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Conspiracy Theories Take Off After Global IT Crash]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/conspiracy-theories-take-off-after-global-it-crash-6145046]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 20 Jul 2024 06:26:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[From fearmongering about a looming "World War III" to false narratives linking a cabal of global elite to a cyberattack, a torrent of online conspiracy theories took off Friday after a major IT crash.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>From fearmongering about a looming "World War III" to false narratives linking a cabal of global elite to a cyberattack, a torrent of online conspiracy theories took off Friday after a major IT crash.</p>

<p>Airlines, banks, TV channels and financial institutions were engulfed in turmoil after the crash, one of the biggest in recent years that was the result of a faulty software update to an antivirus program operating on Microsoft Windows.</p>

<p>The proliferation of internet-breaking conspiracy theories on social media platforms -- many of which have removed guardrails that once contained the spread of misinformation -- illustrates the new normal of information chaos after a major world event.</p>

<p>The outage gave way to a swirl of evidence-free posts on X, the Elon Musk-owned site formerly known as Twitter, that peddled an apocalyptic narrative: The world was under attack by a nefarious force.</p>

<p>"I read somewhere once that ww3 (World War III) would be mostly a cyber war," one user wrote on X.</p>

<p>The IT crash also stirred up an unfounded theory that the World Economic Forum -- long a magnet for wild falsehoods -- had plotted a global cyberattack.</p>

<p>To make that theory appear credible, many posts linked an old WEF video that warned about the possibility of a "cyberattack with Covid-like characteristics."</p>

<p>The video, available on the WEF's website, had cautioned that the only way to stop the exponential spread of the cyber threat would be to disconnect millions of vulnerable devices from each other and the internet.</p>

<p><strong>- 'Sad testament' -</strong><br />
&nbsp;The WEF has long been a target for conspiracy theorists pushing the idea of a shadowy cabal of elites working for private gain under the garb of solving global issues.</p>

<p>Also gaining rapid traction online were conspiratorial posts using the hashtag "cyber polygon," a reference to a global training event aimed at preparing for potential future attacks.</p>

<p>"The proliferation of conspiracy theories in the wake of major global events such as the outage is a sad testament to the volatile nature of the information ecosystem," Rafi Mendelsohn, vice president at the disinformation security company Cyabra, told AFP.</p>

<p>"What is unique to events like these is how social media platforms, forums, and messaging apps facilitate the rapid dissemination of content, allowing theories to gain traction quickly and reach a global audience."</p>

<p>The trend demonstrates the ability of falsehoods to mutate into viral narratives on tech platforms, which have scaled back content moderation and reinstated accounts that are known purveyors of misinformation.</p>

<p>During fast-developing news events, confusion now often reigns on major tech platforms, with users scrambling to obtain accurate information in what appears to be a sea of false or misleading posts that rapidly gain traction.</p>

<p><strong>- 'Nefarious motives' -</strong></p>

<p>"This poses the larger question of combatting mis- and disinformation," Michael W. Mosser, executive director of the Global Disinformation Lab at the University of Texas at Austin, told AFP.</p>

<p>"The level of trust that is required to accept information from reputable sources has declined to such an extent that people are more willing to believe wild conspiracies that 'must be true' rather than the factual information relayed to them."</p>

<p>The global outage, which brought myriad aspects of daily life to a standstill and sent US stocks falling, was linked to a bug in an update to an antivirus program for Windows systems from American cybersecurity group CrowdStrike.</p>

<p>Assurances by the Austin-based company's chief executive, George Kurtz, that CrowdStrike had rolled out a fix and was "actively working" to resolve the crisis did little to stem the spread of online conspiracies.</p>

<p>"Combatting this misinformation with factual rebuttals is difficult, because the issue is so technical," Mosser said.</p>

<p>"Explaining that the fault was in an improperly configured system file and that a fix is in process may be accurate, but it is not believed by those who are predisposed to see nefarious motives behind failures."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/b20d3j08_microsoft-blue-screen-error_625x300_19_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The proliferation of internet-breaking conspiracy theories on social media platforms.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-says-spoke-with-volodymyr-zelensky-pledges-to-end-the-war-6144927]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Says Spoke With Zelensky, Pledges To "End The War"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-says-spoke-with-volodymyr-zelensky-pledges-to-end-the-war-6144927]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 20 Jul 2024 05:43:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump said Friday he had spoken by telephone with Ukraine leader Volodymyr Zelensky, and pledged to end the European country's war with Russia.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump said Friday he had spoken by telephone with Ukraine leader Volodymyr Zelensky, and pledged to end the European country's war with Russia.</p>

<p>"I appreciate President Zelensky for reaching out because I, as your next President of the United States, will bring peace to the world and end the war that has cost so many lives and devastated countless innocent families," Trump said in a post on his Truth Social platform.</p>

<p>Zelensky confirmed the call, adding: "We agreed with President Trump to discuss at a personal meeting what steps can make peace fair and truly lasting."</p>

<p>"I noted the vital bipartisan and bicameral American support for protecting our nation's freedom and independence," he said in a post on social media platform X.</p>

<p>A Trump victory in the November US elections would put into question Washington's continued support for Ukraine, as the country struggles through a third year of fighting against Russian forces.</p>

<p>Trump, who on Thursday formally accepted the Republican Party's presidential nomination, has repeatedly claimed he would end the war very quickly, without offering details as to how.</p>

<p>Last week, the ex-president hosted at his Florida estate Hungary's Prime Minister Viktor Orban, who met with Russian President Vladimir Putin earlier this month.</p>

<p>Trump's frequent praise for Putin and reluctance to outright criticize the Russian invasion have stirred concerns among Ukraine's allies that he would force the country into accepting partial defeat.</p>

<p>He has also repeatedly suggested backing away from NATO. His running mate J.D. Vance leads the isolationist wing of congressional Republicans, who argue the United States should drop aid to Ukraine.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ojr3nf2_donald-trump_625x300_19_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Trump has repeatedly claimed he would end the war very quickly, without offering details as to how.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-is-the-best-person-to-take-on-trump-says-his-campaign-6144282]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Joe Biden Is The Best Person To Take On Trump, Says His Campaign]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-is-the-best-person-to-take-on-trump-says-his-campaign-6144282]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 20 Jul 2024 01:54:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Incumbent President Joe Biden is the best person to take on Donald Trump, the Republican presidential candidate in the November elections, his campaign said on Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;Incumbent President Joe Biden is the best person to take on Donald Trump, the Republican presidential candidate in the November elections, his campaign said on Friday.</p>

<p>"The president's in this race. You've heard him say that time and time again," chair of the Biden-Harris Campaign, Jen O'Malley Dillon, told MSNBC in an interview, a day after Trump accepted his nomination to be the Republican presidential candidate for the November general elections.</p>

<p>Many Democrats at the highest levels want Trump to bow out of the 2024 election to make way for a new nominee and try to prevent widespread party losses in November.</p>

<p>Dillon insisted that Biden is committed to fighting against Trump.</p>

<p>"I think we saw on display last night exactly why. Because Donald Trump is not going to offer anything new to the American people. He's the same person he was in 2020. He's the same person he was at the debate stage. He's the same person he is — about himself and not about the American people. Joe Biden is more committed than ever to beat Donald Trump," Dillon said.</p>

<p>"We believe in this campaign. We are built for the close election that we are in, and we see the path forward. The president is the leader of our campaign and of the country, and he is clearly in our impression, what we've built, and in our engagement with voters, he's the best person to take on Donald Trump and prosecute that case and present his vision versus what we saw last night," Dillon said.</p>

<p>"The president has the delegates. He has the support. He was elected in this process by 14 million voters. In 2020 by 81 million, more than anyone before him. The broad coalition of people that stand with the president is bigger and wider than the people who don't want him to run, and those are the people that are doing the work in the states that really matter, and I am confident when we get back to being able to go take the case to Donald Trump, we have the time to do it, and we can bring home the people that have some concerns or a little undecided today because when they see those two ahead and the visions they have for this country, there's no doubt in my mind that the American people are going to be with Joe Biden," Dillon said.</p>

<p>This is definitely a hard period for the campaign, Dillon said.</p>

<p>"But when the president has been out there talking to voters and being with voters when they have seen him, seen him lay out the contrast, shown that he is doing the job of leading this country and his [candidacy], they see in him the person that's going to win," Dillon said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/81g72018_joe-biden_625x300_19_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Joe Biden is more committed than ever to beat Donald Trump, chair of the Biden-Harris Campaign said.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/1-100-flights-cancelled-in-us-as-microsoft-outage-disrupts-operations-6143989]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[1,100 Flights Cancelled In US As Microsoft Outage Disrupts Operations]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/1-100-flights-cancelled-in-us-as-microsoft-outage-disrupts-operations-6143989]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 20 Jul 2024 00:29:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Air passengers around the United States faced delays, while some airlines halted flight operations as Microsoft-based computers ceased to work after a global outage on Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Air passengers around the United States faced delays, while some airlines halted flight operations as Microsoft-based computers ceased to work after a global outage on Friday.</p>

<p>Many airports across the US experienced unexpected disruption with over 1,100 flights getting cancelled and over 1,700 flights operating behind schedule on Friday morning (local time) after certain cloud services of Microsoft were disrupted.</p>

<p>These disruptions gave a hard time to people flying to and from different airports across the US, with many of them expressing their frustration over the unexpected delays and cancellations of flights.</p>

<p>"No one here knows anything, the gate agents said we all know as much as they do," a United Airlines passenger told ANI, saying his flight from Milwaukee to Washington was delayed for hours first at the gates and then hours on the tarmac.</p>

<p>Another passenger, Mack, said, "I am on my way home...I did not know that the internet was out. It is a global outage."</p>

<p>A passenger named Giane said, "I did not hear anything from the airline that I am travelling from. I just saw a news pop up on my phone...I am tired, I want to get home."</p>

<p>CrowdStrike -- an American cybersecurity technology firm that provides cloud workload protection, threat intelligence, and cyberattack response services - said the outage, which sparked chaos for many, was not a 'cyberattack'. Instead, there was an issue with software and a fix had been deployed.</p>

<p>Several US carriers, including American Airlines, United Airlines, and Delta Air Lines, issued ground stops for all their flights early on Friday due to communication problems, according to the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA).</p>

<p>The FAA told air traffic controllers to tell airborne pilots that airlines are currently experiencing communication issues. There were over 1,100 flights cancelled and more than 1,700 delays as of 8:05 am ET (Eastern Time), according to flight-tracking website FlightAware.</p>

<p>"A third-party software outage is impacting computer systems worldwide, including at United," United Airlines said in a statement on Friday morning. "While we work to restore those systems, we are holding all aircraft at their departure airports. Flights already airborne are continuing to their destinations."</p>

<p>"We're aware of a technical issue with CrowdStrike that is impacting multiple carriers. American is working with CrowdStrike to resolve the issue as quickly as possible and apologize to our customers for the inconvenience," American Airlines said in a statement.</p>

<p>The outage also affected industries ranging from banks to media companies.</p>

<p>"We're investigating an issue impacting users' ability to access various Microsoft 365 apps and services," Microsoft said in a statement released on social media Friday morning.</p>

<p>After various businesses across the world reported IT outages on Friday, which included seeing the 'Windows blue screen of death', CrowdStrike, the security firm linked to a software update that caused the outage said earlier in the day, that the issue has been isolated and a fix deployed.</p>

<p>George Kurtz, President and CEO of CrowdStrike, said the cybersecurity company was working with customers on the issues they faced while giving reassurance that the issue was "not a security incident or cyberattack."</p>

<p>Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella also reacted to the outage and said Microsoft is working closely with CrowdStrike to provide technical guidance and support to the customers.</p>

<p>"Yesterday, CrowdStrike released an update that began impacting IT systems globally. We are aware of this issue and are working closely with CrowdStrike and across the industry to provide customers technical guidance and support to safely bring their systems back online," Nadella posted on X.</p>

<p>On Friday the outage affected companies across various sectors, from airlines, banks, food chains and brokerage houses, to news organisations and railway networks. The travel industry was greatly affected, causing significant delays in flights across the world.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ghkcfpeg_microsoft-outage_625x300_19_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The outage also affected industries ranging from banks to media companies. (Represenational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/melania-trump-makes-rare-appearance-at-republican-national-convention-6143895]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Melania Trump Makes Rare Appearance At Republican National Convention]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/melania-trump-makes-rare-appearance-at-republican-national-convention-6143895]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 20 Jul 2024 00:04:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump's elusive wife Melania made a rare appearance at the Republican National Convention in support of Donald Trump's third bid for the White House, but broke with decades of tradition by not speaking at the event.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump's elusive wife Melania made a rare appearance at the Republican National Convention in support of Donald Trump's third bid for the White House, but broke with decades of tradition by not speaking at the event.</p>

<p>Wearing Republican red, Melania, 54, walked, alone, into the Republican National Convention in Milwaukee on Thursday accompanied by classical music.</p>

<p>She has kept a low profile during her husband's 2024 White House bid. She had not been spotted in Milwaukee since the convention kicked off on Monday.</p>

<p>Last week, Melania issued a statement calling for unity following an assassination attempt against Trump at a campaign rally in Pennsylvania.</p>

<p>"This morning, ascend above the hate, the vitriol, and the simple-minded ideas that ignite violence. We all want a world where respect is paramount, family is first, and love transcends. We can realise this world again. Each of us must demand to get it back. We must insist that respect fills the cornerstone of our relationships again," she said in a statement.</p>

<p>It is traditional at party conventions for the candidates' spouses to give a speech and tell heavily-scripted anecdotes about family life.</p>

<p>On Wednesday evening, Usha Vance - the wife of Trump's newly-minted running mate JD Vance - did just that. But Melania skipped delivering a speech.</p>

<p>Ever since her husband was first elected in 2016, Melania Trump has broken all the rules of normal American presidential politics.</p>

<p>In the White House during Trump's first term, she was a reclusive figure compared to other first ladies, focusing on a narrow set of interests.</p>

<p>And since her husband left office, she has not been seen by her husband's side on many occasions.</p>

<p>She wasn't there when he had his mugshot taken in Atlanta. She wasn't there in New York when he became the first former president to be convicted of a crime. And she wasn't there when he officially won his party's presidential nomination, for the third time, on Monday.</p>

<p>The former first lady spoke in both 2020 and 2016 during Trump's presidential nomination. She was accused of borrowing from Michelle Obama's 2008 speech in her first appearance in 2016.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/17bou6d8_melania-trump-donald-trump_625x300_20_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Melania Trump has kept a low profile during her husband's 2024 White House bid]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-capable-of-producing-fissile-material-for-nukes-in-1-or-2-weeks-us-6143850]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iran Capable Of Producing Fissile Material For Nukes In "1 Or 2 Weeks": US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-capable-of-producing-fissile-material-for-nukes-in-1-or-2-weeks-us-6143850]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Jul 2024 23:54:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iran is capable of producing fissile material for use in a nuclear weapon within "one or two weeks," US Secretary of State Antony Blinken said Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Iran is capable of producing fissile material for use in a nuclear weapon within "one or two weeks," US Secretary of State Antony Blinken said Friday.</p>

<p>News of Iran's capabilities follows the recent election of President Masoud Pezeshkian, who has said his goal is to "get Iran out of its isolation," and who favors reviving the 2015 nuclear deal between Iran and global powers.</p>

<p>Blinken said that "what we've seen in the last weeks and months is an Iran that's actually moving forward" with its nuclear program.</p>

<p>The United States unilaterally withdrew in 2018 from the Iran nuclear deal, which was designed to regulate Iran's atomic activities in exchange for the lifting of international sanctions.</p>

<p>Speaking at a security forum in Colorado, Blinken blamed the collapse of the nuclear deal for the acceleration in Iran's capabilities.</p>

<p>"Instead of being at least a year away from having the breakout capacity of producing fissile material for a nuclear weapon, (Iran) is now probably one or two weeks away from doing that," Blinken said.</p>

<p>He added that Iran had not yet developed a nuclear weapon.</p>

<p>Iran's acting Foreign Minister Ali Bagheri told CNN earlier this week that his country remained committed to the deal, known as the JCPOA.</p>

<p>"We are still a member of JCPOA. America has not yet been able to return to the JCPOA, so the goal we are pursuing is the revival of the 2015 agreement," he said. "We are not looking for a new agreement."</p>

<p>Bagheri added that: "Neither I nor anyone else in Iran has not talked and will not talk about a new agreement. We have an agreement (signed) in 2015."</p>

<p>Blinken made the statement just days after reports emerged that the US Secret Service increased security for Republican presidential nominee Donald Trump weeks ago, after authorities learned of an alleged Iranian plot to kill him.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/5vvg8bm_antony-blinken_625x300_02_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Blinken added that Iran had not yet developed a nuclear weapon. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-deploys-military-imposes-curfew-amid-violent-protests-6143771]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh Imposes Curfew, Deploys Military As 105 Die In Protests]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-deploys-military-imposes-curfew-amid-violent-protests-6143771]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Jul 2024 23:36:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Bangladeshi Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina's office on Friday announced the imposition of a nationwide curfew and the deployment of military forces to keep order after days of deadly student protests.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bangladesh on Friday announced the imposition of a curfew and the deployment of military forces after police failed to quell days of deadly unrest that has spread throughout the country.</p>

<p>This week's clashes between student demonstrators and police have killed at least 105 people, according to an AFP count of victims reported by hospitals, and pose a momentous challenge to Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina's autocratic government after 15 years in office.</p>

<p>"The government has decided to impose a curfew and deploy the military in aid of the civilian authorities," Hasina's press secretary Nayeemul Islam Khan told AFP.</p>

<p>He added that the curfew would take immediate effect.</p>

<p>Police in the capital Dhaka earlier took the drastic step of banning all public gatherings for the day -- a first since protests began -- in an effort to forestall more violence.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"We've banned all rallies, processions and public gatherings in Dhaka today," police chief Habibur Rahman told AFP, adding the move was necessary to ensure "public safety".</p>

<p>That however did not stop another round of confrontations between police and protesters around the sprawling megacity of 20 million people, despite an internet shutdown aimed at frustrating the organisation of rallies.</p>

<p>"Our protest will continue," Sarwar Tushar, who joined a march in the capital and sustained minor injuries when it was violently dispersed by police, told AFP.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"We want the immediate resignation of Sheikh Hasina. The government is responsible for the killings."</p>

<p>Student protesters stormed a jail in the central Bangladeshi district of Narsingdi and freed its inmates before setting the facility on fire, a police officer told AFP on condition of anonymity.</p>

<p>"I don't know the number of inmates, but it would be in the hundreds," he added.</p>

<p><strong>- 'Shocking and unacceptable' -</strong></p>

<p>At least 52 people were killed in the capital on Friday, according to a list drawn up by the Dhaka Medical College Hospital and seen by AFP.</p>

<p>Police fire was the cause of more than half of the deaths reported so far this week, based on descriptions given to AFP by hospital staff.&nbsp;</p>

<p>UN human rights chief Volker Turk said the attacks on student protesters were "shocking and unacceptable".</p>

<p>"There must be impartial, prompt and exhaustive investigations into these attacks, and those responsible held to account," he said in a statement.</p>

<p>The capital's police force earlier said protesters had on Thursday torched, vandalised and carried out "destructive activities" on numerous police and government offices.</p>

<p>Among them was the Dhaka headquarters of state broadcaster Bangladesh Television, which remains offline after hundreds of incensed students stormed the premises and set fire to a building.</p>

<p>Dhaka Metropolitan Police spokesman Faruk Hossain told AFP that officers had arrested Ruhul Kabir Rizvi Ahmed, one of the top leaders of the main opposition Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP).&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>- 'Symbol of a rigged system' -&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p>Near-daily marches this month have called for an end to a quota system that reserves more than half of civil service posts for specific groups, including children of veterans from the country's 1971 liberation war against Pakistan.</p>

<p>Critics say the scheme benefits children of pro-government groups that back Hasina, 76, who has ruled the country since 2009 and won her fourth consecutive election in January after a vote without genuine opposition.</p>

<p>Hasina's government is accused by rights groups of misusing state institutions to entrench its hold on power and stamp out dissent, including by the extrajudicial killing of opposition activists.</p>

<p>Her administration this week ordered schools and universities to close indefinitely as police stepped up efforts to bring the deteriorating law and order situation under control.</p>

<p>"This is an eruption of the simmering discontent of a youth population built over years," Ali Riaz, a politics professor at Illinois State University, told AFP.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The job quotas became the symbol of a system which is rigged and stacked against them by the regime."</p>

<p><strong>- 'Nation-scale' internet shutdown -</strong></p>

<p>Students say they are determined to press on with protests despite Hasina giving a national address earlier this week on the now-offline state broadcaster seeking to calm the unrest.</p>

<p>Nearly half of Bangladesh's 64 districts reported clashes on Thursday, broadcaster Independent Television reported.</p>

<p>London-based watchdog NetBlocks said Friday that a "nation-scale" internet shutdown remained in effect a day after it was imposed.</p>

<p>"Metrics show connectivity flatlining at 10% of ordinary levels, raising concerns over public safety as little news flows in or out of the country," it wrote on social media platform X.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/oje1tbbg_bangladesh_625x300_19_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Around 105 people have been killed in Bangladesh unrest.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/tesla-halted-some-production-lines-due-to-global-it-outage-report-6143727]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Tesla Halted Some Production Lines Due To Global IT Outage: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/tesla-halted-some-production-lines-due-to-global-it-outage-report-6143727]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Jul 2024 23:29:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Tesla halted some production lines due to the global IT outage, Business Insider reported on Friday, citing sources familiar with the matter.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Tesla halted some production lines due to the global IT outage, Business Insider reported on Friday, citing sources familiar with the matter.</p>

<p>The automaker sent some production employees home early during the night shift at its Austin, Texas and Sparks, Nevada facilities, the report added.</p>

<p>The tech outage crippled industries from travel to finance before services started coming back online after hours of disruption due a content update by CrowdStrike for Microsoft Windows hosts.</p>

<p>"We just deleted Crowdstrike from all our systems, so no rollouts at all," Tesla CEO Elon Musk said in a post on social media platform X, without specifying which of his companies had taken action or elaborating on the impact of the outage.</p>

<p>"This gave a seizure to the automotive supply chain," Musk said in a reply to a post by Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella on the outage.</p>

<p>"Users are seeing a blue screen on their devices," the report said, citing an internal notice, adding that the automaker was impacted by a Windows host outage, which caused issues with servers, laptops, and manufacturing devices.</p>

<p>CrowdStrike said it was working with customers impacted by a defect found "in a single content update for Windows hosts."</p>

<p>Tesla did not immediately respond to a Reuters request for comment.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ks0v9ri8_tesla-generic-reuters_625x300_19_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Tesla did not immediately respond to a Reuters request for comment. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/zuckerberg-not-planning-to-endorse-biden-or-trump-in-us-presidential-polls-6143695]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Zuckerberg "Not Planning" To Endorse Biden Or Trump In US Presidential Polls]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/zuckerberg-not-planning-to-endorse-biden-or-trump-in-us-presidential-polls-6143695]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Jul 2024 23:24:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Mark Zuckerberg said that former President Donald Trump's immediate reaction after being shot was "badass" and inspiring, and helps explain his appeal to voters.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Mark Zuckerberg said that former President Donald Trump's immediate reaction after being shot was "badass" and inspiring, and helps explain his appeal to voters.</p>

<p>"Seeing Donald Trump get up after getting shot in the face and pump his fist in the air with the American flag is one of the most badass things I've ever seen in my life," the Meta Platforms Inc. chief executive officer said Thursday during an interview at the company's headquarters in Menlo Park, California. "On some level as an American, it's like hard to not get kind of emotional about that spirit and that fight, and I think that that's why a lot of people like the guy."</p>

<p>Zuckerberg, 40, declined to endorse Trump or his presumed opponent, President Joe Biden, adding that he's "not planning" to be involved in the election in any way. Still, his comments add to a growing chorus of Silicon Valley leaders, including Tesla Inc. billionaire Elon Musk and venture capitalists Marc Andreessen and Ben Horowitz, who are warming to the former president, some pledging donations to his campaign. Zuckerberg made the comments during a wide-ranging discussion about the future of AI, social media and more for The Circuit with Emily Chang. The full episode is set to air on Tuesday.</p>

<p>Zuckerberg said Meta is making changes that he hopes will mean Facebook is not as much of a flashpoint in elections going forward. "The main thing that I hear from people is that they actually want to see less political content on our services because they come to our services to connect with people." Meta is already recommending less political content to its users, he added. "I think you're going to see our services play less of a role in this election than they have in the past."</p>

<p>Zuckerberg's relationship with Trump has been complicated by Trump's use of Meta's products to reach his followers. The former president's posts have routinely contained misinformation or challenged Meta's rules. The company suspended Trump from both Facebook and Instagram for two years in the wake of the January 6, 2021, Capitol riots. At the time, Zuckerberg posted that Trump was using his account to "undermine the peaceful and lawful transition of power to his elected successor."</p>

<p>While the accounts have since been reinstated, Trump indicated he hasn't forgiven Meta or Zuckerberg, and recently suggested that he plans to retaliate. He called Facebook the "enemy of the people" in March. Earlier this month, Trump also appeared to warn Zuckerberg. "All I can say is that if I'm elected President, we will pursue Election Fraudsters at levels never seen before, and they will be sent to prison for long periods of time," Trump wrote on Truth Social. "We already know who you are. DON'T DO IT! ZUCKERBUCKS, be careful!"</p>

<p>Trump has reversed policy positions in the name of punishing Meta. While he was president, Trump pushed for a ban of the Chinese-owned video app, TikTok. Trump has since changed his stance, arguing in Businessweek that a ban would be too beneficial to Meta's business.</p>

<p>Zuckerberg said he welcomes competition. "It's good," he said on The Circuit. "I think we're doing pretty well here. We're gaining market share. So I don't know. They'll go do what they need to do but I think we're gonna be fine and we're gonna continue doing well in this space either way."</p>

<p>When asked if he thought TikTok should be banned, Zuckerberg demurred. "That's above my pay grade," he said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/0hc64vf_mark-zuckerberg_625x300_26_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Zuckerberg, 40, declined to endorse Trump or Biden (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/vietnamese-most-powerful-communist-party-leader-nguyen-phu-trong-dies-at-80-6143533]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Vietnamese Most Powerful Communist Party Leader Nguyen Phu Trong Dies At 80]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/vietnamese-most-powerful-communist-party-leader-nguyen-phu-trong-dies-at-80-6143533]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Jul 2024 22:55:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The general secretary of Vietnam's Communist Party Nguyen Phu Trong -- considered the country's top leader -- died on Friday aged 80, his party said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The general secretary of Vietnam's Communist Party Nguyen Phu Trong -- considered the country's top leader -- died on Friday aged 80, his party said.</p>

<p>In a statement, it said Trong, who had led the party since 2011, died "due to old age and serious illness" at a military hospital in Hanoi.</p>

<p>The announcement came a day after the party announced Trong would hand the reins of power to the country's president and former public security minister To Lam, long seen as jockeying for the top job.</p>

<p>At the time, the party said Trong would be focusing on treatment for an undisclosed medical condition, the first time it had referenced longstanding speculation about the ageing leader's health.</p>

<p>There were no further details about Trong's illness on Friday, and the party said it would later make "a special statement on the organisation of the funeral at the national level".</p>

<p>Trong is the first party general secretary to die in office since the death in 1986 of Le Duan, a brother-in-arms of Ho Chi Minh.</p>

<p>He is also the first leader to have held three consecutive mandates at the head of the party, after the liberalisation of the economy in 1986.</p>

<p>US President Joe Biden called Trong a "champion of the deep ties" between the American and Vietnamese people, and said both countries were more secure because of the bilateral friendship fostered by the late leader.</p>

<p>Russian President Vladimir Putin hailed Trong as a "true friend" of Russia.</p>

<p>China's communist party sent a message of condolences to its Vietnamese counterpart, Chinese state media said.</p>

<p>Vietnam's communist regime, which is in the midst of a complete overhaul, has undergone a series of upheavals in recent months, with ministers, business leaders and two presidents all falling from grace as part of a vast anti-corruption campaign.</p>

<p>On Thursday, when it was announced Trong was handing over his duties, the politburo called "on the entire party, people and army to have absolute trust in the party's leadership and state management".</p>

<p>Lam was voted in as president in May by Vietnam's rubber-stamp parliament after his predecessor was forced to resign as part of the anti-graft drive.</p>

<p>Analysts said at the time that Lam, who was deputy head of the steering committee on anti-corruption matters, had weaponised investigations to take down his political rivals.</p>

<p>- 'Astonishing efficiency' -</p>

<p>Trong's poor health had fuelled widespread speculation that he would not be able to stay in power until the 2026 party congress, which is expected to appoint a successor.</p>

<p>He enjoyed remarkable longevity in office, during a mandate that rights groups say has coincided with increasing authoritarianism.</p>

<p>Known for being a technocrat and on good terms with Beijing, he structured the party around himself, benefiting from a decade of economic growth that strengthened his legitimacy.</p>

<p>"He restructured and reorganised the party around him" through his anti-corruption drive, said Benoit de Treglode, research director at the Institute for Strategic Research at France's military academy in Paris.</p>

<p>"Since 2011, he has cleaned up with astonishing efficiency."</p>

<p>The anti-corruption drive, which analysts say is also linked to political infighting, has swept through the party, police, armed forces and business community.</p>

<p>More than 3,500 people have been indicted since 2021, official figures show, while those sent to prison include a former health minister and two previous mayors of Hanoi.</p>

<p>Following a scandal related to the Covid-19 pandemic last year, President Nguyen Xuan Phuc resigned and two deputy prime ministers were removed from their positions.</p>

<p>Many other prominent officials working across a wide range of sectors, from environment and energy to healthcare and banking, are under investigation.</p>

<p>But the campaign has had unintended consequences. With many fearful of being caught in its crosshairs, everyday transactions within the business sector and the state apparatus have slowed.</p>

<p>Trong would like to be remembered "as a populist, someone very close to the people, who listens to the people", said Linh Nguyen, lead analyst for Control Risks on Vietnam.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/n5i6m7tg_nguyen-phu-trong_625x300_19_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Russian President Vladimir Putin hailed Nguyen Phu Trong as a "true friend" of Russia.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/no-unity-families-of-israeli-hostages-divided-on-how-to-secure-release-6143431]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["No Unity": Families Of Israeli Hostages Divided On How To Secure Release]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/no-unity-families-of-israeli-hostages-divided-on-how-to-secure-release-6143431]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Jul 2024 22:35:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The families of hostages grabbed by Hamas gunmen on October 7 noisily agree they want the captives home but are split on how best to achieve it.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The families of hostages grabbed by Hamas gunmen on October 7 noisily agree they want the captives home but are split on how best to achieve it.</p>

<p>"There is no unity among the families," said Dani Miran, whose 47-year-old son, Omri, was taken at gunpoint from the Nahal Oz kibbutz in Hamas's unprecedented attack on southern Israel.</p>

<p>"There are people on the left, on the right, religious people, secular and Bedouins. We have to find common ground," added the father.</p>

<p>Some direct their frustrations toward Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu, accusing him of sacrificing the captives in pursuit of "total victory" over Hamas.</p>

<p>Others back the government's stance that only increased military force in Gaza will return the remaining captives.</p>

<p>For almost 300 days, the families have tried to set their differences aside to join the solemn rallies staged at least once a week in Tel Aviv.</p>

<p>"The common point between us is that we want the hostages back. But everyone fights in his own way and I don't know which is the right one," said Miran.</p>

<p>The 79-year-old has sworn not to cut his long white beard until his son is returned. He also speaks at the rallies where families have been pushing Netanyahu to reach a truce deal before he visits the United States next week.</p>

<p><strong>Agreement now</strong></p>

<p>On Wednesday night, hundreds of families and their supporters gathered for a last-ditch push before the Israeli leader's departure.</p>

<p>"Netanyahu, without a deal, there is no travelling," read one man's sign.</p>

<p>Another warned, "Time is running out".</p>

<p>Netanyahu will speak before the US Congress on July 24 and is also expected to meet with President Joe Biden.</p>

<p>The visit comes after several months of indirect negotiations between Hamas and Israel, reinvigorating some families' hopes for a ceasefire agreement that would see hostages exchanged for Palestinian prisoners held by Israel.</p>

<p>Omri Shtivi, whose brother Idan is a captive in Gaza, said pushing for the deal was not political so much as "moral".</p>

<p>"We demand the return of our loved ones, we don't want to dismantle the government," he said.</p>

<p>At a gathering nearby, fellow hostage relative Yifat Kalderon disagreed, calling on the government to step down.</p>

<p>"We demand an end to the war immediately and an agreement now. That's the only way to bring them home," said Kalderon, whose French-Israeli cousin Ofer Kalderon was taken from the Nir Oz kibbutz.</p>

<p>"No heroic operation will bring them all back. In nine months, military operations have only saved seven people."</p>

<p>More than 100 hostages were freed during a week-long truce in November, leading many families to believe better odds lie with another deal.</p>

<p>During the October 7 attacks that sparked the war, Palestine's Hamas group seized 251 hostages, 116 of whom are still in Gaza, including 42 the Israeli military says are dead.</p>

<p>The surprise Hamas attack resulted in the deaths of 1,195 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli figures.</p>

<p>Israel's military retaliation has killed at least 38,848 people, also mostly civilians, according to data from the health ministry in Hamas-ruled Gaza</p>

<p><strong>'Until victory'</strong></p>

<p>Yaron Or, the father of hostage Avinatan, represents a minority camp that sees a ceasefire agreement as jeopardising Israel's future by putting it at risk of another attack.</p>

<p>"Fight until victory and bring back Avinatan," read his sign at Wednesday night's rally.</p>

<p>Avinatan was kidnapped from the Nova music festival with his girlfriend Noa Argamani, who was among four hostages rescued in June during an Israeli military raid.</p>

<p>"Only if the army takes control of the whole Gaza Strip and the inhabitants understand that Hamas is defeated will they free the hostages," said Or, who is part of a group of families who reject negotiations with Hamas.</p>

<p>Despite their divergent approaches, the hostage families are still coming together to push their shared goal: bring them home.</p>

<p>On Wednesday, central Tel Aviv was again filled with their shouts.</p>

<p>"Achshav," they chanted, "now".<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/b2q7apl8_protests-for-israeli-hostages_625x300_19_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[For almost 300 days, the families have tried to set their differences aside (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-york-city-council-member-allegedly-bites-cop-during-protest-arrested-for-assault-6143422]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[New York City Council Member Allegedly Bites Cop During Protest, Arrested]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-york-city-council-member-allegedly-bites-cop-during-protest-arrested-for-assault-6143422]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Jul 2024 22:34:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ms Zhuang was protesting the construction of a new homeless shelter at the corner of 25th Avenue and 86th Street in Bensonhurst on Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A New York City council member has been accused of biting a New York Police Department (NYPD) officer during a protest in Brooklyn. According to the<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/07/17/us-news/irate-nyc-councilwoman-busted-in-scream-filled-clash-with-cops-at-homeless-shelter-protest/"> <em>New York Post</em></a>, Susan Zhuang was protesting the construction of a new homeless shelter at the corner of 25th Avenue and 86th Street in Bensonhurst on Wednesday. In a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://x.com/EndWokeness/status/1813915101914644833">viral video of the incident,</a> New York City Councilwoman Ms Zhuang is allegedly seen biting Officer Frank DiGiacomo, the NYPD Chief of Patrol, when he tried to pull her away from the barriers.</p>

<p>Mr DiGiacomo's arm was left with teeth marks and broken skin, as evidenced <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://x.com/yuhline/status/1813770911268339996">by a photo</a> and detailed in the criminal complaint. He was treated with an "anti-viral cocktail" and given a tetanus shot.</p>

<p data-v-3808eee7="">"We are disappointed, disappointed in councilmember&nbsp;Susan Zhuang like she is a great partner, but we will not tolerate it. This is what she did to the officer. Bit the officer on the arm, as you can see the bite wound," NYPD Deputy Commissioner of Operations, Kaz Daughtry said.</p>

<p data-v-3808eee7="">Meanwhile, the councilwoman said she supports the NYPD but that there should be no double standard for conduct.&nbsp;She claimed she was protecting an elderly woman while protesting the homeless shelter. Ms&nbsp;Zhuang further said she informed the police that a woman was trapped under the barricade and needed assistance, but the officers did not respond to her request.</p>

<p>"Mistreatment by our NYPD, who I always support, must be stopped, AAPI hate and Asian hate in any form must end. I was approached from behind, two police officers handcuffed me, one police officer pulled my hair, and another officer grabbed my neck...the issue is not unique to me, as many members of the Asian community have been subject to this excessive enforcement and mistreatment by our NYPD'', she told <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://abc7ny.com/post/nyc-councilwoman-susan-zhuang-accused-biting-officer-speaks/15068420/">ABC7NY.</a></em></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Local residents in Bensonhurst are protesting a homeless shelter that was being opened at 5AM with NO consent from the community, or their Council Member Susan Zhuang! Zhuang stood up for her community, and was arrested this morning protesting this shelter. WE STAND WITH SUSAN… <a href="https://t.co/tCdTYD0jCp">pic.twitter.com/tCdTYD0jCp</a></p>
— Curtis Sliwa (@CurtisSliwa) <a href="https://twitter.com/CurtisSliwa/status/1813588907654611144?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 17, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>She has been charged with felony assault, obstruction of governmental administration and resisting arrest.&nbsp;She was released following an arraignment Wednesday evening and is scheduled to appear in court on October 15.&nbsp;</p>

<p>A council source told The Post that Zhuang's behaviour is "disqualifying for a council member."</p>

<p>"Violence is never acceptable and it is always important to respect city workers doing their jobs. We have seen the public footage circulating of today's incident and will be seeking to learn more about the details. The Council will respect the processes of the NYPD and Brooklyn District Attorney concerning this matter," a City Council spokesperson said.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/hedd1dfo_susan-zhuang_625x300_19_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mr DiGiacomo's arm was left with teeth marks and broken skin]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/this-gave-a-seizure-to-elon-musk-on-microsoft-ceo-satya-nadellas-update-on-outage-6143391]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["This Gave A Seizure To...": Musk On Microsoft CEO's Update On Outage]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/this-gave-a-seizure-to-elon-musk-on-microsoft-ceo-satya-nadellas-update-on-outage-6143391]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Jul 2024 22:30:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella has responded to the biggest tech outage in history after millions of Windows users worldwide experienced the Blue Screen of Death. The outage was caused by an update to CrowdStrike 'Falcon Sensor'.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella has responded to the biggest tech outage in history after millions of Windows users worldwide experienced the Blue Screen of Death. The outage was caused by an update to CrowdStrike 'Falcon Sensor'.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Microsoft CEO posted an update on X and said, "Yesterday, CrowdStrike released an update that began impacting IT systems globally. We are aware of this issue and are working closely with CrowdStrike and across the industry to provide customers technical guidance and support to safely bring their systems back online."</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Yesterday, CrowdStrike released an update that began impacting IT systems globally. We are aware of this issue and are working closely with CrowdStrike and across the industry to provide customers technical guidance and support to safely bring their systems back online.</p>
— Satya Nadella (@satyanadella) <a href="https://twitter.com/satyanadella/status/1814329337451344250?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 19, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>X CEO and Tesla Founder Elon Musk was quick to take a swipe at Mr Nadella's update and said, "This gave a seizure to the automotive supply chain."</p>

<p>Mr Musk has been posting memes and reacting to posts on X on the global outage. He reposted his 2021 post on X in which he said, "Macrohard &gt; Microsoft".&nbsp;</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="qst">… <a href="https://t.co/X9a2ghyo4P">https://t.co/X9a2ghyo4P</a></p>
— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1814203437275361458?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 19, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p><strong>CrowdStrike On Outage</strong></p>

<p>In a statement on X, CrowdStrike CEO George Kurtz said that the company is working with customers who have been impacted by a defect found in a single content update for Windows hosts, adding that Mac- and Linux-based systems have not been affected.</p>

<p>Emphasising that the outage is not a security incident or cyberattack, he wrote, &nbsp;"The issue has been identified, isolated and a fix has been deployed. We refer customers to the support portal for the latest updates and will continue to provide complete and continuous updates on our website."</p>

<p>"We further recommend organizations ensure they're communicating with CrowdStrike representatives through official channels. Our team is fully mobilized to ensure the security and stability of CrowdStrike customers," he added.</p>

<p>Speaking to the 'Today' programme on NBC News later, Mr Kurtz said his company would make sure every customer is "fully recovered".&nbsp;</p>

<p>"We are deeply sorry for the impact that we have caused to customers, to travellers, to anyone affected by this, including our company," he was quoted as saying by news agency Reuters.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Outages In India</strong></p>

<p>In India, almost all air carriers -- Vistara, IndiGo, SpiceJet and Akasa Air -- faced technical issues that affected booking, check-in, and flight updates. The airlines were checking in passengers manually.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Civil Aviation Minister Rammohan Naidu said the ministry and the Airports Authority of India (AAI) are actively managing the situation using manual methods to ensure minimal disruption. "Passengers are advised to cooperate with airport staff during this period of disruption. We have instructed all airlines and airport authorities to keep passengers informed about their flight status and provide necessary assistance," he said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/b78edc8_elon-musk-satya-nadella_625x300_19_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/adidas-drops-pro-palestinian-model-bella-hadid-from-ad-referencing-1973-munich-olympics-6143343]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Adidas Drops Pro-Palestinian Bella Hadid From Ad Referencing Munich Olympics]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/adidas-drops-pro-palestinian-model-bella-hadid-from-ad-referencing-1973-munich-olympics-6143343]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Jul 2024 22:22:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Adidas said Friday it had dropped vocal pro-Palestinian model Bella Hadid from an advertising campaign for retro sneakers referencing the 1972 Munich Olympics, which were overshadowed by a massacre of Israeli athletes.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Adidas said Friday it had dropped vocal pro-Palestinian model Bella Hadid from an advertising campaign for retro sneakers referencing the 1972 Munich Olympics, which were overshadowed by a massacre of Israeli athletes.</p>

<p>The German sportswear giant recently relaunched the SL72, a shoe first showcased by athletes at the 1972 Olympics, as part of a series reviving old classic sneakers.</p>

<p>Eleven Israeli athletes and a German police officer were killed at the 1972 Munich Games after gunmen from the Palestinian Black September group broke into the Olympic village and took them hostage.</p>

<p>Bella Hadid, who was born in the US but has Palestinian roots through her father, has been vocal about her support for Palestinian rights since the Hamas attack on Israel on October 7 triggered the war in Gaza.</p>

<p>Adidas said it would be "revising the remainder of the campaign" with immediate effect.</p>

<p>"We are conscious that connections have been made to tragic historical events -- though these are completely unintentional -- and we apologise for any upset or distress caused," the company said in a statement sent to AFP on Friday.</p>

<p><strong>'Collective memory'</strong></p>

<p>A spokeswoman confirmed that Bella Hadid had been removed from the campaign, which notes that the shoes were first introduced in 1972 but never mentions the terror attack on the Israeli athletes.</p>

<p>Pictures of the American model wearing the retro Adidas shoes had caused an outcry among pro-Israeli groups.</p>

<p>"Guess who the face of the campaign is? Bella Hadid, a model with Palestinian roots who has spread anti-Semitism in the past and incited violence against Israelis and Jews," the Israeli embassy in Germany wrote on X, formerly Twitter, on Thursday.</p>

<p>"How can Adidas now claim that the reference (to the events in Munich) was 'completely unintentional'?" Ron Prosor, Israel's ambassador to Germany, said in response to the company's climbdown.</p>

<p>"The terror of 1972 is etched into the collective memory of Germans and Israelis," he told Die Welt TV on Friday.</p>

<p>A flood of social media posts meanwhile expressed support for Bella Hadid, criticised Adidas for axing the model, and called for a boycott of the company.</p>

<p><strong>Pro-Palestinian demonstrations</strong></p>

<p>The Gaza war was triggered by the October 7 attack by Palestinian Hamas militants on southern Israel which resulted in the deaths of 1,195 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli figures.</p>

<p>Israel's military retaliation to wipe out Hamas has killed at least 38,848 people, also mostly civilians, according to data from the health ministry in Hamas-ruled Gaza.</p>

<p>Bella Hadid has taken part in several pro-Palestinian demonstrations during the conflict and has described Israel's offensive as a "genocide".</p>

<p>In 2021, Bella Hadid, her sister Gigi Hadid and singer Dua Lipa were described as anti-Semitic in an advertisement published in The New York Times by a Jewish group called the World Values Network.</p>

<p>Adidas said it would be continuing the SL72 campaign with other famous faces including footballer Jules Kounde, singer Melissa Bon and model Sabrina Lan.</p>

<p>In late 2022, Adidas ended its contract with the US rapper now known formally as Ye after he triggered an outcry with a series of anti-Semitic social media posts.</p>

<p>Germany's response to the Hamas attack and ensuing war has been driven by guilt over its own dark past, and the slaughter of six million Jews by the Nazis during the Holocaust.</p>

<p>The country has steadfastly backed Israel in the conflict, but its unwavering stance has led to claims that Palestinian voices are being marginalised.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/mm4vjgio_bella-hadid_625x300_21_May_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Bella Hadid was born in the US but has Palestinian roots through her father (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-jails-us-reporter-evan-gershkovich-for-16-years-for-espionage-6143276]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russia Jails US Reporter Evan Gershkovich For 16 Years For "Espionage"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-jails-us-reporter-evan-gershkovich-for-16-years-for-espionage-6143276]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Jul 2024 22:11:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US reporter Evan Gershkovich was sentenced by a Russian court on Friday to 16 years prison for "espionage", a verdict slammed as "despicable", "disgraceful" and a "sham" by Western governments and his employer.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US reporter Evan Gershkovich was sentenced by a Russian court on Friday to 16 years prison for "espionage", a verdict slammed as "despicable", "disgraceful" and a "sham" by Western governments and his employer.</p>

<p>Gershkovich was sentenced after just three court sessions in a secretive closed-door trial in the Urals City of Yekaterinburg, the city where he was arrested while on a reporting trip in March 2023.</p>

<p>After the sentencing, US President Joe Biden said Gershkovich was "targeted by the Russian government because he is a journalist and an American."</p>

<p>"There is no question that Russia is wrongfully detaining Evan," he said.</p>

<p>"We are pushing hard for Evan's release and will continue to do so," he added in a written statement published by the White House.</p>

<p>Both Washington and Moscow say talks over a prisoner swap are ongoing.</p>

<p>Russia has previously said its policy is not to trade people before they have been convicted, suggesting Friday's sentence could pave the way for the 32-year-old journalist to finally be swapped in a deal.</p>

<p>In court on Friday, Gershkovich did not appear to react to the sentencing, standing in a glass defendants' cage in dark trousers and a T-shirt. He waved to his journalist colleagues as he was led away.</p>

<p>Judge Andrei Mineyev said said Gershkovich would be sent to a "strict regime colony" -- a Russian prison camp notorious for harsh conditions and strict rules.</p>

<p><strong>'Disgraceful, sham conviction'</strong></p>

<p>The Wall Street Journal correspondent, who pleaded not guilty, became the first journalist in Russia to be charged with spying since the Cold War when he was detained in 2023.</p>

<p>He has spent almost 16 months in detention on charges the United States government and his employer have always said are fabricated.</p>

<p>"This disgraceful, sham conviction comes after Evan has spent 478 days in prison, wrongfully detained, away from his family and friends, prevented from reporting, all for doing his job as a journalist," the Journal's publisher Almar Latour and editor-in-chief Emma Tucker said in a statement.</p>

<p>Washington believes he is being held as a bargaining chip to secure the release of Russians convicted abroad.</p>

<p>His trial has moved rapidly since the first hearing in late June, with the prosecution and defence teams giving their final arguments on Friday.</p>

<p>Other similar cases in Russia have dragged on far more slowly, with several weeks or even months between hearings.</p>

<p>Western governments expressed outrage at the verdict.</p>

<p>British Prime Minister Keir Starmer called it "despicable," adding that it "only serves to underscore Russia's utter contempt for media freedom."</p>

<p>German Foreign Minister Annalena Baerbock said the case was "politically motivated" and demonstrated Russian President Vladimir "Putin's fear of the power of facts."</p>

<p><strong>Talks ongoing</strong></p>

<p>The Kremlin has provided no public evidence for the espionage allegations, saying only that Gershkovich was caught "red-handed" spying on a tank factory in the Urals region while working for the CIA.</p>

<p>The prosecutor said Friday that Gershkovich acted with "careful measures of secrecy".</p>

<p>Tensions are running extremely high between the countries over Moscow's military offensive in Ukraine.</p>

<p>Moscow and Washington have both said they are open to exchanging the reporter in a deal, but neither has given clues on when that might happen.</p>

<p>When asked Friday, the Kremlin refused to speculate about the prospect of a prisoner swap.</p>

<p>Moscow's Foreign Minister Sergei Lavrov said Wednesday that talks between US and Russian special services over possible prisoner exchanges were ongoing, without naming any specific individuals.</p>

<p>Putin has implied he wants to see the release of Vadim Krasikov, a Russian convicted in Germany of killing a Chechen separatist commander. German judges said it was an assassination orchestrated by Russian authorities.</p>

<p>Among other US nationals detained in Russia are reporter Alsu Kurmasheva and ballerina Ksenia Karelina, who are both dual US-Russian citizens, and former US marine Paul Whelan, who is serving a 16-year sentence for spying.</p>

<p>In his statement Friday, Biden said he had "no higher priority than seeking the release and safe return of Evan, Paul Whelan and all Americans wrongfully detained and held hostage abroad."</p>

<p><strong>'Arbitrary' detention</strong></p>

<p>The US-born son of Soviet emigres raised in New Jersey, Gershkovich had reported from Russia since 2017, still returning for reporting trips following Russia's Ukraine offensive.</p>

<p>In Moscow's isolated Lefortovo prison, where he was held for more than a year in pre-trial detention, he communicated with friends and family in hand-written letters that revealed he had not lost hope.</p>

<p>A United Nations working group this month stated that Gershkovich's detention on spying charges was "arbitrary" and called for his release.</p>

<p>The White House has warned US citizens still in Russia to "depart immediately" due to the risk of wrongful arrest.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/se9o7g48_evan-gershkovich_625x300_19_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Both Washington and Moscow say talks over a prisoner swap are ongoing.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-absolutely-staying-in-us-presidential-race-says-his-campaign-chair-6143220]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden "Absolutely" Staying In US Presidential Race, Says His Campaign Chair]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-absolutely-staying-in-us-presidential-race-says-his-campaign-chair-6143220]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Jul 2024 22:03:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden is "absolutely" staying in the race for the White House, his campaign chair said Friday, despite mounting pressure from Democratic allies to step aside over worries about his age and health.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden is "absolutely" staying in the race for the White House, his campaign chair said Friday, despite mounting pressure from Democratic allies to step aside over worries about his age and health.</p>

<p>Jen O'Malley Dillon acknowledged there had been some "slippage" in support since the 81-year-old's disastrous debate performance against Donald Trump, but insisted he would still win in November.</p>

<p>"Absolutely the president's in this race," Jen O'Malley Dillon told MSNBC's Morning Joe program. "Joe Biden is more committed than ever to beat Donald Trump."</p>

<p>She added: "You have heard from the president directly time and again, he is in this race to win, and he is our nominee, and he's going to be our president for a second term."</p>

<p>Biden is currently holed up at his beach house in Delaware self-isolating with Covid.</p>

<p>Senior Democrats including former president Barack Obama, former House speaker Nancy Pelosi and the party's current leaders in the Senate and House have all reportedly expressed concerns that he will lose the election.</p>

<p>Twenty Democrats in the US House and two senators have meanwhile called on him to step aside from the race.</p>

<p>O'Malley Dillon, Biden's former deputy chief of staff, admitted that the campaign had faced a difficult time since he appeared tired and confused in the June 27 debate.</p>

<p>"I'm not here to say that this hasn't been a tough several weeks for the campaign," she said.</p>

<p>"There's no doubt that it has been, and we've definitely seen some slippage in support, but it has been a small movement."</p>

<p>A series of recent polls have shown Biden behind Trump in the 2024 race, including in all key battleground states.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/81g72018_joe-biden_625x300_19_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Biden is currently holed up at his beach house in Delaware self-isolating with Covid. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/decision-of-lies-israel-pm-netanyahu-on-world-courts-palestine-order-6143170]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Decision Of Lies": Israel PM Netanyahu On World Court's Palestine Order]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/decision-of-lies-israel-pm-netanyahu-on-world-courts-palestine-order-6143170]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Jul 2024 21:57:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said the International Court of Justice made a "decision of lies" on Friday by ruling Israel's occupation of the Palestinian territories illegal.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said the International Court of Justice made a "decision of lies" on Friday by ruling Israel's occupation of the Palestinian territories illegal.</p>

<p>Netanyahu led a chorus of condemnation of the UN court's ruling from conservative, far-right and even centrist politicians in Israel.</p>

<p>"The Jewish people are not occupiers in their own land -- not in our eternal capital Jerusalem, nor in our ancestral heritage of Judea and Samaria" (the occupied West Bank), Netanyahu said in a statement.</p>

<p>"No decision of lies in The Hague will distort this historical truth, and similarly, the legality of Israeli settlements in all parts of our homeland cannot be disputed."</p>

<p>Itamar Ben Gvir, the far-right national security minister and an outspoken champion of Jewish settlement expansion in the occupied West Bank, said: "The decision in The Hague proves yet again - this is a blatantly anti-Semitic and political organisation.</p>

<p>"We will not accept moral preaching from them," the minister said in comments sent to AFP by a spokesperson.</p>

<p>Ben Gvir called for Israel to seek "sovereignty" of the occupied territories through annexation.</p>

<p>Far-right Finance Minister Bezalel Smotrich too called for steps towards annexation of the West Bank, posting on social media platform X: "The answer to The Hague - sovereignty now."</p>

<p>Centrist opposition leader Yair Lapid criticised the court's ruling, calling it "disconnected, one-sided, tainted with anti-Semitism and lacking an understanding of the reality on the ground".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/109p0llo_benjamin-netanyahu_625x300_19_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Netanyahu led a chorus of condemnation of the UN court's ruling (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israels-occupation-of-palestinian-territory-illegal-un-top-court-6143148]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel's Occupation Of Palestinian Territory "Illegal": UN Top Court]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israels-occupation-of-palestinian-territory-illegal-un-top-court-6143148]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Jul 2024 21:51:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel's decades-long occupation of the Palestinian territories is illegal and needs to end "as rapidly as possible", the UN's top court said Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel's decades-long occupation of the Palestinian territories is illegal and needs to end "as rapidly as possible", the UN's top court said Friday.</p>

<p>The UN's General Assembly asked the International Court of Justice (ICJ) in late 2022 to give an "advisory opinion" on the "legal consequences arising from the policies and practices of Israel in the Occupied Palestinian Territory, including East Jerusalem".</p>

<p>"The court has found that Israel's continued presence in the Palestinian Territories is illegal," ICJ presiding judge Nawaf Salam said Friday, adding: "Israel must end the occupation as rapidly as possible."</p>

<p>"The Court has found that Israel's... continued presence in the Occupied Palestinian Territory is illegal," Salam said.</p>

<p>"The State of Israel is under the obligation to bring an end to its unlawful presence in the Occupied Palestinian Territory as rapidly as possible," the judge said.</p>

<p>The ICJ held a week-long session in February to hear submissions from countries following the request -- supported by most countries within the assembly.</p>

<p>Most speakers during the hearings called on Israel to end its 57-year occupation. They warned a prolonged occupation posed an "extreme danger" to stability in the Middle East and beyond.</p>

<p>But the United States said Israel should not be legally obliged to withdraw without taking its "very real security needs" into account.</p>

<p>Israel did not take part in the oral hearings.</p>

<p>Instead, it submitted a written contribution in which it described the questions the court had been asked as "prejudicial" and "tendentious".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/iudl9vb_icj-on-israel-palestine-occupation_625x300_19_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel did not take part in the oral hearings. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-pics-bangladesh-on-fire-buildings-vehicles-burnt-amid-ongoing-clashes-6142760]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[In Pics: Bangladesh On Fire, Buildings, Vehicles Burnt Amid Ongoing Clashes]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-pics-bangladesh-on-fire-buildings-vehicles-burnt-amid-ongoing-clashes-6142760]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Jul 2024 20:53:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Violent clashes broke out between students and cops in Bangladesh last month over the newly reinstated reservation system for hiring in civil services. Around 64 people have been killed in this week due to clashes.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Violent clashes broke out between students and cops in Bangladesh last month over the newly reinstated reservation system for hiring in civil services. Around 64 people have been killed this week, according to news agency AFP and over 2,500 injured in the clashes.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/rd350b5o_bangladesh-protests_625x300_19_July_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: AFP</span></p>
</div>

<p>The protests erupted after a High Court in Bangladesh reinstated the reservation of 30% government jobs for the family members of freedom fighters and veterns from 1971 War of Independance.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/kf6jr0s_bangladesh-protests_625x300_19_July_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: AFP</span></p>
</div>

<p>Bangladesh Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina addressed the nation on Wednesday hoping to calm the situation, however, the protestors set on fire the country's state broadcaster building a day after her address.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont">
<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/hlac1jcg_bangladesh-protests_625x300_19_July_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: AFP</span></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>

<p>Today, the proestors stormed and set on fire a jail in Bangladeshi district of Narsingdi, according to new agency AFP.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/htorno4_bangladesh-protests_625x300_19_July_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: AFP</span></p>
</div>

<p>"The inmates fled the jail and the protesters set the jail on fire. I don't know the number of inmates, but it would be in the hundreds," a cop told AFP on the condition of anonymity.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/hsp963i8_bangladesh-protests_625x300_19_July_24.jpg?im=FitAndFill,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: AFP</span></p>
</div>

<p>The Bangadesh Supreme Court has suspended the High Court's order on reservation and is set to hear the government's challenge on August 7.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/vfvgv7ug_bangladesh-clashes_625x300_19_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The protestors set on fire the country's state broadcaster building yesterday (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/crowdstrike-ceo-says-deeply-sorry-for-tech-outage-report-6142044]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[CrowdStrike CEO Says "Deeply Sorry" For Tech Outage: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/crowdstrike-ceo-says-deeply-sorry-for-tech-outage-report-6142044]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Jul 2024 19:24:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[CrowdStrike CEO George Kurtz apologized for a global tech failure that disrupted multiple industries on Friday, vowing to work with all of its customers as they work to get their operations back online.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>CrowdStrike CEO George Kurtz apologized for a global tech failure that disrupted multiple industries on Friday, vowing to work with all of its customers as they work to get their operations back online.</p>

<p>"We're deeply sorry for the impact that we've caused to customers, to travelers, to anyone affected by this, including our company," he told NBC News' "Today" program.</p>

<p>"Many of the customers are rebooting the system and it's coming up and it'll be operational," George Kurtz said. "It could be some time for some systems that won't automatically recover," he added, but the company "would make sure every customer is fully recovered."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/oj4oa5l_microsoft-generic-afp_625x300_19_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The company "would make sure every customer is fully recovered," said George Kurtz]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>