<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 19:22:29 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/skydiving-student-instructor-die-in-us-after-hitting-dust-devil-during-routine-jump-6301454]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Skydiving Student, Instructor In US Die After Hitting "Dust Devil"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/skydiving-student-instructor-die-in-us-after-hitting-dust-devil-during-routine-jump-6301454]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 18:54:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 28-year-old skydiving student in the United States was killed alongside her diving instructor after the pair hit a "dust devil" in California.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 28-year-old skydiving student in the United States was killed alongside her diving instructor after the pair hit a "dust devil" in California. A dust devil is a small but strong tornado-like whirlwind that forms in very hot conditions and can reach heights of several thousand feet. According to the <em>New York Post</em>, the woman, identified as Kayla Kieko Black, was skydiving with veteran instructor Devry LaRiccia Chase on Friday when a "dust devil" sent them into an "uncontrollable spin" that plunged them to their deaths.</p>

<p>"Kayla was deeply cherished by her family and friends, who will forever remember her kindness, warmth and unwavering support," Ms Black's family said in a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.gofundme.com/f/in-memory-of-kayla-kieko-black-support-for-her-family">GoFundMe page</a>. "In this time of immense sorrow we find solace in knowing that Kayla's legacy will live on through her selfless decision to be an organ donor. Her generosity will provide hope and new beginnings for many individuals and families in need," it added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/08/08/us-news/skydiving-student-killed-in-freak-accident-idd-as-kayla-kieko-black/"><em>Post</em></a>, the 28-year-old was jumping in tandem with Devry LaRiccia Chase, an instructor with Skydive Perrisand. The instructor was able to glide away from the first gust but two were trapped in the second. "Eyewitnesses report that the tandem pair experience a normal free fall and parachute deployment," the skydiving firm's manager Dan Brodsky-Chenfeld said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"All aspects of the equipment and skydive was normal without any reported issues until the landing sequence. While preparing for landing the tandem pair hit disturbed air known as a 'dust devil.' The interaction with this sudden disturbed air causes turbulence and a hard landing for both individuals," the manager added.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read | <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/feature/emergency-helpline-is-a-joke-x-user-accuses-zomato-of-neglect-after-delivery-agents-accident-in-delhi-6300697">X User Accuses Zomato Of Neglect After Delivery Agent's Accident In Delhi</a></strong></p>

<p>After the incident, both, the instructor and the skydiving student, were rushed to a local hospital. Ms LaRiccia's family also started a GoFundMe page to help bring her body to her native state of Maine for burial, with the site raising more than $59,000 by Thursday afternoon.</p>

<p>The instructor's husband, Freddy Chase, told People he wants Ms Black's family to know that he is "truly sorry for what happened" but that he's "glad that she got to share the last conversation with Devrey ever." He previously also stated that "there was no malfunction" before the incident. He explained that his wife was conducting her final jump of the day when she noticed the dust devils and got caught in one. "It then sent her canopy in an uncontrolled spin to the ground," he said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/ci0mr7b8_skydiving-generic_625x300_09_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The incident took place on Friday in California. (Representative pic)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/bangladeshs-new-reality-may-not-bode-well-for-indias-security-6300916]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: Bangladesh's New Reality Doesn't Bode Well For India's Security]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/bangladeshs-new-reality-may-not-bode-well-for-indias-security-6300916]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 17:47:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[At a time when India sees itself as a leading global power, it cannot afford to ignore the challenges emanating from Bangladesh, its most important partner in South Asia.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"></div>
</div>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/0i41r56g_bangladesh_625x300_09_August_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>An interim government led by Nobel laureate Muhammad Yunus has taken charge of a fractured Bangladesh after a meeting between President Mohammed Shahabuddin, military leaders and student activists. Promising to "uphold, support and protect the constitution", Yunus has called for the restoration of law and order as his government faces the reality of the withering away of state apparatus. Sheikh Hasina is gone, but the real challenge begins now. A new reality confronts the people of Bangladesh. There is a new sense of optimism, but it is embedded in a deeply divided society and polity.</p>

<h2><strong>From Certainty To Doubts</strong></h2>

<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi has already extended his best wishes to Professor Muhammad Yunus on his new role and has expressed hope for a swift return to normalcy, emphasising the importance of ensuring the safety and protection of Hindus and all minority communities. For India, challenges abound as Hasina, its long-standing partner, had to depart in ignominy. The certainty of the last 15 years has given way to a sense of the unknown. New Delhi had invested in its partnership with Dhaka confident that the Hasina dispensation would not let it down. As a result, a bilateral partnership that followed could not only resolve some of the most testing challenges but it also emerged as an anchor in the wider Bay of Bengal.</p>

<p>However, Hasina's tendency to centralise decision-making and marginalise the opposition managed to limit Bangladesh's evolution into a mature democracy. As Hasina drifted towards authoritarianism, New Delhi's options got further curtailed. Now, India has to ensure that it manages to build ties with the new leadership in Dhaka.</p>

<h2><strong>Building New Relationships</strong></h2>

<p>After signalling clearly that India will stand by its allies by getting Hasina out of Bangladesh, the next step is to engage the emerging political stakeholders in Bangladesh. This is needed not only for the long-term stability of Delhi-Dhaka ties but also for managing the immediate challenges of protecting minorities within Bangladesh and stabilising the highly volatile border area.</p>

<p>India shares a largely porous 4,096 km of land border with Bangladesh. This border runs along the states of West Bengal, Assam, Meghalaya, Tripura and Mizoram, areas once frequented by insurgent groups. However, under Hasina's leadership, the border remained relatively calm, as these groups have been prevented from finding refuge in Bangladesh. There are already reports of turbulence and New Delhi has asked its border security forces to be on high alert. With India facing serious challenges along its borders with Pakistan and China, the new reality with Bangladesh bodes ill for national security.</p>

<h2><strong>Extremism Remains A Concern</strong></h2>

<p>The rise of Islamist extremism in Bangladesh is another challenge that New Delhi will be closely watching. Before Hasina, various extremist groups were flourishing under the patronage of the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) government. Many of these groups, such as the Ansarullah Bangla Team, the Hizb ut-Tahrir, and the Jamaat-ul-Mujahideen Bangladesh (JMB), have had links to various terrorist outfits based in Pakistan as well as to the Inter-Services Intelligence (ISI). The present situation in Bangladesh opens up new possibilities for reviving these links. Jamaat-e-Islami is widely viewed as a key instigator of the recent riots that toppled Hasina. The Hasina government had banned it in 2013, but today it has re-emerged as a major political force.</p>

<p>The systematic targeting of Hindus also poses a challenge to India-Bangladesh ties as it will harden the mood in New Delhi against any engagement with Dhaka. Domestic politics in both nations will have to maturely handle rapidly deteriorating perceptions about each other.</p>

<h2><strong>Balancing Other Neighbours</strong></h2>

<p>In recent years, the two South Asian neighbours have been focused on enhancing trade and connectivity so as to turn the Bay of Bengal into a hub of regional economic framework. Political trust is a crucial variable in shaping today's economic partnerships. Unless the new government in Dhaka is able to generate trust in Delhi, it won't be possible to revive the old paradigm of bilateral economic engagement. This would be a loss for India as its ability to make its northeastern region economically dynamic is premised on strong India-Bangladesh economic ties. But it would also be a loss for Bangladesh, which has effectively leveraged its two regional economic partners - India and China - to reinvigorate its economic potential.</p>

<p>New Delhi would also be wary of Pakistan and China trying to fish in the troubled waters of the Bay of Bengal. The logic of geography dictates that both Delhi and Dhaka will have to engage each other to nurture their aspiration. It is easy to forget how much despair there was about India-Bangladesh ties before Hasina had come to power. But at a time when India sees itself as a leading global power, it cannot afford to ignore the challenges emanating from its most important partner in South Asia.</p>

<p><em>(Harsh V Pant is Vice-President for Studies at ORF)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/6t4lds3_bangladesh_625x300_09_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/amid-fears-of-israel-iran-war-air-india-latest-message-for-fliers-6300756]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Amid Fears Of Israel-Iran War, Air India's Latest Message For Fliers]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/amid-fears-of-israel-iran-war-air-india-latest-message-for-fliers-6300756]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 17:26:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Air India will not run flights to and from Tel Aviv amid escalating tensions between Israel and Iran, the airlines said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Air India will not run flights to and from Tel Aviv amid escalating tensions between Israel and Iran, the airlines said. The decision to suspend services to Tel Aviv was first taken on August 2, but the Tata Group-owned carrier was expected to resume operations today.</p>

<p>But Air India has said that Tel Aviv flights will remain suspended until further notice.</p>

<p>"In view of the current situation in parts of the Middle East, scheduled operation of our flights to and from Tel Aviv are suspended with immediate effect until further notice," the airlines said in a post on X (formerly Twitter)</p>

<p>"We are continuously monitoring the situation and are offering a full refund to our passengers with confirmed bookings for travel to and from Tel Aviv. Safety of our guests and crew remains our topmost priority," it added.</p>

<p>Earlier this year also, Air India had briefly suspended flights to Tel Aviv at different points of time due to the Middle East tensions.</p>

<p>After nearly five months, the carrier had recommenced the services to the Israeli city on March 3.</p>

<p>Air India had suspended flights to and from Tel Aviv starting on October 7, 2023, after the Hamas group's attack on the Israeli city</p>

<p>Tensions continue to remain high in the Middle East amid conflict between Israel and various terror groups, including Hamas.</p>

<p>As Gaza's war churns on, Israel has been battening down for another attack expected in the coming days following vows from Iran and its Lebanon proxy Hezbollah to retaliate for the assassinations last week of Hamas leader Ismail Haniyeh in Tehran and Hezbollah military commander Fuad Shukr in Beirut.</p>

<p>A relatively contained conflict between Israel and Hezbollah along its northern border, a spillover from the Gaza fighting, now threatens to spiral into an all-out regional war.</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/i6fk4h4g_israelhezbollah_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/5-3-magnitude-earthquake-hits-tokyo-after-japan-issues-megaquake-alert-6300734]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[5.3 Magnitude Earthquake Hits Tokyo After Japan Issues Megaquake Alert]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/5-3-magnitude-earthquake-hits-tokyo-after-japan-issues-megaquake-alert-6300734]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 17:21:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A magnitude-5.3 earthquake hit Tokyo and surrounding areas on Friday evening, the Japan Meteorological Agency said, a day after the government issued a first-ever advisory about the risk of a huge earthquake on the country's Pacific coast.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A magnitude-5.3 earthquake hit Tokyo and surrounding areas on Friday evening, the Japan Meteorological Agency said, a day after the government issued a first-ever advisory about the risk of a huge earthquake on the country's Pacific coast.</p>

<p>The government issued an emergency warning of a strong tremor for the capital city and Kanagawa, Saitama, Yamanashi and Shizuoka prefecture, without a tsunami alert.</p>

<p>The quake shook buildings in Tokyo following the warning. Tokyo Metro briefly stopped at least one of its train lines but the service was quickly resumed.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2017-09/earthquake-generic_650x400_71505899871.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The quake shook buildings in Tokyo following the warning.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/10-killed-35-wounded-in-russian-strikes-on-town-in-eastern-ukraine-6300639]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[10 Killed, 35 Wounded In Russian Strikes On Town In Eastern Ukraine]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/10-killed-35-wounded-in-russian-strikes-on-town-in-eastern-ukraine-6300639]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 17:10:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Russian strike on a supermarket in the eastern Ukrainian town of Kostyantynivka on Friday killed at least 10 people and injured 35, Ukraine's interior minister said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Russian strike on a supermarket in the eastern Ukrainian town of Kostyantynivka on Friday killed at least 10 people and injured 35, Ukraine's interior minister said.</p>

<p>The town is about 13 kilometres (eight miles) from the nearest Russian positions and faces almost daily strikes.</p>

<p>"10 were killed and 35 others were wounded," Interior Minister Igor Klymenko said in a post on Telegram.</p>

<p>He published photos of firefighters working amid the smouldering rubble of the destroyed building.&nbsp;</p>

<p>AFP journalists saw dozens of people fleeing as police officers warned of a potential second strike.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Kostyantynivka, Donetsk region. Russian terrorists hit an ordinary supermarket and a post office. There are people under the rubble. A rescue operation is underway, and everything will be done to save them.<br />
<br />
At the moment, it's known that four people have been killed. My… <a href="https://t.co/Sd9vrGTHTc">pic.twitter.com/Sd9vrGTHTc</a></p>
— Volodymyr Zelenskyy / Володимир Зеленський (@ZelenskyyUa) <a href="https://twitter.com/ZelenskyyUa/status/1821853417276375403?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 9, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>Plumes of black smoke rose from the building and police cordoned off nearby streets. Drones and an uptick in artillery fire in the area were also audible.</p>

<p>President Volodymyr Zelensky vowed retribution for the attack, which happened in the middle of the day and comes on the fourth day of a major Ukrainian cross-border incursion into Russia's western Kursk region.</p>

<p>"Russia will be held accountable for this terror," he said in a post on Telegram.</p>

<p>Vadym Filashkin, Ukraine's governor of the Donetsk region, said Russian forces had shelled the town with cannon artillery.</p>

<p>"This is another targeted attack on a crowded place," he said.</p>

<p>The strike comes one day after two civilians were killed in the same town, Filashkin reported.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/gp6uefh8_russia-strike-on-ukraine_625x300_09_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Plumes of black smoke rose from the building and police cordoned off nearby streets]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-navy-unveils-advanced-missiles-as-regional-tensions-spike-6300509]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iran Navy Unveils Advanced Missiles As Regional Tensions Spike]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-navy-unveils-advanced-missiles-as-regional-tensions-spike-6300509]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 16:52:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Iranian Revolutionary Guards said on Friday that its navy has new cruise missiles equipped with highly explosive warheads that are undetectable, state media reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Iranian Revolutionary Guards said on Friday that its navy has new cruise missiles equipped with highly explosive warheads that are undetectable, state media reported.</p>

<p>The announcement by the country's most powerful security organisation coincides with fears of a full-blown Middle East war after Iran vowed to avenge the assassination in Tehran on July 31 of Ismail Haniyeh, leader of the Palestinian Islamist Hamas.</p>

<p>Iran has blamed Israel, while Israel has neither confirmed nor denied involvement.</p>

<p>"In today's world you either have to be powerful to survive, or surrender. There's no middle ground," said the Guards' top commander, Major-General Hossein Salami.</p>

<p>"A large number of cruise missiles have been added to the Guards' navy fleet. These new missiles have capabilities of highly explosive warheads that are undetectable and can cause extensive damage and sink their targets," a Guards statement said.</p>

<p>The Guards' navy also said in a statement that various types of long and medium-range missile systems, as well as reconnaissance drones and naval radars, have been added to its fleet.</p>

<p>"These systems are among the most up-to-date anti-surface and sub-surface weapons in the Guards' navy," it said.</p>

<p>State television displayed several of the weapons on Friday. The navy added that only 210 of the 2,654 systems were shown as it was not possible to unveil other strategic ones for security reasons.</p>

<p>Iran has one of the biggest missile programs in the Middle East, regarding such weapons as an important deterrent and retaliatory force against US and Israel in the event of war.</p>

<p>According to the US Office of the Director of National Intelligence, Iran is armed with the largest number of ballistic missiles in the region.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/0dg1hq3o_iran-defence-ministry-revolutionary-guard-corps-navy_625x300_09_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Iran has one of the biggest missile programs in the Middle East. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/samsung-recalls-1-million-stoves-as-fires-killed-pets-injured-over-40-6300416]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Samsung Recalls 1 Million Stoves In US After Accidental Fires]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/samsung-recalls-1-million-stoves-as-fires-killed-pets-injured-over-40-6300416]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 16:41:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Samsung is recalling more than one million electric stoves in the United States following reports of accidental fires that injured 40 people and killed pets, the US Consumer Product Safety Commission said Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Samsung is recalling more than one million electric stoves in the United States following reports of accidental fires that injured 40 people and killed pets, the US Consumer Product Safety Commission said Friday.</p>

<p>Owners of one of the 30 models affected by the voluntary recall are advised to contact Samsung for free replacement knob locks or covers, according to the commission's statement.</p>

<p>More than 1.1 million slide-in electric ranges sold between 2013 and 2024 fall under the recall.</p>

<p>Samsung said the announcement was issued due to reports the knobs could be accidentally activated by people or pets bumping into them. The company did not mention fires or pet deaths in its press release.</p>

<p>According to the safety commission, the Samsung stoves have been involved "in approximately 250 fires," which led to about 40 injuries, eight of which required medical attention.</p>

<p>The commission said there were also reports of seven fires involving pet deaths and 18 instances of "extensive property damage".</p>

<p>People continuing to use the recalled models were cautioned to keep children and pets away from the front-range knobs, and to check them before going to bed.</p>

<p>The South Korean electronics and appliances manufacturer said "consumers may continue to use their slide-in electric ranges while awaiting their set of free knob locks or covers."</p>

<p>Samsung's safety reputation suffered a major blow from a worldwide recall of its flagship Galaxy Note 7 smartphone over exploding batteries in 2016, which cost the company billions of dollars.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/8pl35g2o_electric-stove_625x300_09_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Samsung stoves have been involved "in approximately 250 fires", said a report (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/drunk-egyptian-wrestler-arrested-in-paris-for-allegedly-groping-woman-6300272]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Drunk" Egyptian Wrestler Arrested In Paris For Allegedly Groping Woman]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/drunk-egyptian-wrestler-arrested-in-paris-for-allegedly-groping-woman-6300272]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 16:24:00 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[French police early Friday arrested an Egyptian wrestler taking part in the Olympics over allegedly groping a woman in a bar, prosecutors said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>French police early Friday arrested an Egyptian wrestler taking part in the Olympics over allegedly groping a woman in a bar, prosecutors said.</p>

<p>Authorities detained Mohamed Elsayed, 26, in front of a cafe in the French capital's 13th district at around 5 am after he was accused of "placing a hand on the buttocks of a woman patron", the Paris prosecutor's office said.</p>

<p>Elsayed, who won bronze at the Tokyo Games, lost to Azerbaijan's Hasrat Jafarov in the 67 kg Greco-Roman wrestling on Wednesday. His opponent went on to win the bronze medal.</p>

<p>A fellow Egyptian with the same name won a bronze medal in epee fencing at the Paris Olympics.</p>

<p>It was not immediately clear if the wrestler had since been released.</p>

<p>French newspaper Le Parisien said he was "roaring drunk".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/rpfin7u_mohamed-elsayed_625x300_09_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[French newspaper Le Parisien said he was "roaring drunk".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rapper-travis-scott-arrested-after-fight-at-5-star-hotel-in-paris-6299827]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Rapper Travis Scott Arrested After Fight At 5-Star Hotel In Paris]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rapper-travis-scott-arrested-after-fight-at-5-star-hotel-in-paris-6299827]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 15:31:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US rapper Travis Scott was arrested early Friday over a fight at a five-star hotel in the French capital, prosecutors said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US rapper Travis Scott was arrested early Friday over a fight at a five-star hotel in the French capital, prosecutors said.</p>

<p>"Policemen were called to the Georges V hotel and arrested Travis Scott for violence against a security agent. The latter had intervened to separate the rapper from his bodyguard," the Paris prosecutor's office said in a statement.</p>

<p>It was not immediately clear if the 33-year-old singer was being detained.</p>

<p>Scott was seen attending the Olympics men's basketball semi-finals on Thursday evening.</p>

<p>The music star, whose real name is Jacques Bermon Webster, was arrested in Miami Beach in June for trespassing and disorderly intoxication, records showed.</p>

<p>Scott's "Utopia" was a nominee for best rap album at this year's Grammy Awards.</p>

<p>Other endeavours include merchandising deals with Nike, video game maker Epic Games and McDonald's fast food.</p>

<p>Scott has two children with social media giant and business mogul Kylie Jenner.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-08/nt0l9mq_travis-scott_625x300_11_August_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Travis Scott has two children with social media giant and business mogul Kylie Jenner.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/chatgpt-google-openai-openai-is-a-bigger-threat-to-google-than-us-regulators-6299767]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[OpenAI Is A Bigger Threat To Google Than US Regulators]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/chatgpt-google-openai-openai-is-a-bigger-threat-to-google-than-us-regulators-6299767]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 15:21:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Google has long been synonymous with search, commanding around 90% of the global market share and bringing in about $175 billion in annual revenue through the business]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Google is facing a bigger threat from Sam Altman's OpenAI even as it awaits a decision on how antitrust regulators in Washington plan to level the playing field in the internet search business.<br />
A US ruling on Monday, which found that Google built an illegal search monopoly, is being considered a big win for regulators. But an increasing number of people using AI tools including OpenAI's popular ChatGPT chatbot is already eroding Google's dominance, sources, investors and analysts said.</p>

<p>"I think for Google right now, AI (is) a much bigger deal than the ruling. AI is fundamentally changing how the search product also works," said Arvind Jain, a former Google engineer who worked on products including Search for a decade.</p>

<p>Jain, who now runs an enterprise search firm called Glean, said AI's impact was immediate compared with any impact from these rulings that get appealed and take a long time to affect a market.</p>

<p>Google has long been synonymous with search, commanding around 90% of the global market share and bringing in about $175 billion in annual revenue through the business. Even Apple, which prefers to build all the software and much of the hardware that goes into its devices, has allowed Google to be its default search engine for a handsome fee.</p>

<p>But the days of preferential treatment for a fee are over even before slew of antitrust court cases resolve. In its AI foray, Apple announced a partnership with OpenAI to bring ChatGPT to its upcoming devices. It emphasized the deal's non-exclusive basis and talked up the likelihood of bringing on Google as another partner.</p>

<p>A ruling against Google will speed up Apple's move towards AI-powered search services, if it is forced to end its Search deal with Google, analysts have said.</p>

<p>Microsoft-backed OpenAI said last month it was also breaking into the search game with a slow launch of SearchGPT, an AI-powered search engine with real-time access to information from the internet.</p>

<h3><strong>SEARCHGPT</strong></h3>

<p>One former senior Google executive predicted, "AI is going to move faster than the speed that DOJ can move against Google. The whole monopoly will be over, in other words, the speed at which AI will take over search."</p>

<p>Both the former Google executives as well as many Wall Street analysts agree that Google has the raw material needed to take a lead in AI - a large language model to train its AI and a search engine. But the company's efforts seem scattered in the face of OpenAI's onslaught, which is attracting younger users.</p>

<p>Generative AI's popularity caught Google by surprise. Despite being the source of foundational research behind the technology, it did not release a consumer product until well after ChatGPT became the fastest-growing consumer app in early 2023.</p>

<p>"The biggest threat to Google may be Google itself - key to adoption of any AI is trust, and its original missteps with Search Overviews showed that Google's engineers were focused more on rapid releases than getting it right as it tries to keep up with the pace of OpenAI and others," said Rebecca Wettemann, CEO and principal analyst at research firm Valoir.</p>

<p>Wettemann referred to Google's AI Overviews, a new feature that employs AI to answer search queries that appear ahead of links. It drew fire from publishers watching referral traffic from Google decline and was criticized for delivering errors including telling users to eat glue and saying Barack Obama was a Muslim. Google scaled back the feature earlier this year.</p>

<p>Gil Luria, an analyst at D.A. Davidson, believes the regulatory scrutiny as well as the AI threat are related. "Part of the reason (the DOJ) are coming after Google's business practices is that the market is in fact in flux right now and they want to make sure Google does not extend its current market dominance."</p>

<p>While the antitrust ruling may not have a big impact on Google yet, it should open the search market up for more players, said Richard Socher, CEO and founder of AI search engine startup You.com and former chief scientist at Salesforce.</p>

<p>He added, though, that ending Google's dominance in search will be "very hard."</p>

<p>"No one has really made a big dent into Google search dominance yet ... we'll have to see if this will be yet another domino piece that will fall into place to actually give consumers some more choices, real choices."</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/4ks29vs8_openai-vs-google_625x300_09_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[OpenAI launched SearchGPT in July this year, rivaling Google search (Disclaimer: AI Generated Image)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-joe-biden-to-make-their-first-joint-campaign-trip-6299712]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris, Joe Biden To Make Their First Joint Campaign Trip]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-joe-biden-to-make-their-first-joint-campaign-trip-6299712]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 15:13:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kamala Harris and Joe Biden will next week make their first joint campaign trip since the US president's shock decision to drop out of the 2024 White House race against Donald Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kamala Harris and Joe Biden will next week make their first joint campaign trip since the US president's shock decision to drop out of the 2024 White House race against Donald Trump.</p>

<p>Seeking to burnish his legacy in his final months in office and support the new Democratic ticket, Biden will appear alongside his vice president at an event in the state of Maryland near Washington on August 15.</p>

<p>The pair would "discuss the progress they are making to lower costs for the American people", the White House said in a statement Friday, adding that further details would be released later.</p>

<p>Inflation remains a weak spot for Democrats ahead of November's election.</p>

<p>Harris has fired up the Democratic Party since Biden announced he was stepping aside following a disastrous debate against Trump that highlighted concerns about his age and mental acuity.</p>

<p>The first female, Black and South Asian vice president in US history has held a series of packed rallies, pulled in record fundraising and wiped out Republican ex-president Trump's poll lead.</p>

<p>In contrast, Biden has kept a low profile with few public events, in what has become a lame-duck presidency with nearly six months still until his successor takes power in January.</p>

<p>The president, who is currently spending a long weekend at his Delaware beach house, had not been expected to make any major political appearances in support of Harris until the Democratic National Convention starting on August 19 in Chicago.</p>

<p>But there have also been signs that the veteran Democrat is keen to promote his legacy as he prepares to bow out from a nearly five-decade career in US politics.</p>

<h3><strong>Limited schedule&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Part of that is doing whatever he can to help secure Harris's victory against Trump, his nemesis and the man that he beat in the 2020 election.</p>

<p>Harris was a very visible presence at Biden's side in a historic moment last week when they both welcomed home US reporter Evan Gershkovich and other detainees freed in a huge prisoner swap with Russia.</p>

<p>News outlet Politico reported that Harris now wanted Biden's support in battleground states such as Pennsylvania and Michigan where he is still popular, especially with older white voters.</p>

<p>But he would ensure that the spotlight stayed on Harris, embarking mainly on a limited campaign schedule in the fall, it said.</p>

<p>Biden meanwhile stepped into the breach earlier this week to warn against any repeat of the events after the 2020 election, when Trump disputed his loss and his supporters stormed the US capitol.</p>

<p>In his first interview since dropping out of the election, Biden told broadcaster CBS that he was "not confident at all" of a peaceful transfer of power if Trump loses a second time.</p>

<p>One other priority for Biden's remaining days in office is to push for a ceasefire to end the war between Israel and Hamas in Gaza -- an issue that is still divisive for Democrats.</p>

<p>Biden and the leaders of Egypt and Qatar have invited the warring parties to resume talks on August 15 -- the same day as his joint appearance with Harris -- to push for a deal.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/j9gprgd_biden-harris_625x300_22_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kamala Harris has fired up the Democratic Party since Joe Biden announced he was stepping aside (file).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/geometric-storms-expected-to-hit-earth-this-week-power-grids-at-risk-6299475]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Geometric Storms Expected To Hit Earth This Week, Power Grids At Risk]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/geometric-storms-expected-to-hit-earth-this-week-power-grids-at-risk-6299475]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 14:46:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A series of potent solar events is expected to hit Earth, potentially causing significant geomagnetic storms over the next few days, NASA has said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A series of potent solar events is expected to hit Earth, potentially causing significant geomagnetic storms over the next few days, NASA has said. The third storm, potentially the worst one, is expected to hit the planet this week on August 11.</p>

<p>The Sun is currently unleashing a trio of coronal mass ejections (CMEs), with the first two originating from M-class solar flares on August 7.</p>

<p>While these initial CMEs are relatively minor, the third CME, propelled by an X1.3-class solar flare on August 8, is the most powerful. The third CME, from the highly active sunspot AR3777, produced an extreme ultraviolet flash captured by NASA's Solar Dynamics Observatory. It caused a shortwave radio blackout affecting regions from North America to the Hawaiian Islands, disrupting signals below 30 MHz for up to an hour.</p>

<p>Coronal mass ejections are massive bursts of solar wind and magnetic fields ejected from the Sun's corona. These eruptions release billions of tons of plasma into space, potentially disrupting Earth's magnetosphere and impacting satellites, communications and power grids.</p>

<p>Following the flare, the Solar and Heliospheric Observatory (SOHO) detected a halo CME travelling directly toward Earth at speeds exceeding 1,000 km per second. This CME is expected to arrive by August 11, potentially intensifying the effects of the earlier CMEs.</p>

<p>The combined impact of these solar events could elevate geomagnetic storm levels to category G3 (strong), potentially sparking mid-latitude auroras visible in the USA and Europe.</p>

<p>The National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) has issued a geomagnetic storm watch, urging us to prepare for potential impacts on technological infrastructure.</p>

<p>Geomagnetic storms occur when a CME or solar wind disturbs Earth's magnetic field. These storms can lead to beautiful auroras but may also disrupt GPS, radio communications, and power systems. The severity of these storms depends on the strength and direction of the solar wind's magnetic field. The upcoming storms are likely to create prime conditions for auroras, possibly visible much farther from the poles than usual.</p>

<p>Mariners, ham radio operators, and those reliant on satellite-based systems are advised to stay informed and take necessary precautions.</p>

<p>The sunspot AR3777 is currently one of the most active regions on the Sun, showing the increasing solar activity as we approach the solar maximum, the peak of the Sun's 11-year cycle. Space weather experts are closely monitoring the situation as Earth faces potential impacts from these solar particles.</p>

<p>This series of solar storms follows a barrage of similar events in May, which had triggered auroras as far as India and put considerable pressure on satellites.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/e40s2uso_cme_625x300_09_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Coronal mass ejections are massive bursts of solar wind from the Sun's corona]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/muhammad-yunus-honours-heroes-first-act-as-bangladesh-interim-leader-6299227]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Muhammad Yunus Honours Heroes, First Act As Bangladesh Interim Leader]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/muhammad-yunus-honours-heroes-first-act-as-bangladesh-interim-leader-6299227]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 14:14:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Nobel laureate Muhammad Yunus led a solemn tribute to Bangladesh's fallen independence heroes in the first act of his interim government on Friday, after a student-led uprising forced predecessor Sheikh Hasina into exile.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Nobel laureate Muhammad Yunus led a solemn tribute to Bangladesh's fallen independence heroes in the first act of his interim government on Friday, after a student-led uprising forced predecessor Sheikh Hasina into exile.</p>

<p>A day after returning home from Europe and vowing to "uphold, support and protect the constitution" as he was sworn into office, 84-year-old Yunus began the tough challenge of returning the country to democracy.</p>

<p>Hasina, 76, accused of widespread human rights abuses including the jailing of her political opponents, fled by helicopter to neighbouring India on Monday as protesters flooded Dhaka's streets in a dramatic end to her 15-year rule.</p>

<p>The military announced her resignation and then agreed to student demands that Yunus -- who won the Nobel Peace Prize in 2006 for his pioneering microfinancing work -- lead an interim government.</p>

<p>Yunus, who has taken the title of "chief advisor" to a caretaker administration, comprised of fellow civilians bar one retired brigadier-general, has said he wants to hold elections "within a few months".</p>

<p>When polls might take place is not clear.</p>

<p>Officials of Hasina's former ruling party, the Awami League, have gone into hiding after revenge attacks saw some of their offices torched, while former opposition groups such as the key Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) are rebuilding after years of crushing repression.</p>

<h3><strong>'Victory day'</strong></h3>

<p>The new administration faces a daunting task.</p>

<p>The veteran economist has called for the restoration of order in the South Asian nation after weeks of violence that left at least 455 people dead, calling on citizens to guard each other, including minorities who came under attack.</p>

<p>In driving rain, Yunus stood silently on Friday alongside student and civil society leaders in the new "advisory" cabinet tasked with steering democratic reforms.</p>

<p>Together the group laid a wreath in the red-and-green colours of the national flag at the main memorial commemorating the millions who died in Bangladesh's 1971 liberation war against Pakistan.</p>

<p>Yunus suggested on his arrival on Thursday in Dhaka that Hasina's ouster was as significant as the conflict that brought Bangladesh into being.</p>

<p>"Bangladesh has created a new victory day," he told reporters. "Bangladesh has got a second independence."</p>

<p>Several of Yunus' advisers are loosely affiliated with the BNP, led by Hasina's longtime rival and former premier Khaleda Zia, 78, newly released from years of house arrest.</p>

<p>They also include student leaders who started the protests.</p>

<p>Yunus wrote in The Economist this week that his country needed a new generation of leaders "who are not obsessed with settling scores, as too many of our previous governments were".</p>

<p>However, Hasina's son Sajeeb Wazed Joy told the Times of India newspaper his mother still had hope of contesting for political office.</p>

<p>"She will go back to Bangladesh the moment the interim government decides to hold an election," he said.</p>

<h3><strong>'Law and order'</strong></h3>

<p>Hasina's flight abroad has heightened rancour towards India, which played a decisive military role in securing Bangladesh's independence but also backed Hasina to the hilt.</p>

<p>Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi was among the first to offer his "best wishes" to Yunus on Thursday moments after he was sworn in, saying New Delhi was "committed" to working with neighbouring Dhaka.</p>

<p>India's arch-rival Pakistan on Friday also said it hoped it could boost ties with Dhaka, with Prime Minister Shehbaz Sharif wishing Yunus "great success in guiding Bangladesh towards a harmonious and prosperous future".</p>

<p>China said Friday it also welcomed the interim government, promising to work with the country "to promote exchange and cooperation".</p>

<p>Farida Akhter, an adviser to the interim government, told AFP that the group would also visit a monument in Dhaka where the student protests started last month.</p>

<p>"We are paying our respects there, as the student movement began from there," she said, before naming the top task on their to-do list.</p>

<p>"Our first priority is law and order", she said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/mvg10g7g_muhammad-yunus-martyrs_625x300_09_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Muhammad Yunus stood alongside student and civil society leaders in the new "advisory" cabinet.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-origin-man-kris-maharaj-wrongly-jailed-for-38-years-for-murders-dies-in-us-prison-6299225]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Indian-Origin Man Wrongly Jailed For 38 Years For Murders Dies In US Prison]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-origin-man-kris-maharaj-wrongly-jailed-for-38-years-for-murders-dies-in-us-prison-6299225]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 14:14:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kris Maharaj was wrongly convicted in 1986 for the murders of Derrick and Duane Moo Young, and his death sentence was commuted to life imprisonment in 2002. ]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kris Maharaj, a British citizen of Indian origin, has died in a US prison hospital after spending 38 years behind bars for a crime he never committed. He was 85.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Mr Maharaj was wrongly convicted in 1986 for the murders of Derrick and Duane Moo Young. His death sentence was commuted to life imprisonment in 2002.&nbsp;</p>

<p>He was declared innocent in 2019, but remained imprisoned due to a US Court of Appeals ruling that the evidence of his innocence was not sufficient for his release.</p>

<p>Marita Maharaj, his wife, expressed profound sadness over his death, saying, "I promised Kris in 1976 that we would be together until death do us part, and I am devastated that he died alone in that horrible place," as per <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://news.sky.com/story/kris-maharaj-who-spent-38-years-in-florida-prison-despite-judge-finding-him-innocent-dies-13191774">Sky News</a>.</p>

<p>She plans to bring his body to the UK for burial. "The last place he would want to be is where he was falsely charged with murder," she said, and vowed to continue fighting to clear his name so she could "meet him in heaven with a clear conscience that I have done my best for him."</p>

<p>Clive Stafford Smith, Mr Maharaj's pro-bono attorney, confirmed his death and promised to continue the fight to clear his name, stating, "We will certainly fulfil her wish and his, that is to continue to exonerate him for this crime that he patently did not commit."</p>

<h3><strong>The Murder Case Against Kris Maharaj</strong></h3>

<p>Before his arrest, Kris Maharaj lived a life of luxury in England, owning racehorses and Rolls-Royces as a successful businessman.&nbsp;</p>

<p>However, his life took a dramatic turn in December 1986 when Mr Maharaj was accused of orchestrating a meeting with Derrick Moo Young, a Chinese Jamaican businessman, at the DuPont Plaza Hotel in Miami.</p>

<p>According to the prosecution, Mr Maharaj arranged this meeting to confront Moo Young over alleged fraudulent activities involving money taken from his relatives. The prosecution claimed that Mr Maharaj, armed with a gun, shot Mr Moo Young and his son, Duane, in a hotel room. Mr Maharaj was convicted in 1987 of first-degree murder and kidnapping, and sentenced to death.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Human rights organisation 'Reprieve' described Mr Maharaj's case as an "epic miscarriage of justice," citing several issues. Mr Maharaj's alibi witnesses, who could prove he was 25 miles away from the crime scene, were not presented during his trial.</p>

<p>The prosecution's key witness changed their testimony multiple times. Post-trial evidence suggested that the Moo Youngs might have been involved in money laundering and had links to drug traffickers, suggesting the murders might have been orchestrated by Pablo Escobar's Medellin Cartel, not Kris Maharaj.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Despite various appeals and legal battles, including a 2019 court finding of his proven innocence, Mr Maharaj was not released and remained in prison in the US until his death on August 5, 2024.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/70f4ptog_kris-maharaj_625x300_09_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Before his arrest, Kris Maharaj lived a life of luxury in England]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/isis-inspired-suspect-who-planned-suicide-attack-at-taylor-swift-concert-6299035]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Teen ISIS Supporter Admits To Planning "Bloodbath" At Taylor Swift Concert]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/isis-inspired-suspect-who-planned-suicide-attack-at-taylor-swift-concert-6299035]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 13:48:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An Austrian teenager arrested over an alleged plot to strike a Taylor Swift concert in Vienna planned to carry out a suicide attack that would have caused a "bloodbath" and had vowed loyalty to Islamic State (IS), authorities said on Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An Austrian teenager arrested over an alleged plot to strike a Taylor Swift concert in Vienna planned to carry out a suicide attack that would have caused a "bloodbath" and had vowed loyalty to Islamic State (IS), authorities said on Thursday.</p>

<p>The 19-year-old man, who has North Macedonian roots, made a full confession in custody, Austria's general director for public security Franz Ruf told a news conference.</p>

<p>He swore allegiance to the IS group's leader on the internet and had chemicals, machetes and technical devices at his home in the town of Ternitz in preparation for an attack, Ruf added.</p>

<p>The suspect was planning a lethal assault among the estimated 20,000 "Swiftie" fans set to gather outside Vienna's Ernst Happel Stadium, said national intelligence head Omar Haijawi-Pirchner. Two other Austrian youths aged 17 and 15 were detained on Wednesday over the reported plot.</p>

<p>"The main perpetrator has confessed that he was supposed to carry out a suicide attack with two accomplices," said Austrian Chancellor Karl Nehammer.</p>

<p>"The suspects actually had very specific and detailed plans ... to leave a bloodbath in their wake."Authorities painted a picture of the main suspect having self-radicalised, transforming his appearance and sharing Islamist propaganda online. He quit his job on July 25, telling people he had "big plans", Ruf said.</p>

<p>One neighbour told Austrian broadcaster Puls24 that the suspect had kept himself to himself and had grown a "Taliban beard".</p>

<p>The 17-year-old suspect had been given a job with a company a few days ago that was providing services at the stadium, according to security officials.</p>

<p>Event organiser Barracuda Music said it had cancelled Swift's three concerts in Vienna, due to start on Thursday for a sold-out 65,000 audience each, in coordination with the singer's management team.</p>

<p>Fans, many of whom had travelled a long way to Vienna, expressed both dismay and understanding.</p>

<p>"It's just heartbreaking, just frustrating. But at the end of the day I guess it's for everyone's safety," said Mark del Rosario, who had flown from the Philippines to see the wildly popular U.S. singer.</p>

<h3><strong>MUSIC WORLD ROCKED</strong></h3>

<p>U.S. broadcaster ABC cited law enforcement and intelligence sources as saying Austrian authorities had received information about the Swift concert threat from U.S. intelligence.</p>

<p>It quoted the sources as saying that at least one of the suspects had pledged allegiance to ISIS-K, a resurgent wing of IS, on Telegram in June, though the plot was IS-inspired rather than directed by the group's operatives.</p>

<p>Austrian Interior Minister Gerhard Karner said foreign intelligence agencies had helped with the investigation, as Austrian law does not allow monitoring of messenger apps.</p>

<p>Event organiser Live Nation urged fans of Coldplay, which is due to play at the same stadium on Aug. 21, to stay calm and said it was in contact with authorities.</p>

<p>It did not comment on whether the show would take place.</p>

<p>British police said on Thursday there was nothing to indicate that the planned attack in Vienna would have an impact on Swift's shows at Wembley Stadium in London next week.</p>

<p>"Concerts are often a preferred target of Islamist attackers, large concerts," said Karner, listing the 2015 attack on the Bataclan venue in Paris and the 2017 bombing at England's Manchester Arena where U.S. pop star Ariana Grande had played.</p>

<p>The plot in Austria also brought to mind a foiled plan by three IS-linked suspects to attack Vienna's gay pride parade last year.</p>

<p>Islamic State was largely crushed by a U.S.-led coalition several years ago after establishing a "caliphate" in large areas of Iraq and Syria, but has still managed some major attacks while seeking to rebuild and reinvent itself.</p>

<p>This week's shows were to be part of the record-breaking Eras Tour by American singer-songwriter Swift which started on March 17, 2023, in Glendale, Arizona, and is set to conclude on Dec. 8, 2024, in Vancouver, Canada.</p>

<p>Swift, 34, has not yet commented on the cancellations on her official Instagram account, which has 283 million followers.</p>

<p>Her fans were horrified at the threat, with some begging organisers to postpone the concert instead of cancelling it outright. Promoters have said they will pay back tickets.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-02/0vd5tvqs_taylor-swift_625x300_17_February_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The suspect was planning a lethal assault among the estimated 20,000 fans (File).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/cold-war-relic-to-luxe-retreat-albanian-island-braces-for-trump-makeover-6299020]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump's Daughter To Turn Secretive Albanian Island Into Luxury Resort]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/cold-war-relic-to-luxe-retreat-albanian-island-braces-for-trump-makeover-6299020]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 13:44:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Once a Cold War base that would have been the pride of James Bond villains, an Albanian island is set for an overhaul after Jared Kushner and Ivanka Trump unveiled plans to revamp its wild beauty.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Once a Cold War base that would have been the pride of James Bond villains, an Albanian island is set for an overhaul after Jared Kushner and Ivanka Trump unveiled plans to revamp its wild beauty.</p>

<p>The daughter of former US president Donald Trump and her partner want luxury villas to go up on the island of Sazan that for decades served as a garrison with bunkers, fallout shelters and a warren of tunnels designed to withstand a nuclear attack.</p>

<p>The base epitomised the paranoia rampant during the four-decade rule of Albania's Stalinist strongman Enver Hoxha after World War II.</p>

<p>"The island was dotted with 2,840 bunkers with heavy machine guns and other automatic weapons," Ylli Mecaj -- a former soldier stationed at Sazan -- told AFP.</p>

<p>"There were also kilometres of tunnels and underground installations, fallout shelters to house ammunition and food reserves," the 78-year-old retired naval officer added.</p>

<p>During the socialist era, more than 2,000 people lived on the island base -- outfitted with a cinema, school, and hospital -- that was designed to last for months if cut off from the rest of the country.</p>

<p>The base fell into ruin following the collapse of the communist government in 1991.</p>

<h3><strong>Dilapidated base</strong></h3>

<p>The downfall of the communist regime set off years of chaos in Albania, with an economic collapse in 1997 sparking a brief civil war that saw military depots and armouries emptied, including on Sazan.</p>

<p>For now, the island is peppered with wild mulberry and fig trees set against the sea's turquoise waters, while the former military installations are dilapidated shells.</p>

<p>Big changes could be on the way for the island, which was only reopened to the public in 2015.</p>

<p>News first broke in March that Ivanka Trump and her husband were pursuing ambitious development plans on Sazan and a separate project in the Serbian capital Belgrade.</p>

<p>The Trump family has a long history of embarking on luxury projects around the world.</p>

<p>Some critics have accused the power couple of leveraging their time in the White House to secure overseas business deals.</p>

<p>But the Albanian government has sought to bolster the economy through tourism, prompting a building boom along large swaths of the coast.</p>

<p>The Kushner-backed development is still in the planning stages and needs further government approval before ground can be broken on dozens of villas set amid the rocks of Sazan.</p>

<p>But excitement is already palpable in some quarters.</p>

<p>"We can't wait for this to start because it triggers chain reactions for the city's economy," said the mayor of Vlora, Ermal Dredha, whose city looks across the water to Sazan.</p>

<p>Vlora, in southwestern Albania, has been one of the largest beneficiaries of Albania's tourism surge, with apartment blocks and resorts now crowding its shores that attract millions of visitors a year.</p>

<p>The scene stands in stark contrast to Sazan Island, where the Trumps are the latest in a long line of foreigners who have sought a foothold.</p>

<h3><strong>Trump zone</strong></h3>

<p>Situated at the entrance of Vlora Bay at a strategic point where the Adriatic and Ionian seas meet, the tiny island has been coveted over the centuries by the Venetians, Greeks, Italians and Germans, among others.</p>

<p>Still classified as a military zone, the island has seen just a trickle of Albania's tourist onslaught every summer.</p>

<p>Daily boats bring visitors to walk along Sazan's winding paths and admire the island's only inhabitant -- a small grey donkey.</p>

<p>Few official details have emerged about the future luxury development.</p>

<p>In an interview published in July, Ivanka Trump said the island's isolation brought its own unique challenges.</p>

<p>"The logistics of even getting the building materials to an island are no joke, but we will execute on it," she said. "The best architects and the best brands" were involved in the project.</p>

<p>After years of neglect, Sazan's impending makeover will likely leave little of its former James Bond romance -- for better or worse.</p>

<p>"Sazan is no longer Sazan. There are no more weapons, no cannons, no anti-aircraft machine guns, no ships, the bunkers are in ruins," said Mecaj.</p>

<p>"It is open to whoever wants to occupy it."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2017-04/ivanka-trump-jared-kushner-in-white-house_650x400_61493384171.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Trump family has a long history of embarking on luxury projects around the world. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jack-karlson-the-man-behind-democracy-manifest-meme-dies-at-82-6298568]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Jack Karlson, The Man Behind 'Democracy Manifest' Meme, Dies At 82]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jack-karlson-the-man-behind-democracy-manifest-meme-dies-at-82-6298568]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 12:56:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Jack Karlson, famed for the classic "democracy manifest" and "succulent Chinese meal" clip, died on August 7, aged 82.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Jack Karlson, famed for the classic "democracy manifest" and "succulent Chinese meal" clip, died on August 7, aged 82. In a statement, Karlson's family confirmed his death, saying he had prostate cancer.</p>

<p>"He walked a full and colourful path and despite the troubles thrown at him, he lived by his motto - to keep on laughing," they said in a statement.</p>

<p>Karlson had been in the hospital for the past three weeks, trying to break free several times, according to his niece Kim Edwards, who told The Independent that, "he asked us many times to sneak in his pipe."</p>

<p>She also mentioned that as a final farewell, they gave Karlson a "last taste of red wine through his drip".</p>

<p>Karlson was a small-time criminal and serial jail escapee. There's still debate over whether or not this was his true name. He became popular in 2009 when a 1991 news tape of his arrest at a Chinese restaurant in Brisbane's Fortitude Valley was posted online.</p>

<p>Karlson was suspected of using a stolen credit card, but he always claimed it was a case of misidentification.</p>

<p>"What is the charge? Eating a meal? A succulent Chinese meal?" Karlson resisted a group of cops and yelled dramatically.</p>

<p>Among his other now-iconic phrases was "Gentlemen, this is democracy manifest."</p>

<p>Numerous memes, music remixes, response videos, and even a few tattoos have been inspired by this pivotal event. Additionally, there is a racehorse -- a purebred Australian -- named Democracy Manifest. Karlson died a day after his 82nd birthday.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Meanwhile, filmmaker Heath Davis is directing a documentary on Karlson called The Man Who Ate a Succulent Chinese Meal. The film is slated to be released in early 2025. In an interview with The Guardian, Davis referred to Karlson as "the last Australian larrikin."</p>

<p>Mark Depin, documentary's associate producer and author of a nonfiction book inspired by Karlson's life, says the 82-year-old's real name was Cecil George Edwards.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/e3b3e2n_jack-karlson-_625x300_09_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Jack Karlson had been in the hospital for the past three weeks.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-donald-trump-agrees-to-debate-kamala-harris-what-latest-polls-suggest-6298163]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump Agrees To Debate Kamala Harris: What Latest Polls Suggest]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-donald-trump-agrees-to-debate-kamala-harris-what-latest-polls-suggest-6298163]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 12:18:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump has agreed to debate his Democratic counterpart Kamala Harris on September 10.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump has agreed to debate his Democratic counterpart Kamala Harris on September 10. The showdown is set to be hosted by ABC, with additional debates proposed for September 4 and September 25 on Fox and NBC, respectively.</p>

<p>This will be the first face-off between the two rivals, with polls indicating a closely contested race.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>Trump vs Harris: What polls predict</strong></h2>

<h3><strong>Ipsos poll</strong></h3>

<p>A recent Ipsos poll published on August 9, shows Kamala Harris leading Donald Trump 42 per cent to 37 per cent for the November 5 elections. This shows growth in her popularity since a July 22-23 Reuters/Ipsos survey, which found her up 37 per cent to 34 per cent over Trump.</p>

<p>In a separate poll, Ipsos found Harris leading Trump 42 per cent to 40 per cent in the seven states where the election was closest in 2020 - Arizona, Georgia, Michigan, Nevada, North Carolina, Pennsylvania and Wisconsin.</p>

<h3><strong>YouGov poll</strong></h3>

<p>A CBS/YouGov poll released on August 4 shows Kamala Harris levelling up with Donald Trump. She has erased Trump's growing lead since President Joe Biden dropped his reelection bid. The poll indicates Harris has a 1 per cent advantage over Trump nationwide, compared to Trump's previous five-point edge over Biden. In swing states, Harris and Trump are equal.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Moreover, the poll shows only 51 per cent of respondents thought Trump was mentally capable of the presidency, compared to 64 per cent for Harris.</p>

<h3><strong>Marist poll</strong></h3>

<p>An NPR/PBS News/Marist poll shows Harris has a 51-48 per cent edge over Trump among key demographics such as Black voters, white women with college degrees and women who identify as political independents. Independent women voters are crucial swing voters. Harris has made significant inroads with this group, leading Trump by 9 points (53-44 per cent).</p>

<p>The poll also states that Harris has made significant gains in suburban areas and among white voters overall, which has helped her improve her standing compared to earlier polls.&nbsp;</p>

<p>However, Trump still maintains an advantage on economic issues, leading Harris by 3 points (51-48 per cent). Trump also leads Harris on handling immigration, with a 52-46 per cent advantage.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Meanwhile, on the issue of abortion, Harris has a clear advantage, leading Trump by 15 points.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Kamala Harris, who entered the presidential race on July 21 after receiving President Joe Biden's endorsement, has selected Tim Walz, the Governor of Minnesota, as her running mate. This move comes after Biden folded his campaign and exited the race following a disastrous debate performance against Donald Trump on June 27.</p>

<p>Harris and Walz debuted their joint campaign at a rally in Philadelphia, marking the beginning of their bid to take on Republican Trump and his running mate, JD Vance, in the upcoming presidential election.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/knofc75_donald-trump-kamala-harris_625x300_31_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump has agreed to debate his Democratic counterpart Kamala Harris on September 10.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukraine-advances-10-km-into-russias-kursk-region-thousands-evacuated-6298425]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ukraine Advances 10 km Into Russia's Kursk Region, Thousands Evacuated]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukraine-advances-10-km-into-russias-kursk-region-thousands-evacuated-6298425]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 12:14:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ukrainian troops have advanced up to 10 kilometres (six miles) into Russia in possibly the most serious border incursion of the conflict, the Institute for the Study of War said on Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ukrainian troops have advanced up to 10 kilometres (six miles) into Russia in possibly the most serious border incursion of the conflict, the Institute for the Study of War said on Thursday.</p>

<p>Pro-Kyiv forces stormed into Russia's southwestern Kursk region on Tuesday morning, deploying around 1,000 troops and more than two dozen armoured vehicles and tanks, according to the Russian army.</p>

<p>Kyiv has not officially commented on the operation.</p>

<p>Russia's top general vowed on Wednesday to crush the incursion and push the Ukrainian fighters back to the border.</p>

<p>"Ukrainian forces have made confirmed advances up to 10 kilometres (six miles) into Russia's Kursk Oblast amid continued mechanised offensive operations on Russian territory," the US-based Institute for the Study of War (ISW) said in its latest update.</p>

<p>"The current confirmed extent and location of Ukrainian advances in Kursk Oblast indicate that Ukrainian forces have penetrated at least two Russian defensive lines and a stronghold," it added.</p>

<p>The advance has centred on the logistical hub of Sudzha, a town of around 5,000 inhabitants located eight kilometres from the Ukrainian border.</p>

<p>There have been scant updates from officials in Moscow.</p>

<p>But Russian military bloggers, who have links to the army, also reported Kyiv had made significant advances and lamented deteriorating circumstances.</p>

<p>"The situation is complicated and continues to worsen," blogger Yury Podolyaka said in a post on Telegram.</p>

<p>He said the town of Sudzha was "full of Ukrainian soldiers".</p>

<p>"Sudzha has been completely lost," he said.</p>

<p>"The enemy is entrenching, indicating that the fighting is likely to be long-term," the Dva Mayora Telegram channel said.</p>

<p>Multiple military bloggers reported Ukrainian troops had advanced towards the town of Korenevo, more than 25 kilometres from the Ukrainian border.</p>

<p>Russian energy giant Gazprom said on Thursday it would continue shipping gas through the Sudzha metering station, the last transit point for Russian gas heading to Europe via Ukraine.</p>

<p>Russia's defence ministry said its forces had destroyed a US-made Bradley Fighting Vehicle that Ukraine was using in the incursion and that it had downed Ukrainian drones over the region.</p>

<p>The governor of the Kursk region introduced a local state of emergency on Wednesday evening, a move that gives authorities the power to restrict movement in a bid to bring the situation under control.</p>

<p>Several thousand have been evacuated on both sides of the border.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/q2msta7g_ukraine-incursion-into-russia_625x300_09_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The governor of the Kursk region introduced a local state of emergency on Wednesday (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/japan-to-prepare-for-possible-megaquake-that-could-kill-many-6298154]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explainer: Why Did Japan Scientists Issue 'Megaquake' Advisory]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/japan-to-prepare-for-possible-megaquake-that-could-kill-many-6298154]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 11:27:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Japan's earthquake scientists say the country should prepare for a possible "megaquake" one day that could kill hundreds of thousands of people -- although they stress the warning does not mean a colossal tremor is imminent.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Japan's earthquake scientists say the country should prepare for a possible "megaquake" one day that could kill hundreds of thousands of people -- although they stress the warning does not mean a colossal tremor is imminent.</p>

<p>The Japan Meteorological Association (JMA) warning is the first issued under new rules drawn up after a 2011 earthquake, tsunami and nuclear disaster killed around 18,500 people.</p>

<h3><strong>What does the warning say?</strong></h3>

<p>The JMA's "megaquake advisory" warns that "if a major earthquake were to occur in the future, strong shaking and large tsunamis would be generated".</p>

<p>"The likelihood of a new major earthquake is higher than normal, but this is not an indication that a major earthquake will definitely occur during a specific period of time," it added.</p>

<p>The advisory concerns the Nankai Trough "subduction zone" between two tectonic plates in the Pacific Ocean, where massive earthquakes have hit in the past.</p>

<h3><strong>What is the Nankai Trough?</strong></h3>

<p>The 800-kilometre (500-mile) undersea trough runs from Shizuoka, west of Tokyo, to the southern tip of Kyushu island.</p>

<p>It has been the site of destructive quakes of magnitude eight or nine every century or two.</p>

<p>These so-called "megathrust quakes", which often occur in pairs, have been known to unleash dangerous tsunamis along Japan's southern coast.</p>

<p>In 1707, all segments of the Nankai Trough ruptured at once, unleashing an earthquake that remains the nation's second-most powerful on record.</p>

<p>That quake -- which also triggered the last eruption of Mount Fuji -- was followed by two powerful Nankai megathrusts in 1854, and then a pair in 1944 and 1946.</p>

<h3><strong>How much is at stake?</strong></h3>

<p>Japan's government has previously said the next magnitude 8-9 megaquake along the Nankai Trough has a roughly 70 percent probability of striking within the next 30 years.</p>

<p>In the worst-case scenario 300,000 lives could be lost, experts estimate, with some engineers saying the damage could reach $13 trillion with infrastructure wiped out.</p>

<p>"The history of great earthquakes at Nankai is convincingly scary," geologists Kyle Bradley and Judith A Hubbard wrote in their Earthquake Insights newsletter.</p>

<p>And "while earthquake prediction is impossible, the occurrence of one earthquake usually does raise the likelihood of another", they explained.</p>

<p>"A future great Nankai earthquake is surely the most long-anticipated earthquake in history -- it is the original definition of the 'Big One'."</p>

<h3><strong>How worried should people be?</strong></h3>

<p>Japan is reminding people living in quake zones to take general precautions, from securing furniture to knowing the location of their nearest evacuation shelter.</p>

<p>Many households in the country also keep a disaster kit handy with bottled water, long-life food, a torch, radio and other practical items.</p>

<p>But there's no need to panic -- there is only a "small probability" that Thursday's magnitude 7.1 earthquake is a foreshock, according to Bradley and Hubbard.</p>

<p>"One of the challenges is that even when the risk of a second earthquake is elevated, it is still always low," they said.</p>

<p>"For instance, in California, the rule of thumb is that any given earthquake has around five per cent chance of being a foreshock."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-08/0vdfur1o_earthquake-generic_625x300_10_August_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[This warning was first issued under new rules drawn up after a 2011 earthquake (representational).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>