<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Thu, 15 Aug 2024 14:10:37 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/oropouche-virus-kills-2-in-brazil-all-about-the-rare-disease-6342789]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Oropouche Virus Kills 2 In Brazil: All About The Rare Disease]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/oropouche-virus-kills-2-in-brazil-all-about-the-rare-disease-6342789]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 15 Aug 2024 13:32:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Currently, there is no vaccine available for the virus, which belongs to the same family of diseases as Zika virus and Dengue fever.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An insect-borne virus has emerged in South America and two deaths were reported in two young Brazilian women due to the same. The women had no underlying health conditions. In June and July, Europe saw 19 imported cases of the Oropouche virus, as reported by the European Center for Disease Control. Spain accounted for 12 cases, Italy for five, and Germany for two.</p>

<p>The virus is primarily spread through insect bites, including mosquitoes, and midges and originates from pale-throated sloths, non-human primates, and birds, as per <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.newsweek.com/unprecedented-oropouche-mosquito-disease-outbreak-deadly-1939019#:~:text=Its%20symptoms%20are%20similar%20to,other%20potentially%20fatal%20neuroinvasive%20conditions."><em>Newsweek</em></a>. The symptoms include headaches, fever, muscle aches, stiff joints, nausea, vomiting, chills, and light sensitivity, which are similar to dengue fever. In extreme situations, the virus can enter the brain system and cause encephalitis, meningitis, and other potentially lethal neuroinvasive diseases. The <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.cdc.gov/oropouche/hcp/clinical-overview/index.html">Centers for Disease Control</a> estimates that just 4 per cent of patients experience this.</p>

<p>The scientific journal Lancet Infectious Disease stated that the Oropouche outbreak this year has reached an "unprecedented scale."</p>

<p>Currently, there is no vaccine available for the virus, which belongs to the same family of diseases as Zika virus and Dengue fever. According to the Centre for Disease Control, the incubation period for Oropouche virus disease is three to ten days. "Typically, disease starts with the abrupt onset of fever (38-40 degress Celcius) with headache (often severe), chills, myalgia, and arthralgia," they added.</p>

<p>The symptoms of the disease can last up to seven days, however, they can reoccur a few days or even weeks later in about 60 per cent of patients. Further, weakness has been seen in several patients for up to a month following diagnosis.</p>

<p>Since midges are tiny insects that are less affected by typical repellents, common pest control methods like insect repellants and mosquito nets are not usually successful against them. However, chemical pesticides like DEET and deltamethrin work well against these insects.</p>

<p>Outbreaks of the virus have earlier been reported in countries across South and Central America, as well as the Caribbean. In 2024, outbreaks were recorded in Brazil, Bolivia, Colombia, Peru, and more recently in Cuba. Over 8,000 cases have been reported in Brazil, Bolivia, Peru, Colombia, and Cuba since the beginning of this year.</p>

<p>The virus got its name when it was initially discovered in the Trinidad and Tobago town of Oropouche in 1955. Even though there have been almost five lakh cases reported since then, not much is known about the illness.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/ea85sed8_oropouche-virus-_625x300_15_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The symptoms of the disease can last up to seven days.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ayatollah-khamenei-warns-of-divine-wrath-if-iran-backs-down-against-israel-6342388]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ayatollah Khamenei Warns Of "Divine Wrath" If Iran Backs Down Against Israel]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ayatollah-khamenei-warns-of-divine-wrath-if-iran-backs-down-against-israel-6342388]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 15 Aug 2024 12:25:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iran's Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei has issued a warning against any form of retreat or compromise, invoking the concept of "divine wrath".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Iran's Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei has issued a warning against any form of retreat or compromise, invoking the concept of "divine wrath". This comes in the wake of growing tensions between Iran and Israel following the assassination of Ismail Haniyeh, the political chief of Hamas, who was killed last month during an official visit to Tehran.</p>

<p>Khamenei's remarks condemned what he described as "enemy psychological warfare" aimed at pressuring Iran to reconsider any plans for retaliation against Israel. The 86-year-old said that any retreat, whether it be military, political, or economic, would invite severe divine punishment.</p>

<p>Haniyeh's death, which Tehran attributes to Israeli intelligence, has since placed Iran in a precarious position as it deliberates over the timing and nature of its response.</p>

<p>"Governments that yield to the demands of today's dominant powers, regardless of their nation's size or strength, can defy these pressures if they draw on the strength of their people and accurately assess their adversaries' true capabilities," Khamenei <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.iranintl.com/en/202408148230">said</a>, as quoted by Iran International.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Ayatollah also criticised the longstanding tendency to exaggerate the power of enemies, citing historical examples of US, British, and Israeli attempts to undermine Iran since the 1979 Islamic Revolution.</p>

<p>Despite the heated rhetoric, Iran has refrained from immediate retaliation, a move seen by some analysts as a strategic pause. However, Iranian officials have dismissed Western calls for restraint, with the Foreign Ministry criticising Western nations for their perceived double standards. Iran has accused these nations of turning a blind eye to what he described as Israel's "genocidal" actions in Gaza while expecting Iran to forgo its right to retaliate for Haniyeh's killing.</p>

<p>Irann's new president, Masoud Pezeshkian, has publicly aligned himself with Khamenei's hardline stance, although reports suggest he may have privately expressed concerns about the potential fallout from further escalation.</p>

<p>Israel has made it clear that any direct aggression from Tehran will be met with a forceful response. Israeli officials have reportedly warned both the US and European nations that an Iranian strike on Israeli territory would trigger a swift and decisive Israeli retaliation.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/2lceiu2_netanyahu-khamenei-_625x300_04_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Iran blames Israel for Ismail Haniyeh's death.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/he-agreed-to-disney-terms-disney-after-man-sues-it-for-wifes-death-6342338]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA['He Agreed To Disney+ Terms': Disney After Man Sues It For Wife's Death]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/he-agreed-to-disney-terms-disney-after-man-sues-it-for-wifes-death-6342338]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 15 Aug 2024 12:20:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Subscription to a free one month trial of Disney+ is the reason a man cannot sue after his wife died from eating at Disney World resort, the company's lawyers argued.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Subscription to a free one-month trial of Disney+ is the reason a man cannot sue after his wife suffered an allergic reaction and died after eating at Disney World resort in Florida, the company's lawyers have argued. Disney said the man signed away his right to take action against the company when he agreed to the terms and conditions of Disney+ during a free trial of the streaming service several years ago.</p>

<p>Jeffrey Piccolo filed a "wrongful death" lawsuit against Disney after his wife Kanokporn Tangsuan, a doctor from New York, died last year. Mr Piccolo has claimed in his lawsuit that his wife died after suffering an allergic reaction from her meal at a resort restaurant in Disney Springs at the Walt Disney World Resort in Florida.</p>

<p>Mr Piccolo said his wife had a severe allergy to dairy and nuts and the couple questioned the restaurant waiter numerous times about the ingredients of the meal they ordered. He said they were reassured that their food would be "allergen free".</p>

<p>After their meal, he claimed his wife suffered a "severe acute allergic reaction" and died later that day.&nbsp;</p>

<p>After autopsy, the cause of her death was determined as anaphylaxis -- a flood of chemicals that can cause the body to go into shock -- due to high levels of dairy and nuts in her system.</p>

<p>In his lawsuit against Walt Disney Parks and Resorts, he argued that the waiter was negligent and demanded damages over $50,000.</p>

<p>Disney, on the other hand, argued that the case should be dismissed and settled out of court because Mr Piccolo had agreed to the company's terms of use when he signed up for a one-month free trial of Disney+ in 2019 and in 2023. Disney says the terms state that users of Disney's service agree to settle any disputes with the company out of court via arbitration.</p>

<p>“When you create a Disney+ or ESPN+ account, you also agree to the Walt Disney Company's Terms of Use, which govern your use of other Disney Services. The services include sites, software, applications, content, product and services, which include the Disney Parks and Resorts website," it said.</p>

<p>Disney has argued that these terms of use include a clause that applies to “all disputes” including those involving “The Walt Disney Company or its affiliates” of which Walt Disney Parks and Resorts is a part.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-03/a5o0daoo_disney-merchandise_625x300_19_March_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-lags-behind-in-fight-against-child-marriage-300-000-cases-since-2000-6342304]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Lags Behind In Fight Against Child Marriage: 300,000 Cases Since 2000]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-lags-behind-in-fight-against-child-marriage-300-000-cases-since-2000-6342304]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 15 Aug 2024 12:10:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Despite global focus on South Asia and Africa, child marriage remains legal in 37 US states, with over 300,000 cases reported since 2000.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The global dialogue over child marriage frequently focusses on South Asia, which includes countries like India, Pakistan, Bangladesh, and Nepal, as well as several African countries. This concentrated attention on these areas has overshadowed the prevalence of this harmful practice in other parts of the world especially the 'superpower' United States.</p>

<p>Though it is widely believed that child marriage is a problem limited to backward regions of the world, the fact that child marriages are still legal in most of the United States indicates that reform is urgently needed in the country.</p>

<p>India has made significant strides in combating child marriage through strict laws and enforcement. While the practice is now a punishable offense with severe penalties, the United States presents a stark contrast. Despite being illegal in most countries, child marriage remains a pervasive issue across 37 states in the US.</p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.unchainedatlast.org/child-marriage-in-the-u-s/">Unchained At Last, </a>an organization in the United States that works to end child and forced marriage, Child marriage, or marriage before age 18, was legal in all 50 US states as of 2017. Delaware and New Jersey in 2018 became the first two states to end this human rights abuse, followed by American Samoa in 2018, the US Virgin Islands, Pennsylvania and Minnesota in 2020, Rhode Island and New York in 2021, Massachusetts in 2022 Vermont, Connecticut and Michigan in 2023, and Washington, Virginia and New Hampshire in 2024."</p>

<p>"However, child marriage remains legal in 37 states and is happening in the US at an alarming rate: Unchained's groundbreaking research revealed that more than 300,000 children as young as 10 were married in the US since 2000 - mostly girls wed to adult men."</p>

<p>Unchained At Last has revealed in <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.unchainedatlast.org/child-marriage-in-the-u-s/">its report</a> that child marriage, which is legal in many US states, often masks a sinister reality: forced marriage. The report states that the age of majority, when children become legal adults and get the rights of adulthood, is 18 or higher in every US state. Children who have not yet reached the age of majority have limited legal rights and therefore can easily be forced into marriage or forced to stay in a marriage."</p>

<p>"They face overwhelming legal and practical barriers if they try to leave home to escape a forced marriage, get help from an advocate, enter a domestic violence shelter, or retain an attorney."</p>

<p>"Perhaps most shockingly, children are typically not allowed to initiate a legal proceeding, such as seeking a protective order or even filing for divorce, unless they act through a guardian or other representative. This outrageous legal setup puts the "lock" in "wedlock."</p>

<p>The <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.unicefusa.org/stories/what-you-need-know-about-child-marriage-us">organisations and and other advocates</a> say Child marriage victims, especially girls, face heightened abuse and legal exploitation.Texas leads with the highest number of child marriages (41,774) from 2000-2018, followed by California, Florida, Nevada, and North Carolina. Rhode Island recorded the least with 171 cases.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/2tlik3uo_child-marriages_625x300_15_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Texas has the highest number of child marriages.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trumps-son-suggests-federal-job-for-elon-musk-cant-imagine-a-better-person-6342280]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump's Son Suggests Federal Job For Musk: "Can't Imagine A Better Person"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trumps-son-suggests-federal-job-for-elon-musk-cant-imagine-a-better-person-6342280]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 15 Aug 2024 12:08:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Mr Musk himself seemed to be angling for a position under a potential Trump administration, indicating that he would like to be on a committee that cuts costs.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The eldest son of former US President Donald Trump, has suggested that billionaire Elon Musk should have a government job in his father's administration, if he wins the US polls scheduled in November.</p>

<p>Donald Trump Jr took to X (formerly Twitter) and asked if his followers love and support the idea of Mr Musk "heading up a government efficiency committee to eliminate the likely trillions of dollars of waste we have in our bloated bureaucracy?"</p>

<p>He added, "I can't imagine a better person for the task. Trump will make this happen!"</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Who else loves the idea of Elon Musk heading up a government efficiency committee to eliminate the likely trillions of dollars of waste we have in our bloated bureaucracy? I can't imagine a better person for the task.<br />
<br />
Trump will make this happen!</p>
— Donald Trump Jr. (@DonaldJTrumpJr) <a href="https://twitter.com/DonaldJTrumpJr/status/1823416270785491241?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 13, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>These comments came after Donald Trump was interviewed by Elon Musk on X Spaces. Mr Trump commended Musk during the interview for sacking striking employees, and called the CEO of SpaceX and Tesla as the "greatest cutter." "You're the greatest cutter. I mean, I look at what you do. You walk in, you just say: 'You want to quit?' They go on strike - I won't mention the name of the company - but they go on strike. And you say: 'That's okay, you're all gone.'" Notably, Mr Musk stated that after acquiring Twitter in 2022, he fired almost 80% of the company's employees.</p>

<p>Mr Musk himself seemed to be angling for a position under a potential Trump administration, indicating that he would like to be on a committee that cuts costs, during the conversation with Mr Trump that was aired on X. He stated repeatedly that if Mr Trump were to return to the White House again in January, he would be "happy to help out."</p>

<p>"I think it would be great to just have a government efficiency commission that takes a look at these things and just ensures that taxpayer money...is spent in a good way," Mr Musk said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>He added, "I'd be happy to help out on such a commission."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ldckr8sg_elon-musk_625x300_18_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[These comments came after Donald Trump was interviewed by Elon Musk on X Spaces.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/angry-airline-passenger-jumps-check-in-counter-throws-monitor-at-employees-6342224]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Angry Passenger In US Throws Computer At Airline Staff, Calls Them "Stupid"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/angry-airline-passenger-jumps-check-in-counter-throws-monitor-at-employees-6342224]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 15 Aug 2024 11:58:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The woman's meltdown, captured in a video, showed her climbing over the baggage counter, grabbing and screaming at employees.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A shocking incident unfolded at Chicago's O'Hare International Airport last month when a furious passenger hurled a computer monitor at Frontier Airlines staff after missing her flight. The woman's meltdown, captured in a video, showed her&nbsp;climbing over the baggage counter, grabbing and screaming at employees.&nbsp;</p>

<p>After being pushed back, she retaliates by throwing a computer monitor at the staff, striking one in the stomach. She then slams down another computer and continues her rampage, shouting "Stupid!" at the employees. According to police, the unidentified 31-year-old woman also threw a cell phone, hitting a 40-year-old victim, and struck a 24-year-old woman in the leg.&nbsp;Following the chaotic outburst, the passenger fled the airport.</p>

<p>A fellow traveller captured the shocking incident on camera and shared it on TikTok on July 30, revealing that the woman's outburst was triggered after she missed her flight.&nbsp;Following the chaotic scene, the Chicago Police Department arrived at the airport, and the woman's passport was confiscated, according to the user's account.&nbsp;Although TikTok removed the original video due to its violent and graphic nature, it had already been shared on other social media platforms.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Watch the video here:</strong></p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Angry passenger hurls computer monitor at airline staff in O'Hare<br />
<br />
A woman shocked onlookers as she leaped over a check-in counter and hurled a computer monitor at Frontier Airlines staff at Chicago O'Hare International Airport in Illinois. <a href="https://t.co/bOYrxHDeF1">pic.twitter.com/bOYrxHDeF1</a></p>
— T_CAS videos (@tecas2000) <a href="https://twitter.com/tecas2000/status/1823829754010599782?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 14, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>There has been a significant rise in reports of unruly passenger behaviour and meltdowns on flights and in airports in recent years.&nbsp;Airlines, airports, and aviation authorities have been working to address this issue through enhanced security measures, improved passenger communication, and increased support for staff dealing with difficult situations.</p>

<p>Last year, a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/video-shows-us-womans-bizarre-meltdown-on-flight-as-she-screams-climbs-over-seats-4595283">video surfaced showing an airline passenger's epic</a> meltdown aboard a Frontier Airlines flight bound from Houston to Denver. The shocking footage showed a woman crying, screaming, and arguing with the in-flight crew and passengers as they tried to restrain her.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/0s6b7o58_angry-passenger_625x300_15_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Following the chaotic outburst, the passenger fled the airport.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/in-touch-with-india-over-bangladesh-political-crisis-us-state-department-6342097]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[In Touch With India Over Bangladesh Political Crisis: US State Department]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/in-touch-with-india-over-bangladesh-political-crisis-us-state-department-6342097]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 15 Aug 2024 11:39:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United States is in touch with India and other countries in the region regarding the situation in Bangladesh and is seeking an end to the violence there, a State Department official has said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United States is in touch with India and other countries in the region regarding the situation in Bangladesh and is seeking an end to the violence there, a State Department official has said.</p>

<p>"I'm not going to get into private diplomatic discussions but we continue to push for an end to violence in Bangladesh, accountability and for the respect for rule of law," US State Department Deputy Spokesperson Vedant Patel said at his daily news conference on Wednesday.</p>

<p>He was responding to a question regarding the communication between India and the US on the situation in Bangladesh following the collapse of the Sheikh Hasina government.</p>

<p>"We have been in touch with our Indian partners as well as other countries in the region to discuss recent events in Bangladesh," Patel said.</p>

<p>He also welcomed Bangladesh's Chief Adviser Muhammad Yunus' statement, calling for calm and an end to the recent violence. "We welcome the new government's focus on restoring security and protection of members of minority communities as well," Patel said.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the Hindu American Foundation on Wednesday urged the White House to act to protect the minority Hindu community in Bangladesh.</p>

<p>"Latest reports are that the President (Joe Biden) is not commenting on the plight of Bangladeshi Hindus despite continuing reports of attacks," the foundation said.</p>

<p>"Demand Action Now! The silence from President, Vice President and Secretary Blinken on the atrocities against #BangladeshiHindus is unacceptable. Lives lost, homes &amp; temples destroyed - yet no condemnation from our US government," it said in a post on X.</p>

<p>Washington-based NGO HinduACTion claimed that Hindus in rural areas of Bangladesh are being targeted the most.</p>

<p>"Their remoteness allows the Islamists more freedom and time to target them. Now that Mohammad Yunus is the new caretaker leaders, should the Vice President and the State Department work towards enabling grassroots education and awareness that ensures that the country's Madrassa curriculum and the public discourse is purged of its anti-Hindu theological content.</p>

<p>"We hope the president and his advisors realize that if Bangladesh loses the last eight per cent of its Hindus, it will be a Taliban state with a lot of tree canopy cover," it said on X.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-01/p579c7u_vedant-patel_625x300_27_January_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["We have been in touch with our Indian partners," the US State Department spokesperson said.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/japan-set-to-lift-megaquake-warning-if-there-is-no-major-seismic-activity-6341863]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Japan Set To Lift Megaquake Warning If There Is No "Major Seismic Activity"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/japan-set-to-lift-megaquake-warning-if-there-is-no-major-seismic-activity-6341863]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 15 Aug 2024 10:53:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Japan was set on Thursday to lift a week-old warning that a "megaquake" potentially causing colossal damage and loss of life could strike, the government said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Japan was set on Thursday to lift a week-old warning that a "megaquake" potentially causing colossal damage and loss of life could strike, the government said.</p>

<p>The alert that such a catastrophe might hit the archipelago of 125 million people prompted thousands of Japanese to cancel holidays and stock up on essentials, emptying shelves in some stores.</p>

<p>Japan's disaster management minister Yoshifumi Matsumura said the "special call for attention" would be lifted at 5:00 pm (0800 GMT) assuming there was no major seismic activity.</p>

<p>Matsumura cautioned, however, that the "possibility of a major earthquake has not been eliminated", urging people to regularly check their preparedness "for the major earthquake that is expected".</p>

<h3><strong>Higher than normal&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Last Thursday, Japan's weather agency said the likelihood of a megaquake was "higher than normal" after a magnitude 7.1 jolt earlier in the day that injured 15 people.</p>

<p>That was a particular kind of tremor known as a subduction megathrust quake, which in the past has occurred in pairs and can unleash massive tsunamis.</p>

<p>The advisory concerned the Nankai Trough between two tectonic plates in the Pacific Ocean.</p>

<p>The 800-kilometre (500-mile) undersea gully runs parallel to Japan's Pacific coast, including off the Tokyo region, the world's biggest urban area and home to around 40 million people.</p>

<p>In 1707, all segments of the Nankai Trough ruptured at once, unleashing an earthquake that remains the nation's second-most powerful on record.</p>

<p>That quake -- which also triggered the last eruption of Mount Fuji -- was followed by two powerful Nankai megathrusts in 1854, and one each in 1944 and 1946.</p>

<h3><strong>Slower trains&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Japan's government has previously said the next magnitude 8-9 megaquake along the Nankai Trough has a roughly 70 per cent probability of striking within the next 30 years.</p>

<p>In the worst-case scenario, 300,000 lives could be lost, experts estimate, with some engineers saying the damage could reach $13 trillion, with infrastructure wiped out.</p>

<p>Experts, however, said the risk was still low, and the agriculture and fisheries ministry urged people on Saturday "to refrain from excessively hoarding goods".</p>

<p>The statement came after supermarkets put limits on purchases including bottled water, and as demand for emergency items such as portable toilets and preserved food soared online.</p>

<p>The megaquake warning even prompted Prime Minister Fumio Kishida to cancel a four-day trip to Central Asia due to take place last weekend.</p>

<p>Some bullet trains reduced their speed as a precaution and nuclear plants were instructed by authorities to double-check their disaster preparations.</p>

<h3><strong>'Convincingly scary'&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Sitting on top of four major tectonic plates, Japan sees some 1,500 quakes every year, most of them minor.</p>

<p>Even with larger tremors, the impact is generally contained thanks to advanced building techniques and well-practised emergency procedures.</p>

<p>The Japan Meteorological Association (JMA) warning was the first under new rules drawn up after a 2011 quake, tsunami and nuclear disaster that left around 18,500 people dead or missing.</p>

<p>The 2011 tsunami sent three reactors into meltdown at the Fukushima nuclear plant, causing Japan's worst post-war catastrophe and the world's most serious nuclear accident since Chernobyl.</p>

<p>"The history of great earthquakes at Nankai is convincingly scary," geologists Kyle Bradley and Judith A. Hubbard wrote in their Earthquake Insights newsletter last week.</p>

<p>But there was only a "small probability" that last week's magnitude 7.1 earthquake was a foreshock, according to Bradley and Hubbard.</p>

<p>"One of the challenges is that even when the risk of a second earthquake is elevated, it is still always low," they said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2017-09/earthquake-generic_650x400_71505899871.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Japan sees some 1,500 quakes every year, most of them minor (representational).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/is-great-britain-still-great-millions-face-hunger-as-poverty-crisis-escalates-6341832]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Is Great Britain Still Great? Nation Grapples With Deepening Poverty Crisis]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/is-great-britain-still-great-millions-face-hunger-as-poverty-crisis-escalates-6341832]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 15 Aug 2024 10:48:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The once-dominant British Empire has seen its global influence wane significantly, with India now surpassing the UK as the world's fifth-largest economy.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Two centuries ago, the British Empire ruled the lands, the seas, and a quarter of all people on Earth. The influence of the once-dominant United Kingdom has significantly shrunk, and in 2022, its former colony, India, surpassed it to become the world's fifth-largest economy.</p>

<p>The 21st century has been a rather tough time for the UK, starting with a monetary crisis in 2008, which exposed some underlying economic weaknesses, and then the cutting of long-lasting relations with its most significant trade partner, the EU, after the Brexit vote in 2016.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-slips-behind-india-to-become-worlds-sixth-biggest-economy-3311010"><strong>Also Read | India Now World's Fifth Largest Economy, Overtakes UK</strong></a><br />
<br />
The decision to leave the European Union in 2020 not only caused the UK's economy to suffer but also stirred up internal divisions, especially in Scotland and Northern Ireland, where independence movements gained momentum.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Covid-19 pandemic made the problems even worse, thus contributing to the mess. The damage done in terms of the death tolls and economic recessions was, among the developed countries, one of the worst.</p>

<p>One thing that stands out from these circumstances and hardships is that Britain used to be a superpower but now is just a middle-sized power that is trying to adjust to its reduced importance in the global community.</p>

<p>Will Hutton who is an Observer columnist, writes in <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2023/aug/13/uk-stop-kidding-ourselves-rich-nation-gone-bust"><em>The Guardian</em></a>, "2 million British people report going without food for at least a day in any month.Malnutrition stalks children - Britain's five-year-olds are among the shortest in Europe. One in three children live in poverty. It is time to stop talking and thinking of Britain as a rich country. We are poor and living on the edge."</p>

<p>"Britain has to start thinking of itself not as a rich industrial country but as a poor country facing first-order economic development challenges. Large parts of the UK are scarcely better off than middle-income developing countries, and on current trends are about to get poorer."</p>

<p><strong>UK Poverty Soars to 30-Year High</strong></p>

<p>The UK's absolute poverty increased at its fastest rate in thirty years due to the energy price problem.</p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.unicef.org.uk/press-releases/unicef-uk-responds-to-the-report-on-uk-child-poverty-from-the-un-special-rapporteur/">UNICEF</a> and <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://cpag.org.uk/news/child-poverty-reaches-record-high-failure-tackle-it-will-be-betrayal-britains-children">Child Poverty Action Group</a>, in 2022/23, the UK government estimated that 4.3 million children, or 30% of all children in the country, were living in relative low-income households after housing costs. This is an increase of 100,000 from the previous year, and 700,000 since 2010.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The government attributes the rise to high inflation caused by the war in Ukraine and supply chain issues. They also say that falling inflation, rising real wages, and higher benefits will help low-income households in the future.</p>

<p>Over the past few weeks, severe violence has erupted in several English cities as well as in Northern Ireland, indicating widespread anger throughout the nation. The UK Police have made almost 1,000 arrests in relation to the riots that included acts of violence, looting, and arson in addition to racist attacks.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/nncsh088_uk-poverty_625x300_15_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The 21st century has been challenging for the UK.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladeshi-students-on-alert-to-remain-on-streets-to-resist-chaos-6341495]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bangladeshi Students On Alert, To Remain On Streets To Resist Chaos]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladeshi-students-on-alert-to-remain-on-streets-to-resist-chaos-6341495]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 15 Aug 2024 09:40:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hundreds of Bangladeshi students wielding bamboo rods patrolled the site of a planned gathering Thursday of ousted premier Sheikh Hasina's supporters, vowing to quash any show of strength.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hundreds of Bangladeshi students wielding bamboo rods patrolled the site of a planned gathering Thursday of ousted premier Sheikh Hasina's supporters, vowing to quash any show of strength.</p>

<p>Hasina, 76, fled by helicopter last week to neighbouring India, where she remains, as student-yet protests flooded Dhaka's streets in a dramatic end to her iron-fisted 15-year rule.</p>

<p>Thursday is the anniversary of the 1975 assassination of her father, independence hero Sheikh Mujibur Rahman, during a military coup -- a date her government had declared a national holiday.</p>

<p>Previous years saw huge rallies around Bangladesh to mark the occasion, but the students who toppled Hasina were eager to ensure supporters of her Awami League party did not have a chance to regroup.</p>

<p>"Awami League will try to create chaos on Thursday in the name of observing (the) mourning day," prominent student leader Sarjis Alam told reporters the previous day, according to the Daily Star newspaper.</p>

<p>"We will remain on the streets to resist any such attempts."</p>

<p>With no police in sight, hundreds of students on Thursday patrolled the street leading into Hasina's old family home where her father and many of her relatives were gunned down nearly 50 years ago.</p>

<p>The landmark was until recently a museum to her father, but it was torched and vandalised by a mob hours after her fall.</p>

<p>In her first public statement since her abrupt departure, Hasina had this week asked supporters to "pray for the salvation of all souls by offering floral garlands and praying" outside the landmark.</p>

<p>Thousands of civil servants were required to join public demonstrations marking her father's death during her tenure.</p>

<p>Awami League organisers would also set up temporary public address systems around Dhaka to blare Mujib's old speeches and devotional songs praising his leadership.</p>

<p>The caretaker administration now running Bangladesh cancelled observance of the politically charged holiday on Tuesday, requiring bureaucrats to remain in office.</p>

<p>And on Thursday, the prevailing sound in the city of 20 million people was the horns and motors of its perennially gridlocked traffic.</p>

<h3><strong>&nbsp;'Identified and punished'&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Hasina's statement came hours after a court in the capital opened a murder case into her, two senior Awami League allies and four police officers related to last month's unrest.</p>

<p>Several other top Awami League politicians have also been detained in unrelated probes, including former law minister Anisul Huq and business adviser Salman Rahman.</p>

<p>Hasina's statement also demanded an investigation into violence during the unrest that forced her out of office, with the culprits to be "identified and punished".</p>

<p>Police weaponry was the cause of the more than 450 people killed during the protests that ousted Hasina, according to police and hospital figures previously gathered by AFP.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/08p889ro_bangladesh-students-amid-unrest-afp-_625x300_15_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[With no police in sight, students on Thursday patrolled the street leading into Hasina's old family home]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/taylor-swift-eras-tour-taylor-swift-to-return-to-stage-for-eras-tour-after-vienna-attack-plot-6341284]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Taylor Swift To Return To Stage For Eras Tour After Vienna Attack Plot]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/taylor-swift-eras-tour-taylor-swift-to-return-to-stage-for-eras-tour-after-vienna-attack-plot-6341284]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 15 Aug 2024 09:06:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Taylor Swift will return to the stage in London on Thursday to end the European leg of her "Eras" tour, a week after her Vienna concerts were cancelled due to a suicide attack plot.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Taylor Swift will return to the stage in London on Thursday to end the European leg of her "Eras" tour, a week after her Vienna concerts were cancelled due to a suicide attack plot.</p>

<p>Around 90,000 fans will again pack London's Wembley Stadium for the first date in the five-day run, with additional ticket checks and restrictions in place.</p>

<p>Last week, all three of the American mega-stars shows in the Austrian capital were cancelled following the discovery of an Islamic State-inspired plan to launch an attack using explosives and knives.</p>

<p>Three alleged Islamic State sympathisers have been arrested on charges of plotting the atrocity, which was thwarted with the help of US intelligence.</p>

<p>London's Metropolitan Police has said there was "nothing to indicate that the matters being investigated by the Austrian authorities will have an impact on upcoming events here in London".</p>

<p>The force was working "closely with venue security teams and other partners to ensure there are appropriate security and policing plans in place", a police spokesperson said in a statement.</p>

<p>Fans have been warned on Wembley's website to expect "additional ticket checks" around the stadium.</p>

<h3><strong>'Tay-gating'&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Swift's return to the British capital, following three sold-out shows in June, also comes two weeks after three young girls were killed in a stabbing at a dance class themed around the pop star's music in northwest England.</p>

<p>Following the knife attack, Swift said she was "completely in shock" and at a "complete loss for how to ever convey my sympathies to these families".</p>

<p>She has not yet commented on the decision to cancel the Vienna shows.</p>

<p>London's mayor Sadiq Khan told Sky News that the city was "going to carry on working closely with police, ensuring that the Taylor Swift concerts can take place in London safely".</p>

<p>"We have a huge amount of experience in policing these events, we're never complacent, many lessons were learned after the awful Manchester Arena attack," Khan added.</p>

<p>He was referring to the 2017 bombing at an Ariana Grande concert that killed 22 people, some of them children.</p>

<p>Fans without tickets will also not be allowed to "tay-gate" the event -- the practice of Swift fans standing outside the venue during the live show to hear the music.</p>

<h3><strong>Royal audience&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>The stadium's website says that "no one is allowed to stand outside any entrance or... at the front of the stadium" and "non-ticket holders will be moved on".</p>

<p>While the practice was not permitted at her June concerts there, some fans still managed to gather outside Wembley.</p>

<p>After two performances in Madrid at the end of July, Swift noted around 50,000 "people came out and listened to the show" from a nearby hillside on both nights, "participating in the show from afar".</p>

<p>Meanwhile, her last London appearances were attended by some high-profile names.</p>

<p>They included Keir Starmer, who was then running to become Britain's prime minister, and Prince William -- celebrating his birthday -- along with his children, Prince George and Princess Charlotte.</p>

<p>The singer posted a photo posing with the royals and her boyfriend, American football player Travis Kelce, with the caption "Happy Bday M8! London shows are off to a splendid start".</p>

<p>After wrapping up the European leg of her record-breaking tour -- which began in Paris in May and saw the star perform across the continent -- Swift will then head back to North America.</p>

<p>Its final leg there starts on October 18 in Miami.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/ppmudgjg_taylor-swift_625x300_08_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Taylor Swift's return to the British capital comes two weeks after the Southport killings (file).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/targeted-violence-against-hindus-vivek-ramaswamy-on-bangladesh-unrest-6341207]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Targeted Violence Against Hindus...": Vivek Ramaswamy On Bangladesh Unrest]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/targeted-violence-against-hindus-vivek-ramaswamy-on-bangladesh-unrest-6341207]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 15 Aug 2024 08:50:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former Republican presidential candidate Vivek Ramaswamy has spoken out strongly against attacks on the Hindu minority community in Bangladesh during the recent political unrest in the country following the ouster of Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former Republican presidential candidate Vivek Ramaswamy has spoken out strongly against attacks on the Hindu minority community in Bangladesh during the recent political unrest in the country following the ouster of Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina.&nbsp;Condemning the violence, Mr Ramaswamy said the deeper issues in Bangladesh are rooted in the country's long-standing, yet controversial, quota system.</p>

<p>"The targeted violence against Hindus in Bangladesh is wrong, it's concerning, and it's a cautionary tale for victimhood-laced quota systems," Mr Ramaswamy wrote on X.&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">The targeted violence against Hindus in Bangladesh is wrong, it's concerning, and it's a cautionary tale for victimhood-laced quota systems. Here's what happened: Bangladesh fought a bloody war for its independence in 1971. Hundreds of thousands of Bangladeshi civilians were…</p>
— Vivek Ramaswamy (@VivekGRamaswamy) <a href="https://twitter.com/VivekGRamaswamy/status/1823533267984749035?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 14, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>Mr Ramaswamy went on to explain the origins of the quota system, which was implemented after the 1971 war that saw Bangladesh gain independence from Pakistan.</p>

<p>"Bangladesh fought a bloody war for its independence in 1971. Hundreds of thousands of Bangladeshi civilians were raped and murdered. It was a tragedy, and it was rightly mourned. But in its aftermath, Bangladesh implemented a quota system for jobs in their civil service: 80% of the jobs were allocated to specific social groups (war veterans, rape victims, underrepresented residents, etc.), and only 20% were allocated based on merit," he said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The political turmoil in Bangladesh reached a climax on August 5, when Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina, aged 76, fled the country by helicopter to India as protesters overran the streets of Dhaka. Her 15-year rule, marked by allegations of human rights abuses, came to a dramatic end. The weeks leading up to her ousting were bloody, with more than 450 dying during the unrest.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The quota system proved to be a disaster," Mr Ramaswamy claimed, pointing to the 2018 protests that led Bangladesh to scrap most of the quotas, only for them to be reinstated in 2024. The Indian-origin politician warned that such systems, designed to rectify past wrongs, can inadvertently perpetuate cycles of violence.</p>

<p>"Once chaos begins, it can't easily be reined in. Radicals are now targeting Hindu minorities. A quota conflict created to rectify the wrongs of rape and violence in 1971 is now leading to more rape and violence in 2024. Bloodshed is the endpoint of grievance and victimhood. It's hard not to look at Bangladesh and wonder what lessons we would do well to learn right here at home," he said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Members of Ms Hasina's Awami League party went into hiding, and the country plunged into further instability. According to reports from the Bangladesh Hindu Buddhist Christian Unity Council and the Bangladesh Puja Udjapan Parishad, there have been at least 205 incidents of attacks on minority communities across 52 districts since Ms Hasina's departure. Thousands of Bangladeshi Hindus have sought refuge in India, fearing for their safety in the volatile environment.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-08/6jgbfcqo_vivek-ramaswamy-afp-_625x300_24_August_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["The quota system proved to be a disaster," Vivek Ramaswamy claimed.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/brazil-plane-crash-probe-reveals-brazil-plane-crashed-one-minute-after-pilots-sensed-trouble-6341169]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Probe Reveals Brazil Plane Crashed One Minute After Pilots Sensed Trouble]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/brazil-plane-crash-probe-reveals-brazil-plane-crashed-one-minute-after-pilots-sensed-trouble-6341169]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 15 Aug 2024 08:46:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Authorities investigating the Brazilian plane crash that killed all 62 on board last week now have the full transcript of the "black box" but its content did not immediately explain the cause of the accident, local TV station Globo said on Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Authorities investigating the Brazilian plane crash that killed all 62 on board last week now have the full transcript of the "black box" but its content did not immediately explain the cause of the accident, local TV station Globo said on Wednesday.</p>

<p>The transcript from the cockpit voice recorder shows the pilot and copilot noticed a steep loss of altitude about one minute before the crash, TV Globo reported in its main newscast Jornal Nacional on Wednesday evening, citing unnamed people working on the investigation.</p>

<p>TV Globo did not release the audio or the transcript.</p>

<p>According to TV Globo, the transcript covers about two hours of audio recording, including a question from the copilot to the pilot about what was going on, and saying the plane needed "more power" to be stabilized.</p>

<p>The plane, an ATR-72 turboprop from local airline Voepass, was bound for Sao Paulo from Cascavel, in the southern state of Parana, and crashed at around 1:30 p.m. (1630 GMT) in the town of Vinhedo, some 80 km (50 miles) northwest of Sao Paulo.</p>

<p>The crash killed all aboard but no one on the ground was hurt.</p>

<p>Video shared on social media right after the accident showed the ATR-72 aircraft spinning out of control as it plunged down behind a cluster of trees near houses, followed by a large plume of black smoke.</p>

<p>The pilots did not report an emergency or adverse weather conditions, the Brazilian Air Force said on Friday in a statement.</p>

<p>TV Globo said that, according to people investigating the crash, analysis of the audio alone will not make it possible for now to determine the cause of the crash.</p>

<p>TV Globo also said the authorities did not identify any characteristic sounds, such as from fire, electrical collapse or engine breakdowns, although the audio was said to be difficult to listen to.</p>

<p>A potential icing issue on the plane's wing was neither discarded nor confirmed by authorities, TV Globo said.</p>

<p>Videos of the crash analyzed by aviation experts led some to speculate that ice had built up on the plane.</p>

<p>Brazil's aviation accident investigation centre, Cenipa, could not immediately respond to a Reuters request for comment about the TV Globo report outside of regular business hours.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/juu3are_brazil-plane-crash_625x300_12_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The crash killed all aboard but no one on the ground was hurt (file).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-columbia-university-president-quits-4-months-after-gaza-war-campus-protests-6340942]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Columbia University President Quits 4 Months After Gaza War Campus Protests]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-columbia-university-president-quits-4-months-after-gaza-war-campus-protests-6340942]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 15 Aug 2024 08:05:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Columbia University President Minouche Shafik resigned on Wednesday, nearly four months after the Ivy League university's handling of campus protests over Israel's war in Gaza was criticized by pro-Israel and pro-Palestinian sides alike.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Columbia University President Minouche Shafik resigned on Wednesday, nearly four months after the Ivy League university's handling of campus protests over Israel's war in Gaza was criticized by pro-Israel and pro-Palestinian sides alike.</p>

<p>"It has also been a period of turmoil where it has been difficult to overcome divergent views across our community," Shafik said in an email to staff and students. "This period has taken a considerable toll on my family, as it has for others in our community."</p>

<p>Shafik said her departure "at this point would best enable Columbia to traverse the challenges ahead." She said she made the announcement so new leadership could be in place before the new term begins.</p>

<p>Columbia was rocked in April and May as protesters occupied parts of the Upper Manhattan campus in opposition to Palestinian civilian deaths in Gaza, resulting in hundreds of arrests. The demonstrators denounced Shafik for calling police onto campus to halt the demonstrations, while pro-Israel supporters castigated her for failing to crack down sufficiently.</p>

<p>Katrina Armstrong, Columbia's executive vice president for health and biomedical services, will serve as the interim president, according to the university website.</p>

<p>Republican US Representative Elise Stefanik from upstate New York, who castigated Shafik and other university leaders in congressional hearings over Gaza protests nationwide, welcomed her resignation on X, saying it was "overdue" because of her failure to protect Jewish students.</p>

<p>Shafik, an Egyptian-born economist who holds British and U.S. nationality, was previously deputy governor of the Bank of England, president of the London School of Economics and deputy managing director at the International Monetary Fund.</p>

<p>She became the 20th president of Columbia University in July 2023.</p>

<p>After protesters set up dozens of tents and demanded that the university sell its Israeli assets, university officials tried to negotiate an agreement with protesters on dismantling the camps.</p>

<p>As talks failed, Shafik on April 18 took the unusual step of asking New York police to enter the campus, angering many rights groups, students and faculty.</p>

<p>More than 100 people were arrested and the tents were removed from the main lawn, but within a few days, the encampment was back in place. The university called the police back in on April 30, when they arrested 300 people at Columbia and the City College of New York.</p>

<p>Shafik then asked police to stay until at least May 17 - two days after graduation - "to maintain order and ensure that encampments are not re-established."</p>

<p>The current Gaza conflict was triggered on Oct. 7 when Palestinian fighters from Hamas attacked Israel, killing 1,200 and taking about 250 hostages, according to Israeli tallies.</p>

<p>Israel's subsequent assault on the Hamas-governed enclave has since killed nearly 40,000 Palestinians, according to the local health ministry, while displacing nearly the entire population of 2.3 million, causing a hunger crisis and leading to genocide allegations at the World Court that Israel denies.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/q8n9brmg_columbia-university-president-reuters-_625x300_15_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Minouche Shafik became the 20th president of Columbia University in July 2023.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-speaks-with-netanyahu-over-gaza-truce-and-hostage-deal-says-sources-6340782]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Speaks With Netanyahu Over Gaza Truce And Hostage Deal: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-speaks-with-netanyahu-over-gaza-truce-and-hostage-deal-says-sources-6340782]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 15 Aug 2024 07:35:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump spoke on the phone with Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu on Wednesday and discussed the Gaza ceasefire and hostage release deal, Axios reported, citing two US sources.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump spoke on the phone with Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu on Wednesday and discussed the Gaza ceasefire and hostage release deal, Axios reported, citing two US sources.</p>

<p>One source told Axios that Trump's call was intended to encourage Netanyahu to take the deal, but stressed he did not know if this was indeed what the former president told Netanyahu. The Trump campaign did not immediately respond to a request for comment.</p>

<p>Late last month, Netanyahu visited the US and met President Joe Biden, Vice President and Democratic presidential candidate Kamala Harris and Republican former President Trump.</p>

<p>Egypt, the United States and Qatar have scheduled a new round of Gaza ceasefire negotiations for Thursday.</p>

<p>Biden laid out a three-phase ceasefire proposal in an address on May 31. Washington and regional mediators have since tried arranging the Gaza ceasefire-for-hostages deal but have run into repeated obstacles.</p>

<p>Hamas said on Wednesday it would not take part in a new round of Gaza ceasefire talks slated for Thursday in Qatar, but an official briefed on the talks said mediators expected to consult with the Palestinian Islamist group afterwards.</p>

<p>Washington, Israel's most important ally, has said that a ceasefire in Gaza will reduce the rising threat of a wider war in the Middle East.</p>

<p>There has been an increased risk of a broader war after the recent killings of Hamas leader Ismail Haniyeh in Iran and Hezbollah military commander Fuad Shukr in Beirut. Both drew threats of retaliation against Israel.</p>

<p>The latest bloodshed in the decades-old Israeli-Palestinian conflict was triggered on Oct. 7 when Hamas attacked Israel, killing 1,200 and taking about 250 hostages, according to Israeli tallies.</p>

<p>Israel's subsequent assault on the Hamas-governed enclave has since killed nearly 40,000 Palestinians, according to the local health ministry, while also displacing nearly the entire population of 2.3 million, causing a hunger crisis and leading to genocide allegations at the World Court that Israel denies.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/has938mg_donald-trump-netanyahu_625x300_26_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Benjamin Netanyahu met Joe Biden, Kamala Harris and Donald Trump late last month (file).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/google-says-iran-hackers-target-trump-kamala-harris-campaigns-6340311]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iran-Backed Hackers Targeting Donald Trump, Kamala Harris Campaigns: Google]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/google-says-iran-hackers-target-trump-kamala-harris-campaigns-6340311]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 15 Aug 2024 05:12:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Google on Tuesday confirmed that hackers backed by Iran are targeting the campaigns of US presidential rivals Kamala Harris and Donald Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Google on Tuesday confirmed that hackers backed by Iran are targeting the campaigns of US presidential rivals Kamala Harris and Donald Trump.</p>

<p>A hacker group known as "APT42" linked to Iran's Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps went after high-profile individuals and organizations in Israel and the United States, including government officials and political campaigns, according to a threat report released by Google.</p>

<p>Democratic presidential candidate Kamala Harris's campaign said Tuesday it had been targeted by foreign hackers, days after rival Donald Trump's campaign suggested that it had been hacked by Iran.</p>

<p>"In July, the campaign legal and security teams were notified by the FBI that we were targeted by a foreign actor influence operation," a Harris campaign official told AFP.</p>

<p>"We have robust cybersecurity measures in place and are not aware of any security breaches of our systems resulting from those efforts."&nbsp;</p>

<p>Google's threat analysis group continues to see unsuccessful attempts from APT42 to compromise personal accounts of individuals affiliated with President Joe Biden, Vice President Harris and Trump, the report said.</p>

<p>- <strong>Phishing</strong> -<br />
The hacking group works by gleaning information about targets and tailoring "phishing" efforts to dupe victims into revealing log-in information for accounts like Gmail.</p>

<p>Examples given in the report included posing as a think tank or other credible contact to lure victims to fake video meeting landing pages, where log-in credentials are needed to take part.</p>

<p>While technical tools abound in hacker arsenals, some opt for "social engineering" tactics that trick people into clicking on booby-trapped links or logging in to realistic replicas of legitimate web pages.</p>

<p>Google said it disrupted APT42 attempts to hack the campaigns of Biden and Trump in 2020.</p>

<p>In May and June of this year, the Iranian hacker group's targets included personal email accounts of about a dozen people affiliated with Biden or Trump and Google blocked numerous attempts by APT42 to log in to their accounts, according to the report.</p>

<p>Google also reported that the group got into the personal Gmail account of an influencial political consultant.</p>

<p>"APT42 is a sophisticated, persistent threat actor and they show no signs of stopping their attempts to target users and deploy novel tactics," Google said.</p>

<p>"This spring and summer, they have shown the ability to run numerous simultaneous phishing campaigns, particularly focused on Israel and the United States."</p>

<p>Google urged high-risk individuals associated with the coming election to remain vigilant and to take advantage of ramped-up defenses offered by the internet firm.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The US State Department warned Iran on Monday of consequences over election interference following the Trump campaign's announcement that it had been hacked.</p>

<p>The Trump campaign has suggested that Iran was behind the breach, which resulted in private documents being sent to reporters, including research the campaign used to vet running mate J.D. Vance.</p>

<p>It warned media outlets against reprinting the documents, saying that such action would be "doing the bidding of America's enemies."</p>

<p>The tone was different from 2016, when Trump said at a news conference that he hoped Russia would "find" Hillary Clinton's emails, remarks widely viewed as encouraging further hacks of his election opponent.</p>

<p>US intelligence concluded that Russia intervened in the 2016 election to support Trump, who has rejected the findings.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ugf3uu1g_trump-harris-_625x300_22_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Google confirmed that Iranian backed are targeting the campaigns of Kamala Harris and Donald Trump.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/1-4-million-afghan-girls-banned-from-schools-since-taliban-return-to-power-6340103]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[1.4 Million Afghan Girls Banned From Schools Since Taliban Return To Power]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/1-4-million-afghan-girls-banned-from-schools-since-taliban-return-to-power-6340103]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 15 Aug 2024 04:08:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[At least 1.4 million girls in Afghanistan have been denied access to secondary education since the Taliban returned to power in 2021, with the future of an entire generation now "in jeopardy", the United Nations' cultural agency said Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At least 1.4 million girls in Afghanistan have been denied access to secondary education since the Taliban returned to power in 2021, with the future of an entire generation now "in jeopardy", the United Nations' cultural agency said Thursday.</p>

<p>Access to primary education has also fallen sharply, with 1.1 million fewer girls and boys attending school, UNESCO said in a statement as the Taliban authorities marked three years since retaking Afghanistan on August 15, 2021.</p>

<p>"UNESCO is alarmed by the harmful consequences of this increasingly massive drop-out rate, which could lead to a rise in child labour and early marriage," the agency said.</p>

<p>"In just three years, the de facto authorities have almost wiped out two decades of steady progress for education in Afghanistan, and the future of an entire generation is now in jeopardy."</p>

<p>There are now nearly 2.5 million girls deprived of their right to education, representing 80 percent of Afghan school-age girls, the UN agency said.</p>

<p>The Taliban administration, which is not recognised by any other country, has imposed restrictions on women that the UN has described as "gender apartheid."</p>

<p>Afghanistan is the only country in the world to stop girls and women attending secondary schools and universities.</p>

<p>"As a result of bans imposed by the de facto authorities, at least 1.4 million girls have been deliberately denied access to secondary education since 2021," UNESCO said.</p>

<p>This represents an increase of 300,000 since the previous count carried out by the UN agency in April 2023.</p>

<p>UNESCO Director General Audrey Azoulay urged the international community to remain mobilised "to obtain the unconditional reopening of schools and universities to Afghan girls and women."</p>

<p>The number of primary pupils has also fallen. Afghanistan had only 5.7 million girls and boys in primary school in 2022, compared with 6.8 million in 2019, UNESCO said.</p>

<p>The UN agency blamed the drop on the authorities' decision to ban female teachers from teaching boys as well as the lack of incentive for parents to send children to school.</p>

<p>Enrolment in higher education in equally concerning, the statement said, adding that the number of university students had decreased by 53 percent since 2021.</p>

<p>"As a result, the country will rapidly face a shortage of graduates trained for the most highly-skilled jobs, which will only exacerbate development problems," UNESCO said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-08/a070en6s_herat-afp-650_625x300_18_August_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[There are now nearly 2.5 million girls deprived of their right to education, the UN agency said.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-judge-says-monopolist-google-cant-avoid-app-store-reforms-6340048]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Judge Says "Monopolist" Google Can't Avoid App Store Reforms]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-judge-says-monopolist-google-cant-avoid-app-store-reforms-6340048]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 15 Aug 2024 03:41:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A U.S. judge said he was planning to issue an order forcing Alphabet's Google to give Android users more ways to download apps, but would not micromanage the tech giant's business, following a jury verdict last year for "Fortnite" maker Epic Games.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A U.S. judge on Wednesday said he was planning to issue an order forcing Alphabet's Google to give Android users more ways to download apps, but would not micromanage the tech giant's business, following a jury verdict last year for “Fortnite” maker Epic Games.</p>

<p>U.S. District Judge James Donato in San Francisco heard from technology experts and lawyers for Epic and Google about proposed reforms in the blockbuster antitrust case.</p>

<p>Donato showed impatience for Google's protests about the costs and difficulty of implementing many of Epic's proposals, and signaled he would issue a ruling that would maximize users' and developers' flexibility to download and distribute apps outside the Play store.</p>

<p>“You're going to end up paying something to make the world right after having been found to be a monopolist,” Donato said.</p>

<p>He said his injunction will be about three pages long and will ensure Google knows what the “rules of the road are.”</p>

<p>Donato said he will rule in the coming weeks and set up a three-person compliance and technical committee to implement and monitor the injunction.</p>

<p>“Google foreclosed competition for years and years and years. We're opening the gate now and letting competitors come in,” Donato said.</p>

<p>Google declined to comment, and Epic did not immediately respond to a request for one.</p>

<p>Epic's lawsuit accused Google of monopolizing how consumers access apps on Android devices and how they pay for in-app transactions.</p>

<p>The Cary, North Carolina-based company persuaded a jury in December 2023 that Google unlawfully stifled competition through its controls over app distribution and payments.</p>

<p>Epic has asked Donato to require Google to make it easier for Android users to download apps from third-party app stores, such as Epic's, and from other internet sources. It also wants the court to forbid Google from automatically installing its Play store on Android devices.</p>

<p>Google has denied harming competition, and it told Donato that Epic's proposals "would make it nearly impossible" for the Alphabet unit to compete and harm consumer privacy and security.</p>

<p>Google lawyer Glenn Pomerantz told Donato on Wednesday that Google should not be forced to distribute its rivals' app stores. "Competition will be worse if you impose a duty that you have to deal with your competitor," Pomerantz said.</p>

<p>Epic's lawyer Gary Bornstein urged the court to direct Google to act quickly to implement his injunction.</p>

<p>Google faces another threat to its business practices in a separate government lawsuit in Washington, D.C. challenging the company's dominant search engine.</p>

<p>Last week, U.S. District Judge Amit Mehta ruled for the U.S. Justice Department and said Google had illegally monopolized web search, spending billions to become the internet's default search engine. Google has denied the claims.</p>

<p>Mehta has set a Sept. 6 hearing to discuss a timeline for the court to impose remedies on Google in that case.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-05/2r3h93qg_google-office_625x300_11_May_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Google lawyer said that tech giant should not be forced to distribute its rivals' app stores.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-ucla-must-protect-jewish-students-access-to-campus-judge-rules-6339350]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US' UCLA Must Protect Jewish Students' Access To Campus, Judge Rules]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-ucla-must-protect-jewish-students-access-to-campus-judge-rules-6339350]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 15 Aug 2024 00:06:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The University of California in Los Angeles cannot allow pro-Palestinian protesters to block Jewish students from accessing campus buildings, classes and services, a federal judge has ruled.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The University of California in Los Angeles cannot allow pro-Palestinian protesters to block Jewish students from accessing campus buildings, classes and services, a federal judge has ruled.</p>

<p>US District Judge Mark Scarsi's order appears to be the first ruling against a US university connected with the demonstrations protesting the Israel-Gaza conflict that erupted at hundreds of college campuses earlier this year.</p>

<p>The decision to issue a preliminary injunction against the prestigious university, issued on Tuesday, came as part of a lawsuit filed in June by three Jewish students, who said pro-Palestinian protesters blocked them from campus based on their faith.</p>

<p>"In the year 2024, in the United States of America, in the State of California, in the City of Los Angeles, Jewish students were excluded from portions of the UCLA campus because they refused to denounce their faith," Scarsi wrote, calling it "unimaginable" and "abhorrent."</p>

<p>He barred the school from offering any programs, activities or access to campus buildings if it knows any of them are not available to Jewish students.</p>

<p>In court papers, the school had argued it could not be held legally responsible for alleged discrimination perpetrated by third parties. The university also said it worked with law enforcement to dismantle encampments and had taken steps to improve its response to protests in the future, including creating a new campus safety office and blocking at least three new efforts to occupy parts of campus.</p>

<p>The school's vice chancellor for strategic communications, Mary Osako, said in a statement that UCLA was considering "all our options" in response to the ruling.</p>

<p>"UCLA is committed to fostering a campus culture where everyone feels welcome and free from intimidation, discrimination, and harassment," she said. "The district court's ruling would improperly hamstring our ability to respond to events on the ground and to meet the needs of the Bruin community."</p>

<p>One of the students who brought the lawsuit, law student Yitzchok Frankel, said in a statement, "No student should ever have to fear being blocked from their campus because they are Jewish."</p>

<p>UCLA was thrust into the national spotlight when masked assailants attacked a pro-Palestinian encampment on April 30 with clubs and poles, sparking a fight that saw both sides exchanging blows and pepper spray.</p>

<p>The next night, police forcibly dismantled the encampment and arrested more than 200 people.</p>

<p>Activists criticized police for responding too slowly to the attack and then for moving too aggressively to take down the tent camp a day later. The chief of the campus police department was reassigned pending an outside review.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/i1k2a7h8_ucla-protest-reuters_625x300_15_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[UCLA faculty stands on the frontlines after they were asked to leave by UCLA campus police in May. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/laughable-us-on-allegation-that-it-was-involved-in-sheikh-hasinas-ouster-6339290]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Laughable": US On Allegation That It Was Involved In Sheikh Hasina's Exit]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/laughable-us-on-allegation-that-it-was-involved-in-sheikh-hasinas-ouster-6339290]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 14 Aug 2024 23:52:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United States Department of State strongly rejected the allegations of the government's involvement in former Bangladesh Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina's resignation, terming them 'laughable' and 'absolutely false' claims.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United States Department of State strongly rejected the allegations of the government's involvement in former Bangladesh Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina's resignation, terming them 'laughable' and 'absolutely false' claims.</p>

<p>"That's laughable. Any implication that the United States was involved in Sheikh Hasina's resignation is absolutely false," Principal Deputy Spokesperson of the US Department of State, Vedant Patel, said in a press briefing on Tuesday (local time).</p>

<p>Patel further said that a lot of disinformation has been seen in recent weeks regarding the current happenings in Bangladesh.</p>

<p>"We have seen a lot of disinformation in recent weeks and we were made incredibly committed to strengthening information and integrity across the regional ecosystem, especially our partners in South Asia," he said.</p>

<p>Recently, in an interview with ANI, Michael Kugelman, a US-based Foreign Policy expert, and Director of the South Asia Institute at The Wilson Center, refuted allegations of foreign interference behind the mass uprising that led to Sheikh Hasina's ouster, stating he had not seen any 'plausible evidence' to support these claims.</p>

<p>He noted that the Hasina government's harsh crackdown on protesters escalated the movement. "My view has been very simple. I see this as a crisis that was driven by purely internal factors, by students who were unhappy about a particular issue, job quotas that they didn't like and they were worried about the government. Sheikh Hasina's government cracked down very hard on the students and that then turned the movement into something much bigger. And this was simply driven by internal factors," Kugelman said.</p>

<p>Kugelman dismissed allegations from Sheikh Hasina's son, Sajeeb Wazed Joy, who claimed foreign interference behind the protests, saying that the unrest was driven by "internal factors."</p>

<p>"Now, you know, when there is a conspiracy theory that is rooted in issues of foreign influence, one cannot disprove such type of allegation. Also, at the same time, one cannot conclusively prove it. I think the onus, is the responsibility to provide a plausible explanation for how it can be true. I am yet to hear that from Sheikh Hasina's son, from anyone," he added.</p>

<p>Bangladesh has been witnessing a fluid political situation ever since protests started across the country, leading to Sheikh Hasina's resignation from the post of Prime Minister on August 5. The protests, led mainly by students demanding an end to a quota system for government jobs, evolved into anti-government demonstrations.</p>

<p>A large number of people protested outside the White House in Washington on Friday last week against alleged violence targeting minority Hindus and others in Bangladesh since former Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina's ouster.</p>

<p>Protesters carried American and Bangladeshi flags and held posters demanding that Bangladeshi minorities be "saved." They chanted slogans of "We want justice" and called for peace amid the recent surge in violence.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/81hfi6o_sheikh-hasina_625x300_07_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Bangladesh has been witnessing a fluid political situation.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>