<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Sat, 10 Aug 2024 09:34:33 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/airstrike-on-gaza-school-kills-100-israel-says-it-was-hamas-command-centre-6305227]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Airstrike On Gaza School Kills 100, Israel Says It Was Hamas Command Centre]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/airstrike-on-gaza-school-kills-100-israel-says-it-was-hamas-command-centre-6305227]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 10 Aug 2024 09:17:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Gaza's civil defence agency said Saturday an Israeli strike hit a school in Gaza City, killing 90-100 people, while the Israeli military said it had struck a Hamas command centre.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Gaza's civil defence agency said Saturday an Israeli strike hit a school in Gaza City, killing 90-100 people, while the Israeli military said it had struck a Hamas command centre.</p>

<p>"Forty martyrs and dozens wounded after the Israeli bombing of the Al-Taba'een school in the Al-Sahaba area in Gaza City," agency spokesman Mahmoud Basal said in a post on Telegram.</p>

<p>Basal described the incident as "a horrific massacre", with some bodies catching fire.</p>

<p>"The crews are trying to control the fire to retrieve the bodies of the martyrs and rescue the wounded," he said.</p>

<p>Israel's army said Saturday it had "precisely struck Hamas terrorists operating within a Hamas command and control center embedded in the Al-Taba'een school".</p>

<p>On Thursday, the agency said Israeli strikes had hit two schools in Gaza City, killing more than 18 people.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said at the time it had struck Hamas command centres.</p>

<p>The war in Gaza began with Hamas's October 7 attack that resulted in the deaths of 1,198 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli official figures.</p>

<p>Palestinian operatives seized 251 hostages, 111 of whom are still held in Gaza, including 39 the Israeli military says are dead.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory military campaign in Gaza has killed at least 39,699 people, according to the Hamas-run territory's health ministry, which does not give details of civilian and militant deaths.</p>

<p>Israel has vowed to destroy the Palestinian group in retaliation for its October attack, but during 10 months of war across the Gaza Strip, the military has found itself returning to some areas to fight the militants again.</p>

<p>Israel's military on Friday said troops were operating around Khan Yunis, the southern Gaza city from which soldiers had withdrawn in April after months of fierce fighting with Hamas.</p>

<p>After the military issued an evacuation order for parts of Khan Yunis, AFPTV images showed a crowd of people flowing through dusty, damaged streets on foot or on donkeys and motorcycle carts piled with belongings.</p>

<p>By Friday, the United Nations Humanitarian Office OCHA estimated that "at least 60,000 Palestinians may have moved towards western Khan Yunis in the past 72 hours", said UN spokeswoman Florencia Soto Nino.</p>

<p>The Gaza war has already pulled in Iran-aligned groups in the region, and fears of a broader Middle East war have surged following vows of vengeance for the killing of two senior militants, including Hamas's political leader.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/mq9rsdc_gaza-august-2024-afp-_625x300_10_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel has vowed to destroy the Palestinian group in retaliation for its October attack.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/inquest-to-look-into-british-girl-who-died-after-drinking-costa-hot-chocolate-6305230]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Inquest To Look Into UK Girl Who Died After Drinking Costa Hot Chocolate]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/inquest-to-look-into-british-girl-who-died-after-drinking-costa-hot-chocolate-6305230]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 10 Aug 2024 09:14:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Despite her mother's request for soya milk due to Hannah's dairy intolerance, the drink contained regular milk. Hannah, who had multiple food allergies, experienced severe distress and passed away after emergency treatment failed.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An inquest will begin next week to investigate the death of a teenage girl who died after suffering a suspected allergic reaction to a hot chocolate purchased from Costa Coffee, according to <em>The Guardian.</em></p>

<p>Thirteen-year-old Hannah Jacobs, of Barking, East London, collapsed and died on February 8 last year following a suspected anaphylactic reaction to the hot chocolate from Costa Coffee.</p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/article/2024/aug/09/inquest-to-look-into-13-year-old-girl-who-died-after-drinking-costa-hot-chocolate"><em>The Guardian,</em></a> Hannah and her mother had visited the Costa Coffee shop on the way to a dentist appointment. Despite Hannah's mother warning the barista that Hannah was intolerant of dairy and she should have soy milk, regular milk was in the drink.</p>

<p>Hannah had suffered from a number of food allergies since she was young to things like dairy, eggs, fish, and wheat. When she tasted the hot chocolate, she knew she had been given the wrong milk, and she felt acute distress.</p>

<p>The mother rushed Hannah to a pharmacy for help, where an EpiPen was administered to try and calm the allergic reaction. Emergency services rushed her to the hospital within minutes, but Hannah couldn't be revived and was pronounced dead at 1 pm.</p>

<p>According to<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.lbc.co.uk/news/schoolgirl-13-dies-after-suffering-severe-allergic-reaction-to-costa-hot-chocola/"><em> LBC news</em></a>, the death of Hannah reminds us of another case-that of Natasha Ednan-Laperouse, who died in 2016 from an allergic reaction to sesame seeds in a Pret a Manger baguette. That led the UK government to implement Natasha's Law in 2021, under which firms are compelled to label the allergens used in pre-packaged foods prepared on their premises.</p>

<p>Every year, some 10 people in Britain die from food allergies, while about 5,000 get hospitalised for severe reactions. Some 2.4 million people live with food allergies in the UK.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/t8t6dvho_costa-coffee_625x300_10_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Teen suffered suspected anaphylactic reaction to cows' milk in takeaway beverage.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/most-violent-pro-trump-us-capitol-rioter-handed-20-year-jail-sentence-6305113]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Most Violent" Pro-Trump US Capitol Rioter Handed 20-Year Jail Sentence]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/most-violent-pro-trump-us-capitol-rioter-handed-20-year-jail-sentence-6305113]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 10 Aug 2024 08:46:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A man described by prosecutors as one of the "most violent" members of a pro-Donald Trump mob that stormed the US Capitol on January 6, 2021, was sentenced to 20 years in prison on Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A man described by prosecutors as one of the "most violent" members of a pro-Donald Trump mob that stormed the US Capitol on January 6, 2021, was sentenced to 20 years in prison on Friday.</p>

<p>The sentence handed down to David Dempsey, 37, of Santa Ana, California, is the second longest for any of the nearly 1,500 people charged for their roles in the attack on Congress.</p>

<p>Enrique Tarrio, the former leader of the far-right Proud Boys group, was convicted of seditious conspiracy and sentenced to 22 years in prison.</p>

<p>The assault on the Capitol left at least five people dead and 140 police officers injured.</p>

<p>It followed a fiery speech by then-president Trump to tens of thousands of his supporters near the White House in which he repeated his false claims that he won the 2020 election.</p>

<p>Prosecutors sought a term of nearly 22 years for Dempsey, noting in their sentencing memorandum that the former construction worker and fast-food restaurant employee had an extensive criminal record.</p>

<p>Dempsey pleaded guilty to two counts of assaulting police officers and was sentenced by Senior District Judge Royce Lamberth, an appointee of Republican president Ronald Reagan, to 20 years in prison and three years of supervised release.</p>

<p>Prosecutors, in their memo, called Dempsey "one of the most violent rioters, during one of the most violent stretches of time, at the scene of the most violent confrontations at the Capitol."</p>

<p>"Unlike other rioters who slowly pushed their way through the crowd towards the Capitol, Dempsey climbed atop his fellow rioters, using them like human scaffolding, thrusting himself to the front," they said.</p>

<p>Dempsey used his "hands, feet, flag poles, crutches, pepper spray, broken pieces of furniture, and anything else he could get his hands on, as weapons against the police," they said.</p>

<p>Trump faces four federal felony charges in Washington related to efforts to overturn the results of the 2020 election, but the case is unlikely to reach trial before the November presidential vote, in which he is once again the Republican candidate.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-01/ka676kk8_us-capitol-attack_625x300_07_January_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The assault on the US Capitol in 2021 left at least 5 people dead and 140 police officers injured (file).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/irans-guards-want-to-hit-israel-cities-new-president-has-eyes-on-mossad-6305078]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[In Iran, New President vs Revolutionary Guards Over Israel Air Strikes]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/irans-guards-want-to-hit-israel-cities-new-president-has-eyes-on-mossad-6305078]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 10 Aug 2024 08:38:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A standoff between Iran's newly elected President Masoud Pezeshkian and some hardliners in the powerful Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps (IRGC) has put the future of Iran's response to Hamas leader Ismail Haniyeh's assassination hanging in balance.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A standoff between Iran's newly elected President Masoud Pezeshkian and some hardliners in the powerful Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps (IRGC) has put the future of Iran's response to Hamas leader Ismail Haniyeh's assassination in Tehran hanging in the balance. According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.telegraph.co.uk/world-news/2024/08/09/iran-president-masoud-pezeshkian-israel-revolutionary-guard/">The Telegraph</a>, the Iranian government is divided over how to retaliate against Israel following the killing.</p>

<p>The IRGC is reportedly advocating for a direct and severe missile strike on Tel Aviv and other major Israeli cities. However, President Pezeshkian, who assumed office just days before the assassination, is pushing back against this aggressive strategy. Pezeshkian, known for his relatively moderate stance and his electoral victory over a candidate backed by the IRGC, is advocating for a more calculated response. He is urging for strikes on alleged Mossad bases located outside Israel, particularly in neighbouring regions such as the Republic of Azerbaijan and Iraqi Kurdistan. This approach, he argues, would minimise the risk of a full-scale war with Israel, a conflict he believes could have grave consequences for Iran.</p>

<p>"Pezeshkian fears that any direct attack on Israel would have serious consequences," a close aide to President Pezeshkian told The Telegraph. The aide reportedly added that Pezeshkian has suggested notifying Azerbaijan and Iraqi Kurdistan before any strikes on alleged Israeli bases within their borders.</p>

<p>The IRGC, which has historically enjoyed significant autonomy and influence within the Iranian government, is reportedly undermining Pezeshkian's efforts to avoid a major confrontation with Israel. An official from the IRGC told The Telegraph that the organization is largely dismissive of the president's more restrained approach. "The number one consideration is still striking Tel Aviv with Hezbollah and others at the same time," the official said as quoted by The Telegraph</p>

<p>Esmail Qaani, the commander of the IRGC's elite Quds Force, has also voiced strong support for an immediate and decisive retaliation.</p>

<p>According to The Telegraph, Pezeshkian faces an uphill battle in asserting his authority over the IRGC, which remains loyal to Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei. According to another aide close to the president, the IRGC's push for a more aggressive response is "more about undermining his week-long presidency rather than covering the humiliation they have suffered" from the assassination.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/28pf3gc8_iran-_625x300_10_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The IRGC is reportedly advocating for a direct missile strike on Israel.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/taylor-swift-us-confirms-sharing-intel-to-prevent-attack-at-taylor-swifts-vienna-concert-6305004]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Confirms Sharing Intel To Prevent Attack At Taylor Swift's Vienna Concert]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/taylor-swift-us-confirms-sharing-intel-to-prevent-attack-at-taylor-swifts-vienna-concert-6305004]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 10 Aug 2024 08:11:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United States provided intelligence to Austria that helped disrupt an alleged Islamic State plot to attack a Taylor Swift concert, the White House confirmed Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United States provided intelligence to Austria that helped disrupt an alleged Islamic State plot to attack a Taylor Swift concert, the White House confirmed Friday.</p>

<p>"We work closely with partners all over the world to monitor and disrupt threats," National Security Council spokesman John Kirby told reporters</p>

<p>"As part of that work, the United States did share information with Austrian partners to enable the disruption of a threat to Taylor Swift's concert in Vienna," he said.</p>

<p>Three alleged Islamic State sympathizers have been arrested on charges of plotting a suicide attack at the megastar's concert in Vienna.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/ppmudgjg_taylor-swift_625x300_08_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Three alleged ISIS supporters have been arrested for plotting a suicide attack at Taylor Swift's concert.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/covid-19-making-a-comeback-urgent-who-warning-on-severe-variants-6304945]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Covid-19 Cases Rising Again: WHO Issues Urgent Alert On Severe Variants]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/covid-19-making-a-comeback-urgent-who-warning-on-severe-variants-6304945]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 10 Aug 2024 07:58:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The World Health Organization (WHO) warns that Covid-19 is making a comeback, with positive test rates increasing across 84 countries and the potential for more severe variants emerging.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you believe that Covid-19 is no longer a concern or that its impact has diminished, think again. The World Health Organization (WHO) reports that the percentage of positive tests has been increasing across 84 countries in recent weeks.</p>

<p>The UN health agency is also warning that more severe variants of the coronavirus may soon be on the horizon.</p>

<p>"Covid-19 is still very much with us," and circulating in all countries, Dr Maria Van Kerkhove of WHO <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.unognewsroom.org/story/en/2284/covid-19-situation-update-who-06aug2024">told journalists in Geneva.</a></p>

<p>"Data from our sentinel-based surveillance system across 84 countries reports that the percent of positive tests for SARS-CoV-2 has been rising over several weeks," she said. "Overall, test positivity is above 10 per cent, but this fluctuates per region. In Europe, percent positivity is above 20 per cent," Dr Van Kerkhove added.</p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://fortune.com/well/article/covid-summer-surge-2024-symptoms-treatment-isolation-guidelines/"><em>Fortune Magazine,</em></a> the virus has spread far and wide this summer; President Joe Biden tested positive in July and, according to the World Health Organization (WHO), at least 40 athletes at the Paris Olympics have been infected with Covid or other respiratory illnesses.</p>

<p>As per a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.unognewsroom.org/story/en/2284/covid-19-situation-update-who-06aug2024"><em>WHO release</em></a>, new waves of infection have been registered in the Americas, Europe and Western Pacific. Wastewater surveillance suggests that the circulation of SARS-CoV-2 is two to 20 times higher than what is currently being reported. Such high infection circulation rates in the northern hemisphere's summer months are atypical for respiratory viruses, which tend to spread mostly in cold temperatures.</p>

<p>"In recent months, regardless of the season, many countries have experienced surges of Covid-19, including at the Olympics where at least 40 athletes have tested positive," Dr Van Kerkhove said.</p>

<p>"As individuals it is important to take measures to reduce risk of infection and severe disease, including ensuring that you have had a Covid-19 vaccination dose in the last 12 months, especially, if you are in an at-risk group," stressed Dr Van Kerkhove.</p>

<p>Vaccines availability has declined substantially over the last 12-18 months, WHO admits, because the number of producers of Covid-19 vaccines has recently decreased. "It is very difficult for them to maintain the pace," Dr Van Kerkhove explained. "And certainly, they don't need to maintain the pace that they had in 2021 and 2022. But let's be very clear, there is a market for Covid-19 vaccines that are out there."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/ullf6j0o_covid19_625x300_10_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[WHO urges individuals, especially those in at-risk groups, to ensure they are vaccinated.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-port-braces-for-bombardment-amid-fears-of-iran-hezbollah-attacks-6304942]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israeli Port Braces For Bombardment Amid Fears Of Iran, Hezbollah Attacks]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-port-braces-for-bombardment-amid-fears-of-iran-hezbollah-attacks-6304942]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 10 Aug 2024 07:56:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Haifa's residents gaze warily onto the sprawling industrial port that flanks their Israeli city, knowing the potential for a major blast as they brace for bombardment from Hezbollah.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Haifa's residents gaze warily on to the sprawling industrial port that flanks their Israeli city, knowing the potential for a major blast as they brace for bombardment from Hezbollah.</p>

<p>The historic city cascades down a steep hillside to the very edge of the port, a complex which contains Israel's biggest oil refinery, giant fuel tanks and other highly flammable targets.</p>

<p>Memories are vivid in Haifa, about 30 kilometres (less than 20 miles) from the Lebanese border, of the 2006 war with Hezbollah when the group's rockets repeatedly slammed into the city, reducing homes to rubble and leaving more than a dozen people dead.</p>

<p>Residents are also aware of the notorious Beirut port blast that killed more than 220 people, injured at least 6,500 and devastated large parts of the Lebanese capital in August 2020.</p>

<p>Haifa is now in the crosshairs once again with Iran and its proxies feared to be preparing an attack over last week's killings of top officials from Hezbollah and the Palestinian operative group Hamas.</p>

<p>"Of course, it's a main concern, especially after what we've seen happening four years ago in the harbour of Beirut," long-time resident Patrice Wolff told AFP, when asked about the potential for a big explosion.</p>

<p>"We know how damaging it can be, a blast from this area, so we are very conscious of it. And we certainly hope it will not come to be that bad."</p>

<h3><strong>'We are very exposed'&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Haifa's Mount Carmel offers panoramic views across the city, port, Israeli coast and northern Israel, all the way up to the mountainous, disputed border.</p>

<p>However, the area has come under repeated drone attacks in recent days, increasing jitters in the frontline region.</p>

<p>The residents of Haifa, population 280,000, know the drill: if the air raid siren sounds, or is alerted via smartphone, they have one minute to reach a bomb shelter or secure area.</p>

<p>Wolff, 58, who works for a medical supplies company, sleeps with his phone next to him in case of an alert.</p>

<p>"We're all very conscious of the risk and we know what to do if things go astray. We have instructions from the civil defence on how to behave," he said.</p>

<p>"We certainly hope that it will not come to this extent but we are very exposed because we're in a straight line from Lebanon."</p>

<p>As tensions climb, the number of tourists to the laid-back, beachside city -- home to Jews, Muslims and Christians -- has plunged.</p>

<p>"There are fewer tourists now; there used to be a lot, but now there are fewer. Business is slow," said Nadia Abu-Shaker of Humus Abu Shaker, a popular restaurant close to the port.</p>

<p>"Many people are afraid and don't leave their homes, they don't go anywhere," she added.</p>

<p>However, the prospect of an attack does not faze Abu-Shaker, who lived through the 2006 Hezbollah strikes as well as 1991, when Iraqi missile fire hit her home.</p>

<p>"I'm not afraid. I live near the port, at the Abu Shaker restaurant. If there is a war, I'm not afraid because I know that God protects us," she said.</p>

<h3>&nbsp;<strong>'We don't trust them'&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Many of Haifa's hotel rooms are occupied by evacuees from border areas, forced out of their homes by Hezbollah shelling since the Israel-Hamas war started in October.</p>

<p>The city has made careful preparations for an attack, opening bomb shelters with capacity for tens of thousands of people, according to Leonid Reznik, head of emergency preparedness at the Haifa municipality.</p>

<p>The shelters, many of which are converted underground car parks, can house people for days at a time and come equipped with generators, wifi, water and first aid, he said.</p>

<p>Kindergarten teachers will be deployed to the bigger shelters to keep young children occupied, Reznik added.</p>

<p>Haifa's main hospital, which received dead and wounded soldiers during the 2006 war with Lebanon, has a large underground facility that is already in use, he said.</p>

<p>"Because we're waiting for the response from the Iranians or Hezbollah, we understand that something will happen. They will not do nothing. They will respond in some way," Reznik said.</p>

<p>"We hope it will not be shooting into the city but we understand something will happen."</p>

<p>Reassurances that some of the most explosive chemicals have been removed from the port do not reassure Andre Suidan, whose wine shop overlooks the complex.</p>

<p>"We don't trust them. We don't trust that they did (move the chemicals)," said the Haifa native, 57, calling the refinery's presence "horrific".</p>

<p>"People are completely impatient and they're completely stressed out. These are not normal times," Suidan said.</p>

<p>"It's affecting people on the street, it's affecting people everywhere. Everybody's extra-tense."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/j3gpcq9g_haifa-israeli-port-afp-_625x300_10_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Haifa's Mount Carmel offers panoramic views across the city, port, Israeli coast and northern Israel.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mexican-druglords-son-surrendered-voluntarily-to-us-partner-was-kidnapped-6304848]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Mexican Druglord's Son Surrendered Voluntarily To US, Partner Was Kidnapped]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mexican-druglords-son-surrendered-voluntarily-to-us-partner-was-kidnapped-6304848]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 10 Aug 2024 07:24:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The US embassy in Mexico said on Friday that Joaquin Guzman Lopez, the son of the infamous cartel kingpin "El Chapo," had surrendered voluntarily while his father's former partner Ismael "El Mayo" Zambada seemed to have been taken against his will.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The US embassy in Mexico said on Friday that Joaquin Guzman Lopez, the son of the infamous cartel kingpin "El Chapo," had surrendered voluntarily while his father's former partner Ismael "El Mayo" Zambada seemed to have been taken against his will.</p>

<p>Both Zambada and Guzman Lopez have pleaded not guilty to drug trafficking charges in the United States and their lawyers offered contrasting versions of their arrests.</p>

<p>Zambada's lawyer said Guzman Lopez and six men in military uniforms "forcibly kidnapped" his client near the Sinaloa state capital of Culiacan and flew him to the United States against his will. The Guzman family lawyer denied a kidnapping and called it a voluntary surrender after extended negotiations.</p>

<p>The murky circumstances leading to the Sinaloa Cartel members' US arrest last month caused Mexico's president to reproach the Latin American nation's neighbour for lack of cooperation.</p>

<p>"No US resources were used in the surrender. It was not our plane, nor our pilot, nor our people," the embassy said in a statement.</p>

<p>It added that no flight plan had been shared with US authorities and the pilot was neither a U.S. citizen and nor had he been hired by the US government.</p>

<p>"This represents a great victory for both countries," the embassy said in the statement. "It is the result of a very precise work based on the principles of respect for our respective sovereignties and we do this work as partners.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/7vj0hpbo_joaquin-guzman-lopez-_625x300_31_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[El Chapo's Son Guzman Lopez have pleaded not guilty to drug trafficking charges in the US (file).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/imane-khelif-boxer-in-gender-row-and-now-olympic-champion-6304776]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Imane Khelif: Boxer In Gender Row And Now Olympic Champion]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/imane-khelif-boxer-in-gender-row-and-now-olympic-champion-6304776]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 10 Aug 2024 07:00:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Born in a poor village, Algerian boxer Imane Khelif has overcome numerous obstacles throughout her life to win a controversial Paris Olympics gold on Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Born in a poor village, Algerian boxer Imane Khelif has overcome numerous obstacles throughout her life to win a controversial Paris Olympics gold on Friday.</p>

<p>Sporting braided hair and standing strong at 1.79 metres (5ft 9in), the 25-year-old has unwittingly become one of the central figures of the Games.</p>

<p>Along with Taiwan's Lin Yu-ting, she was disqualified from last year's world championships after failing gender eligibility testing, only to be cleared to compete in the French capital.</p>

<p>Ms Khelif was born in a village 300 kilometres (180 miles) from the Algerian capital Algiers.</p>

<p>From a family of limited means, she spoke before the Games of the difficulty of her life in "a village of conservative people" in semi-desert surroundings.</p>

<p>"I came from a conservative family. Boxing is not a widely practised sport by women, especially in Algeria," she told Canal Algerie a month before the Games, smiling readily and her voice soft.</p>

<p>"It was difficult."</p>

<p>A strong athlete, she played football with the boys in her village of Biban Mesbah, but beating them in matches brought on brawls where she fought back with punches.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/mcmocc7_imane-khelif-afp_625x300_10_August_24.jpeg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>These fights ultimately led her to boxing, and on Friday one of the most contentious gold medals in recent memory.</p>

<p>In an interview with UNICEF, she said she used to sell scrap metal and her mother sold homemade couscous to pay for bus tickets to a nearby town.</p>

<p>Ms Imane's father Omar at first did not approve of her decision to pursue boxing, but he eventually became one of her biggest fans.</p>

<p>The unemployed welder previously told AFP that his daughter is "an example of the Algerian woman", praising also her dedication to training.</p>

<h2><strong>'Brave girl'</strong></h2>

<p>In 2022, Khelif told the Algerian news agency APS that she had considered giving up boxing "because my family did not accept the idea and because of how society looked at me, considering that I was doing something wrong".</p>

<p>"But all these barriers made me even stronger and were an extra motivation to achieve my dreams."</p>

<p>She also expressed her determination in an interview on the UNICEF website, where she said her "dream is to win a gold medal".</p>

<p>"If I win, mothers and fathers will be able to see how far their children can go," she said. "I want to inspire girls and children in Algeria."</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/ta1rp0s_imane-khelif_625x300_10_August_24.jpeg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Ms Khelif's international career took off with her participation at the Covid-delayed Tokyo Olympics in 2021, where she came fifth in her weight class.</p>

<p>In 2023 she made it to the semi-finals of the world championships in New Delhi.</p>

<p>But then she was disqualified following gender eligibility testing by the International Boxing Association, which is not recognised by the International Olympic Committee (IOC) and is not running the sport in Paris.</p>

<p>She initially appealed but then withdrew her complaint, according to the IBA.</p>

<p>There is no suggestion that Ms Khelif identifies as anything other than a woman.</p>

<p>Her father showed identity documents and her birth certificate to AFP and, having been sceptical about her boxing career when she was young, hailed her as "a heroine".</p>

<p>"My child is a girl," Omar Khelif said. "She was raised as a girl. She is a strong girl -- I raised her to work and be brave."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/2mvojk88_imane-khelif-afp_625x300_10_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[There is no suggestion that Ms Khelif identifies as anything other than a woman.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/paraguay-swimmer-luana-alonso-who-was-kicked-out-of-olympic-village-wanted-to-represent-us-6304724]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Swimmer Who Was Kicked Out Of Olympic Village Wanted To Represent US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/paraguay-swimmer-luana-alonso-who-was-kicked-out-of-olympic-village-wanted-to-represent-us-6304724]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 10 Aug 2024 06:45:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Paraguayan swimmer Luana Alonso who made headlines for her controversial departure from the Olympic Village wants to compete for the United States instead of her home country, a report said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Paraguayan swimmer Luana Alonso who made headlines for her controversial departure from the Olympic Village wants to compete for the United States instead of her home country, a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/08/07/sports/2024-paris-olympics-paraguay-swimmer-luana-alonso-who-was-kicked-out-of-olympic-village-over-inappropriate-behavior-wanted-to-compete-for-team-usa/">report</a> said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to Paraguayan outlet<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.hoy.com.py/espectaculos/farandula/2024/07/31/luana-alonso-yo-le-quiero-representar-mas-a-estados-unidos"> HOY</a>, 20-year-old Alonso had expressed her preference for representing the United States, citing her strong ties to the country where she attended college. "I want to represent the United States more," Alonso allegedly stated during a live video on social media before the Olympics.</p>

<p>Alonso swam for Southern Methodist University (SMU) after spending the 2021-2022 season at Virginia Tech University. The swimmer said that the more competitive environment in the US was a better fit for her aspirations.</p>

<p>Her Olympic journey was marred by controversy even before she entered the pool. Alonso qualified for the women's 100-metre butterfly event through the universality system. Despite this achievement, her relationship with the Paraguayan Olympic Committee (COP) and her teammates seemed fraught with tension.</p>

<p>During her social media video, Alonso did not hold back in criticising the COP's treatment of its athletes. She accused the committee of undermining her achievements and relying heavily on sponsors rather than providing adequate support. "They threaten me that they are going to publish a statement, that I am going to leave because of universality," she said, adding that the COP sought to humiliate her by downplaying her qualification. Alonso also voiced her frustration with the lack of support and trust from her Paraguayan teammates, claiming that it was "not a pleasure" to represent her country.</p>

<p>COP President Camilo Perez responded sharply to Alonso's comments, pointing out that her performance would not meet the rigorous standards required to qualify for the Olympics as part of Team USA. "There is no universality there. She came here as a Paraguayan. She has to train a lot more to represent the USA; her times have to be much better," Perez said.</p>

<p>The controversy escalated further when Alonso was reportedly expelled from the Olympic Village due to "inappropriate" conduct that allegedly included a trip to Disneyland and wearing revealing outfits that were deemed distracting to other athletes. In a statement, Alonso denied the claims about her removal, pushing back against the reports and maintaining that she had not been a disruption.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/82tci84g_luana-alonso_625x300_08_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Alonso was reportedly expelled from the Olympic Village.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sheikh-hasinas-son-strongly-opposes-interim-government-in-bangladesh-6304359]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Sheikh Hasina's Son Strongly Opposes Interim Government In Bangladesh]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sheikh-hasinas-son-strongly-opposes-interim-government-in-bangladesh-6304359]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 10 Aug 2024 04:34:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Sajeeb Wazed Joy, son of former Bangladesh Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina, has claimed that the recent protests in Bangladesh were likely instigated by a foreign intelligence agency, specifically suspecting the involvement of the ISI.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sajeeb Wazed Joy, son of former Bangladesh Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina, has claimed that the recent protests in Bangladesh were likely instigated by a foreign intelligence agency, specifically suspecting the involvement of the ISI.</p>

<p>Speaking to ANI, he said that the unrest was driven by external forces rather than domestic issues and criticized how his mother's statement was distorted to fuel the protests.</p>

<p>"I now firmly believe this was instigated by a small group and most likely by a foreign intelligence agency. I strongly suspect the ISI.&nbsp;</p>

<p>There was no reason for the protests to continue because the quotas were not mandated by our government and were restored by a court ruling. Our government had lifted the quotas in 2018 or so when the first quota protests happened," he said.</p>

<p>He alleged that the protesters twisted Sheikh Hasina's statement on Razakars, which led to the escalation of the protests.</p>

<p>"When the protests started, they were peaceful. Our police provided security for the protesters. Then they took my mother's statement where she said that we don't want Razakars' families getting jobs.&nbsp;</p>

<p>They took that statement and twisted it, saying that my mother said the protesters were Razakars. My mother never said that. But this was spread online. And then, in the middle of the night, some group--nobody knows who did that--marched through Dhaka University chanting, 'We are Razakars'. And that is what happened. The other students, especially Bangladesh Chhatra League, our student supporters, and the pro-liberation students, got angry.&nbsp;</p>

<p>They attacked the protesters, and that is how the violence started," he said while adding, "The police tried to stop the violence, and in doing so, some police members used live ammunition, which they were not authorized to do. Our government never ordered anyone to attack.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Our government never ordered the police to use live ammunition. We immediately called our student leaders and said, 'Stop the fighting.' The fighting stopped. We immediately suspended the police officers who used excessive force."</p>

<p>He also questioned the presence of weapons among the protestors and emphasized that his mother, Sheikh Hasina, chose to leave her residence to prevent a potential massacre, prioritizing the lives of students.</p>

<p>"They increased the demand for the resignation of the government. And once they did that, they started attacking the police with firearms. Where did these weapons come into Bangladesh from? How did the students get weapons? So these weren't students. This was a mob. This was militancy that was instigated to try to overthrow a democratically elected government," he said.</p>

<p>"My mother left (even when) her security forces were heavily armed and prepared to guard the prime minister's residence. But if the protesters had marched in hundreds, they would have been killed. It would have been a massacre. And my mother did not want a massacre. That is why she left," he explained.</p>

<p>He added, "She left to protect the lives of the students."</p>

<p>Wazed said that the current interim government in Bangladesh, led by Nobel laureate Muhammad Yunus, was 'unconstitutional'.</p>

<p>"We want a quick restoration of democracy. Right now, this government is completely unconstitutional. There is no provision for a selected government slected by a small minority, because we have 170 million people in Bangladesh, and 20,000-50,000 protesters are a tiny fraction of the minority. No one has voted for this government. So whether they can restore law and order remains to be seen.&nbsp;</p>

<p>They've only been in power for less than 24 hours," he said.</p>

<p>"It's one thing to take over power in a coup; it's another thing to govern. They don't have the people's bandwidth. Who is going to listen to them? Right now, there are two main political parties in Bangladesh. No matter what you do, if you want democracy with 170 million people... we have 100 million followers. They have not voted for or supported this government. So without their support, how are you going to govern? I wait to see who is going to listen to this government. It's one thing to be placed in power. It's another thing to have people following you," he said.</p>

<p>He claimed that within 12 hours of coming to power, the interim government had begun to make mistakes.</p>

<p>"In 12 hours, they're already starting to make mistakes. They've already announced that elections are not a priority. The priority is to have trials of the previous government to reform the country. But no one gave them the mandate to reform the country. They don't have the mandate of the people of Bangladesh. So who is going to support them? Who is going to follow their orders?" Wazed said.</p>

<p>He said that the Awami League has always protected minorities, and pointed out that the last 15 years were the safest for minorities in Bangladesh. He added that the interim government has failed to keep minorities safe as they are trying to flee the country.</p>

<p>"In the history of Bangladesh, only one government kept the minorities of Bangladesh safe from all militancy and violence. That was the Awami League. The last 15 years were the safest period in Bangladesh's history for minorities and for Bangladesh itself. And it was also the period of the highest economic development growth. Even those who are criticizing Sheikh Hasina cannot deny it. This non-elected government does not have the support of almost the entire population of Bangladesh. Are they going to be able to keep minorities safe? The minorities are trying to flee the country. I am worried about them. I want to do what I can to keep the minority safe, restore law and order to Bangladesh, and bring back democracy. That is our goal," he added.</p>

<p>Bangladesh is facing a fluid political situation with Sheikh Hasina, tendering her resignation from her post on August 5 in the wake of mounting protests. The protests erupted in early July due to demands for reforming the quota system that reserves civil service jobs for specific groups, including descendants of 1971 war veterans.</p>

<p>The unrest intensified after students opposed a new policy allocating government jobs to descendants of freedom fighters, leading to violence, including attacks on state television headquarters and police booths in Dhaka.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/6fgmohkg_yunus_625x300_08_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Muhammad Yunus has sworn in as the head of Bangladeshs interim government on Thursday.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-student-leader-who-led-protest-wants-sheikh-hasina-to-face-trial-6303974]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh Student Leader Who Led Protest Wants Sheikh Hasina To Face Trial]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-student-leader-who-led-protest-wants-sheikh-hasina-to-face-trial-6303974]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 10 Aug 2024 02:18:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Bangladeshi student leader who was instrumental in overthrowing Sheikh Hasina and is now part of an interim government said she must face trial when she returns home as planned for the killings during her term.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Bangladeshi student leader who was instrumental in overthrowing Sheikh Hasina and is now part of an interim government said she must face trial when she returns home as planned for the killings during her term, including during recent protests, which led her to resign and flee on Monday.</p>

<p>About 300 people, many of them university and college students, were killed in the demonstrations that began in July with students demonstrating against quotas in government jobs before spiralling into violent protests to oust Hasina, who had ruled Bangladesh for 20 of the last 30 years.</p>

<p>Hasina's son Sajeeb Wazed Joy has said she will return to Bangladesh from India, where she is sheltering, once elections are announced in her home country, which the main opposition has demanded should be held in three months.</p>

<p>"I am curious why she fled the country," student leader Nahid Islam, who is effectively a minister in the caretaker government, told Reuters late on Friday in his first interview since joining the government on Thursday as an adviser.</p>

<p>"We will seek justice for all the killings that happened under her, that has been one of the main demands of our revolution. Even if she does not come back, we will work towards that."</p>

<p>"We want to arrest her - whether that will work through the regular judicial system or a special tribunal on that or not, we are discussing how to proceed on the matter," said Islam, 26, who now heads the postal, telecommunication and information technology ministries.</p>

<p>Joy, who is based in the United States, did not respond to a request seeking comment. Hasina, who is under the protection of the Indian government, could not be contacted.</p>

<p>Another student leader, Abu Baker Mojumder, separately told Reuters they want Hasina to return and face trial.</p>

<p>Islam said one of the caretaker government's main priorities was to hold a free and fair election, after the last election was boycotted by the opposition, and also investigate suspected corruption in the previous government.</p>

<p>Islam said Bangladesh would need electoral and constitutional reforms before any election, so it was not clear when the next vote would be held. He declined to give a specific timeline.</p>

<p>"My ambition on what I next become depends on the people of Bangladesh," he said, when asked whether one day he would like to be prime minister.</p>

<p>He said India had fostered a relationship with Hasina's Awami League party, but not the people of Bangladesh as a whole.</p>

<p>"We want friendly ties with India," he said. "India also needs to look at its foreign policy, else it will become a problem for the whole of South Asia."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/p06203bg_sheikh-hasina_625x300_05_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sheikh Hasina's son said that she will return to Bangladesh from India.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-announces-125-million-in-new-military-aid-for-ukraine-6303718]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Announces $125 Million In New Military Aid For Ukraine]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-announces-125-million-in-new-military-aid-for-ukraine-6303718]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 10 Aug 2024 01:00:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United States on Friday announced $125 million in new military aid for Kyiv, as Ukrainian forces push ahead with a surprise offensive inside Russian territory.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United States on Friday announced $125 million in new military aid for Kyiv, as Ukrainian forces push ahead with a surprise offensive inside Russian territory.</p>

<p>The aid package underscores "our unwavering commitment to (Ukraine) as they continue to battle back against Russian aggression," National Security Council spokesman John Kirby told journalists.</p>

<p>US Secretary of State Antony Blinken said the aid would be drawn from American stockpiles and "includes air defense interceptors, munitions for rocket systems and artillery, multi-mission radars, and anti-tank weapons."</p>

<p>The equipment "will help Ukraine protect its troops, its people and its cities from Russian attacks and reinforce its capabilities across the front lines," he said in a statement.</p>

<p>The United States has been a key military backer of Ukraine, committing more than $55 billion in weapons, ammunition and other security aid since Russia launched its full-scale invasion in February 2022.</p>

<p>The latest aid announcement comes as Kyiv's troops press an attack into Russia's western Kursk region -- a surprise offensive that appears to be the most significant attack on Russian soil since Moscow launched the invasion of its neighbor.</p>

<p>Kirby said that the United States is "in touch with our Ukrainian counterparts, and we are working to gain a better understanding of what they're doing, what their goals are, what their strategy is."<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/j1qeblo8_russia-ukraine-war_625x300_20_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The United States on Friday announced $125 million in new military aid for Kyiv.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/muhammad-yunus-to-oversee-27-ministries-in-bangladeshs-interim-government-6303509]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Muhammad Yunus To Oversee 27 Ministries In Bangladesh's Interim Government]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/muhammad-yunus-to-oversee-27-ministries-in-bangladeshs-interim-government-6303509]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:09:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Bangladesh's interim leader Muhammad Yunus on Friday announced the portfolios of the newly-appointed council of advisors and took charge of 27 ministries, including defence.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bangladesh's interim leader Muhammad Yunus on Friday announced the portfolios of the newly-appointed council of advisors and took charge of 27 ministries, including defence, and named career diplomat Mohammad Touhid Hossain to head the foreign ministry.</p>

<p>Nobel laureate Yunus, 84, on Thursday took oath as the head of an interim government, replacing Sheikh Hasina who abruptly resigned and fled to India leaving the country in turmoil following deadly protests against her government over a controversial quota system in jobs.</p>

<p>He was sworn in as the chief advisor - a position equivalent to prime minister.</p>

<p>Other advisors were selected in consultation with student leaders, the military, and civil society representatives.</p>

<p>According to an official announcement, Yunus will oversee a broad array of ministries keeping to himself 27 portfolios including the defence, public administration, education, energy, food, water resources and information ministries.</p>

<p>Former foreign secretary Hossain has been entrusted with the charge of the foreign ministry while retired Army brigadier general M Sakhawat Hossain was tasked to oversee the home ministry.</p>

<p>Hossain was the Deputy High Commissioner of Bangladesh in Kolkata from 2001 to 2005 and served as Foreign Secretary of Bangladesh from 2006 to 2009.</p>

<p>Former Bangladesh Bank governor Salahuddin Ahmed will be in charge of the finance and planning ministries while former attorney general A F Hassan Arif will oversee the local government ministry.</p>

<p>Two coordinators of Students Against Discrimination inducted in the interim cabinet M Nahid Islam and Asif Mahmud were given the charge of telecommunications and information technology and youth and sports ministries respectively.</p>

<p>The group waged first the street movement to reform the quota system for government jobs last month which later turned into a public upsurge and ousted Hasina's 15-year regime and installed the interim government, visibly backed by the military.</p>

<p>Three members of the advisers' council, mostly civil society figures, could not take the oath on Thursday night at the Bangabhaban presidential palace as they were outside of the capital and officials presumed that Yunus might distribute some of the 27 portfolios to them.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/bqlfmhv8_muhammad-yunus_625x300_09_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[He was sworn in as the chief advisor - a position equivalent to prime minister.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-embassy-in-japan-issues-advisory-after-experts-warn-of-megaquake-6303365]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Indian Embassy In Japan Issues Advisory After Experts Warn Of 'Megaquake']]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-embassy-in-japan-issues-advisory-after-experts-warn-of-megaquake-6303365]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 23:33:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Indian Embassy in Japan issued a mega-quake advisory for Indian citizens residing in Japan on Friday, urging them to prepare for natural disasters after a strong magnitude 7.1 earthquake occurred on Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Indian Embassy in Japan issued a mega-quake advisory for Indian citizens residing in Japan on Friday, urging them to prepare for natural disasters after a strong magnitude 7.1 earthquake occurred on Thursday.</p>

<p>Experts have said a 'megaquake' may strike Japan in the coming days. An earthquake of over 8-magnitude is called a megaquake.</p>

<p>Further, the embassy asks citizens to follow guidelines set by Japanese authorities and monitor the embassy's website and social media handles for updates.</p>

<p>"The Govt of Japan has promulgated an advisory for preparedness for natural disasters. All Indian citizens in Japan are advised to follow the advisories promulgated by the Japanese authorities and monitor the website and social media handles of the Embassy of India in Tokyo," the Indian Embassy in Japan said in a post on X.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">The Govt of Japan has promulgated an advisory for preparedness for Natural Disasters. All Indian citizens in Japan are advised to follow the advisories promulgated by the Japanese authorities and monitor the website and social media handles of Embassy of India Tokyo. <a href="https://t.co/Ef5lD08Yjb">pic.twitter.com/Ef5lD08Yjb</a></p>
 India in Japan (@IndianEmbTokyo) <a href="https://twitter.com/IndianEmbTokyo/status/1821895976359227824?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 9, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The embassy also shared the advisory document, which states that the Japan Meteorological Agency has issued an emergency bulletin on the Nankai Trough earthquake (warning a massive earthquake).&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Government of Japan held a disaster response meeting, established a state of alert and has urged the citizens to reaffirm their earthquake preparedness on a daily basis.</p>

<p>Further, the Tokyo Metropolitan Government (TMG) issued an advisory and set up a Disaster Management Headquarters (DMHQ) on August 8 to enhance preparedness in connection with the Mega-quake advisory (Nankai Trough Earthquake Extra Information) issued by the Japan Meteorological Agency.</p>

<p>The advisory by TMG estimates that if the mega quake occurs, the damage in Tokyo will be of seismic intensity 6 or lower and there may be a tsunami that could effect the island areas.</p>

<p>According to the advisory, all Indian citizens in Japan are advised to adhere to warnings and instructions promulgated by the Government of Japan and local governments from time to time.</p>

<p>The Government of Japan has further reassured that there is no need to panic and that the advisory is only meant to enhance preparedness.</p>

<p>Two powerful earthquakes struck off Japan's southern coast on Thursday. The first, a 6.9-magnitude quake, was followed by another 7.1-magnitude tremor, according to the United States Geological Survey (USGS).</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/78f74ep_earthquake_625x300_08_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/plane-with-62-on-board-crashes-in-brazil-6303315]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[All 62 On Board Killed In Brazil Plane Crash]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/plane-with-62-on-board-crashes-in-brazil-6303315]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 23:24:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A regional turboprop plane carrying 62 people crashed near Sao Paulo in Brazil on Friday, killing all on board, local officials near the crash site said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A regional turboprop plane carrying 62 people crashed near Sao Paulo in Brazil on Friday, killing all on board, local officials near the crash site said.</p>

<p>Video shared on social media showed what appeared to be the ATR-made plane spinning out of control as it plunged down behind a cluster of trees near houses, followed by a large plume of black smoke.</p>

<p>City officials at Valinhos, near Vinhedo, said there were no survivors and only one home in the local condominium complex had been damaged while none of the residents were hurt.</p>

<p>"I have to be the bearer of really bad news," said President Luiz Inacio Lula da Silva speaking at an event shortly after the crash. He asked for a minute of silence for the victims of the crash.</p>

<p>Airline Voepass said the plane, which had taken off from Cascavel, in the state of Parana, bound for Sao Paulo's main international airport, crashed in the town of Vinhedo, about 80 km (50 miles) northwest of Sao Paulo.</p>

<p>The unlisted airline said it could not provide further information on what caused the plane, which had a PS-VPB registration, to crash.</p>

<p>Just minutes after the apparent accident, Sao Paulo's state fire brigade said it was rushing seven crews to the scene of the crash.</p>

<p>The aircraft was listed by flight tracker FlightRadar24 as an ATR 72-500 turboprop. ATR is jointly owned by Airbus and Italian aerospace group Leonardo.</p>

<p>ATR did not immediately respond to a request for comment.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/0b7epb28_brazil-plane-crash_625x300_09_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iranian-nobel-prize-winner-hurt-in-prison-clashes-with-guards-family-6302918]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iranian Nobel Prize Winner Hurt In Prison Clashes With Guards: Family]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iranian-nobel-prize-winner-hurt-in-prison-clashes-with-guards-family-6302918]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 22:23:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Jailed Iranian Nobel Peace Prize winner Narges Mohammadi and other female inmates were hurt in clashes that erupted at Tehran's Evin prison following a spate of executions, her family said, raising new concerns for her health.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Jailed Iranian Nobel Peace Prize winner Narges Mohammadi and other female inmates were hurt in clashes that erupted at Tehran's Evin prison following a spate of executions, her family said, raising new concerns for her health.</p>

<p>Iranian authorities acknowledged a confrontation had taken place on Tuesday but blamed Mohammadi for a "provocation" and denied any of the prisoners had been beaten.</p>

<p>Human rights activist Mohammadi, 52, who won the 2023 prize for her campaigning including against the death penalty, has been jailed since November 2021 and has spent much of the past decade in and out of prison.</p>

<p>The Paris-based family of Mohammadi emphasised it had had no direct contact with her since her right to make phone calls was revoked in November.</p>

<p>But it said it had learnt from several other families of detainees held in Evin that clashes erupted on Tuesday as the female prisoners launched a protest in the yard against the executions.</p>

<p>According to rights groups, around 30 convicts were hanged this week, including Gholamreza (Reza) Rasaei, who the Iranian judiciary said was executed on Tuesday in connection with 2022 protests.</p>

<p>"The protest by prisoners against the execution of Reza Rasaei led to a violent crackdown by prison guards and security agents," Mohammadi's family said in a statement late Thursday, citing the reports.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Several women who stood in front of the security forces were severely beaten. The confrontation escalated, resulting in physical injuries for some prisoners."</p>

<p><strong>- 'Deeply worried' -</strong></p>

<p>The family said that after being punched in the chest, Mohammadi suffered a respiratory attack and intense chest pain, causing her to collapse and faint on the ground in the prison yard.</p>

<p>She was bruised and treated in the prison infirmary but not transferred to a hospital outside, it said.</p>

<p>"We are deeply worried about her health and well-being under these circumstances," the family said.</p>

<p>Relatives and supporters had earlier this month raised concern about Mohammadi's condition, saying they had been informed of the results of medical tests carried out in July "which showed a worrying deterioration of her health".</p>

<p>In the past eight months, Mohammadi has been suffering from acute back and knee pain, including a slipped disc. In 2021, a stent was placed on one of her main coronary arteries due to a blockage.</p>

<p>Iran's prison authority denied that prisoners were beaten and blamed the confrontation on Mohammadi and other inmates who it said had broken the lock of an outer door.</p>

<p>Two prisoners "had heart palpitations due to the stress," but medical examinations determined that their general condition "is favourable," it said in a statement, according to the Tasnim news agency.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>- 'Alarmingly high' -</strong></p>

<p>Reports have suggested increasing tensions in the women's wing of Evin prison after two Kurdish female activists, Sharifeh Mohammadi and Pakhshan Azizi, were sentenced to death on charges of membership of an outlawed group.</p>

<p>Rights groups say that Iran has intensified the use of capital punishment after a brief lull in the run-up to the June-July election that brought reformist President Masoud Pezeshkian to power.</p>

<p>Authorities executed 29 people at two prisons in the Tehran satellite city of Karaj on Wednesday alone, according to Norway-based Iran Human Rights.</p>

<p>Volker Turk, the UN high commissioner for human rights, "is extremely concerned" by the reports, spokeswoman Elizabeth Throssell told journalists in Geneva. "This represents an alarmingly high number of executions in such a short period of time."</p>

<p>Mohammadi has kept campaigning even behind bars and strongly supported the protests that erupted across Iran following the September 2022 death in custody of Mahsa Amini. The 22-year-old Iranian Kurd had been arrested for an alleged breach of Iran's strict dress rules for women.</p>

<p>She received a new one-year prison term in June for "propaganda against the state", adding to sentences that already amounted to 12 years and three months of imprisonment, 154 lashes, two years of exile and various social and political restrictions.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-10/13c0nn4c_jailed-iranian-womens-rights-activist-narges-mohammadi_625x300_31_October_23.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Paris-based family of Narges Mohammadi emphasised it had had no direct contact with her.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uncontacted-tribe-in-peru-attacks-encroaching-loggers-with-bows-and-arrows-6302826]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Uncontacted Tribe In Peru Attacks Encroaching Loggers With Bows And Arrows]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uncontacted-tribe-in-peru-attacks-encroaching-loggers-with-bows-and-arrows-6302826]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 22:08:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Peru's Mashco Piro tribe recently used bows and arrows to attack loggers suspected of encroaching on their territory in the Amazon.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Peru's Mashco Piro tribe recently used bows and arrows to attack loggers suspected of encroaching on their territory in the Amazon. According to <em>CBS News</em>, the regional Indigenous organisation FENAMAD said on Monday that it believes illegal logging was taking place on Mashco Piro territory and that one logger was injured in the July 27 attack.</p>

<p>This comes weeks after photos emerged of the uncontacted tribe searching for food on a beach in the Peruvian Amazon. Experts say the pictures were evidence that logging concessions are "dangerously close" to its territory. Survival International, an advocacy group for Indigenous peoples which closely follows the Mashco Piro's issues, said that photos and videos showed about 53 male Mashco Piro on the beach. The group estimated as many as 100 to 150 tribal members would have been in the area with women and children nearby.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"It is presumably illegal because the area where the incident occurred is a forestry concession that belonged to Wood Tropical Forest until November 2022, and we are not aware of a concession that has requested or granted enabling rights in the same area," said a FENAMAD representative, speaking anonymously out of personal security concerns, per <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/uncontacted-tribe-mashco-piro-attacks-loggers-arrows-peru-amazon/"><em>CBS News</em></a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The organisation further stated that a lack of protection measures by the Peruvian government and the increased activity of companies and illegal operators on the Mascho Piro territory could produce "devastating consequences", such as the transmission of diseases and increased violence.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Notably, in 2022, two loggers were shot with arrows while fishing in the area. There have also been several other previous reports of conflicts, the outlet reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/skydiving-student-instructor-die-in-us-after-hitting-dust-devil-during-routine-jump-6301454">Skydiving Student, Instructor Die In US After Hitting "Dust Devil" During Routine Jump</a></strong></p>

<p>According to FENAMAD, increased logging activity in the area is likely pushing the tribe out of their traditional lands. They believe that the Mashco Piro may be venturing closer to settlements in search of food and a safer refuge.</p>

<p>Separately, Survival International said it is pressuring the Peruvian government to move deeper into these areas of the Amazon to help control the situation. "This is a permanent emergency. For the last month we have been seeing the Mascho Piro every two weeks at different points, and in all of them they are surrounded by loggers," Teresa Mayo, a researcher at Survival International, told CBS News.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"It's truly a matter of life and death. And only the government can and has the duty to stop it," Ms Mayo said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/a286f9g_mashco-piro_625x300_18_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The attack reportedly took place in July this year.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladeshi-students-oversee-law-and-order-as-police-unions-strike-6302533]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bangladeshi Students Oversee Traffic Management As Cops Go On Strike]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladeshi-students-oversee-law-and-order-as-police-unions-strike-6302533]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 21:22:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Bangladeshi students battled police for control of the streets and won, but if their country is to embark on a new journey, someone has to clear the road ahead.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bangladeshi students battled police for control of the streets and won, but if their country is to embark on a new journey, someone has to clear the road ahead.</p>

<p>Gridlock is a fact of life in the capital Dhaka, a megacity of 20 million which relies on a corps of police wardens to clear long snarls of cars and pedal rickshaws through intersections.</p>

<p>With officers on strike after the resignation of ex-premier Sheikh Hasina, the students who forced her ouster have stepped up to do the job themselves.</p>

<p>"Our country can't remain in a standstill," Nasrin Akter Koly, 21, told AFP.</p>

<p>"We clashed with the police, that's why the police are not on duty," she added. "So instead of the police, our people must do the work."</p>

<p>Traffic control is a humdrum job at the best of times and many of Dhaka's usual wardens are known for a casual indifference to aggressive drivers zooming by out of turn.</p>

<p>But Koly and her classmates have brought a new enthusiasm to the vocation as they wave through cars at one of the downtown business district's busiest crossroads.</p>

<p>Drivers are in turn treating the volunteers with respect.</p>

<p>Nearly all are stopping on command and heeding polite but firm directions to fasten their seatbelts -- the kind of minor traffic infraction that would have previously been ignored.</p>

<p>"After a revolution, every country faces some difficulties," said Nahid Kalam Nabil, 22, while directing traffic alongside Koly.</p>

<p>"The students are handling the situation now, and they will keep the country safe," he added.</p>

<p><strong>'Teaching the people'</strong></p>

<p>More than 450 people were killed during weeks of clashes between protesters and security forces before Hasina quit and fled to India on Monday.</p>

<p>Protests had been largely peaceful until police attempted to violently disperse them, setting in motion the chain of events that led to the end of Hasina's iron-fisted 15-year tenure.</p>

<p>Dozens of police officers were killed in the unrest, according to police and hospital figures given to AFP.</p>

<p>After her departure, vandalism and arson attacks hit roughly 450 of the country's 600 police stations, according to the force.</p>

<p>Police unions declared a national strike on Tuesday "until the security" of officers was assured, and a new police chief apologised for the conduct of officers under his sacked predecessor.</p>

<p>Unrest has since subsided, thanks in part to students volunteering for neighbourhood watch patrols and guarding houses of worship for minority religions, which were subjected to isolated looting attacks.</p>

<p>"They are safeguarding the houses at night, they are safeguarding the mosques, temples and churches," Nabil said.</p>

<p>"They are teaching the people law and order. They are designing the country in a new way."</p>

<p>Many police officers began returning to work Friday with soldiers -- held in high esteem for not intervening on Hasina's side during the unrest -- standing guard.</p>

<p>Farida Akhter, a member of the interim government tasked with steering democratic reforms, told AFP that restoring law and order was the "first priority" of the new dispensation.</p>

<p>The sudden collapse of Hasina's administration left a gaping vacuum in political administration, with many civil servants staying home waiting for the dust to settle.</p>

<p>The city government in Dhaka has also laid low, prompting other student volunteers to take on its duties.</p>

<p>"With this students' protest, we have made a fascist regime fall," 20-year-old Samanjar Chowdhury Mrittika told AFP while wielding a broom to sweep up garbage from a downtown sidewalk.</p>

<p>"The country is not in a good condition," she added. "Someone must take responsibility."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/4noeato_bangladesh-student-cop_625x300_09_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Police unions declared a national strike on Tuesday "until the security" of officers was assured.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/palestinians-evacuate-khan-yunis-to-escape-fresh-israeli-military-operation-6302333]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Palestinians Evacuate Khan Yunis In Gaza To Escape Fresh Israeli Operation]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/palestinians-evacuate-khan-yunis-to-escape-fresh-israeli-military-operation-6302333]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 20:52:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Crowds fleeing Khan Yunis after an Israeli evacuation order gave way to empty streets on Friday as Palestinian residents tried to escape a new Israeli military operation in Gaza's main southern area.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Crowds fleeing Khan Yunis after an Israeli evacuation order gave way to empty streets on Friday as Palestinian residents tried to escape a new Israeli military operation in Gaza's main southern area.</p>

<p>"They threw leaflets at us, ordering us to evacuate", Reem Abu Hayya told AFP, referring to the flyers that Israeli forces drop from planes to order the evacuation of areas ahead of a military operation.</p>

<p>The Khan Yunis area had already seen evacuation orders in late July, and heavy fighting that devastated the area earlier this year.</p>

<p>"We don't know where we're going, and we have sick and disabled people with us. Where can we go?" Abu Hayya asked AFP as she stood on the street in front of a building reduced to a pile of rebar and broken concrete.</p>

<p>In a besieged territory that has been consistently bombed over the past 10 months and where supplies enter with great difficulty, people carried all they could as they fled on Thursday.</p>

<p>AFP journalists saw one young man carrying planks of wood loosely tied in bundles, to be used as shelter structure or fuel in the near future.</p>

<p>With petrol scarce, only the most fortunate drove, often with mattresses piled high on the car roof. The vast majority walked. They carried their belongings in plastic and garbage bags, on donkey-pulled carts, bikes, strollers or wheelchairs.</p>

<p>By dusk, streets of Khan Yunis stood completely deserted and eerily quiet, AFP journalists reported. Only the ruins of buildings damaged in earlier strikes still stood.</p>

<p>The flyers dropped Thursday ordered residents to leave eastern towns of Khan Yunis governorate including Al-Salqa, Al-Qarara, Bani Suheila, and neighbourhoods in the city of Khan Yunis.</p>

<p>"Hamas and terrorist organisations continue to launch rockets from your areas", read the flyers which echoed past orders and warned that the Israeli army "will act forcefully against these elements".</p>

<p>Late last month Philippe Lazzarini, who heads the United Nations agency for Palestinian refugees, UNRWA, said on social media site X that only "14 percent of areas in Gaza" were not subject to evacuation orders.</p>

<p>On Friday, the military said it launched a new operation in Khan Yunis following "intelligence indicating the presence of terrorists and terror infrastructure" there.</p>

<p>"The troops are engaging in combat both above and below-ground to eliminate terrorists in the area while locating and dismantling weaponry and terrorist infrastructure," the military said in a statement.</p>

<p><strong>'We are exhausted'</strong></p>

<p>The military has often returned in Gaza to areas where it had previously completed major operations against Palestinian militants, only to find them resurfacing or to act on intelligence about the location of hostages.</p>

<p>"Enough! For both, the Jews and Hamas! Both of them should look at the people of Gaza, have mercy on us for God's sake," Ahmed al-Najjar, angry at the war and the prospect of yet another displacement, told AFP.</p>

<p>War in Gaza began when Hamas Palestinian militants on October 7 attacked southern Israel, resulting in the deaths of 1,198 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on official Israeli figures.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory military offensive has killed at least 39,699 people in Gaza, according to the health ministry of the Hamas-run territory, which does not provide details of civilian and militant deaths.</p>

<p>Mohammad al-Farra, from Sheikh Nasser in the east of Khan Yunis, also expressed frustration at the several displacements his family has lived through.</p>

<p>"We were the first to return to our home... as soon as the military operation in our area ended, to escape the heat, the displacement, and the hardship", the 46-year-old told AFP.</p>

<p>"Then the occupation returned to drive us out again, making us suffer the tragedy multiple times over", he said, referring to Israel.</p>

<p>"We are exhausted. The war must end immediately so that we can feel human again, even just a little."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/tvebgnig_gaza_625x300_30_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Khan Yunis area had already seen evacuation orders in late July. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>