<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Dec 2024 18:50:08 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-korea-presidential-impeachment-motion-fails-7194755]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Motion To Impeach South Korean President Who Imposed Martial Law Fails]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-korea-presidential-impeachment-motion-fails-7194755]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Dec 2024 18:23:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An opposition-led motion to impeach South Korean President Yoon Suk Yeol over his brief declaration of martial law failed Saturday as it did not meet the required quorum after his party boycotted the vote.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An opposition-led motion to impeach South Korean President Yoon Suk Yeol over his brief declaration of martial law failed Saturday as it did not meet the required quorum after his party boycotted the vote.</p>

<p>"With a total of 195 votes, the number of members who voted did not reach the required two-thirds majority of the total members. Therefore, I declare that the vote on this matter is not valid," National Assembly speaker Woo Won-shik said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/thp2f5po_south-korea-impeachment_625x300_07_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Lawmakers in the voting chamber during the plenary session for the impeachment vote.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-visa-rules-relaxed-for-pakistanis-sparks-security-concerns-for-india-7194624]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh Visa Rules Eased For Pakistanis, Sparks Concerns For India]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-visa-rules-relaxed-for-pakistanis-sparks-security-concerns-for-india-7194624]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Dec 2024 18:04:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Zia's party has historically kept closer ties with Pakistan unlike Sheikh Hasina's Awami League, who had kept a more pro-India stance. There is growing uncertainty about Bangladesh's new diplomatic and political outlook as well.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p>

<p>Amid shifting Bangladesh-Pakistan ties, and growing proximity between the two countries, the interim government has removed the requirement for Pakistani citizens to get a security clearance before applying for a visa.</p>

<p>The clearance requirement was introduced in 2019 amid tensions and broader security measures.</p>

<p>However, this new policy removed such constraints when it was introduced through an announcement by the Security Services Division (SSD) of the Ministry of Home Affairs, on December 2.</p>

<p>This shift came a day before Pakistan's high commissioner to Bangladesh, Syed Ahmed Maroof, met with Khaleda Zia, the leader of the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) in Dhaka on December 3.</p>

<p>This drew attention especially after the Bangladesh government allowed cargo vessel movement directly from Karachi to Chittagong in November.</p>

<p>Zia's party has historically kept closer ties with Pakistan unlike Sheikh Hasina's Awami League, who had kept a more pro-India stance. There is growing uncertainty about Bangladesh's new diplomatic and political outlook as well.</p>

<p>"This signals not a shift but a balancing act by Bangladesh. Bangladeshi officials are persistently stating that they want a friendly relationship with India though India is not reciprocating that. They not only gave refuge to Hasina but politicians are using inflammatory remarks based on half-truth and disinformation on Bangladesh", Mubashar Hasan, an expert on Bangladesh politics and executive director of the Sydney Policy and Analysis Centre in Australia, told ThePrint.</p>

<p>"So it seems by normalising relationships with India's arch-rival Pakistan, Bangladesh's administration is signalling that it is not going to see South Asian politics through [an] Indian prism anymore. Whether in the long run, Bangladesh can continue to afford that remains to be seen as the West-specifically the US-sees South Asia through [an] Indian prism and the US is a vital ally for Bangladesh. Having said that, India, too, must realise its neighbourhood policy is in shambles."</p>

<p>The security clearance poses serious questions for India's security, especially in the North East as there are rising concerns that the evolving political landscape in Bangladesh could facilitate extremist groups in the region.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/j4vjvr9g_muhammad-yunus-afp_625x300_19_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[There is growing uncertainty about Bangladesh's new diplomatic and political outlook as well]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/car-drove-away-at-high-speed-explosion-hits-block-of-flats-at-the-hague-7194439]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Car Drove Away At High Speed": Explosion Hits Block Of Flats At The Hague]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/car-drove-away-at-high-speed-explosion-hits-block-of-flats-at-the-hague-7194439]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Dec 2024 17:35:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A three-storey apartment block in The Hague partially collapsed Saturday after a fire and explosion, firefighters said, with first responders searching for people under the rubble.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A three-storey apartment block in The Hague partially collapsed Saturday after a fire and explosion, firefighters said, with first responders searching for people under the rubble.</p>

<p>Four people have already been pulled out of the debris and taken to hospital, as elite teams with sniffer dogs deployed to rescue others trapped by the disaster.</p>

<p>It was not known how many people were still missing nor what caused the explosion in the block of flats not far from the centre of the city.</p>

<p>"We still don't know how many people might be under the rubble," a police officer on-site told AFP.</p>

<p>An AFP reporter on the scene saw dozens of fire trucks as firefighters battled the blaze from the ground and from higher positions. Police helicopters circled overhead.</p>

<p>Debris was strewn across the street and several windows had been blown out, the AFP reporter said.</p>

<p>Huge plumes of smoke were billowing from a large hole where the building stood, with an acrid smell in the air.</p>

<p>"I was asleep and suddenly there was this huge bang," Adam Muller, a 14-year-old local resident, told AFP.</p>

<p>"I looked out of the window and just saw flames. It's a massive shock," he added.</p>

<p><strong>'Like an earthquake'</strong></p>

<p>Authorities warned locals to keep their windows shut and shut off ventilation systems due to the smoke.</p>

<p>Forensic investigators arrived on the scene to begin to probe a potential cause for the accident, an AFP reporter said.</p>

<p>Police appealed for witnesses, saying that a car had driven away from the scene at high speed after the explosion, which occurred around 6:15 am (0515 GMT).</p>

<p>The three floors of the building consisted of shops on the ground floors and five two-storey apartments, authorities said, with living rooms on the second floor and bedrooms on the top.</p>

<p>The city's mayor Jan van Zanen travelled to the site to coordinate rescue efforts.</p>

<p>"It was like an earthquake," said a 53-year-old man who identified himself as Dimi, declining to give his family name.</p>

<p>"Something collapsed but we didn't see where it came from. I know these neighbours. My kids go to school with them."</p>

<p>"My new car has also been seriously damaged," he added.</p>

<p>Early images from public broadcaster NOS showed several dozen firefighters tackling a large blaze and breaking down doors to gain access to the block.</p>

<p>A picture from local news agency ANP showed one person being led away on a stretcher into a waiting ambulance.</p>

<p>Hospitals in the area were on standby to treat victims.</p>

<p>Residents told local media the apartment block was mainly inhabited by elderly people and families with children.</p>

<p>Around 40 residents of other blocks near the collapsed building have been evacuated. Some have been taken away by bus to an unknown location.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Dick Schoof wrote on X that he was "shocked by the terrible images of a collapsed apartment building in The Hague."</p>

<p>"My thoughts go out to the victims, all other people involved and the emergency services who are now working on the scene," said Schoof.</p>

<p>He said he had been in contact with the city authorities and promised any help necessary.</p>

<p>Dutch King Willem-Alexander wrote on social media: "We sympathise with those personally affected or are worried about their loved-ones."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/c0m9nsmg_the-hague-explosion_625x300_07_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Huge plumes of smoke were billowing from a large hole where the building stood.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/australian-woman-who-lost-over-1-million-in-scam-recalls-meeting-criminal-during-overseas-trip-7193939]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Australian Woman Who Lost $1 Million In Scam Recalls Meeting Criminal]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/australian-woman-who-lost-over-1-million-in-scam-recalls-meeting-criminal-during-overseas-trip-7193939]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Dec 2024 16:13:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A woman in Australia who lost over a million in an elaborate scam eerily came face to face with one of the criminals while she was vacationing in China with her husband.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A woman in Australia who lost over a million in an elaborate scam eerily came face to face with one of the criminals while she was vacationing in China with her husband. The woman, who did not want to reveal her identity, runs a Chinese immigration and education business. Speaking to <em>news.com.au</em>, she said that she was distraught after learning that scammers had kept her on the hook for nearly a year through a fake online trading platform, before finally serving ties with her after draining her bank account.&nbsp;</p>

<p>It all started when the woman received a text message from a man called Wei Chen, asking her how she was. At first, she asked the man who he was, however, she didn't find the message alarming or strange as she runs a Chinese immigration and education business. "I thought my friends or clients introduced him to me," she told the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.news.com.au/finance/money/costs/melbourne-woman-loses-19m-to-scammers-eerily-meets-criminal-facetoface-during-overseas-trip/news-story/cd15bf384f1a297cf8df93f23ecce69a" rel="noindex,nofollow">outlet</a>.</p>

<p>Later, the two ended up getting on well. They messaged each other over WeChat and WhatsApp about food and how they had both moved to Australia. Chen told her that he was a permanent resident who ran a furniture store and he lived in the expensive Sydney suburb in a house worth over $12,000,000.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Eventually, Chen mentioned that he staked his fortune on an investment trading website called SpreadEx. Notably, a legitimate company exists by that name in the UK as a sports betting and financial trading company, regulated by the Financial Conduct Authority.</p>

<p>Chen convinced the woman to put some money in. She had $191,215.50 in savings and over a period of time put all that in, and then some more. The woman also revealed that she encouraged her friends to invest in the scheme and also borrowed money from them.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Unfortunately, the company she was dealing with was actually run by a group of scammers. In December last year - six months after the woman had invested - the UK financial watchdog put out a warning, flagging that the scammers were using an extra 's', using the domain spreadexs.com instead of spreadx.com. The Australian government also put out a warning about the fraudulent site.</p>

<p>The woman had already invested all her savings on the platform. She even borrowed a further $286,823.25 from friends and redrew the mortgage she shared with her husband. Some of her school friends also invested as well after she encouraged them.</p>

<p>The woman told the outlet that when she went on a vacation to China she wanted to continue investing on the platform. This is when the scammers told her that she could directly hand over the cash to them while she was in mainland China. She met a man in what she described as a "remote dark place" and handed him over 500,000 yuan in cash.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/feature/watch-author-aija-mayrock-shares-unique-experience-of-renting-old-man-in-japan-7186504">Watch: Author Aija Mayrock Shares Unique Experience Of "Renting" Old Man In Japan</a></strong></p>

<p>While overseas, the woman also left her SpreadEx trading account in the hands of Chen, who at this point she considered a mentor. But when she returned, she tried withdrawing some of her money but her trading account was suddenly suspended.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The scammers then told her she had to pay a risk fee for withdrawing cash. They also charged her a penalty because she had let someone else take over her account.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The woman said the last contact she had with Chen was in April, meaning he kept the ruse going for nearly a year. After multiple unsuccessful attempts to contact him, Roxy and her husband concluded it was a scam and alerted police in September this year.</p>

<p>The woman said she still owes money she took from her friends and the mortgage. Victoria police is still investigating the woman's case.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/3ltqu45_scammers_625x300_25_April_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The woman runs a Chinese immigration and education business. (Representative pic)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/tiktoks-future-in-the-us-how-trump-could-impact-it-7193824]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[TikTok's Future In The US: How Trump Could Impact It]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/tiktoks-future-in-the-us-how-trump-could-impact-it-7193824]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Dec 2024 15:51:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[With 170 million Americans using TikTok, this decision will sound the death knell for the app in one of its biggest markets.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>TikTok is inching closer to being banned in the United States after a new law that could lead to the banning was unanimously upheld by a panel of federal judges.</p>

<p>With 170 million Americans using TikTok, this decision will sound the death knell for the app in one of its biggest markets.</p>

<p>The judges in the US Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit denied TikTok's petition to overturn the law.</p>

<p>According to the law, in order for TikTok to operate in the US, the Chinese owner of the app - ByteDance is required to sell the app to a non-Chinese company by January. This happens amid rising concerns regarding TikTok being a national security concern under ByteDance.</p>

<p>Lawmakers and officials have said that the Chinese government would retrieve and use sensitive information from the app about Americans and spread propaganda, although there's no public evidence of the same occurring. It is also interesting to note that the Chinese government has banned Facebook and Youtube in China and that TikTok is not allowed there.</p>

<p>The app has kept free speech central to the argument and has sparked concern from content creators and influencers whose income depends on it. The American Civil Liberties Union said the decision is "a major blow to freedom of expression online" setting dangerous precedents for other platforms under foreign ownership.</p>

<p>TikTok will move to the Supreme Court and expects a different outcome on the same, although there is no guarantee the apex court will take it up.</p>

<p>"The Supreme Court has an established historical record of protecting Americans' right to free speech, and we expect they will do just that on this important constitutional issue," Michael Hughes, spokesperson for TikTok, said. He also said the ban is an "outright censorship of the American people and that its "based upon inaccurate, flawed and hypothetical information".</p>

<p>Attorney General Merrick Garland says the ruling is "an important step in blocking the Chinese government from weaponising TikTok."</p>

<p>Moreover, President-elect Donald Trump has repeatedly supported the app but the law will get into effect a day before his inauguration. According to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/12/06/business/media/tiktok-ban-court-decision.html" rel="noindex,nofollow">New York Times</a>, some experts speculate that Trump could ask his new attorney general to refrain from enforcing it, but that in turn could put Apple and Google in a delicate situation with the law delineating that companies distributing TikTok in their stores will be penalised.</p>

<p>In any case, Trump had said in September,&nbsp;“For all of those who want to save TikTok in America, vote for Trump" and said that a TikTok ban would only help Meta and Mark Zuckerberg, who he considers&nbsp;“an enemy of the people". But considering his hawkish stance on China, anything is possible.</p>

<p>Trump currently has 14.6M followers on TikTok.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/vod0e7n8_tiktok-afp_625x300_07_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[With 170 million Americans using TikTok, this decision will sound the death knell for the app]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/unacceptable-us-congressman-calls-on-bangladesh-to-end-anti-hindu-violence-7193365]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Unacceptable": US Congressman Calls On Bangladesh To End Anti-Hindu Violence]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/unacceptable-us-congressman-calls-on-bangladesh-to-end-anti-hindu-violence-7193365]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Dec 2024 14:38:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US Congressman Raja Krishnamoorthi has expressed grave concern over the recent unrest in Bangladesh following the arrest of ISKCON priest Chinmoy Krishna Das Brahmachari.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US Congressman Raja Krishnamoorthi has expressed grave concern over the recent unrest in Bangladesh following the arrest of ISKCON priest Chinmoy Krishna Das Brahmachari.</p>

<p>In an official statement, he urged the Bangladeshi government to uphold human rights, guarantee legal protections, and end the wave of violence targeting Hindus and other minority groups.</p>

<p>"The ongoing violence against Hindus and others across Bangladesh is unacceptable and must end immediately. I strongly urge the government of Bangladesh to take decisive steps to reduce tensions peacefully now," he said.</p>

<p>The Illinois Congressman highlighted the need for Bangladesh to safeguard peaceful protests and ensure the arrested individuals receive proper legal representation.</p>

<p>"The government of Bangladesh must uphold and protect human rights and fundamental freedoms, including the rights to peaceful protest and proper legal representation," he stated, adding that such measures are vital to de-escalate the current tensions.</p>

<p>The unrest stems from the sedition charges filed against Chinmoy Krishna Das for allegedly raising a saffron flag above Bangladesh's national flag in Chittagong on October 25. His arrest on November 25 sparked protests, culminating in violent clashes between his followers and law enforcement outside the Chattogram Court Building on November 27, which resulted in the death of a lawyer.</p>

<p>The situation has worsened following additional arrests.</p>

<p>According to ISKCON Kolkata, two monks, Adipurush Shyam Das and Ranganath Das Brahmachari, were detained on November 29 after visiting Chinmoy Krishna Das in custody. The organisation's Vice President, Radha Raman, also claimed that rioters vandalised an ISKCON centre in Bangladesh during the unrest.</p>

<p>Adding to the controversy, the Bangladesh Hindu Buddhist Christian Unity Council condemned what they described as a "false and harassing case" against 70 minority lawyers and two journalists accused of fabricated crimes, including vandalism and bomb explosions. The council has called for the immediate withdrawal of these charges, stating they were designed to hinder the sedition case against Chinmoy Krishna Das and suppress related news coverage.</p>

<p>The Indian Ministry of External Affairs has also voiced concern over escalating violence and extremist rhetoric in Bangladesh, emphasising that it has consistently raised the issue of targeted attacks on minorities with Dhaka.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/q2lv04lk_bangladesh-violence-targeting-hindus-ians_625x300_29_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The situation in Bangladesh has worsened following additional arrests.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/cambridge-university-responds-to-backlash-over-thesis-linking-body-odour-to-racism-7193355]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Cambridge Responds To Backlash Over Thesis Linking Body Odour To Racism]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/cambridge-university-responds-to-backlash-over-thesis-linking-body-odour-to-racism-7193355]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Dec 2024 14:36:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Cambridge University issued a statement supporting Dr Ally Louks after she faced online abuse for her viral social media post celebrating her PhD achievement.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A scholar of Cambridge University, Dr Ally Louks faced a wave of online abuse, including misogynistic bullying and threats, after her social media post celebrating her academic milestone went viral. In response to the backlash, Cambridge University issued a statement expressing full support for Dr. Louks and condemning the harassment she faced.</p>

<p>"Dr Louks, we support you," the statement began. "Last week, Cambridge PhD student @allylouks published this photo on X to celebrate passing her viva with no corrections. Her tweet went viral, attracting over 100 million views."</p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/DDO1dxuN3pu/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DDO1dxuN3pu/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DDO1dxuN3pu/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DDO1dxuN3pu/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by University of Cambridge (@cambridgeuniversity)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p>"But the attention that Ally's achievement received turned to harassment and misogyny when trolls attacked Ally's PhD topic, her education, her achievement, and her gender."</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/thesis-linking-body-odor-with-racism-goes-viral-internet-reacts-7146062"><strong>Also Read | Thesis Linking Body Odour With Racism Goes Viral. Internet Reacts</strong></a></p>

<p>It continued, "In the days afterwards, thousands of commenters-including from Cambridge's own student, staff, and alumni communities-have added their supportive messages for Ally."</p>

<p>"Ally has told us that the majority of the 11,000 comments and 20,000 retweets are from people showing "generosity, intellectual curiosity, and kindness.".</p>

<p>"Curious about Dr Louks' topic? 'Olfactory Ethics: The Politics of Smell in Modern and Contemporary Prose' studies how literature registers the importance of olfactory discourse-the language of smell and the olfactory imagination it creates-in structuring our social world. Congratulations, Dr Louks, on passing your viva with no corrections."</p>

<p>Just like Dr Ally's post, the statement by Cambridge University has also gone viral and is getting a good response.</p>

<p>"Congratulations, Dr I would love to read your thesis. Also kudos to Cambridge for supporting your learners offline and online," commented a user.</p>

<p>"Congratulations on this achievement. I am really looking forward to reading and quoting your research," wrote another user.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/c5etpado_cambridge-university-_625x300_07_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The universitys response, like Dr Louks' post, has garnered positive reactions.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rape-assault-allegations-norways-royal-family-rocked-by-biggest-scandal-7193280]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Rape, Assault Allegations: Norway's Royal Family Rocked By 'Biggest Scandal']]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rape-assault-allegations-norways-royal-family-rocked-by-biggest-scandal-7193280]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Dec 2024 14:25:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A string of rape and assault allegations against the son of Norway's future queen have plunged the royal family into its "biggest scandal" ever, wrapping up an "annus horribilis" for the monarchy.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A string of rape and assault allegations against the son of Norway's future queen have plunged the royal family into its "biggest scandal" ever, wrapping up an "annus horribilis" for the monarchy.</p>

<p>The legal troubles surrounding Marius Borg Hoiby, the 27-year-old son born of a relationship before Crown Princess Mette-Marit's marriage to Crown Prince Haakon, have dominated the Scandinavian country's headlines since August.</p>

<p>The tall strapping blond with a "bad boy" look -- often photographed in tuxedos, slicked back hair, earrings and tattoos -- was arrested in Oslo on August 4 suspected of assaulting his girlfriend the previous night.</p>

<p>A photograph of a knife stuck in the wall of her apartment soon emerged in the media, alongside news reports that Hoiby handed over a partially destroyed cell phone with no SIM card to police.</p>

<p>Hoiby admitted the assault and damage a few days later, saying in a written statement to the media they were the result of a cocaine- and alcohol-fuelled argument.</p>

<p>He said he had struggled "for a long time with substance abuse" and "mental health troubles".&nbsp;</p>

<p>Hoiby, who has friends in criminal circles according to media, was raised with his two step-siblings but has no official role in the royal family.</p>

<p>His legal troubles have only continued to mount since August.</p>

<p>Two ex-girlfriends have come forward to say they were also assaulted by Hoiby.&nbsp;</p>

<p>By December, the police suspicions against him had swelled to include death threats, violation of a restraining order, two rapes and a third possible sex crime.</p>

<p>When the first rape allegation emerged in November, Hoiby spent a week in police custody -- unprecedented for a member of the Norwegian royal family.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"It's snowballing and it doesn't seem to be able to stop," said Sigrid Hvidsten, a columnist at daily Dagbladet.</p>

<p>"It's the biggest scandal ever in the Norwegian royal family."</p>

<p>Police have yet to press any charges against Hoiby, who has so far only admitted the assault and damage during the night of August 3-4 as well as death threats against an unidentified man.</p>

<p>While still far from over, the saga is the culmination of a challenging year for Norway's royal family, its own "annus horribilis", said Hvidsten.</p>

<h3><strong>Wedding criticism</strong></h3>

<p>Norway's royals have been hugely popular and scandal-free for decades.</p>

<p>But even before the Hoiby affair, its image had been clouded by Princess Martha Louise's second wedding in August.</p>

<p>The 53-year-old eldest child of King Harald and Queen Sonja married an American self-proclaimed shaman, Durek Verrett.</p>

<p>Both are alternative therapy devotees: she claims to be a clairvoyant who can speak with angels; he calls himself a "sixth-generation shaman" and sells pricey gold medallions that he says save lives, prompting critics to call him a charlatan.</p>

<p>The couple have faced harsh criticism for their use of her royal title for commercial gain, which intensified when they signed deals with Hello! magazine and Netflix for exclusive coverage of their wedding.</p>

<p>In 2017, the royal family enjoyed the support of 81 percent of Norwegians but by September this year that had slumped to 62 percent.</p>

<p>Adding to the family's misfortunes, 87-year-old King Harald has suffered a slew of health issues.</p>

<p>In February, Europe's oldest-serving monarch had to be repatriated from a vacation in Malaysia on a medical transport plane after contracting an infection.</p>

<p>He was then put on a lengthy sick leave.</p>

<p>In a sign of things to come, the government earmarked 20 million kroner ($1.8 million) in October for a sarcophagus for the king and queen, to be installed in the royal mausoleum in Oslo.</p>

<h3><strong>Down but not out</strong></h3>

<p>The ageing monarch has only briefly, and indirectly, addressed the family's struggles.</p>

<p>"Sometimes, life is just very difficult. It's something that everyone can experience, including our family," he said in late October.</p>

<p>"When people we love are not doing well, it's hard for everyone around them. We're doing our best to look out for one another," he added.</p>

<p>Experts say the monarchy will survive as long as the scandals only concern peripheral royals.</p>

<p>The king, queen and the crown prince couple all remain hugely popular.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"A republic is not an immediate threat," said Tor Bomann-Larsen, the author of several royal biographies.</p>

<p>"Even the worst polls show that there are twice as many Norwegians who support the monarchy. As long as its central members hold the line, the monarchy is safe."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/mvlb1ih_norway_625x300_07_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Norway's royals have been hugely popular and scandal-free for decades.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/temples-set-on-fire-centre-burnt-down-in-dhaka-claims-iskcon-7193231]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Temples Set On Fire, Centre Burnt Down In Dhaka, Claims ISKCON]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/temples-set-on-fire-centre-burnt-down-in-dhaka-claims-iskcon-7193231]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Dec 2024 14:15:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The International Society for Krishna Consciousness (ISKCON) on Saturday alleged that its centre in Dhaka district in neighbouring Bangladesh was burnt down earlier in the day.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The International Society for Krishna Consciousness (ISKCON) on Saturday alleged that its centre in Dhaka district in neighbouring Bangladesh was burnt down earlier in the day.</p>

<p>Iskcon Kolkata vice president Radharamn Das told PTI that the targetted attack on members of the community and members of the Vaishnavite order goes on unabated as "vandals set ablaze idols inside the temple at the Namhatta property."</p>

<p>He said in a post on X handle, "ISKCON Namhatta Centre burned down in Bangladesh. The deities of Sri Sri Laxmi Narayan and all items inside the temple were burned down completely. The centre is located in Dhaka. Early morning today, between 2-3 AM, miscreants set fire to the Shri Shri Radha Krishna Temple and the Shri Shri Mahabhagya Lakshmi Narayan Temple, which fall under the Hare Krishna Namhatta Sangha, located in Dhour village, under the jurisdiction of Turag Police Station, Dhaka district."</p>

<p>"The fire was initiated by lifting the tin roof at the back of the temple and using petrol or octane. Address: H-02, R-05, Ward-54," he said in the post.</p>

<p>Mr Das claimed that attacks are continuing and despite the ISKCON drawing the attention of the interim government in Bangladesh, not much is being done by the police and administration to assuage their grievances and address their concern.</p>

<p>"Iskcon India has expressed concern about the safety of Hindus in Bangladesh and urged its monks and followers from Bangladesh not to wear 'tilaks' and practice their faith discreetly. The targeted attacks continue," he had earlier said.</p>

<p>The Iskcon Kolkata vice president also expressed concern over arrested Hindu community leader Chinmoy Krishna Das's safety following his denial of bail and the violent attacks.</p>

<p>Since the installation of the interim government and the dislodging of the Awami League from power in August, ISKCON properties have come under attack at various places across Bangladesh in the past four months.</p>

<p>West Bengal BJP president and Union minister Sukanta Majumdar in a post on X said, "Strongly condemn the horrific arson attack on the #ISKCON Namhatta Centre in Dhaka, Bangladesh, which destroyed the Deities of Sri Sri Laxmi Narayan and sacred temple items." "This is an unforgivable act of hatred against a place of worship. Immediate action must be taken to bring the culprits to justice and ensure the safety of religious minorities," the Union Minister of State for Education said.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/kedlb8uo_isckon-bangladesh-ani_625x300_07_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Iskcon Kolkata official claimed attacks on minorities are continuing In Bangladesh.(Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-race-donald-trump-joe-biden-kamala-harris-raised-jaw-dropping-4-7-billion-7192012]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump, Biden, Kamala Harris Raised Total Of $4.7 Billion Funds For US Polls]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-race-donald-trump-joe-biden-kamala-harris-raised-jaw-dropping-4-7-billion-7192012]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Dec 2024 13:54:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donors poured a staggering $4.7 billion into the campaigns of Donald Trump, Kamala Harris,Joe Biden, and their supporting groups during the 2024 US presidential election.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">Donors poured a staggering $4.7 billion into the campaigns of Donald Trump, Kamala Harris,&nbsp;Joe Biden, and their supporting groups during the 2024 US presidential election. The amount was revealed through final campaign finance reports released on December 5.&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">The figure represents contributions from October 17 to November 25, as detailed in the latest filings, combined with earlier reports. The data highlights a stark financial divide between the parties, with Democrats and their affiliated groups raising approximately $2.9 billion compared to the Republicans' $1.8 billion.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Donald Trump and the Republican National Committee (RNC) raised $1.2 billion from November 2022 - when he launched his campaign - till election day. His key super PACs, including MAGA Inc, Right for America, Turnout for America, America PAC, and Preserve America, added another $849 million.</p>

<p dir="ltr">The Biden-Harris campaign benefitted from an early start, avoiding a competitive primary and signing a joint fundraising agreement with the Democratic National Committee (DNC) well ahead of their rivals. This enabled the Democrats to secure larger contributions. From April 2023, when Biden announced his re-election bid, till election day, the campaign raised around $2 billion. Their main allies super PACs, Future Forward and American Bridge, contributed an additional $652 million.</p>

<p dir="ltr">The overall $4.7 billion total includes funds raised during the Republican primary, much of which Trump's campaign used against other Republican challengers.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Dark money significantly influenced the final weeks of the election. Both Trump's and Harris's main super PACs relied heavily on contributions from affiliated dark-money groups. These funds, often termed "grey money," raise transparency concerns as the origins of the donations remain undisclosed.</p>

<p dir="ltr">MAGA Inc, Trump's primary super PAC, collected $78 million during the closing weeks, with $53 million originating from Securing American Greatness, its affiliated dark-money group. Similarly, Future Forward, the super PAC backing Harris, raised nearly $164 million during the same period, over $128 million of which came from its dark-money nonprofit, Future Forward USA Action.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Future Forward USA Action reportedly raised more than $900 million during the election cycle, including $58 million in 2023, according to a recent tax filing. This dark money later funded the super PAC in 2024, showcasing the blurred lines between transparency and influence.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Managing campaign finances post-election remains a delicate balance. Overspending can lead to debt, while underspending raises questions about unutilised resources.</p>

<p dir="ltr">The Trump campaign reported $11.4 million in unpaid bills as of November 25 but also held $10 million in cash and was owed $4.7 million. The Harris campaign faced criticism for being $20 million in debt post-election but ended the race with no outstanding debts and $2 million on hand.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Elon Musk emerged as a major financial player, donating $277 million through his entities to federal groups supporting Trump. This included $238.7 million funnelled into America PAC, a super PAC Musk established discreetly in 2024. Musk also made headlines as the sole donor to RBG PAC, a super PAC created to align Trump with the late Supreme Court Justice Ruth Bader Ginsburg on abortion issues. Elon Musk contributed $20 million to the group in October 2024.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/ejv2hkd_trump-kamala-biden_625x300_07_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Managing campaign finances post-election remains a delicate balance.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/watch-sunita-williams-demonstrates-zero-gravity-drinking-in-virtual-space-session-7193097]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Sunita Williams Demonstrates Zero-Gravity Drinking In Virtual Space Session]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/watch-sunita-williams-demonstrates-zero-gravity-drinking-in-virtual-space-session-7193097]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Dec 2024 13:53:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[She explained the use of special pouches and shared insights into spaceflight, inspiring young minds to explore the cosmos.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Indian-origin astronaut, Sunita Williams, recently hosted a highly engaging virtual session for students of Sunita Williams Elementary School in her hometown of Needham, Massachusetts. During the event she discussed the peculiar challenge of drinking liquids in space and offered an interesting glimpse into life aboard the International Space Station (ISS).</p>

<p><strong>Watch the video here:&nbsp;</strong></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">A student gets a demonstration from astronaut, Sunita Williams on how to drink liquids in space. Williams and Barry "Butch" Wilmore hit the six-month mark in space after becoming the first to ride Boeing's new Starliner capsule on what was supposed to be a week-long test flight.… <a href="https://t.co/1UQSgvcHsN">pic.twitter.com/1UQSgvcHsN</a></p>
— Francynancy (@FranMooMoo) <a href="https://twitter.com/FranMooMoo/status/1864858918184456274?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 6, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Williams, an experienced astronaut with many years of experience in spaceflight, presented firsthand insights into the creative ways astronauts drink fluids in the microgravity environment. She described how liquids move differently in zero gravity and demonstrated how to drink using special pouches designed for this purpose, which do not rely on gravity.</p>

<p>The interactive session gave students a chance to ask questions of the astronaut directly. Explaining and demonstrating the details of space and the astonishing adaptations necessary for human flight will excite the minds of young viewers to begin exploring the wonders of the cosmos.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/217p6adg_sunita-williams-diwali_625x300_29_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sunita Williams hosted a virtual session for students in her hometown.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/tax-collector-elephant-in-sri-lanka-goes-viral-for-stopping-vehicles-seeking-food-7193019]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA['Tax Collector' Elephant Goes Viral For Stopping Vehicles, Seeking Food]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/tax-collector-elephant-in-sri-lanka-goes-viral-for-stopping-vehicles-seeking-food-7193019]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Dec 2024 13:40:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Social media users have given their seal of approval to Raja to continue his bureaucratic duties and chomp on bananas and other fruits.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>You might be used to paying the road toll to scrupulous transport employees sitting in a cooped-up cabin roadside but things are a little different in Sri Lanka. Along the Buttala-Kataragama road, a majestic wild elephant, believed to be over 40 years old, performs the duties of a toll collector. Known to locals as Raja, meaning king, the elephant <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://x.com/nuttinessnature/status/1865066933680304221?s=46" rel="noindex, nofollow">stands </a>roadside but quickly seizes upon a vehicle coming from either direction and immediately requests food. The jumbo needs to be served.</p>

<p>Raja is patient in his approach. He understands that getting angry will only drive the people away. Hence, after stopping the vehicles, Raja calmly uses his massive trunk to poke the drivers for food, who after some negotiation, albeit failed, offer the food items to him. It is an efficient business -- one that only Raja appears to be the master of.</p>

<p>What started as an innocuous food search by Raja has now turned into a full-fledged tradition. Many motorists buy fruits including bananas in advance at wayside little stalls that dot the road from Lunugamvehera to Sella Kataragama, anticipating an encounter with the elephants, particularly Raja.</p>

<p>Notably, the Buttala-Kataragama road is a major linkway that connects Sri Lanka's west coast with the southeast coast. With wild untamed jungle on either side, the road is popular among the locals as well as foreigners who seek the thrill of engaging with nature in its visceral glory.</p>

<p>Despite causing significant hassle on the road by blocking the vehicles, the locals treat Raja with respect and give in to his authoritarian 'tax-collection' policy.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/elephants-the-engineers-of-ecosystems-6318698" rel="noindex, nofollow"><strong>Also read | Elephants - The Engineers Of Ecosystems</strong></a></p>

<h3><strong>Social media reacts</strong></h3>

<p>Social media users have given their seal of approval to Raja to continue his bureaucratic duties and chomp on bananas and other fruits.</p>

<p>"This is where and how l want my tax to be paid," said one user, while another added: For people saying it's dangerous, I mean who's gonna stop him? It's called hustle!"</p>

<p>A third added: "These elephants are true businessmen. Look how patiently he's dealing with the drivers."</p>

<p>Elephants are revered in Sri Lanka. 70 per cent of the population is Buddhist and before Buddha was born, his mother dreamt of a great white elephant. It is believed that Buddha himself could have been in the form of an elephant in previous lives. Similarly, those belonging to the Hindu faith in the island nation worship Lord Ganesha, the elephant-headed god who is the son of Lord Mahadev and Goddess Parvati.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/gig258fo_elephant_625x300_07_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Raja stops the vehicles and demands food. (Representational image)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/storm-darragh-brings-life-threatening-winds-to-uk-red-warning-issued-7192883]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Storm Darragh Brings Life-Threatening Winds To UK, Red Warning Issued]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/storm-darragh-brings-life-threatening-winds-to-uk-red-warning-issued-7192883]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Dec 2024 13:13:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Millions of people in the affected areas have been advised to stay indoors due to potentially life-threatening weather conditions such as flying debris and falling trees could cause injury or danger to life.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Met Office has issued a rare red warning for wind, signaling "danger to life," as Storm Darragh hits parts of Wales and south-west England on Saturday. Millions of people in the affected areas have been advised to stay indoors due to potentially life-threatening weather conditions such as flying debris and falling trees could cause injury or danger to life.</p>

<p>The warning has been issued from 03:00 to 11:00 GMT on Saturday, covering western and southern Wales, and the Bristol Channel coast. Wind gusts of up to 91 mph are expected, posing a significant risk of disruption.</p>

<p>Tens of thousands of homes are without power in south Wales and western England and residents are advised to gather essential items, such as torches, batteries, and power packs, in case of power cuts. Three million people received emergency alerts on their mobiles, advising them to stay indoors and avoid driving.</p>

<p>Amber weather warnings are in place for Northern Ireland, Wales, and western England until Saturday morning.</p>

<p>Buildings may be damaged, including tiles blown from roofs, the Met Office said. Power cuts and large waves are expected. Roads and bridges may be closed due to falling trees.</p>

<p>Storm Darragh is the fourth named storm of the season, following severe flooding caused by storms Bert and Conall last month. The Met Office urges residents to prioritise their safety and follow the guidance provided. The storm's impact is expected to be significant, with widespread disruption anticipated across the affected areas.</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/ic3sntv_met-warning-afp_625x300_07_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Met Office issued a rare red warning, signaling "danger to life," as Storm Darragh hits UK]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/private-dinner-with-donald-trump-and-his-wife-will-cost-you-1-million-7192830]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Want Invitation To Private Dinner With Trump, His Wife? It Will Cost You...]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/private-dinner-with-donald-trump-and-his-wife-will-cost-you-1-million-7192830]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Dec 2024 13:06:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Top donors to the inauguration committee of US President-elect Donald Trump will be having dinner with him and his wife, Melania Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">Top donors to the inauguration committee of US President-elect Donald Trump will be having dinner with him and his wife, Melania Trump.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Ahead of Mr Trump's oath ceremony at the US Capitol on January 20 in Washington DC, money is being raised for his inauguration in increments as high as $2 million, The New York Times reported.</p>

<p dir="ltr">A flier titled “Trump Vance Inaugural Committee Benefits” has listed the perks of donating $1 million or raising $2 million for the key event.&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">Individuals who reach that elite level will be given a half-dozen tickets to eight inaugural events scheduled to take place from January 17 to January 20.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Among the major highlights of the schedule of events for both the elite donors as well as fund-raisers is a reception, which will include all the cabinet picks and a dinner with US Vice President-elect JD Vance and his wife, Usha Vance, which will take place on January 18.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Meanwhile, an “elegant and intimate dinner with President Donald J Trump and Mrs Melania Trump” has been described as the "pinnacle event", set to take place on January 19.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Before the dissemination of this flier, Melania Trump did not confirm whether she was supposed to attend the inaugural festivities, including a Sunday morning interfaith service -- which she plans to attend with Donald Trump.</p>

<p dir="ltr">For the inauguration day on January 20 (Monday), the big donors will be provided six tickets each to attend the mega event.</p>

<p dir="ltr">It must be noted that donors and corporations usually send money to the presidents' inaugural committees as a way to mark their support for the president, besides seeking support from the administration that shall remain in power for the next four years.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Although there are no limits on the donations that are being made to the Donald Trump committee, structured as a political non-profit for tax purposes, gifts that are more than $200 have to be disclosed to the Federal Election Commission.</p>

<p dir="ltr">During Donald Trump's previous term, his maiden inaugural committee was able to raise $107 million in 2016 and 2017. However, it was later investigated by federal prosecutors for illegal foreign donations, resulting in a 12-year prison sentence for one of the donors.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Steven Witkoff, real estate mogul who has donated roughly $2 million to Donald Trump's political causes over the past decade and was recently named a special envoy to the Middle East, is leading the current inaugural committee along with Kelly Loeffler, ex-Republican senator from Georgia.</p>

<p dir="ltr">On his behalf, Donald Trump continues to raise funds for his political efforts. He is expected to headline an event on December 19 at his Florida club, Mar-a-Lago. This is being done for a pro-Trump super PAC, named MAGA Inc., while tickets for the event cost were $1 million a person.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/90s2jl_donald-trump-melania-trump_625x300_07_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[nA "intimate dinner" with Trump and his wife Melania is set to take place on January 19.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/worlds-most-expensive-dinosaur-fossil-apex-returns-to-nyc-museum-7192352]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[World's Most Expensive Dinosaur Fossil 'Apex' Returns To NYC Museum]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/worlds-most-expensive-dinosaur-fossil-apex-returns-to-nyc-museum-7192352]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Dec 2024 11:26:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Stegosaurus, nicknamed Apex, will be available for public viewing for the next four years at an NYC museum.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 150-million-year-old fossil of a Stegosaurus which became the most expensive dinosaur fossil ever sold earlier this year, has been put on display at the American Museum of Natural History in Manhattan. The Stegosaurus, nicknamed Apex, will be available for public viewing for the next four years after billionaire Kenneth C. Griffin, who bought the fossil for $44.6 million, generously decided to offer it to the museum authorities. Afterwards, a cast of the specimen will take the fossil's place.</p>

<p>The impressive specimen was revealed to reporters, photographers and museum employees and is expected to be opened to the public on Sunday (Dec 8).</p>

<p>"It's one of the dinosaurs that every kid knows how to draw. This is a unique opportunity to have something that simultaneously, I think, really resonates in the public imagination about dinosaurs, but also from a research standpoint, is really a pretty special specimen to understand," Sean M. Decatur, the museum's president was quoted as saying by NYT.</p>

<p>"We hope our millions of visitors are as awe-struck as we are by Apex."</p>

<p>Commenting about lending the fossil, Mr Griffin said Apex "offers a unique window into our planet's distant past" and that he is grateful millions of visitors and researchers will be able to learn from the magnificent specimen at the museum.</p>

<p>"The joy and awe every child feels colouring a Stegosaurus with their crayons will now be brought to life for the millions of people who have the opportunity to see this epic dinosaur in person."</p>

<p>This is not the first instance when Mr Griffins, the founder and chief executive of the hedge fund Citadel, has shown interest in the massive reptiles.In 2017, he donated $16.5 to Chicago's Field Museum to fund an exhibit featuring the largest Tyrannosaurus rex skeleton ever discovered.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-billionaire-buys-largest-stegosaurus-skeleton-for-44-6-million-shatters-auction-records-6147977" rel="noindex, nofollow"><strong>Also Read | US Billionaire Buys Largest Stegosaurus Skeleton For $44.6 Million, Shatters Auction Records</strong></a></p>

<h3><strong>When was Apex found?</strong></h3>

<p>Apex was discovered by palaeontologist Jason Cooper on his private land in Colorado in 2022. Measuring 11 feet tall and 27 feet long, scientists stated it was a nearly complete and remarkably preserved fossil, which eventually fetched the record-breaking sum from Mr Griffins.</p>

<p>The skeleton was initially anticipated to fetch somewhere around $6 million but interest from six other participants saw the value balloon to $44.6 million, which smashed the previous record set by a Tyrannosaurus rex fossil, which sold for $$31.8 million in 2020.</p>

<h3><strong>What are Stegosaurus?</strong></h3>

<p>The Stegosaurus is recognisable by its distinct double row of large, kite-shaped plates along its back plates and spiked tail. It roamed the Earth as a herbivorous dinosaur in the late Jurassic period, around 155-150 million years ago. Despite its impressive armour, Stegosaurus was a relatively small dinosaur, measuring about 30 feet in length and weighing around two to three metric tons.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/o277qeo_dinosaur_625x300_07_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The stegosaurus fossil nicknamed Apex on display.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/syria-bashar-al-assad-syria-war-as-rebels-advance-bashar-al-assad-loses-another-key-syrian-city-10-facts-7192239]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Damascus Awaits": Syrian Rebels Have Begun Encircling Capital, Says Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/syria-bashar-al-assad-syria-war-as-rebels-advance-bashar-al-assad-loses-another-key-syrian-city-10-facts-7192239]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Dec 2024 11:08:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In another setback to President Bashar al-Assad's hold on power, the Syrian government forces have lost control of Daraa city, widely regarded as the birthplace of Syria's 2011 civil uprising.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<ol>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Syrian rebels said they have started to surround government-held Damascus after snatching the southern province of Daraa from government control, as the defence ministry denied the army had fled positions near the capital. "Damascus awaits you," Syria Islamist rebel leader told fighters.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">In 2011, Daraa city, located roughly 100 km from capital Damascus, became the epicentre of nationwide protests after the Assad government detained and allegedly tortured a group of boys for scrawling anti-regime graffiti. What began as peaceful demonstrations soon spiralled into a violent conflict that has since seen over 500,000 dead and millions displaced.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Daraa's fall follows the swift loss of Aleppo, Syria's second-largest city, and Hama in the country's central region. These major victories have emboldened rebels to push south toward Homs, Syria's third-largest city, and even closer to Damascus, the seat of Assad's power.&nbsp;</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">The rebel coalition spearheading this offensive is led by Hayat Tahrir al-Sham (HTS), a group with origins in Al-Qaeda. Though designated a terrorist organisation by Western governments, HTS leader Abu Mohammed al-Jolani said in an interview that the group's primary goal remains the overthrow of Assad.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">In the country's east, government forces vacated Deir Ezzor, ceding territory to Kurdish-led Syrian Democratic Forces (SDF) backed by the United States. The withdrawal appears sudden, with troops reportedly regrouping in Palmyra, a key junction on the road to Homs.&nbsp;</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Airstrikes by Syrian and Russian aircraft have sought to slow the rebel advance, but observers note that these efforts have been relatively limited, likely reflecting Russia's stretched military commitments elsewhere, particularly in Ukraine.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Jordan has closed its border crossings with Syria, while Lebanon has imposed restrictions on land crossings. Israel, which occupies the Golan Heights, announced reinforcements to its aerial and ground forces. Turkey, which has supported elements of the Syrian opposition, expressed a mix of approval and caution over the rebel advance.&nbsp;</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">The <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-issues-midnight-advisory-over-grave-situation-in-syria-complete-details-here-7190703#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll_Imagetopscroll" target="_blank">Centre has issued an advisory</a> to completely "avoid all travel to Syria until further notice". Indians currently in Syria have been advised to "remain in touch with the Indian Embassy in Damascus".</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">According to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/12/06/world/middleeast/iran-syria-evacuation.html" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">New York Times</a>, Iran is evacuating its military personnel and military officials from Syria into Iraq and Lebanon. Iranian civilians in Syria are also reportedly evacuating thanks to heightened hostility towards the Iranian regime for its continued support of al-Assad.&nbsp;</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Over 280,000 people have been displaced since the offensive began, according to UN estimates. In Homs, which has endured some of the conflict's deadliest violence, tens of thousands of residents, particularly from Assad's Alawite minority, are fleeing in anticipation of the rebels' arrival.&nbsp;</li>
</ol>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/jpc7gff8_hayat-tahrir-alsham-afp-_625x300_07_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The rebel coalition spearheading this offensive is led by Hayat Tahrir al-Sham (HTS).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/philadelphia-couple-become-world-s-oldest-newlyweds-with-combined-ages-exceeding-200-years-7192119]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Man, 100, Marries 102-Year-Old Woman, Become World's Oldest Married Couple]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/philadelphia-couple-become-world-s-oldest-newlyweds-with-combined-ages-exceeding-200-years-7192119]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Dec 2024 10:42:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Bernie Littman and Marjorie Fiterman set a Guinness World Record as the oldest newlyweds with a combined age of 202 years.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">A couple from Philadelphia has set a Guinness World Record by becoming the world's oldest newlyweds. Bernie Littman, aged 100, and Marjorie Fiterman, aged 102, got married earlier this year, with their combined ages totalling an extraordinary 202 years and 271 days, as confirmed on December 3 by the Guinness World Records.</p>

<p dir="ltr">The centenarian couple's love story began at a senior living facility in Philadelphia, where they both resided. They met nine years ago at a costume party held on their floor and quickly developed a romantic connection. Their journey together culminated in a wedding ceremony held on May 19, at the very same facility where their relationship began.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Both Bernie and Marjorie had lived rich and fulfilling lives, having been married to their respective spouses for more than six decades before becoming widowed. Despite attending the University of Pennsylvania simultaneously in their youth, they never crossed paths until fate brought them together in their later years. Bernie became an engineer, while Marjorie pursued a career as a teacher.</p>

<p dir="ltr">When announcing the centenarians' wedding, Littman's granddaughter, Sarah Sicherman, told the <a href="https://www.thejc.com/news/usa/jewish-couple-become-worlds-oldest-newlyweds-with-a-combined-age-of-202-sfvdo9cb#:~:text=A%20Jewish%2DAmerican%20couple%20with,Littman%27s%20great%2Dgranddaughters%20was%20born." rel="nofollow noindex">Jewish Chronicle</a>, “With so much sadness (and) fear in the world, it's nice to be able to share something that brings people joy.”</p>

<p dir="ltr">She shared in a post: "Today my 100-year-old grandfather married his 102-year-old girlfriend! Bernie Littman and Marjorie Fiterman live on the same floor of a senior living facility in Philadelphia. They both had 60-plus years of marriage to their first spouses and found love again at 100 years old!”</p>

<p dir="ltr">Rabbi Adam Wohlberg, who officiated the wedding, told <a href="https://www.foxnews.com/lifestyle/philadelphia-couple-ages-102-100-get-married-surprise-their-families.amp" rel="nofollow noindex">Fox News</a>, “Most of the couples I marry these days met on some kind of dating app. I much prefer the old ways. You live in the same building, you bump into each other, and you fall in love.”</p>

<p dir="ltr">The couple's bond deepened over shared meals and their active participation in the community's events, including theatrical productions. Bernie attributes his longevity and happiness to his love of reading and staying informed, while Marjorie credits buttermilk as her secret to a long life.</p>

<p dir="ltr">The wedding ceremony was a personal affair, attended by four generations of Bernie's family. Held under a traditional Jewish chuppah at their senior living facility, the couple exchanged vows in the presence of loved ones and well-wishers. Both Bernie and Marjorie were escorted to the ceremony in their wheelchairs, beaming with joy as they began this new chapter together.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/pnppbnf8_marjorie-fiterman-bernie-littman_625x300_07_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/comets-brought-water-to-earth-billions-of-years-ago-new-study-claims-7191963]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Comets Brought Water To Earth Billions Of Years Ago, New Study Claims]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/comets-brought-water-to-earth-billions-of-years-ago-new-study-claims-7191963]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Dec 2024 10:12:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The water on Earth has a unique molecular signature which has to do with specific rations of the hydrogen variant, or isotope, called deuterium.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Comets may have been responsible for the presence of water on Earth, scientists have claimed, according to a new research published this week in <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/sciadv.adp2191" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>Science Advances</em></a>. The researchers focused on Comet 67P/Churyumov-Gerasimenko and discovered that the molecular structure of water found on the celestial body closely resembled that of Earth's oceans. While water existed in the gas and dust form when Earth formed around 4.6 billion years ago, questions regarding how it ultimately became rich in liquid water have puzzled scientists.</p>

<p>Researchers are of the view that a substantial portion of our oceans came from the ice and minerals on asteroids and possibly comets that crashed into Earth. To further their theory, the researchers led by Kathleen Mandt, a planetary scientist at NASA's Goddard Space Flight Center, decided to use an advanced statistical computation technique to find the molecular structure of water on 67P which belongs to the Jupiter family of comets, using data captured by European Space Agency's (ESA) Rosetta mission to the asteroid.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/science/dark-comets-mysterious-dark-comets-may-pose-bigger-threat-than-previously-thought-to-earth-6131464" rel="noindex, nofollow"><strong>Also Read | Mysterious 'Dark Comets' May Pose Bigger Threat Than Previously Thought To Earth</strong></a></p>

<h3><strong>Earth's specific signature</strong></h3>

<p>The water on Earth has a unique molecular signature which has to do with specific rations of the hydrogen variant, or isotope, called deuterium. For the last few decades, deuterium levels in water found in the vapour trails of several Jupiter-family comets displayed similar levels to that of Earth's water.</p>

<p>"So I was just curious if we could find evidence for that happening at 67P. And this is just one of those very rare cases where you propose a hypothesis and actually find it happening," said Ms Mandt.</p>

<p>As it turned out, Ms Mandt's team found a clear connection between deuterium measurements in the comet and the amount of dust around the Rosetta spacecraft.</p>

<p>"As a comet moves in its orbit closer to the Sun, its surface warms up, causing gas to release from the surface, including dust with bits of water ice on it. Water with deuterium sticks to dust grains more readily than regular water does," the study highlighted.</p>

<p>"When the ice on these dust grains is released into the coma, this effect could make the comet appear to have more deuterium than it has," it added.</p>

<p>The research has big implications not only for understanding comets' role in delivering Earth's water but also for understanding comet observations that provide insight into the formation of the early solar system.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/g672g7n8_comet_625x300_07_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Image of Comet 67P/Churyumov-Gerasimenko taken by ESAs Rosetta navigation camera.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-student-fatally-stabbed-in-canada-during-altercation-with-housemate-7191930]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Indian Student Stabbed To Death In Canada, Housemate Arrested]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-student-fatally-stabbed-in-canada-during-altercation-with-housemate-7191930]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Dec 2024 10:07:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 22-year-old Indian student was fatally stabbed in Canada's Ontario by his housemate, who has been charged with second-degree murder by the Sarnia Police.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;A 22-year-old Indian student was stabbed to death in Canada's Ontario by his housemate, who has been charged with second-degree murder by the Sarnia Police.</p>

<p>Gurasis Singh, a first-year business management student at Lambton College, was stabbed by 36-year-old Crossley Hunter on Sunday. Early on December 1, the police received an emergency call reporting a stabbing at a rooming house on Queen Street in Sarnia. The incident occurred when the duo were engaged in a physical altercation while in the kitchen. The latter accessed a knife and stabbed Mr Singh multiple times, killing him.</p>

<p>On reaching the location, they retrieved the victim's body and took the accused into custody.</p>

<p>The accused will appear before a judicial officer on Saturday. "The Sarnia Police Criminal Investigations Division continues to gather all available evidence to determine the circumstances surrounding this criminal act and what, if any, motive may have existed that led to the murder of this young man. At this time, we do not believe this crime to be racially motivated," police chief Derek Davis said.</p>

<p>Davis added that the police, with Lambton College, "will continue our efforts to support Gurasis' family and friends as they seek to navigate these tragic circumstances."</p>

<p>The college issued a statement condoling Singh's death. "Students are at the heart of Lambton College, and the loss of a student is a tragedy of the highest magnitude. We extend our deepest condolences to Gurasis's family, loved ones, and friends. Many of our employees knew Gurasis from teaching him or providing student services. Even more have stepped in to provide support for his grieving friends and classmates," it added.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/pd8j22sg_gurasis-singh-shot-dead-in-canada_625x300_07_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Gurasis Singh was a first-year business management student at Lambton College.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sex-video-of-couple-in-flight-goes-viral-crew-under-investigation-7191848]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Couple Engage In Sexual Activity On Flight, Crew Under Probe For Video Leak]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sex-video-of-couple-in-flight-goes-viral-crew-under-investigation-7191848]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Dec 2024 09:49:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A video of a couple engaging in sexual activity onboard a commercial flight has sparked massive outrage over social media leading to an internal investigation by the airline.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">A video of a couple engaging in sexual activity onboard a commercial flight has sparked massive outrage over social media leading to an internal investigation by the airline.</p>

<p dir="ltr">The video was captured by the cockpit-controlled security cameras on the Swiss Air passenger jet.</p>

<p dir="ltr">It shows the couple engaging in sexual activity in the galley of the plane. It was filmed in November on Swiss Air's 12-hour-long Flight 181 flying from Bangkok to Zurich.</p>

<p dir="ltr">"A couple on board a recent Swiss Air flight from Bangkok to Zurich joined the mile-high club in the first-class galley while secretly being recorded by the pilots. The cockpit crew are now under investigation for sharing the footage on group chats which has since gone viral," one person wrote on X, while sharing a screenshot from the viral video.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">A couple on board a recent Swiss Air flight from Bangkok to Zurich joined the mile-high club in the first-class galley while secretly being recorded by the pilots.<br />
<br />
The cockpit crew are now under investigation for sharing the footage on group chats which has since gone viral. <a href="https://t.co/B9cGA8dVKZ">pic.twitter.com/B9cGA8dVKZ</a></p>
— ᒍᑌᔕT ᗰIKE (@JustMikeMcKay) <a href="https://twitter.com/JustMikeMcKay/status/1864591991457419455?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 5, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p dir="ltr">Swiss Air has launched an investigation into privacy 'violations', while airline officials have promised to identify and discipline the crew members who are responsible for recording the video without the permission of the couple and later posting it on social media.</p>

<p dir="ltr">"The filming of people without their clear consent as well as the transfer of these recordings contradict our guidelines and values and violate the applicable data protection regulations," Daily Mail quoted Swiss Air media spokesperson Meike Fuhlrott as saying.</p>

<p dir="ltr">She noted that the crew after spotting the couple on camera should have "intervened directly" and not filmed the act.&nbsp;"Our crews are known for their professionalism. We trust in the competence of our crews and are convinced of their abilities," Fuhlrott added.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Further, the airline noted that both the viral footage as well as the sarcastic commentary on social media were "disrespectful" to passengers.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Fuhlrott said that the airline is trying to find out "exactly what happened and how these recordings came out".&nbsp;The trust of our passengers and respectful interactions are our top priority," the airline official said.</p>

<p dir="ltr">It must be noted that the CCTV cameras on the planes were part of crew security measures that were installed after the 9/11 hijackings. These are aimed at monitoring any attempts to break into the cockpit, rather than spying on passengers, she added.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/oddu0cq_swiss-air_625x300_24_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Swiss Air has launched an investigation into privacy 'violations'.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>