<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Mon, 16 Sep 2024 00:52:35 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-safe-after-gunshots-in-his-vicinity-at-florida-golf-club-6573553]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump Safe After "Gunshots In His Vicinity" At Florida Golf Club]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-safe-after-gunshots-in-his-vicinity-at-florida-golf-club-6573553]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 16 Sep 2024 00:47:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump's campaign reported Sunday that there had been "gunshots in his vicinity" but added that the Republican presidential candidate was safe.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump's campaign reported Sunday that there had been "gunshots in his vicinity" but added that the Republican presidential candidate was safe.</p>

<p>"President Trump is safe following gunshots in his vicinity. No further details at this time," said a statement from his campaign spokesman Steven Cheung.</p>

<p>Trump had been golfing at his golf course in West Palm Beach, Florida, not far from his Mar-a-Lago residence, during a day away from the presidential campaign, multiple media reports said.</p>

<p>It was unclear who had fired the shots, and there was no immediate indication that Trump had been targeted.</p>

<p>Some reports said the gunfire was between two people in a dispute near the course.</p>

<p>Still, it came amid heightened concern for the candidate's safety -- just two months after the former president was wounded in the ear when a gunman opened fire during a Trump rally in Pennsylvania.</p>

<p>The US Secret Service, tasked with protecting presidents, former presidents and other dignitaries, faced criticism after the Pennsylvania incident.</p>

<p>The head of the agency later resigned, and at least five of its agents were placed on administrative leave.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-06/o898g2bg_donald-trump-reuters_625x300_14_June_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Some reports said the gunfire was between two people in a dispute near the course. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-backed-houthis-strike-israel-with-ballistic-missile-for-1st-time-6573277]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iran-Backed Houthis Strike Israel With Ballistic Missile For 1st Time]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-backed-houthis-strike-israel-with-ballistic-missile-for-1st-time-6573277]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 15 Sep 2024 23:33:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said Israel would inflict a "heavy price" on the Iran-aligned Houthis who control northern Yemen, after they reached central Israel with a missile on Sunday for the first time.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said Israel would inflict a "heavy price" on the Iran-aligned Houthis who control northern Yemen, after they reached central Israel with a missile on Sunday for the first time.</p>

<p>Houthi military spokesman Yahya Sarea said the group struck with a new hypersonic ballistic missile that travelled 2,040 km (1270 miles) in just 11 1/2 minutes.</p>

<p>After initially saying the missile had fallen in an open area, Israel's military later said it had probably fragmented in the air, and that pieces of interceptors had landed in fields and near a railway station. Nobody was reported hurt.</p>

<p>Air raid sirens had sounded in Tel Aviv and across central Israel moments before the impact at around 6:35 a.m. local time (0335 GMT), sending residents running for shelter. Loud booms were heard.</p>

<p>Reuters saw smoke billowing in an open field in central Israel.</p>

<p>At a weekly cabinet meeting, Netanyahu said the Houthis should have known that Israel would exact a "heavy price" for attacks on Israel.</p>

<p>"Whoever needs a reminder of that is invited to visit the Hodeida port," Netanyahu said, referring to an Israeli retaliatory air strike against Yemen in July for a Houthi drone that hit Tel Aviv.</p>

<p>The Houthis have fired missiles and drones at Israel repeatedly in what they say is solidarity with the Palestinians, since the Gaza war began with a Hamas attack on Israel in October.</p>

<p>The drone that hit Tel Aviv for the first time in July killed a man and wounded four people. Israeli air strikes in response on Houthi military targets near the port of Hodeidah killed six and wounded 80.</p>

<p>Previously, Houthi missiles have not penetrated deep into Israeli air space, with the only one reported to have hit Israeli territory falling in an open area near the Red Sea port of Eilat in March.</p>

<p>Israel should expect more strikes in the future "as we approach the first anniversary of the Oct. 7 operation, including responding to its aggression on the city of Hodeidah," Sarea said.</p>

<p>The deputy head of the Houthi's media office, Nasruddin Amer, said in a post on X on Sunday that the missile had reached Israel after "20 missiles failed to intercept" it, describing it as the "beginning".</p>

<p>The Israeli military also said that 40 projectiles were fired towards Israel from Lebanon on Sunday and were either intercepted or landed in open areas.</p>

<p>"No injuries were reported," the military said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/o2dpp94g_houthis-strike-israel_625x300_15_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Air raid sirens had sounded in Tel Aviv and across central Israel moments before the impact]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-official-says-group-has-high-ability-to-continue-gaza-war-6573247]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hamas Official Says Group Has "High Ability" To Continue Gaza War]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-official-says-group-has-high-ability-to-continue-gaza-war-6573247]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 15 Sep 2024 23:28:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A senior Hamas official told AFP on Sunday that the Palestinian Islamist movement had ample resources to continue fighting Israel despite losses sustained over more than 11 months of war in Gaza.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A senior Hamas official told AFP on Sunday that the Palestinian Islamist movement had ample resources to continue fighting Israel despite losses sustained over more than 11 months of war in Gaza.</p>

<p>"The resistance has a high ability to continue," Osama Hamdan told AFP during an interview in Istanbul.</p>

<p>"There were martyrs and there were sacrifices... but in return there was an accumulation of experiences and the recruitment of new generations into the resistance."</p>

<p>His comments came less than a week after Israeli Defence Minister Yoav Gallant told journalists that Hamas, whose October 7 attack triggered the war, "no longer exists" as a military formation in Gaza.</p>

<p>"The number of casualties... is much less than what is expected in a battle of this size, level and breadth," Hamdan said on Sunday.</p>

<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu launched retaliatory military operations to destroy Hamas after the group's surprise attack on southern Israel, which resulted in the deaths of 1,205 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli official figures.</p>

<p>The Israeli military campaign has killed at least 41,206 people in Gaza, according to the Hamas-run territory's health ministry, which does not provide breakdowns of civilian and militant deaths.</p>

<p>Militants also seized 251 hostages on October 7, 97 of whom are still held in Gaza, including 33 the Israeli military says are dead.</p>

<p>Netanyahu is facing mounting domestic pressure to seal a deal in which hostages would be released in exchange for Palestinian prisoners.</p>

<p>Israel's announcement this month that the bodies of six hostages had been recovered from a tunnel in Gaza after they were "executed" by Hamas spurred an outpouring of grief and anger, leading to a brief general strike and large-scale demonstrations that continued in Tel Aviv and Jerusalem on Saturday night.</p>

<p>But months of negotiations aimed at securing a truce -- mediated by the United States, Egypt and Qatar -- have apparently stalled.</p>

<p>In the interview on Sunday, Hamdan said the United States, Israel's most important military backer, was not doing enough to force concessions from Netanyahu that would end the bloodshed.</p>

<p>"The American administration does not exert sufficient or appropriate pressure on the Israeli side," Hamdan said.</p>

<p>"Rather it is trying to justify the Israeli side's evasion of any commitment."</p>

<p>During two press conferences after officials announced the deaths of the six hostages earlier this month, Netanyahu said it was Hamas who refused to compromise and vowed "not to give in to pressure" on remaining sticking points.</p>

<p>He also said Israel's military campaign had killed "no less than 17,000" Hamas militants.</p>

<p><strong>Israel 'not immune'</strong></p>

<p>The war between Israel and Iran-backed Hamas has drawn in other Iran-backed groups in the Middle East, notably Lebanon-based Hezbollah and Huthi rebels in Yemen.</p>

<p>On Sunday the Huthis claimed a missile attack on central Israel that, while producing no casualties, triggered a rush to shelters and added to regional tensions.</p>

<p>Hamdan said the attack showed the limits of Israel's ability to defend itself, including its oft-touted aerial defence system.</p>

<p>"It is a message to the entire region that Israel is not an immune entity," Hamdan said.</p>

<p>"Even Israeli capabilities have limits."</p>

<p>Hamdan also reiterated Hamas's view that an attack earlier this month in which a Jordanian truck driver shot dead three Israeli guards at a border crossing underscored widespread anger at Israel in the region.</p>

<p>As for Arab leaders who have normalised diplomatic ties with Israel or are considering doing so, Hamdan said they should ask themselves how they would feel if their countries were occupied and the world stood by and watched.</p>

<p>"If you see Israel as a blessing and a gain... give them a piece of your country," he said, jokingly adding that it could be called "the new Israel".</p>

<p><strong>'Day after' planning</strong></p>

<p>Hamas has ruled Gaza since 2007, but with Israel calling for the group to be eliminated it is unclear what form it will exist in after the war.</p>

<p>Hamdan said on Sunday it was impossible to imagine a scenario in which Hamas chief Yahya Sinwar would leave the besieged territory.</p>

<p>Sinwar and other leaders "are ready to be martyred thousands of times in Palestine rather than leaving it because everything he is doing is to free Palestine," Hamdan said.</p>

<p>Hamas has demanded a complete Israeli withdrawal from Gaza, including the Philadelphi corridor, a narrow strip of land along Egypt's border that has emerged as a key sticking point in the truce talks.</p>

<p>Hamdan said that Hamas wants "joint Palestinian rule" in Gaza, adding that Hamas officials and representatives of other Palestinian factions would meet soon in Cairo to discuss their post-war vision.</p>

<p>"The day after the battle is a Palestinian day," he said.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/q399todg_osama-hamdan_625x300_15_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel-Gaza war has been going on since October 7 (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/i-hate-taylor-swift-donald-trump-after-singer-endorses-kamala-harris-6572908]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["I Hate Taylor Swift": Donald Trump After Singer Endorses Kamala Harris]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/i-hate-taylor-swift-donald-trump-after-singer-endorses-kamala-harris-6572908]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 15 Sep 2024 22:15:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The post came as a surprise, even from the provocative Donald Trump: "I HATE TAYLOR SWIFT!" the former president said on his social media platform Truth Social on Sunday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The post came as a surprise, even from the provocative Donald Trump: "I HATE TAYLOR SWIFT!" the former president said on his social media platform Truth Social on Sunday.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="The post was made at 8:14 pm." id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/8h11i18_donald-trump-taylor-swift_625x300_15_September_24.jpg?im=FitAndFill,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="The post was made at 8:14 pm." /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">The post was made at 8:14 pm.</p>
</div>

<p>Though the all-caps post came without accompanying commentary or explanation, the context was clear.</p>

<p>On Tuesday, just minutes after a debate with Vice President Kamala Harris that Republican Trump was widely seen as losing, the superstar singer/songwriter posted a message on Instagram saying she would be voting for his Democratic rival, calling Harris a "steady-handed, gifted leader."</p>

<p>Celebrity endorsements rarely carry enormous weight, but the hugely popular Swift is seen as being in a class of her own, with more than 100 million followers on social-media -- 10 million of whom "liked" her Instagram post.</p>

<p>"Going after Taylor Swift is a genuinely bad campaign strategy," said one poster on social media platform X. "Taylor doesn't get mad, she gets even."</p>

<p>It was not clear what Trump hoped to gain by attacking Swift, though he may calculate that any publicity is better than none.</p>

<p>He has been criticized, even by fellow Republicans, for his recent association with conspiracy-minded right-wing influencer Laura Loomer, who has at times joined him on his campaign plane.</p>

<p>The 31-year-old Loomer -- who has called the Sept. 11 terror attacks an "inside job" and said some recent mass shootings were staged by Democrats -- recently suggested that Swift had entered an "arranged relationship" with football star Travis Kelce "to influence the 2024 election."</p>

<p>There is no evidence to support any of those claims.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/ug7ir0q_donald-trump-debate_625x300_11_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US Presidential elections will be held in November this year (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/as-ex-abercrombie-ceo-probed-for-sex-abuse-8-more-male-models-say-metoo-bbc-report-6572324]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[As Ex-Abercrombie CEO Probed For Sex Abuse, 8 More Male Models Say #MeToo]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/as-ex-abercrombie-ceo-probed-for-sex-abuse-8-more-male-models-say-metoo-bbc-report-6572324]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 15 Sep 2024 20:20:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The former CEO of American fashion brand Abercrombie & Fitch is facing fresh allegations of abuse at sex events across the world, according to a BBC investigation.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The former CEO of American fashion brand Abercrombie &amp; Fitch is facing fresh allegations of abuse at sex events across the world, according to a BBC investigation.</p>

<p>A BBC Panorama investigation in October last year had first revealed claims that Mike Jeffries and his British partner Matthew Smith exploited young men between 2009 and 2015. A lawsuit was filed against Jeffries, Smith and Abercrombie &amp; Fitch (A&amp;F) last year, alleging "international sex trafficking and abuse of prospective models". Eight more men have now come forward to the BBC.</p>

<p>A witness said he went to a sex event in Spain with Jeffries and his partner, believing it was a photoshoot, the report said. "It was like a movie set of an Abercrombie store," he told the BBC about the event in 2011. Then aged 20, he said he was offered a chance to feature in a company advert if he flew from his home in Los Angeles to Madrid to meet the CEO of A&amp;F.</p>

<p>The night before the event, he said he was paid EUR 3,500 in cash, which he believed was general spending money for his three-day stay in Madrid.</p>

<p>On the night of the event, he was guided to their hotel suite where he said Jeffries and his partner Smith immediately started touching him and Jeffries forcibly kissed him. The former Abercrombie chief then performed oral sex on him, he said as per the BBC.</p>

<p>"I tried to say no repeatedly. And then I just got kind of convinced to do something. But I constantly was saying no, and I wanted to go," he told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cj9l9dlgpmno" rel="No follow, no index" target="_blank">the BBC</a>.</p>

<p>A middleman, who worked as a talent scout and executive assistant for Jeffries, offered him the opportunity, he added.</p>

<p>According to multiple witnesses, young men were also injected with liquid viagra by Jeffries' assistants. One man told the BBC that he felt he was "going to die" after one of these injections caused an extreme reaction during an event in New York at Jeffries' home. He said he felt hot and dizzy but nobody called an ambulance.</p>

<p>A middleman linked to the events denied any wrongdoing, adding that men participated "with their eyes wide open".<br />
In the aftermath of the BBC's report, the FBI had reportedly launched an investigation into the claims. But enforcement officials have declined to comment.</p>

<p>Jeffries, 80, who was the CEO of A&amp;F from 1992 to 2014, has denied all allegations.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-12/p8g563n8_abercrombie_625x300_06_December_23.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mike Jeffries was the CEO of Abercrombie & Fitch from 1992 to 2014. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-navys-top-meet-amid-bangladesh-crisis-chinas-aggressive-tactics-6572095]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Indian Navy's Top Meet Amid Bangladesh Crisis, China's Aggressive Tactics]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-navys-top-meet-amid-bangladesh-crisis-chinas-aggressive-tactics-6572095]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 15 Sep 2024 19:49:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The top commanders of the Indian Navy will hold a meeting to review the security situation in and around the country from Tuesday amid growing instability in the region.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The top commanders of the Indian Navy will hold a meeting to review the security situation in and around the country from Tuesday amid growing instability in the region.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The regime change in Bangladesh and an increasing influence of extremist radical groups there is one of the emerging security concerns that is expected to come up for discussion at the meeting. Another key concern is growing Chinese activities and military support to Pakistan.</p>

<p>The meeting will be held in the new Naval Headquarters in Delhi from September 17 for four days, defence officials said according to news agency ANI. It will be the first conference since Admiral Dinesh K Tripathi took over as the Chief of Naval Staff in April this year.</p>

<p>The announcement comes after Defence Minister Rajnath Singh's recent call to the defence forces to be ready for the unexpected at the Joint Commanders' Conference in Lucknow.</p>

<p>Creation of new theatre commands will also be taken up for discussion at the meeting.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Admiral has instructed all commanders to maintain high operational preparedness at all times.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Navy will also review its operations in the Gulf of Aden, where it achieved a lot of success against pirates and drone attacks early this year.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The force holds its commander's conference twice a year, where all senior officers give their inputs and presentations.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/lg7ok3to_indian-navy-maritime-exercise-ians_625x300_02_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Navy will also review its operations in the Gulf of Aden. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-sends-relief-supplies-to-typhoon-hit-myanmar-laos-and-vietnam-6571973]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India Sends Relief Supplies To Typhoon-Hit Myanmar, Laos And Vietnam]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-sends-relief-supplies-to-typhoon-hit-myanmar-laos-and-vietnam-6571973]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 15 Sep 2024 19:23:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India on Sunday sent urgent relief materials to Myanmar, Laos and Vietnam under an operation christened 'Sadbhav' to assist them in dealing with the impact of a major typhoon.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India on Sunday sent urgent relief materials to Myanmar, Laos and Vietnam under an operation christened 'Sadbhav' to assist them in dealing with the impact of a major typhoon.</p>

<p>Various parts of Myanmar, Laos and Vietnam have been reeling under massive floods after Typhoon Yagi, said to be Asia's most powerful storm this year, hit the three countries.</p>

<p>External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar said 10 tonnes of aid including dry ration, clothing and medicines were dispatched to Myanmar onboard Indian naval ship INS Satpura.</p>

<p>A military transport aircraft of the Indian Air Force is carrying 35 tonnes of aid to Vietnam and 10 tonnes of relief materials to Laos.</p>

<p>"India launches #OperationSadbhav. Demonstrating our solidarity with the people affected by Typhoon Yagi, India is dispatching aid to Myanmar, Vietnam and Laos," Jaishankar said on 'X'.</p>

<p>"10 tons of aid including dry ration, clothing and medicines left for Myanmar onboard @indiannavy INS Satpura today," he said.</p>

<p>Jaishankar added: "@IAF_MCC is carrying 35 tons of aid comprising of water purification items, water containers, blankets, kitchen utensils, solar lanterns for Vietnam." "10 tons of aid comprising genset, water purification items, hygiene supplies, mosquito nets, blankets and sleeping bags for Laos," he said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/dcsjgt1o_typhoon-yagi_625x300_10_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[10 tonnes of aid were dispatched to Myanmar, External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar said]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/its-terrifying-woman-in-china-finds-human-tooth-in-mooncake-probe-underway-6571277]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[''Terrifying'': China Woman Finds Human Tooth In Mooncake, Probe Underway]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/its-terrifying-woman-in-china-finds-human-tooth-in-mooncake-probe-underway-6571277]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 15 Sep 2024 17:16:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[She confirmed the tooth wasn't from anyone in her family and immediately reported the incident to the police.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sam's Club, a US-based supermarket chain, is facing investigation after a shocking discovery in one of its China branches. According to the <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3278480/woman-finds-human-tooth-mooncake-us-supermarket-china-leading-police-probe">South China Morning Post</a></em>, a customer was left stunned after she found a human tooth in a meat-filled mooncake purchased from the Changzhou location in Jiangsu province. A video posted on Douyin by the woman shows the unsettling find in the 30-yuan ($4) pastry.&nbsp;The disturbing footage shows a hand holding a suspected human molar, covered in meat filling, on a piece of tissue paper next to a partially consumed mooncake.&nbsp;She confirmed the tooth wasn't from anyone in her family and immediately reported the incident to the police.&nbsp;</p>

<p>''My family ate this just now... Look at what they ate. It's terrifying,'' a voice can be heard saying.</p>

<p>Sam's Club has now launched an investigation into the disturbing discovery, while the mooncake manufacturer has denied any possibility of contamination. Speaking to Hongxing News, spokesperson Liu insisted it's ''impossible'' for a tooth to be mixed into the meat filling.</p>

<p>Liu explained that the manufacturing process involves mincing meat, which is then scanned by X-ray machines designed to detect bone fragments. He emphasised that the company has a decade-long track record of incident-free production.&nbsp;The manufacturer has also handed over surveillance footage for review by Sam's Club and the Changzhou market regulatory department.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Online reactions ranged from disgust to dark humour, with one user joking, ''Mooncake: now with meat and a side of calcium!''</p>

<p>However, another user offered an alternative explanation, suggesting the customer double-check if a family member unknowingly lost a tooth. He wrote, ''It's possible to lose part of a tooth without feeling any pain, so they might not even realize it's missing.''</p>

<p>Sam's Club has faced food safety concerns in China before. In 2022, a woman from Fujian province alleged that her uncle discovered three artificial human teeth inside Swiss rolls bought from a Sam's Club store. The uncle reportedly broke his teeth after biting into the product. Although the store promised an investigation, no definitive findings were ever made public.</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/00peh2d_mooncake_625x300_15_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sam's Club has now launched an investigation into the disturbing discovery]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/french-authorities-confirm-8-migrants-died-in-channel-crossing-attempt-6570198]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[French Authorities Confirm 8 Migrants Died In Channel Crossing Attempt]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/french-authorities-confirm-8-migrants-died-in-channel-crossing-attempt-6570198]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 15 Sep 2024 14:10:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Eight migrants died early Sunday when their overcrowded vessel capsized while trying to cross the Channel from France to England, French authorities said, less than two weeks after the deadliest such disaster this year.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Eight migrants died early Sunday when their overcrowded vessel capsized while trying to cross the Channel from France to England, French authorities said, less than two weeks after the deadliest such disaster this year. &nbsp;</p>

<p>The French and British governments have sought for years to stop the flow of migrants, who pay smugglers thousands of euros per head for the passage to England from France aboard small boats.&nbsp;</p>

<p>A police source told AFP the accident occurred shortly after the boat embarked.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Regional prefect Jacques Billant is set to hold a news conference at 10:00 am (0800 GMT), his office said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Maritime authorities said Saturday that numerous attempts by migrants to make the perilous crossing in small boats have been attempted in recent days, with 200 people rescued in 24 hours over Friday and Saturday alone.&nbsp;</p>

<p>At least 12 migrants, mostly from Eritrea, died off the northern French coast when their boat carrying dozens of people capsized this month.&nbsp;</p>

<p>It was the deadliest such disaster this year, and brought to 37 the number of migrant deaths in the Channel, up from 12 in 2023.&nbsp;</p>

<p>More than 22,000 migrants have arrived in England by crossing the Channel since the beginning of this year, according to British officials.&nbsp;</p>

<p>British Prime Minister Keir Starmer and France's President Emmanuel Macron pledged this summer to strengthen "cooperation" in handling the surge in undocumented migrant numbers.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Channel crossings often prove perilous, and in November 2021, 27 migrants died when their boat capsized in the deadliest single such disaster to date.&nbsp;</p>

<p>French authorities seek to stop migrants taking to the water but do not intervene once they are afloat except for rescue purposes, citing safety concerns.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/35icm46_english-channel-migrants_625x300_23_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[More than 22,000 migrants have arrived in England by crossing the Channel in 2024 (file).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/historic-spacex-polaris-dawn-splashes-down-after-first-private-spacewalk-6570103]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Historic SpaceX Polaris Dawn Splashes Down After First Private Spacewalk]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/historic-spacex-polaris-dawn-splashes-down-after-first-private-spacewalk-6570103]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 15 Sep 2024 13:58:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[SpaceX's Polaris Dawn mission capsule splashed down off the coast of Florida early Sunday after making history when its crew conducted the first-ever spacewalk by non-government astronauts.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The SpaceX Polaris Dawn mission, which made history when its crew conducted the first spacewalk by non-government astronauts, splashed down off the coast of Florida early Sunday.</p>

<p>The Dragon spacecraft landed in the ocean at 3:37 am (0737 GMT), a webcast of the splashdown showed, with a recovery team deploying in the pre-dawn darkness to retrieve the capsule and crew.</p>

<p>The four-member team led by fintech billionaire Jared Isaacman launched Tuesday from the Kennedy Space Center, quickly journeying deeper into the cosmos than any humans in the past half century as they ventured into the dangerous Van Allen radiation belt.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Watch the <a href="https://twitter.com/PolarisProgram?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@PolarisProgram</a>'s Polaris Dawn astronauts return to Earth aboard Dragon → <a href="https://t.co/WpSw0gzeT0">https://t.co/WpSw0gzeT0</a> <a href="https://t.co/wC8cUNSBie">https://t.co/wC8cUNSBie</a></p>
— SpaceX (@SpaceX) <a href="https://twitter.com/SpaceX/status/1835202095781495050?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 15, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>They hit a peak altitude of 870 miles (1,400 kilometres) -- more than three times higher than the International Space Station and the furthest humans had ever travelled from Earth since the Apollo missions to the Moon.</p>

<p>Then on Thursday, with their Dragon spacecraft's orbit brought down to 434 miles, Isaacman swung open the hatch and climbed out into the void, gripping a structure called "Skywalker" as a breathtaking view of Earth unfolded before him.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"SpaceX, back at home we all have a lot of work to do, but from here, Earth sure looks like a perfect world," he told mission control in Hawthorne, California, where teams erupted in applause.</p>

<p>He went back inside after a few minutes and was replaced by a second astronaut, SpaceX engineer Sarah Gillis, who, like Isaacman, performed a series of mobility tests on SpaceX's sleek, next-generation suits.</p>

<p>Since Dragon doesn't have an airlock, the entire crew were exposed to the vacuum of space. Mission pilot Scott Poteet and SpaceX engineer Anna Menon remained strapped in throughout as they monitored vital support systems.</p>

<p>It marked a "giant leap forward" for the commercial space industry, said NASA chief Bill Nelson, as well as another triumphant achievement for SpaceX.</p>

<p>Though the company was only founded in 2002, it has outpaced its legacy competitors thanks in large part to founder Elon Musk's vast fortune and zeal to begin the colonization of Mars.</p>

<h3><strong>Rousing violin solo&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Since completing their extravehicular activity, the crew have continued to carry out roughly 40 science experiments -- for example inserting endoscopic cameras through their noses and into their throats to image their airways and better understand the impact of long-duration space missions on human health.</p>

<p>They also demonstrated connectivity with SpaceX's Starlink internet satellite constellation by sending back to ground control a high-resolution video of Gillis playing "Rey's Theme" by "Star Wars" composer John Williams, on the violin.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Polaris Dawn is the first of three missions under the Polaris program, a collaboration between Isaacman and SpaceX.</p>

<p>Financial terms of the partnership remain under wraps but Isaacman, the 41-year-old founder and CEO of Shift4 Payments, reportedly poured $200 million of his own money into leading the 2021 all-civilian SpaceX Inspiration4 orbital mission.</p>

<p>The final Polaris mission aims to be the first crewed flight of SpaceX's Starship, a prototype next-generation rocket that is key to Musk's interplanetary ambitions.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/hltmb42_space-x-polaris-dawn-_625x300_15_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Polaris Dawn is the first of the three missions, which are a collaboration between Isaacman and SpaceX.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/missile-fired-from-yemen-fell-into-central-israel-military-says-6570053]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Missile Fired From Yemen Fell Into Central Israel, Military Says]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/missile-fired-from-yemen-fell-into-central-israel-military-says-6570053]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 15 Sep 2024 13:49:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Israeli military said a missile fired from Yemen crossed into central Israel on Sunday, causing no injuries but again adding to regional tensions nearly a year into the Gaza war.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Israeli military said a missile fired from Yemen crossed into central Israel on Sunday, causing no injuries but again adding to regional tensions nearly a year into the Gaza war.</p>

<p>After the incident, AFP photographers saw firefighters putting out a brush fire near Lod, and saw broken glass at a train station in Modin. Both areas are southeast of Tel Aviv, Israel's commercial hub.</p>

<p>Yemen's Huthi rebels did not immediately claim the attack but are among Iran-backed groups around the Middle East that have been drawn into the conflict triggered by the October 7 attack by Hamas Palestinian militants against Israel that triggered war in the Gaza Strip.</p>

<p>In July, the Huthis claimed a drone strike that penetrated Israel's air defences and killed a civilian in Tel Aviv, at least 1,800 kilometres (1,200 miles) from Yemen.</p>

<p>In a statement on Sunday, Israel's military said "a surface-to-surface missile was identified crossing into central Israel from the East and fell in an open area. No injuries were reported."</p>

<p>"The missile was fired from Yemen," it added later.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The military said explosions "heard in the last few minutes" were from air-defence interceptors and the result of the interception was under review.</p>

<p>Yemen's Huthis have been launching attacks against Israel and its perceived interests in what they say is solidarity with Palestinians during the war between Israel and Hamas in the Gaza Strip.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The rebels are part of the "axis of resistance", which also includes Tehran-aligned militant groups in Iraq, Syria and Lebanon.</p>

<h3><strong>Deadly shipping attacks</strong></h3>

<p>Since November, the Huthis have carried out dozens of missile and drone strikes on shipping in the Gulf of Aden and the Red Sea, waterways vital to global trade.</p>

<p>Several Filipino sailors have been killed in the strikes which have led to American military retaliation against Huthi targets.</p>

<p>Huthi missiles last month hit a Greek-flagged tanker carrying more than a million barrels of crude, leaving it ablaze off the coast of the Yemeni port of Hodeida and threatening environmental disaster.&nbsp;</p>

<p>A Greek defence ministry source on Saturday told AFP that a salvage operation was underway and the Sounion vessel was being towed northward under military escort.</p>

<p>After the Huthis' deadly July attack on Tel Aviv, Israeli warplanes bombed Huthi-controlled Hodeida in response, destroying much of the facility's fuel storage capacity and killing several people, according to the rebels.</p>

<p>It was Israel's first claimed strike in Yemen.</p>

<p>A rebel official vowed at the time to "meet escalation with escalation". A Huthi statement last month affirmed "once again that the Yemeni response is definitely coming".</p>

<p>On Israel's northern flank, Lebanon's Hezbollah movement has been trading regular cross-border fire with Israeli forces in exchanges that threaten to spiral into all-out war.</p>

<p>On Sunday morning about 40 projectiles were fired from Lebanon toward Israel's Upper Galilee region and the Golan Heights, Israel's military said.</p>

<p>The hostilities have displaced tens of thousands of people in both countries from their homes near the border.</p>

<h3><strong>Israelis protest</strong></h3>

<p>Hezbollah number two Naim Qassem warned in a speech Saturday that "if Israel does unleash a war, we will face up to it -- and there will be large losses on both sides".</p>

<p>"If they think such a war would allow the 100,000 displaced people to return home... we issue this warning: prepare to deal with hundreds of thousands more displaced."</p>

<p>The cross-border violence since early October has killed 623 people in Lebanon, mostly fighters but also including at least 142 civilians, according to an AFP tally.</p>

<p>On the Israeli side, including in the Golan Heights, authorities have announced the deaths of at least 24 soldiers and 26 civilians.</p>

<p>Hezbollah has said it is acting in support of its ally Hamas in the Gaza Strip.</p>

<p>The Hamas attack which began Gaza's war resulted in the deaths of 1,205 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli official figures.</p>

<p>Militants also seized 251 captives during the attack, 97 of whom are still held in Gaza, including 33 the Israeli military says are dead.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory military campaign has killed at least 41,182 people in Gaza, according to the Hamas-run territory's health ministry, which does not provide breakdowns of civilian and militant deaths.&nbsp;</p>

<p>On Saturday thousands of people once more took to the streets of Israel's main cities in a bid to increase pressure on the government to reach a hostage release deal.</p>

<p>Months of effort by Qatari, Egyptian and US mediators have failed to secure a truce and hostage release deal. Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's government is facing rising anger from critics who accuse him of not doing enough to get the captives home.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/q653ak6_yemen-missile-israel-afp_625x300_15_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[AFP photographers saw firefighters putting out a brush fire near Lod, southeast of Tel Aviv]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/tasmanian-skull-theft-150-year-old-crime-still-dividing-a-city-6569753]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Tasmanian Skull Theft: 150-Year-Old Crime Still Dividing A City]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/tasmanian-skull-theft-150-year-old-crime-still-dividing-a-city-6569753]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 15 Sep 2024 13:25:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Over 150 years ago, surgeon and politician William Crowther allegedly stole the skull of an Aboriginal leader, William Lanne, from a Hobart morgue.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Over 150 years ago, surgeon and politician William Crowther allegedly stole the skull of an Aboriginal leader, William Lanne, from a Hobart morgue. Today, the crime continues to spark debate in the city as the statue of Crowther, once towering over a central square, lies in ruins – its feet severed by vandals.</p>

<p>In the heart of Hobart, Tasmania, the bronze monument once stood over the oak-lined square. The statue, earlier, was cut down at the ankles, leaving only severed bronze feet behind, the BBC reported. The vandalism, along with the words "what goes around" spray-painted on its base, symbolised a larger struggle – a debate about colonialism, racism and the dark history of Tasmania's treatment of its Aboriginal people.&nbsp;</p>

<p>William Crowther's notoriety stems from an event that took place over 150 years ago, when he allegedly broke into a morgue and mutilated the body of William Lanne, an Aboriginal leader. Lanne's skull was stolen and later sent overseas as a trophy, which showed the colonisers' view of Tasmanian Aboriginal people as extinct. Today, Lanne's descendants and many in the Aboriginal community see Crowther as a symbol of colonial brutality and erasure.</p>

<p>William Lanne, often referred to as the last "full-blooded" Aboriginal Tasmanian, is a symbol of the tragic history of Tasmania's Indigenous population and their mistreatment by British colonisers. Born around 1835, Lanne was part of the Palawa people, the original inhabitants of Tasmania (formerly Van Diemen's Land). Lanne was forcibly removed from his homeland and lived through two notorious camps established to confine Aboriginal people. He is remembered as a shipmate and advocate for his people.</p>

<p>William Lanne, once thought to be the last Aboriginal man in Tasmania, became the subject of scientific exploitation. He died at the age of 34 in 1869 due to disease. Before his burial in 1869, parts of his body, including his hands, feet and skull, were stolen by physicians eager to study the so-called "missing link" between humans and Neanderthals. Though Crowther denied involvement, the scandal rocked the city at the time, leading to his suspension from the hospital.</p>

<p>For Aboriginal activists, like Nala Mansell, the statue of William Crowther represented not just a man but the false narrative that Aboriginal Tasmanians were wiped out. In contrast, some Hobart residents, including Crowther's descendants, see him as a significant historical figure whose contributions should not be overshadowed by past misdeeds.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/c2lhemj8_william-crowther-statue-twitter_625x300_15_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[William Crowther's statue has divided the city of Hobart.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/worlds-top-10-most-visited-theme-parks-6569203]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[World's Top 10 Most-Visited Theme Parks]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/worlds-top-10-most-visited-theme-parks-6569203]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 15 Sep 2024 11:11:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Leading the pack, Walt Disney World's Magic Kingdom in Orlando retained its title as the most-visited theme park, drawing 17.7 million guests.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As the global tourism industry continues its recovery from the pandemic, theme parks worldwide are experiencing significant growth. The sector grew by 2.9% in 2024 and 3% in 2023, according to the World Economic Outlook Report.</p>

<p>The latest data from the Theme Index Report by the Themed Entertainment Association (TEA) and AECOM Economics &amp; Advisory highlights Disney's continued dominance in the theme park industry. Disney operates eight of the top 10 most-visited parks globally for the 2023-24 period.</p>

<p>Leading the pack, Walt Disney World's Magic Kingdom in Orlando retained its title as the most-visited theme park, drawing 17.7 million guests. Disneyland Park in Anaheim followed, with just under 17.2 million visitors. Universal Studios Japan in Osaka ranked third with 16 million attendees, while Tokyo Disneyland came fourth, hosting 15 million visitors.</p>

<p>Overall, theme park attendance surged by 23% in 2023, with over 240 million visitors, marking a notable increase from the previous year. The top 10 theme parks alone contributed significantly to this rise, with the combined total for the top 10 theme park operator groups reaching 512.3 million visitors.</p>

<p><strong>World's 10 most-visited theme parks in 2023-24:</strong><br />
&nbsp;Rank Theme Park&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; Location&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Attendance (in millions)</p>

<p>Disney's Magic Kingdom&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Orlando, Florida, USA&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; 17.7<br />
Disneyland Park&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;Anaheim&nbsp; &nbsp; California, USA&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;17.3<br />
Universal Studios Japan&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Osaka, Japan&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; 16.0<br />
Tokyo Disneyland&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; Tokyo, Japan&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;15.1<br />
Shanghai Disneyland&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; Shanghai, China&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;14.0<br />
Chimelong Ocean Kingdom&nbsp; &nbsp;Zhuhai, China&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; 12.5<br />
Tokyo DisneySea&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Tokyo, Japan&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; 12.4<br />
EPCOT&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Orlando, USA&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;12.0<br />
Paris Disneyland Park&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Marne-la-Vallee, France&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; 10.4</p>

<p>Disney's Hollywood Studios Orlando, USA&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; 10.3<br />
<br />
Chinese theme parks saw dramatic increases in attendance due to eased Covid restrictions. Chimelong Ocean Kingdom saw a 184.5% rise in visitors, Zigong Fantawild Dino Kingdom saw a 178% increase, Shanghai Disneyland experienced a 164% boost, Chimelong Paradise observed a 142% uptick, and Universal Studios Beijing saw a 109% gain.</p>

<p>In a historic first, Warner Bros. World Abu Dhabi entered the global top 25 theme parks, securing the 17th spot with 1.75 million annual visitors, underscoring the growing appeal of Middle Eastern attractions.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/8u908qao_walt-disney-world_625x300_15_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Disney operates eight of the top 10 most-visited parks globally for the 2023-24 period.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/michaela-deprince-americas-trailblazing-ballerina-dies-aged-29-6568976]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Michaela DePrince, America's Trailblazing Ballerina, Dies Aged 29]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/michaela-deprince-americas-trailblazing-ballerina-dies-aged-29-6568976]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 15 Sep 2024 10:23:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[DePrince, who rose from being an orphan in war-torn Sierra Leone to international fame, was hailed as an "unforgettable inspiration" by her family.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ballet dancer Michaela Mabinty DePrince, who moved to the United States from an orphanage in conflict-ridden Sierra Leone and graced some of the world's most prestigious stages, died aged 29. Her death was announced on her personal Instagram page by a family spokesperson, though the cause of death has not been disclosed.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Michaela touched so many lives across the world, including ours," her family shared in a statement, describing her death as "sudden." Her sister, Mia Mabinty DePrince, expressed her devastation, stating, "I am in a state of shock and deep sadness. My beautiful sister is no longer here."</p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/C_3WuKCxYQM/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C_3WuKCxYQM/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C_3WuKCxYQM/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C_3WuKCxYQM/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by Michaela Mabinty DePrince (@michaeladeprince)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p>Tributes from the ballet world and beyond have poured in, with American ballerina Misty Copeland writing, "Despite being told the 'world wasn't ready for black ballerinas,' she remained determined and made big strides." DePrince's life and career shattered barriers for dancers of colour, challenging stereotypes in the ballet community.</p>

<p>Born in 1995 in Kenema, Sierra Leone, DePrince's early life was marked by tragedy. She lost both parents during the country's civil war and was sent to an orphanage at age three, where she was mistreated due to her vitiligo. DePrince was later adopted by an American couple and moved to New Jersey, where her adoptive mother nurtured her love for ballet. She went on to become the youngest principal dancer at the Dance Theatre of Harlem and performed in Beyonce's Lemonade.</p>

<p>In 2021, she joined Boston Ballet as a second soloist and appeared in Dancing with the Stars at just 17. DePrince was also a dedicated humanitarian, advocating for children affected by conflict.</p>

<p>Her spokesperson said her artistry "touched countless hearts" and her life was defined by "grace, purpose, and strength." DePrince's legacy, they added, will continue to inspire future generations.</p>

<p>DePrince's family is also mourning the loss of their mother, Elaine DePrince, who passed away around the same time.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/vg5iqt1g_michaela-deprince_625x300_15_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[In 2021, she joined Boston Ballet as a second soloist and appeared in Dancing with the Stars at just 17.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/generative-ai-uses-more-energy-is-accelerating-climate-crisis-experts-6568924]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Generative AI Uses More Energy, Is 'Accelerating Climate Crisis' : Experts]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/generative-ai-uses-more-energy-is-accelerating-climate-crisis-experts-6568924]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 15 Sep 2024 10:12:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[If you care about the environment, think twice about using AI.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you care about the environment, think twice about using AI.</p>

<p>Generative artificial intelligence uses 30 times more energy than a traditional search engine, warns researcher Sasha Luccioni, on a mission to raise awareness about the environmental impact of the hot new technology.</p>

<p>Recognized as one of the 100 most influential people in the world of AI by the American magazine Time in 2024, the Canadian computer scientist of Russian origin has sought for several years to quantify the emissions of programs like ChatGPT or Midjourney.</p>

<p>"I find it particularly disappointing that generative AI is used to search the Internet," laments the researcher, who spoke with AFP on the sidelines of the ALL IN artificial intelligence conference, in Montreal.</p>

<p>The language models on which the programs are based require enormous computing capacities to train on billions of data points, necessitating powerful servers.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Then there's the energy used to respond to each individual user's requests.</p>

<p>Instead of simply extracting information, "like a search engine would do to find the capital of a country, for example," AI programs "generate new information," making the whole thing "much more energy-intensive," she explains.</p>

<p>According to the International Energy Agency, the combined AI and the cryptocurrency sectors consumed nearly 460 terawatt hours of electricity in 2022 -- two per cent of total global production.</p>

<h3><strong>Energy efficiency&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>A leading researcher on the impact of AI on climate, Luccioni participated in 2020 in the creation of a tool for developers to quantify the carbon footprint of running a piece of code. "CodeCarbon" has since been downloaded more than a million times.</p>

<p>Head of the climate strategy of startup Hugging Face, a platform for sharing open-access AI models, she is now working on creating a certification system for algorithms.</p>

<p>Similar to the program from the US Environmental Protection Agency that awards scores based on the energy consumption of electronic devices and appliances, it would make it possible to know an AI product's energy consumption in order to encourage users and developers to "make better decisions."</p>

<p>"We don't take into account water or rare materials," she acknowledges, "but at least we know that for a specific task, we can measure energy efficiency and say that this model has an A+, and that model has a D," she says.</p>

<h3><strong>Transparency&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>In order to develop her tool, Luccioni is experimenting with it on generative AI models that are accessible to everyone, or open source, but she would also like to do it on commercial models from Google or ChatGPT-creator OpenAI, which have been reluctant to agree.</p>

<p>Although Microsoft and Google have committed to achieving carbon neutrality by the end of the decade, the US tech giants saw their greenhouse gas emissions soar in 2023 because of AI: up 48 per cent for Google compared to 2019 and 29 per cent for Microsoft compared to 2020.</p>

<p>"We are accelerating the climate crisis," says Luccioni, calling for more transparency from tech companies.</p>

<p>The solution, she says, could come from governments that, for the moment, are "flying blindly," without knowing what is "in the data sets or how the algorithms are trained."</p>

<p>"Once we have transparency, we can start legislating."</p>

<h3><strong>'Energy sobriety'&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>It is also necessary to "explain to people what generative AI can and cannot do, and at what cost," according to Luccioni.</p>

<p>In her latest study, the researcher demonstrated that producing a high-definition image using artificial intelligence consumes as much energy as fully recharging the battery of your cell phone.</p>

<p>At a time when more and more companies want to integrate technology further into our lives -- with conversational bots and connected devices, or in online searches -- Luccioni advocates "energy sobriety."</p>

<p>The idea here is not to oppose AI, she emphasizes, but rather to choose the right tools -- and use them judiciously.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/uf7isjn8_artificial-intelligence-ai-on-climate_625x300_15_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Generative AI uses 30 times more energy than a traditional search engine, warns researcher.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/two-russian-couples-get-married-following-hindu-vedic-rituals-in-haridwar-6568882]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Watch: Two Russian Couples Get Married As Per Hindu Rituals In Haridwar]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/two-russian-couples-get-married-following-hindu-vedic-rituals-in-haridwar-6568882]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 15 Sep 2024 10:02:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The couples were dressed in traditional Indian attire, with the brides sporting mehndi (henna) designs on their hands.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Haridwar witnessed a unique celebration of love on Saturday when two Russian couples got married as per Hindu traditions. The wedding took place at the Akhand Param Dham Ashram, where the couples embraced Indian customs, including the chanting of Vedic hymns and completing seven rounds (<em>saat phere</em>) around a sacred fire, symbolising their commitment.</p>

<p>The couple, who have been married for 20 years and have three children, chose to renew their vows as per Hindu customs, a guest revealed to the news agency PTI.</p>

<p>“They have already tested their relationship and are confident they'll be together for the rest of their lives,” the guest said. “Their admiration for Indian culture inspired them to renew their vows here.”</p>

<p><iframe allow="autoplay; fullscreen" allowfullscreen="true" frameborder="0" height="281" mozallowfullscreen="true" scrolling="no" src="https://www.ndtv.com/videos/embed-player/?id=837584&amp;mute=1&amp;autostart=1&amp;mutestart=true&amp;pWidth=100&amp;pHeight=100" webkitallowfullscreen="true" width="500"></iframe></p>

<p>The wedding ceremony was conducted by the Ashram's priest, who shared insights into the growing international interest in Indian culture.</p>

<p>“Every year, we hold meditation camps here, attracting people from around the world,” he told PTI.</p>

<p>“Many come for spiritual guidance and receive mantras and blessings from Gurudev Bhagwan. Today, these two couples decided to marry as per Indian customs, so we conducted their weddings following the Vedic traditions.”</p>

<p>The couples were dressed in traditional Indian attire, with the brides sporting mehndi (<em>henna</em>) designs on their hands. Friends and family joined in the celebrations, singing and dancing. They wore flower garlands, creating a festive Indian wedding atmosphere.</p>

<p>Guests at the wedding shared how deeply moved the Russian couples were by Indian culture. A guest mentioned, “The couples wanted a bond that would last not just for one lifetime but for seven lifetimes, as they had heard that Indian weddings signify an unbreakable bond. This is why they chose to marry according to Hindu customs.”</p>

<p>This is not the first instance of Russians embracing Indian culture. In October 2023, three <a href="https://www.etvbharat.com/english/state/uttarakhand/3-russian-couples-marry-following-hindu-customs-in-haridwar/na20231005145151108108122 ">Russian couples married</a>&nbsp;in a traditional Hindu ceremony at the Akhand Paramdham Ashram in Haridwar. The couple, who were part of a 50-member Russian pilgrimage group, were impressed by Indian culture and decided to get married according to Hindu customs. The wedding ceremony included the procession of the three brides, seeking blessings from Lord Shiva, and taking seven rounds around the sacred fire. The couples wore traditional Indian attire, and the ceremony was accompanied by Hindi songs, drums and Uttarakhandi musical instruments.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/meds3v9g_russian-couples_625x300_15_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The couples were dressed in traditional Indian attire]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/albert-einsteins-1939-atomic-bomb-warning-letter-sells-for-rs-32-7-crore-6568675]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Albert Einstein's 1939 Atomic Bomb Warning Letter Sells For Rs 32.7 Crore]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/albert-einsteins-1939-atomic-bomb-warning-letter-sells-for-rs-32-7-crore-6568675]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 15 Sep 2024 09:16:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[This letter, which played a pivotal role in the development of the atomic bomb, was originally addressed to the US president.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The letter that Albert Einstein penned in 1939, urging President Roosevelt to prioritize nuclear research, sold for a staggering $3.9 million at a recent <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.christies.com/en/auction/pushing-boundaries-ingenuity-from-the-paul-g-allen-collection-30730/overview" rel="nofollow, noindex"><em>Christie's </em></a>auction. This letter, which played a pivotal role in the development of the atomic bomb, was originally addressed to the US president, highlighting the grave potential of nuclear weapons and the urgent need for American involvement.</p>

<h2><strong>A Warning That Changed History</strong></h2>

<p>The original letter, now part of the Franklin D. Roosevelt Library's collection in New York, was Einstein's attempt to warn President Roosevelt that Germany might be developing nuclear weapons. In the letter, Einstein discussed recent breakthroughs in nuclear physics, noting that uranium could become "a new and important source of energy" and warning that this energy could be harnessed to create "extremely powerful bombs."</p>

<p>Einstein, along with fellow physicist Leo Szilard, had fled Europe due to the rise of Adolf Hitler. Feeling a sense of urgency, Einstein's letter helped convince the U.S. government to expedite its research into nuclear fission, leading to the Manhattan Project and the eventual development of atomic bombs.</p>

<p>Peter Klarnet, senior specialist in Americana, books, and manuscripts at Christie's, described the letter as "one of the most influential letters in history." Written in the summer of 1939, it set the stage for the nuclear arms race and changed the course of the war and human history.</p>

<p>According to <em>Business Insider</em>, the auctioned copy was the only one in private hands, previously owned by the late Microsoft co-founder Paul Allen, who purchased it in 2002 for $2.1 million. Before that, it was part of publisher Malcolm Forbes' collection, acquired from Leo Szilard's estate.</p>

<h2><strong>Einstein's "Great Mistake"</strong></h2>

<p>Though instrumental in advancing the U.S. nuclear program, Einstein later expressed profound regret. He called his involvement in the development of nuclear weapons his "one great mistake." After the atomic bombings of Hiroshima and Nagasaki in 1945, Einstein reportedly lamented, "Woe is me," recognizing the immense human suffering caused by these weapons.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2018-10/llghespg_albert-einstein-afp_625x300_03_October_18.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Einstein's letter helped convince the U.S. government to expedite its research into nuclear fission]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/swiss-inaugurates-new-supercomputer-alps-with-emphasis-on-ai-solutions-6568277]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Swiss Inaugurates New Supercomputer Alps, With Emphasis On AI Solutions]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/swiss-inaugurates-new-supercomputer-alps-with-emphasis-on-ai-solutions-6568277]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 15 Sep 2024 07:14:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Switzerland on Saturday inaugurated its new supercomputer called Alps -- one of the world's fastest -- which it hopes will help place the country first for trustworthy artificial intelligence solutions.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Switzerland on Saturday inaugurated its new supercomputer called Alps -- one of the world's fastest -- which it hopes will help place the country first for trustworthy artificial intelligence solutions.</p>

<p>The ETH Zurich University officially inaugurated Alps at the Swiss National Supercomputing Centre (CSCS) in Lugano, southern Switzerland.</p>

<p>"Alps is an expression of our vision of a future characterised by knowledge and progress," Economy, Education and Research Minister Guy Parmelin said in a speech at the CSCS site.</p>

<p>In June, Alps was ranked as the world's sixth most powerful supercomputer. However, at the time it was not fully constructed and had only reached 60 per cent of its potential.</p>

<p>The supercomputer was developed to meet extreme data and computing scientific requirements and allows artificial intelligence to be utilised more fully.</p>

<p>It is the central part of an initiative "to position Switzerland as the world's leading hub for the development and implementation of transparent and trustworthy AI solutions", ETH Zurich said in a statement.</p>

<p>Andreas Krause, head of the AI Centre at ETH Zurich, said: "Alps makes it possible to train complex AI models for important applications, for example, in medicine and climate research."</p>

<p>The MeteoSwiss national weather service is already using the Alps to produce a higher-resolution weather prediction model that better reflects Switzerland's complex topography of mountains and valleys.</p>

<p>Parmelin said on X that the Alps would be "opening new horizons, clearing the path for the future, placing Switzerland in pole position for scientific research".</p>

<p>CSCS deputy director Michele De Lorenzi told Switzerland's Keystone-ATS news agency it would take 40,000 years for a commercial laptop to perform the operations that the Alps can do in a day.</p>

<p>The supercomputer is housed in 33 cabinets covering 116 square metres.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/4i0f2348_supercomputer-alps_625x300_15_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[In June, Alps was ranked as the world's sixth most powerful supercomputer.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-ukraine-war-russia-ukraine-exchange-206-prisoners-in-second-swap-in-2-days-6568206]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russia, Ukraine Exchange 206 Prisoners In Second Swap In 2 Days]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-ukraine-war-russia-ukraine-exchange-206-prisoners-in-second-swap-in-2-days-6568206]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 15 Sep 2024 06:52:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russia and Ukraine conducted a major exchange of 206 prisoners on Saturday, 103 apiece, in their second such swap in two days, following negotiations mediated by the United Arab Emirates, officials said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russia and Ukraine conducted a major exchange of 206 prisoners on Saturday, 103 apiece, in their second such swap in two days, following negotiations mediated by the United Arab Emirates, officials said. President Volodymyr Zelensky&nbsp;credited the release of the prisoners to his forces' recent incursion into Russia. The released Ukrainians -- 82 soldiers and privates and 21 officers -- had been held since the early months of the war, he said.</p>

<p>The Russian Defence Ministry said that the 103 Russian soldiers exchanged had been taken prisoner in the border Kursk region where Ukrainian forces launched the surprise incursion in August.</p>

<p>"Our people are home," Zelensky&nbsp;said on the Telegram messaging app. "We have successfully brought back another 103 warriors from Russian captivity to Ukraine."</p>

<p>In his nightly video address, he thanked his combat forces for their courage and the team handling the exchanges. "In particular, our operation in the Kursk region gave a necessary boost," he added.</p>

<p>Zelensky&nbsp;posted pictures of servicemen wrapped in the national blue and yellow flag, hugging each other, talking on mobile phones and posing for group photographs at an undisclosed location.</p>

<p>In his video address, he said those released included soldiers who fought to defend the city of Mariupol. The Azov brigade, which took part in the three-month defence of the port in 2022, said in a post on its Telegram channel that 23 of its men were among the captives released on Saturday.</p>

<p>The exchange was mediated by the UAE, Emirati state news agency WAM said. It was the country's eighth such mediation since the start of 2024, it said.</p>

<p>Kyiv and Moscow have frequently exchanged prisoners since Russia's invasion in February 2022, and Saturday's swap was the third since Ukraine began a cross-border incursion into Russia's Kursk region in early August.</p>

<p>Ukrainian officials have previously said Kyiv's forces had captured at least 600 Russian soldiers during the incursion, and that this would help it secure the return of captured Ukrainians.</p>

<p>Dmytro Lubinets, Ukraine's human rights ombudsman said that Kyiv had so far secured the return of 3,672 Ukrainians in 57 exchanges.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/kp95eco8_russiaukraine-war_625x300_15_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The released Ukrainians had been held since the early months of the war]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-pledges-mass-deportation-of-haitians-in-ohio-city-if-elected-6566661]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump Pledges Mass Deportation Of Haitians In Ohio City If Elected]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-pledges-mass-deportation-of-haitians-in-ohio-city-if-elected-6566661]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 14 Sep 2024 22:57:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump pledged on Friday to conduct mass deportations of Haitian immigrants from the Ohio city of Springfield, even though the majority of them are in the United States legally.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump pledged on Friday to conduct mass deportations of Haitian immigrants from the Ohio city of Springfield, even though the majority of them are in the United States legally.</p>

<p>The city for days has found itself at the center of a social media maelstrom after right-wing agitators latched onto false claims that Haitian arrivals were eating household pets.</p>

<p>"We will do large deportations in Springfield, Ohio," Trump said at a press conference at his golf resort near Los Angeles.</p>

<p>The majority of the 15,000 Haitians in Springfield are there legally. Trump's longstanding pledge to conduct mass deportations usually refers to those in the country illegally.</p>

<p>Trump did not repeat the assertion he made during Tuesday's presidential debate with Democrat Kamala Harris that immigrants were eating dogs and cats, remarks that have been widely mocked.</p>

<p>Two elementary schools were evacuated and one middle school in Springfield was closed on Friday after anonymous bomb threats were made against the community for the second day in a row, according to ABC News.</p>

<p>At the White House, President Joe Biden urged the attacks on the Haitian community to cease.</p>

<p>"It's simply wrong. There's no place in America. This has to stop - what he's doing. It has to stop," Biden said.</p>

<p>The Biden administration extended Temporary Protected Status to hundreds of thousands of Haitians in the United States in June, a decades-old program that protects legal immigrants from deportation and gives them work permits. Gang wars in Haiti have displaced over half a million people and nearly five million are facing severe food insecurity.</p>

<p>Trump has cited the tensions in Springfield as another example of the need for hardline immigration polices. The influx of Haitians has boosted the economy but also has strained social services.</p>

<p>"I'm angry about illegal Haitian migrants taking over Springfield, Ohio. You see that mess, don't you?" Trump said at a rally in Las Vegas, later on Friday.</p>

<p>"I'm angry about young American girls being raped and murdered by savage criminal aliens that come into our country very easily, but very illegally," he added later in his speech.</p>

<p>Haitian community leaders across the United States said the Republican candidate's remarks could put lives at risk and further inflame tensions in Springfield.</p>

<p>"We need help, not hate," Springfield's mayor Rob Rue told ABC News.</p>

<p>City officials say they have received no credible reports of anybody eating household animals. Karen Graves, a city spokesperson, said she was not aware of recent hate crimes targeting Haitian residents but that some had been victims of "crimes of opportunity," such as property theft.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/ug7ir0q_donald-trump-debate_625x300_11_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["We will do large deportations in Springfield, Ohio," Trump said. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>