<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 15:34:24 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/angi-angie-hicks-woman-turned-down-job-to-pursue-her-dreams-built-a-rs-10-000-crore-empire-7185960]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Woman Turned Down Job To Pursue Her Dreams, Built A Rs 10,000 Crore Empire]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/angi-angie-hicks-woman-turned-down-job-to-pursue-her-dreams-built-a-rs-10-000-crore-empire-7185960]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 14:43:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Once terrified of speaking to strangers, Hicks developed strategies to build confidence and grow Angi into a household name, now valued at $1.2 billion.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It's hard to imagine that someone afraid to speak to strangers could go on to own a billion-dollar business. But that's exactly the story of Hicks, co-founder of Angi, previously known as Angie's List.A self-described introvert, Hicks once considered talking to strangers her biggest fear. Despite this, she co-founded Angi, an online home services platform that connects millions of users with trusted professionals. Today, the company has grown into a household name, with a valuation of $1.2 billion (Rs&nbsp;9997 Crore).</p>

<p>According to CNBC, Hicks is Angi's chief customer officer, a role she's had since 2017. But when the business launched in 1995, she wore many hats-often literally walking door-to-door to recruit Angi's first customers. It was a daunting task for someone who shied away from socialising with strangers.</p>

<p>"I'm very shy," Hicks, 51, tells <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.nbcchicago.com/news/business/money-report/51-year-old-introvert-overcame-her-worst-nightmare-to-build-her-1-2-billion-company/3565916/"><em>CNBC</em></a> Make It. "Going door to door like that was my worst nightmare."&nbsp;</p>

<p>Hicks' journey is an inspiring example of overcoming personal challenges to achieve extraordinary success.</p>

<p>However, becoming an entrepreneur wasn't her first choice. A boutique consulting firm in Washington, DC, had offered a job to her with a starting salary of $40,000. She didn't opt for the job and joined her former boss on half of the pay she was offered.</p>

<p>Angi connects homeowners with local service professionals for various tasks like home repairs, cleaning, and renovations. Users can browse service providers, read reviews, request quotes, and book appointments directly through the platform.</p>

<p>As an introvert, Hicks says socialising and marketing the business didn't come naturally. But she developed strategies to become a more confident leader, like practicing her script before a daunting presentation or sales pitch and setting small, realistic goals to celebrate.</p>

<p>"If I sold one membership in a day, I was thrilled," she says. "I also learnt to tackle the hardest tasks first and save the fun tasks for later in the day, which helped me stay motivated and be more productive."</p>

<p>However, after years of persistent work, Angi's efforts paid off, and the company became well-known.</p>

<p>In the $90 billion home services sector in the United States today, Angi is a major player. Homeowners submitted almost 23 million service requests to Angi in 2023 alone, bringing in over $1.3 billion.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/r1njuj2g_angie-hicks_625x300_06_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Angie Hicks, transformed from a shy introvert into a business leader.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-behind-golds-wild-ride-this-year-7185812]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Who Is Behind Gold's Wild Ride This Year?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-behind-golds-wild-ride-this-year-7185812]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 14:24:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Gold prices have been on a rampage, hitting record after record since the beginning of the year.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Gold prices have been on a rampage, hitting record after record since the beginning of the year. The conventional wisdom has always been that gold spikes when geopolitical tensions escalate or economic uncertainty spreads-the traditional bread and butter of gold bugs. The prospect of a US soft landing and lower interest rates have also added fuel to the sparkly fire.</p>

<p>But 2024's gold rush is different from most in at least one key way. In the Bloomberg Originals mini-documentary Who Is Behind Gold's Crazy Rise? we reveal that-along with conflicts like Russia's war on Ukraine and the regional conflagration in the Middle East-something else has been driving gold prices this year.</p>

<p>It's hard to think of a safer asset than gold-a fact that hasn't been lost on central banks or consumers. One derivative of the Kremlin's botched effort to annex its neighbor has been the West's successful effort to freeze Russian assets. The move set off alarm bells around the world, spurring central banks to protect themselves. The People's Bank of China led the way, loading up on gold to diversify away from dollars.</p>

<p>But it was the Chinese people who really drove the gold train in 2024. Unsettled not only by global instability but a struggling domestic economy, the nation's massive consumer market moved to scoop up gold jewelry-and even bullion-to protect against the unknown, sending prices skyward. By October though, a funny thing was happening to the red-hot gold market. Watch Who Is Behind Gold's Crazy Rise? to find out more.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/vv59slno_gold-deposit_625x300_29_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[It was the Chinese people who really drove the gold train in 2024.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/amid-middle-east-tensions-iran-launches-heaviest-space-payload-into-orbit-7185623]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Amid Middle East Tensions, Iran Launches Heaviest Space Payload Into Orbit]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/amid-middle-east-tensions-iran-launches-heaviest-space-payload-into-orbit-7185623]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 13:59:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iran successfully launched on Friday its heaviest space payload, which includes a satellite and a space tug, using a domestically developed satellite carrier, official media reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Iran successfully launched on Friday its heaviest space payload, which includes a satellite and a space tug, using a domestically developed satellite carrier, official media reported.</p>

<p>Weighing 300 kilogrammes (660 pounds), the payload consisted of the Fakhr-1 telecommunications satellite and the Saman-1 space tug, according to state television.</p>

<p>The Saman-1 is an "orbital transmission system" designed to transport satellites from lower orbits to higher ones, as described by the Iran Space Research Center when it was unveiled in 2017.</p>

<p>The launch marks an "operational step" toward transferring satellites into higher orbits, the TV report said.</p>

<p>The system was first introduced in February 2017 at a ceremony attended by Iran's then-president, Hassan Rouhani, and was test-launched in 2022.</p>

<p>The payloads were launched using the homegrown Simorgh satellite carrier from the Imam Khomeini launch base in Semnan province.</p>

<p>Named after a mythical Iranian bird, the Simorgh is a two-stage, liquid-fuelled satellite launch vehicle developed by Iran's defence ministry.</p>

<p>In September, Iran said it successfully put the Chamran-1 research satellite into orbit using the Ghaem-100 carrier, which is produced by the Revolutionary Guards' aerospace division.</p>

<p>Western governments, including the United States, have repeatedly warned Iran against such launches, arguing technology used for satellites could be applied to ballistic missiles, potentially capable of carrying nuclear warheads.</p>

<p>Iran denies it wants nuclear weapons. It has consistently stated that its satellite and rocket launches are focused on civil and defence applications.</p>

<p>Last month, Russia launched 55 satellites, including two built by Iran -- Koswar and Hodhod -- reflecting the deepening political, economic and military relations between the two nations.</p>

<p><br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/2r55j0ko_iran-space-reuters-_625x300_06_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The payloads were launched using the homegrown Simorgh satellite carrier.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-a-dior-handbag-caused-one-of-south-koreas-biggest-political-scandals-7185360]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How A Dior Handbag Caused One Of South Korea's Biggest Political Scandals]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-a-dior-handbag-caused-one-of-south-koreas-biggest-political-scandals-7185360]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 13:45:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Amid talks of his impeachment, South Korean President Yoon Suk Yeol is battling a series of blunders, including the brief but controversial imposition of martial law, to save his political career.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Amid talks of his impeachment, South Korean President Yoon Suk Yeol is battling a series of blunders, including the brief but controversial imposition of martial law, to save his political career. Among the several incidents that have eroded his public support and shifted sentiment against the government is a luxury handbag from Dior that was given to First Lady Kim Keon Hee under questionable circumstances.</p>

<p>Although this incident took place in 2022, it came into the spotlight in November 2023 and escalated into a political storm this year, <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-12-05/south-korea-how-first-lady-s-dior-bag-uproar-shook-politics?srnd=homepage-asia">Bloomberg</a> reported.</p>

<p>While prosecutors have cleared Kim of criminal charges, the Opposition parties in South Korea claim the luxury bag was given as a bribe and have demanded an independent investigation into the matter.</p>

<p>On their behalf, both Yoon and the First Lady have denied all charges and claimed the gift was part of a “manoeuvre” to discredit them.</p>

<p>It all began after a video shot by a pastor, Choi Jae-young, showed the purchase of the Dior bag for 3 million won ($2,250 or roughly ₹1,90,000 back then).</p>

<p>Choi, who has taken a stand against the president's tough stance towards the neighbouring country, North Korea, shot the controversial video through a camera concealed on a watch.</p>

<p>In the video, he is seen walking into what looks like the office of a planning firm run by Kim and giving her a shopping bag, which apparently had the Dior bag. “Why do you keep bringing these?” Kim was heard saying in the video. She then added, "Never buy something expensive like this."</p>

<p>However, the video emerged a year later on a left-leaning political site, which usually expresses views opposed to Yoon's policies.</p>

<p>The incident soon reminded the people of the past “pay-to-play” scandals where individuals used their access to power for personal gains. Further, it started a debate over whether the First Lady brought the unwelcome publicity upon herself or was she being targeted for raising her profile.</p>

<p>In July this year, Kim was questioned by the prosecutors for nearly 12 hours in connection with the incident. After that, her lawyer told Yonhap News that the South Korean First Lady responded in a “sincere manner and told the truth.”&nbsp;</p>

<p>As a result, the prosecutors did not find any evidence of favours offered in return for the luxury bag.&nbsp; Addressing the issue, Yoon said that it stemmed from his wife not being able to cut ties with the pastor.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"It will be important to draw a clearer line to ensure that such incidents do not happen again," Yoon noted.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/h62h2s4o_south-korea-first-lady-afp-_625x300_21_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Prosecutors did not find any evidence of favours offered in return for the luxury bag.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jewish-synagogue-set-on-fire-by-masked-men-in-australias-melbourne-7185494]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Jewish Synagogue Set On Fire By Masked Men In Australia's Melbourne]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jewish-synagogue-set-on-fire-by-masked-men-in-australias-melbourne-7185494]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 13:35:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Mask-wearing arsonists set a synagogue ablaze in a pre-dawn attack Friday in the Australian city of Melbourne, police said, sparking widespread condemnation.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Mask-wearing arsonists set a synagogue ablaze in a pre-dawn attack Friday in the Australian city of Melbourne, police said, sparking widespread condemnation.</p>

<p>The fire broke out at 4:10 am (1710 GMT) in the Adass Israel Synagogue when some congregants were already inside, police said, gutting much of the building in the southeast Melbourne suburb of Ripponlea.</p>

<p>No serious injuries were reported.</p>

<p>A witness entering the synagogue for morning prayers saw "two individuals wearing masks", Detective Inspector Chris Murray of the Victorian police arson and explosive squad told reporters at the scene.</p>

<p>"They appeared to be spreading an accelerant of some type in the premises," he said.</p>

<p>The synagogue was "engulfed in flames", he added.</p>

<p>"We believe it was deliberate. We believe it has been targeted. What we don't know is why."</p>

<p>Police will increase patrols as they hunt for the arsonists, who were wearing dark clothing, he said.</p>

<p>Detectives would be looking at CCTV footage and interviewing any witnesses, Murray said.</p>

<p>Television images showed firefighters hosing down the embers through the blackened door of the single-storey building, which has a grey concrete facade.</p>

<p>A board member of the synagogue, Benjamin Klein, said a few congregants were sitting and praying inside when the fire started.</p>

<p>"They heard loud banging," Klein told AFP.</p>

<h2><strong>'Completely gutted'</strong></h2>

<p>Liquid was poured inside the synagogue and set alight, he said.</p>

<p>"If this had happened an hour later, there would have been hundreds of people inside," Klein said.</p>

<p>The congregants "ran out the back of the synagogue. One man who ran out -- his hand got burnt," he said.</p>

<p>"The fire was extensive," he told AFP.</p>

<p>"Inside is completely gutted."</p>

<p>Holy books and furniture had been destroyed, he said, vowing however that the community would "rebuild".</p>

<p>Members of the congregation formed a human chain to remove religious items from the damaged synagogue, including Torah scrolls -- one of which was brought to Australia from Germany in World War II, the Age newspaper reported.</p>

<p>Klein said the synagogue had increased security over the past 12 months amid safety concerns, without giving further details.</p>

<p>In 1995, the synagogue was damaged by a deliberately lit fire, with walls and Torah scrolls burned.</p>

<p>Klein, who was a child at the time, said he remembered standing inside the damaged synagogue with his grandfather, who he said was a Holocaust survivor.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese "unequivocally" condemned the fire and said federal police would help the state to investigate it.</p>

<p>"This violence and intimidation and destruction at a place of worship is an outrage," Albanese said in a statement.</p>

<p>"This attack has risked lives and is clearly aimed at creating fear in the community."</p>

<p>The prime minister said he had "zero tolerance" for anti-Semitism.</p>

<p>"It has absolutely no place in Australia."</p>

<h2><strong>'Fear'&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p>The war in Gaza has sparked protests from supporters of Israel and Palestinians in cities around Australia, as in much of the world.</p>

<p>Executive Council of Australian Jewry president Daniel Aghion said the community had been living in fear of such an incident since the start of the war in Gaza.</p>

<p>"This for us is just evidence of that fear," he told reporters.</p>

<p>"This is something that is the greatest manifestation of what we have been seeing and hearing in terms of threatening e-mails, threatening social media, threatening letters and all sorts of other material."</p>

<p>Hamas' October 7, 2023 attack which triggered the Gaza war resulted in the deaths of 1,208 people in Israel, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on official figures.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory offensive has killed at least 44,580 people in Gaza, mostly civilians, according to figures from the Hamas-run health ministry that the United Nations considers reliable.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/ftm19em_australia-synagogue-fire-afp-_625x300_06_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[No serious injuries were reported.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-says-youre-welcome-after-bitcoin-hits-new-all-time-high-of-100-000-7185207]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["You're Welcome", Says Trump After Bitcoin Hits New All-Time High]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-says-youre-welcome-after-bitcoin-hits-new-all-time-high-of-100-000-7185207]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 12:56:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President-elect Donald Trump on Thursday took credit for bitcoin's historic surge past $100,000, telling his social media followers "you're welcome" after the cryptocurrency jumped more than 50 percent since his election victory.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President-elect Donald Trump on Thursday took credit for bitcoin's historic surge past $100,000, telling his social media followers "you're welcome" after the cryptocurrency jumped more than 50 percent since his election victory.</p>

<p>"CONGRATULATIONS BITCOINERS!!! $100,000!!! YOU'RE WELCOME!!! Together, we will Make America Great Again!" Trump, who in September launched his own crypto platform, wrote on Truth Social.</p>

<p>Bitcoin broke $100,000 for the first time Thursday after Trump nominated cryptocurrency backer Paul Atkins to head the US securities regulator, reinforcing optimism the incoming president will deregulate the sector.</p>

<p>The digital unit has enjoyed a blistering rally since the November 5 election of Trump, who pledged to make the United States the "bitcoin and cryptocurrency capital of the world".</p>

<p>Bitcoin hit a record of $103,800.45 in Asian trading hours Thursday before dipping back to around $101,000.</p>

<p>Following Trump's remarks, it began climbing again, reaching $103,320.</p>

<p>The volatile asset has soared by around 140 percent since the turn of the year.&nbsp;</p>

<p>However, its advance had stalled in recent weeks, sitting just below $100,000 as traders awaited new catalysts before jumping in to buy.</p>

<p>That came after Trump, who takes office in January, announced Wednesday that he would nominate Atkins to take over as chair of the Securities and Exchange Commission.</p>

<p>Atkins, an SEC commissioner from 2002 to 2008, founded risk consultancy firm Patomak Global Partners in 2009, whose clients include companies in the banking, trading and cryptocurrency industries.</p>

<p>An announcement from the Trump transition team noted that Atkins had been co-chairman of the Digital Chamber of Commerce, which promotes the use of digital assets, since 2017.</p>

<p>"Paul is a proven leader for common sense regulations," Trump said in a statement that emphasised Atkins' commitment to "robust, innovative" capital markets.</p>

<p>"He also recognises that digital assets and other innovations are crucial to making America greater than ever before," Trump added.</p>

<p>- Trump's U-turn -<br />
Atkins replaces Gary Gensler, who led a crackdown on the sector after a 2022 market rout.</p>

<p>Even so, the SEC this year authorised the trading on the American market of two new financial products, allowing a wider public to buy cryptocurrencies, called ETFs (exchange-traded funds).</p>

<p>"Institutional interest and regulatory shifts are adding legitimacy, turning what once seemed like a fringe asset into a force reshaping finance," said Matt Britzman, a senior analyst at Hargreaves Lansdown.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Love it or doubt it, bitcoin's climb is rewriting the rule book for digital assets," he added.</p>

<p>Despite having once branded cryptocurrencies a "scam", Trump changed his stance and has been a major advocate of the unit during his election campaign.</p>

<p>In September, he announced that he, along with his sons and entrepreneurs, would launch a digital currency platform named World Liberty Financial.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Trump has also become close to tycoon Elon Musk, who he said would lead a new US government-efficiency group tasked with cutting federal waste.</p>

<p>Musk, a cryptocurrency fan himself, reportedly spent more than $100 million to help Trump regain the White House, repeatedly boosting his candidacy on his X social media platform.</p>

<p>Reacting on X to the news of bitcoin hitting the $100,000 mark, Musk wrote: "Wow".</p>

<p>- Integration hopes -<br />
Among measures expected with Trump at the helm is the creation of a strategic reserve of bitcoins in the United States, consisting mainly of tokens seized by the courts, which could push other countries to grant more legitimacy to the virtual currency.</p>

<p>Cryptocurrencies have made headlines since their creation, from their extreme volatility to the collapse of several industry giants, foremost among them the FTX exchange platform.</p>

<p>"It's volatile, unpredictable and is driven by speculation, none of which makes for a sleep-at-night investment," said Dan Coatsworth, an analyst at investment group AJ Bell.</p>

<p>Bitcoin was conceived in 2008 by a person or group writing under the name Satoshi Nakamoto.</p>

<p>It was pitched as a way to break free of mainstream financial institutions by establishing a decentralised platform for transactions.</p>

<p>The digital currency is created -- or "mined" -- as a reward when powerful computers solve complex problems to validate transactions made on a meddle-proof register known as the blockchain.</p>

<p>Bitcoin has long been criticised for being the currency of choice for making untraceable payments on the dark web, the hidden part of the internet used for criminal activities.</p>

<p>The asset has often come under attack for facilitating money laundering and allowing extortion through ransomware attacks.</p>

<p>In September 2021, the unit was accepted by El Salvador as legal tender, though according to a study by Central America University, in 2023, 88 percent of Salvadorans have never used it.</p>

<p>Its carbon footprint has also come under scrutiny as mining cryptocurrencies requires huge amounts of energy.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ncepoq1g_donald-trump_625x300_20_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Following Trump's remarks, it began climbing again, reaching $103,320.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-university-vice-chancellor-james-tooley-suspended-over-allegations-of-affair-with-hyderabad-woman-7185199]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK University Vice Chancellor Suspended Over Affair With Hyderabad Woman]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-university-vice-chancellor-james-tooley-suspended-over-allegations-of-affair-with-hyderabad-woman-7185199]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 12:55:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Professor James Tooley's wife accused him of having affair with a woman in Hyderabad when he was working there.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Professor James Tooley, the vice-chancellor of University of Buckingham, has been suspended due to "serious allegations", including his relationship with a woman in India. According to <em>The Telegraph</em>, the allegations have been levelled by his estranged wife Cynthia, who also accused Professor Tooley of possessing a junior air rifle. The decision was announced in an email sent to almost 4,000 staff members and students in October, the outlet further said. However, as the issue started gaining traction, senior academics accused the university of suspending Professor Tooley over his "Right-wing" views.</p>

<p>He was suspended by Mark Qualter, chair of the university council, with immediate effect on October 11. Professor's estranged wife had claimed that the academician, now 65, was in a relationship with a woman in Hyderabad while working there in his fifties, as per <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/2024/12/05/university-buckingham-vice-chancellor-ousted-anti-woke-view/" rel="noindex,nofollow"><em>The Telegraph</em> report</a>.</p>

<p>Professor Tooley held the position since 2020 and was known for his work helping to set up low-cost private schools, especially in developing countries, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cly6ry6y6nzo" rel="noindex,nofollow">the <em>BBC</em></a> said in a report.</p>

<p>But other professors at the university accused the staff of seizing upon the allegations, as it gave them opportunity to oust him.</p>

<p>One professor told <em>The Telegraph</em> on condition of anonymity: "The paradox here is that this so-called free market university appears to be populated at its high levels with people who don't believe anything of the sort. And they particularly don't seem to believe in freedom of expression and freedom of speech."</p>

<p>The professor is a staunch free speech advocate who has spoken out publicly against the "cancel culture" he claimed had taken root across British campuses. He succeeded Sir Anthony Seldon as Buckingham's vice-chancellor in 2020.</p>

<p>The university has now set up an independent investigation panel to look into the issue. A meeting of the panel was held on Wednesday in which members raised concerns about how Professor Tooley was treated, according to&nbsp;<em>The Telegraph</em>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/kbtd3r8_professor-james-tooley_625x300_06_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Professor James Tooley was suspended in October this year.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/gencast-all-about-googles-new-ai-agent-that-aces-15-day-weather-forecast-7184707]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[GenCast: All About Google's New AI Agent That Aces 15-Day Weather Forecast]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/gencast-all-about-googles-new-ai-agent-that-aces-15-day-weather-forecast-7184707]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 12:28:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Google DeepMind has introduced a new artificial intelligence tool, claiming it possesses unmatched skill and speed to devise 15-day weather forecasts.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Google DeepMind has introduced a new artificial intelligence tool, claiming it possesses unmatched skill and speed to devise 15-day weather forecasts. In their latest report in the Nature Journal, published on Wednesday, the London-based company claimed its new model could outperform best forecasts in the world meant to track deadly storms and save lives.</p>

<p>Ilan Price, the lead author of the new study and a senior research scientist at DeepMind, said their new AI agent, 'GenCast', was much faster than the traditional methods. “And it's more accurate,” he claimed.</p>

<p>The team discovered that GenCast ran circles around the company's earlier AI weather program that debuted in late 2023, featuring a reliable 10-day forecast.</p>

<p>"I'm a little bit reluctant to say it, but it's like we've made decades' worth of improvements in one year. We're seeing really, really rapid progress," said Rémi Lam, the lead scientist on the other project and was also among one of the dozen co-authors on the new study.</p>

<p>The European Center for Medium-Range Weather Forecasts is often considered the global leader in atmospheric prediction. Its projections exceed all others in accuracy during regular comparative tests.</p>

<p>The new AI program by DeepMind was tested against the centre's Ensemble Prediction System, which is utilised by 35 countries in the world to produce weather forecasts.</p>

<p>During the study, the team compared how the 15-day forecasts of both systems performed while making predictions about a designated set of 1,320 global wind speeds, temperatures and other atmospheric features.</p>

<p>The latest report claimed the new agent outperformed the centre's forecasts 97.2% of the time. This achievement, according to the authors, “helps open the next chapter in operational weather forecasting.”</p>

<p>"It's a big deal... It's an important step forward," <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/12/04/science/google-ai-weather-forecast.html">The New York Times </a>quoted Kerry Emanuel, a professor emeritus of atmospheric science at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology, as saying.</p>

<p>Dr Emanuel and six other experts had in 2019 argued that further advancing the development of reliable forecasts from 10 days to the length of 15 days would have “enormous socioeconomic benefits” as it can help people avoid the worst effects of extreme weather.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/p378ak18_gencast_625x300_06_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The latest report claimed the new agent outperformed the centre's forecasts 97.2% of the time.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ex-chile-president-michelle-bachelet-awarded-indira-gandhi-peace-prize-2024-7184996]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ex-Chile President Michelle Bachelet Awarded Indira Gandhi Peace Prize 2024]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ex-chile-president-michelle-bachelet-awarded-indira-gandhi-peace-prize-2024-7184996]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 12:25:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Michelle Bachelet, the former President of Chile and a global advocate for human rights, has been awarded the 2024 Indira Gandhi Prize for Peace, Disarmament, and Development.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Michelle Bachelet, the former President of Chile and a global advocate for human rights, has been awarded the 2024 Indira Gandhi Prize for Peace, Disarmament, and Development.</p>

<p>The announcement was made by an international jury chaired by Shivshankar Menon, former National Security Advisor and Foreign Secretary of India.</p>

<p>“The Indira Gandhi Prize for Peace, Disarmament and Development for 2024 is awarded to Her Excellency Michelle Bachelet for the example and inspiration that she is to women and men around the world of steadfastly striving for peace, gender equality, human rights, democracy and development in difficult circumstances and her contributions to India's relations with Chile,” a statement said.</p>

<p>Bachelet, whose full name is Veronica Michelle Bachelet Jeria, is celebrated worldwide for her steadfast commitment to peace, equality, and human rights. In her illustrious career, she has held key positions, including being the Founding Director of UN Women, the United Nations High Commissioner for Human Rights, and serving two terms as Chile's first female President.</p>

<p>She has consistently championed gender equality and the rights of marginalised communities, leaving an indelible impact both domestically and internationally.</p>

<p>Born on September 29, 1951, in La Cisterna, Santiago Province, Chile, Bachelet faced significant personal and political challenges during General Augusto Pinochet's dictatorship. Following her arrest, imprisonment, and torture in 1973, she went into exile in Australia and later Germany. Undeterred, she returned to Chile to contribute to its political transformation and was elected President in 2006 and again in 2014.</p>

<p>During her presidency, Bachelet introduced sweeping education and tax reforms. Her tenure also witnessed the signing of a free trade agreement between India and Chile, enhancing bilateral ties.</p>

<p>Beyond her presidency, Bachelet led global efforts to promote gender equality as the first Director of UN Women from 2010 to 2013. Later, as UN High Commissioner for Human Rights from 2018 to 2022, she vocally addressed critical global issues, including the denial of human rights in Palestine and other conflict zones.</p>

<p>Her unwavering commitment to LGBTQ rights, democracy, and progressive values has made her an inspirational figure worldwide. Despite facing criticism, she has remained a tireless advocate for peace and justice.</p>

<p>The Indira Gandhi Prize recognises Bachelet's extraordinary contributions to promoting gender equality, democracy, and development, as well as strengthening India-Chile relations. Her resilience and dedication serve as a beacon of hope for men and women across the globe.</p>

<p>--IANS</p>

<p>skp/rad</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/6tl9oveg_michelle-bachelet_625x300_06_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Michelle Bachelet is celebrated for her steadfast commitment to peace, equality, and human rights.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/23-year-old-colombian-hitwoman-arrested-for-multiple-murders-including-her-ex-boyfriend-7184470]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Colombian Hitwoman, Known As 'The Doll,' Arrested For Multiple Murders]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/23-year-old-colombian-hitwoman-arrested-for-multiple-murders-including-her-ex-boyfriend-7184470]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 12:08:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 23-year-old Colombian woman has been arrested in connection with several targeted killings, including the recent murder of her former boyfriend.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 23-year-old Colombian woman has been arrested in connection with several targeted killings, including the recent murder of her former boyfriend. Karen Julieth Ojeda Rodriguez, known to police by the alias “La Muneca,” which translates to “The Doll,” was taken into custody over her alleged involvement in several high-profile murders in the municipality of Barrancabermeja, New York Post reported.</p>

<p>These killings were said to have been carried out at the behest of the Los de la M gang, according to Spanish language outlet Libertad Digital. At the time of arrest, Rodriguez was looking forward to expanding her career. She led a small cadre of hitmen, who terrorised the region before her arrest.</p>

<p>Her arrest came after an ambush following the assassination of her ex-boyfriend on July 23 in a rural area of Colombia called Piedecuesta, the Magdalena Medio Police said.</p>

<p>According to police, Rodriguez called her ex-boyfriend, Deyvy Jesus, and beckoned him to meet and supposedly resolve a money dispute between them.</p>

<p>When Devvy moved, two bike-borne men killed him, allegedly at the behest of Rodriguez. "The Doll", along with an accomplice Paula Valentina Joya Rueda, 24,&nbsp; was arrested by police.</p>

<p>Rueda was also on the police radar and was known under the alias “Gorda Sicaria,” translating to “Fat Hitwoman”.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, another accomplice, identified as “Leopoldo,” was arrested by the police at the same time as “The Doll”. Police officials said they seized a revolver and a 9-millimeter calibre pistol at the time of arrest.</p>

<p>As of now, the police are investigating whether any of these weapons were used in the recent killings.</p>

<p>Lieutenant Colonel Mauricio Herrara of the Magdalena Medio Police said that with the arrest of 'La Muneca' and 'Leopoldo', "a period of calm has been created in the region."&nbsp;</p>

<p>"These arrests mark progress in the dismantling of criminal structures responsible for the recent homicides,” Herrara added.</p>

<p>According to the World Population Review, a case of homicide is reported every three days in Bucaramanga, Colombia, which has a total population of more than 13 lakh people.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/6q43q098_colombian-hitwoman-twitter_625x300_06_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Police officials said they seized a revolver and a 9-millimeter calibre pistol at the time of arrest.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/a-call-for-exemplary-punishment-in-bangladesh-after-attacks-on-hindus-7184837]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[After Attacks On Hindus, Bangladesh's Minority Rights Group Says This]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/a-call-for-exemplary-punishment-in-bangladesh-after-attacks-on-hindus-7184837]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 12:01:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Bangladesh Hindu Buddhist Christian Unity Council, the largest minority advocacy group in the country, has condemned the recent attacks on Hindus in the eastern Sunamganj district.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Bangladesh Hindu Buddhist Christian Unity Council, the largest minority advocacy group in the country, has condemned the recent attacks on Hindus in the eastern Sunamganj district. In a statement released on Thursday, the council recounted instances of violence and called for swift government action to hold the perpetrators accountable.</p>

<p>According to a press release from the group, violence erupted on the night of December 3. More than 100 houses and businesses belonging to the Hindu community in Manglargaon and Monigaon East Gunigram were allegedly attacked, looted, and vandalised.</p>

<p>The statement added that a temple was damaged. The council estimated the damages to exceed 1.5 million Bangladeshi taka (over Rs 10 lakh), noting that many minority villagers fled their homes out of fear.</p>

<p>The attacks reportedly stemmed from allegations against Akash Das, a 20-year-old Hindu villager accused of blasphemy for a Facebook post. Mr Das had already been arrested before the attacks unfolded.</p>

<p>"Bangladesh Hindu Buddhist Christian Oikya Parishad strongly condemns and protests such communal attacks and immediately arrests the attackers, compensates and rehabilitates the victims and the attackers", the press statement said.</p>

<p>It further demanded the government ensure "exemplary punishment" for those responsible to deter future incidents.</p>

<h2><strong>Heightened Tensions</strong></h2>

<p>These events come amid rising tensions over the treatment of minority communities in Bangladesh. The arrest of Hindu spiritual leader Chinmoy Krishna Das on sedition charges has amplified concerns. Mr Das, a spokesperson for the Bangladesh Sammilit Sanatan Jagran Jote, remains in custody despite calls from India for his release.</p>

<p>Protests have erupted outside the Bangladesh Deputy High Commission in Kolkata and other Indian cities, with political and religious groups voicing outrage.</p>

<p>In response, Bangladesh summoned Shikder Mohammad Ashrafur Rahman, its Acting Deputy High Commissioner in Kolkata, for consultations. Mr Rahman also joined the Bangladesh delegation for upcoming foreign secretary-level talks with India. The Bangladesh Assistant High Commission in Tripura, has suspended visa and consular services citing "security reasons" after protesters breached the mission's premises recently.</p>

<p>The Bangladesh foreign ministry, in turn, summoned the Indian High Commissioner in Dhaka to protest the vandalism at its Agartala mission.</p>

<h2><strong>Yunus Government's Position</strong></h2>

<p>Amid escalating criticism, Muhammad Yunus, head of Bangladesh's interim government, has sought to address the concerns of minority communities. At a meeting with religious leaders from various faiths, Yunus urged the need for accurate reporting and urged collaboration to bridge gaps between reality and media narratives.</p>

<p>"We want to establish a process for obtaining accurate information and holding perpetrators accountable," Mr Yunus said.</p>

<p>Yunus reiterated that all citizens of Bangladesh, regardless of faith, are entitled to equal rights.</p>

<p>The Hindu community in Muslim-majority Bangladesh has reportedly faced over 200 attacks across 50 districts since the fall of Sheikh Hasina's Awami League government on August 5.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/as2juek8_bangladesh-iskcon_625x300_01_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[These events come amid rising tensions over the treatment of minority communities in Bangladesh.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/harry-potters-invisibility-cloak-now-a-reality-scientists-unveil-novel-camouflage-material-7184800]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Harry Potter's Invisibility Cloak Now A Reality? Scientists Unveil Material]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/harry-potters-invisibility-cloak-now-a-reality-scientists-unveil-novel-camouflage-material-7184800]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 11:59:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The scientists added that SAP can also be used as a spray-on coating by adding polycaprolactone - a biodegradable polyester.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Taking inspiration from Harry Potter movies, Chinese scientists may have finally created the 'Cloak of Invisibility', that could make us disappear in plain sight. Researchers at China's University of Electronic Science and Technology have devised a camouflage material that adjusts its molecular composition to blend into the background -- making the wearer imperceptible to the naked eye. The details regarding the 'chameleon' material have been published in the journal <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/sciadv.ads2217" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>Science Advances</em></a>.</p>

<p>The researchers said they managed to achieve 'invisibility' through a process called self-adaptive photochromism (SAP) in which molecules rearrange themselves when exposed to certain wavelengths of light. This causes the substance to change colour and effectively become unseeable. Notably, in nature, both chameleons and octopuses rely on active camouflage to change their appearance by blending into the surroundings.</p>

<p>"Applying this technology to clothing could make an individual effectively 'invisible'," head researcher Wang Dongsheng was quoted as saying by&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3289121/scientists-china-achieve-invisibility-chameleon-colour-breakthrough?module=AI_Recommended_for_you_In-house&amp;pgtype=homepage" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>South China Morning Post (SCMP).</em></a></p>

<p>As per Wang, the SAP technology offers a simpler and more efficient way to achieve adaptive camouflage effects. Currently, most man-made systems achieve the effect using complex electronic devices, resulting in high costs and limited usability.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/feature/science-fiction-into-reality-real-life-invisibility-shield-hides-users-in-plain-sight-5367208" rel="noindex, nofollow"><strong>Also Read | "Science Fiction Into Reality": Real Life 'Invisibility Shield' Hides Users In Plain Sight</strong></a></p>

<h3><strong>How was invisibility achieved?</strong></h3>

<p>According to the study, the "SAP materials are in primary black state under dark". They spontaneously switch to another colour after being triggered by transmitted and reflected light in the background.</p>

<p>The researchers tested the material by placing a transparent container of SAP solution in coloured acrylic boxes. In turn, the SAP solution changed colour, matching the acrylic box. Next, the scientists placed a SAP solution-filled container in environments with matching colours. The solution adapted its colour to blend seamlessly with the surroundings within 30 to 80 seconds.</p>

<p>"A white light LED (10,000 lux) was used as the light source for triggering photochromism and illumination," the study added.</p>

<p>Despite the advancement, scientists are yet to mimic the entire spectrum of colour with Mr Wang hopeful of achieving the same in his future work.</p>

<p>"We have not yet fully mimicked all colours within the visible light spectrum in this work, that would be revealed in our future work. By adding more photochromic molecules to the material or adjusting its composition, we aim to achieve finer distinctions in colour, and faster changing speed."</p>

<p>The scientists added that SAP can also be used as a spray-on coating by adding polycaprolactone - a biodegradable polyester.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/9bkf4c6g_invisible-_625x300_06_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The 'invisibility' was achieved through a process called self-adaptive photochromism (SAP).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/most-mispronounced-words-of-the-year-kamala-harris-zendaya-and-more-7184401]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Most Mispronounced Words Of The Year: Kamala Harris, Zendaya And More]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/most-mispronounced-words-of-the-year-kamala-harris-zendaya-and-more-7184401]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 11:57:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Language learning platform Babbel has revealed the list of the most mispronounced words of 2024 in the United States and the United Kingdom.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Language learning platform Babbel has revealed the list of the most mispronounced words of 2024 in the United States and the United Kingdom. It features the names of several politicians, public figures, and many foreign words that entered the English lexicon, <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/12/05/world/babbel-mispronounced-words-scli-intl/index.html">CNN</a> reported.</p>

<p>One of the prominent names on the list is US Vice President Kamala Harris, who lost to Donald Trump in the November 5 presidential election. Her first name, 'Kamala', has long been a source of plenty of confusion. Babbel says it should be pronounced as "COM-a-la".</p>

<p>The pronunciation was widely discussed during the presidential campaign as well. Her great-nieces, Amara and Leela, once even took to the stage to share how to pronounce it correctly. “First you say ‘Kama,' like a comma in a sentence,” Amara said, while Leela added, "Then you say ‘La,' like ‘la-la-la-la-la'.”</p>

<p>The other name that featured on US and UK lists was Barry Keoghan. The actor appeared in films such as Bird and Bring Them Down this year, besides his role in the mini-series Masters of the Air.</p>

<p>Another dual entry that has made it to the list is the Chinese fashion brand Shein. It's to be pronounced 'SHE-in', rather than SHEEN.</p>

<p>Another notable entrant was actress Zendaya, who featured in Dune: Part Two and Challengers this year. Her name should be pronounced "zen-DAY-uh".</p>

<p>Besides them, other entries are semaglutide, which is an active ingredient in the popular weight loss drug Ozempic, pronounced as 'sem-ah-GLOO-tide' as well as music star Chappell Roan, who should be called 'CHAP-uhl ROHN'.</p>

<p>The UK list also features two words from the Swedish language. Among these are smokeless tobacco Snus, which should be pronounced as 'SNOOZ' and flygskam, the name of a movement aimed towards discouraging people from flying. It should be called 'FLEEG-skam'.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, another popular word on the list is espresso. The word became widely popular this year as Sabrina Carpenter's single, Espresso, topped the UK charts.</p>

<p>The language learning platform has now suggested it be called 'es-PRESS-oh' and not 'EX-press-oh'.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ve2sodu8_zendaya-_625x300_13_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Zendaya's name should be pronounced "zen-DAY-uh".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/professor-who-fled-gaza-teaches-trapped-students-from-canada-7184722]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Professor Who Fled Gaza Teaches Trapped Students From Canada]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/professor-who-fled-gaza-teaches-trapped-students-from-canada-7184722]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 11:48:00 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[University professor Ahmed Abu Shaban often gets up at 3:00 am in Toronto to remotely teach his students in Gaza -- motivated by loyalty to his trapped pupils, and a deep sense of guilt.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>University professor Ahmed Abu Shaban often gets up at 3:00 am in Toronto to remotely teach his students in Gaza -- motivated by loyalty to his trapped pupils, and a deep sense of guilt.</p>

<p>Shaban, an academic who fled Gaza days after October 7, 2023, said he has an obligation to students in the Palestinian Territory desperate to study in defiance of unimaginable challenges.</p>

<p>He also said he has a responsibility to help preserve higher education in Gaza, while the world is focused on the humanitarian emergency.&nbsp;</p>

<p>But the 50-year-old conceded that guilt also weighs on him.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Guilty for leaving Gaza," he told AFP. "Like we just abandoned our country, our people, our institution."</p>

<p>Shaban is still the dean of the Faculty of Agriculture and Veterinary Medicine at Al-Azhar University, which was destroyed -- along with most university buildings -- by Israeli air strikes.</p>

<p>Shaban crossed to Egypt shortly after the war began, anticipating Israel's response to the Hamas attack would be "massive," he said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Canadian contacts arranged a posting at Toronto's York University, where he is a visiting professor in the Faculty of Environmental and Urban Change.</p>

<p>In a campus office with empty book shelves and mostly bare walls, Shaban explained that he felt compelled to help make Al-Azhar operational in some form.&nbsp;</p>

<p>He wanted "to give the very clear message for the whole world: Yes, they just destroyed our infrastructure. Yes, they destroyed our buildings... but we are still alive and we will just continue," he said.</p>

<p>"This is actually a responsibility for our students, for our nation, and for our independent state in the future."</p>

<p>- Hunger to study -<br />
Shaban, who is on Al-Azhar's board, said its pre-war enrolment was 14,000 students.&nbsp;</p>

<p>When registration opened for online courses earlier this year he expected 1,000 students to join.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"We got 10,000," he said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"It was really, for me, shocking because, just imagine: you live in a tent, you have no electricity, you have no internet. You have nothing at all.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"But you still have the hope to go to sign up for online courses and to walk for five (kilometres) to get internet connection and even to communicate, to sit and study. And sometimes you risk your life even while you are searching for internet."</p>

<p>Shaban conceded his personal schedule is "stressful," as he tries to work in two time zones.&nbsp;</p>

<p>One day last month, he was up at 3:00 am to join a workshop on Gaza's food system, before an Al-Azhar board meeting at 6:00 am. He then headed to his Toronto office to prepare a guest lecture on the Gaza war.&nbsp;</p>

<p>On evenings and weekends he records and uploads lectures for his Palestinian students.</p>

<p>Shaban said the study program is flexible, given the challenges of internet access. Students watch lectures and complete assigments when they can get online. &nbsp;</p>

<p>- Star student killed -<br />
He said students in Gaza can be "angry" and "pushy": they want to know, for example, when they will able to do lab work, even though all the labs have been destroyed.</p>

<p>Shaban said he understands their frustrations.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Sometimes you feel the students are looking at us like we can do things that actually are not doable," he said. "I have to be responsive in a gentle way." &nbsp;</p>

<p>As agitated student messages pour in, Shaban said he reminds himself that he is living comfortably in a city with electricity and grocery stores stocked with food.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"(I) try just to provide them with whatever support that I can. There are many things that I cannot do," he said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Students who have died are always front of mind.</p>

<p>He recalled five engineering students killed as they gathered by an internet source to work on an assignment.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Shaban said he will never forget his "star student" Bilal al Aish, who, days before the war started, was trying to decide whether to pursue a scholarship in Germany or the American Fulbright.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"I saw the hope in his eyes, not only for his own future, but also the future of our institutions."</p>

<p>Shaban said Aish was killed by an Israeli strike early in the war.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"I got the feeling they are killing the future," the professor said. "That was really painful for me."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/cm9foito_ahmed-abu-shaban-afp_625x300_06_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Ahmed Abu Shaban said he has a responsibility to help preserve higher education in Gaza.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-nvidia-ceo-jensen-huang-one-of-the-worlds-richest-men-is-avoiding-8-billion-in-taxes-7184595]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How Nvidia CEO, One Of The World's Richest, Is Avoiding $8 Billion In Taxes]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-nvidia-ceo-jensen-huang-one-of-the-worlds-richest-men-is-avoiding-8-billion-in-taxes-7184595]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 11:29:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Jensen Huang, the 61-year-old co-founder and CEO of Nvidia, is the 10th wealthiest individual in the US with a net worth of $127 billion.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Jensen Huang, the 61-year-old co-founder and CEO of Nvidia, is the 10th wealthiest individual in the US with a net worth of $127 billion. When an estate reaches such an extraordinary valuation, federal estate taxes claim 40% of the total - potentially exceeding $50 billion. But, Huang's financial strategies indicate that he is set to pass on much of his wealth with minimal tax liability, avoiding an estimated $8 billion in taxes, according to securities and tax filings reviewed by The New York Times (NYT).</p>

<p>Huang's strategies aren't one-of-a-kind but show how the ultra-wealthy often find ways to avoid estate tax. First introduced in 1916 to limit inherited wealth, the estate tax has become less effective due to changes in laws and clever loopholes used by the rich. It has contributed little to federal tax revenue since the early 2000s. If the tax had kept up with the growth of the ultra-wealthy, it could have brought in about $120 billion last year. Instead, it generated only a small portion of that amount.</p>

<p>Daniel Hemel, a tax law professor at NYU, says that about $200 billion is passed on every year without paying estate taxes, thanks to trusts and smart financial plans. These strategies are not just clever loopholes. They are often recommended by expensive legal and financial experts who use complex tax rules, court decisions and IRS guidelines.</p>

<p>"You have an army of well-trained, brilliant people who sit there all day long, charging $1,000 an hour, thinking up ways to beat this tax," Jack Bogdanski, a professor at Lewis &amp; Clark Law School and an author, was quoted as saying by the NYT.</p>

<p>Huang's tax strategy has drawn attention for its sophistication. In 2012, he set up an irrevocable trust with 5.84 lakh shares of Nvidia, valued at $7 million at that time. This step was part of a larger scheme, known within financial circles as "I Dig It," which was first validated by the IRS in 1995. This type of trust avoids both estate and gift taxes, providing a shield for assets that appreciate after being transferred.</p>

<p>"From an estate-tax-planning perspective, it's a grand slam. He's done a magnificent job," said Jonathan Blattmachr, a trusts and estates lawyer.</p>

<p>By 2023, the value of Huang's trust holdings ballooned to over $3 billion. Without such a strategy, heirs would be subject to a tax bill exceeding $1 billion.</p>

<p>In 2016, Huang and his wife, Lori, further reduced their tax burden by establishing grantor-retained annuity trusts (GRATs). This technique allows assets to be transferred to beneficiaries free of estate tax if their value appreciates beyond the amount repaid to the grantor. The shares in these trusts have since surged, now worth over $15 billion.</p>

<p>Huang has also taken advantage of his charitable foundation, the Jen Hsun &amp; Lori Huang Foundation, through substantial donations of Nvidia shares. Such contributions provide immediate tax deductions and help reduce income and estate taxes.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/a83hk5e8_nvidia-ceo-_625x300_06_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/reviled-south-korean-president-yoon-suk-yeol-still-likely-to-survive-impeachment-7184509]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Reviled South Korean President Still Likely To Survive Impeachment]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/reviled-south-korean-president-yoon-suk-yeol-still-likely-to-survive-impeachment-7184509]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 11:11:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The conservative party of embattled South Korean President Yoon Suk Yeol faces a quandary: How do members distance themselves from an unpopular leader without handing a big win to their political opponents.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The conservative party of embattled South Korean President Yoon Suk Yeol faces a quandary: How do members distance themselves from an unpopular leader without handing a big win to their political opponents.&nbsp;</p>

<p>For now, they are trying to accomplish that by blocking Yoon's impeachment in a vote set to take place in the coming days over his imposition of martial law earlier this week, while also asking him to quit the People Power Party, or PPP.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Han Dong-hoon, the party's leader, sought to thread that needle in a meeting with colleagues on Thursday, saying he condemned Yoon's "unconstitutional martial law" while also saying he needs to think about "the hearts of my supporters as a conservative politician."</p>

<p>"As the leader of the party, I will endeavor to ensure that this impeachment is not passed to prevent the damage to the people and supporters caused by the unprepared chaos," Han said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>For the impeachment motion to be successful, the opposition Democratic Party - which controls parliament after a big win in April legislative elections - needs only eight of the 108 lawmakers in the PPP to switch sides and vote to remove Yoon. Local newspaper Donga Ilbo reported Friday that at least five members of the party are still undecided.</p>

<p>For many conservative lawmakers, it makes more sense to position themselves to win an election down the road rather than triggering an early vote next year in which they could get battered. Although Yoon is unpopular, with a 17% approval rating even before the martial law fiasco, voting him out now would only help the political fortunes of the Democratic Party and Han's main rival for the presidency, Lee Jae-myung.</p>

<p>"For lawmakers, the single most important consideration in all of this is how they can prolong their life," said Shin Yul, a political science professor at Seoul's Myongji University. "The ruling party members are weighing the pros and cons, and they'll probably think that they have more to gain by voting against impeachment this time."</p>

<p>Lee, the opposition leader, acknowledged that dynamic in an interview with Bloomberg on Thursday, saying that it may be difficult to get the votes from the ruling party this week. Still, he said the Democratic Party would continue pushing for the president's ouster even if he survives the initial impeachment motion.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"He will be impeached - the only question is whether he will be ousted the day after tomorrow, a week after, or a month or three later," Lee said.&nbsp;</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Lee Jae-myung, center, and other party members hold protest signs demanding the resignation of Yoon at the National Assembly in Seoul." id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/9qg6077_south-korea-party-members-bloomberg_625x300_06_December_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Lee Jae-myung, center, and other party members hold protest signs demanding the resignation of Yoon at the National Assembly in Seoul." /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">Lee Jae-myung, center, and other party members hold protest signs demanding the resignation of Yoon at the National Assembly in Seoul.&nbsp;<span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: Bloomberg</span></p>
</div>

<p>For the PPP, its recent history is helping to shape its decision-making. Some conservative lawmakers who supported the impeachment of former President Park Geun-hye in 2016 later suffered from a negative public image for appearing to betray her.</p>

<p>In the wake of that scandal, the conservative bloc rebranded as the PPP. Despite some internal opposition, the party recruited the outsider Yoon - a former prosecutor who helped convict Park - to help clean up its image.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Instead, the party is now looking to avoid another prolonged period in the political wilderness. While Yoon has become politically toxic, he backs a tough line on North Korea and pro-business policies that attract conservative voters.</p>

<p><strong>'I Will Take Charge'</strong></p>

<p>By blocking the initial impeachment vote, conservative lawmakers can look to appeal to their base while they work to cut ties with Yoon himself. And Han, who is also a former prosecutor and a relative political novice, can use the time to consolidate power.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Han's faction of the PPP has about 20 lawmakers, and they were among those who joined with the opposition in the early-morning hours of Wednesday to vote down the martial law order. He's now looking to convince the other members of the party, many of whom sit in the middle between him and Yoon, to move over to his camp.</p>

<p>"I met with the president yesterday, but his perception of the situation was very different from mine and the people's, and it was difficult to empathize with him," Han told his colleagues on Thursday. He asked for their support, adding: "I will take charge and take the lead to fix this situation."</p>

<p>While the left-leaning opposition leader Lee was confident that Yoon would eventually be impeached, others in his party were worried that pushing for impeachment too fast allowed the conservatives to gain momentum.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Former Democratic Party lawmaker Woo Sang-ho, who led the passage of the impeachment bill against former leader Park, told local newspaper Donga Ilbo that the opposition should've taken the time to woo conservatives and build public support for ousting Yoon.</p>

<p>"The political power has a mission to clean up the national mess and organize the country," the newspaper cited Woo as saying, referring to the opposition. "And if it treats the impeachment of the president like a political battle, it may blow this opportunity and not succeed."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/s7366vf8_south-korean-president-yoon-suk-yeol-bloomberg_625x300_06_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[People are calling for the resignation of South Korea President Yoon Suk Yeol.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bluesky-a-platform-that-looks-and-feels-a-lot-like-twitter-7184459]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bluesky, A Platform That Looks And Feels A Lot Like Twitter]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bluesky-a-platform-that-looks-and-feels-a-lot-like-twitter-7184459]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 11:05:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Created in 2019, the goal with Bluesky was to build a decentralised standard for social media that Twitter could eventually adopt.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>What would you say at Twitter's funeral?</p>

<p>That's the question my collaborators and I asked over 1,000 people on social media as part of a broader research project on Twitter migration. Responses ranged from the profane to the poetic, but one common theme was that despite its significant flaws, Twitter at its best was truly great … until it wasn't.</p>

<p>“The world is a better place for it having existed, and a better place now that it's gone.”</p>

<p>“It takes so little to destroy so much.”</p>

<p>“I will miss it for what it could be in its best moments, but I will be happy that we can finally move on to healthier spaces.”</p>

<p>For many, it was time to leave in the hopes of finding greener pastures.</p>

<p>Since Elon Musk purchased Twitter, now branded as X, in October 2022, there have been reports of mass migration from the platform, and much ink was spilled – <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://theconversation.com/mass-migration-from-twitter-is-likely-to-be-an-uphill-battle-just-ask-ex-tumblr-users-193677" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">including some by me</a>, a researcher who studies online communities – speculating where those users might land.</p>

<p>The decentralized social network Mastodon attracted a lot of early attention, gaining a significant influx of users in the months following Musk's acquisition of Twitter. In July 2023, Meta's microblogging platform Threads <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://theconversation.com/metas-threads-is-surging-but-mass-migration-from-twitter-is-likely-to-remain-an-uphill-battle-209367" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">gained 30 million users in its first day</a>. Other Twitter alternatives appeared in 2023, some of which have chugged along with relatively small user bases, while others have already shut down. But these days, all the buzz seems to be about Bluesky.</p>

<h3><strong>Looking for the familiar</strong></h3>

<p>Bluesky was created in 2019 as a research project within Twitter led by then-CEO Jack Dorsey. It eventually severed ties with Twitter and became an independent company following Musk's acquisition. The goal with Bluesky was to build a decentralized standard for social media that Twitter could eventually adopt. In that way, Bluesky is comparable to Mastodon in that they both allow for the creation of different servers that interact, and users can move their data and network between servers.</p>

<p>But what does all this mean for your experience on Bluesky? If you are confused by – or just don't care about – centralized versus decentralized social media, Bluesky won't seem very different. It looks and feels a lot like Twitter. Nearly all of Bluesky currently operates from a single server, bsky.social, which means that you don't have to choose a server when you sign up and your experience is contained there. Though Bluesky provides the option for users to host their own server and therefore store and control their own data, most users will experience what they're accustomed to on traditional, centralized social media.</p>

<p>My previous research on platform migration revealed how leaving a platform requires both a compelling reason and an immediate viable alternative. Musk's acquisition of Twitter was a compelling reason for many users, and there have been a number of policy, design and cultural changes since that have compelled even more users to jump ship.</p>

<p>As for an immediate alternative in November 2022, Mastodon had a significant head start because Bluesky hadn't launched, and when it did in February 2023 it remained invitation-only for about a year. Threads didn't launch until July 2023. Though Mastodon has a very dedicated user base, particularly among people who share a commitment to decentralization and user autonomy, there are a number of factors that have limited widespread adoption.</p>

<p>My colleagues and I found that even among those on Mastodon, knowing how to find and join a specific server was the biggest challenge, and this has been enough of a barrier to keep many people off the social network entirely. Research on the migration of “Academic Twitter,” a broad community of academics connected on Twitter, also revealed that the decentralized structure of Mastodon created challenges for community building and sustained user engagement.</p>

<h3><strong>Bluesky's moment</strong></h3>

<p>Meanwhile, the U.S. election in November seems to have been the tipping point as a compelling reason to leave for many X users, along with terms of service changes regarding AI training. And it seems that at this moment there are other different “immediate viable alternatives.”</p>

<p>Bluesky in particular saw huge growth in November, topping 20 million users, and at the time of this writing is still gaining several users per second.</p>

<p>Though media and popular attention has been focused on Bluesky, Threads, which has nearly 300 million users, saw even more new sign-ups in November than Bluesky's entire user base. Nevertheless, even Meta seems to be focused on Bluesky's surge. It has scrambled to incorporate features into Threads that are selling points of Bluesky, such as customizable feeds.</p>

<p>Perhaps Bluesky's growth is particularly impressive – and therefore threatening to Meta – because it occurred essentially by word of mouth. In contrast, Threads has an absolutely enormous advertising platform: Instagram. Not only can Threads users simply use their existing Instagram accounts, but Meta has also started pushing Threads posts to Instagram.</p>

<p>So when considering these three major Twitter alternatives – Mastodon, Bluesky and Threads – Bluesky's moment actually makes a lot of sense to me. It feels less corporate than Meta's Threads, and so it represents an alternative to Big Tech platforms controlled by billionaires. It also appeals to people who believe in the vision of decentralized social media or who want the option to control their data.</p>

<p>But at the same time, the user experience is nearly identical to familiar, traditional social media, and it addresses some of the challenges identified with Mastodon, such as the learning curve for choosing a server. A surge in creation and use of starter packs on Bluesky – curated lists of people to follow – have also accelerated the creation of community and social networks. And the sudden buzz around the platform all at once has created momentum for entire former Twitter communities, such as Academic Twitter, to partially reconstitute themselves.</p>

<h3><strong>No one site to rule them all</strong></h3>

<p>Despite my optimism for the continued growth of Bluesky, I don't think there <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://theconversation.com/mass-migration-from-twitter-is-likely-to-be-an-uphill-battle-just-ask-ex-tumblr-users-193677" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">will ever be a “new Twitter</a>.” Social media fragmentation is here to stay, and many people are very happy on Threads or Mastodon or even smaller alternatives capitalizing on the latest X exodus. And X itself has over 600 million active monthly users.</p>

<p>These platforms all provide something different, with different communities and priorities, and none will be the best option for everyone. Moreover, as Bluesky continues to grow, it will inevitably face many of the same problems that Twitter did even when the platform was perceived as being at its greatest.</p>

<p>But for those who were hoping to “move on to healthier spaces” after attending Twitter's funeral, there are multiple doors open for them.<!-- Below is The Conversation's page counter tag. Please DO NOT REMOVE. --><img alt="The Conversation" height="1" referrerpolicy="no-referrer-when-downgrade" src="https://counter.theconversation.com/content/244019/count.gif?distributor=republish-lightbox-basic" style="border: none !important; box-shadow: none !important; margin: 0 !important; max-height: 1px !important; max-width: 1px !important; min-height: 1px !important; min-width: 1px !important; opacity: 0 !important; outline: none !important; padding: 0 !important" width="1" /><!-- End of code. If you don't see any code above, please get new code from the Advanced tab after you click the republish button. The page counter does not collect any personal data. More info: https://theconversation.com/republishing-guidelines --></p>

<p><em><span>(Author:&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/casey-fiesler-1390346" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">Casey Fiesler</a>, Associate Professor of Information Science, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/university-of-colorado-boulder-733" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">University of Colorado Boulder</a>)</span></em></p>

<p><em>(This article is republished from <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://theconversation.com" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">The Conversation</a> under a Creative Commons license. Read the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://theconversation.com/bluesky-isnt-the-new-twitter-but-its-resemblance-to-the-old-one-is-drawing-millions-of-new-users-244019" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">original article</a>.)</em></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/qagomdhg_bluesky_625x300_06_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Bluesky was created in 2019 as a research project within Twitter led by then-CEO Jack Dorsey.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/notre-dames-voice-and-soul-an-8-000-pipe-organ-to-be-revived-7184381]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Notre Dame's "Voice And Soul", An 8,000-Pipe Organ, To Be 'Revived']]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/notre-dames-voice-and-soul-an-8-000-pipe-organ-to-be-revived-7184381]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 10:54:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Notre Dame's famed 8,000-pipe organ, known as the voice and soul of the beloved cathedral, will be "revived" after a five-year absence in one of the highlights of this weekend's reopening ceremony at the landmark.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Notre Dame's famed 8,000-pipe organ, known as the voice and soul of the beloved cathedral, will be "revived" after a five-year absence in one of the highlights of this weekend's reopening ceremony at the landmark.</p>

<p>The vast organ escaped the worst of a devastating 2019 blaze that destroyed Notre Dame's roof and spire, but it suffered minor water damage and was left covered with ash and a film of poisonous lead dust.</p>

<p>Workers had to dismantle it to clean its five keyboards, winch down the pipes -- some of them are almost 10 metres (32 feet) long -- and replace internal leather components.</p>

<p>The entire ensemble was re-tuned at night over a six-month period ahead of the reopening ceremony on Saturday that will be attended by incoming US president Donald Trump, among other VIPs.</p>

<p>After symbolically knocking on the door and then entering the cathedral at the start of proceedings, Paris archbishop Laurent Ulrich will call on the instrument on eight occasions, commanding it to "wake up".</p>

<p>Organist Thierry Escaich and three colleagues will be at the keyboards and stops, responding with bursts of improvised playing that will once again reverberate throughout the cleaned Gothic vaults of the 12th-century edifice.</p>

<p>"Reviving the organ is done at almost every inauguration of an organ that has been damaged or is new," he told AFP. "It's a ritual within the rituals of the church because it's often said that the organ is the soul of the church."</p>

<p>The ceremony is about "giving it new life and reintegrating it into this new cathedral with its freshness".&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Notre Dame organ can be traced back to 1733 but has undergone multiple modernisations and enlargements since then.</p>

<p><strong>'Magnificent' </strong></p>

<p>For aficionados, the organ is likely to sound slightly different given that centuries of dust have been scraped off the limestone walls of Notre Dame which are now fully exposed and cream-coloured.</p>

<p>"For the last month I've been able to come back to work with my colleagues, to try all the instruments," Escaich said, explaining that different keys of the organ correspond to the instruments of an orchestra.</p>

<p>He plans to use those representing the trumpets of the apocalypse -- a biblical story in the Book of Revelations -- during one of his improvisations.</p>

<p>"The sound has remained magnificent," he said.</p>

<p>Notre Dame's organ is the largest in France, but not the biggest in the world.</p>

<p>That title belongs to an instrument in Atlantic City in the United States which has around 33,000 pipes and underwent its own restoration in recent years.</p>

<p>Saturday's reopening ceremony for VIPs and foreign dignitaries will be followed by two religious services on Sunday.</p>

<p>The cathedral, a symbol of Paris and one of the best-known landmarks worldwide, has been restored at a cost of 700 million euros ($750 million) from public donations.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/1dn0ui8_notre-dame-reuters_625x300_06_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Notre Dame organ can be traced back to 1733.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/former-pakistan-pm-imran-khan-party-leaders-charged-in-may-9-attack-case-7184386]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Former Pakistan PM Imran Khan, Party Leaders Charged In May 9 Attack Case]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/former-pakistan-pm-imran-khan-party-leaders-charged-in-may-9-attack-case-7184386]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 10:54:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An Anti-Terrorism Court has indicted Pakistan's former Prime Minister Imran Khan and other Pakistan Tehreek-e-Insaf (PTI) leaders in connection with the May 9 attack on the General Headquarters (GHQ) in 2023.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An Anti-Terrorism Court (ATC) in Rawalpindi has indicted Pakistan's former Prime Minister Imran Khan and other Pakistan Tehreek-e-Insaf (PTI) leaders in connection with the May 9 attack on the General Headquarters (GHQ) in 2023, The Express Tribune reported.</p>

<p>The attack took place during the protests that erupted in Pakistan after Imran Khan's arrest. ATC Judge Amjad Ali Shah conducted a hearing for the GHQ attack case at a makeshift court setup in Rawalpindi's Adiala Jail.</p>

<p>More than 100 individuals, including Omar Ayub, Sheikh Rashid Shafiq, Sheikh Rashid, Omar Ayub, Raja Basharat, Zartaj Gul have been indicted in the case, according to The Express Tribune report.</p>

<p>After the judge announced his decision, opposition leader in the National Assembly, Omar Ayub, was arrested, while Punjab's former law minister Raja Basharat was taken into custody immediately after leaving the jail.</p>

<p>Subsequently, the judge adjourned the case until December 10. Earlier, several PTI leaders including Sadaqat Abbasi, Musarrat Jamshed Cheema, Mohammad Ahmed Chatha, Omar Ayub, Zartaj Gul, Rashid Shafiq, Sadaqat Abbasi, Waseem Qayyum Abbasi, Javed Kausar, Sajid Qureshi, and Usman Dar, reached Adiala Jail for the hearing.</p>

<p>The court had summoned all accused in the GHQ attack case, with charges expected to be formally brought against 120 individuals, including Imran Khan, The Express Tribune reported.</p>

<p>Furthermore, the court has ordered Pakistan's former Foreign Minister Shah Mehmood Qureshi, who is incarcerated in Lahore Jail, to appear before the court. The court ordered that arrests be made for several PTI leaders, including Khyber Pakhtunkhwa Chief Minister Ali Amin Gandapur, Shibli Faraz, Shireen Mazari, Zartaj Gul, Zain Qureshi, and Taiba Raja.</p>

<p>In addition, arrest warrants were issued for 45 absconding accused, with the court warning that legal proceedings would start to declare them fugitives if they did not appear before the court.</p>

<p>Earlier this year, PTI founder Imran Khan was arrested in the GHQ attack case, after his release warrant was issued in the cypher case. The GHQ attack case report mentions 27 severe charges against Imran Khan and other accused individuals, The Express Tribune reported.</p>

<p>The report alleges that the accused under the leadership of former Provincial Law Minister Raja Basharat stormed the GHQ gate, causing significant property damage despite being warned by military personnel to stop. The accused have been alleged of storming sensitive areas of GHQ, setting fire, throwing petrol bombs and creating chaos within the premises.</p>

<p>Chants like "No Pakistan without Khan" and "Behind this terrorism is the uniform" were allegedly raised, targeting military personnel and attacking the reputation of Pakistan's armed forces. The investigation report stated that attacks were made on sensitive ISI and GHQ offices, terming the protest as a criminal conspiracy.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/3a5hhu9_imran-khan_625x300_27_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The attack took place during the protests that erupted in Pakistan after Imran Khan's arrest. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/what-is-broken-heart-syndrome-when-stress-can-physically-shatter-your-heart-7184233]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Broken Heart Syndrome: How Stress Can Physically Weaken Your Heart]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/what-is-broken-heart-syndrome-when-stress-can-physically-shatter-your-heart-7184233]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Dec 2024 10:33:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Effective treatment involves symptom management and stress relief, while preventive measures include regular exercise, mindfulness practices, and seeking support during difficult times.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Heartbreak can be a terrible experience, but for some people, it has serious physical consequences, which is named as broken heart syndrome, also known as Takotsubo cardiomyopathy. It is a temporary heart condition brought about by extreme emotional or physical stress. It generally mimics the symptoms of a heart attack, thus making it very hard to diagnose. This condition is mainly seen on the left ventricle of the heart, and it rapidly weakens the heart muscles.</p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.health.harvard.edu/heart-health/takotsubo-cardiomyopathy-broken-heart-syndrome"><em>Harvard University, </em></a>first described in 1990 in Japan, takotsubo cardiomyopathy is a weakening of the left ventricle, the heart's main pumping chamber. The condition is usually the result of severe emotional or physical stress, such as a sudden illness, the loss of a loved one, a serious accident, or a natural disaster such as an earthquake. That's why the condition is also called stress-induced cardiomyopathy, or broken-heart syndrome.</p>

<p><strong>What Is Broken Heart Syndrome?</strong></p>

<p>According to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.mayoclinic.org/diseases-conditions/broken-heart-syndrome/symptoms-causes/syc-20354617"><em>Mayo Clinic,</em></a> broken heart syndrome is a heart condition that's often brought on by stressful situations and extreme emotions. The condition can also be triggered by a serious physical illness or surgery. Broken heart syndrome is usually temporary. But some people may continue to feel unwell after the heart is healed.</p>

<p>People with broken heart syndrome may have sudden chest pain or think they're having a heart attack. Broken heart syndrome affects just part of the heart. It briefly interrupts the way the heart pumps blood. The rest of the heart continues to work as usual. Sometimes the heart contracts more forcefully. Medicines are used to treat symptoms of broken heart syndrome.</p>

<h3><strong>Symptoms, Risks, and Recovery</strong></h3>

<p><strong>Key Symptoms:</strong></p>

<ul>
	<li>Chest pain</li>
	<li>Shortness of breath</li>
	<li>Irregular heartbeat</li>
</ul>

<p>Women over 50 face a higher risk of this condition, but experts caution that anyone enduring intense stress can develop it. This underscores the importance of effective stress management.</p>

<p><strong>Recovery and Treatment:</strong></p>

<p>Broken Heart Syndrome is a reversible condition with proper care. Recovery typically spans weeks to months, focusing on symptom relief and stress management. Doctors may prescribe beta-blockers to reduce the heart's workload and regulate stress hormones.</p>

<p><strong>Preventive Measures:</strong></p>

<p>Minimising stress is vital in preventing broken heart syndrome. Experts recommend:</p>

<ul>
	<li>Engaging in regular physical activity to boost heart health</li>
	<li>Practicing mindfulness through meditation or yoga</li>
	<li>Seeking therapy or counselling during emotionally taxing times</li>
</ul>

<p>By prioritising mental and physical well-being, individuals can reduce the risks associated with this stress-induced heart condition.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/q532dh58_broken-heart-syndrome_625x300_06_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[It mainly affects the left ventricle, weakening the heart's pumping ability.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>