<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Wed, 16 Oct 2024 12:17:02 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jemima-goldsmith-says-concerned-about-welfare-of-ex-husband-imran-khan-6800623]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Imran Khan Kept In Solitary Confinement, Literally In Dark," Says Ex-Wife]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jemima-goldsmith-says-concerned-about-welfare-of-ex-husband-imran-khan-6800623]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 16 Oct 2024 11:47:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The ex-wife of Pakistan's former prime minister Imran Khan called for his immediate release, citing "serious and concerning" reports about his treatment in prison.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The ex-wife of Pakistan's former prime minister Imran Khan on Tuesday called for his immediate release, citing "serious and concerning" reports about his treatment in prison.</p>

<p>Jemima Goldsmith said the Pakistani authorities had stopped all visits to him by his family and lawyers, postponed court hearings, and prevented him calling his two sons since early September.</p>

<p>Electricity had been cut to his cell and he was no longer allowed out at any time, while the jail cook had been sent on leave, she wrote in a lengthy post on social media platform X.</p>

<p>"He is now completely isolated, in solitary confinement, literally in the dark, with no contact with the outside world," Goldsmith, who was married to the former Pakistan cricket team captain from 1995 to 2004.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">In the last few weeks there have been serious and concerning developments regarding my sons' father, Imran Khan's treatment in prison. The Pakistan authorities have stopped all visits to him by his family and his lawyers. They have also postponed all court hearings. In addition…</p>
— Jemima Goldsmith (@Jemima_Khan) <a href="https://twitter.com/Jemima_Khan/status/1846152372466094171?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 15, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>The couple have two sons, Sulaiman and Kasim, who live in London.&nbsp;</p>

<p>A panel of UN experts in July criticised Pakistan for arbitrarily detaining Khan in breach of international law to apparently prevent him for running for political office.</p>

<p>Khan, 72, was prime minister of Pakistan from 2018 to 2022, and has been embroiled in more than 200 legal cases since he was ousted in a parliamentary no-confidence vote he claims was orchestrated by the country's powerful generals.</p>

<p>He has been detained since August last year and barred from standing for office. He has since applied to become the next chancellor of Britain's Oxford University.</p>

<p>Goldsmith said Khan's family had also been targeted, and his sisters and nephew were arrested and jailed unlawfully, while she had faced rape and death threats from her ex-husband's political opponents.</p>

<p>The release of Khan, his nephew and sisters, plus the re-establishment of contact with his sons will provide "assurance first-hand that he is well and not being mistreated", she added.</p>

<p>"I disagree with IK on many political issues," she wrote. "But this is not about politics -- it's about my children's father, his human rights &amp; international law."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/2gcamtfg_imran-khan-jemima-goldsmith_625x300_16_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Jemima Goldsmith was married to the former Pakistan cricket team captain from 1995 to 2004]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/indian-man-breaks-world-record-with-the-smallest-washing-machine-ever-6800591]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Indian Man Breaks World Record With The Smallest Washing Machine Ever]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/indian-man-breaks-world-record-with-the-smallest-washing-machine-ever-6800591]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 16 Oct 2024 11:43:00 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Indian engineer Sebin Saji has set a Guinness World Record by creating the world's smallest functioning washing machine, measuring just 1.28 by 1.32 by 1.52 inches.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sebin Saji has surprised the world with his extraordinary engineering skills by creating an offbeat gadget that a techie would not think of creating-the world's smallest functional washing machine. This little gadget measures 1.28 inches by 1.32 inches by 1.52 inches, making it smaller than a Tamagotchi digital pet, a popular handheld toy from the 1990s.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.guinnessworldrecords.com/news/2024/10/worlds-smallest-washing-machine-unveiled-in-india-is-tinier-than-a-tamagotchi"><em>Guinness World Records</em></a> acknowledged that Saji's washing machine is the tiniest ever manufactured. Despite its microsize, the washing machine functions similarly to a standard-sized one; however, it is designed for exceedingly small loads. Saji's design has received attention for its precise craftsmanship, which demonstrates the possibility of miniaturisation in engineering.</p>

<p><iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="315" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/OtUo9eLLolc?si=GqDEvE2i4ccEcOK2" title="YouTube video player" width="560"></iframe></p>

<p>According to the Guniess World Records, to qualify for the title, he had to design and assemble the washing machine and then demonstrate it could run for a full cycle: wash, rinse, and spin. He needed to use special digital callipers to measure it. Sebin is seen demonstrating his machine in a video, scooping up just a pinch of washing powder and pouring the water in before closing it up and setting it off.</p>

<p>A crowd had gathered to watch him show off his engineering skills, and applause broke out when the measurements were announced.And while it may be completely impractical for getting your washing done, it's a lot of fun. The world's smallest vacuum cleaner was also recently created in India, measuring just 0.65 cm (0.25 in) at its shortest axis.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/0lu6iu4g_guinness-world-record_625x300_16_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Despite its tiny size, the machine operates like a full-sized version.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/giant-pandas-bao-li-qing-bao-flown-to-us-from-china-aboard-panda-express-6800580]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Giant Pandas Flown To US From China Aboard 'Panda Express']]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/giant-pandas-bao-li-qing-bao-flown-to-us-from-china-aboard-panda-express-6800580]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 16 Oct 2024 11:40:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Two giant pandas arrived at the Washington zoo on Tuesday in the latest chapter in China's campaign of international "panda diplomacy."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Two giant pandas arrived at the Washington zoo on Tuesday in the latest chapter in China's campaign of international "panda diplomacy."</p>

<p>Bao Li, a male panda, and Qing Bao, a female, were flown from Chengdu to Dulles airport in Virginia aboard a FedEx Boeing 777F cargo plane dubbed the "Panda Express," the Smithsonian National Zoo said.</p>

<p>The three-year-old bears were then loaded on to trucks and taken to their new home at the zoo in the US capital.</p>

<p>"Bao Li and Qing Bao exited their crates and began exploring their new indoor enclosures, in which keepers placed ample bamboo for the bears to eat," a zoo statement said.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">ICYMI: Two "treasures" arrived at the Zoo today! Join us in welcoming giant pandas Bao Li and Qing Bao, who entered Zoo grounds shortly after 11:30 a.m. today and are settling into their new homes at the David M. Rubenstein Family Giant Panda Habitat. <a href="https://twitter.com/smithsonian?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@smithsonian</a> <a href="https://t.co/gt8OfvpPXi">pic.twitter.com/gt8OfvpPXi</a></p>
— National Zoo (@NationalZoo) <a href="https://twitter.com/NationalZoo/status/1846306384616288259?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 15, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>It said they will be quarantined for at least 30 days and will not go on public display until January 24, 2025.</p>

<p>"We're thrilled to welcome Bao Li and Qing Bao to Washington," said Brandie Smith, director of the National Zoo and Conservation Biology Institute. "Today we joyfully celebrate a new chapter of our 52-year-long giant panda breeding and conservation program."</p>

<p>Only a few of the beloved black-and-white bears remain in the United States after almost all were returned to China in recent years under pre-arranged contracts -- including all three of the National Zoo's pandas last November.</p>

<p>The lack of immediate replacements was viewed by many as a symbol of the heightened tensions between Washington and Beijing.</p>

<p>China has been using so-called "panda diplomacy" since 1972, when the first animals were sent to Washington as a gift, following US president Richard Nixon's historic visit to the Communist nation.</p>

<p>Chinese President Xi Jinping said after meeting his counterpart Joe Biden at a summit in California last November that China could send new pandas as "envoys of friendship between the Chinese and American people."</p>

<p>In August, the San Diego Zoo welcomed two new giant pandas, the first to be sent by China to the United States in 21 years.</p>

<p>Renovations have been undertaken at the National Zoo's panda habitat "to enhance the safety of the facilities and maximize space for the bears to roam," according to the zoo's website.</p>

<p>The new structures constructed for the pandas include shallow pools to allow them to bathe and bamboo stands that require the bears to mimic the foraging techniques they would use in the wild.</p>

<p>A popular Giant Panda Cam will be relaunched once the bears make their public debut in January.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/gb1o4c28_pandas-flown-from-china-to-us-_625x300_16_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[They will be quarantined for at least 30 days and will not go on public display until January 24, 2025.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/nijjar-row-why-exactly-is-a-beleaguered-trudeau-challenging-india-6800434]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: Nijjar Row: How US Backing Has Emboldened A Beleaguered Trudeau]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/nijjar-row-why-exactly-is-a-beleaguered-trudeau-challenging-india-6800434]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 16 Oct 2024 11:20:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[With two broad factors  US backing and foreign interference closely associated with the Nijjar killing, the Justin Trudeau government in Canda is making drastic and dramatic moves against India.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont">
<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/60vrnsn8_trudeau_625x300_16_October_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>

<p>Coincidents are rare in diplomacy. It may be significant to keep a note of that as the issue of the killing of Khalistan separatist Hardeep Singh Nijjar blows up between India and Canada. The timing of the allegations, each time, from Canada and the&nbsp;escalation of the row despite Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau's domestic political troubles indicate that the actions may have been carefully thought through rather than being just a diversionary tactic, which it initially appeared to be. Here's why.</p>

<h2><strong>America Has Canada's Back</strong></h2>

<p>In the latest round of allegations, Canadian foreign minister Melanie Joly said about the Nijjar killing investigation that the Royal Canadian Mounted Police (RCMP) “gathered information that established linkages between the investigation and agents of the Government of India". It was this message that the Deputy Commissioner of Federal Policing, Mark Flynn, wanted to communicate to his Indian counterpart last week. When the attempts were unsuccessful, he met with officials of the Indian government, along with National Security and Intelligence Advisor (NSIA) Nathalie Drouin and Deputy Minister of Foreign Affairs David Morrison over the weekend.</p>

<p>The Canadian government's decision to expel the diplomats has been based on the RCMP's findings and was taken within a day of the stated meeting, where the NSIA was present along with his Indian counterpart, Ajit Doval, as reported by a US publication. What explains the hurry to present the evidence to India and then immediately act on it with expulsion? Could this have been prompted because the Indian enquiry committee looking into similar allegations by the US was visiting Washington DC just a day after Canada's action?</p>

<p>Now, turn the clock back to September last year when Justin Trudeau told the Canadian Parliament that Indian government agents possibly had a hand in the killing of Hardeep Singh Nijjar outside a gurudwara in Surrey, British Columbia. Many were taken aback by the public announcement by Trudeau on a sensitive issue.</p>

<p>That Trudeau may have wanted to create a distraction from domestic issues only partly explained his action. What seemed more probable was the fact that he was possibly aware of the parallel investigations underway in the US. That Canada was sounded out by the US on the issue is now quite evident, even though what we know now is only that a Five Eyes country alerted Ottawa. Within 10 days of Trudeau's Parliament statement, the US released details of their investigations against Indian national Nikhil Gupta and an Indian government employee referred to as 'CC1' by the US Department of Justice, who plotted the foiled assassination bid on Gurpatwant Singh Pannun, another Khalistani extremist who lives in New York.</p>

<p>The unfolding of the events in September 2023 and today should give a clear sense that there is much greater coordination on this matter between the US and Canada than what meets the eye. Having America's backing on the issue can explain the steps that Canada has taken and the ones it has indicated when Joly did not rule out sanctions by saying that “everything is on the table”.</p>

<h2><b>Foreign Interference</b></h2>

<p>India has repeatedly raised the issue of&nbsp;Khalistan with Canada as a threat to its sovereignty and territorial integrity. With the killing of Nijjar, Canada is using the argument of sovereignty. The issue is also being conflated with the overarching concern over foreign interference. &nbsp;As a result, the matter has gained traction not just with the public but also politically from an otherwise adversarial opposition, the Conservatives. Pierre Poilievre said, “Any foreign interference from any country, including India, is unacceptable and must be stopped.”</p>

<p>A Parliamentary Committee report identified India as the second most significant&nbsp;foreign threat&nbsp;to Canada following China. The National Security and Intelligence Committee of Parliamentarians report said, “In addition to interference against Canadian democratic processes and institutions by the&nbsp;PRC, India and to a limited extent Pakistan, other countries, notably Iran engaged in episodic foreign interference directed towards suppressing dissidents and critics in Canada. Known as 'transnational repression,' these activities represent one of the most egregious forms of foreign interference.”</p>

<p>The issue of foreign interference could be a prickly matter for any sovereign nation but more so for Canada and the US in the recent past with their concerns about China and Russia. Hence, this issue is one that generates fear or worry, and thus has the power to mobilise both public and political opinion around India.</p>

<p>Another Five Eyes country, Australia, had earlier reported about a "nest of spies" that was discovered by the Australian Security Intelligence Organization in 2020. Australian news channel <em>ABC </em>reported that “National security and government figures have now confirmed to the ABC that India's foreign intelligence service was responsible for the 'nest of spies', and 'a number' of Indian officials were later removed from Australia by the Morrison government.”</p>

<p>With these two broad factors – US backing and foreign interference&nbsp;– closely associated with the Nijjar killing, the Justin Trudeau government is making drastic and dramatic moves, but perhaps with the knowledge that any backfire will be cushioned.</p>

<p><em>(Maha Siddiqui is a journalist who has extensively reported on public policy and global affairs.)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/sbma1ph8_trudeau_625x300_16_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/tsavo-man-eaters-centuries-old-lion-teeth-reveal-shocking-new-details-6800396]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Tsavo Man-Eaters: Centuries-Old Lion Teeth Reveal Shocking New Details]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/tsavo-man-eaters-centuries-old-lion-teeth-reveal-shocking-new-details-6800396]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 16 Oct 2024 11:14:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[This study not only identifies the specific animals the lions preyed on but also provides clues as to why they targeted humans.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In 1898, two male lions in Kenya's Tsavo region gained infamy for killing several railway workers. These two male lions spent months terrorising workers building a railroad bridge across the Tsavo River, sparking tales of "man-eaters." Recent DNA analysis of animal hairs found inside the teeth of the lions has provided some real answers to not only what they were eating but also why they began attacking humans. The research works to debunk the myths that exist around the Tsavo lions while demonstrating unusual predatory behaviours, showing under which conditions wild animals may start hunting humans.</p>

<p>Researchers from the United States and Kenya used recent breakthroughs in technology for sequencing and analysing old and degraded DNA to analyse animal hairs lodged in lion teeth.</p>

<p>In a new study, researchers report on the exact species eaten by lions.</p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.sciencealert.com/human-dna-found-in-lions-teeth-confirms-a-tragic-legend-of-history"><em>ScienceAlert, </em></a>insight like this might help us not only fact-check stories about the episode but also better understand what could drive wild predators to behave so unusually.</p>

<p>The first reports of lion attacks began in March 1898, shortly after the arrival of Lieutenant-Colonel John Henry Patterson, a British army officer and engineer overseeing the project to connect the interiors of Kenya and Uganda with a railway.</p>

<p>The British had brought in thousands of workers to build the bridge, mostly from India, housing them in camps spanning several miles, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.gutenberg.org/files/3810/3810-h/3810-h.htm">Patterson wrote.</a></p>

<p>Patterson initially doubted reports of two workers abducted by lions but was convinced weeks later when Ungan Singh, an Indian military officer accompanying him, suffered the same fate.</p>

<p>Patterson spent that night in a tree, promising to shoot the lion if it returned. He did hear "ominous roaring," he wrote, then a long silence, followed by "a great uproar and frenzied cries coming from another camp about half a mile away."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/7vp89pq_tsavo-lions_625x300_16_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[These findings could help debunk long-standing myths about the Tsavo lions.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mysterious-black-balls-spotted-at-sydney-beaches-6800203]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA['Mysterious Black Balls' Spotted At Sydney Beaches]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mysterious-black-balls-spotted-at-sydney-beaches-6800203]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 16 Oct 2024 10:48:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hundreds of mysterious black tar-like balls have washed up on two popular Sydney beaches, prompting lifeguards to close the strands to swimmers.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hundreds of mysterious black tar-like balls have washed up on two popular Sydney beaches, prompting lifeguards to close the strands to swimmers.</p>

<p>"Mysterious, black, ball-shaped debris" began appearing on Coogee Beach on Tuesday afternoon the local mayor said, leaving flummoxed Australian authorities scrambling to find out what they might be, and where they may have come from.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Black, ball-shaped debris washes ashore on Sydney's Coogee Beach prompting closure and investigation by Randwick City Council <a href="https://t.co/ktrGzxzK7v">pic.twitter.com/ktrGzxzK7v</a></p>
— 南洋辉叔 Uncle Hui (@alexcmhwee) <a href="https://twitter.com/alexcmhwee/status/1846340686322585900?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 16, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>Hundreds of golf-to-cricket-ball-sized spheres could be seen littering the coast, which is usually thronged with Sydneysiders and tourists.</p>

<p>Instead, a few seagulls wandered among the spheres, pecking and examining.</p>

<p>The balls were also spotted at nearby Gordon's Bay, an aquatic reserve popular for snorkelling and fishing, which was also closed.</p>

<p>"At this stage, it is unknown what the material is," Mayor Dylan Parker said in a social media post.</p>

<p>"However, they may be 'tar balls' which are formed when oil comes in to contact with debris and water, typically the result of oil spills or seepage."</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/pvj7hf8_mysterious-black-balls-sydney-beaches_625x300_16_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hundreds of golf-to-cricket-ball-sized spheres could be seen littering the coast.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-canada-diplomatic-row-hardeep-singh-nijjar-killing-on-nijjar-killing-us-says-wanted-to-see-india-canada-cooperate-but-6800196]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[On Nijjar Killing, US Says "Wanted To See India, Canada Cooperate But..."]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-canada-diplomatic-row-hardeep-singh-nijjar-killing-on-nijjar-killing-us-says-wanted-to-see-india-canada-cooperate-but-6800196]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 16 Oct 2024 10:46:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United States has called on India to cooperate with Canada's investigation into "extremely serious allegations" linking "agents" of the Indian government with the killing of Khalistani terrorist and Canadian citizen Hardeep Singh Nijjar.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United States has called on India to cooperate with Canada's investigation into "extremely serious allegations" linking "agents" of the Indian government with the killing of Khalistani terrorist and Canadian citizen <a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/topic/hardeep-singh-nijjar" target="_blank">Hardeep Singh Nijjar</a> in Vancouver in June last year.</p>

<p>At a press briefing in Washington, D.C. Tuesday, State Department spokesperson Matthew Miller said the US had made it clear that Canada's allegations "need to be taken seriously".</p>

<p>"When it comes to the Canadian matter, we have made clear the allegations are extremely serious. We wanted to see the Government of India cooperate with Canada... obviously they have not chosen that path," Mr Miller <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.state.gov/briefings/department-press-briefing-october-15-2024/" target="_blank">said</a> in response to a US reporter's question on 'round two' of the Delhi-Ottawa crisis.</p>

<p>The US - discreet since the row erupted in September last year - was similarly restrained Tuesday, only emphasising the need for cooperation between the two countries.</p>

<p>"I do not have any further comment beyond what the two countries have said publicly. We have urged them to cooperate and will continue to urge them to do so," Mr Miller said.</p>

<p>New Delhi has not yet responded to these comments but has repeatedly rejected the "absurd" and "motivated" allegations. Delhi has repeatedly asked for evidence and also pointed out the charges come as Mr Trudeau's popularity tanks before next year's general election.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/reject-preposterous-imputations-india-strongly-hits-back-at-canada-6785660" target="_blank">"Preposterous Imputations": Trudeau's Escalation, India's Strong Rebuttal</a></p>

<p>Meanwhile, Mr Miller also underlined the strength of India-US relations.</p>

<p>"India continues to be an incredibly strong partner. We've worked with them on a number of matters, including our shared vision for a free, open and prosperous Indo-Pacific, and, when we have concerns, we can take those concerns to them and have candid conversations..." he said.</p>

<p>The India-Canada crisis, simmering over the past 18 months, erupted in September last year after Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau accused "agents" of Delhi of being involved in killing Nijjar. He claimed "credible information" had been <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/khalistani-terrorist-hardeep-singh-nijjar-justin-trudeau-pm-narendra-modi-us-envoy-confirms-canada-received-five-eyes-intel-against-india-report-4416628" target="_blank">shared with intelligence partners, including the US</a>.</p>

<p>India, though, has said it has not been presented with evidence to back the charges.</p>

<p>The September accusation led to tension that included a fierce response from the Indian side and Prime Minister Narendra Modi, and a tit-for-tat expulsion of diplomats.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ndtv-explains-hardeep-singh-nijjar-killing-lawrence-bishnoi-gang-trade-talks-how-india-canada-relations-soured-6793249" target="_blank">Nijjar Killing, Bishnoi Gang, Trade Talks: How India-Canada Ties Soured</a></p>

<p>This week ties soured further after Royal Canadian Mounted Police said Indian government "agents" had colluded with organised criminal elements, particularly the Lawrence Bishnoi gang, to "target (Canada's) South Asian community... specifically pro-Khalistani elements".</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hardeep-singh-nijjar-killing-bishnoi-gang-canada-bishnoi-gang-linked-to-indian-government-agents-canada-cops-big-claim-6792233" target="_blank">"Bishnoi Gang Linked To Indian Government Agents": Canada Cops' Claim</a></p>

<p>That was followed by Mr Trudeau holding a press conference in which he backed the cops' charges and criticised "a fundamental error" - that India thinks it can "engage in supporting criminal activity against Canadians, here on Canadian soil".</p>

<p>"Whether it be murders or extortion or other violent acts, it is absolutely unacceptable," Mr Trudeau said, claiming also that his administration had "shared our concerns" with Delhi.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hardeep-singh-nijjar-killing-justin-trudeau-doubles-down-on-charges-after-india-canada-diplomatic-showdown-6791322" target="_blank">Trudeau Doubles Down On Charges In India-Canada Diplomatic Row</a></p>

<p>He said Canadian police had spoken to Indian government officials but been rebuffed.</p>

<p>The Canadian federal police's claims resulted by another round of diplomats being expelled from either side; this time Ottawa named India's High Commissioner, career diplomat Sanjay Kumar Verma, as a 'person of interest' in an ongoing criminal investigation and removed him.</p>

<p>A furious India retaliated by expelling Canada's acting High Commissioner, Stewart Wheeler, and five of his staff, and formally recalling Mr Verma and his staff over security concerns.</p>

<p>Nijjar - the mastermind behind banned terror outfit Khalistan Tiger Force - was on Delhi's list of 'most wanted' terrorists for multiple crimes, including the murder of Hindu priest in Punjab. Anti-terror agency NIA had offered a Rs 10 lakh reward for information leading to his capture.</p>

<p><em>NDTV is now available on WhatsApp channels. <a href="https://www.whatsapp.com/channel/0029Va4lixw7z4kcvZI9JM12">Click on the link</a> to get all the latest updates from NDTV on your chat. </em></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2018-03/pm-modi-justin-trudeau-pti_650x400_61519877647.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[India-Canada Diplomatic Ties: PM Modi and Trudeau are at odds over Canada's allegations (File).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/canadian-air-force-plane-ferries-stranded-air-india-passengers-from-iqaluit-airport-to-chicago-6800180]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Air India's Latest Update Day After Hoax Call Grounded Its Jet In Canada]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/canadian-air-force-plane-ferries-stranded-air-india-passengers-from-iqaluit-airport-to-chicago-6800180]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 16 Oct 2024 10:41:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Canadian Air Force aircraft is ferrying 191 stranded passengers of an Air India flight from Iqaluit airport to Chicago, more than 18 hours after the flight was diverted to the airport due to a bomb threat.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Canadian Air Force aircraft is ferrying 191 stranded passengers of an&nbsp;Air India flight from Iqaluit airport to Chicago on Wednesday, a day after the flight was diverted to the airport owing to a bomb threat.</p>

<p>The aircraft departed from Iqaluit at 3.54 am UTC (9.30 am IST) and is expected to land in Chicago at around 7.48 am UTC (1.15 pm IST).&nbsp;&nbsp;Air&nbsp;India's Boeing 777-300 ER aircraft enroute to Chicago from Delhi was <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/air-india-delhi-chicago-diverted-to-canada-after-online-security-threat-6795199">diverted to the Canadian airport</a> following a bomb threat on Tuesday. It had&nbsp;211 people, including 20 crew members.</p>

<p>At least 10 Indian flights have received hoax bomb threats in the last 48 hours, an issue over which a Parliamentary Standing Committee and the Ministry of Civil Aviation will meet at 11 am.</p>

<p>Apart from the&nbsp;Air India Delhi-Chicago flight, the Dammam-Lucknow IndiGo flight, Ayodhya-Bengaluru Air India Express, a SpiceJet flight from Darbhanga to Mumbai (SG116), an Akasa Air flight from Bagdogra to Bengaluru (QP 1373) an Alliance Air Amritsar-Dehradun-Delhi flight (9I 650) and an Air India Express flight (IX 684) from Madurai to Singapore also received bomb threats on Tuesday.</p>

<p>On Monday,&nbsp;two IndiGo and one Air India flight received hoax threats.&nbsp;These included an Air India flight AI119 from Mumbai to New York's JFK Airport, and IndiGo flight 6E1275 bound for Muscat, and flight 6E56 heading to Jeddah.</p>

<p>The fake bomb threats were made from an unverified X handle and the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/investigating-aviation-body-after-bomb-threats-to-6-flights-in-36-hours-6796027">Bureau of Civil Aviation Security</a> (BCAS) is investigating the matter.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/ekji6veg_air-india-generic_625x300_07_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/canada-marine-protection-plan-aims-to-serve-as-global-model-6800082]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Canada Marine Protection Plan Aims To Serve As Global Model]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/canada-marine-protection-plan-aims-to-serve-as-global-model-6800082]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 16 Oct 2024 10:23:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Viewed from above, Canada's newest Marine Protected Area (MPA) is deceptively simple: stretches of blue Pacific Ocean waters and a few patches of green forest.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Viewed from above, Canada's newest Marine Protected Area (MPA) is deceptively simple: stretches of blue Pacific Ocean waters and a few patches of green forest.</p>

<p>But beneath the surface of the area known as the Great Bear Sea, off Vancouver Island, lies an area so rich in biodiversity it has been dubbed the "Galapagos of the North." It may also serve as a model for how to protect marine life elsewhere.</p>

<p>In July, the federal government took an unprecedented step, designating an area roughly as large as Greece an MPA. Previously, protected areas were significantly smaller in size.</p>

<p>The step followed years of consultation and aimed to pioneer a new model of holistic protection, which would see marine populations shielded from a variety of harmful activities across an enormous stretch of ocean, hopefully allowing them to replenish and thrive.</p>

<p>Crucially, the talks also involved a new approach to collaboration.</p>

<p>In addition to the government, fishing industry representatives and the indigenous communities who rely on the area's resources for their livelihoods worked together to develop a protection scheme that balances various interests.</p>

<p>"I am optimistic that we are going to be able to be a model for any future initiatives" on marine protection, said Danielle Shaw, chief of the Wuikinuxv nation, one of the indigenous communities in the area.</p>

<p>The UN COP Biodiversity Conference known as COP-16 opens in Cali, Colombia next week.</p>

<p>At the last conference, COP-15 held in Montreal in 2022, nations agreed to protect 30 percent of the seas by 2030, but there was no clear definition of what amounts to a protected area -- an uncertainty the Canadian model aims to help address.</p>

<p><strong>'Species at risk'</strong></p>

<p>Around the Great Bear Sea, overfishing, pollution and warming waters caused by climate change have altered the area substantially.</p>

<p>Shaw told AFP that "recently there's been some years where we've had to close (fishing) all together for our own people," in order to protect vulnerable fish populations.</p>

<p>That is devastating for the remote community as it means "people haven't been able to stock up their shelves and their freezers for the winter," she said.</p>

<p>The area newly designated for official protection includes 64 species of fish, 70 seabird species, as well as whales, bears, wolves and ancient cedar forest. The seafloor also counts more than 47 underwater mountains, or seamounts.</p>

<p>"It's home to really unique ecosystems and species, but also there are species that are at risk," said Kate MacMillan, conservation director for the ocean program at the Canadian Parks and Wilderness Society - British Columbia.</p>

<p>Federal MPA guidelines aim to put a variety of new restrictions on the activities allowed across a vast marine area, including prohibitions on oil and gas exploration, mineral exploitation, waste disposal and the use of dredging gear, among others.</p>

<p>MacMillan described the MPA model as "an important tool," but warned it is not "a silver bullet."</p>

<p>"They don't stop everything. They won't solve every threat," she said.</p>

<p>Those threats are set to persist, especially with the region of British Columbia surrounding the MPA seeing an increase of maritime traffic, including shipments of liquefied natural gas.</p>

<p>Enforcement remains a challenge and the Canadian model aims to involve First Nations in monitoring potential violations, even if they won't have enforcement power.</p>

<p><strong>'We have no choice'</strong></p>

<p>Bo Owadi, a member of the Wuikinuxv nation, said she spends most of her days on the water and is among those who will be working with police and researchers to document misconduct to assess the health of marine life.</p>

<p>She said her generation has "an ingrained sense of responsibility to take care of the land," and that joining forces with the government and others was inevitable.</p>

<p>"We have to come together," she told AFP. "We have no choice."</p>

<p>Chief Shaw agreed that collaborating on protection efforts, including by weighing the economic considerations of the fishing industry, could help foster more durable support.</p>

<p>"The hope is, in the long term, a stronger ecosystem means more food sources for humans and also the stronger economy," she said.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/pk1svq48_canada-river_625x300_16_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[In July, the federal government designated an area roughly as large as Greece an Marine Protected Area.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/lufthansa-fined-record-4-million-for-barring-jewish-passengers-6800029]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Lufthansa Fined 'Record' $4 Million For Barring Jewish Passengers]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/lufthansa-fined-record-4-million-for-barring-jewish-passengers-6800029]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 16 Oct 2024 10:17:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[128 Jewish passengers were denied boarding to a connecting flight after a few did not follow instructions, including anti-Covid mask requirements, on a flight from the US to Germany, US transport authorities said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US authorities have hit Lufthansa with a record $4 million penalty after finding the airline discriminated against over 100 Jewish travelers by blocking them from boarding a flight in 2022, officials said Tuesday.</p>

<p>The 128 passengers were denied boarding to a connecting flight after a few did not follow instructions, including anti-Covid mask requirements, on a flight from the United States to Germany, US transport authorities said.</p>

<p>The airline did not immediately reply to an AFP request for comment.</p>

<p>The US Department of Transportation said the penalty over the boarding refusal on May 3, 2022 in Frankfurt was the largest it had issued for a civil rights violation.</p>

<p>The travelers -- who wore distinctive garments like black hats and jackets -- told investigators they were treated as if they were one group even though many weren't flying together and didn't know each other.</p>

<p>Lufthansa denied boarding "to everyone for the apparent misbehavior of a few, because they were openly and visibly Jewish," DOT authorities said in a filing.</p>

<p>The problem began when the captain of the first flight reported to Lufthansa security that some passengers were not following rules, including wearing of face masks during the trip and not standing in groups in aisles or near emergency exits.</p>

<p>DOT authorities received over 40 discrimination complaints from Jewish passengers in this case.</p>

<p>Lufthansa told DOT that it has publicly apologized on numerous occasions for barring the passengers from continuing their trips, but denied any suggestion that any of its employees engaged in any form of discrimination.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/u3s74fio_german-airline-lufthansa_625x300_11_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[DOT authorities received over 40 discrimination complaints from Jewish passengers.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sri-lankan-pilot-locks-woman-colleague-out-of-cockpit-over-toilet-break-6799898]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Sri Lankan Pilot Locks Woman Colleague Out Of Cockpit Over Toilet Break]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sri-lankan-pilot-locks-woman-colleague-out-of-cockpit-over-toilet-break-6799898]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 16 Oct 2024 09:55:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A pilot locked a woman co-pilotout of the cockpit of a Sydney-Colombo Sri Lankan Airlines flight when shetook a mid-air toilet break.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A pilot locked a woman co-pilot&nbsp;out of the cockpit of a Sydney-Colombo SriLankan Airlines flight when she&nbsp;took a mid-air toilet break.</p>

<p>The incident was reported aboard a 10-hour-long flight, when the pilot took a break without arranging for her substitute in the cockpit, as per standard operating procedures. This led to a a stand-off between the two pilots.</p>

<p>The male pilot locked the woman pilot out when she went to use the restroom. To remedy the situation, a cabin crew member used a communication link to the cockpit to urge the captain to let the co-pilot back in.</p>

<p>Sri Lanka's Civil Aviation Authority is investigating the incident. The airline, meanwhile, said it is fully cooperating with the probe and the male pilot has been derostered till the investigation concludes.</p>

<p>With safety concerns in mind, several airlines and aviation authorities mandate the presence of at least two crew members in the cockpit at all times during a flight.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/h7nl8l18_flight_625x300_16_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Many aviation authorities mandate the presence of at least two crew members in the cockpit]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/study-links-lower-caloric-intake-to-increased-longevity-in-groundbreaking-research-6799857]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Study Links Lower Caloric Intake To Increased Longevity In New Research]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/study-links-lower-caloric-intake-to-increased-longevity-in-groundbreaking-research-6799857]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 16 Oct 2024 09:44:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The research involving nearly one thousand genetically distinct mice examined the impact of various diets on lifespan.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A groundbreaking study published in <em>Nature</em> has revealed that a consistent lower caloric intake significantly outperforms periodic fasting in extending lifespan. The research, conducted by scientists at Researchers at The Jackson Laboratory (JAX), involved nearly a thousand genetically distinct mice on various dietary regimens.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-024-08026-3">The study</a> challenged existing theories on the biological markers of ageing and longevity. Previous research had suggested that periodic fasting could be as effective as reducing overall caloric intake. However, the new findings indicate that maintaining a consistently lower caloric intake is more beneficial.</p>

<p>The authors of the study wrote that caloric restriction extends healthy lifespan in multiple species. Intermittent fasting, an alternative form of dietary restriction, is potentially more sustainable in humans, but its effectiveness remains largely unexplored. Identifying the most efficacious forms of dietary restriction is key for developing interventions to improve human health and longevity.</p>

<p>As per<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-024-08026-3"> the study</a>, the researchers performed an extensive assessment of graded levels of caloric restriction (20% and 40%) and intermittent fasting (1 and 2-day fasting per week) on the health and survival of 960 genetically diverse female mice. They show that caloric restriction and intermittent fasting both resulted in lifespan extension in proportion to the degree of restriction.</p>

<p>Lifespan was heritable, and genetics had a larger influence on lifespan than dietary restriction. The strongest trait associations with lifespan included retention of body weight through periods of handling-an indicator of stress resilience, high lymphocyte proportion, low red blood cell distribution width, and high adiposity in late life.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/g0n979og_mice_625x300_16_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Researchers compared caloric restriction and fasting effects in 960 diverse mice.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-kamala-harris-will-cut-her-own-path-says-president-joe-biden-6799780]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Elections: Kamala Harris Will 'Cut Her Own Path', Says Joe Biden]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-kamala-harris-will-cut-her-own-path-says-president-joe-biden-6799780]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 16 Oct 2024 09:30:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden said Tuesday that Kamala Harris would "cut her own path" if elected, as the Democratic nominee tries to convince voters she would bring change to the White House.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden said Tuesday that Kamala Harris would "cut her own path" if elected, as the Democratic nominee tries to convince voters she would bring change to the White House.</p>

<p>Vice President Harris came under fire from Republican rival Donald Trump last week after saying there was "not a thing comes to mind" when asked what she would have done differently from Biden.</p>

<p>"Every president has to cut their own path. That's what I did. I was loyal to Barack Obama but I cut my own path as president," Biden told a Democratic party dinner in Philadelphia.</p>

<p>"That's what Kamala's going to do. She's been loyal so far but she'll cut her own path."</p>

<p>Biden added: "Kamala's perspective on our problems will be fresh and new. Donald Trump's perspective is old and failed and quite frankly thoroughly totally dishonest."</p>

<p>Biden was vice president while Obama was in the White House from 2009 to 2017.</p>

<p>Biden's comments in the critical swing state of Pennsylvania were a clear attempt to support Harris, who replaced the 81-year-old Biden as the party's standard-bearer in July.</p>

<p>Harris has faced a balancing act between presenting herself as a "change candidate", but without disavowing the policies of the administration she has been part of for four years.</p>

<p>A New York Times/Siena poll one week ago found voters were marginally more likely to see her, rather than Trump, as a break from the status quo.</p>

<p>But Trump and his Republican allies pounced on Harris's comments made in an interview with a daytime TV show last week.</p>

<p>"There is not a thing that comes to mind... and I've been part of most of the decisions that have had impact," Harris said when asked how she would have done things differently from Biden.</p>

<p>The outgoing president meanwhile launched into a full-throated attack on Trump in his speech to local Democrats in Philadelphia.</p>

<p>Biden mocked Trump over a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hope-hes-okay-kamala-harris-as-trump-dances-during-town-hall-6799707">town hall that turned into a bizarre music session</a> on Monday, saying: "'He stood on the stage for 30 minutes and danced. I'm serious. What's wrong with this guy?"</p>

<p>Biden also lashed out at Trump for "demonizing" migrants.</p>

<p>"Trump hides all his racism, now it's all out front. He has the same ideas on race as the 1930s. Trump's ideas on the economy are from the 20s. Trump's ideas on women are from the 50s," he said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/6o5s14u8_joe-biden-kamala-harris_625x300_30_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["Every president has to cut their own path": Joe Biden]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hope-hes-okay-kamala-harris-as-trump-dances-during-town-hall-6799707]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Hope He's Okay": Kamala Harris As Trump Dances During Town Hall]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hope-hes-okay-kamala-harris-as-trump-dances-during-town-hall-6799707]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 16 Oct 2024 09:16:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kamala Harris went after her US presidential election rival Donald Trump's mental state and fitness for office Tuesday after the 78-year-old Republican's televised town hall veered into a surreal, impromptu music session.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kamala Harris went after her US presidential election rival Donald Trump's mental state and fitness for office Tuesday after the 78-year-old Republican's televised town hall veered into a surreal, impromptu music session.</p>

<p>Three weeks ahead of the US election, Harris's campaign has begun to focus aggressively on Trump's health and mental stability, and was quick to weigh in, saying the ex-president appeared "lost, confused, and frozen on stage."</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Trump appears lost, confused, and frozen on stage as multiple songs play for 30+ minutes and the crowd pours out of the venue early <a href="https://t.co/6r0TE2qCYM">pic.twitter.com/6r0TE2qCYM</a></p>
— Kamala HQ (@KamalaHQ) <a href="https://twitter.com/KamalaHQ/status/1846006129953833365?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 15, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>For about half an hour, Monday's event in Oaks near Philadelphia was standard fare ahead of the November 5 election, as Trump took friendly questions from supporters on the economy.</p>

<p>But a pause for two medical emergencies in the crowd turned into a bizarre 39 minutes of music and dancing as Trump abandoned the discussion of the election to put on his favorite hits, swaying awkwardly on stage.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Everyone is sharing Trump dancing to Ave Maria today during his disaster town hall, but personally I feel this was the best part. Once you see it, you can't unsee it. I'll never see this song the same way again <a href="https://t.co/0msBEQonyw">pic.twitter.com/0msBEQonyw</a></p>
— AZResist? (@az_resist) <a href="https://twitter.com/az_resist/status/1846049098522415617?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 15, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>"Who the hell wants to hear questions, right?" he said, bringing the Q&amp;A section to an abrupt end and telling his people to crank up the volume.</p>

<p>Trump has made a brief, jerky dance his signature at the end of rallies for years, nearly always to his exit song -- the Village People's 1978 disco anthem "YMCA."</p>

<p>On Monday, however, he stayed on stage for nine songs, ranging from opera to Guns N' Roses and Elvis, with the ex-president alternating his dance moves with standing in place and staring into the crowd.</p>

<p>"Hope he's okay," Harris opined dryly on X.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Everyone is sharing Trump dancing to Ave Maria today during his disaster town hall, but personally I feel this was the best part. Once you see it, you can't unsee it. I'll never see this song the same way again <a href="https://t.co/0msBEQonyw">pic.twitter.com/0msBEQonyw</a></p>
— AZResist? (@az_resist) <a href="https://twitter.com/az_resist/status/1846049098522415617?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 15, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>Undeterred, Trump was bopping to the Village People again Tuesday at a rally in Atlanta, where he turned up 90 minutes late and didn't mention the previous night's events or the criticism.</p>

<p>Delivering his usual stump speech focusing on illegal immigration, Trump pushed his now-customary falsehoods and exaggerations about migrant crime in Colorado and Ohio and referred to the country as "occupied" by foreign criminals.</p>

<p>But if he was trying to draw a line under Monday's strangeness, he didn't succeed.</p>

<p><strong>Dead heat</strong></p>

<p>Trump called the two world wars "beautiful" and claimed to have invented the word "caravan." Explaining how he was going to make America great again, he lurched into an aside about his wealthy friends, beachwear and President Joe Biden.</p>

<p>"I have a lot of rich friends. They go here. They go there. They're boring as hell," he began, apropos of nothing in particular. "Nobody cares. They put on their bathing suit. They don't look a lot better than Biden."</p>

<p>Harris and Trump are locked in a dead heat, according to polls, and the election is set to be decided by seven swing states where the margins could come down to a few thousand votes each.</p>

<p>The Republican is the oldest person ever to be nominated for a presidential bid, after Biden dropped out of the race following a disastrous debate that sparked fears about his own age.</p>

<p>Trump has not released a recent comprehensive report on his state of health, prompting fierce criticism from Harris, 59, who has increasingly been homing in on Trump's age and physical and mental condition.</p>

<p>It was the topic of her closing argument as she sat down with popular radio host Charlamagne tha God in an effort to boost her messaging to Black male voters -- a part of the electorate where Trump has made gains.</p>

<p>After setting out her policies for improving the lives of African American men, she turned to Trump's rallies and repeated a claim that riled him during their September debate -- that bored supporters were leaving his rallies early.</p>

<p>"This man is weak and he is unfit," Harris said.</p>

<p>Trump had begun the day with a less freewheeling tone at an Economic Club of Chicago event, where he said he was for slapping "obnoxious" tariffs on trading partners like Mexico so that companies move factories to the United States.</p>

<p>"To me, the most beautiful word in the dictionary is tariff," Trump said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/dbfvvbko_trump-dance-during-town-hall_625x300_16_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A pause for two medical emergencies in the crowd turned into a bizarre 39 minutes of music and dancing.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chinese-aquariums-star-whale-shark-turns-out-to-be-a-robot-visitors-outraged-6799619]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Chinese Aquarium's 'Whale Shark' Turns Out To Be A Robot, Visitors Outraged]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chinese-aquariums-star-whale-shark-turns-out-to-be-a-robot-visitors-outraged-6799619]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 16 Oct 2024 08:56:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Excitement quickly turned to disappointment as visitors discovered the 'whale shark' was a mechanical imitation.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>China's Xiaomeisha Sea World aquarium is facing widespread criticism after revealing its prized whale shark exhibit is actually a robotic replica. Following a five-year renovation, the aquarium reopened on October 1, attracting 100,000 visitors eager to see the world's largest fish. However, excitement quickly turned to disappointment as visitors discovered the 'whale shark' was a mechanical imitation, the <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/10/14/lifestyle/aquariums-star-whale-shark-shocks-visitors-because-it-turned-out-to-be-a-robot/">New York Post</a></em> reported. Photos showed the fake shark's obvious seams and gaps, sparking outrage among park-goers who paid $40 to see the real attraction.</p>

<p>Visitors on site angrily demanded their money back over the fake shark and&nbsp;flooded social media with complaints. One user wrote, "The venue isn't large enough, and even the whale shark is artificial,&nbsp;By 3 o'clock, people were already demanding refunds."</p>

<p>Another commented, "The most disappointing part was the whale shark exhibit. When I heard the name, I was full of anticipation, but when I arrived, I saw a mechanical whale shark. Even though it's for the sake of animal protection, I'd rather they didn't have one at all than show a fake one. It's not interesting at all."</p>

<p>Xiaomeisha Sea World has responded to the controversy, clarifying that the robotic whale shark was not intended to deceive visitors, but rather to comply with laws prohibiting the capture and trade of whale sharks.</p>

<p>Notably, the whale shark (Rhincodon typus) is the largest known surviving fish species. Reaching remarkable lengths, the largest confirmed whale shark measured 18 meters. To replicate this majestic creature, Xiaomeisha SeaWorld invested millions of Chinese yuan.</p>

<p>China has faced similar controversies in the past regarding animal exhibits and deception. The incident involving dogs being <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/watch-outrage-after-china-zoo-paints-chow-chow-dogs-to-look-like-pandas-5618273">spray-painted to resemble pandas</a> sparked widespread outrage and raised concerns about animal welfare and ethics. the incident happened in Taizhou Zoo in China's Jiangsu Province which opened on May 1 for visitors to see the new animals. &nbsp;</p>

<p>The zoo advertised the attraction of "Xiong Mao Quan" which translates as "panda dogs" to boost its visitor footfall during the May Day holiday. As per the&nbsp;<em><a href="https://nypost.com/2024/05/06/lifestyle/zoogoers-outraged-to-discover-panda-exhibit-was-actually-dogs-dyed-black-and-white/">New York Post,</a></em>&nbsp;zoo officials trimmed the manes of two chow dogs and dyed their faces black to resemble miniature pandas.&nbsp;The painted dogs were left on display every day between 8 am and 5 pm, where throngs of visitors congregated to look at them.</p>

<p>Despite their striking resemblance to giant pandas, some observers noted strange behaviour,&nbsp;such as head shaking. There was widespread outrage when visitors realised they were looking at chow-chow dogs instead of pandas. Many&nbsp;criticised zoo authorities for animal cruelty and deception.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/tnjvj15_whale-shark-_625x300_16_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Visitors on site angrily demanded their money back over the fake shark]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/why-climate-change-and-biodiversity-loss-should-be-addressed-together-6799578]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Climate Change And Biodiversity Loss Should Be Addressed Together]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/why-climate-change-and-biodiversity-loss-should-be-addressed-together-6799578]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 16 Oct 2024 08:42:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Some approaches to tackling global warming can have unintended knock-on consequences for nature and the protection of biodiversity, say scientists urging a more coordinated effort on these challenges.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Some approaches to tackling global warming can have unintended knock-on consequences for nature and the protection of biodiversity, say scientists urging a more coordinated effort on these challenges.</p>

<p>"Sometimes by trying to find a solution to a problem, we risk creating damage elsewhere," Anne Larigauderie at the Intergovernmental Scientific and Political Platform on Biodiversity (IPBES), an expert independent body, told AFP.</p>

<p>The IPBES will publish a report in December on how different crises -- including climate change and biodiversity loss -- are closely related and should be addressed together, not in isolation.</p>

<p>The IPBES and the UN's Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC) warned in 2021 that a siloed approach risked "actions which, inadvertently, prevent the resolution of one or the other problem, or even both."</p>

<p>In Britain, for example, an ostensibly sound policy of planting trees on wetlands backfired when in turn these carbon-rich landscapes dried up, releasing the planet-heating emissions stored in their roots and soil.</p>

<p><strong>Negative effects</strong></p>

<p>Climate Action Network, a collective of non-government organisations, has warned against "false solutions" which promise a healthier planet but with a cost to people or ecosystems attached.</p>

<p>Intentionally injecting iron into the oceans, for example, to boost microplankton growth may seem promising but "geoengineering" techniques have raised concerns about potential repercussions.</p>

<p>Alison Smith, a researcher at the University of Oxford, said iron fertilisation was "likely to cause massive environmental damage for uncertain climate gain."</p>

<p>"Measures taken to mitigate climate change must be evaluated according to their overall benefits and risks and not only according to their carbon footprint," said the Foundation for Biodiversity Research in 2022.</p>

<p>Wind turbines produce clean power and reduce the dependence of energy systems on fossil fuels, but can pose a risk to migratory birds or bats in some locations.</p>

<p>And building dams for hydroelectricity can block the passage of fish along waterways, reducing their populations.</p>

<p><strong>'Breaking down silos'</strong></p>

<p>"With crises as vast, complex and interconnected as climate change and biodiversity loss, focusing on one aspect of the problem will never be enough," said Tom Oliver at the University of Reading.</p>

<p>It is "important to look beyond 'sticking plaster fixes'" such as geoengineering, he said, which "can have huge anticipated side effects."</p>

<p>Installing "underwater curtains" to protect glaciers in Antarctica from warming waters -- an idea floated at last year's UN climate summit -- could impede nutrient flow, Lars Smedsrud, from the University of Bergen, wrote in the journal Nature this year.</p>

<p>In the quest for solutions to our biggest and most daunting challenges it is "important to look at the big picture -- not just focus narrowly on climate change," said Smith.</p>

<p>She is one of many experts pushing for nature-based solutions that have "combined benefits for biodiversity, the climate and populations".</p>

<p>A 2020 study in the journal Global Change Biology concluded that "nature-based interventions were most often shown to be as effective or more so than alternative interventions for addressing climate impacts."</p>

<p>And it is in preserving existing ecosystems, rather than trying to recreate new ones, that the potential is greatest.</p>

<p>A 2023 study in Nature found that simply protecting existing forests and leaving them alone to regenerate would deliver considerable carbon removal benefits.</p>

<p>"There is no one single silver bullet -- we need to do everything we can, across all sectors, countries and methods," said Smith.</p>

<p>"Breaking down silos is the only way forward that won't cause more problems than it solves."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/99d98mr8_climate-change_650x400_05_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Different crises -- including climate change and biodiversity loss -- are closely related.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/plastics-in-lungs-hearts-and-brains-of-newborns-new-research-uncovers-alarming-truth-6799415]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Plastics In Lungs, Hearts, And Brains Of Newborns, Study Raises Concerns]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/plastics-in-lungs-hearts-and-brains-of-newborns-new-research-uncovers-alarming-truth-6799415]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 16 Oct 2024 08:00:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Researchers warn of potential long-term health effects, raising concerns about environmental microplastics and their impact on maternal and fetal health.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Microplastics can be passed from pregnant mothers to their unborn offspring, new research has revealed. Tiny plastic pieces are actually living in the lungs, hearts, livers, kidneys, and brains of newborn mice exposed through inhalation of polyamide-12, or PA-12, researchers from Rutgers University reveal in a new study.</p>

<p>Through this research, it is indicated that during pregnancy, the microplastics can pass through the placenta and may expose the developing fetus. Even though this fact clearly indicates exposure of such offspring to unknown long-term health consequences, the presence of these plastics in such life-saving organs is very alarming.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/science/microplastics-invade-human-brains-researchers-call-for-global-emergency-6395977"><strong>Also Read | Microplastics Invade Human Brains, Researchers Call For Global Emergency</strong></a></p>

<p>According to the Rutgers Health study published in the journal <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0048969724055001?via%3Dihub"><em>Science of the Total Environment,</em></a> Researchers have long understood that micro- and nanoplastic particles (MNPs), which enter the environment through oxidation and natural degradation of consumer products, are easily deposited in the human body through inhalation, absorption and diet. Experts also understand that these pollutants can cross the placental barrier and deposit in fetal tissues.</p>

<p>What's been unclear is whether these particles remained in tissue long after birth. The Rutgers Health researchers found that they do, at least in rats. Their data that could have implications for human health.</p>

<p>"Nobody wants plastic in their liver," said Phoebe A Stapleton, an associate professor of pharmacology and toxicology at the Rutgers Ernest Mario School of Pharmacy, and the study's senior author. "Now that we know it's there - as well as in other organs - the next step is to understand why and what that means."</p>

<p>As per a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.rutgers.edu/news/researchers-examine-persistence-invisible-plastic-pollution"><em>release by the Rutgers University,</em></a> to assess the persistence of micro- and nanoplastic particles in neonatal tissue following maternal exposure, Stapleton and colleagues exposed six rats to aerosolized food-grade plastic powder for 10 days during pregnancy.</p>

<p>Rodents are good test subjects for this type of study, Stapleton said, because humans and rodents both possess a hemochorial placenta, meaning that maternal and fetal blood don't come into direct contact during circulation.</p>

<p>Two weeks after birth, two newborn rats - one male and one female - were tested for micro- and nanoplastic exposure. In both cases, the same type of plastic that the mothers inhaled during pregnancy were found in the offspring's lung, liver, kidney, heart and brain tissue. No plastics were found in a control group.</p>

<p>Stapleton said the findings are one more piece of evidence illustrating the potential dangers of micro- and nanoplastics in the environment.</p>

<p>"These results raise concerns for the toxicological impacts associated with MNPs exposure, maternal-fetal health, and systemic MNPs particle deposition," the researchers wrote.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-03/qaca5hm_microplastics-unsplash_625x300_11_March_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Microplastics can pass from pregnant mothers to their unborn offspring.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hezbollah-tunnels-nothing-like-we-saw-in-gaza-israel-shares-video-of-hezbollah-tunnel-6799411]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Nothing Like We Saw In Gaza": Israel Shares Video Of Hezbollah Tunnel]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hezbollah-tunnels-nothing-like-we-saw-in-gaza-israel-shares-video-of-hezbollah-tunnel-6799411]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 16 Oct 2024 07:59:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Israeli military today released a video of a tunnel allegedly used by Hezbollah members in Lebanon and said it was "nothing like" the one built by Hamas in Gaza.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Israeli military today released a video of a tunnel allegedly used by Hezbollah members in Lebanon and said it was "nothing like" the one <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-israel-shares-video-of-cramped-tunnel-where-hostages-were-held-and-killed-6537722" target="_blank">built by Hamas in Gaza</a>. In a one-minute video, an Israeli troop was seen showing a "hundred-metre" tunnel in south Lebanon with iron doors, "functioning" rooms, AK-47 rifles, a bedroom, a bathroom, storage room of generators, water tanks and two-wheelers.</p>

<p>It was not immediately clear when and where the video was exactly filmed.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israels-netanyahu-opposes-ceasefire-deal-that-wont-halt-hezbollah-from-rearming-6798116" target="_blank">Israel and Hezbollah</a> have been fighting across the Lebanese border since the war in Gaza erupted after <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-gaza-israel-hezbollah-israel-strikes-lebanon-netanyahu-says-we-will-win-on-october-7-attack-anniversary-6732608" target="_blank">Hamas</a> attacked Israeli towns on October 7 last year.</p>

<p>"We are crossing the border into south Lebanon to see what Hezbollah has been doing in the villages of south Lebanon. Embedding itself underneath civilian houses preparing for an October 7-style attack on northern Israel," the Israeli soldier can be heard saying in the clip.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">INSIDE LOOK into a Hezbollah terrorist tunnel in southern Lebanon: <a href="https://t.co/h3ZastZHxC">pic.twitter.com/h3ZastZHxC</a></p>
— Israel Defense Forces (@IDF) <a href="https://twitter.com/IDF/status/1846258005764886660?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 15, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Radwan "terrorists could stay here for weeks," she said while referring to Iran-backed Hezbollah's elite units.</p>

<p>"This is nothing like the tunnels we saw in Gaza," she added.</p>

<p>She also showed the tunnel's exit and claimed it was a Lebanese civilian house in southern Lebanon.</p>

<p>Since launching a cross-border ground assault into <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-military-says-50-rockets-fired-from-lebanon-6799019" target="_blank">Lebanon</a> late last month, the Israeli military says it has found multiple tunnel shafts under homes, including one it said was about 25 metres long and crossed into Israel.</p>

<p>On Tuesday, it said its troops in south Lebanon had captured three Hezbollah fighters.</p>

<p>"An underground shaft was located inside a building used by Hezbollah. The forces surrounded the building, where three terrorists of the Radwan Force were entrenched," the military said in a statement.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"They were found alongside many weapons and equipment needed for a long stay," it added.</p>

<p>On Sunday, the Israeli military said it had <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hezbollah-conflict-update-israel-army-captures-hezbollah-fighter-from-underground-tunnel-in-lebanon-6779928" target="_blank">captured a Hezbollah fighter from an underground tunnel</a> shaft in south Lebanon.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/d35d5bfo_hezbollah-tunnel_625x300_16_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A bedroom and a bathroom was seen in the tunnel allegedly used by Hezbollah members]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-minister-wants-to-give-obese-people-weight-loss-injections-to-get-them-back-to-work-6799404]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Unemployed People In The UK May Get Weight-Loss Drugs To Return To Work]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-minister-wants-to-give-obese-people-weight-loss-injections-to-get-them-back-to-work-6799404]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 16 Oct 2024 07:51:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Health Secretary Wes Streeting believes these medications could be "life-changing" for individuals struggling with obesity.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United Kingdom government has announced plans to provide weight loss medications to unemployed individuals struggling with obesity, to help them return to work. British Health Minister Wes Streeting emphasized the growing burden of obesity on the National Health Service (NHS), citing the staggering 11 billion pounds annual expenditure on obesity-related healthcare costs, surpassing even those associated with smoking, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cjd54zd0ezjo"><em>BBC</em></a> reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The initiative aims to utilise innovative weight loss treatments, such as Novo Nordisk's Wegovy and Lilly's Mounjaro, which have shown promising results in clinical trials.&nbsp;Health Secretary Wes Streeting believes these medications could be "life-changing" for individuals struggling with obesity, enabling them to regain control of their health and rejoin the workforce.</p>

<p>The minister said that unhealthy eating impacts people's lives, cutting their life expectancy. "Our widening waistbands are also placing a significant burden on our health service, costing the NHS 11bn pounds a year – even more than smoking. And it's holding back our economy. Illness caused by obesity causes people to take an extra four sick days a year on average, while many others are forced out of work altogether,''&nbsp;Mr Streeting wrote in an&nbsp;<a href="https://www.telegraph.co.uk/politics/2024/10/14/widening-waistbands-are-a-burden-on-britain/" target="_blank">opinion piece for the Telegraph</a>.</p>

<p>However, individuals will still need to remain responsible for taking "healthy living more seriously", as the "NHS can't be expected to always pick up the tab for unhealthy lifestyles", he said.</p>

<p>His proposal to use weight-loss medications comes the same day the UK government announced a 279 million pounds investment from Lilly — the world's largest pharmaceutical company and the chief rival to Wegovy and Ozempic-maker Novo Nordisk in the obesity drug market.</p>

<p>UK Prime Minister Keir Starmer also expressed support for weight-loss medications during a BBC interview, highlighting their potential benefits for both the economy and public health. He emphasised that these drugs can aid individuals in shedding excess weight, enabling them to return to work and alleviate pressure on the National Health Service (NHS).</p>

<p>However, this approach has also raised significant ethical questions.&nbsp;Dr Dolly van Tulleken, who specialises in obesity policy argued that eligible people should be able to receive the treatment, but warned that this must be coupled with measures to ease healthy food choices. She said, ''It's incredibly important that people in the UK access healthcare based on their health need rather than their potential economic value.''</p>

<p>She also questioned the feasibility of providing treatment to the millions who could be eligible given that specialist weight management services currently treat only 49,000 people per year.</p>

<p><br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/tds52ntg_wes-streeting_625x300_16_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[UK Prime Minister Keir Starmer also expressed support for weight-loss medications]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trumps-cryptocurrency-platform-falters-on-first-day-of-sales-6800743]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump's Cryptocurrency Platform Falters On First Day Of Sales]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trumps-cryptocurrency-platform-falters-on-first-day-of-sales-6800743]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 16 Oct 2024 06:07:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former US president Donald Trump's cryptocurrency platform had a faltering sales launch Tuesday, with only a fraction of its digital tokens that went on the market finding a buyer.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former US president Donald Trump's cryptocurrency platform had a faltering sales launch Tuesday, with only a fraction of its digital tokens that went on the market finding a buyer.</p>

<p>The Republican candidate announced in mid-September that he, along with his sons and entrepreneurs, would launch the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-launches-new-cryptocurrency-platform-with-family-6583616">platform named World Liberty Financial</a>.</p>

<p>Some 20 billion digital tokens, priced at 1.5 cents each, were offered by the company -- a total value of $300 million -- but just three percent had been purchased by Tuesday evening.</p>

<p>The tokens can be used as cryptocurrencies and give buyers a vote on the platform's governance.</p>

<p>Many observers blamed the low sales on technical problems, as the company's website suffered outages earlier in the day.</p>

<p>World Liberty Financial will enable users to lend or borrow cryptocurrencies to or from one another, a service already offered by many platforms, one of the best-known of which is Aave.</p>

<p>During his presidency Trump referred to cryptocurrencies as a scam, but has since radically changed his position, presenting himself as a "pro-bitcoin president" if elected in November.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/ajjnau2g_donald-trump-_625x300_14_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>