<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Sep 2024 20:42:45 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-to-accuse-russia-of-effort-to-influence-2024-election-report-6491045]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US To Accuse Russia Of Effort To Influence 2024 Election: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-to-accuse-russia-of-effort-to-influence-2024-election-report-6491045]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Sep 2024 20:42:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United States plans to accuse Russia on Wednesday of a campaign to influence the 2024 elections using online platforms to target American voters with disinformation, CNN reported, citing six sources familiar with the matter.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United States plans to accuse Russia on Wednesday of a campaign to influence the 2024 elections using online platforms to target American voters with disinformation, CNN reported, citing six sources familiar with the matter.</p>

<p>Russian state media network RT will be a focus of the announcement, CNN reported.</p>

<p>The news comes just hours before Attorney General Merrick Garland is due to make public remarks at a meeting of the Justice Department's Election Threats Task Force.</p>

<p>He will be joined by FBI Director Chris Wray, Deputy Attorney General Lisa Monaco, Principal Deputy Assistant Attorney General Nicole Argentieri, and Matt Olsen, the Assistant Attorney General for the National Security Division.</p>

<p>A Justice Department spokesman declined to comment ahead of the election task force meeting.</p>

<p>The Justice Department has previously warned that Russia remains a threat to the Nov. 5 presidential election.</p>

<p>In a speech last month, Monaco warned that Russian President Vladimir Putin "and his proxies are using increasingly sophisticated techniques in their interference operations."</p>

<p>"They're targeting specific voter demographics and swing-state voters in an effort to manipulate presidential and congressional election outcomes," she said.</p>

<p>"They're intent on co-opting unwitting Americans on social media to push narratives advancing Russian interests. They're working to diminish American support for Ukraine. And they're always adapting."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/ch356g6o_kamala-campaign_625x300_04_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Russian state media network RT will be a focus of the announcement, CNN reported. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-pics-prime-minister-narendra-modis-visit-to-brunei-6490829]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[In Pics: Prime Minister Narendra Modi's Visit To Brunei]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-pics-prime-minister-narendra-modis-visit-to-brunei-6490829]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Sep 2024 20:16:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Narendra Modi went to Brunei on a state visit on Tuesday, marking the first-ever bilateral trip by an Indian prime minister to the southeast Asian nation.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi went to Brunei on a state visit on Tuesday, marking the first-ever bilateral trip by an Indian prime minister to the southeast Asian nation. The visit coincided with the 40th anniversary of establishment of diplomatic ties between India and Brunei.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/5ivbrma8_modi-brunei-ani_625x300_04_September_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"></div>
</div>

<p>Upon his arrival, the Indian PM received a ceremonial Guard of Honour.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/mo96suk8_modi-brunei-ani_625x300_04_September_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>&nbsp;PM Modi was received by Brunei Crown Prince Haji Al-Muhtadee Billah.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/u1cerhvg_modi-brunei-ani_625x300_04_September_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"></div>

<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont">
<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/k9c3726o_modi-brunei-ani_625x300_04_September_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>
</div>

<p>PM Modi was accorded a warm welcome by the Indian community on his arrival. The leader also signed a drawing of him made by a child.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/cdv4vveg_modi-brunei-ani_625x300_04_September_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>PM Modi was invited by Sultan Haji Hassanal Bolkiah, the ruler of Brunei, at his official residence, the Istana Nurul Iman Palace. It is the world's largest residential palace and is registered in Guinness World Records.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/8avjjn9g_modi-brunei-ani_625x300_04_September_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p></p>

<p>PM Modi meets Brunei Sultan Haji Hassanal Bolkiah. The Sultan is the second-longest reigning monarch in the world after the late Queen Elizabeth II.</p>
</div>
</div>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/iaa4tsmo_modi-brunei-ani_625x300_04_September_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi with Brunei's Minister of Religious Affairs Pehin Dato Ustaz Haji Awang Badaruddin and other dignitaries during his visit to Omar Ali Saifuddien Mosque, in Bandar Seri Begawan.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/3i4105u_modi-brunei-ani_625x300_04_September_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>&nbsp;PM Modi shook hands with a child during his visit to Omar Ali Saifuddien Mosque in Bandar Seri Begawan.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/3sa9sqn8_modi-brunei-ani_625x300_04_September_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/33a78kq8_modi-brunei-ani_625x300_04_September_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>The Prime Minister inaugurated the Chancery building of the Indian High Commission by unveiling a commemorative plaque. The PM also lit a ceremonial lamp. External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar, National Security Adviser (NSA) Ajit Doval and other dignitaries were also present.</p>

<p>"Delighted to inaugurate the new Chancery of the High Commission of India, indicative of our stronger ties with Brunei Darussalam. This will also be serving our diaspora," the PM wrote on X.</p>

<p>PM Modi has now reached Singapore for an official two-day visit to strengthen bilateral ties between the two nations. His visit to the two nations is a part of New Delhi's 'Act East' policy.</p>

<p></p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/e8tbkng_modi-brunei-ani_625x300_04_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[PM Modi's visit to Brunei was the 1st-ever bilateral trip by an Indian PM to the southeast Asian nation]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-zealand-hikes-tourist-tax-by-200-to-support-economy-and-conservation-efforts-6490790]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[New Zealand Hikes Tourist Tax By 200% To Support Economy, Biodiversity]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-zealand-hikes-tourist-tax-by-200-to-support-economy-and-conservation-efforts-6490790]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Sep 2024 20:10:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[New Zealand will significantly raise its International Visitor Conservation and Tourism Levy from NZ$35 to NZ$100 starting October 1st, aiming to boost economic growth and ensure tourists contribute to public services and conservation efforts.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>New Zealand will drastically raise its international visitor entry charge on October 1st, raising concerns about possible effects on the number of tourists. The International Visitor Conservation and Tourism Levy is going to increase by almost three times, from NZ$35 (Rs 1,825) to NZ$100 (Rs 5,214).</p>

<p>The government of New Zealand has defended the hefty increase, citing it as an essential step to encourage economic expansion and guarantee that tourists contribute equitably to public services and the calibre of experiences provided in the nation. This action is a component of a larger plan to reduce tourism's negative environmental effects while boosting the local economy.</p>

<p>"The International Visitor Conservation and Tourism Levy (IVL) will be raised to NZ$100 to ensure visitors contribute to public services and high-quality experiences while visiting New Zealand," Minister for Tourism and Hospitality Matt Doocey and Minister of Conservation <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.doc.govt.nz/news/media-releases/2024-media-releases/ivl-increase-to-ensure-visitors-contribute-more-to-new-zealand/">Tama Potaka said.</a></p>

<p>"The government is serious about enabling the tourism sector to grow as part of our overall goal of doubling exports in 10 years. International tourism plays a hugely important role in the New Zealand economy, with international visitors spending over NZ$11 billion in the year ending March 2024," Mr Doocey said.</p>

<p>"But international tourism also comes with costs to local communities, including additional pressure on regional infrastructure and higher upkeep and maintenance costs across our conservation estate.</p>

<p>"The IVL was introduced in 2019 as a mechanism to ensure international visitors were contributing directly to these costs, the vast majority of which are paid for by New Zealand taxpayers and ratepayers."</p>

<p>"Public consultation by the Ministry of Business Innovation and Employment (MBIE) found 93 per cent of submitters supported raising the IVL, with the main rationale being an increase would be reasonable to help cover the costs of tourism."</p>

<p>"The new IVL remains competitive with countries like Australia and the UK, and we are confident New Zealand will continue to be seen as an attractive visitor destination by many around the world."</p>

<p>"A NZ$100 IVL would generally make up less than 3 per cent of the total spending for an international visitor while in New Zealand, meaning it is unlikely to have a significant impact on visitor numbers."</p>

<p>"Increasing the IVL means we can continue to grow international tourism to support economic growth while ensuring international visitors contribute to high-value conservation areas and projects, such as supporting biodiversity in national parks and other highly visited areas and improving visitor experiences on public conservation land," Mr Doocey said.</p>

<p>"Taxpayers already contribute close to NZ$884 million a year directly on tourism and conservation, including tourism promotion, natural heritage, and recreation. This money funds Tourism New Zealand, protects biodiversity within the Department of Conservation estate, and provides quality experiences at the likes of Milford Sound, Aoraki/Mt Cook, and the Tongariro Alpine Crossing," Mr Potaka said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/4528lpno_new-zealand_625x300_04_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The government maintains that the levy will support infrastructure, biodiversity.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-boy-12-suffers-cardiac-arrest-after-attempting-chroming-challenge-on-tiktok-6490308]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK Boy, 12, Suffers Cardiac Arrest After Attempting "Chroming" Challenge]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-boy-12-suffers-cardiac-arrest-after-attempting-chroming-challenge-on-tiktok-6490308]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Sep 2024 19:03:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The 36-year-old was horrified to find her son having a seizure on the kitchen floor before he went into cardiac arrest.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 12-year-old boy nearly lost his life after participating in a dangerous social media trend. Cesar Watson-King inhaled a can of deodorant as part of a challenge known as "chroming," and collapsed at his home in Doncaster, South Yorkshire, on August 21, reported the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://metro.co.uk/2024/09/02/boy-12-narrowly-survives-deadly-social-media-challenge-goes-wrong-21534581/" rel="nofollow, noindex"><em>Metro</em></a>.</p>

<p>His mother, Nichola King, who had just finished breastfeeding her youngest child upstairs, was alarmed by a loud thud and rushed downstairs to investigate. The 36-year-old was horrified to find her son having a seizure on the kitchen floor before he went into cardiac arrest.</p>

<p>Nichola's eldest son, Kaiden, immediately called 999 while Nichola performed CPR on Cesar as they awaited the ambulance. Cesar was rushed to the hospital, where he was placed in a medically induced coma for two days after experiencing further seizures and cardiac arrests.</p>

<p>Fortunately, Cesar recovered and is now back home, but Nichola, a mother of four, has shared photos of her son receiving CPR and in intensive care to warn others about the dangers of chroming. The trend involves inhaling toxic chemicals from substances like paint, solvents, aerosol cans, cleaning products, or petrol to achieve a brief 'high.'</p>

<p>This practice can cause slurred speech, dizziness, hallucinations, nausea, and disorientation, but it can also lead to heart attacks or suffocation.</p>

<p>Recalling the moment she heard her son collapse, Nichola said, "I had just finished breastfeeding my baby and was drifting off to sleep when I heard a really loud bang. I thought one of the kids had done something. I heard Cesar creeping downstairs and assumed he was getting something to eat. The bang sounded like someone had fallen over. I heard a moaning sound from downstairs and thought Cesar had broken a bone or something. When I went downstairs, I saw him lying on the floor, and his eyes were rolling back into his head. It was terrifying. He was having a seizure."</p>

<p>Nichola ran upstairs to grab her phone, but her hands were shaking so much she couldn't unlock it, so she asked her eldest to call an ambulance. She then began performing CPR on Cesar to try to restore his breathing.</p>

<p>"I thought he'd fallen and hit his head. I had no idea what had happened. He turned blue and stopped breathing. I thought he'd died. I was in complete shock. I watched my son die and saw the light go out of his eyes."</p>

<p>After Cesar was taken to Doncaster Royal Infirmary, police informed Nichola that they had found a can of Aldi Lacura deodorant and other chroming paraphernalia on the kitchen floor, leading them to believe Cesar had inhaled the deodorant before losing consciousness.</p>

<p>Nichola said, "I hadn't heard of chroming before this. An older boy had shown him how to do it. When police told me what he'd inhaled, I thought he was going to die. I knew the warnings on the back of the cans that say 'solvent abuse kills instantly.'"</p>

<p>Cesar was later transferred to Sheffield Children's Hospital, where he was kept in a medically induced coma for 48 hours. When he came out of the coma, he began showing signs of progress, soon breathing on his own and able to talk and walk.</p>

<p>After eight days in the hospital, Cesar was discharged and allowed to return home.</p>

<p>Nichola said, "I was over the moon. He was almost back to normal when he was discharged-eating, drinking, having a laugh. He just feels tired. We don't know about long-term damage, but his short-term memory is very bad. He couldn't remember what had happened. If I hadn't heard something that night, I would have found a dead body the next morning. I've spoken to Cesar and asked him never to do anything like this again. I've thrown out everything in the house that sprays."</p>

<p>Nichola also wants to warn other children who might be tempted to try chroming: "It's not worth it. It might feel good, but it definitely doesn't when you're in the hospital struggling to breathe and causing pain to your parents."</p>

<p>She added, "I also want to stress the importance of parents being trained in first aid. I believe anyone with kids should attend a course, as it could be the difference between life and death."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/95pkmgeg_cesar-watsonking-_625x300_04_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[This practice can cause slurred speech, dizziness, hallucinations, nausea, and disorientation]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/zelensky-removes-foreign-minister-face-of-ukraine-war-diplomacy-in-rejig-6490154]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Zelensky Removes Foreign Minister, Face Of Ukraine War Diplomacy, In Rejig]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/zelensky-removes-foreign-minister-face-of-ukraine-war-diplomacy-in-rejig-6490154]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Sep 2024 18:47:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky said Wednesday his government needed "new energy" during a major reshuffle that saw the foreign minister and several others hand in their resignation.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky said Wednesday his government needed "new energy" during a major reshuffle that saw the foreign minister and several others hand in their resignation.</p>

<p>"We need new energy. And these steps are related to strengthening our state in various areas," said Zelensky, when asked about the reshuffle and Foreign Minister Dmytro Kuleba's future.</p>

<p>"I am very grateful to the ministers and the entire Cabinet team who have been working for Ukraine, for the sake of Ukrainians, for four and a half years, and some of them have been our ministers for five years," he added.</p>

<p>A source close to the presidential office told AFP that Zelensky and Kuleba "will discuss and decide" his future post.</p>

<p>The announcement came a day after several other ministers and officials resigned in one of Kyiv's most significant government reshuffles since Russia invaded two and a half years ago.</p>

<p>Kuleba -- the face of Ukrainian diplomacy during the war -- is the most senior of the ministers to offer to step down.</p>

<p>The 43-year-old has held the post since 2020 and since Russia's 2022 attack has travelled the world to advocate for Western support for Kyiv and sanctions on Moscow.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/7ccbgih8_zelensky-afp_625x300_04_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Ukraine war has been going on for over two and a half years]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/major-marketing-firm-admits-to-listening-to-your-phone-conversations-report-6489997]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Marketing Firm Admits To Listening To Your Phone Conversations: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/major-marketing-firm-admits-to-listening-to-your-phone-conversations-report-6489997]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Sep 2024 18:28:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A recent report reveals that a major marketing firm with clients including Facebook and Google, has admitted to using its "Active Listening" software to monitor smartphone conversations for targeted advertising.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Since the start of targeted advertising on websites and social media, there have been many theories circulating that claim smartphones and other gadgets, including tablets and laptops, actively listen to users' conversations in order to offer personalised ads. Now, a new report has validated these long-standing suspicions.</p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.404media.co/heres-the-pitch-deck-for-active-listening-ad-targeting/"><em>404 Media,</em></a> Cox Media Group, a marketing firm whose clients include Facebook and Google, has privately admitted that it listens to users' smartphone microphones and then places ads based on the information that is picked up. The television and radio news conglomerate admitted in a pitch deck to investors that its "Active Listening" software uses artificial intelligence to "capture real-time intent data by listening to our conversations."</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/webstories/feature/how-to-choose-right-laptop-step-by-step-guide-23680"><strong>Also Read | How To Choose Right Laptop: Step-by-Step Guide</strong></a></p>

<p>"Advertisers can pair this voice data with behavioural data to target in-market consumers," the company wrote in the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.404media.co/heres-the-pitch-deck-for-active-listening-ad-targeting/">pitch deck.</a></p>

<p>"Consumers leave a data trail based on their conversations and online behaviour," and that the AI-powered software collects and analyses said "behavioural and voice data from 470+ sources," CMG noted in the deck.</p>

<p>Google removed CMG from its "Partners Program" website after it was contacted by 404 Media to comment on the matter.</p>

<p>"All advertisers must comply with all applicable laws and regulations as well as our Google Ads policies, and when we identify ads or advertisers that violate these policies, we will take appropriate action," a Google spokesperson told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/09/03/business/marketing-firm-spies-on-you-through-your-phones-microphone-report/"><em>The Post.</em></a></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/d9bbqj3o_listening-to-your-phone-conversations_625x300_04_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The companys pitch deck disclosed that its software captures real-time voice data.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/all-about-iphone-16-series-set-to-launch-on-september-9-6489624]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[All About iPhone 16 Series Set To Launch On September 9]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/all-about-iphone-16-series-set-to-launch-on-september-9-6489624]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Sep 2024 17:44:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Apple is set to release its highly anticipated iPhone 16 series at the upcoming "It's Glowtime" event on September 9. Alongside the new iPhones, the tech behemoth will also likely introduce the Watch Series 10 and a few accessories.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Apple is set to release its highly anticipated iPhone 16 series at the upcoming "It's Glowtime" event on September 9. Alongside the new iPhones, the tech behemoth will also likely introduce the Watch Series 10 and a few accessories. However, all eyes will be on the iPhone 16 lineup, including four models: the iPhone 16, iPhone 16 Plus, iPhone 16 Pro, and iPhone 16 Pro Max.</p>

<h2><strong>Features and updates of the iPhone 16 series:</strong></h2>

<h3><strong>New screen sizes</strong></h3>

<p>Each iPhone 16 model will sport a different screen size, catering to various user preferences.&nbsp;</p>

<ul>
	<li>iPhone 16: 6.1-inch display</li>
	<li>iPhone 16 Pro: 6.3-inch display (new size)</li>
	<li>iPhone 16 Plus: 6.7-inch display</li>
	<li>iPhone 16 Pro Max: 6.9-inch display (largest iPhone yet)</li>
</ul>

<p>As with previous models, the iPhone 16 and 16 Plus will feature a 60Hz refresh rate OLED panel, while the iPhone 16 Pro and Pro Max will offer a smoother 120Hz refresh rate.</p>

<h3><strong>Design</strong></h3>

<p><strong>-iPhone 16 and 16 Plus:</strong></p>

<p>Colours: Black, White, Green, Yellow, Pink, Blue, and Purple<br />
Glass back and aluminium frame</p>

<p><strong>-iPhone 16 Pro and Pro Max:</strong></p>

<p>Sophisticated finishes: Black Titanium, White Titanium, Gray Titanium, and Gold Titanium<br />
Glass back and titanium frame with a glossy finish (similar to iPhone 14 Pro)</p>

<h3><strong>The A18 chip</strong></h3>

<p>The iPhone 16 series is powered by Apple's new A18 chip, a unified processor across all models. The Pro and Pro Max versions feature a speed-binned A18 Pro chip for enhanced performance, with higher CPU clock speeds and more GPU cores. Both chips use TSMC's cutting-edge 3nm manufacturing process. Additionally, all models come with at least 8 GB of RAM, optimised for Apple Intelligence, and storage ranging from 128 GB to 2 TB, depending on the model.</p>

<h3><strong>Camera upgrades</strong></h3>

<p>While the iPhone 16 and 16 Plus will likely retain similar camera setups to their predecessors, the iPhone 16 Pro and Pro Max are expected to receive significant upgrades.</p>

<p>The Pro models will feature a new 48 MP ultra-wide-angle lens, alongside a telephoto camera capable of 5x optical zoom. The cameras will also support spatial video recording with 3D playback on Apple Vision, though video resolution will remain capped at 4K.</p>

<h3><strong>New buttons&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Apple is reportedly adding new buttons to the iPhone 16 series. The Pro models will feature an enlarged action button, introduced with the iPhone 15 Pro, as well as a new capture button designed to make taking photos as seamless as using a traditional digital camera.</p>

<h3><strong>Apple Intelligence</strong></h3>

<p>The new A18 chip will enable all models to support Apple Intelligence, bringing advanced AI capabilities to the entire lineup. While details are sparse, the iPhone 16 series will introduce exclusive Apple Intelligence features, which will likely be available with an iOS 18.1 update following the initial launch.</p>

<h3><strong>Battery life</strong></h3>

<p>Battery life is always a crucial aspect of new iPhones, and the iPhone 16 series promises improvements.&nbsp;</p>

<ul>
	<li>iPhone 16 Pro Max: 4,676 mAh (largest battery ever in an iPhone)</li>
	<li>iPhone 16 Plus: 4,006 mAh</li>
	<li>iPhone 16: 3,561 mAh</li>
	<li>iPhone 16 Pro: 3,355 mAh</li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-01/20istb9_iphone-generic-reuters_625x300_15_January_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[iPhone 16 and 16 Plus will feature a 60Hz refresh rate OLED panel (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/greta-thunberg-arrested-at-gaza-war-protest-at-copenhagen-university-6489530]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Greta Thunberg Arrested At Gaza War Protest At Copenhagen University]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/greta-thunberg-arrested-at-gaza-war-protest-at-copenhagen-university-6489530]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Sep 2024 17:35:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Environmental activist Greta Thunberg has been arrested today at a protest against the Gaza war in Denmark, a spokesperson for the student group organising the demonstration said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Environmental activist Greta Thunberg has been arrested today at a protest against the Gaza war in Denmark, a spokesperson for the student group organising the demonstration said.</p>

<p>A total of six people were arrested at the University of Copenhagen after around 20 people blocked the entrance to a building and three entered it, a police spokesperson told news agency Reuters.</p>

<p>Images published by local daily Ekstra Bladet showed Ms Thunberg wearing a black-and-white keffiyeh shawl around her shoulders and being escorted out of the campus by the police.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Ms Thunberg shared visuals on Instagram of police entering a building where the group 'Students against the Occupation' was staging a protest. The group wrote on Instagram that the protestors entered the university's rector's office to demand an institutional boycott of Israeli universities.</p>

<p>"While the situation in Palestine worsens, the University of Copenhagen continues its collaboration with Israeli universities and thereby contributes to knowledge that is used to commit genocide. Our university must not contribute to genocide," 'Students against the Occupation' said in a statement on Instagram.</p>

<p>Police declined to confirm the identities of those arrested but 'Students against the Occupation' told Reuters that the 21-year-old climate activist was among those detained.</p>

<p>Students around the US and Europe have set up encampments at universities to protest against Israel's military operation in Gaza and occupation of Palestinian territories.</p>

<p>Israel's Gaza siege began after Palestinian group Hamas launched an unprecedented attack in southern Israel on October 7 last year. According to Gaza's ministry of health, more than 40,000 Palestinians have been killed and thousands more have been displaced.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to the latest data from the United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs, the World Health Organization and the Palestinian government, Israeli attacks have destroyed - more than half of Gaza's homes, around half of healthcare facilities, 80 percent of commercial buildings, 85 percent of school buildings and 65 percent of road networks.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/ig0o8ub_greta-thunberg-arrest_625x300_04_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Greta Thunberg has been arrested today at a protest against the Gaza war in Denmark]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/deaths-in-uk-tower-fire-which-killed-72-were-all-avoidable-finds-probe-6489382]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Deaths In UK Tower Fire, Which Killed 72, Were "All Avoidable", Finds Probe]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/deaths-in-uk-tower-fire-which-killed-72-were-all-avoidable-finds-probe-6489382]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Sep 2024 17:16:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The UK's Grenfell Tower fire disaster that killed 72 people was the result of "decades of failure" by government and construction industry bodies and the "systematic dishonesty" of building material firms, a damning final report said on Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The UK's Grenfell Tower fire disaster that killed 72 people was the result of "decades of failure" by government and construction industry bodies and the "systematic dishonesty" of building material firms, a damning final report said on Wednesday.</p>

<p>The fire in the early hours of June 14, 2017 spread rapidly through the 24-storey block in west London due to highly combustible cladding fixed to the exterior.</p>

<p>Started in a faulty freezer on the fourth floor, the blaze took barely half an hour to climb to the building's top floor with catastrophic consequences.</p>

<p>The highly-critical report marks the end of a two-part independent inquiry led by retired judge Martin Moore-Bick into Britain's worst residential fire since World War II.</p>

<p>Unveiling his findings, Moore-Bick said all the 72 deaths as a result of the fire were "all avoidable" and said the victims had been "badly failed".</p>

<p>Some of those who played a part in the sowing the seeds of disaster had shown "incompetence", as well as "dishonesty and greed", he said.</p>

<p>The report makes scathing criticism of government and other influential bodies over a refurbishment of Grenfell that led to the cladding and other dangerous materials being installed.</p>

<p>In particular the report condemns firms involved in supplying rainscreen cladding panels and other insulation products.</p>

<p>Accusing them of "systematic dishonesty", it said they "engaged in deliberate and sustained strategies to manipulate the testing processes, misrepresent test data and mislead the market".</p>

<p>Following the release of the report, Prime Minister Keir Starmer pledged that his government would ensure a similar tragedy does not occur again.</p>

<p>"The Government will carefully consider the report and its recommendations, to ensure that such a tragedy cannot occur again," he said in a written statement to parliament.</p>

<p><strong>'Stay-put'</strong></p>

<p>The London Fire Brigade (LFB) also comes in for heavy criticism with senior officers described as "complacent".</p>

<p>The service failed to ensure that the danger posed by the increasing use of cladding "was shared with the wider organisation and reflected in training", it said.</p>

<p>It also failed to learn the lessons of a previous fire in 2009 which "should have alerted the LFB to the shortcomings in its ability to fight fires in high-rise buildings".</p>

<p>Residents who phoned the emergency services were told to remain in their flats and await rescue for nearly two hours after the fire broke out.</p>

<p>The "stay-put" advice, now considered to have cost lives, has since been revised.</p>

<p>It led to some of the men, women and children who died, including whole family groups, becoming trapped in their own homes.</p>

<p>Abdulaziz El-Wahabi, 52, and his wife Faouzia, 41, died on the 21st floor with their three children, the youngest of whom, Mehdi, was eight years old.</p>

<p>Mehdi's teacher recalled his ability to "make us laugh and smile" and "lighten our mood".</p>

<p>Abdulaziz was described as a "loyal family man" who would always "help neighbours with their bags and open doors".</p>

<p>Faouzia was "lively and friendly".</p>

<p>The tragedy's youngest victims were a still-born child and a six-month-old baby, Leena Belkadi, found with her mother in a stairwell between the 19th and 20th floors.</p>

<p><strong>Dangerous buildings</strong></p>

<p>The disaster has left many people living in buildings covered in similar cladding permanently fearful of a repeat tragedy.</p>

<p>Those who owned their own homes also faced financial problems as their apartments became unsaleable.</p>

<p>The UK's then Conservative government announced in 2022 that developers would be required to contribute more to the cost of the removal, with those in buildings over 11 metres high not having to pay at all.</p>

<p>But a fire in Dagenham, east London, just over a week ago illustrated the ongoing risks.</p>

<p>Over 80 people had to be evacuated in the middle of the night after waking to smoke and flames in a block where work to remove "non-compliant" cladding was part-completed.</p>

<p>London fire commissioner Andy Roe said there were still around 1,300 buildings in London alone where urgent "remediation" work still needed to be done.</p>

<p><strong>Criminal charges?</strong></p>

<p>Bereaved relatives and survivors said ahead of the report they hoped it would bring them what they say is the "truth we deserve".</p>

<p>For some that means jail for those who "made decisions putting profit above people's safety".</p>

<p>"For me there's no justice without people going behind bars," said Sandra Ruiz, whose 12-year-old niece Jessica Urbano Ramirez died.</p>

<p>London's Metropolitan Police, however, has said its investigators will need until the end of 2025 to finalise its own investigation.</p>

<p>Prosecutors will then need a year to decide whether anyone will face charges.</p>

<p>For former Grenfell Tower resident Edward Daffarn, however, a delay that long is unacceptable.</p>

<p>"We are not prepared to wait for much longer, and this report needs to be the catalyst for significant movement forward from the Met Police in bringing charges against people who perpetrated the deaths of 72 people," he said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/ij32p5i_grenfell-tower-fire-afp_625x300_04_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The fire started in the early hours of June 14, 2017 (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/real-vs-reel-here-is-how-the-1999-hijack-really-played-out-6489281]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: Real Vs Reel: Here is How 1999 IC 814 Hijack Really Played Out]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/real-vs-reel-here-is-how-the-1999-hijack-really-played-out-6489281]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Sep 2024 17:03:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[It is the second time a major OTT platform has agreed to make changes after the ministry took up the issue with them.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/91n3627g_kandahar_625x300_04_September_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p><em>(In light of the controversy over the Netflix series 'IC 814: The Kandahar Hijack', here is a view on the 1999 hijack and its aftermath. <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/opinion-ic-814-whats-in-a-name-just-a-reason-to-outrage-6489378">Click here to read Nishtha Gautam's counterview</a>)</em></p>

<p>The late evening wind chill on December 31, 1999, caused considerable discomfort for everyone gathered at Indira Gandhi International Airport in New Delhi. Braving the cold were the relatives of the recently freed passengers, media personnel, curious locals from the National Capital Region, numerous security personnel, and logistical staff from various organisations.</p>

<p>The arrival of an Indian Airlines plane elicited cheers. Suddenly, the crowd seemed to forget the tragic killing of Rupin Katyal and the muted anger over the release of three notorious terrorists-Masood Azhar, Mushtaq Zargar, and Omar Shaikh-in exchange for the hostages aboard the hijacked Indian Airlines IC814 flight from Kathmandu to New Delhi. The excitement to see the passengers return home safely overshadowed all other concerns.</p>

<p>As the passengers began to disembark, media personnel focused on two main aspects: the trauma and suffering endured by the hostages, and the identities of the hijackers.</p>

<h2><strong>Chief, Doctor, Burger, Bhola, And Shankar</strong></h2>

<p>The following morning, the pseudonyms or call signs used by the five hijackers - Chief, Doctor, Burger, Bhola, and Shankar - were widely reported in newspapers. With the real identities of the hijackers still undisclosed, the public dissemination of these pseudonyms heightened anxiety and tension for the then Vajpayee government. Rumours, particularly from across the border, suggesting that some hijackers were Kashmiri Hindus, exacerbated the situation.</p>

<p>Soon after, the Mumbai Police, in close cooperation with central intelligence agencies, apprehended four Harkat-ul-Ansar/Mujahideen operatives-Mohammed Rehan, Mohammed Iqbal, Yasuf Nepali, and Abdul Latif-who had supported the hijackers. Rehan hailed from Karachi, Iqbal from Multan, Yusuf was reportedly a Nepali national, and Latif was an Indian from Mumbai, reportedly recruited by Pakistan ISI during his time in the Gulf Region and later trained in Pakistan and Afghanistan.</p>

<p>During interrogation, these operatives revealed the real identities of all the hijackers. This prompted the then Home Minister, L.K. Advani, to issue a detailed public statement about those involved in the hijack, the evidence linking them to Pakistan and its notorious ISI to relay this information globally. The statement identified Ibrahim Athar from Bahawalpur, Pakistan, as 'Chief'; Shahid Akhtar Sayed Gulshan Iqbal, Sunny Ahmed Qazi and Mistri Zahoor Ibrahim, all from Karachi, as 'Doctor', 'Burger' and 'Bhola', respectively; and Shakir from Sukkur as 'Shankar'. The names and places of origin of the hijackers were provided to dispel any misgivings about them that may have been there for the past few days.</p>

<p>After over 24 years, the release of a series on the IC 814 Kandahar hijack has revived these memories and controversies, particularly surrounding the names of the hijackers - Bhola and Shankar - which has sparked a passionate public debate.</p>

<p>The debate mainly focused on two issues:</p>

<h2><strong>1. Intent Of the series:</strong></h2>

<p><em>Is there malicious intent by the producer and director to craft a narrative that exonerates Pakistan and the ISI, while placing all blame on Osama bin Laden's Al-Qaeda and Afghanistan?</em></p>

<p>This question arose because Osama bin Laden and Al-Qaeda's direct involvement was not discussed in detail by those at the helm then. It's true that Laden was living in Afghanistan and was one of the principal players in the state of affairs there. There were scenes of jubilation immediately after the landing and release of three terrorists by Indian authorities. But that Laden or his group masterminded the hijack had not been under scrutiny.</p>

<p>All three released terrorists soon returned to Pakistan to get a hero welcome, formed terror outfits and used Pakistan's soil to indulge in terror activities or export terrorism from there - further proof of the country's direct complicity in the crime. The series, however, has characters playing leads in intelligence agencies and shows how ISI couldn't have been connected with the hijackers.</p>

<h2><strong>2. Misleading Names</strong></h2>

<p>Did the series mislead viewers by using names like Bhola and Shankar, thereby causing confusion?</p>

<p>A statement issued in the name of Monika Shergill, Vice President, Content, Netflix India, after a meeting of the OTT platform's representatives with the Information and Broadcasting Ministry, clears the air on the issue.</p>

<p>"For the benefit of audiences unfamiliar with the 1999 hijacking of Indian Airlines Flight 814, the opening disclaimer has been updated to include the real and code names of the hijackers. The code names in the series reflect those used during the actual event. India has a rich culture of storytelling - and we are committed to showcasing these stories and their authentic representation," the statement said. The statement gives a sense that the platform realised that it was perhaps a mistake on the part of the makers not to give the real identities of the five hijackers at any point in the series.</p>

<p>The series portrays Jaswant Singh, the then external affairs minister, as the one who was taking all the calls. The real story is slightly different.</p>

<p>With Netflix agreeing to make amendments, at least the ferocity of the controversy subsides for now. It is the second time a major OTT platform has agreed to make changes after the ministry took up the issue with them. In January 2021, on the ministry's intervention, Amazon Prime made some changes to the series <em>Tandav</em>. But then there is a difference - Tandav was fiction, while<em> IC814: The Kandahar Hijack </em>is based on a real incident.</p>

<p><em>(Sanjay Singh is Contributing Editor, NDTV)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/4pk6fti_knadahar_625x300_04_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-vs-kamala-harris-on-x-over-who-will-be-what-on-day-one-6489103]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk vs Kamala Harris On X Over Who Will Be What On "Day One"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-vs-kamala-harris-on-x-over-who-will-be-what-on-day-one-6489103]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Sep 2024 16:40:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Elon Musk, a staunch Trump supporter, shared an AI-generated image of US Vice President Kamala Harris and said she "vows to be a communist dictator on day one".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Elon Musk, a staunch Trump supporter, shared an AI-generated image of US Vice President Kamala Harris and said she "vows to be a communist dictator on day one".&nbsp;</p>

<p>Elon Musk came forward to defend Donald Trump when Ms Harris said "Donald Trump vows to be a dictator on day one.".&nbsp;</p>

<p>He called her out and said "You are lying" and then shared the AI-generated image where the Democratic Party's presidential candidate is wearing a red blazer, a colour central to Communism and a peak cap with the iconic 'hammer and sickle' symbol.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Kamala vows to be a communist dictator on day one. Can you believe she wears that outfit!? <a href="https://t.co/Anu9tKQHXN">https://t.co/Anu9tKQHXN</a> <a href="https://t.co/ISKFXYnSon">pic.twitter.com/ISKFXYnSon</a></p>
â€” Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1830656672211103825?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 2, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>The US Vice President has not reacted to Elon Musk's post on X.</p>

<p>Elon Musk, who backed Joe Biden in the 2020 US Presidential Election, has switched over to the Republican camp and is now rallying behind Donald Trump who is seeking a second term as President. In the past, SpaceX founder has worked closely with the Obama administration and said he voted for Hilary Clinton too. When Biden was elected president, he said he was "fired up that the new administration is focused on climate."</p>

<p>The feud between Democrats and Elon Musk began when the Biden regime rejected his idea of a carbon tax, something Mr Musk has been rallying for since 2015. Their policies on immigration and the treatment of Tesla by Biden compared to Ford. The feud escalated in 2021 when Tesla wasn't invited to an EV summit at the White House. Mr Musk said he found it "odd".&nbsp;</p>

<p>He has been regularly posting in support of Donald Trump and had even said in the past (before Joe Biden stepped aside from the race) that if Mr Biden came back to power then it would be the last free election in America because millions of undocumented immigrants would be legalized and democracy would be finished, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/07/18/us/politics/elon-musk-trump.html" rel="no follow, no index">New York Times reported</a>.</p>

<p>He has shown interest in working with Donald Trump in case he gets reelected, in auditing US agencies to identify programmes for cuts.</p>

<p>Donald Trump has previously acknowledged the Tesla CEO's potential value as a consultant. However, ethics experts are concerned that Mr Musk's involvement may lead to conflicts of interest between his business and the commission's objectives.</p>

<p>The US Presidential elections are scheduled in November. It's a close contest between Kamala Harris and Donald Trump.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/a7gvhmj_elon-musk-kamala-harris_625x300_04_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The US Vice President has not reacted to Elon Musk's post on X.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/meta-to-inform-brazilians-how-it-uses-their-personal-data-to-train-ai-6489034]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Meta To Inform Brazilians How It Uses Their Personal Data To Train AI]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/meta-to-inform-brazilians-how-it-uses-their-personal-data-to-train-ai-6489034]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Sep 2024 16:32:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In July, Meta also actively suspended the use of generative AI tools in Brazil, which included tools used to create popular AI-made stickers for messaging platform WhatsApp]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Social media giant Meta Platforms will inform Brazilians how it intends to use their personal data to train generative artificial intelligence (AI), it said on Tuesday, following a demand from the country's data protection watchdog.</p>

<p>Meta's users in Brazil will receive the warnings starting on Tuesday by email and notifications on Facebook and Instagram and will be able to reject the use of their data by the firm to train generative AI, it said in a statement.</p>

<p>Brazil's National Data Protection Authority (ANPD) in July suspended Meta's new privacy policy over the use of personal data to train AI but overturned this last Friday saying Meta had agreed to issue the disclosures.</p>

<p>In July, Meta also actively suspended the use of generative AI tools in Brazil, which included tools used to create popular AI-made stickers for messaging platform WhatsApp. Brazil is WhatsApp's second-largest customer base.</p>

<p>At the time, Meta said it had decided to suspend the tools while it was in talks with ANPD to address the authority's doubts over its use of generative AI.</p>

<p>Asked by Reuters on Tuesday if it would resume the tools after ANPD lifted the suspension, Meta only reaffirmed that the suspension had been issued while it was in talks with the ANPD.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/tfapom6g_meta-ai_625x300_04_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Meta's users in Brazil will receive the warnings on Tuesday, with an option to opt out.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russias-9m370-burevestnik-5-facts-on-flying-chernobyl-6488892]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russia's 9M370 Burevestnik 'Invincible' Nuke: 5 Facts On 'Flying Chernobyl']]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russias-9m370-burevestnik-5-facts-on-flying-chernobyl-6488892]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Sep 2024 16:18:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US researchers recently located the deployment site of Russia's new nuclear-powered, nuclear-armed cruise missile, the 9M370 Burevestnik. Nicknamed "flying Chernobyl," the missile has been touted by President Putin as "invincible."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<ol>
	<li>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://sputnikglobe.com/20231006/how-russian-stormbringer-nuclear-cruise-missile-can-help-bankrupt-us-war-machine-1113988401.html"><em>Sputnik News,</em></a> Development work on the Burevestnik began in December 2001, shortly after the US announced its intention to withdraw from the ABM Treaty.&nbsp;The Burevestnik missile, with a potential range of 20,000 km, could target locations worldwide from Russia, according to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.iiss.org/en/online-analysis/military-balance/2021/02/burevestnik-russia-cruise-missile/"><em>International Institute for Strategic Studies.</em></a></li>
	<li>"Burevestnik," which means "stormbringer," "prophet of a storm," or "petrel" in Russian, was the name given to the prospective cruise missile in 2018, several weeks after its existence was revealed, in an online vote open to the public by the Russian Defense Ministry.</li>
	<li>Putin has said the weapon - <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-researchers-find-probable-launch-site-of-russias-nuclear-powered-missile-9m370-burevestnik-6475004">dubbed the SSC-X-9 Skyfall by NATO</a> - has an almost unlimited range and can evade US missile defences. But some Western experts dispute his claims and the Burevestnik's strategic value, saying it will not add capabilities that Moscow does not already have and risks a radiation-spewing mishap.</li>
	<li>The two researchers identified a construction project abutting a nuclear warhead storage facility known by two names - Vologda-20 and Chebsara - as the new missile's potential deployment site. The facility is 295 miles (475 km) north of Moscow.</li>
	<li>In 2020, then-UK Chief of Defense Intelligence Lt Gen Jim Hockenhull warned that the Burevestnik has what is effectively a "global reach and would allow attack from unexpected directions," giving Moscow a weapon with a "near infinite loiter time."&nbsp;</li>
</ol>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/s2s7a3b_russias-9m370-burevestnik-is-a-nuclearpowered-missile_625x300_04_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Russia's 9M370 Burevestnik is a nuclear-powered, nuclear-armed cruise missile.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/brave-man-saves-5-year-old-son-from-mountain-lion-attack-in-the-us-6488549]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Brave Man Saves 5-Year-Old Son From Mountain Lion Attack In US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/brave-man-saves-5-year-old-son-from-mountain-lion-attack-in-the-us-6488549]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Sep 2024 15:31:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An American family's Labor Day picnic at Malibu Creek State Park turned into a terrifying ordeal when a mountain lion attacked their 5-year-old son. The father bravely fought off the predator, saving the child.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>During a Labor Day picnic at Malibu Creek State Park in California, an American family experienced a terrifying ordeal when a mountain lion attacked their 5-year-old son. The father's courageous actions brought the situation under control, preventing a potentially fatal disaster. He valiantly fought off the vicious predator, saving his young child.</p>

<p>According to a report by <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://ktla.com/news/local-news/mountain-lion-attacks-5-year-old-boy-at-malibu-creek-state-park/"><em>KTLA5, </em></a>The heart-pounding encounter took place just before 4:30 p.m. Sunday, as the boy's family was relaxing at the Tapia Day Use Area of the Malibu State Creek Park in Calabasas, the Los Angeles County Sheriff's Office said. At least six adults and several children were at the picnic when a mountain lion grabbed the 5-year-old boy by the head and started to run.</p>

<p>The victim's aunt, who did not want to be identified, spoke to <em>KTLA's</em> correspondent about the incident by phone. &nbsp;</p>

<p>"Somebody screamed the baby's name, and his dad started running," she explained. "The father grabbed the mountain lion with his hands, and he just fought. Then the mountain lion let go." &nbsp;</p>

<p>About 40 people in the immediate vicinity witnessed the dangerous incident, some even telling<em> KTLA</em> that the large mountain lion appeared brazen and unafraid during the attack. &nbsp;</p>

<p>According to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.fs.usda.gov/visit/know-before-you-go/mountain-lions#:~:text=Mountain%20lion%20facts,level%20to%2010%2C000%2Dfoot%20elevations.">US Department of Agriculture</a>, the mountain lion is also known as cougar, panther, or puma. May be more than 8 feet long (from the tip of the nose to the tip of the tail) and can weigh between 130 and 150 pounds. Mountain lions can be found in deserts as well as coastal forests, and from sea level to 10,000-foot elevations. An adult male's home range is typically more than 100 square miles, and females generally use smaller areas, approximately 20 to 60 square miles.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/4k9vjuio_mountain-lion_625x300_04_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Numerous witnesses describing the mountain lion as brazen and unafraid.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-research-shows-mobile-phones-are-not-linked-to-brain-cancer-6488201]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[New Research Shows Mobile Phones Are Not Linked To Brain Cancer]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-research-shows-mobile-phones-are-not-linked-to-brain-cancer-6488201]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Sep 2024 14:47:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A systematic review into the potential health effects from radio wave exposure has shown mobile phones are not linked to brain cancer. The review was commissioned by the World Health Organization and is published today.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="theconversation-article-title">A systematic review into the potential health effects from radio wave exposure has shown mobile phones are not linked to brain cancer. The review was commissioned by the World Health Organization and is published today in the journal Environment International.</p>

<div class="theconversation-article-body">
<p>Mobile phones are often held against the head during use. And they emit radio waves, a type of <a href="https://www.arpansa.gov.au/understanding-radiation/what-radiation/what-non-ionising-radiation">non-ionising radiation</a>. These two factors are largely why the idea mobile phones might cause brain cancer emerged in the first place.</p>

<p>The possibility that mobile phones might cause cancer has been a long-standing concern. Mobile phones â€“ and wireless tech more broadly â€“ are a major part of our daily lives. So it's been vital for science to address the safety of radio wave exposure from these devices.</p>

<p>Over the years, the scientific consensus has remained strong â€“ there's no association between mobile phone radio waves and brain cancer, or health more generally.</p>

<h3><strong>Radiation as a possible carcinogen</strong></h3>

<p>Despite the consensus, occasional research studies have been published that suggest the possibility of harm.</p>

<p>In 2011, the International Agency for Research on Cancer (IARC) classified <a href="https://www.iarc.who.int/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/pr208_E.pdf">radio wave exposure as a possible carcinogen to humans</a>. The meaning of this classification was largely misunderstood and led to some increase in concern.</p>

<p>IARC is part of the World Health Organization. Its classification of radio waves as a possible carcinogen was largely based on limited evidence from human observational studies. Also known as epidemiological studies, they observe the rate of disease and how it may be caused in human populations.</p>

<p>Observational studies are the best tool researchers have to investigate long-term health effects in humans, but the results can often be biased.</p>

<p>The IARC classification relied on previous observational studies where people with brain cancer reported they used a mobile phone more than they actually did. One example of this is known as <a href="https://academic.oup.com/ije/article/39/3/675/631387?login=false">the INTERPHONE study</a>.</p>

<p>This new systematic review of human observational studies is based on a much larger data set compared to what the IARC examined in 2011.</p>

<p>It includes more recent and more comprehensive studies. This means we can now be more confident that exposure to radio waves from mobile phones or wireless technologies is not associated with an increased risk of brain cancer.</p>

<h3><strong>No association</strong></h3>

<p>The new review forms part of a <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/special-issue/109J1SL7CXT">series of systematic reviews</a> commissioned by the World Health Organization to look more closely at possible health effects associated with exposure to radio waves.</p>

<p>This systematic review provides the strongest evidence to date that radio waves from wireless technologies are not a hazard to human health.</p>

<p>It is the most comprehensive review on this topic â€“ it considered more than 5,000 studies, of which 63, published between 1994 and 2022, were included in the final analysis. The main reason studies were excluded was that they were not actually relevant; this is very normal with search results from systematic reviews.</p>

<p>No association between mobile phone use and brain cancer, or any other head or neck cancer, was found.</p>

<p>There was also no association with cancer if a person used a mobile phone for ten or more years (prolonged use). How often they used it â€“ either based on the number of calls or the time spent on the phone â€“ also didn't make a difference.</p>

<p>Importantly, these findings align with <a href="https://bmjopen.bmj.com/content/8/12/e024489.full">previous research</a>. It shows that, although the use of wireless technologies has massively increased in the past few decades, there has been no rise in the incidence of brain cancers.</p>

<h3><strong>A good thing</strong></h3>

<p>Overall, the results are very reassuring. They mean that our <a href="https://www.arpansa.gov.au/regulation-and-licensing/regulatory-publications/radiation-protection-series/codes-and-standards/rpss-1">national</a> and <a href="https://www.icnirp.org/en/publications/article/rf-guidelines-2020.html">international</a> safety limits are protective. Mobile phones emit low-level radio waves below these safety limits, and there is no evidence exposure to these has an impact on human health.</p>

<p>Despite this, it is important that research continues. Technology is developing at a rapid pace. With this development comes the use of radio waves in different ways using different frequencies. It is therefore essential that science continues to ensure radio wave exposure from these technologies remains safe.</p>

<p>The challenge we now face is making sure this new research counteracts the persistent misconceptions and misinformation out there regarding mobile phones and brain cancer.</p>

<p>There remains no evidence of any established health effects from exposures related to mobile phones, and that is a good thing.<!-- Below is The Conversation's page counter tag. Please DO NOT REMOVE. --><img alt="The Conversation" height="1" referrerpolicy="no-referrer-when-downgrade" src="https://counter.theconversation.com/content/237882/count.gif?distributor=republish-lightbox-basic" style="border: none !important; box-shadow: none !important; margin: 0 !important; max-height: 1px !important; max-width: 1px !important; min-height: 1px !important; min-width: 1px !important; opacity: 0 !important; outline: none !important; padding: 0 !important" width="1" /><!-- End of code. If you don't see any code above, please get new code from the Advanced tab after you click the republish button. The page counter does not collect any personal data. More info: https://theconversation.com/republishing-guidelines --></p>

<p><em><span><a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/sarah-loughran-185774">Sarah Loughran</a>, Director of Radiation Research and Advice, Australian Radiation Protection and Nuclear Safety Agency (ARPANSA), and Adjunct Associate Professor, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/university-of-wollongong-711">University of Wollongong</a> and <a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/ken-karipidis-1647392">Ken Karipidis</a>, Assistant Director, of Health Impact Assessment, Australian Radiation Protection and Nuclear Safety Agency (ARPANSA), and Adjunct Associate Professor (Practice), School of Public Health and Preventive Medicine, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/monash-university-1065">Monash University</a></span></em></p>

<p><em>This article is republished from <a href="https://theconversation.com">The Conversation</a> under a Creative Commons license. Read the <a href="https://theconversation.com/mobile-phones-are-not-linked-to-brain-cancer-according-to-a-major-review-of-28-years-of-research-237882">original article</a>.</em></p>
</div><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-11/545d8c3o_mobile-phone-generic-_625x300_02_November_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The possibility that mobile phones might cause cancer has been a long-standing concern (representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/rafi-songs-to-roti-bruneis-deep-cultural-connect-with-india-6488122]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: Rafi Songs To Roti, Brunei's Deep Cultural Connect With India]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/rafi-songs-to-roti-bruneis-deep-cultural-connect-with-india-6488122]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Sep 2024 14:38:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[While it's heartening to see the influence of Indian culture in Brunei even before Prime Minister Modis visit, India must further engage with this small yet affluent nation to enhance its strategic position in the region.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/qqvetf6g_brunei_625x300_04_September_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Brunei, a tiny yet relatively new nation, holds a wealth of records and a lengthy list of&nbsp;landmarks. From the ruler's long and elaborate official nameâ€”Sultan Haji Hassanal Bolkiah Mu'izzaddin Waddaulah ibni Al-Marhum Sultan Haji Omar â€˜Ali Saifuddien Sa'adul Khairi Waddienâ€”to his claim as one of the wealthiest rulers and the world's longest-reigning monarch, Brunei consistently makes its mark in the record books. However, this former British protectorate, which gained full independence in 1984, is more than its oil riches and opulence.</p>

<h2><strong>Bonded Through Language and History</strong></h2>

<p>The country is officially known as Negara Brunei Darussalam in its official language, Malay, or Bahasa Melayu. The Malay term â€œBahasaâ€ originates from the Sanskrit word â€œbhashaâ€, meaning language, while â€œNegaraâ€ is derived from the Sanskrit word â€œNagara/Nagariâ€, meaning city. Brunei's capital, Bandar Seri Begawan, was renamed in 1970 from its previous name, Bandar Brunei, to honour the country's former ruler, Sultan Omar Ali Saifuddien III, whose name draws from the Sanskrit term â€œShri Bhagwanâ€, meaning Lord Almighty or â€˜the Blessed One'.</p>

<p>Over a century ago, a historical connection to India emerged when British soldier and sojourner James Brooke, born in Bandel, West Bengal, was granted a significant portion of Brunei's territory in 1841 by Sultan Omar Ali Saifuddin II for quelling a rebellion. Brooke later received the title of Rajahâ€”derived from the Sanskrit word for Kingâ€”of Sarawak, now a state in Malaysia, and became known as the White Rajah.</p>

<h2><strong>Not-So-Proactive Engagement</strong></h2>

<p>During my recent visit to Bandar Seri Begawan, particularly at the Royal Regalia Museum in the heart of the capital, I spotted a photograph of an Indian teacher dressed in a saree. The image featured the current ruler from his student days at Sultan Omar Ali Saifuddien College in 1964. Surprisingly, amidst the museum's glittering collection of royal regaliaâ€”showcasing exquisite state gifts from several heads of state and top ministers from countries like China, Singapore, Thailand, Pakistan, Ukraine, and the USAâ€”the Indian gift was attributed to a former Indian High Commissioner and not a minister.</p>

<h2><strong>PM's Historic Visit</strong></h2>

<p>Linguistically and historically, Brunei and India share a long-standing connection. However, their geopolitical relations require a boost, particularly as India aims to enhance its role in the Indo-Pacific region. Notably, no Indian Prime Minister had visited Brunei for a bilateral discussion before Narendra Modi embarked on a trip as part of his proactive Act East policy. Although Brunei's Sandhurst-educated Sultan has made four visits to India since the establishment of diplomatic ties in 1984, Prime Minister Manmohan Singh was the only Indian leader to visit Brunei for two back-to-back multilateral eventsâ€”the 11th ASEAN-India Summit and the 8th East Asia Summitâ€”held in Bandar Seri Begawan in October 2013. The transition from the earlier Look East policy to a more active Act East policy began after Modi took office in 2014, leading to the first-ever high-level bilateral visit to Brunei by Vice-President Hamid Ansari in 2016.</p>

<h2><strong>Oil-Driven Economic Partnerships</strong></h2>

<p>Brunei boasts a high-income, oil-rich economy. Despite the pandemic's temporary stagnation of its oil-driven sector, Brunei maintains a currency valued at par with Singapore's dollar, which is also widely used in the country. India's primary exports to Brunei include automobiles, transport equipment, rice, and spices. Conversely, India is one of Brunei's largest importers of crude oil, with annual imports valued at approximately $500-600 million. At the recently opened Brunei Energy Hub, an interactive oil and gas museum in Bandar Seri Begawan, the country's oil and gas development timeline highlights India as one of the â€œkey customersâ€ of Brunei Shell Petroleum (BSP), a joint venture between the Government of Brunei and Shell, noting the first delivery of oil cargo to India in 2003, with approximately 25,000 barrels supplied each year thereafter. A significant portion of Brunei's Indian diaspora, nearly 15,000, primarily works in the oil and gas sector, with an increasing number of unskilled Indian workers entering the construction and other unorganised sectors in recent years.</p>

<h2><strong>Eye On China</strong></h2>

<p>With 161 kilometres of coastline along the South China Sea, Brunei, home to nearly 4,50,000 people, holds both geographical and geopolitical significance in the Indo-Pacific region. The nation is a silent claimant to this contested maritime area, maintaining a delicate balance in its relations with China and other ASEAN neighbours, despite China's growing assertiveness in the region. In May of this year, Brunei signed a maritime cooperation agreement with the Philippines, which has recently taken a stand against China's aggression in the South China Sea, officially referring to the area near its coastline as the West Philippine Sea. Simultaneously, the Islamic nation has strengthened its defence ties with India over the years. Prime Minister Modi's visit is anticipated to solidify this relationship, especially in light of China's expanding influence in the region.</p>

<h2><strong>Culinary Connection</strong></h2>

<p>Interestingly, Brunei's population comprises more than 10% Chinese immigrants, with nearly 70% of their ancestors hailing from the Taiwanese islands of Kinmen. This group fled heavy shelling by China during the First and Second Taiwan Strait crises in the 1950s. While enjoying traditional â€˜roti kacang kahwin' and â€˜roti kuning kahwin' (the word "roti" means bread in Malay, like in Hindi) at Chop Jing Chew, a historic bakery and eatery in Bandar Seri Begawan, I was surprised to find that the Chinese-immigrant-owned establishment is run entirely by Indian staff. My culinary exploration also revealed that one of Brunei's most popular and top-rated (by Tripadvisor) restaurants, Riyaz, located in a prominent hotel, is managed by a team of Indian chefs and hospitality staff.</p>

<h2><strong>Bollywood's Soft Power</strong></h2>

<p>A visit to another well-regarded restaurant, Soto Pabo, along the Brunei riverfront, highlighted Brunei's deep-rooted cross-cultural connection with India. I encountered two elderly Bruneians jamming with a guitar, who greeted me with a warm "Namaste" in fluent Hindi. After introducing myself and joining their gathering, one of them, Hajiali, told me that he had studied in Lucknow for a year in the 1970s. The septuagenarian, together with his friend and the eatery's owner's octogenarian father-in-law, entertained us with a medley of classic Bollywood songs. I was captivated by the nostalgic tunes of Mukesh's â€œSawan Ka Mahina,â€ Kishore Kumar's â€œZindagi Ek Safar,â€ and Mohammad Rafi's â€œJo Wada Kiya.â€ A little later, after savouring their signature Ambuyat setâ€”a traditional Bruneian mealâ€”I took a ferry to Kampung Ayer, a traditional water village near the capital. As we sailed through the mangroves populated with long-nosed proboscis monkeys&nbsp;(featured in the&nbsp;<i>Tintin&nbsp;</i>adventure, Flight 714), the boatman began singing â€œKuch Kuch Hota Haiâ€ upon learning my nationality. This experience reminded me of my travels to Timor-Leste and Indonesia, where locals also fondly recalled the Bollywood classic. It was a profound demonstration of India's enduring soft power through Bollywood.&nbsp;</p>

<p>While it's heartening to see the influence of Indian culture in Brunei even before Prime Minister Modi's visit, India must further engage with this small yet affluent nation to enhance its strategic position in the region.</p>

<p><i>(Suvam Pal works as a broadcast journalist with TaiwanPlus news channel in Taipei)</i></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/6qgu0aqg_brunei_625x300_04_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-modi-in-singapore-to-enhance-strategic-ties-know-all-about-his-visit-6488099]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[PM Modi In Singapore To Enhance Strategic Ties. Know All About His Visit]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-modi-in-singapore-to-enhance-strategic-ties-know-all-about-his-visit-6488099]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Sep 2024 14:33:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[PM Modi has arrived in Singapore for his official two-day visit to further strengthen bilateral ties between the two nations. The prime minister's visit to Singapore comes after a historic visit to Brunei as part of New Delhi's 'Act East' policy.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi has arrived in Singapore for his official two-day visit to further strengthen bilateral ties between the two nations. The prime minister's visit to Singapore comes after a historic visit to Brunei as part of New Delhi's 'Act East' policy.</p>

<p>India and Singapore already share a strategic alliance in the region and PM Modi's visit today aims to "deepen the strategic partnership". Prime Minister Modi is visiting Singapore at the invitation of his counterpart Lawrence Wong.</p>

<p>The prime minister's visit comes after six years. PM Modi's previous visit was in 2018. "His first visit to Singapore was in his first term as the Prime Minister. This visit is of great significance as it's his visit early in his term, and also as the new Prime Minister Lawrence Wong has taken oath recently and Singaporeans are excited to welcome PM Modi," Secretary East, Ministry of External Affairs, Jaideep Mazumdar said.</p>

<p>PM Modi's visit comes within days of Lawrence Wong becoming the new prime minister of Singapore and within weeks of Narendra Modi taking charge as Prime Minister for his third consecutive term.</p>

<p>Ahead of his arrival in Singapore, PM Modi shared a post on X, which reads, "I look forward to my discussions to deepen our Strategic Partnership with Singapore, particularly in new and emerging areas of advanced manufacturing, digitalisation, and sustainable development."</p>

<p>Prime Minister Modi, who last visited Singapore in 2018, is accompanied by Minister of External Affairs S Jaishankar, National Security Adviser Ajit Doval and other top government officials.</p>

<p>"The leaders will review the progress of India-Singapore Strategic Partnership and exchange views on regional and global issues of mutual interest," a Ministry of External Affairs (MEA) statement said ahead of his departure for Brunei and Singapore.</p>

<p>Foreign Minister S Jaishankar said "India and Singapore's bilateral ties "have been extremely strong in the last two decades."</p>

<p>"Given the transformation underway in India and the changes in the world, they need to become more contemporary. In many ways, that is why Prime Minister Narendra Modi has chosen to visit Singapore so early in his third term," The Straits Times quoted Mr Jaishankar as saying in an interview.</p>

<p>"Just like Singapore had an opportunity in 1992 and then again in 2006, it should seize the moment and fully utilise the new landscape," the minister said.</p>

<p><strong>PM MODI'S MEETINGS</strong></p>

<p>During his visit, PM Modi will receive an official welcome at the Parliament House tomorrow and will also meet President Tharman Shanmugaratnam, apart from his meeting with Prime Minister L:awrence Wong.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Modi is also scheduled to meet three generations of Singapore's leadership and will meet top CEO's as well.</p>

<p>PM Modi will meet senior minister Lee Hsien Loong and Emeritus senior minister Goh Chok Tong. Mr Wong and Mr Lee will host Prime Minister Modi for separate meals.</p>

<p>PM Modi will also meet business leaders and interact with those in the country's semiconductor ecosystem. This visit will build synergies in semiconductor ecosystems of Singapore and India. Both PMs will visit a semiconductor manufacturing facility, officials said.</p>

<p><strong>AGREEMENTS TO BE SIGNED</strong></p>

<p>Memorandums of Understanding or MoUs will be signed for cooperation in manpower skilling in the semiconductor sector. From skilling centres to training and recruitment by Singapore firms, this will help India's youth with better skills and opportunities, officials added.</p>

<p>Agreements are also likely in the areas of maritime cooperation, maritime security, trade, investment, digitisation, skill, sustainability, health, advanced manufacturing and connectivity.</p>

<p><strong>INDIA-SINGAPORE TIES</strong></p>

<p>Singapore is India's largest trade partner in ASEAN. It is also a leading source of Foreign Direct Investment (FDI) in the last financial year with an investment of $11.77 billion in 2023 alone. Singapore has been a long-term investor in India. Since 2000 till now, we have an accumulative FDI of USD 160 billion dollars.</p>

<p>"This is an opportune time to set the stage for India-Singapore's vibrant bilateral relations for the next stage of India-Singapore bilateral relations. Our ties have evolved and we have a dynamic strategic partnership encompassing diverse areas from our shared history and people-to-people ties, which form an important link between us," the Ministry of External Affairs said ahead of the PM's visit.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/cektlbho_narendra-modi-singapore-pm-lawrence-wong_625x300_30_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[PM Modi is on a two-day official visit to Singapore and will meet his counterpart Lawrence Wong]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/screen-time-in-bed-is-worse-than-screen-time-before-bed-study-6488051]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Screen Time In Bed Is Worse Than Screen Time Before Bed: Study]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/screen-time-in-bed-is-worse-than-screen-time-before-bed-study-6488051]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Sep 2024 14:26:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Parents of children and teenagers have long been warned about the dangers of screen time and digital devices before bed the worry being that screens could harm the sleep patterns of young people.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="theconversation-article-title">Parents of children and teenagers have long been warned about the dangers of screen time and digital devices before bed â€“ the worry being that screens could harm the sleep patterns of young people.</p>

<div class="theconversation-article-body">
<p>But do screens really hurt the length and quality of sleep?</p>

<p>Our <a href="https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamapediatrics/article-abstract/2822859">new research</a> found that using screens in bed was worse for sleep than using screens for hours before going to bed.</p>

<p>Sleep guidelines recommend no screen use in an hour or two before bed. However, we found screen time in the two hours before bed had little impact on young people's sleep. Instead, it was screen time once in bed that caused problems.</p>

<p>Using cameras to track device usage and sleep, we found using a device in bed could cause more harm than screen time right up to bedtime.</p>

<p>These findings challenge long-held assumptions about screen time at night and could help parents improve the quality of their children's sleep.</p>

<h3><strong>Connecting sleep and screens</strong></h3>

<p>A number of global organisations <a href="https://www.sleepfoundation.org/teens-and-sleep/screen-time-and-insomnia-for-teens">recommend adolescents stop using devices</a> in the hour or two before bed, and instead <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5839336/">undertake activities</a> like reading a book or quiet time with the family.</p>

<p>However, these recommendations are based on research with a number of limitations. The studies were designed in such a way that researchers could link sleep and screens. But they don't tell us if changes in how young people used screens had an effect on the length or quality of sleep.</p>

<p>Most of the existing research also used questionnaires to assess both screen time and sleep. Questionnaires are unlikely to capture true screen time accurately, particularly if you are interested in knowing more than just how long an adolescent has spent on their device.</p>

<p>To address some of these weaknesses in the previous research, we asked 85 adolescents aged between 11 and 14 to wear a body camera on their chest for three hours before bed, for four nights.</p>

<p>These cameras faced outwards and accurately captured when and how adolescents used their screens. Because we were interested in overnight screen time as well, a second infrared camera was placed on a tripod in the teenagers' bedroom and captured their screen time while in bed. The research participants also wore an actigraph â€“ a watch-sized device that objectively measured screen time.</p>

<h3><strong>Teen nighttime activity</strong></h3>

<p>It quickly became obvious that adolescents spent a lot of their screen time while in bed.</p>

<p>Our analysis looked at two time periods â€“ from the two hours before they got into bed, and from once they were in bed (clearly under the covers) until they put their devices down and were clearly trying to go to sleep.</p>

<p>Our data showed that 99% of the adolescents used screens in two hours before bed, more than half once they were in bed, and a third even after first trying to go to sleep for the night. Just one teenager did not use screens before bed on any of the four nights.</p>

<p>The screen time before they got into bed had little impact on their sleep that night. However, screen time once in bed did impair their sleep. It stopped them from going to sleep for about half an hour, and reduced the amount of sleep they got that night.</p>

<p>This was particularly true for more interactive screen activities like gaming and multitasking â€“ when they use more than one device at the same time (like watching a movie on Netflix on a laptop while playing Xbox on a gaming device).</p>

<p>In fact, every additional ten minutes of this type of screen time reduced the amount of sleep they got that night by almost the same amount â€“ nine minutes.</p>

<h3><strong>Revisiting guidelines</strong></h3>

<p>Our research was an observational study looking at the established screen habits of young people.</p>

<p>The next step to better understand this will be to conduct experiments that can actually prove different types and timings of screen time affect sleep.</p>

<p>That said, what we have already found challenges existing guidelines. Screens at night may not be the bogeyman they have been made out to be. However, allowing young people to have screens in bed can be detrimental to their quality of sleep.</p>

<p>So the simple message might be to keep those devices out of the bedroom.<!-- Below is The Conversation's page counter tag. Please DO NOT REMOVE. --><img alt="The Conversation" height="1" referrerpolicy="no-referrer-when-downgrade" src="https://counter.theconversation.com/content/237955/count.gif?distributor=republish-lightbox-basic" style="border: none !important; box-shadow: none !important; margin: 0 !important; max-height: 1px !important; max-width: 1px !important; min-height: 1px !important; min-width: 1px !important; opacity: 0 !important; outline: none !important; padding: 0 !important" width="1" /><!-- End of code. If you don't see any code above, please get new code from the Advanced tab after you click the republish button. The page counter does not collect any personal data. More info: https://theconversation.com/republishing-guidelines --></p>

<p><em><span><a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/rachael-taylor-1649269">Rachael Taylor</a>, Professor, Department of Medicine, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/university-of-otago-1304">University of Otago</a></span></em></p>

<p><em>This article is republished from <a href="https://theconversation.com">The Conversation</a> under a Creative Commons license. Read the <a href="https://theconversation.com/its-almost-impossible-to-keep-teens-off-their-phones-in-bed-but-new-research-shows-it-really-does-affect-their-sleep-237955">original article</a>.</em></p>
</div><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/fmeipelo_screen-time-_625x300_04_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sleep guidelines recommend no screen use in an hour or two before bed (representational).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jonny-kim-this-navy-seal-mathematician-harvard-doctor-will-now-be-a-nasa-astronaut-6487696]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[This Navy SEAL, Mathematician, Harvard Doctor Will Now Be A NASA Astronaut]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jonny-kim-this-navy-seal-mathematician-harvard-doctor-will-now-be-a-nasa-astronaut-6487696]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Sep 2024 13:38:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Lieutenant Commander Jonny Kim has a resume that would make Asian parents swell with pride. At 40, he is already a decorated Navy SEAL, a Harvard-trained physician, and now, a NASA astronaut preparing for his next great adventure  space.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lieutenant Commander Jonny Kim has a resume that would make Asian parents swell with pride. At 40, he is already a decorated Navy SEAL, a Harvard-trained physician, and now, a NASA astronaut preparing for his next great adventure â€“ space.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
The Los Angeles native joined <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/news-release/nasa-assigns-astronaut-jonny-kim-to-first-space-station-mission/Â ">NASA</a> in 2017 and will be launched into space aboard the Roscosmos Soyuz MS-27 spacecraft in March 2025. On his mission, accompanied by two Russian cosmonauts, he will spend nearly eight months aboard the International Space Station (ISS), conducting critical scientific investigations and preparing the station for future missions.<br />
<br />
Mr Kim's journey to the stars is as impressive as his other accomplishments. He earned a bachelor's degree in mathematics from the University of San Diego before graduating from Harvard Medical School. He served as an emergency room intern at Massachusetts General Hospital.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
But his medical career came after a decade of service as a Navy SEAL. He is also a dual-designated naval aviator and flight surgeon.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
In NASA, Mr Kim has played several roles, including that of lead operations officer for Expedition 65 and the T-38 operations liaison, within the organisation. Now, he is set to take on his most challenging role yet â€“ living and working in space.<br />
<br />
Mr Kim's mission comes when NASA is grappling with unforeseen challenges. Two other astronauts, Sunita Williams and Butch Wilmore, remain stranded on the ISS due to malfunctions in the Boeing Starliner spacecraft.<br />
<br />
The issues, caused by helium leaks that were more extensive than previously believed, have forced NASA to delay their return to Earth until a SpaceX Crew Dragon capsule can bring them home in February next year.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/ko30q1jg_jonny-kim_625x300_04_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/campaign-launched-to-increase-participation-of-indian-americans-in-us-polls-6487668]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Campaign Launched To Increase Participation Of Indian-Americans In US Polls]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/campaign-launched-to-increase-participation-of-indian-americans-in-us-polls-6487668]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Sep 2024 13:33:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ahead of the November 5 US presidential elections, an Indian diaspora group has launched a campaign to increase the policy impact and participation of Indian-American voters in the polls.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ahead of the November 5 US presidential elections, an Indian diaspora group has launched a campaign to increase the policy impact and participation of Indian-American voters in the polls.</p>

<p>Launched by the non-profit institution Foundation for India and Indian Diaspora Studies (FIIDS), the "Indo American Votes Matter" campaign underscores the critical role the community can play in shaping the nation's future, a statement issued on Tuesday said.</p>

<p>"As a vibrant and growing immigrant minority, Indo-Americans-- numbering approximately 4.5 million across the United States -- have a unique opportunity to make a significant impact in the 2024 elections. Concentrated in key swing states such as Florida, Georgia, Arizona, Virginia, New Jersey, and Pennsylvania, the Indo-American vote could be decisive in determining the outcome of crucial races," the FIIDS said.</p>

<p>A comprehensive survey of Indian-Americans will gather their views on both domestic and global policy matters of the US important to them, it said.</p>

<p>"With a sizable population in swing states crucial to the presidential elections, Indian-Americans have a unique opportunity to make an impact," said Khanderao Kand, chief of policy and strategy at FIIDS.</p>

<p>"Therefore, their policy issues and preferences should be seriously considered by both the Republican National Committee (RNC) and the Democratic National Committee (DNC). With the voters registration campaign, we want to have at least a million plus Indian American voters in this election," Kand said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ugf3uu1g_trump-harris-_625x300_22_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The "Indo American Votes Matter" campaign marks the the critical role the Indian diaspora can play (file)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>