<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Sep 2024 21:05:03 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/apple-event-2024-apple-glowtime-event-2024-everything-to-expect-from-apples-iphone-16-launch-on-september-9-6506923]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Apple Event 2024: Everything To Expect From Apple's iPhone 16 Launch]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/apple-event-2024-apple-glowtime-event-2024-everything-to-expect-from-apples-iphone-16-launch-on-september-9-6506923]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Sep 2024 21:05:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Apple Inc.'s most important event of the year takes place Monday, when the company will roll out its latest iPhones and set the stage for a new artificial intelligence platform.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Apple Inc.'s most important event of the year takes place Monday, when the company will roll out its latest iPhones and set the stage for a new artificial intelligence platform.</p>

<p>The event kicks off from Apple's headquarters in Cupertino, California, on Sept. 9 at 10 a.m. local time. Apple doesn't typically hold this event on a Monday, but the earlier timing lets the company get out ahead of an eventful Tuesday: There's a US presidential debate that day, and the European Commission is slated to announce a decision on whether Apple has to pay $14 billion in taxes stemming from a longstanding agreement with Ireland.</p>

<p>The most significant product announcement will be the iPhone 16 line, but the company is also preparing major updates to both the Apple Watch and AirPods. Apple Intelligence - a new suite of AI tools that includes an updated Siri digital assistant - also will feature prominently. The theme of the event, "It's Glowtime," is a reference to Siri's new interface.</p>

<p>The stakes are high for Apple, which looks to prove to both consumers and Wall Street that it's now a major player in generative artificial intelligence. But the company's AI technology is still a work in progress. Apple Intelligence has faced numerous delays, and many key features won't arrive until next year. For now, the technology is focused on summarizing messages and notifications, rather than matching the dazzling interactivity of rival systems.</p>

<p>Even so, Monday's updates will breathe new life into products that sit at the heart of the Apple device lineup and generate roughly 60% of the company's annual revenue. They also drive consumer spending on services, an increasingly vital source of sales. Apple's finances could use the boost. The company has only just begun to emerge from its longest sales slump in decades.</p>

<p><strong>Here's everything that's expected to be announced at Monday's presentation:</strong></p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Apple's iPhone 15 Pro.(Photographer: David Paul Morris / Bloomberg)" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/9eb18i6o_apple-iphone-bloomberg_625x300_06_September_24.jpg" title="Apple's iPhone 15 Pro.(Photographer: David Paul Morris / Bloomberg)" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">Apple's iPhone 15 Pro.(Photographer: David Paul Morris / Bloomberg)</p>
</div>

<p><strong>iPHONE</strong></p>

<p>In line with the past several years, Apple will introduce four new iPhone models: the iPhone 16, 16 Plus, 16 Pro and 16 Pro Max.</p>

<p>Like in 2023, the changes to the non-Pro iPhones will be minor. The iPhone 16 and 16 Plus will look like last year's versions, including 6.1-inch and 6.7-inch screen sizes and aluminum cases. They'll gain faster processors and include a total of 8 gigabytes of memory (up from 6). That memory will help support Apple Intelligence and other features.</p>

<p>Those lower-end phones will get the same Action button currently featured on the Pro models, as well as vertically stacked rear cameras that support spatial video recording - the 3D clips that can be viewed with Apple's Vision Pro headsets.</p>

<p>The iPhone 16 Pro and Pro Max, meanwhile, will retain the iPhone 15 Pro line design save for one noticeable change: the displays. The screen sizes are increasing to 6.3 inches on the smaller model (up from from 6.1 inches) and going to 6.9 inches from 6.7 inches on the Max version. While the changes represent an increase of less than 5% on both models, the shift will come with bezels that are now about a third slimmer. That should make for a sleeker overall look.</p>

<p>Like the iPhone 15 Pro line, the 16 Pro models will support Apple Intelligence with the inclusion of 8 gigabytes of memory. They'll also get speedier chips with an enhanced neural engine that Apple will say is optimized for AI.</p>

<p>Both of the iPhone 16 Pro models will get camera upgrades as well, including a move to a 48-megapixel lens from a 12-megapixel one for the ultrawide-angle camera. That will match the megapixels of the standard, wide-angle camera on last year's model. The smaller iPhone 16 Pro will also gain 5x optical zoom on the telephoto lens, up from 3x, to match the Max version.</p>

<p>The most significant camera enhancement coming to both models: a dedicated, touch-sensitive button on the right side of the phone for taking photos and video. This button will be the biggest selling point for the new iPhones, other than AI. It will work similarly to a shutter button on a DSLR camera, allowing a user to lightly press it to focus on a subject and then press harder to take a picture. It will also be capacitive, allowing a user to swipe across it to move between still and video modes and zoom in and out.</p>

<p>While the phones will all look mostly the same as last year, Apple is shaking up its color palette. The Pro models will now come in a gold titanium to replace blue titanium, while the black, white and natural options will still be available. The non-Pro versions will trade in yellow for white and get new shades of green, pink and blue.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="An AirPods display at an Apple retail store. (Photographer: Hollie Adams / Bloomberg)" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/uika34ag_apple-airpods-bloomberg_625x300_06_September_24.jpg" title="An AirPods display at an Apple retail store. (Photographer: Hollie Adams / Bloomberg)" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">An AirPods display at an Apple retail store. (Photographer: Hollie Adams / Bloomberg)</p>
</div>

<p><strong>AIRPODS</strong></p>

<p>Apple is preparing two new AirPods models to replace the entry-level, second-generation earbuds and mid-tier, third-generation model. Both new versions will look similar to the AirPods Pro and include a new case, USB-C charging and improved audio quality.</p>

<p>Apple will distinguish the two models by giving the new mid-tier version a higher-end case with a speaker - making it easier to locate with Apple's Find My feature - as well as noise cancellation to match the AirPods Pro.</p>

<p>A few weeks ago, Apple discovered a bug in the upcoming AirPods that made the earbuds quickly drain battery life. This issue was determined to be software-related and resolved prior to factories shipping out the products.</p>

<p>One major new feature is a bigger push into hearing health. Apple has been working to turn the AirPods into a replacement for hearing aids as well as a device for conducting hearing tests. The company is preparing to announce the enhancements - codenamed Yodel - but they've suffered some delays and may not be available until later.</p>

<p>A new version of the AirPods Pro remains in the works, including an upgraded design and improved noise cancellation. It's due as early as next year.</p>

<p>And Apple has been working on updated AirPods Max headphones that will come in new colors and switch the Lightning connector to USB-C to comply with the latest laws from the European Union. But there's still plenty of current AirPods Max inventory on hand, suggesting that the update could be coming later.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="The Apple Watch Ultra 2. (Photographer: David Paul Morris / Bloomberg)" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/v974p7o4_apple-watch-ultra-2-bloomberg_625x300_06_September_24.jpg" title="The Apple Watch Ultra 2. (Photographer: David Paul Morris / Bloomberg)" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">The Apple Watch Ultra 2. (Photographer: David Paul Morris / Bloomberg)</p>
</div>

<p><strong>APPLE WATCH</strong></p>

<p>For the first time in two years, the company is preparing to update all of its Apple Watch models at once. There will be a new low-end Apple Watch SE, a mid-level Series 10 model and an Ultra 3.</p>

<p>The Apple Watch Ultra will only get minor tweaks, focusing on internal upgrades rather than outside changes.</p>

<p>The biggest upgrade to the Apple Watch line will be with the Series 10 model, which marks the decade anniversary of the product's introduction in 2014. For the first time since the Series 7, the flagship Apple Watch model will get an updated look.</p>

<p>The overall design will be similar to the Apple Watch Series 9, but the company will now offer slightly larger screen-size options and the watch case itself will be noticeably thinner.</p>

<p>Though new AI features are coming to the iPhone, iPad and Mac, don't expect the watches to get major Apple Intelligence capabilities. Any AI technology will probably be tied specifically to a future health coach service.</p>

<p>At the start of the year, Apple was forced to remove blood-oxygen sensing from new watches due to a lawsuit with Masimo Corp. over patents. There's been no evidence that the feature is returning in time for the latest models, and that may affect whether users want to upgrade their existing watches to versions that won't have the function.</p>

<p>A major new health feature is coming, though: sleep apnea detection, which will build on the existing sleep tracking. This feature will attempt to determine if a wearer has sleep apnea and then suggest further testing with a medical professional. While Apple has been preparing to announce it, the enhancement may not be available on day one of the new model going on sale.</p>

<p>On the other hand, while Apple aimed to bring hypertension - or high blood pressure - detection to the Apple Watch this year, signs point to that feature being delayed and no longer in the cards for an immediate release.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Apple's MacBook Pro. (Photographer: Samsul Said / Bloomberg)" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/11iik5sk_apple-macbook-pro-bloomberg_625x300_06_September_24.jpg" title="Apple's MacBook Pro. (Photographer: Samsul Said / Bloomberg)" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">Apple's MacBook Pro. (Photographer: Samsul Said / Bloomberg)</p>
</div>

<p><strong>OTHER PRODUCTS</strong></p>

<p>Apple is working on transitioning its entire Mac line to M4 chips, starting with the MacBook Pro, Mac mini and iMac. But any Mac upgrades are likely to come at a follow-up launch - no earlier than October - rather than at the September event.</p>

<p>While the company has been working on an update to the Apple TV set-top box for as early as this year, no new model has come to fruition and stable inventory of the device suggests a new version isn't on the immediate horizon.</p>

<p>A new iPhone SE with an OLED display, edge-to-edge screen and no home button is in advanced testing, but a release isn't planned until next year. A fresh AirTag is also in development, though Apple isn't planning a release until next year either.</p>

<p>There are also new iPads in the works, including an upgraded mini version. They're on deck for Apple's October event alongside the M4 Macs.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/c9mf5958_apple-logo-apple-event-reuters_625x300_06_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Apple Event: Apple Glowtime Event, where the iPhone 16 will be launched, is scheduled for September 9]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-iraq-deal-would-see-hundreds-of-troops-withdraw-in-1st-year-report-6506853]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US-Iraq Deal Would See Hundreds Of Troops Withdraw In 1st Year: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-iraq-deal-would-see-hundreds-of-troops-withdraw-in-1st-year-report-6506853]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:53:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United States and Iraq have reached an understanding on plans for the withdrawal of US-led coalition forces from Iraq, according to multiple sources familiar with the matter.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United States and Iraq have reached an understanding on plans for the withdrawal of US-led coalition forces from Iraq, according to multiple sources familiar with the matter.</p>

<p>The plan, which has been broadly agreed but requires a final go-ahead from both capitals and an announcement date, would see hundreds of troops leave by September 2025, with the remainder departing by the end of 2026, the sources said.</p>

<p>"We have an agreement, its now just a question of when to announce it," a senior US official said.</p>

<p>The US and Iraq are also seeking to establish a new advisory relationship that could see some US troops remain in Iraq after the drawdown.</p>

<p>An official announcement was initially scheduled for weeks ago but was postponed due to regional escalation related to Israel's war in Gaza and to iron out some remaining details, the sources said.</p>

<p>The sources include five US officials, two officials from other coalition nations, and three Iraqi officials, all speaking on condition of anonymity as they were not authorized to discuss the matter publicly.</p>

<p>Several sources said the deal could be announced this month.</p>

<p>Farhad Alaaldin, foreign affairs adviser to the Iraqi prime minister, said technical talks with Washington on the coalition drawdown had concluded.</p>

<p>"We are now on the brink of transitioning the relationship between Iraq and members of the international coalition to a new level, focusing on bilateral relations in military, security, economic, and cultural areas," he said.</p>

<p>He did not comment on details of the plan and the US-led coalition did not respond to emailed questions.</p>

<p>The agreement follows more than six months of talks between Baghdad and Washington, initiated by Prime Minister Mohammed Shia al-Sudani in January amid attacks by Iran-backed Iraqi armed groups on US forces stationed at Iraqi bases.</p>

<p>The rocket and drone attacks have killed three American troops and wounded dozens more, resulting in several rounds of deadly US retaliation that threatened government efforts to stabilize Iraq after decades of conflict.</p>

<p>The US has approximately 2,500 troops in Iraq and 900 in neighbouring Syria as part of the coalition formed in 2014 to combat Islamic State as it rampaged through the two countries.</p>

<p>The group once held roughly a third of Iraq and Syria but was territorially defeated in Iraq at the end of 2017 and in Syria in 2019. Iraq had demonstrated its ability to handle any remaining threat, Alaaldin said.</p>

<p>The US initially invaded Iraq in 2003, toppling dictator Saddam Hussein before withdrawing in 2011, but returned in 2014 at the head of the coalition to fight Islamic State.</p>

<p>Other nations, including Germany, France, Spain, and Italy, also contribute hundreds of troops to the coalition.</p>

<p>Under the plan, all coalition forces would leave the Ain al-Asad airbase in western Anbar province and significantly reduce their presence in Baghdad by September 2025.</p>

<p>US and other coalition troops are expected to remain in Erbil, in the semi-autonomous northern Kurdistan region, for approximately one additional year, until around the end of 2026, to facilitate ongoing operations against Islamic State in Syria.</p>

<p>Exact details of troop movements are being kept secret due to their military sensitivity.</p>

<p>The drawdown would mark a notable shift in Washington's military posture in the region.</p>

<p>While primarily focused on countering Islamic State, US officials acknowledge their presence also serves as a strategic position against Iranian influence.</p>

<p>This position has grown more important as Israel and Iran escalate their regional confrontation, with US forces in Iraq shooting down rockets and drones fired towards Israel in recent months, according to US officials.</p>

<p>Prime Minister al-Sudani has stated that, while he appreciates their help, US troops have become a magnet for instability, frequently targeted and responding with strikes often not coordinated with the Iraqi government.</p>

<p>The agreement, when announced, would likely present a political win for al-Sudani as he balances Iraq's position as an ally of both Washington and Tehran. The first phase of the drawdown would end one month before Iraqi parliamentary polls set for October 2025.</p>

<p>For the US , the two-year time frame provides "breathing room," allowing for potential adjustments if the regional situation changes, a US official said.</p>

<p>The State Department and US Embassy in Baghdad did not respond to requests for comment.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/tbrtu2s_us-iraq-officials_625x300_06_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Exact details of troop movements are being kept secret due to their military sensitivity. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/alina-kabaeva-vladimir-putin-has-2-sons-with-ex-olympic-gymnast-and-girlfriend-alina-kabaeva-report-6505721]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Vladimir Putin Has 2 Sons With Ex Olympic Gymnast Alina Kabaeva: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/alina-kabaeva-vladimir-putin-has-2-sons-with-ex-olympic-gymnast-and-girlfriend-alina-kabaeva-report-6505721]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Sep 2024 18:16:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A report by an investigative site reveals that Russian President Vladimir Putin has two sons with former Olympic gymnast Alina Kabaeva.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russian President Vladimir Putin and his rumoured partner, former Olympic gymnast Alina Kabaeva, have two sons-ages five and nine-according to <em>the Dossier Centre</em>, a report in <em>Forbes</em> claimed. The outlet has attributed the info to a Russian investigative organisation that cited unnamed sources who claimed to regularly see the children.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://dossier.center/succession-en/">The<em> portal </em></a>claims that the couple's children are growing up in a highly secured residence in complete privacy. The boys live a solitary existence away from the spotlight and seldom see their parents.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/feature/vladimir-putin-buys-luxury-mansion-shares-it-with-girlfriend-alina-kabaeva-report-3826223"><strong>Also Read | Vladimir Putin Buys Luxury Mansion, Shares It With "Girlfriend" Alina Kabaeva: Report</strong></a></p>

<p>Mr Putin, 71, has <a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://en.putin.kremlin.ru/bio/page-3">declared in public</a> that he is the father of two daughters, Maria, 39, and Katerina, 38, with his former spouse Lyudmila Putin, whom he wed in 1983.</p>

<p><em>The Dossier Centre </em>claims Ms Kabaeva and Mr Putin started dating in 2008, which was six years prior to the official end of his divorce from Lyudmila. According to the report, Ms Kabaeva, 41, gave birth to Ivan in a maternity centre in Lugano, Switzerland, and to Vladimir Jr in Moscow.</p>

<p>Both Ivan and Vladimir Jr live in Mr Putin's mansion northwest of Moscow, though they have no interaction with other children their age, the Dossier Centre report claimed, and they receive music lessons and have personal trainers for swimming and artistic gymnastics.</p>

<p>Ivan has reportedly competed in artistic gymnastics competitions and often plays in hockey matches with his father.</p>

<p>Last year, a report about Russian President Vladimir Putin secretly spending millions on his girlfriend to buy big properties for her and their young children came out. <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.telegraph.co.uk/world-news/2023/02/28/putin-secretly-living-gymnast-girlfriend-children-luxury-mansion/">The Telegraph</a>&nbsp;</em>claimed that the leader allegedly funnelled millions in illicit funds to buy a big mansion and a large penthouse for his girlfriend, Alina Kabaeva.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/ho7g7odg_vladimir-putinalina-kabaeva_625x300_06_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Vladimir Putin's sons with Alina Kabaeva live a life of luxury isolated from the world.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/watch-donald-trump-announces-major-role-for-elon-musk-should-he-win-the-2024-us-election-6502018]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Watch: Trump Announces Major Role For Musk Should He Win The US Election]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/watch-donald-trump-announces-major-role-for-elon-musk-should-he-win-the-2024-us-election-6502018]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Sep 2024 17:19:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump revealed his initial plans, should he be voted to power in the 2024 US presidential election. Mr Trump said he will set up a task force shortly after assuming office, aimed at conducting a thorough audit of the entire federal government.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump has revealed his initial plans, should he be voted to power in the 2024 US presidential election. Mr Trump said he will set up a task force shortly after assuming office, aimed at conducting a thorough financial and performance audit of the entire federal government.</p>

<p>Donald Trump went on to say that once the audit is complete, the new task force will then make recommendations for drastic reforms, which he believes, is the need of the hour.</p>

<p>Elaborating his plan about the committee and who will head it, Donald Trump said that SpaceX, Tesla and X CEO Elon Musk shall head the task force, adding that Mr Musk has already agreed to take up the responsibility. A video of Donald Trump announcing this was shared on social media website X by local media outlet CSpan News Network.</p>

<p>Elon Musk too, welcomed Donald Trump's decision stating that such a move is "badly needed."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">This is badly needed <a href="https://t.co/H9AKYbDssZ">https://t.co/H9AKYbDssZ</a></p>
— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1831778370180329962?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 5, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>Talking more about his plans for the United States, Mr Trump said he aims to "Make America the world's capital for crypto and bitcoin." He also said he plans to eliminate at least ten old regulations and will bring in ten new ones to replace them.</p>

<p>Addressing the Economic Club of New York, Donald Trump said on September 5, "To stop this onslaught at lower prices, I'm pledging today that in my second term we will eliminate a minimum of ten old regulations. For every one new regulation, we'll be able to do that quite easily. Actually, and instead of attacking industries of the future, we will embrace them, including making America the world capital for crypto and bitcoin."</p>

<p>Donald Trump heaped praise on Elon Musk saying, "At the suggestion of Elon Musk, who has given me his complete and total endorsement, that's a nice smart guy. He knows what he's doing. Very much appreciated. I will create a Government Efficiency Commission task with conducting a complete financial and performance audit of the entire federal government and making recommendations for drastic reforms we need to do. It can't go on the way we are now. And Elon, because he's not very busy, has agreed to head that task force, be interesting if he has the time be good one to do it, but he's agreed," Donald Trump said.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">"At the suggestion of <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@elonmusk</a>...I will create a Government Efficiency Commission tasked with conducting a complete financial &amp; performance audit of the entire federal government and making recommendations for drastic reforms. And Elon...has agreed to head that task force." <a href="https://t.co/ep2WU9ySRT">pic.twitter.com/ep2WU9ySRT</a></p>
— CSPAN (@cspan) <a href="https://twitter.com/cspan/status/1831738407476977868?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 5, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>Mr Trump spoke about how improper and fraudulent payments cost US taxpayers an estimated "hundreds of billions of dollars" in 2022. He announced that the commission will create an action plan to eliminate payments within months and added that it will "save trillions of dollars", according to the video posted by CSpan on X.</p>

<p>Donald Trump said, "In 2022, fraud and improper payments alone cost taxpayers an estimated hundreds of billions of dollars. As the first order of business, this commission will develop an action plan to totally eliminate fraud and improper payments within six months. This will save trillions of dollars trillions. It's massive for the same service that you have right now, trillions of dollars is wasted and gone, and nobody knows where it went further, taming inaction and bringing prices way down."</p>

<p>He also pledged to make 'Trump tax cuts' permanent and announced that there will be no tax on tips. He alleged that US Vice President Kamala Harris copied his plan and announced to impose no tax on tips. He claimed that Kamala Harris will not move ahead with it and will stick to her plan.</p>

<p>Mr Trump said, "The 5th pillar of my plan is to make the Trump tax cuts permanent. They are massive tax cuts, biggest ever permanent and to cut tax even more, and we will have no tax on tips, something which they copied four weeks after I said it. She got upset and said no tax on tips. I said I just said that she is actually copying a lot of my plan. In fact, we're going to send her a MAGA sometime in the next week....But we also know she doesn't mean it. She's going to stick with what has been about and also no tax on Social security benefits."</p>

<p>Pledging to save social security, Donald Trump said that he will not impose tax on the benefits of people in social security, stressing that they have been wiped out by inflation.</p>

<p>Mr Trump said, "People in social security have been wiped out by inflation and now on top of it, we tax their benefits. We're not going to tax their benefits. We have so many different ways of making so much money. This country, the potential is so incredible. We don't have to take it away from people on social security. We're not going to do that. We're going to save social security. She's going to destroy Social Security."</p>

<p>The former US President said that his administration has proved that targeted tax cuts do not increase the deficit. He said that it reduces the deficit by growing the economy and raising revenue, according to the video posted by CSpan on X.</p>

<p>He said, "After we gave the massive tax cuts, we took in the following year with a much lower rate. Billions and billions of dollars more than we did the previous year with a high rate, think of that. So, with a much lower rate, we took in more money because people were incentivised."</p>

<p>Speaking about reducing the corporate tax burden, Mr Trump said he plans to reduce the corporate tax rate from 21 per cent to 15 per cent for companies that make their product in the US.</p>

<p>"Corporate tax revenues are 31 per cent higher today than before, my tax law was signed with all of those cuts 31 percent higher. To further support the revival of American manufacturing, my plan calls for expanded R&amp;D tax credits, 100 percent bonus depreciation, expensing for no manufacturing investments, and a reduction in corporate tax rate from 21 percent to 15 per cent solely for companies that make their product in America," he said.</p>

<p>Responding to the video which shows Donald Trump announcing his plans, Elon Musk took to X to post, "This is badly needed."<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/hl6ceebk_donald-trump-afp_625x300_06_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump said Elon Musk has agreed to take up a major role should Trump win the 2024 US election.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/victims-family-pardons-pakistan-industrialist-wife-natasha-danish-who-killed-2-with-luxury-suv-6505070]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Victims' Family Pardons Pak Industrialist's Wife Who Killed 2 With SUV]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/victims-family-pardons-pakistan-industrialist-wife-natasha-danish-who-killed-2-with-luxury-suv-6505070]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Sep 2024 16:58:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Relatives of a father-daughter duo have forgiven a female from a wealthy, influential Pakistani business family here who ran down a luxurious SUV over them, her lawyer said on Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Relatives of a father-daughter duo have forgiven a female from a wealthy, influential Pakistani business family here who ran down a luxurious SUV over them, her lawyer said on Friday.</p>

<p>The incident drew widespread condemnation as the two killed came from lower middle class. The rich lady also injured three other motorcyclists on the main Karsaz Road in the city as she lost control of her car.</p>

<p>The accident on August 19 garnered lot of attention on social media and became a raging debate on television channels as videos of Natasha Danish appearing disoriented and unrepentant over her actions went viral.</p>

<p>As Natasha Danish hit Imran Arif and his daughter Amna Arif from behind, their motorcycle went flying, according to videos of the incident shared on social media and by the police.</p>

<p>Imran used to sell papers to shops while his daughter was employed in a private firm.</p>

<p>After the hearing at a Sessions Court earlier on Friday, Barrister Uzair Ghouri, representing the bereaved families, told the media outside the court that they (the families) had forgiven the driver in the name of Allah.</p>

<p>The defence lawyer had claimed after the incident that the accused had mental health issues and was under treatment since 2005.</p>

<p>The victims' family submitted an affidavit in the court forgiving the accused.</p>

<p>The agreement between the affected families and the accused were presented in the court of a judicial magistrate where the case was under trial, after which the accused was granted bail.</p>

<p>Soon after social media erupted with blames that the family accepted blood money.</p>

<p>"The bereaved families have forgiven the accused in the name of Allah and it is baseless rumours that they have taken blood money (Diyat in Islamic Shariah laws) to forgive her for the deaths," he said.</p>

<p>In Pakistan, under Sharia laws, a victim's family/heirs can forgive an accused even if he or she has caused deaths.</p>

<p>The law is called Qisas and Diyat law. Qisas, defined as "punishment by causing similar hurt at the same part of the body of the convict," and diyat meaning, "compensation ... payable to the heirs of the victims." "The court has released Natasha on bail, she can go anywhere in the world," said defence lawyer barrister Amir Mansoob.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/pa7a5bko_natasha-danish-ali_625x300_28_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Videos of Natasha Danish appearing disoriented and unrepentant over her actions went viral]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/video-asteroid-burns-up-in-earths-atmosphere-lighting-up-philippine-sky-6504974]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Video: Asteroid Burns Up In Earth's Atmosphere, Lighting Up Philippine Sky]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/video-asteroid-burns-up-in-earths-atmosphere-lighting-up-philippine-sky-6504974]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Sep 2024 16:45:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A small asteroid, 2024 RW1, burned up in Earth's atmosphere over Luzon Island, Philippines, after being discovered just hours earlier by astronomers in Arizona.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>American space agency NASA has confirmed that early on Wednesday afternoon, over Luzon Island in the Philippines, a minor asteroid, about the size of a meter, broke apart in Earth's atmosphere.</p>

<p>Astronomers in Arizona initially discovered the space rock, known as 2024 RW1, a few hours before it entered the Earth. There was a brilliant flare in the sky as the asteroid burnt up over the Philippine shore.</p>

<p>2024 RW1 is only the ninth asteroid to be detected before impact, according to the European Space Agency. The incident strengthens astronomers' increasing capacity to foresee the presence of near-Earth objects.</p>

<p>The beautiful celestial event was caught on camera and shared on social media: an orange tail that vanished fast and a green fireball that flashed, lighting up the sky behind clouds. A bright green flame could be seen blazing across the Philippines in many of the internet videos.</p>

<p><strong>Watch the video here:</strong></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Here's how Asteroid RW1 looks like from Gonzaga, Cagayan, Philippines. Best shot so far!! ? <a href="https://t.co/eYgQsHqxFP">pic.twitter.com/eYgQsHqxFP</a></p>
— Raymon Dullana (@raymongdullana) <a href="https://twitter.com/raymongdullana/status/1831378111453392958?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 4, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The impact was expected to be visible from the east coast of the nation as a fireball, according to NASA's Asteroid Watch prediction. Space aficionados all around the world were captivated by the spectacle in no time.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">⚠️☄️Incoming!<br />
<br />
A roughly 1 metre asteroid will strike Earth's atmosphere over the Philippines near Luzon Island at 17:08 UTC today, 4 September.<br />
<br />
The object is harmless, but people in the area may see a spectacular fireball!<br />
<br />
Discovered this morning by the Catalina Sky Survey,… <a href="https://t.co/UjQLbh3fFr">pic.twitter.com/UjQLbh3fFr</a></p>
— European Space Agency (@esa) <a href="https://twitter.com/esa/status/1831270255454191893?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 4, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The impact of the asteroid was confirmed by various sensors, according to NASA's Planetary Defence Coordination Office. This sighting, which came just hours after astronomers first noticed the tiny asteroid, increased popular curiosity with the celestial event.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/m325o_asteroid-2024-rw1_625x300_06_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The green fireball, followed by an orange tail, lit up the sky and was captured in videos shared online.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/pakistan-must-stop-blaming-others-for-its-balochistan-problem-6504755]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: It's Time Pakistan Stopped Blaming Others For Its Balochistan Problem]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/pakistan-must-stop-blaming-others-for-its-balochistan-problem-6504755]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Sep 2024 16:20:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Pakistan needs to abandon the policy of rewarding those who attack Baloch nationalists and stop promoting conspiracy theories that India, Iran, and Afghanistan are behind all the chaos in Balochistan.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2017-05/pakistan-flag_650x400_71493967261.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>On August 26, one of the bloodiest attacks in Pakistan's Balochistan province occurred, with over 70 people, including Pakistan Army soldiers, reportedly killed by the separatist group Balochistan Liberation Army (BLA). The date held significant meaning for Balochistan as it marked the 18th death anniversary of Nawab Akbar Bugti, a Baloch nationalist leader killed by the Pakistani military in 2006.</p>

<p>The BLA's Majeed Brigade, its suicide squad, conducted a coordinated attack across various parts of Balochistan. The assault involved blowing up infrastructure such as railway tracks and bridges and resulted in the deaths of migrant labourers from Punjab.</p>

<p>The Baloch rebellion in Pakistan stems from both historical and contemporary resentments, impacting stability in India and the broader region. Balochistan has a long history of political unrest, economic oppression, anti-Punjabi sentiment, enforced disappearances, and extrajudicial killings. These issues have rekindled the fight for Baloch nationalism. For two decades, the mineral-rich province has experienced low-level insurgency against Pakistan's central government, accompanied by brutal retaliatory actions.</p>

<p>Pakistan has described the recent attacks as a "nefarious scheme supported by external rivals to undermine its development ties with Beijing".</p>

<p>The BLA is considered the largest armed group in Balochistan, with thousands of members. It collaborates closely with the Baloch Liberation Front (BLF), another major separatist militant group advocating for Baloch self-determination. Both groups have been labelled as "terrorist organisations" by Pakistan.</p>

<h2><b>The 1999 Coup</b></h2>

<p>Many Baloch believe they were coerced into joining Pakistan in 1948. The princely state of Kalat, now part of Balochistan, briefly enjoyed independence before being 'forced' into accession with Pakistan. Apart from initial resistance, there were uprisings in 1958 and 1977 seeking either independence or greater autonomy.</p>

<p>Pervez Musharraf's military coup in 1999 further alienated the Baloch from Pakistan. Distrust of Punjabi dominance in the Pakistani army and bureaucracy, along with the lack of Baloch representation, has been a persistent issue. In one of Musharraf's counter-insurgency operations, Baloch leader Nawab Akbar Bugti was killed in 2006. Pakistan has not made significant efforts to integrate the region or address the local issues of its inhabitants.</p>

<p>"The Baloch have been alienated by the Pakistani state since the country's inception. This alienation has intensified over the past two decades due to Pakistan's failure to engage in meaningful reflection and its numerous cases of enforced disappearances, torture, and killings of Baloch activists," says Malik Siraj Akbar, a political analyst based in Washington, D.C.</p>

<h2><strong>How Things Stand Today</strong></h2>

<p>Balochistan is Pakistan's largest province by area but remains one of its most impoverished regions. Years of poverty, neglect, and mistreatment by the central government have fueled anger, which is exploited by separatists. Revenue from Balochistan's rich natural resources has been used to develop other parts of Pakistan, including Punjab and Sindh, which are more prosperous. Balochistan contributes only 4% to Pakistan's economy.</p>

<p>The province also lags in social development indicators, with the highest infant and maternal mortality rates, the highest poverty rate, and the lowest literacy rate in Pakistan.</p>

<p>There is no forum for dissent, as enforced disappearances of thousands of Balochs continue. Political parties in Balochistan, which previously formed most provincial governments, lost power in controversial elections. Later, Islamabad supported puppet leaders, worsening the situation.</p>

<p>"While Pakistan may appear to be a democratic state, real power rests with its military and intelligence agencies, which are primarily blamed for the violence in Balochistan," says Akbar. "Unless the military ends its illegal operations and is held accountable, any confidence-building measures with the Baloch and prospects for negotiations are unlikely," he adds.</p>

<p>Apart from using brutal force and repression, the Pakistani establishment has also failed to engage with civil rights movements in Balochistan. Resentment is so high that in the current uprising, the Baloch nationalist movement has garnered support from women, children, and the families of the missing persons, with some even joining the suicide bombers.</p>

<p>Baloch separatists are also opposed to the China-Pakistan Economic Corridor (CPEC), which passes through Balochistan and is seen as an example of exploitation. They have targeted Chinese workers as part of their resistance. Balochistan is a crucial location in China's multi-billion-dollar CPEC, part of President Xi Jinping's Belt and Road Initiative (BRI). In January, insurgents attacked government offices in Gwadar, a key hub for Chinese investments in energy and infrastructure. The BLA also targeted Pakistan's largest naval air force base.</p>

<p>The current insurgency is driven by the construction of Gwadar, a Chinese-funded project announced in 2001 intended to transform the small village into a port city like Dubai. The Pakistani government has excluded Baloch from the development process, employing Chinese engineers and non-Baloch Pakistani workers, fueling antipathy and violence. The Taliban's seizure of neighbouring Afghanistan has also enhanced the capabilities of armed groups in the region, including Baloch separatists.</p>

<h2><b>Pakistan Should Stop Blaming Others</b></h2>

<p>Pakistan has accused India of providing arms, training, and financial support to insurgent groups in Balochistan. India denies these allegations and has urged Pakistan to examine its own support for terrorism. In 2016, Prime Minister Narendra Modi's remarks highlighting Pakistan's atrocities and repression of the Baloch people had sparked controversy in Islamabad.</p>

<p>India has been closely monitoring the situation in Balochistan and has expressed concerns about rising attacks in both Khyber Pakhtunkhwa and Balochistan since the Taliban's return to Kabul. Pakistan needs to abandon the policy of rewarding those who attack Baloch nationalists and stop promoting conspiracy theories that India, Iran, and Afghanistan are behind all the tumult in Balochistan.</p>

<p>"Pakistan has mastered the art of externalising responsibility for its self-created problems. Unable to address the two-decade-long insurgency in Balochistan despite using brutal tactics similar to those in East Pakistan in 1971, Pakistan has intermittently blamed India for its troubles," says Tilak Devasher, a member of the National Security Advisory Board, India. "It has, however, failed to produce any evidence to substantiate its claims. Consequently, its assertions are not taken seriously by the international community," adds Devasher.</p>

<p>Pakistan must demonstrate political will to address the Balochistan issue by engaging with civil rights groups, involving Baloch in the development process, and alleviating their poverty and suffering. Meanwhile, India continues to observe the situation closely.</p>

<p><em>(Bharti Mishra Nath is Contributing Editor, NDTV)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2017-05/pakistan-flag_650x400_71493967261.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/food-dye-can-make-skin-and-muscle-temporarily-transparent-heres-how-6504130]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Common Food Dye Can Make Skin Temporarily Transparent: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/food-dye-can-make-skin-and-muscle-temporarily-transparent-heres-how-6504130]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Sep 2024 15:25:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Researchers at Stanford University were able to peer into the bodies of living animals as they discovered that a common food dye made their skin, muscle and connective tissues temporarily transparent.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Wouldn't the doctors have it easier if our skin were transparent and they could see everything beyond or underneath it? Sounds hypothetical, no? Even with advanced technologies and highly sophisticated imaging techniques, doctors get unclear results while peeking inside a living body. However, recent research showed this distant dream may soon be a reality, surprisingly by just applying a common food dye.</p>

<p>Researchers at <a href="https://news.stanford.edu/stories/2024/09/using-a-common-food-dye-researchers-made-mouse-skin-transparent">Stanford University</a> have managed to peer into the bodies of living animals with the help of common food dye, making their skin, muscle and connective tissues temporarily transparent, <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/article/2024/sep/05/common-food-dye-found-to-make-skin-and-muscle-temporarily-transparent?CMP=share_btn_url">The Guardian</a> reported.</p>

<p>Published in Science on September 5, the research details how rubbing the FDA-approved dye solution on a mouse's skin allowed the researchers to see through the skin, without making an incision. They were able to do this with the naked eye.<br />
<br />
The liver, intestines and bladder of the mouse were visible through the abdominal skin after the dye was applied to the belly. Not just that, the researchers even witnessed the blood vessels in the rodent's brain.</p>

<p>Interestingly, the treated skin regained its normal colour once the researchers washed off the dye.</p>

<p>“As soon as we rinsed and massaged the skin with water, the effect was reversed within minutes. It's a stunning result," said Guosong Hong, assistant professor of materials science and engineering.<br />
<br />
<strong>How does it work?</strong></p>

<p>The idea behind this echoes the approach of a character in the popular 1897 novel, The Invisible Man. In the science fiction novel, written by HG Wells, a scientist discovers how the secret to invisibility depends on matching the object's refractive index -- or the ability to bend light -- with that of the surrounding air.</p>

<p>When the light waves strike the biological tissue, it scatters them, thus making it appear opaque and non-transparent to the eye. The effects take place due to the difference in the refractive indices of various tissue components, like lipids and water. In the visible spectrum, water generally has a lower refractive index than lipids. This causes visible light to scatter while it passes through tissue containing both.</p>

<p>The researchers massaged a solution of red tartrazine on the sedated mouse's abdomen, scalp, and hindlimb to match the refractive indices of various tissue components.</p>

<p>Soon after, the rodent's skin turned red, indicating that much of the blue light got absorbed due to the light-absorbing molecule's presence, the study states.</p>

<p>The increase in absorption further altered the refractive index of water at different wavelengths -- which was red in this case. As a result, the refractive index of water matched with that of lipids in the red spectrum. Ultimately, this led to reduced scattering and made the mouse's skin appear more transparent at the red wavelength.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/2p7h5i9g_skin-generic-_625x300_06_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-mans-shooting-spree-leaves-80-animals-dead-in-california-arrested-6504267]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Man's Shooting Spree Leaves 80 Animals Dead In California, Arrested]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-mans-shooting-spree-leaves-80-animals-dead-in-california-arrested-6504267]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Sep 2024 15:19:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A California man hasbeen arrestedafter his nighttime shooting spree left over 80 animals dead, sparking panic among residents. The incident occurred on Tuesday in Prunedale, a rural community roughly 100 miles south of San Francisco.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A California man has&nbsp;been arrested&nbsp;after his nighttime shooting spree left over 80 animals dead, sparking panic among residents. The incident occurred on Tuesday in Prunedale, a rural community roughly 100 miles south of San Francisco. The sheriff's office responded to reports of gunfire and issued a shelter-in-place order for residents within a five-mile radius, according to a report in <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/09/05/us/california-man-kills-animals-shooting.html">NYT</a>.</p>

<p>The suspect, 39-year-old Vicente Joseph Arroyo of Salinas, was taken into custody after<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8efwX7W2t2s&amp;authuser=1"> firing multiple weapons</a>&nbsp;for over three hours in a vineyard. Law enforcement described the scene as&nbsp;extremely&nbsp;dark and heavily vegetated, making it challenging to locate the suspect immediately.</p>

<p>Officers from several agencies eventually tracked down Arroyo and found his vehicle crashed along a vineyard road by dawn. He&nbsp;was arrested&nbsp;without resistance. A search of the area revealed a large cache of firearms, including rifles, shotguns, handguns and an illegal assault weapon. The authorities also found a stockpile of ammunition and bulletproof vests at the scene.</p>

<p>Among&nbsp;the animals killed were miniature horses, goats, rabbits, chickens and various birds, according to Commander Andres Rosas of the Monterey County Sheriff's Office.&nbsp;Most animals were kept&nbsp;in pens on rented land adjacent to Arroyo's trailer. While some initially survived, many had to&nbsp;be euthanised&nbsp;due to severe injuries. Authorities confirmed the animals did not belong to Arroyo but were the property of a neighbouring landowner and a tenant who rented the land.</p>

<p>Following his arrest, Arroyo&nbsp;was booked&nbsp;on multiple charges, including animal cruelty, wilful discharge of a firearm, illegal possession of an assault weapon and vandalism. His bail was Initially set at $50,000 (around Rs 41.96 lakh) but&nbsp;was then raised&nbsp;to $1,000,000 (around Rs 8.39 crore), stated a report in <a href="https://www.ktvu.com/news/california-man-arrested-after-killing-80-animals-sheriff">KTVU FOX 2</a>.</p>

<p>The report quoted Commander Rosas as saying, “I've been doing this for 24 plus years now, and no, I've unfortunately never seen anything like this when it comes to animal life lost.”</p>

<p>The incident has left the small community of Prunedale in shock. Jason Maynard, a resident, described the chaos of that night, telling KSBW that upon hearing the gunshots, he instructed his wife and child to get down on the floor for safety.</p>

<p>The reports added that officials have not yet identified a motive for the shooting.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-11/3eb3kf1_us-police-generic_625x300_14_November_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The incident has left the small community of Prunedale in shock (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-woman-accused-of-drugging-killing-2-of-her-children-faces-extradition-from-uk-6504216]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Woman Accused Of Killing 2 Of Her Children Faces Extradition From UK]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-woman-accused-of-drugging-killing-2-of-her-children-faces-extradition-from-uk-6504216]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Sep 2024 15:09:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A US woman, suspected of killing two of her children, attended her extradition hearing in London on Wednesday, reported BBC. Kimberlee Singler, 36, is accused of murdering her son Aden, 7, and daughter Elianna, 9.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A US woman, suspected of killing two of her children, attended her extradition hearing in London on Wednesday,<a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c4gqyerxjnyo"> reported BBC</a>. Kimberlee Singler, 36, is accused of murdering her son Aden, 7, and daughter Elianna, 9. The two kids were found dead in their bedrooms on December 19, 2023 in the state of Colorado.</p>

<p>Singler allegedly also stabbed her oldest kid, who was eleven years old at the time. She, however, survived the attack and underwent an emergency surgery after which, she was moved into foster care. Singler has denied all the accusations in court.</p>

<p>Singler was arrested in London on December 30, 2023 after an arrest warrant was issued against her by Colorado police. She faces seven&nbsp;charges, including two counts of first-degree murder, one count of attempted murder, three counts of child abuse, and one act of assault.</p>

<p>The father of the children claims he and his ex-wife <a href="http://https://www.cbsnews.com/colorado/news/colorado-springs-mother-kimberlee-singler-attends-hearing-london-after-deaths-2-children/">Singler have been embroiled in a bitter divorce and custody battle since 2018.</a> A Larimer County Court ruled that the children would spend more time with their father.</p>

<p>Singler was supposed to bring the kids for the exchange on December 16 but she never came and efforts to get in touch went in vain. According to investigators, Singler killed her youngest daughter and son on December 18 last year.</p>

<p>She called the police early on December 19 on the pretext of a burglary investigation. Upon reaching the residence, the officers discovered two dead children and one with a severe neck injury, who was immediately taken to the hospital.</p>

<p>The prosecution stated that a "blood-stained handgun" was found on the bedroom floor and live rounds and spent cartridges were recovered from the closet. There was also a blood-stained knife discovered in the home's living room.</p>

<p>Kimberlee Singler's London hearing is expected to last three days. The UK home secretary will decide whether or not to extradite her to the US.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/fp4o7l1o_kimberlee-singler_625x300_06_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kimberlee Singler was arrested in London on December 30, 2023 (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-becomes-worlds-2nd-largest-5g-mobile-market-surges-past-us-apple-tops-report-6503573]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India Now World's 2nd Largest 5G Mobile Market, Surges Past US: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-becomes-worlds-2nd-largest-5g-mobile-market-surges-past-us-apple-tops-report-6503573]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Sep 2024 14:58:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India has overtaken the US to become the world's second-biggest 5G handset market for the first time, behind China, a report has mentioned.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India has overtaken the US to become the world's second-biggest 5G handset market for the first time, behind China, a report has mentioned.</p>

<p>Global 5G handset shipments grew 20 per cent (year-on-year) in the first half of 2024, according to the Counterpoint Research. Apple led the 5G handset shipments, accounting for more than 25 per cent share.</p>

<p>Apple led the 5G handset shipments globally, accounting for more than 25 per cent share, driven by strong shipments of the iPhone 15 series and 14 series, reported news agency IANS.</p>

<p>5G handset shipments have been growing steadily and with the increased availability of 5G handsets in the budget segment, the emerging markets have witnessed high growth in this segment.</p>

<p>"India became the second-biggest 5G handset market during the first half, overtaking the US. The strong shipments from Xiaomi, Vivo, Samsung and other brands in the budget segment were the main reason for this trend," said senior analyst Prachir Singh.</p>

<p>Samsung followed in the second position, capturing more than 21 per cent share, driven by the Galaxy A series and S24 series. Apple and Samsung took five spots each in the top-10 list for 5G models in the first half of 2024, with Apple taking the top four spots.</p>

<p>Other emerging markets also witnessed high growth in 5G handsets. Consumers in emerging markets are looking at 5G handsets as an upgrade to their devices, even in the lower price segments.</p>

<p>Asia-Pacific accounted for 63 per cent of the overall global net adds and commanded a 58 per cent 5G shipment share. In Europe and the Middle East and Africa (MEA) regions also, 5G handset shipments witnessed double-digit growth.</p>

<p>Research Director Tarun Pathak said that as the democratisation of 5G handsets increases with increasing 5G penetration in lower price segments as well as increasing expansion of 5G networks, this trend will further grow.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/clegqgm8_5g-network-generic_625x300_06_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[India has overtaken the US to become the world's second-biggest 5G handset market. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-firm-launches-ai-life-assistant-that-can-order-food-hail-taxis-6504002]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[China Firm Launches AI "Life Assistant" That Can Order Food, Hail Taxis]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-firm-launches-ai-life-assistant-that-can-order-food-hail-taxis-6504002]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Sep 2024 14:39:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The fintech firm backed by Chinese e-commerce giant Alibaba has made a foray into products powered by artificial intelligence after announcing a "life assistant" mobile app.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The fintech firm backed by Chinese e-commerce giant Alibaba has made a foray into products powered by artificial intelligence after announcing a "life assistant" mobile app.</p>

<p>Ant Group said its Zhixiaobao app can help users "order meals, hail taxis, book tickets, and discover local dining and entertainment options" as well as access services in the digital payment app Alipay.</p>

<p>Unveiled in Shanghai on Thursday, comes as tech giants such as Google, Meta and Microsoft ramp up investment in the AI market, with many firms touting tighter integration of chatbots.</p>

<p>"Alipay is committed to harnessing AI's potential to improve the user experience, ensuring that AI assistants like Zhixiaobao become valuable tools in everyday life for all," Ant Group president Cyril Han said in a news release.</p>

<p>Since Ant's initial public offering was scrapped by Chinese authorities in 2020, the firm has been forced to overhaul its business model to satisfy financial regulators.</p>

<p>Last year, it was fined 7.1 billion yuan (US$984 million) for "illegal" acts months after its billionaire founder Jack Ma relinquished control.</p>

<p>The Hangzhou-based company saw its profits fall 10 percent in the January-March quarter, Bloomberg News reported, adding that Ant's valuation has fallen more than 70 percent since the aborted IPO.</p>

<p>Ant on Thursday described its new product as an "AI-native application powered by Ant Group's BaiLing foundation model", referring to the company's large language model.</p>

<p>The Chinese government gave the green light last year for Ant to offer products that used BaiLing.&nbsp;</p>

<p>At the Shanghai event, the firm also announced AI-powered products for merchants, healthcare service users and insurance</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-12/5oia0dg8_artificial-intelligence-generic-ai-generic-_625x300_20_December_23.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/florida-surgeon-accused-removing-patients-liver-instead-of-spleen-causing-death-report-6503655]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Died Helpless": Wife Of US Man Whose Liver Was Mistakenly Removed]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/florida-surgeon-accused-removing-patients-liver-instead-of-spleen-causing-death-report-6503655]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Sep 2024 13:45:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The family of 70-year-old William Bryan accused Dr Thomas Shaknovsky of removing the wrong organ from his body.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Florida doctor has been accused of removing the wrong organ from a man's body, resulting in his death. The family of William "Bill" Bryan, 70, claimed that surgeon Dr Thomas Shaknovsky mistakenly removed Bryan's liver instead of the spleen,&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/article/2024/sep/04/alabama-man-death-wrong-organ-surgery" rel="nofollow,noindex">reported The Guardian</a>. As of Wednesday, Shaknovsky has not been charged but the law firm appointed by Bryan's family stated that they planned to move the court.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to the law firm, Bryan visited the Ascension Sacred Heart Emerald Coast Hospital on August 18 after experiencing pain in his flank area. The patient and his wife Beverly were given a rundown of the "risks, benefits, and alternatives" of the surgery before he underwent a splenectomy under surgeon Thomas Shaknovsky on August 21. However, instead of removing Bryan's spleen as intended, the doctor removed his liver, resulting in his untimely death.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
"Dr Shaknovsky removed Mr Bryan's liver and, in so doing, transected the major vasculature supplying the liver, causing immediate and catastrophic blood loss resulting in death,” read the statement. "The surgeon proceeded with labeling the removed liver specimen as a 'spleen,' and it wasn't until following the death that it was identified that the organ removed was Mr Bryan's liver, as opposed to the spleen."</p>

<p>The lawyers also claimed that Shaknovsky had a history of "wrong-site surgery". In 2023, the surgeon mistakenly removed a portion of a patient's pancreas instead of performing the intended adrenal gland resection. The law firm claimed the matter was settled and the terms were not made public. Beverly Bryan stated she hired the legal team to pursue "justice" for her husband.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
In a statement, she said, “My husband died while helpless on the operating room table by Dr Shaknovsky. I don't want anyone else to die due to his incompetence at a hospital that should have known or knew he had previously made drastic, life-altering surgical mistakes.” She is pursuing both civil and criminal actions in the case.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
The Ascension Sacred Heart Emerald Coast Hospital has also released a statement, saying it “take[s] allegations like this very seriously, and our leadership team is performing a thorough investigation into this event”.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-03/8r3kgal_surgery-generic_625x300_21_March_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Representational Image]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/ic-814-row-and-my-chance-encounter-with-a-global-terrorist-6503645]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: IC 814 Row, And My 1994 Encounter With Terrorist Omar Sheikh]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/ic-814-row-and-my-chance-encounter-with-a-global-terrorist-6503645]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Sep 2024 13:43:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Netflix web series IC 814: The Kandahar Hijack has sparked a controversy over names of a few of the hijackers. But it has taken me back to my chance encounter with Omar Sheikh, one of the three terrorists released after the hijack.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/indiatoday/images/story/202004/omar_shiekh_reuters_0.jpeg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>It was around 8:30 or 9 in the evening on the last day of 1999. I was in Copenhagen, the capital of Denmark, and was visiting a fellow Bihari friend, Tabish Khair - now an established novelist and poet - to celebrate the New Year festivities. While waiting for others to get ready, I switched on the TV to get an update on IC 814, an Indian Airlines plane hijacked eight days earlier with 155 passengers on board. The news was that the terrible saga had ended, and all passengers had been freed. But, of course, their freedom was secured in exchange for the release of three terrorists.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Two of them released from jail were known in India - Maulana Masood Azhar (founder of terror outfit Jaish-e-Mohammed) and Mushtaq Ahmed Zargar (Al Umar Mujahideen). But except the police and intelligence agencies, only a few had heard of the third person: Omar Saeed Sheikh. Just two years later, Sheikh would become infamous worldwide for kidnapping and beheading a US journalist. He also nearly caused a diplomatic crisis between India and Pakistan following the November 26 terror attacks in Mumbai in 2008.</p>

<h2><strong>The Kidnapping Of 3 Westerners</strong></h2>

<p>The Netflix web series <em>IC 814: The Kandahar Hijack</em> has sparked a controversy over names and the portrayal of a few of the hijackers. But it has taken me back to my chance encounter with Sheikh.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The year was 1994. My cameraman and I were out to cover a story for a Delhi-based TV channel; it was going through dry runs before the launch. We had barely reached Ghaziabad when we witnessed elaborate security arrangements outside a private hospital. The road was cordoned off. We were told that a terrorist was admitted to the hospital after being wounded in a police encounter in Saharanpur the previous night, during which a police inspector had been shot dead.</p>

<p>Security was tighter inside the hospital. But some smooth-talking with an amiable Uttar Pradesh '<em>daroga ji</em>' did the trick. He allowed us in on the condition that we would brief him on our conversation with the man inside, Omar Sheikh, whose English accent, he admitted, he did not understand. We rolled the camera as we entered the room, not knowing who Sheikh was and how big a catch he was for the police. The only piece of information we had was that the injured man had kidnapped three Britons and an American in Delhi and hid them in a house in Saharanpur on their way to Kashmir. He had told his captives that his name was Rohit Sharma, and that he was taking them to his quaint ancestral village in Kashmir. But when a Saharanpur police patrol party stumbled upon the captives, a shootout ensued. A police inspector was killed, and Sheikh got injured. All the captives though were freed.</p>

<h2><strong>Omar Sheikh, The London-Born, LSE-Educated Terrorist</strong></h2>

<p>The hospital was posh, Sheikh's room big and clean. He lay in bed with a bandage around his right shoulder. The camera was rolling as we came face to face with a tall and bearded young man, propped up against hospital pillows, looking puzzled and befuddled. His first reaction was to shout a barrage of questions at us, "Who are you, why are you here, who has sent you?".&nbsp;</p>

<p>We asked for an interview, but he refused to speak to us in protest because he said he had no prior notice we were going to do an interview with him. He relented after I produced my press ID card. Before the interview began, he told us his name and that he was 20 years old. He was a student at the prestigious London School of Economics (LSE). He also said he was born in London and was raised both there and in Lahore. His Pakistani immigrant parents lived in London, where they ran a clothes business.&nbsp;</p>

<p>During the half-hour interview, Sheikh Omar looked extremely worried. He told me he would give anything to return to life in Britain. He also kept pleading with me, "Brother, take me out of here, please." During the interview, he revealed how at the age of 18, he had already done 'jihad' in Bosnia, fighting alongside and on behalf of Bosnian Muslims, who, he said, were being butchered by the Serbs. He was strikingly young and his accent was distinctly British. I thought he had the gift of the gab. I am not surprised he managed to lure foreign tourists and later, in 2002, used the same trick to lure American journalist Daniel Pearl into captivity.</p>

<h2><strong>Fooled by Extremists</strong></h2>

<p>He also recounted how he had been indoctrinated on the campus by an Islamist organisation that wanted to establish an Islamic society in Britain. He said he had been fooled by the hard-luck stories he had heard about the plight of Muslims and Kashmiris in India.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Sheikh admitted that he was charged with kidnapping some foreign tourists to barter for Maulana Masood Azhar, who was then held in prison in India. He also admitted that he had been in Delhi for more than a month before the kidnapping and was struck by the religious freedom he saw. "I had been told that Muslims in India had no religious rights and Kashmiri Muslims were being subjected to torture and rape by the Hindu army," he said.</p>

<p>I asked him, if released, would he go back and tell people in Britain that Indian Muslims were free to build mosques, say prayers, and work in government offices? He said he would. He appeared repentant, but clearly not enough.</p>

<h2><b>Meeting Masood Azhar</b></h2>

<p>Why Omar Sheikh chose the path of destruction was hard to say. He was exposed to Islamist extremism at a tender age. But that doesn't fully explain the path he chose early in his life. He was privileged. He went to the private Forest School in London - the same school former cricketer Nasser Hussain studied in. But while Sheikh became a terrorist, Hussain went on to become the captain of the England cricket team.&nbsp;</p>

<p>At LSE, Sheikh was known for his academic brilliance, especially in maths and economics. But he dropped out before completing his degree to join the 'jihad' in Bosnia. It is reported that he met a couple of Pakistani "fighters" there, who introduced him to Maulana Masood Azhar upon his return to Pakistan. He trained in both Pakistan and Afghanistan.</p>

<p>After his release, it's unclear where Sheikh went in Pakistan. According to some Pakistani papers, he lived in Lahore, where he married a local woman and had a child.</p>

<p>Until this time, Omar Sheikh was known mostly to Indian investigators and intelligence communities. His name cropped up at the time of his release in December 1999 from Tihar, but outside of India, he remained unknown.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>The Kidnapping Of Daniel Pearl</strong></h2>

<p>That changed after the kidnapping of American journalist Daniel Pearl. Suddenly, everyone wanted to know who Sheikh was. A foreign media outlet published my encounter with him, and I was inundated with requests for interviews by the Western media.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Sheikh was found guilty of kidnapping and murdering Pearl. He was given a death sentence, which was later turned into life imprisonment. According to a respected Pakistani journalist, who met a prison officer where Sheikh was lodged, Omar was shuttled regularly between Karachi and Hyderabad jails, spending a fortnight in each. The officer told the journalist that it was necessitated by the fact that he used his gift of the gab and often cast his spell on prison officials, who would then do him favours, like smuggling cellphones.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>When Sheikh Posed As Pranab Mukherjee</strong></h2>

<p>It is precisely this gift that once landed the authorities into hot water and led to a near diplomatic crisis between India and Pakistan. A year after the 2008 Mumbai terror attacks, Karachi's Dawn newspaper ran an investigative story claiming that Sheikh had called the Pakistani President at the time, Asif Zardari, claiming to be India's then-foreign minister Pranab Mukherjee. It was reported that he used unparliamentary language on the call and threatened Zardari with dire consequences for the Mumbai attacks. The English daily claimed, "Omar Saeed Sheikh, a detained Pakistani militant, had made hoax calls to President Asif Ali Zardari and the Chief of Army Staff, Gen Ashfaq Parvez Kayani, in a bid to heighten Pakistan-India tensions after last year's terrorist attacks on Mumbai, investigators have told Dawn."</p>

<p>A diplomatic crisis was averted after the call was traced to his cell in Hyderabad jail. The cell was raided, and it was found that Sheikh used a British SIM card to make the threatening calls.</p>

<p>Despite Daniel Pearl's wife, Mariane Pearl, writing a book, titled A Mighty Heart, and despite the book being made into a Hollywood film with the same title, the story of Omar Sheikh remains shrouded in mystery. In dozens of court appearances, he often appeared affable and charming, but not a lot of his terror connections have been confirmed.</p>

<h2><strong>Omar Sheikh Is Still A Mystery</strong></h2>

<p>Former dictator Pervez Musharraf called him a British spy in his autobiography. Omar himself boasted of his deep links to Pakistan's Inter-Services Intelligence (ISI) in his off-the-cuff remarks to journalists during court hearings. He was known to have good relations with Jaish-e-Mohammed's Maulana Masood Azhar and Lashkar-e-Toiba's Zaki-ur-Rehman Lakhvi. Some journalists, who investigated the roles terror outfits played in the &nbsp;9/11 attacks, claimed he was an operative of Al-Qaeda.</p>

<p>Omar is being held in jail despite his release order by the Supreme Court in Pakistan. It is believed the country has kept him in prison after re-arresting him because of international pressure. But some also claim that he is better off in jail, lest he reveal too much.</p>

<p><em>(Syed Zubair Ahmed is a London-based senior Indian journalist with three decades of experience with the Western media)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/indiatoday/images/story/202004/omar_shiekh_reuters_0.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/treated-like-garbage-french-woman-on-husband-who-let-50-men-rape-her-6503587]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Treated Like Garbage": French Woman On Husband Who Let 50 Men Rape Her]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/treated-like-garbage-french-woman-on-husband-who-let-50-men-rape-her-6503587]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Sep 2024 13:36:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[During investigation, police found a file, labelled as "abuses" on the USB drive that was connected to the accused husband's computer. While searching the drive, officials found nearly 20,000 images and films of the woman getting raped almost 100 tim]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 72-year-old French woman, whose husband admitted to drugging her and inviting dozens of men to rape her over a decade, told a court that she was treated "like a rag doll" and was "sacrificed on the altar of vice".<br />
<br />
In a calm and clear voice, Gisele Pelicot, in the southern French city of Avignon, detailed the horror of how her husband Dominique Pelicot, 71, allegedly lined up scores of men to rape her while she was unconscious.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
This happened close to 100 times in their home for nearly a decade, while her husband systematically filmed the suspected rapes and stored thousands of images as well as videos later found by the investigators.<br />
<br />
“I was sacrificed on the altar of vice... They regarded me like a rag doll, like a garbage bag... I no longer have an identity. I don't know if I will ever rebuild myself," she testified, as per a report in <a href="https://www.independent.co.uk/news/world/europe/france-wife-rape-trial-gisele-dominique-pelicot-b2607529.html">The Independent</a>.<br />
<br />
She added, “For me, everything collapses. These are scenes of barbarity, of rape.”<br />
<br />
She said she was abused at least six times by someone, who was known to have HIV.<br />
<br />
“My life was in danger but not one second did anyone stop... I was tested for HIV as one man who came (to rape me) six times was seropositive,” Gisele told the court, testifying about the abuse inflicted on her between 2011 and 2020, <a href="http://https://nypost.com/2024/09/05/world-news/french-husband-accused-of-drugging-wife-allegedly-let-hiv-positive-attacker-rape-her-six-times/">New York Post</a> reported.<br />
<br />
<strong>Police 'saved my life'</strong><br />
<br />
The woman said the “police saved my life” after they investigated her husband's computer back in November 2020 after he was caught by a security guard filming up the skirts of women at a supermarket near their home in a village in southern France, <a href="http://https://www.theguardian.com/world/article/2024/sep/05/french-woman-world-fell-apart-alleged-rapes-men-invited-by-husband-gisele-pelicot">The Guardian</a> reported.<br />
<br />
Describing the moment the investigators first showed her the videos of images of sexual abuse orchestrated and filmed by her husband, Gisele Pelicot termed it as “an explosion, a tsunami”.<br />
<br />
“My world is falling apart. For me, everything is falling apart. Everything I have built up over 50 years... Frankly, these are scenes of horror for me,” she said while Dominique Pelicot kept listening to her in court with his head bowed.<br />
<br />
The report stated that while investigating the case, police saw a file, labelled "abuses" on the USB drive that was connected to Dominique Pelicot's computer. While searching the drive, officials found nearly 20,000 images and films of the woman getting raped almost 100 times.<br />
<br />
<strong>The crime</strong><br />
<br />
According to police, the accused husband used to crush sleeping pills and anti-anxiety medication and mix them into his wife's meal or wine. He then used to invite men to rape her after contacting them through an online chatroom.<br />
<br />
Dominique Pelicot as well as 50 other men, aged between 26 and 74, are on trial, reports said.<br />
<br />
According to <a href="https://www.telegraph.co.uk/world-news/2024/09/05/french-rape-trial-latest-updates/">The Telegraph</a>, the woman's husband and 14 other co-accused have admitted to rape, while 35 men, belonging to all walks of life, have denied the charges, claiming the woman was in some way consented to libertine sex.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/95tt9k4k_gisele-pelicot_625x300_06_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/17-children-die-after-fire-rips-through-primary-school-hostel-in-kenya-6503406]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[17 Children Die After Fire Rips Through Primary School Hostel In Kenya]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/17-children-die-after-fire-rips-through-primary-school-hostel-in-kenya-6503406]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Sep 2024 13:08:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[At least 17 children died after a fire ripped through their primary school dormitory overnight in central Kenya, police said Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At least 17 children died after a fire ripped through their primary school dormitory overnight in central Kenya, police said Friday.</p>

<p>The blaze in Nyeri county's Hillside Endarasha Academy broke out at around midnight, police said, engulfing rooms where the children were sleeping.</p>

<p>The primary school caters to some 800 pupils, aged between roughly five and 12.</p>

<p>"There are 17 fatalities from this incident and there are also others who were taken to hospital with serious injuries," national police spokesperson Resila Onyango told AFP.</p>

<p>"The bodies recovered at the scene were burnt beyond recognition," she said.</p>

<p>Police said the average age of the victims was around nine years old.</p>

<p>Several others were injured, Onyango said, 16 of them seriously, and had been rushed to a nearby hospital.</p>

<p>"More bodies are likely to be recovered once (the) scene is fully processed," she said.</p>

<p>The cause of the fire remains unknown, she said, but an investigation had been launched.</p>

<p>President William Ruto expressed his condolences for those killed.</p>

<p>"Our thoughts are with the families of the children who have lost their lives in the fire tragedy," he said in a post on X.</p>

<p>"This is devastating news."</p>

<p>He said he had instructed officials to "thoroughly investigate this horrific incident", and promised that those responsible will be "held to account".&nbsp;</p>

<p>The school is located around 170 kilometres (100 miles) north of the capital Nairobi, in Nyeri county.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Kenyan Red Cross said it was on the ground assisting a multi-agency response team.</p>

<p>In a post on X, it said it was "providing psychosocial support services to the pupils, teachers and affected families".</p>

<h2>Deadly blazes</h2>

<p>There have been numerous school fires in Kenya and across East Africa.</p>

<p>In 2016, nine students were killed by a fire at a girls' high school in the Kibera neighbourhood of Nairobi.</p>

<p>In 2001, 67 pupils were killed by an arson attack on their dormitory at the Kyanguli Mixed Secondary School David Mutiso in Kenya's southern Machakos district.</p>

<p>Two pupils were charged with the murder, and the headmaster and deputy of the school were convicted of negligence.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In 1994, 40 school children were burned alive and 47 injured in a fire that ravaged the Shauritanga Secondary School for Girls in the northern region of Kilimanjaro in Tanzania.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/a8a2gqf_house-fire-generic_625x300_11_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Police said the average age of the victims was around nine years old. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-easyjet-flight-forced-to-make-emergency-landing-after-drunk-passenger-causes-chaos-mid-air-6503079]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Video: Drunk EasyJet Passenger Forces Emergency Landing In Munich]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-easyjet-flight-forced-to-make-emergency-landing-after-drunk-passenger-causes-chaos-mid-air-6503079]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Sep 2024 12:16:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An EasyJet flight, bound for Kos International Airport in Greece, was forced to make an emergency landing at Munich International Airport after an allegedly drunk passenger caused midair chaos and terrorised others onboard.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An EasyJet flight, bound for Kos International Airport in Greece, was forced to make an emergency landing at Munich International Airport after an allegedly drunk passenger caused midair chaos and terrorised others onboard. According to the <em>New York Post,</em> the incident took place on Tuesday. The trouble began about two hours after flight U28235 took off from London Gatwick Airport. As the Airbus A320 flew through some turbulence during the scheduled four-hour flight, the passenger, who was clearly intoxicated, stood up to disrupt the flight and also berated the Captain.&nbsp;</p>

<p>A video shared on X by @FlightModeblog captured the dramatic aftermath. In the clip, passengers were seen erupting into cheers, with some even shouting, "Get off, you loser", as German police escorted the rowdy traveller off the plane. Another passenger also received applause for reportedly holding the man down until the Captain landed the plane safely.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Take a look at the video below:&nbsp;</strong></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">On September 3, <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/easyJet?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#easyJet</a> Airbus A320 (G-EZUR) flight <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/U28235?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#U28235</a> from <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/London?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#London</a> Gatwick to <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Kos?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Kos</a>, Greece, was forced to divert to <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Munich?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Munich</a> after a drunk passenger allegedly attempted to open an emergency exit door during the flight.<br />
<br />
? ©Charlotte_keen1/TikTok<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/aviation?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#aviation</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/AvGeek?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#AvGeek</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/avgeeks?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#avgeeks</a> <a href="https://t.co/ZakIQO8FEv">pic.twitter.com/ZakIQO8FEv</a></p>
— FlightMode (@FlightModeblog) <a href="https://twitter.com/FlightModeblog/status/1831568908018454798?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 5, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/09/05/world-news/easyjet-flight-makes-emer/" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>The Post</em></a>, EasyJet said that the emergency landing stemmed from a "passenger behaving disruptively on board".&nbsp;</p>

<p>The outlet reported that the passenger, whose identity hasn't been revealed, got into a war of words with other passengers. He even broke the onboard intercom and fought with the flight crew, which led to a brawl and the traveller being detained.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Safety is easyJet's highest priority and our cabin crew are trained to assess and act quickly and appropriately in all situations to ensure that the safety of the flight and other passengers is not compromised at any time," the airline told <em>The Post</em>. "While such incidents are rare, we take them very seriously and do not tolerate abusive or threatening behaviour onboard," it added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The remaining passengers, on the other hand, disembarked the plane and received hotel and meal accommodations overnight before the flight departed for Greece on Wednesday. "While this was outside of our control, we are sorry for the inconvenience caused," the airline said.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-or-donald-trump-nostradamus-of-us-elections-makes-final-prediction-for-2024-6501674">Harris Or Trump? 'Nostradamus' Of US Presidential Elections Makes Final Prediction For 2024</a></strong></p>

<p>Meanwhile, in another incident, a US man was arrested in August for his alleged disruptive and life-threatening behaviour on an American Airlines flight. Twenty-six-year-old Eric Nicholas Gapco, travelling on flight 2101 from Seattle to Dallas on July 18, exhibited what authorities described as "unruly" behaviour.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Apart from propositioning a female crew member for sex, Gapco also reportedly attempted to open the plane's door mid-flight multiple times, forcing the emergency landing. According to the outlet, he removed his shirt mid-flight and began inhaling on a vape pen while cursing and hitting on a crew member, proposing to her for sex. The passenger also allegedly assaulted a flight attendant.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/a06114s_easyjet-passenger-_625x300_06_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The incident took place on Tuesday. (Representative pic)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/researchers-find-connection-between-alzheimers-and-night-time-light-pollution-6502947]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Researchers Find Connection Between Alzheimer's, Night Time Light Pollution]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/researchers-find-connection-between-alzheimers-and-night-time-light-pollution-6502947]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Sep 2024 11:57:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A team of US researchers on Friday said that they have found a connection between Alzheimer's disease (AD) and night time light pollution from the outdoors.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A team of US researchers on Friday said that they have found a connection between Alzheimer's disease (AD) and night time light pollution from the outdoors.</p>

<p>Researchers at Rush University Medical Center, US have found that night time light pollution is more strongly correlated with the prevalence of Alzheimer's disease (AD) in people aged under 65, than other risk factors like alcohol abuse, chronic kidney disease, depression, and obesity.</p>

<p>“We show that there is a positive association between AD prevalence and exposure to light at night, particularly in those under the age of 65. Nightly light pollution – a modifiable environmental factor, may be an important risk factor for AD,” said Dr Robin Voigt-Zuwala, Associate Professor at Rush University Medical Center.</p>

<p>Other risk factors, such as diabetes, high blood pressure, and stroke, were more strongly associated with AD than light pollution.</p>

<p>However, for people under 65, higher night time light intensity was associated with a greater AD prevalence than any other risk factor.</p>

<p>This could be due to individual differences in light sensitivity and lifestyles in urban areas.</p>

<p>“Awareness of the association should empower people – particularly those with risk factors for AD – to make easy lifestyle changes. Easy to implement changes include using blackout curtains or sleeping with eye masks. This is useful, especially for those living in areas with high light pollution,” noted Dr Voigt-Zuwala.</p>

<p>The researchers hope that their findings can help educate people about the potential risks of light at night and encourage lifestyle changes to prevent the onset of diseases like Alzheimer's and other debilitating conditions.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-09/i248cja_alzheimers-glance_625x300_07_September_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Other risk factors, such as diabetes, stroke, were more strongly associated with AD.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nga-wai-hono-i-te-po-is-new-zealands-maori-queen-know-her-key-responsibilities-6502835]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Key Responsibilities Of New Zealand's Second-Ever Maori Queen]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nga-wai-hono-i-te-po-is-new-zealands-maori-queen-know-her-key-responsibilities-6502835]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Sep 2024 11:39:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Nga Wai Hono I Te Po was anointed as the new Maori Queen in New Zealand on Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Nga Wai Hono I Te Po was anointed as the new Maori Queen in New Zealand on Thursday. The decision was taken by a council of the Indigenous Maori chief after the death of King Kiingi Tuheitia Potatau Te Wherowhero VII. Although the monarch is primarily a ceremonial role and has little official authority, it is still regarded by many tribes as the supreme chief.<br />
<br />
<strong>Role and responsibilities</strong><br />
<br />
<a href="http://https://monarchy.org.nz/home/kingitanga/">As per the official Monarchy New Zealand website</a>, the role of the Maori monarch is different from that of the King of New Zealand. However, the role of monarchy remains important.<br />
<br />
"When Kingitanga, the Maori King movement, was established in 1858, it was hoped that by creating a King, Maori tribes could deal with the settlers on a more equal political footing," reads the website.<br />
<br />
The current <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-new-zealand-s-new-maori-queen-5-points-on-nga-wai-hono-i-te-po-paki-6495087">Maori Queen</a>, Nga Wai Hono I Te Po, has a major symbolic function but no constitutional role. The Maori King or Queen is the paramount chief of several tribes, or iwi, but is not affiliated with all of them, according to Reuters.<br />
<br />
The Queen -- like her predecessor -- has no judicial or legal authority in New Zealand.<br />
<br />
The <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-zealands-maori-crowned-new-queen-after-fathers-death-6494926">Maori monarchy </a>might be old, but it is not an outdated institution and is still relevant. It persists as a lasting manifestation of unity. It is fundamental to Maori communities' cultural and social identities as well as the larger New Zealand identity.<br />
<br />
The Kingitanga movement in New Zealand serves as an example of why monarchies are popular. A monarch is a mana person who dedicates their life to serving others. He or she is the centre of culture and a live representation of a group of people or a country.<br />
<br />
While the Maori Queen functions solely at the cultural level, New Zealand's current monarch Charles III acts on both constitutional and cultural levels. As of now, there seems to be no tension between the two positions. The monarchs enhance each other and share mutual respect, allowing both to better represent New Zealand.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/i97ql18g_nga-wai-hono-i-te-po-paki_625x300_06_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Nga Wai Hono I Te Po is 27 years old]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-malik-obama-barack-obamas-half-brother-vote-for-donald-trump-6502692]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Meet Malik Obama, Barack Obama's Half-Brother Who Will Vote For Trump]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-malik-obama-barack-obamas-half-brother-vote-for-donald-trump-6502692]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Sep 2024 11:16:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In 1992, Malik Obama was the best man during his half-brother Barack Obama’s wedding to Michelle.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Abon'go Malik Obama, half-brother of former US president Barack Obama, is in the spotlight after declaring he will vote for Republican presidential nominee Donald Trump in the November 5 elections.<br />
<br />
"I am Malik Obama. I'm a registered Republican and I'm voting for President Donald Trump," Malik wrote on the social media site X.<br />
<br />
However, this was not the first time he extended support to Trump. He backed the former US president in 2016 as well, saying he supported Trump's policies, especially his focus on security.<br />
<br />
Who is Abon'go Malik Obama?<br />
<br />
Born in Kenya, Malik is the son of economist Barack Obama Sr and his first wife Kezia Obama. The Kenyan-American businessman and philanthropist is a US citizen.<br />
<br />
He serves as the Lead Ambassador at Puppet, a software configuration management tool,<a href="https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/who-is-malik-obama-barack-obamas-half-brother-now-backs-donald-trump-following-tim-walz-family-controversy/articleshow/113087800.cms"> The Times of India</a> reported.<br />
<br />
In the US, he has majorly worked as an accountant for organisations in and around Washington DC. Some of these include Lockheed Martin, the American Red Cross and Fannie Mae.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
Earlier, Malik tried to run for governor in Kenya's Siaya district, where his father hailed from. However, he only managed to get 1% of the vote.<br />
<br />
As per public records, he still maintains a residence in Maryland and is a registered voter there.<br />
<br />
Personal life<br />
<br />
Malik has often been in the limelight due to his controversies and political endorsements. His relationship with his half-brother Barack Obama has witnessed several ups and downs.<br />
<br />
In 1992, Malik was the best man during Barack's wedding to Michelle. He even visited the White House during his half-brother's time in office, <a href="https://nypost.com/2024/09/05/us-news/barack-obamas-half-brother-malik-says-hes-voting-for-trump/">New York Post</a> reported.<br />
<br />
Earlier, several media reports even suggested that Malik was married to between three and 12 women, but he refuted these claims later.<br />
<br />
Malik had a fallout with the former US president after he launched a charity, named Barack H. Obama Foundation. However, he failed to register it and even lied about it being a tax-exempt organisation.<br />
<br />
"My brother didn't help me at all. He wanted me to shut it down when I set it up. He hasn't supported me at all," Malik said in an earlier interview.<br />
<br />
Malik even added fuel to the conspiracy theory, which was earlier spread majorly by Donald Trump, claiming that Barack Obama was not born in the US and was rather a citizen of Kenya.<br />
<br />
To prove his claims, Malik reportedly even shared a fake image of a birth certificate, dated from before the 1964 establishment of the Republic of Kenya. It purportedly showed Barack Obama was born outside the US.<br />
<br />
Calling his younger half-sibling a “deep disappointment,” Malik earlier also slammed Hillary Clinton, the 2016 Democratic nominee, for his exit from the party.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/lkoh694g_barack-obama-half-brother_625x300_06_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>