<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Tue, 20 Aug 2024 02:27:10 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistan-confirms-mpox-case-detected-last-week-not-new-strain-6373415]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Pakistan Confirms Mpox Case Detected Last Week Not New Strain]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistan-confirms-mpox-case-detected-last-week-not-new-strain-6373415]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 20 Aug 2024 00:02:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A case of mpox in Pakistan announced last week was not the new strain spreading through Africa, health officials said Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A case of mpox in Pakistan announced last week was not the new strain spreading through Africa, health officials said Monday.</p>

<p>The mpox diagnosis in a 34-year-old man recently returned from a Gulf country was declared by health officials on Friday, while testing over the exact strain was carried out.</p>

<p>"The virus has been classified as Clade 2b," the health ministry said in a statement on Monday.</p>

<p>"Currently, the ongoing outbreak in the Democratic Republic of the Congo (DRC) is primarily associated with Clade 1b. Notably, as of now, there have been no reported cases of Clade 1b in Pakistan."</p>

<p>Mpox infections surged worldwide in May 2022, mostly affecting gay and bisexual men due to the Clade 2b subclade, but cases have largely subsided.</p>

<p>The World Health Organization declared last week the rapid spread of the new Clade 1b strain in Africa a public health emergency of international concern -- the highest alarm it can sound.</p>

<p>Sweden's Public Health Agency said Thursday that it had registered a case of the Clade 1b subclade, the first to be diagnosed out of Africa.</p>

<p>Around 16,000 cases have been recorded in the Democratic Republic of Congo, the epicentre of the epidemic which has killed 548 people in the country so far.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-07/fcd7k5c_monkeypox-afp_650x400_23_July_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["The virus has been classified as Clade 2b," Pak health ministry said. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/as-polio-reemerges-in-gaza-a-mother-fears-for-her-childs-health-6373369]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[As Polio Reemerges In Gaza, A Mother Fears For Her Child's Health]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/as-polio-reemerges-in-gaza-a-mother-fears-for-her-childs-health-6373369]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 19 Aug 2024 23:57:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In Gaza, a mother worries that her month-old son, Mohammed, could be infected with polio after the Palestinian health ministry confirmed the first case in the enclave on Friday, ending a 25 year period in which the Strip was polio-free.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In Gaza, a mother worries that her month-old son, Mohammed, could be infected with polio after the Palestinian health ministry confirmed the first case in the enclave on Friday, ending a 25 year period in which the Strip was polio-free.</p>

<p>Just three days after his birth, Ghada al-Ghandour's son Mohammed started developing skin rashes.</p>

<p>"He had skin rashes as if he was burnt," she said.</p>

<p>A doctor told her there were no creams to treat her child.</p>

<p>She later brought him to Al-Aqsa Martyrs Hospital in Deir al-Balah in central Gaza to seek a diagnosis and treatment.</p>

<p>The rash fueled his mother's fears that other symptoms and diseases could follow due to a lack of hygiene and medical supplies in Gaza after more than 10 months of conflict.</p>

<p>In a statement, the Palestinian health ministry confirmed the first case of polio in the city of Deir al-Balah had been detected in a 10-month-old baby who had not been vaccinated.</p>

<p>Likewise, Mohammed has not received a polio vaccine.</p>

<p>"My son was deprived of the first vaccine in his first month," his mother said.</p>

<p>Polio was detected in sewage in Gaza's Deir al-Balah and Khan Younis governorates, Dr. Hamid Jafari, a polio specialist at the World Health Organization (WHO), said on Aug. 7, adding it was possible the virus had been circulating since September.</p>

<p><strong>'YET ANOTHER THREAT TO CHILDREN'</strong></p>

<p>Poliomyelitis, which is spread mainly through the fecal-oral route, is a highly infectious virus that can invade the nervous system and cause paralysis.</p>

<p>Children under 5 are most at risk from the viral disease, and especially infants under 2 since normal vaccination regimens have been disrupted by the war.</p>

<p>"If the occupation (Israeli forces) continues to close the (border) crossing and denies access to vaccines, it will lead to a health disaster," said Khalil al-Daqran, spokesperson of Al-Aqsa Martyrs Hospital.</p>

<p>Israel announced on Sunday that it would facilitate the transfer into Gaza of polio vaccines for around one million children.</p>

<p>More than 43,000 vials of the vaccine were expected to arrive in Israel in the coming weeks and would be sent to Gaza, according to a statement from COGAT, the Israeli defence agency that coordinated civilian matters with the Palestinians. This would be enough for two rounds of doses for over a million children, it said.</p>

<p>But Al-Daqran of Al-Aqsa Martyrs Hospital said a vaccination campaign could not happen without a pause in fighting.</p>

<p>The reemergence of polio "represents yet another threat to the children in the Gaza Strip and neighbouring countries," the WHO said on Aug. 16.</p>

<p>Nearly half of Gaza's 2.3 million population are under the age of 18 and around 15% are children under the age of 5, according to the Palestinian Central Bureau of Statistics.</p>

<p>Aside from the resurgence of polio and the threat of other diseases, Palestinians face a humanitarian crisis with shortages of food, fuel and water inflicting suffering every day.</p>

<p>The war in Gaza started after Hamas attacked southern Israel, killing 1,200 people and taking over 250 hostage, according to Israeli tallies. The death count of Palestinians killed by the Israeli military campaign has exceeded 40,000, according to Gaza authorities.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/id5us9h_gaza-polio-scare_625x300_19_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Children under 5 are most at risk from polio]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-islamic-jihad-claim-responsibility-for-bomb-blast-in-tel-aviv-6373359]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hamas, Islamic Jihad Claim Responsibility For Bomb Blast In Tel Aviv]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-islamic-jihad-claim-responsibility-for-bomb-blast-in-tel-aviv-6373359]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 19 Aug 2024 23:52:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The armed wings of Hamas and Islamic Jihad claimed responsibility on Monday for a bomb blast near a synagogue in Tel Aviv that Israeli police and the Shin Bet intelligence agency described as a terrorist attack.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The armed wings of Hamas and Islamic Jihad claimed responsibility on Monday for a bomb blast near a synagogue in Tel Aviv that Israeli police and the Shin Bet intelligence agency described as a terrorist attack.</p>

<p>A man who was carrying the bomb was killed and a passerby was injured in the incident late on Sunday, according to police at the scene in Israel's commercial capital.</p>

<p>Israeli government spokesperson David Mencer said the man was carrying a backpack loaded with explosives that detonated "before he managed to reach a more heavily populated area".</p>

<p>In a joint statement, the two Palestinian groups said their "martyrdom operations" inside Israel would return to the forefront as long as the "occupation's massacres and assassination policy continue". This was an allusion to Israel's offensive in Gaza and the July 31 killing of Hamas leader Ismail Haniyeh in Tehran.</p>

<p>Israel has neither claimed nor denied responsibility for Haniyeh's death in the Iranian capital.</p>

<p>The war in Gaza began on Oct. 7 last year when Hamas gunmen entered across the border into Israeli communities, killing around 1,200 people and abducting about 250 hostages according to Israeli tallies.</p>

<p>Israel's military campaign has since levelled wide swathes of the Gaza Strip and killed at least 40,000 people, according to the enclave's health authorities.</p>

<p>Sunday's explosion in Tel Aviv came about an hour after U.S. Secretary of State Antony Blinken arrived in Tel Aviv to push for a ceasefire in Gaza to end the 10-month-old war between Israel and Hamas.</p>

<p>There has been increased urgency to reach a ceasefire deal amid fears of an escalation across the wider region. Iran has threatened to retaliate against Israel after the assassination of Haniyeh.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/qpvr6jso_tel-aviv-bomb-blast_625x300_19_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sunday's explosion in Tel Aviv came about an hour after Blinken arrived in Tel Aviv]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/blinken-says-israel-accepts-gaza-truce-proposal-ball-now-in-hamas-court-6373320]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Blinken Says Israel "Accepts" Gaza Truce Proposal, Ball Now In Hamas' Court]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/blinken-says-israel-accepts-gaza-truce-proposal-ball-now-in-hamas-court-6373320]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 19 Aug 2024 23:47:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Secretary of State Antony Blinken on Monday urged Hamas to accept a US bridging proposal for a Gaza ceasefire and hostage release deal after what he said was a "very constructive" meeting with Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Secretary of State Antony Blinken on Monday urged Hamas to accept a US bridging proposal for a Gaza ceasefire and hostage release deal after what he said was a "very constructive" meeting with Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu.</p>

<p>He had earlier said the latest push for a deal was probably the best and possibly last opportunity, urging both sides towards agreement.</p>

<p>Talks in Qatar last week paused without a breakthrough, but the negotiations are expected to resume this week based on the US proposal to bridge the gaps between Israel and Hamas.</p>

<p>However, with the Palestinian Islamist group announcing a resumption of suicide bombing inside Israel after many years, and medics saying Israeli military strikes killed at least 30 Palestinians across the Gaza Strip on Monday, there are few signs of conciliation on the ground.</p>

<p>"In a very constructive meeting with Prime Minister Netanyahu today, he confirmed to me that Israel accepts the bridging proposal - that he supports it," Blinken told reporters in Tel Aviv.</p>

<p>"It's now incumbent on Hamas to do the same, and then the parties, with the help of the mediators - the United States, Egypt and Qatar - have to come together and complete the process of reaching clear understandings about how they'll implement the commitments that they've made under this agreement."</p>

<p>Despite US expressions of optimism and Netanyahu's office describing the meeting as positive, both Israel and Hamas have signalled that any deal will be difficult.</p>

<p>Hamas accused Netanyahu on Sunday of "thwarting the mediators' efforts" and Turkey said Hamas envoys had told it that US officials were "painting an overly optimistic picture".</p>

<p>Months of on-off talks have circled the same issues, with Israel saying the war can only end with the destruction of Hamas as a military and political force and Hamas saying it will only accept a permanent, and not a temporary, ceasefire.</p>

<p>There are disagreements over Israel's continued military presence inside Gaza, particularly along the border with Egypt, over the free movement of Palestinians inside the territory, and over the identity and number of prisoners to be freed in a swap.</p>

<p>The current war in Gaza began on October 7 last year when Hamas gunmen rushed across the border into Israeli communities, killing around 1,200 people and abducting about 250 hostages according to Israeli tallies.</p>

<p>Israel's military campaign has since levelled swathes of Gaza, driving nearly all of its 2.3 million people from their homes, giving rise to deadly hunger and disease and killing at least 40,000 people according to Palestinian health authorities.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/iq5k0vlg_-gaza-strip_625x300_12_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The current war in Gaza began on October 7 last year (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/95-year-old-groom-90-year-old-bride-and-a-six-decade-love-story-6373275]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[95-Year-Old Groom, 90-Year-old Bride And A Six-Decade Love Story]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/95-year-old-groom-90-year-old-bride-and-a-six-decade-love-story-6373275]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 19 Aug 2024 23:35:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 95-year-old Kenyan man married his 90-year-old long-time sweetheart at the weekend, six decades after they first met, local media reported on Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 95-year-old Kenyan man married his 90-year-old long-time sweetheart at the weekend, six decades after they first met, local media reported on Monday.</p>

<p>Ibrahim Mbogo walked down the aisle with Tabitha Wangui at a white wedding at a church on Sunday, private media outlet Citizen Digital reported.</p>

<p>"We met and fell in love in 1960, do you hear?" Mbogo was quoted as saying outside the church in Mukurweini, a town about a three-hour drive northeast of the Kenyan capital Nairobi.</p>

<p>"We deliberated together and decided it would be great if we did a white wedding, we know in our Kikuyu custom that we are legally married, but since we are also Christians, we decided to do a church wedding."</p>

<p>The groom wore a smart grey suit and silver tie for their special day, while his new bride was dressed in a white hat with a cream brocade jacket over a white outfit.</p>

<p>Asked about their secret, Wangui told Citizen Digital: "Women, you must respect your husbands, if you do that, then you will live as we have."</p>

<p>"Don't do any wrong, and when you do, just apologise and seek forgiveness."</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/nl1uvmhg_ibrahim-mbogo-tabitha-wangui_625x300_19_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["We met and fell in love in 1960," said Ibrahim Mbogo]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-shows-doctored-pictures-showing-taylor-swifts-support-6373114]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump Shows Doctored Pictures Showing Taylor Swift's Support]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-shows-doctored-pictures-showing-taylor-swifts-support-6373114]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 19 Aug 2024 23:07:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump has shared doctored images on social media showing Taylor Swift and her fans supporting his presidential campaign, in an apparent effort to tap into the pop singer's mega star power in the US election.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump has shared doctored images on social media showing Taylor Swift and her fans supporting his presidential campaign, in an apparent effort to tap into the pop singer's mega star power in the US election.</p>

<p>Ms Swift has not yet publicly thrown her weight behind any presidential candidate in the November 5 election, but she backed President Joe Biden in 2020 and has previously been critical of Trump.</p>

<p>On Sunday, Trump shared screenshots of posts with manipulated images -- including some that an expert said appeared to be AI-generated -- suggesting that the pop star and her fans, popularly known as Swifties, support his campaign.</p>

<p>In his Truth Social post, which includes a poster of Swift clad in an Uncle Sam outfit and instructing her fans to vote for Trump, the former president wrote: "I accept!"</p>

<p>That poster is either "AI generated or just classically manipulated," Hany Farid, a digital forensics expert at the University of California, Berkeley, told AFP.</p>

<p>The post also includes photos of women wearing shirts with the slogan "Swifties for Trump," some of which Farid said had the "tell-tale signs of being AI-generated."</p>

<p>What makes the mash-up "particularly devious" is that is a combination of real and fake imagery, with at least one photo of a woman wearing such a shirt looking legitimate, Farid said.</p>

<p>There was no immediate comment from Swift about the post by Trump, who separately shared on Truth Social a video of a supporter voicing the dubious claim that "Swifties were rallying for Trump."</p>

<p>Swift's soaring popularity and sway over her fans could make her support valuable in the upcoming presidential election.</p>

<p>Both Republicans and Democrats have long wanted to count on her support, but the megastar has been largely reticent about her political leanings.</p>

<p>In a demonstration of her star power, when Swift encouraged her fans to register to vote last fall, directing them to the nonpartisan nonprofit Vote.org, her plea had an immediate impact.</p>

<p>Following her message, the institution said it recorded more than 35,000 new registrations, 23 per cent more than last year and the most since 2020.</p>

<p>Swift's feelers into politics have been heavily scrutinized, making her a ripe target for political misinformation and right-wing conspiracy theories.</p>

<p>Her reserve led many critics to speculate Swift was a closet Republican, until 2018, when she broke both her silence and the internet by endorsing the Democratic opponent of far-right US Senator Marsha Blackburn in Tennessee.</p>

<p>She has since spoken out in particular for the legal right to an abortion and LGBTQ+ rights.</p>

<p>In recent weeks, intense speculation has swirled on social media that Swift will endorse Democratic nominee Kamala Harris in the November election.</p>

<p>The megastar has not commented publicly, but that has not stopped legions of fans from forming a group called "Swifties for Kamala," attracting tens of thousands of followers on platforms such as Instagram and X, formerly Twitter.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/vjnq2ub_donald-trump_625x300_18_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump shared screenshots of posts with manipulated images.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-ukraine-war-has-turned-ex-google-ceo-eric-schmidt-into-licensed-arms-dealer-6372469]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How Ukraine War Has Turned Ex Google CEO Into "Licensed Arms Dealer"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-ukraine-war-has-turned-ex-google-ceo-eric-schmidt-into-licensed-arms-dealer-6372469]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 19 Aug 2024 21:19:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former Google CEO, Eric Schmidt, has said that the Ukraine war has turned him into a licensed arms dealer. Mr Schmidt's new venture aims to converge AI and defense technology to help Ukraine fight in the ongoing war against Russia.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former Chief Executive Officer of Google, Eric Schmidt, has said that the Ukraine war has turned him into a licensed arms dealer, a career path he "doesn't recommend". Mr Schmidt's new venture aims to &nbsp;converge AI and defense technology to help Ukraine fight in the ongoing war against Russia.</p>

<p>Mr Schmidt reportedly delivered a lecture in Stanford University in April where he talked about how Russian atrocities in Ukraine affected him. "Watching the Russians use tanks to destroy apartment buildings with little old ladies and kids just drove me crazy," he said.</p>

<p>Mr Schmidt, who was Google's CEO from 2001 to 2011, along with Sebastian Thrun, CEO of Udacity, is working on a new start up called White Stork. "The idea basically is to do two things- use AI in complicated, powerful ways for these essentially robotic wars and the second one is to lower the cost of robots," he said.</p>

<p>The lecture Mr Schmidt delivered at Stanford in April was posted by the university on its YouTube last week, according to a report in Business Insider. The lecture quickly went viral, however, it was later taken down.</p>

<p>In the lecture, Mr Schmidt reportedly informed that White Stork will mass-produce drones equipped with Artificial Intelligence to identify targets to eliminate the need for ground battles with tanks, artillery and mortar.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In a clip of the lecture, now in wide circulation on X, formerly twitter, Mr Schmidt says, "The whole theory of armies is tanks, artilleries and mortar and we can eliminate all of them, and we can make the penalty for invading a country, at least by land, essentially be impossible."</p>

<p>Mr Schmidt said that he is now a licensed arms dealer "because of the way the system works". "A computer scientist, businessman, arms dealer. I do not recommend this in your career path, I'd stick with AI," he said.</p>

<p>"Because of the way the laws work, we're doing this privately and this is all legal with the support of the government, so it goes straight into Ukraine and then they fight the war," he added.</p>

<p>The Russia-Ukraine war, which started in February 2022, has been going on for almost two and a half years now.</p>

<p>In the latest development, Ukrainian forces struck a third bridge in an attack on Russia's Kursk region. According to Ukraine, the ongoing offensive in the Kursk region is aimed at creating a "buffer zone" and to bring war closer to an end.</p>

<p>Ukraine's ongoing offensive in Kursk is said to be the biggest attack on Russia since World War II.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/enmvvahg_eric-schmidt_625x300_14_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mr Schmidt said that he is now a licensed arms dealer "because of the way the system works" (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-tech-tycoon-missing-after-superyacht-sinks-off-sicily-in-italy-6371906]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK Tech Tycoon Missing After Superyacht Sinks Off Sicily In Italy]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-tech-tycoon-missing-after-superyacht-sinks-off-sicily-in-italy-6371906]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 19 Aug 2024 19:47:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[UK businessman Mike Lynch, who was recently acquitted in the United States of an $11 billion fraud, is among those missing Monday after a superyacht sank off southern Italy, according to the head of the Civil Protection Agency.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>UK businessman Mike Lynch, who was recently acquitted in the United States of an $11 billion fraud, is among those missing Monday after a superyacht sank off southern Italy, according to the head of the Civil Protection Agency.</p>

<p>The 56-metre-long luxury yacht, The Bayesian, had been moored off Porticello, east of Palermo, when the storm swept suddenly up the coast before dawn, tearing through beach clubs and little fishing ports.</p>

<p>Lynch's wife was among 15 people rescued after the luxury yacht sank amid violent winds and rains off the Sicily coast, according to Salvo Cocina of the Civil Protection Agency, leaving six others missing.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Italian authorities have opened a probe into the incident as the emergency response continued Monday.</p>

<p>Lynch, 59, was acquitted on all charges in a San Francisco court in early June after he was accused of the massive fraud linked to the sale of his software firm Autonomy to Hewlett-Packard.&nbsp;</p>

<p>He co-founded Autonomy in Cambridge in 1996.&nbsp;</p>

<p>US prosecutors accused Lynch of wire fraud and securities fraud, and conspiracy to commit offenses involving years of falsified records.</p>

<p>He had been extradited to the US from Britain to stand trial on the criminal charges.</p>

<p>A University of Cambridge graduate from Suffolk in eastern England, Lynch had disputed all charges and denied any wrongdoing. He was facing two decades in jail if convicted of the 17 charges.</p>

<p>A celebrated technology sector entrepreneur and investor, sometimes referred to as the UK's answer to Bill Gates, he had won numerous awards and plaudits in Britain and beyond.</p>

<p>A spokesperson for Invoke Capital, another firm he founded, declined to comment.</p>

<p>Lynch was reportedly on board the boat with colleagues from the company when the storm struck.</p>

<p>Following his US acquittal, he had been critical of his prosecution in the US.&nbsp;</p>

<p>He had told the BBC that the only reason he was free was "because I had enough money not to be swept away by a process that's set up to sweep you away".</p>

<p>"You shouldn't need to have funds to protect yourself as a British citizen", he said in the interview aired earlier this month.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/onohern_mike-lynch_625x300_19_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mike Lynch's wife was among 15 people rescued after the luxury yacht sank.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/muhammad-yunus-message-to-diplomats-big-reforms-ahead-of-bangladesh-polls-6370076]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh Polls Postponed? Muhammad Yunus Prioritises Big Reforms]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/muhammad-yunus-message-to-diplomats-big-reforms-ahead-of-bangladesh-polls-6370076]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 19 Aug 2024 14:59:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In a key address to diplomats in Dhaka on Sunday, Muhammad Yunus, the Chief Adviser to Bangladesh's interim government, called for comprehensive reforms before holding the next general elections.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a key address to diplomats in Dhaka on Sunday, Muhammad Yunus, the Chief Adviser to Bangladesh's interim government, called for comprehensive reforms before holding the next general elections. This meeting marked Mr Yunus' first engagement with the diplomatic community since assuming office on August 8, following the resignation of former Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina.</p>

<p>Mr Yunus, a Nobel laureate, took charge amid a volatile political landscape that saw mass protests and violence resulting in the ousting of Ms Hasina. In his address, Yunus outlined the interim government's roadmap for a stable and democratic Bangladesh, starting with a free, fair, and participatory election.</p>

<p>"We will hold a free, fair participatory election as soon as we can complete our mandate to carry out vital reforms in our election commission, judiciary, civil administration, security forces and media," he told diplomats, including India's High Commissioner in Dhaka, Pranay Verma.</p>

<h3><strong>Restoring Normalcy&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>On August 5, Ms Hasina, aged 76, fled Bangladesh by helicopter to India as protesters overran the streets of Dhaka. Her 15-year rule, marked by allegations of human rights abuses, came to a dramatic end. The weeks leading up to her ousting were bloody, with more than 450 dying during the unrest and several reports of attacks on Bangladesh's Hindu minority community.</p>

<p>The Chief Adviser said restoring law and order in the country is a top priority for his government. "We will be close to normalcy within a short period, with the unwavering support of our people and patriotic armed forces," Mr Yunus said. "The top priority of the Interim Government would be to bring the law and order situation under control...The armed forces will continue to serve in aid of civil power as long as the situation warrants."</p>

<h3><strong>Reviving Economy&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>In addition to political reforms, Mr Yunus spoke about the need for robust economic reforms. The country had suffered under what he described as Ms Hasina's "brutal dictatorship," which, according to Mr Yunus, had led to widespread corruption and mismanagement.</p>

<p>"Our government will undertake far-reaching economic reforms to restore macroeconomic stability and sustain growth," he said.</p>

<p>Mr Yunus accused Sheikh Hasina of systematically destroying the country's institutions during her 15-year tenure. He alleged that elections under Ms Hasina's rule were rigged, and democratic rights were suppressed.</p>

<p>"In their efforts to stay in power, Sheikh Hasina's dictatorship destroyed every institution of the country," Mr Yunus said. He described the judiciary as broken and accused the former administration of allowing political patronage to rob banks and plunder the state coffers.</p>

<p>The Nobel laureate described the recent mass uprising as a "Second Revolution," led by students and ordinary citizens who sought to reclaim their democratic rights.&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>International Support</strong></h3>

<p>In his message to the international community, Mr Yunus called for continued support in rebuilding Bangladesh and transitioning to a fully functional democracy. He assured the diplomats that Bangladesh would maintain its role as a proponent of multilateralism, with the United Nations at the core of its foreign policy.</p>

<p>"We believe all our friends and partners in the international community will stand by our government and people as we chart a new democratic future," Yunus said.</p>

<p>"Bangladesh stands at the crossroads of a new beginning. Our valiant students and people deserve a lasting transformation of our nation. It is a difficult journey and we need your help along the way. We need to fulfil their aspirations. The sooner the better," he added.</p>

<p>Mr Yunus also welcomed the United Nations' decision to send a fact-finding mission to investigate the recent violence, committing to cooperate fully with the international inquiry.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/j4vjvr9g_muhammad-yunus-afp_625x300_19_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mr Yunus accused Sheikh Hasina of systematically destroying the country's institutions.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gen-z-traveller-whos-been-to-190-countries-calls-egypt-most-annoying-6370048]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Gen Z Traveller, Who's Been To 190 Countries, Calls Egypt "Most Annoying"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gen-z-traveller-whos-been-to-190-countries-calls-egypt-most-annoying-6370048]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 19 Aug 2024 14:54:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Egypt might be on the bucket list of numerous travellers fond of exploring the country's past and mythology. However, a Gen-Z travel influencer has raised eyebrows by calling the Land of the Pharaohs an overrated destination.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Egypt might be on the bucket list of numerous travellers fond of exploring the country's past and mythology. However, a Gen-Z travel influencer has raised eyebrows by calling the Land of the Pharaohs an overrated destination. Luca Pferdmenges, a 22-year-old German juggler-turned-explorer, made the bold claim in an interaction with <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/article-13738333/Ive-visited-190-countries-five-left-picks-best-worst-food-dangerous-favourite-European-country.html">Daily Mail</a>.</p>

<p>Without citing any reason for his statement Luca said, "Egypt is the most annoying country for tourists in my opinion." He added a few more coastal destinations, including Seychelles, Mauritius, Maldives, and most of the Caribbean Lesser Antilles, to the list. According to the young adult, these places were "very touristy" and did not offer much "besides pretty beaches."</p>

<p>As per Daily Mail, Luca Pferdmenges started his globe-trotting adventures when he was just 15 years old. Since then, he has visited as many as 190 countries. In the interview, Luca opened up on his least and most favourite countries, along with the place's best and worst cuisines and which locations were the cheapest and most expensive.</p>

<p>In his opinion, Belgium was "pretty ugly" with its depressive weather. Luca Pferdmenges felt "super unsafe" at night in the country's capital Brussels. "It just feels super unsafe at night in my opinion - and I'm talking about Brussels here. And many of the Belgian cities are pretty ugly as well. Grey and depressive, especially in winter. Avoid Brussels North at night. But Paris, London, or Frankfurt aren't much better at night, either," he revealed.</p>

<p>Luca Pferdmenges has also helped tourists by sharing a list of the most underrated travel destinations he wished more people would visit. The countries that fall in the category include Uzbekistan, Montenegro, Myanmar, Bhutan, North Macedonia, some parts of Central Asia, Baltic countries, and several countries in Latin America.</p>

<p>When asked to disclose his top favourite destinations, the traveller said, "No particular order: Mexico, Brazil, Israel, Spain, Bhutan, UK, UAE, Portugal, Austria."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/igsjj8go_luca-pferdmenges_625x300_19_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Luca Pferdmenges reportedly started his globe-trotting adventures when he was 15 (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-2024-joe-biden-accused-of-impeachable-offence-ahead-of-democratic-convention-6370040]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Joe Biden Accused Of "Impeachable" Offence Ahead Of Democratic Convention]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-2024-joe-biden-accused-of-impeachable-offence-ahead-of-democratic-convention-6370040]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 19 Aug 2024 14:51:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US House of Representatives Republicans issued a report on Monday alleging Democratic President Joe Biden committed impeachable offences, but it was unclear whether they would push for a vote.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US House of Representatives Republicans issued a report on Monday alleging Democratic President Joe Biden committed impeachable offences, but it was unclear whether they would push for a vote following a probe the White House has long dismissed as politically motivated.</p>

<p>A 291-page report by three House committees alleged that Biden profited from an influence-peddling scheme to enrich himself and members of his family through foreign business dealings beginning in 2014 when Biden was vice president.</p>

<p>"The committees present this information to the House of Representatives for its evaluation and consideration of appropriate next steps," the report said.</p>

<p>It was not clear if Republican House Speaker Mike Johnson would schedule a vote to impeach Biden in the weeks leading up to the Nov. 5 election, in which Republican Donald Trump is locked in a tight battle with Vice President Kamala Harris.</p>

<p>Even if the Republican-controlled House were to pass such a measure, it would be unlikely to remove Biden from office, given that he would need to be convicted by a Senate controlled 51-49 by his own Democratic Party. Biden, who withdrew his own reelection bid last month, is due to leave office when his successor is sworn in on Jan. 20.</p>

<p>A similar House impeachment against Biden's top border official, Homeland Security Secretary Alejandro Mayorkas, was put to a swift end by the Senate in April.</p>

<p>The House investigators claim that Biden used his influence to benefit the business dealings of his son, Hunter Biden, with partners from Ukraine, China, Russia and other countries.</p>

<p>Hunter Biden has been convicted on charges that he lied about his illegal drug use to buy a gun and is awaiting trial on charges of tax evasion, including an allegation that he accepted payments from a Romanian businessman who sought to influence U.S. government agencies in connection with a criminal probe in Romania.</p>

<p>The impeachment inquiry, which lawmakers formally authorized last December and has been carried out by the House Oversight, Judiciary and Ways &amp; Means Committees, has been criticized by members of both parties for failing to produce hard evidence of wrongdoing by Biden.</p>

<p>Democrats have disparaged the effort as retribution for Trump, who was impeached twice by a Democratic-controlled House and acquitted each time by the Senate. The first impeachment alleged that Trump pressured Ukraine President Volodymyr Zelenskiy to help smear Joe Biden in return for US aid.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/r5eouhrg_joe-biden-new_625x300_22_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden is due to leave office when his successor is sworn in on Jan 20 (file).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/switzerland-offers-rs-50-lakh-for-solutions-to-clear-ammunition-from-lakes-6369003]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Switzerland Offers Rs 50 Lakh For Solutions To Clear Ammunition From Lakes]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/switzerland-offers-rs-50-lakh-for-solutions-to-clear-ammunition-from-lakes-6369003]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 19 Aug 2024 14:38:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Swiss government is looking for innovative solutions to remove thousands of tonnes of ammunition dumped in the lakes. And it comes with a massive 50,000 franc (Rs 48.5 lakhs) prize money.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Swiss government is looking for innovative solutions to remove thousands of tonnes of ammunition dumped in the lakes. And it comes with a massive 50,000 franc (Rs 48.5 lakhs) prize money. The ammunition, estimated to be around 3,300 tonnes in Lake Lucerne and 4,500 tonnes in Lake Neuchatel, was disposed of by the Swiss military.</p>

<h2><strong>Background</strong></h2>

<p>Dumping munitions in lakes dates back to the Cold War era when Switzerland maintained a large militia army as part of its “armed neutrality” defence strategy. For decades, between 1918 and 1964, the Swiss military used the lakes – Neuchatel, Thun, Brienz and Lucerne – as dumping grounds for old munitions, believing it to be a safe disposal method. However, the reality is far from it. Some munitions lie at depths of 150-220 metres, while others are just six or seven metres below the surface. The risk of explosion and water and soil contamination is high, with toxic TNT potentially polluting the lake water and sediment.</p>

<h2><strong>Challenges</strong></h2>

<p>The submerged ammunition is covered by a fine sediment layer, and recovery efforts may stir up sediments, leading to oxygen loss and damage to the lake ecosystem. Previous assessments have shown that proposed recovery techniques would lead to muddy waters and high risks for the sensitive ecosystem of the lake.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The recovery operation is expected to be long and costly, with estimates suggesting it could cost billions, which is why the Swiss defence department is seeking ideas for a safe and environmental solution to retrieve the munitions, with the public invited to submit their proposals until February next year.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The competition, where the top three entries will be given&nbsp;prize money worth almost Rs 50 lakh, is open and anonymous, and the last date to submit entries is February 6, 2025. A panel of experts will assess the entries based on predefined criteria and announce the results in April 2025.</p>

<p>Retired Swiss geologist Marcos Buser suggests seeking advice from countries with experience in dealing with wartime wrecks containing unexploded weapons, such as the UK, Norway or Denmark. Mr Buser who advised the government on the issue warned of the dangers of explosion and contamination and stated the need for a careful and well-planned recovery operation, as per the BBC.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In his research paper, Mr Buser highlighted two primary concerns: the risk of explosion and water and soil contamination.</p>

<p>Since fuses were not removed from the munitions before dumping, the risk of explosion remains even underwater. It poses a significant threat to the environment and human safety. Water and soil contamination is another concern, as highly toxic TNT could pollute the lake water and sediment. It could have devastating effects on the ecosystem.&nbsp;</p>

<p>This is not the first time the Swiss military has faced criticism for its handling of munitions. In 1947, a massive blast in Mitholz killed nine people and destroyed the village. More recently, the military revealed that 3,500 tonnes of unexploded ammunition buried in the mountain was not safe, requiring a decade-long clean-up operation.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/5npcvk8g_switzerland_625x300_09_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The submerged ammunition is covered by a fine sediment layer (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gen-z-is-turning-their-climate-change-anxiety-into-activism-heres-why-6369919]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Gen Z Is Turning Their Climate Change Anxiety Into Activism, Here's Why]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gen-z-is-turning-their-climate-change-anxiety-into-activism-heres-why-6369919]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 19 Aug 2024 14:34:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In June 2024, 13 young people in Hawaii took on their state government in court and won the right to have greater input in climate policy.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In June 2024, 13 young people in Hawaii took on their state government in court and won the right to have greater input in climate policy.</p>

<p>They sued the state for infringing on their right to "a clean and healthful environment", as promised under the State constitution.</p>

<p>In victory, the young people forced a number of concessions including a pledge to pursue net zero by 2040 and over USD 40 million investment in electric vehicles over the next six years.</p>

<p>Young people are turning to activism as a way to process the emotional weight of a world in crisis.</p>

<p>From Greta Thunberg to Australia's Anjali Sharma, there are plenty of people in Gen Z who are taking action on climate.</p>

<p>Despite the United Nations also adding the right to a clean, healthy and sustainable environment to the Universal Declaration of Human Rights in 2022 which further opens the possibility to take governments to the courts, it's not easy.</p>

<p>Gen Z is growing up in an era where the impacts of climate change are both immediate and undeniable and it's leaving them feeling powerless.</p>

<p>Generation Z - those born between 1995 and 2010 - make up 30 per cent of the global population. In Australia's latest census, Gen Z accounted for 18.2 per cent (or 4.6 million) of the country's 25 million population.</p>

<p>Unlike previous generations, who had time to gradually adjust to the realities of environmental transformations, Generation Z is acutely aware of the ecological crises unfolding around them, leading to a deep sense of environmental anxiety.</p>

<h3><strong>Distress and fear </strong></h3>

<p>As a result, many digitally connected, globally aware Gen Zers experience intense climate anxiety, characterised by chronic fear, distress and deep concern for the planet's future.</p>

<p>A survey of Australian Gen Z university students was conducted between September 2021 and April 2022 with 446 participants which revealed that climate change is their top environmental concern.</p>

<p>They often feel let down by older generations, governments and institutions, whose actions seem inadequate in the face of the growing evidence about the environmental threats the world and Australia in particular face.</p>

<p>More than 80 per cent of the young people participating in the survey expressed significant worry and many experienced severe climate anxiety.</p>

<p>This anxiety manifests in various forms, including eco-anxiety, solastalgia (distress triggered by environmental changes) and climate grief, reflecting the complex emotional landscape of a generation coming of age amid a global environmental emergency.</p>

<p>The situation Gen Z faces and their future prospects are further exacerbated by the complexity of other developments resulting in what is known as a polycrisis, a "great disagreement, confusion, or suffering that is caused by many different problems happening at the same time so that they together have a very big effect."</p>

<h3><strong>Existential threat</strong></h3>

<p>Eco-anxiety, a chronic fear of an environmental catastrophe, arises from the perception that climate change poses an existential threat.</p>

<p>For many in Gen Z, the overwhelming nature of this threat leads to persistent worry and stress. This is also fuelled by the sense of urgency and responsibility they think they have to comply with.</p>

<p>Gen Z is witnessing their local natural environments and the broader global ecosystem undergo rapid, often destructive and irreversible changes, including biodiversity loss, species extinction and the degradation of ecosystems.</p>

<p>Many experience profound grief which is tied not just to physical harm, but also to the loss of hope for a stable and prosperous future.</p>

<p>With 96 per cent of Australian Gen Zs believing that climate change is human-made, young people are experiencing heightened levels of stress, anxiety and depression as they grapple with the realities of a warming planet.</p>

<p>For some members of Gen Z, the constant stream of climate-related news, coupled with personal experiences of climate-related calamities, such as wildfires, floods, droughts or cyclones, leads to a form of trauma that can have long-lasting effects on mental health.</p>

<h3><strong>A generational crisis</strong></h3>

<p>For Gen Z, climate change anxiety is not just about fear of environmental destruction; it is also about grappling with a crisis of identity and purpose.</p>

<p>As they come of age in a world that seems increasingly unstable and unpredictable, many young people are questioning what kind of future they can expect to have, and whether it is even ethical to plan for the future in traditional ways, such as pursuing professional careers, starting families or buying homes, when the planet is in such peril.</p>

<p>This crisis of identity is further complicated by the pressure to act. Many young people feel a deep sense of responsibility to address climate change, but this can also ignite feelings of guilt and shame when they perceive their actions as insufficient.</p>

<p>The weight of this responsibility can be overwhelming, leading to burnout and a sense of futility.</p>

<h3><strong>The role of activism</strong></h3>

<p>In response to these challenges, some members of Gen Z are channelling their anxiety into activism.</p>

<p>Climate activism is seen as a way to regain a sense of control and agency in the face of overwhelming challenges.</p>

<p>This activism takes many forms, from participating in global climate strikes to advocating for sustainable policies at the local level. However, activism is not a panacea for climate anxiety.</p>

<p>This is seen from the answers of 65 per cent of Australia's university Gen Z who do not engage in traditional climate activism, but instead are using technology and social media to voice their concerns.</p>

<p>While it can provide a sense of purpose and community, activism can also be exhausting. The constant need to fight for change, coupled with the slow pace of progress, can lead to burnout and exacerbate mental health issues.</p>

<p>Additionally, the pressure to always be "on" and engaged in activism can be mentally and emotionally draining, leading to further feelings of hopelessness and despair.</p>

<h3><strong>Mental health support</strong></h3>

<p>Given the significant mental health challenges posed by climate change anxiety, there is a growing recognition of the need for robust mental health support for Gen Z.</p>

<p>This support must be tailored to address the unique challenges of climate anxiety, experiencing unprecedented levels of fear and despair, and feelings of hopelessness that are so prevalent among young people.</p>

<p>There is a need for more mental health professionals trained to understand and address eco-anxiety and related issues. Therapeutic interventions that focus on building resilience, fostering a sense of agency and helping young people navigate their complex emotions are crucial.</p>

<p>Building supportive communities where young people can share their experiences, particularly positive outcomes, and feelings about climate change is also important.</p>

<p>These communities can provide a sense of solidarity and help combat the isolation that often accompanies climate anxiety. Schools and educational institutions can play a key role in addressing climate anxiety by incorporating discussions about mental health and climate change into their curricula.</p>

<p>By providing young people with the tools to understand and cope with their emotions, educational initiatives can help mitigate the psychological impacts of climate anxiety.</p>

<h3><strong>The way forward</strong></h3>

<p>The challenges posed by climate change anxiety for Gen Z are indeed profound and multifaceted.</p>

<p>However, the importance and urgency of their role cannot be overstated. With the climate crisis in a time of polycrisis worsening, Gen Z's involvement in shaping a resilient and sustainable future is critical.</p>

<p>Their unique perspective and relentless drive for change position them as key players in responding to global warming as well as in bridging generational divides, fostering global cooperation and ensuring that climate action is grounded in science and equity.</p>

<p><em>(Originally published under&nbsp;<a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/">Creative Commons</a>&nbsp;by&nbsp;<a href="https://360info.org/">360info</a>)</em></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/m6dirrcg_climate-change_625x300_13_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The challenges posed by climate change anxiety for Gen Z are profound and multifaceted (representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-ukraine-war-ukraines-501st-marine-battalion-returns-to-fight-russia-as-incursion-continues-6369863]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ukraine's Marine Battalion Returns To Fight Russia As Incursion Continues]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-ukraine-war-ukraines-501st-marine-battalion-returns-to-fight-russia-as-incursion-continues-6369863]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 19 Aug 2024 14:25:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The 501st Marine Battalion's troubles began during Russia's annexation of Crimea in 2014.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The 501st Marine Battalion, a notorious unit in Ukraine's marine corps, has entered the fight in Russia's Kursk Oblast. The battalion, rebuilt after surrendering twice since 2014, is seeking redemption in the ongoing conflict.</p>

<p>The conflict between Russia and Ukraine first began in 2014, when Moscow annexed Crimea, a Ukrainian peninsula.</p>

<p>Russia's actions were motivated by a desire to maintain influence over Ukraine and prevent it from joining Western institutions such as NATO and the EU.</p>

<p>Ukraine, seeking independence and self-determination, has resisted Russian aggression, leading to a protracted and devastating conflict that has resulted in thousands of deaths, millions of displaced people, and significant economic losses.</p>

<p>As of July 31, 2024, the Office of the High Commissioner for Human Rights (OHCHR) reported 35,160 civilian casualties in Ukraine since February 2022, including 11,520 fatalities and 23,640 injuries. However, OHCHR notes that the actual numbers are likely higher due to underreporting.</p>

<h3><strong>Ukraine's 501st Marine Battalion</strong></h3>

<p>The 501st Separate Marine Infantry Battalion is an elite military unit within the Ukrainian Marine Corps, operating under the 36th Marine Brigade of the Ukrainian Armed Forces. Headquartered in Berdyansk, Zaporizhzhia Oblast, this battalion plays a vital role in Ukraine's defence capabilities.</p>

<h3><strong>Initial Surrender</strong></h3>

<p>The 501st Marine Battalion's troubles began during Russia's annexation of Crimea in 2014. The battalion was stationed as part of the Ukrainian garrison when Russian forces invaded. As Ukrainian troops retreated, only 64 of the 501st's members managed to escape Crimea. The remaining personnel, likely hundreds, chose to remain in Crimea, effectively siding with Russian occupiers.</p>

<h3><strong>Second Surrender</strong></h3>

<p>In the early stages of Russia's invasion of Ukraine, the 501st Marine Battalion was deployed to Mariupol, a strategic Black Sea port, where they joined a larger garrison. Russian forces brutally besieged them - subjected them to relentless bombardment and cut off essential supplies.</p>

<p>Although the main garrison of over 2,000 troops fought on until May 2022, the 501st Marine Battalion's leaders ordered an unauthorised surrender in April, abandoning their positions and handing over around 270 marines to Russian captivity. Kyiv authorities later investigated this surrender, targeting the battalion's leadership.</p>

<h3><strong>Rebuilding And Redeployment</strong></h3>

<p>After the loss of its previous personnel and the controversy surrounding its earlier surrenders, the Battalion was reconstituted with new officers and fresh recruits. The battalion rejoined the fight in 2023, initially operating in southern Ukraine's Kherson Oblast before moving to Kharkiv Oblast. Here, it played a role in defending the town of Vovchansk from ongoing Russian incursions.</p>

<p>Currently, the 501st Marine Battalion made a high-profile move by joining the invasion of Russia's Kursk Oblast. The battalion announced its presence through a video showing marines tearing down a Russian flag in a settlement within Kursk.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/8b9je35_russiaukraine-war_625x300_19_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[File photo]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-bans-clooney-foundation-enlists-it-as-undesirable-organization-6369703]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russia Bans Clooney Foundation, Enlists It As "Undesirable" Organization]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-bans-clooney-foundation-enlists-it-as-undesirable-organization-6369703]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 19 Aug 2024 13:58:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russia's prosecutor general on Monday said it had banned a foundation started by US film star George Clooney and his human rights lawyer wife Amal.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russia's prosecutor general on Monday said it had banned a foundation started by US film star George Clooney and his human rights lawyer wife Amal.</p>

<p>"The activities of The Clooney Foundation for Justice are declared undesirable on the territory of our country," it said in a statement.</p>

<p>The organisation "conducts extensive work aimed at discrediting Russia, actively supports false patriots and members of banned terrorist and extremist groups".</p>

<p>"Under the guise of humanitarian ideas, these 'warriors for justice'... advance initiatives of criminal probes against the highest Russian authorities," it said in the statement entitled "The Russian Prosecutor General's Office Appreciates Hollywood Activists' Acting Talent".</p>

<p>After Moscow sent troops into Ukraine in February 2022, Russian authorities have upped repression of dissent to levels not seen since the Soviet Union.</p>

<p>In July, the Clooney Foundation, along with several other non-governmental organisations, filed a case with the UN Human Rights Committee, accusing Russia of violating the human rights of Ukrainians killed in a 2022 missile attack on Vinnytsia.</p>

<p>In early August, Russia's prosecutor general banned as "undesirable" German pro-democracy foundation Konrad Adenauer and in July did the same with the Moscow Times news outlet.</p>

<p>The "undesirable" status forces organisations to shut down in Russia and means Russians that work for, fund or collaborate with them can also be liable to prosecution.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-04/2qp33gu_george-clooney_625x300_23_April_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[In July, the Clooney Foundation accused Russia of violating the human rights of Ukrainians (file).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-attacks-israeli-troops-allegedly-infiltrating-lebanese-border-6369516]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hezbollah Claims Attacks On Israeli Troops For "Infiltrating" Lebanese Border]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-attacks-israeli-troops-allegedly-infiltrating-lebanese-border-6369516]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 19 Aug 2024 13:23:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hezbollah on Monday claimed attacks on troops and military positions in northern Israel, including a drone strike on a base and an assault on soldiers allegedly "infiltrating" near the Lebanese border.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hezbollah on Monday claimed attacks on troops and military positions in northern Israel, including a drone strike on a base and an assault on soldiers allegedly "infiltrating" near the Lebanese border.</p>

<p>The Iran-backed group has exchanged regular cross-border fire with the Israeli army in support of ally Hamas since the Palestinian group's October 7 attack on Israel sparked the Gaza war.</p>

<p>Fears of a major escalation skyrocketed after an Israeli strike last month on Beirut's southern suburbs killed Fuad Shukr, one of Hezbollah's top commanders, hours before an attack in Tehran, blamed on Israel, killed Hamas's political leader Ismail Haniyeh.</p>

<p>Iran and Hezbollah have vowed to respond.</p>

<p>Hezbollah said Monday it launched a "simultaneous air attack" with "explosive-laden drones" on two Israeli military positions -- a barracks near the border and a base near the coastal town of Acre, around 15 kilometres (10 miles) from the frontier.</p>

<p>It said it came "in response" to an Israeli "attack and assassination" in south Lebanon's Tyre area.</p>

<p>A fighter from the group was killed in an Israeli strike in the area on Saturday.</p>

<p>The Israeli military had said its aircraft "eliminated" a Hezbollah operative in the Tyre area, describing him as a "commander" in the group's elite Radwan force.</p>

<p>Overnight, Hezbollah said its fighters targeted a group of Israeli soldiers "infiltrating" near the border and confronted them "with rocket weapons and artillery, forcing them to return".</p>

<p>Also Monday morning, Hezbollah claimed a rocket and artillery attack on another Israeli barracks in stated retaliation for "Israeli enemy attacks".</p>

<p>The cross-border violence has killed some 582 people in Lebanon, mostly Hezbollah fighters but including at least 128 civilians, according to an AFP tally.</p>

<p>On the Israeli side, including in the annexed Golan Heights, 22 soldiers and 26 civilians have been killed, according to army figures.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/2caj1vvo_israel-lebanon-fight_625x300_03_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hezbollah has exchanged regular cross-border fire with the Israeli Army since the Gaza War began (file)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/is-india-really-at-risk-of-an-mpox-outbreak-6369408]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: Is India Really At Risk Of A Monkeypox Outbreak?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/is-india-really-at-risk-of-an-mpox-outbreak-6369408]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 19 Aug 2024 13:05:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The WHO, on August 14, declared the current upsurge of Mpox or Monkeypox in Central Africa as a global emergency requiring urgent action. Though India has not reported any cases yet, the Central government is keeping a close eye on the situation.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/kgn3rhjo_mpox_625x300_19_August_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>More than four years since Covid-19 was declared a pandemic by the WHO (World Health Organization) in March 2020, fear of another mass outbreak looms large. The WHO, on August 14, declared the current upsurge of Mpox or Monkeypox in Central Africa as a global emergency requiring urgent action. The global concern for the virus grew as it spread to other African countries, and, within no time, the deadly strain of Mpox - Clade 1b - crossed the African continent to reach Sweden, Pakistan, and other countries.</p>

<p>The virus has killed more than 500 people so far, mainly in the Democratic Republic of Congo, where the disease has been spreading since last year. The country saw more than 96% of the world's roughly 17,000 recorded cases of Mpox this year.</p>

<p>Though India has not reported any cases yet, the Central government is keeping a close eye on the situation. Our healthcare infrastructure faced severe challenges during the Covid-19 pandemic, which resulted in thousands of deaths. One wouldn't wish to be caught unawares this time.</p>

<h2><strong>Is Mpox As Dangerous As Covid-19 Or Swine Flu?</strong></h2>

<p>Mpox is a zoonotic infection that causes flu-like symptoms and skin lesions. Fatal in some cases, the WHO first declared it a global emergency in 2022.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Mpox virus can be categorised into two clades: Clade 1 and Clade 2. The first, which is found mainly in Central African countries, is more severe and has a high mortality rate. Clade 2 has milder symptoms and is found in western Africa. The latter caused a public health emergency in 2022, wherein some 300 cases — though mild — were reported from Sweden. This time, it's the newer and more serious Clade 1b, identified in September last year, that has been driving the current outbreak.</p>

<p>Though experts worry that Mpox may be as dangerous as Covid-19 or the swine flu, there is a difference in the nature of transmission. Both Covid-19 and swine flu were highly infectious because they were airborne. In contrast, Mpox is transmitted through close skin-to-skin contact, talking or breathing close to an infected person, or using their soiled clothes or bedsheets. “Mpox is unlikely to become a pandemic like Covid-19 primarily due to its mode of spread. It requires very close and physical contact, unlike the airborne SARS-CoV-2. Also, symptoms like blisters on the skin are more visible indicators and therefore, it's easier to identify the disease and isolate a person to contain the spread,” says Rakesh K. Mishra, former director of the Centre for Cellular and Molecular Biology.</p>

<p>India's first Mpox case was recorded in Kerala in 2022, from a traveller from the UAE. Soon, the virus spread within the country, with cases emerging in Delhi even from individuals who had no recent international travel. India reported 27 confirmed cases and one death that year, according to WHO. The last case in the country was in March this year, in Kerala, and since then, no new cases have been recorded.</p>

<h2><strong>How To Stay Safe</strong></h2>

<p>In response to the WHO's warning, both Central and state governments have sprung into action. There are monkeypox advisories in place and public health measures are being taken. Both the Indian Council of Medical Research (ICMR) and the National Centre for Disease Control (NCDC) are closely monitoring the situation and reviewing international trends.</p>

<p>In Tamil Nadu, the Directorate of Public Health and Preventive Medicine (DPH) has already issued alerts. Reports say that passengers arriving from the Democratic Republic of Congo and Central African countries are being tracked by airport health officers and port health personnel. Both Hyderabad and New Delhi — cities popular among African students pursuing higher education — have also been placed on high alert.</p>

<h2><strong>The Need For Vaccines</strong></h2>

<p>The first Mpox strain was isolated by ICMR researchers in 2022. Pharmaceutical companies and drug manufacturers are being called upon to develop vaccines and testing kits for the virus. Existing vaccines for smallpox and chickenpox might also offer protection in India.&nbsp;</p>

<p>About other prevention strategies, Mishra says, “It is important to closely monitor the spread of the disease in different countries and be ready for screening by already available methods of DNA-based diagnostics. There is an effective vaccine already available but supply of that may not be easy to ensure.”&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p>“Simple practices like avoiding close physical contact with suspected/potentially infected person, maintaining distance from people with symptoms, and wearing a mask, should be effective in containing the spread of the infection,” Mishra adds.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Developed nations, mostly those in Europe, already have vaccines available for those at greater risk of monkeypox. And given the high quality of healthcare there, containing the disease will be less challenging. It's underdeveloped African countries, which have neither vaccines nor the resources to buy them, that remain at most risk and which need the most help.&nbsp;</p>

<p><em>(Bharti Mishra Nath is Contributing Editor, NDTV)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/1agedtko_monkeypox_625x300_19_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-year-old-boy-fights-for-life-after-accidentally-shooting-himself-in-us-6369297]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[3-Year-Old Boy Fights For Life After Accidentally Shooting Himself In US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-year-old-boy-fights-for-life-after-accidentally-shooting-himself-in-us-6369297]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 19 Aug 2024 12:49:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Newark Department of Public Safety asked gun owners to be "vigilant about gun safety by taking extra precautions when storing a firearm."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A three-year-old boy in New Jersey, United States, accidentally shot himself with a gun. When police arrived at the scene of a shooting on August 15, around 5:47 pm local time, they discovered the boy and two other children inside a home on Wainwright Street, according to a statement from Newark Public Safety Director Fritz Frage. The boy was brought to the University Hospital for treatment and is currently in critical condition.</p>

<p>As per a report in <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://people.com/new-jersey-boy-3-in-critical-condition-after-accidentally-shooting-himself-with-gun-8696965"><em>People</em></a>, the police department said that the incident is under investigation. "A firearm was recovered at the scene. The shooting appears to have been accidental and self-inflicted. This incident remains under investigation. No further information is available," they added.</p>

<p>Notably, the three-year-old's older brother was seen asking people for help at a local store, according to the CCTV footage. The store manager recalled that the boy was covered in blood and informed that his brother could not breathe. A clerk at the store went to the boy's home and found the younger one in a pool of blood. He told the manager, "Boss, there's a little boy rolling around in blood," before the manager called 911.</p>

<p>"I'm scared myself because we were here, but we didn't know what was happening, but we saw all the cops and everything," Newark resident Edith Frinpong, who is a mother of two, said.</p>

<p>She added, "We should be careful to put weapons in our homes ... in a safe place."</p>

<p>The Newark Department of Public Safety later took to Facebook, and asked gun owners to be "vigilant about gun safety by taking extra precautions when storing a firearm." They asked them to keep guns "unloaded and locked up" in storage, secure ammunition "separate from the gun," and consider using a "gun lock". They also asked the locals to hide keys or passcodes to gun storage.</p>

<p><iframe allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="true" frameborder="0" height="550" scrolling="no" src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/post.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2FNewarkNJPublicSafety%2Fposts%2Fpfbid0VLNK3LBNfedopHzy6LK7aMYFsAWyPf2gjPYbqqoSJmkUoA3Fj4GoanJffFvSPpzul&amp;show_text=true&amp;width=500" style="border:none;overflow:hidden" width="500"></iframe></p>

<p>"You cannot be too careful about where and how you secure a firearm, especially in homes or other locations where children may be present," the caption said.</p>

<p>The incident comes almost a year after a three-year-old accidentally shot and killed her sister in Harris County, Texas, according to local news outlet KTVB7. Sheriff Ed Gonzales posted about the incident, saying the four-year-old died on the spot. The outlet quoted him as saying that there were five adults at an apartment on Bammel North Houston Road near Tomball Parkway where the incident took place. They were all family and friends, Mr Gonzales added. According to law enforcement authorities, the girl lived at the apartment with their parents.</p>

<p>The parents of the girls left them alone in one room and that's where the three-year-old found a loaded gun, according to the sheriff. The toddler fired a single shot, which killed her elder sister, the officer added.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/e26a8fnk_child-gun-generic-istock_625x300_31_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The boy is in a critical condition.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-model-suffers-multiple-injuries-after-swallowing-broken-plastic-from-beverage-sues-american-airlines-6369220]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Model Sues Airline After Swallowing "Broken Plastic" In Beverage]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-model-suffers-multiple-injuries-after-swallowing-broken-plastic-from-beverage-sues-american-airlines-6369220]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 19 Aug 2024 12:35:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Shana Wall was served the beverage on a flight to Rome on May 1. The plastic in the drink injured her throat, esophagus, vocal chords and digestive system.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Model and actor Shana Wall has sued American Airlines, claiming she sustained injuries from a beverage that allegedly contained "broken plastic and shards". According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/08/17/us-news/ryan-seacrests-ex-seriously-injured-after-swallowing-shards-of-plastic-from-beverage-on-american-airlines-flight-suit/"><em>New York Post</em></a>, the beverage was served to Ms Wall on a flight to Rome on May 1. Her throat, esophagus, vocal chords and digestive system were injured when she gulped down the drink, the outlet further said in the report, citing from her lawsuit. She was confined to bed and unable to walk following the incident.</p>

<p>The 51-year-old filed the lawsuit in Manhattan Supreme Court on Monday.</p>

<p>"American Airlines had a duty to provide beverages and food that was uncontaminated and fit for consumption... it created the dangerous, defective and unsafe condition on the airplane," Ms Wall said in her August 12 lawsuit.</p>

<p>She is seeking damages, but the amount has not been revealed. American Airlines has so far not commented on her lawsuit.</p>

<p>Shana Wall is originally from California, but now lives in Meatpacking District in Manhattan where she works as a sommelier and contributes to the men's magazine '<em>Best Life'</em>.</p>

<p>She dated TV host and producer Seacrest from 2003 to 2005, as per <em>Post</em>, and even made appearances on '<em>Married... with Children</em>' and '<em>Entourage</em>'.</p>

<p>In her lawsuit, Ms Wall has said that due to her injuries she "became incapacitated from the duties of her occupation, sustaining wage and economic loss; has incurred, and will in the future continue to incur, expenses for the treatment of her injuries; she became obligated to expend monies for physicians' services and other medical care and treatment".</p>

<p>In June, a passenger on an Air India flight from Bengaluru to San Francisco reported finding a blade-like piece of metal inside his in-flight meal.</p>

<p>Another similar incident was reported from South Korea where a traveller allegedly found a piece of glass in her mouth while drinking coffee.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/jaf2fueo_shana-wall-model_625x300_19_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The 51-year-old filed the lawsuit in Manhattan Supreme Court on Monday.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-state-secretary-antony-blinken-brokers-gaza-truce-with-israel-president-isaac-herzog-pm-benjamin-netanyahu-maybe-the-last-chance-6369133]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Antony Blinken Pushes For Gaza Truce In Israel, Calls It "A Decisive Moment"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-state-secretary-antony-blinken-brokers-gaza-truce-with-israel-president-isaac-herzog-pm-benjamin-netanyahu-maybe-the-last-chance-6369133]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 19 Aug 2024 12:19:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US Secretary of State Antony Blinken, in Israel to push for a Gaza truce, said on Monday ongoing negotiations were "maybe the last" chance to reach an agreement to end the war.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US Secretary of State Antony Blinken, in Israel to push for a Gaza truce, said on Monday ongoing negotiations were "maybe the last" chance to reach an agreement to end the war.</p>

<p>"This is a decisive moment -- probably the best, maybe the last, opportunity to get the hostages home, to get a ceasefire and to put everyone on a better path to enduring peace and security," Blinken said as he met Israeli President Isaac Herzog.</p>

<p>The top US diplomat said President Joe Biden had sent him "to get this agreement to the line and ultimately over the line".</p>

<p>"It is time for it to get done. It's also time to make sure that no one takes any steps that could derail this process," Blinken said.</p>

<p>"We're working to make sure that there is no escalation, that there are no provocations, that there are no actions that in any way could move us away from getting this deal over the line, or, for that matter, escalating the conflict to other places, and to greater intensity."</p>

<p>Blinken, on his ninth visit to the Middle East since Hamas's October 7 attack on Israel, is scheduled to meet later on Monday with Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu.</p>

<p>The visiting secretary of state said it was a "fraught moment" in Israel and warned against any moves that could heighten regional tensions, following threats from Iran and the Lebanese armed group Hezbollah to avenge the recent killings of two operative leaders.</p>

<p>Herzog, who holds a largely ceremonial role, said Israelis wanted to see the return "as soon as possible" of hostages still held in Gaza since the October 7 attack that triggered the war.</p>

<p>"There is no greater humanitarian objective, and there's no greater humanitarian cause, than bringing back our hostages," Herzog told Blinken.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/tlr2l40g_antony-blinken_625x300_27_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US Secretary of State Antony Blinken warned against any move that could heighten regional tensions (file)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>