<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Sat, 13 Jul 2024 07:50:14 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/alec-baldwin-cries-in-court-after-judge-dismisses-rust-shooting-trial-6094839]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Alec Baldwin Breaks Down In Court As Judge Dismisses 'Rust' Shooting Trial]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/alec-baldwin-cries-in-court-after-judge-dismisses-rust-shooting-trial-6094839]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 13 Jul 2024 07:10:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Alec Baldwin's trial for involuntary manslaughter collapsed in spectacular fashion Friday as a judge found key evidence over a fatal shooting on the set of "Rust" had been withheld from the defense, and dismissed the case.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Alec Baldwin's trial for involuntary manslaughter collapsed in spectacular fashion Friday as a judge found key evidence over a fatal shooting on the set of "Rust" had been withheld from the defense, and dismissed the case.</p>

<p>Judge Mary Marlowe Sommer, presiding over the trial in Santa Fe, New Mexico, said bullets potentially linked to the death of cinematographer Halyna Hutchins that could have been favorable to Baldwin's case had not been shared with his lawyers by police and prosecutors.</p>

<p>The Hollywood A-lister immediately burst into tears, as the case -- which could have seen him sentenced to 18 months in prison if found guilty -- was abruptly tossed out in sensational scenes.</p>

<p>"The state's willful withholding of this information was intentional and deliberate. If this conduct does not rise to the level of bad faith, it certainly comes so near to bad faith as to show signs of scorching prejudice," said Marlowe Sommer.</p>

<p>"The court concludes that this conduct is highly prejudicial to the defendant."</p>

<p>Baldwin was holding a gun in the direction of Hutchins during a rehearsal in October 2021 when the weapon fired, killing Hutchins and wounding the film's director.</p>

<p>The movie's armorer Hannah Gutierrez, who loaded the fatal weapon, is already serving 18 months in prison for involuntary manslaughter.</p>

<p>Baldwin was facing the same charge. Prosecutors claim he ignored basic gun safety laws and acted recklessly on set.</p>

<p>Baldwin's celebrity lawyer Alex Spiro argued the actor had no responsibility for checking the weapon's deadly contents and did not know it contained live rounds.</p>

<p>But the defense's case also rested heavily on discrediting the police investigation.</p>

<p>And Spiro on Thursday introduced evidence that live bullets potentially linked to the shooting had been handed to police, but not disclosed to Baldwin's lawyers.</p>

<h2>'Buried'</h2>

<p>The bullets were handed into police by a "Good Samaritan" earlier this year, more than two years after the "Rust" tragedy.</p>

<p>The "Good Samaritan" was a former police officer and a family friend of Gutierrez, the armorer. He told police the bullets matched the rounds that killed Hutchins.</p>

<p>Spiro accused police of having "buried" evidence by not filing it under the "Rust" case, depriving the defense of a chance to see it.</p>

<p>"Which was a perfect plan," he told the court.</p>

<p>Crime scene technician Marissa Poppell, under questioning from Spiro, said she had catalogued the bullets, but had been told not to file them under the "Rust" case.</p>

<p>Special prosecutor Kari Morrissey scrambled to respond, telling the court she had never seen or heard of the bullets before this week.</p>

<p>But when it emerged that Morrissey had been present for discussions in which it was decided not to submit the bullets into the "Rust" case file, Morrissey voluntarily called herself as a witness in a last-ditch attempt to salvage the state's case.</p>

<p>She claimed the allegedly "buried" bullets did not match the live rounds on the set of "Rust," and had been stored in a different state, Arizona, up to the day of the tragic shooting.</p>

<p>Marlowe Sommer was not convinced and dismissed the case, prompting the emotional scenes among Baldwin and his family.</p>

<h2>'Dumbfounded'</h2>

<p>Baldwin is highly unlikely to see the inside of a criminal court again over the shooting, legal experts said, though he could still face civil suits.</p>

<p>"As far as the criminal proceedings, it's over. They can't refile," said Los Angeles lawyer Tre Lovell.</p>

<p>"It's been dismissed with prejudice. To try to do it again would be double jeopardy. You can't do that."</p>

<p>University of Richmond law professor Carl Tobias agreed that "on the criminal side, I think it's done."</p>

<p>"The prosecutors could try to somehow mount an extraordinary appeal. But I don't think any appellate court is going to agree with the prosecutor," he said.</p>

<p>The withheld evidence could benefit Gutierrez, the film's armorer who has already launched an appeal, and David Halls, the movie's first assistant director who took a plea deal and admitted negligence.</p>

<p>Christopher Melcher, a Los Angeles-based attorney, told AFP he was "dumbfounded" by the case's sudden collapse.</p>

<p>"The case unfolded as quickly as I've ever seen a case... It was just absolutely amazing to watch."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ga054ma8_alec-baldwin_625x300_13_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Alec Baldwin was holding a gun in the direction of a cinematographer when it fired, killing her.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-donates-sizeable-amount-to-trump-campaign-ahead-of-us-polls-6094779]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk Donates 'Sizeable' Amount To Trump Campaign Ahead Of US Polls]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-donates-sizeable-amount-to-trump-campaign-ahead-of-us-polls-6094779]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 13 Jul 2024 06:57:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Billionaire Elon Musk has donated to a super political action committee working to elect Donald Trump to the White House, a major gambit by the world's richest person to make his imprint on the US political landscape.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Billionaire Elon Musk has donated to a super political action committee working to elect Donald Trump to the White House, a major gambit by the world's richest person to make his imprint on the US political landscape.</p>

<p>Musk has contributed to a low-profile group called America PAC, according to people familiar with the matter, who requested anonymity to detail his plans. It's unclear how much Musk has given, but the people characterized the figure as a sizable amount. The PAC is next required to disclose its list of donors on July 15.</p>

<p>The move highlights the growing influence of a technology mogul who tops the Bloomberg Billionaires Index with a net worth of $263.6 billion and his shift from a self-described political independent - who said he preferred to stay out of politics - into a figure who regularly uses his X social-media platform to espouse right-leaning views and assail Democrats.</p>

<p>The money injection from Musk comes at a time when Trump has overtaken his rival, President Joe Biden, in fundraising with the help of deep-pocketed Wall Street and corporate donors. Biden's own money raising has dropped off following a calamitous debate that led prominent Democratic donors to put away their checkbooks.</p>

<p>Musk has yet to publicly endorse a candidate in the 2024 race and said earlier this year he did not anticipate financing either Trump or Biden's election efforts, but his decision to open his pocketbook presents an opportunity for him to become a financial juggernaut for Republicans.</p>

<p>Multiple requests for comment to Musk were not returned. The Trump campaign declined to comment.</p>

<p>Chris Gober, America PAC's treasurer, declined to comment.</p>

<h3>Ground-Game Boost</h3>

<p>America PAC is working mostly behind the scenes to bolster the Trump campaign's ground game.</p>

<p>Though Federal Election Commission disclosures don't detail where work is occurring, canvassing and get-out-the-vote efforts are conducted most intensively in key battleground states that will determine the outcome of the election.</p>

<p>Musk's efforts threaten to deal a devastating blow to Biden and Democrats, who are already mired in an intraparty battle over the president's political future.</p>

<p>Democrats invested heavily in field offices and staff in swing states, moves Biden regularly touts on the stump.</p>

<p>A super PAC matching those efforts on Trump's behalf gives Republicans a major cash advantage to spend official campaign money elsewhere, in what is shaping up to be the most expensive presidential election in US history.</p>

<p>Among outside organizations backing Trump, America PAC is the biggest spender on direct voter contacts. It has spent $15.8 million so far, with $13.1 million of that going for field operations, federal records show. It has also paid for digital media, texting and phone calls to reach voters.</p>

<p>The group focuses on door-to-door persuasion and get-out-the-vote efforts. A recent ruling by the FEC allows super PACs to coordinate with campaigns on voter outreach.</p>

<p>America PAC has hired In Field Strategies, a national grassroots firm that's also done work for the Republican National Committee.</p>

<p>Representatives for In Field didn't respond to a request for comment.</p>

<h3>Corporate Impact</h3>

<p>The political money makes Musk an even more formidable Washington player. He derives his wealth primarily from his holdings in electric vehicle maker Tesla Inc., SpaceX and X. His companies already boast sizable government contracts and regularly clash with federal agencies over regulations.</p>

<p>Some of Trump's proposed policies, such as dismantling Biden's measures to transition the US to electric vehicles and vows to impose tariffs on Chinese EV makers, would have a direct impact on Tesla.</p>

<p>Musk and Trump have clashed in the past but the two have grown closer with the tech entrepreneur advising the former president on electric vehicles and crypto policy.</p>

<p>During Tesla's annual meeting last month, Musk discussed his relationship with Trump.</p>

<p>"He does call me out of the blue for no reason," Musk said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/fpd88p5s_elon-musk-donald-trump_625x300_30_May_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The move highlights his shift from a self-described political independent.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korea-denounces-declaration-at-nato-summit-6094571]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[North Korea Denounces Declaration At NATO Summit]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korea-denounces-declaration-at-nato-summit-6094571]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 13 Jul 2024 05:49:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[North Korea "most strongly denounces" the declaration at the recent NATO summit, KCNA said on Saturday, citing the country's foreign ministry spokesperson.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>North Korea "most strongly denounces" the declaration at the recent NATO summit, KCNA said on Saturday, citing the country's foreign ministry spokesperson.</p>

<p>Leaders of NATO countries stressed a membership pledge for Ukraine and took a stronger stance on China's support for Russia in a declaration this week at a summit in Washington.</p>

<p>"The "Washington Summit Declaration," cooked up and made public on July 10, goes to prove that the U.S. and NATO, reduced to a tool for its confrontation, pose the most serious threat to the global peace and security," North Korea's state media KCNA quoted a foreign ministry spokesperson as saying.</p>

<p>North Korea's statement added that the U.S. moves to expand military blocs with NATO countries and Asian partners, including South Korea and Japan are "the vicious root cause of seriously threatening the regional peace, extremely exacerbating the international security environment and sparking off worldwide arms race."</p>

<p>The summit declaration called on China to cease all material and political support for Russia's war effort. It also accused Iran and North Korea of fuelling Russia's war in Ukraine by providing direct military support to Moscow.</p>

<p>Separately, South Korea and the United States on the sidelines of a NATO summit signed a guideline on establishing an integrated system of extended deterrence for the Korean peninsula to counter nuclear and military threats from North Korea.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-01/m375bsec_kim-jong-un_625x300_01_January_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[North Korea "most strongly denounces" the declaration at the recent NATO summit, KCNA said.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/i-promise-you-i-am-ok-joe-biden-insists-on-return-to-campaign-trail-6094541]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["I Promise You, I'm OK": Biden Tells Supporters Amid Series Of Gaffes]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/i-promise-you-i-am-ok-joe-biden-insists-on-return-to-campaign-trail-6094541]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 13 Jul 2024 05:38:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden returned to the campaign trail Friday seeking to reassure voters and Democrats alike about his fitness for office, after a major news conference failed to silence calls for him to quit.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden returned to the campaign trail Friday seeking to reassure voters and Democrats alike about his fitness for office, after a major news conference failed to silence calls for him to quit.</p>

<p>"We've got to finish the job. And I promise you I am OK," the 81-year-old told supporters at a diner in Northville in the battleground state of Michigan, which he must win in November to beat Donald Trump.</p>

<p>Biden was to give a speech later in Detroit warning of the "nightmare" of a second Trump term under a hard-right manifesto that his campaign is pinning to the former president.</p>

<p>But the drumbeat of Democrats urging Biden to step aside kept getting louder, with 19 lawmakers having now openly called on him not to seek reelection following a disastrous debate performance against Trump on June 27.</p>

<p>The bloodletting continued despite a defiant Biden insisting in a high-stakes press conference at a NATO summit in Washington on Thursday that he would run again, and win.</p>

<p>A series of gaffes, including referring to Vice President Kamala Harris as "Vice President Trump" and mixing up Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky with Russian strongman Vladimir Putin, kept the focus on his mental acuity.</p>

<p><strong>- 'Gaffes for 40 years' -</strong></p>

<p>"The president understands that there's still some anxiety," Biden campaign communications director Michael Tyler told reporters traveling to Michigan with the president aboard Air Force One.</p>

<p>"That's why he's laser focused on demonstrating that he is the best person to take on Donald Trump and defeat him in November."</p>

<p>Tyler played down the verbal slip-ups, saying Biden has been known for making them throughout his long political career.</p>

<p>"Joe Biden has been making gaffes for 40 years, he made a couple of last night, he probably will continue to do so," he said.</p>

<p>As the row sparked by the debate enters a third week, Biden has been making efforts to reach out to lawmakers, speaking by telephone to Latino and Asian members of the House of Representatives on Friday.</p>

<p>The top Democrat in the House of Representatives, Hakeem Jeffries, meanwhile said he had met with Biden late Thursday after the press conference.</p>

<p>Jeffries said he "expressed the full breadth of insight, heartfelt perspectives and conclusions about the path forward" but did not give further details.</p>

<p><strong>- 'Complete losers' -</strong></p>

<p>The campaign event in Detroit is Biden's fourth trip this year to the state, part of the industrial "blue wall" along with Wisconsin and Pennsylvania that were key to his 2020 win against his rival.</p>

<p>Biden's speech is expected to focus on "Project 2025", a blueprint for power by hardline conservatives that Democrats have said the former president would implement, despite the 78-year-old's denials.</p>

<p>"Project 2025 is run and paid for by Trump people," Biden was to say according to excerpts released by the campaign.</p>

<p>"And here is the nightmare it would unleash."</p>

<p>The concerns over Biden are affecting Democratic donors, with Hollywood star and high-profile supporter George Clooney calling on Biden to step aside on Wednesday.</p>

<p>A number of other key donors have told the largest Biden campaign fund that around $90 million in pledged donations is on hold if he carries on running, the New York Times reported on Friday.</p>

<p>Trump, who mocked Biden on social media during the news conference, followed up on Friday by saying the Zelensky gaffe was "unpardonable."</p>

<p>But he added that Biden "shouldn't allow complete losers like George Clooney, under the total auspices and control of Barack Hussein Obama, to push him out of office. That must be his decision, and his decision alone."</p>

<p>Trump was referring to reports in US media that some in Biden's camp believe former president Obama, under whom Biden served as vice president, is involved behind the scenes with the rebels.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/435vo76_joe-biden_625x300_24_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden returned to the campaign trail Friday seeking to reassure voters.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-killed-after-plane-crashes-in-russia-6094161]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[3 Killed After Plane Crashes In Russia]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-killed-after-plane-crashes-in-russia-6094161]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 13 Jul 2024 03:11:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Three people were killed after a plane crashed in the Moscow Region, the Russian Emergencies Ministry said in a statement.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Three people were killed after a plane crashed in the Moscow Region, the Russian Emergencies Ministry said in a statement.</p>

<p>According to preliminary information, the plane, a Russian-designed Superjet 100, fell in a forest area in the Kolomensky district of the Moscow Region, Xinhua news agency reported on Friday.</p>

<p>The crash took place during a test flight after a scheduled repair, the TASS news agency reported.</p>

<p>No casualties have been reported among the local population.</p>

<p></p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2018-03/police-generic-international-afp_650x400_41520126059.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The crash took place during a test flight after a scheduled repair, the TASS news agency reported.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/cosmic-ballet-2-galaxies-merge-in-space-webb-telescope-sends-in-pics-6093460]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Cosmic Ballet": 2 Galaxies Merge In Space, Webb Telescope Sends In Pics]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/cosmic-ballet-2-galaxies-merge-in-space-webb-telescope-sends-in-pics-6093460]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 23:36:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[NASA released a pair of images taken by the James Webb Space Telescope showing two galaxies in the process of merging in sort of a cosmic ballet.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>NASA released on Friday a pair of images taken by the James Webb Space Telescope showing two galaxies - one nicknamed the Penguin and the other the Egg - in the process of merging in sort of a cosmic ballet as the U.S. space agency marked two years since it unveiled the orbiting observatory's first scientific results.</p>

<p>Webb, which was launched in 2021 and began collecting data the following year, has reshaped the understanding of the early universe while taking stunning pictures of the cosmos. The two galaxies in the images are situated 326 million light-years from Earth in the constellation Hydra. A light year is the distance light travels in a year, 5.9 trillion miles (9.5 trillion km).</p>

<p>"We see two galaxies, each a collection of billions of stars. The galaxies are in the process of merging. That's a common way that galaxies like our own build up over time, to grow from small galaxies - like those that Webb has found shortly after the Big Bang - into mature galaxies like our own Milky Way," said Jane Rigby, NASA Webb senior project scientist.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/hofnufao_galaxies-merging-webb-telescope-reuters_625x300_12_July_24.jpeg?im=FitAndFill,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: Reuters</span></p>
</div>

<p>Since becoming operational, Webb has observed galaxies teeming with stars that formed within a few hundred million years of the Big Bang event that marked the beginning of the universe about 13.8 billion years ago.</p>

<p>The mingling Penguin and Egg galaxies are collectively known as Arp 142. They are shown in the imagery joined by a haze that is a mix of stars and gas amid their slow-motion merger.</p>

<p>The Penguin galaxy, so dubbed because its shape from the perspective of the telescope resembles that flightless bird, including a beak-like region, is formally called NGC 2936. It is a spiral-shaped galaxy, now a bit distorted. The Egg galaxy, also named for its shape, is formally called NGC 2937. It is a compact elliptical-shaped galaxy. Together, their appearance is suggestive of a penguin guarding its egg.</p>

<p>Their interaction, according to NASA, was set in motion between 25 and 75 million years ago, and they are expected to become a single galaxy hundreds of millions of years from now.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/li3kc9cg_galaxies-merging-webb-telescope-reuters_625x300_12_July_24.jpeg?im=FitAndFill,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: Reuters</span></p>
</div>

<p>Webb has detected the earliest-known galaxies and has provided insight into areas such as the composition of planets beyond our solar system, known as exoplanets, and the nature of star-forming regions in the cosmos.</p>

<p>"This mission has allowed us to look back to the most distant galaxies ever observed and understand the very early universe in a new way," said Mark Clampin, astrophysics division director at NASA headquarters. "For example, with Webb, we've found that these very early galaxies are more massive and brighter than we expected, posing the question: How did they get so big so quickly?"</p>

<p>Webb was designed to be more sensitive than its Hubble Space Telescope predecessor, which also is continuing its work. Webb looks at the universe mainly in the infrared, while Hubble has examined it primarily at optical and ultraviolet wavelengths.</p>

<p>"Webb is the largest, most powerful telescope ever put in space. It specializes in capturing infrared light - wavelengths of light longer than our eyes can see. With its incredible sensitivity to those wavelengths, we've been able to look back into the early universe in a way previous missions couldn't, see through dust and gas into the heart of star formation, and examine the composition of exoplanet atmospheres like never before," Clampin said.</p>

<p>Looking ahead, Clampin added, "Some of Webb's most exciting investigations will be the things we haven't even thought of yet."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/uh2kf9_galaxies-merging-webb-telescope-reuters_625x300_12_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Rho Ophiuchi cloud complex seen in a composite of separate exposures acquired by Webb Telescope]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/turkey-presents-bill-to-get-millions-of-stray-dogs-off-the-streets-6093213]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Turkey Presents Bill To Get Millions Of Stray Dogs Off The Streets]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/turkey-presents-bill-to-get-millions-of-stray-dogs-off-the-streets-6093213]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 22:53:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Turkey's ruling party presented a bill to parliament on Friday that aims to round up millions of stray dogs, a plan that has alarmed animal lovers who say a mass neutering campaign would be a better solution than locking dogs up in shelters.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Turkey's ruling party presented a bill to parliament on Friday that aims to round up millions of stray dogs, a plan that has alarmed animal lovers who say a mass neutering campaign would be a better solution than locking dogs up in shelters.</p>

<p>Under the draft law proposed by the AK party, municipalities would be charged with getting strays off the street and into shelters until they are adopted. Aggressive dogs or any with untreatable diseases would be put down.</p>

<p>"Streets are not a space for dogs to live. But they have the right to live in more qualified shelters," Abdullah Guler, chair of the AK party's parliamentary group, told reporters.</p>

<p>An earlier version of the bill, which was leaked to Turkish media months ago, said all street dogs could be put down within a month but the provision was removed after public outcry, including from opposition politicians.</p>

<p>The population of street dogs in Turkey is estimated to be 4 million, and 2.5 million dogs have been neutered in the past 20 years by municipalities, according to the draft bill.</p>

<p>Under current legislation, municipalities have to neuter and vaccinate all street dogs and leave them where they were found following treatment.</p>

<p>There are currently 322 animal shelters with a capacity to host a total of 105,000 dogs, according to the bill.</p>

<p>The draft bill also requires all municipalities to spend at least 0.3% of their annual budget on animal rehabilitation services and building shelters.</p>

<p>Municipalities will be given time until 2028 to build new shelters and improve current shelters, the bill says.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/mnmn4gg_turkey-stray-dogs-reuters_625x300_12_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The population of street dogs in Turkey is estimated to be 4 million (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/amazon-must-comply-with-us-rights-agency-pregnancy-bias-probe-new-york-federal-judge-6093181]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Amazon Must Comply With US Rights Agency's Pregnancy Bias Probe: Judge]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/amazon-must-comply-with-us-rights-agency-pregnancy-bias-probe-new-york-federal-judge-6093181]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 22:48:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A New York federal judge has ordered Amazon.com to comply with a subpoena from a US civil rights agency investigating claims that the online retailer discriminated against pregnant warehouse workers.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A New York federal judge has ordered Amazon.com to comply with a subpoena from a U.S. civil rights agency investigating claims that the online retailer discriminated against pregnant warehouse workers.</p>

<p>U.S. District Judge Lorna Schofield in Manhattan late Thursday rejected Amazon's claims that the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (EEOC) subpoena was too broad and sought irrelevant information.</p>

<p>The EEOC is seeking data on requests that pregnant workers at five U.S. warehouses made for accommodations such as limits on heavy lifting and additional breaks, and whether Amazon granted or denied them.</p>

<p>The commission's probe was prompted by complaints from five women who say they faced pregnancy discrimination while working at Amazon warehouses in New Jersey, Connecticut, North Carolina, and California.</p>

<p>Amazon provided the EEOC with more than 200,000 pages of data in response to the subpoena, but not the specific information requested by the agency, according to court filings.</p>

<p>Schofield in her ruling said the information sought in the subpoenas was necessary for the EEOC to determine whether Amazon engaged in illegal discrimination. The judge gave Amazon until Aug. 9 to comply with the subpoena.</p>

<p>Amazon did not immediately respond to a request for comment on Friday. An EEOC spokesman declined to comment.</p>

<p>In 2022, a New York state agency filed an administrative complaint accusing Amazon of requiring pregnant and disabled warehouse workers to take unpaid leaves of absence, even if they were capable of working, instead of providing accommodations. That case is pending.</p>

<p>Amazon has denied wrongdoing and said it strives to support its workers, but acknowledged in a statement responding to the New York complaint that "we don't always get it right."</p>

<p>The EEOC launched its probe last year and issued a subpoena seeking five categories of information, including data on accommodations Amazon provided to warehouse workers with disabilities. At the time, federal law only required companies to provide the same accommodations to pregnant workers that they gave to employees with disabilities.</p>

<p>A law passed later last year mandates that employers accommodate workers' pregnancies regardless of how they treat workers with disabilities.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/5if0puog_amazon-logo-reuters_625x300_12_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Amazon has provided over 200,000 pages of data in response to the subpoena (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/world-population-to-peak-at-10-3-billion-in-2080s-un-report-6093168]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[World Population To Peak At 10.3 Billion In 2080s: UN Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/world-population-to-peak-at-10-3-billion-in-2080s-un-report-6093168]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 22:42:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Earth's population will peak in the mid-2080s at around 10.3 billion people, then drop slightly to a level much lower than anticipated a decade ago, the United Nations said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Earth's population will peak in the mid-2080s at around 10.3 billion people, then drop slightly to a level much lower than anticipated a decade ago, the United Nations said.</p>

<p>The current population of 8.2 billion people will rise to that maximum over the next 60 years, then dip to 10.2 billion by the end of the century, says a report released Thursday entitled "World Population Prospects 2024."</p>

<p>It said the size of the world's population in 2100 will be six percent lower, or 700 million people fewer, than what was anticipated in June 2013.</p>

<p>"The demographic landscape has evolved greatly in recent years," said Li Junhua, UN Under-Secretary-General for Economic and Social Affairs.</p>

<p>He said the unexpected population peak stems from several factors that include lower levels of fertility in some of the world's largest countries, especially China.</p>

<p>He said this lower maximum will also come earlier than previously calculated and this is a hopeful sign as the world fights global warming: fewer humans accounting for less aggregate consumption would mean less pressure on the environment.</p>

<p>"However, slower population growth will not eliminate the need to reduce the average impact attributable to the activities of each individual person," this official said.</p>

<p>More than a quarter, or 28 percent, of the world's population, now lives in one of 63 countries or areas where the population has already peaked, including China, Russia, Japan, and Germany, the report said.</p>

<p>Nearly 50 other countries should join that group over the next 30 years, including Brazil, Iran, and Turkey.</p>

<p>However, population growth will continue in more than 120 countries beyond 2054. These include India, Indonesia, Nigeria, Pakistan, and the United States, according to the UN.</p>

<p>A rise in global life expectancy -- interrupted by the COVID-19 pandemic -- has resumed, with an average of 73.3 years of longevity in 2024. It will average 77.4 years in 2054.</p>

<p>So the world's population will get more and more gray. By the late 2070s, the number of people 65 or older is projected to be 2.2 billion, surpassing those under 18, the study predicts.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-02/610ld0o_population-generic-pixabay_625x300_28_February_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The size of the world's population in 2100 will be six percent lower, the report said (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/2-french-rugby-players-charged-with-aggrevated-rape-in-argentina-6093121]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[2 French Rugby Players Charged With "Aggravated" Rape In Argentina]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/2-french-rugby-players-charged-with-aggrevated-rape-in-argentina-6093121]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 22:37:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Two French international rugby players were formally charged Friday with the aggravated rape of an Argentine woman after a night out following a match, according to a prosecution statement.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Two French international rugby players were formally charged Friday with the aggravated rape of an Argentine woman after a night out following a match, according to a prosecution statement.</p>

<p>The accused, Hugo Auradou, 20, and Oscar Jegou, 21, chose "not to testify" at a hearing in the city of Mendoza, where the rape is alleged to have occurred after a game between France and Argentina on Saturday.</p>

<p>The prosecutor's office "proceeded to formally charge the two French citizens... for the crime of sexual assault with penetration aggravated by the participation of two people," said the statement, using the Argentine legal definition of rape.</p>

<p>The pair will remain in custody as further investigations are carried out. A request by the defense for them to be placed under house arrest "will be resolved in due course," the statement said.</p>

<p>The two men were arrested Monday in Buenos Aires after a 39-year-old woman accused them of raping her multiple times and beating her in a Mendoza hotel room after the match, part of a tour of South America by the French national squad.</p>

<p>The men deny the accusation, saying they had consensual sexual relations with the woman.</p>

<p>The players were transferred Thursday by car from Interpol's Buenos Aires headquarters to Mendoza, some 1,000 kilometers west (620 miles).</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the 39-year-old woman's lawyer, Natacha Romano, said her client was hospitalized Thursday after feeling ill emotionally and physically "because of everything that happened."</p>

<p>Psychologist Nicolas Yungman, who was not treating the woman, told local media that her symptoms, as described, could be indicative of post-traumatic stress disorder.</p>

<p>The woman will receive treatment at a health facility for 24 to 48 hours, Romano said.</p>

<p><strong>Up To 20 Years In Jail</strong></p>

<p>If found guilty, the players face between eight and 20 years in prison.</p>

<p>Defense attorney Romano told AFP on Wednesday her client had suffered "fierce" violence at the hands of her assailants in a hotel room, with injuries to her face, back, breasts, legs and ribs as well as various bite and scratch marks.</p>

<p>The woman claims to have been raped "at least six times" by one of the men and once by the other, according to the lawyer.</p>

<p>She allegedly tried to escape several times.</p>

<p>The attack allegedly took place Saturday night at the Diplomatic Hotel in Mendoza, where France's players and staff were staying after beating Argentina.</p>

<p>Romano told AFP the woman had gone with one of the men from a nightclub to a hotel room, where she alleges she was held against her will and abused for several hours.</p>

<p>"The violence was fierce," said Romano. "There is more than one crime to investigate."</p>

<p>Lawyer Rafael Cuneo Libarona, who represents the players, arrived in Mendoza on Wednesday and said "sexual relations" had been "consensual."</p>

<p>"There are witnesses who saw her leave (the hotel). There are cameras that saw her leave. Apparently no injuries are seen in the footage," Libarona -- who is the brother of Justice Minister Mariano Cuneo Libarona -- told journalists.</p>

<p>Romano told AFP "the overwhelming proof that there was no consent is the victim's body" and the wounds she bears.</p>

<p>French Rugby Federation (FFR) president Florian Grill, who is in Argentina, told AFP the players have "a quite different version" of events to that of the woman, with "a lot of inconsistencies."</p>

<p>"We are not judges. We are not investigators. But we think that the Argentine justice system should look at the case very quickly," he said.</p>

<p>Aradou and Jegou have been replaced by lock Mickael Guillard and flanker Judicael Cancoriet for Saturday's second match against Argentina in Buenos Aires.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-10/oshohg3c_arrest-generic_625x300_17_October_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The pair will remain in custody as further investigations are carried out (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/defiant-joe-biden-hits-campaign-trail-as-calls-to-quit-grow-stronger-6093088]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Defiant Joe Biden Hits Campaign Trail As Calls To Quit Grow Stronger]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/defiant-joe-biden-hits-campaign-trail-as-calls-to-quit-grow-stronger-6093088]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 22:30:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden returns to the campaign trail Friday, pushing ahead with his reelection bid after a mixed performance at a major news conference failed to silence calls for him to quit.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden returns to the campaign trail Friday, pushing ahead with his reelection bid after a mixed performance at a major news conference failed to silence calls for him to quit.</p>

<p>The 81-year-old will give a speech bashing rival Donald Trump in Detroit in the rust-belt state of Michigan, a crucial battleground state that the Democrat must win in November's election.</p>

<p>A defiant Biden insisted in a pivotal appearance at a NATO summit on Thursday that he would run again, and win -- despite concerns about his age and health following a disastrous debate performance two weeks ago.</p>

<p>But a series of gaffes, including referring to Vice President Kamala Harris as "Vice President Trump," kept Biden's fitness for a second term under the microscope.</p>

<p>The top Democrat in the House of Representatives, Hakeem Jeffries, said he had met with Biden late Thursday, as the number of members calling on the president to step aside rose to 20.</p>

<p>Jeffries said he and Biden "expressed the full breadth of insight, heartfelt perspectives, and conclusions about the path forward" but did not give further details.</p>

<p>The president has faced a steady drumbeat of Democrats calling for him to abandon his 2024 candidacy since the June 27 debate, during which Biden often lost his train of thought and appeared tired.</p>

<p>But Biden has obstinately dug in and insists that he can convince voters to back him despite most polls showing him trailing the criminally convicted, twice-impeached Trump.</p>

<p><strong>"Most Qualified"</strong></p>

<p>The campaign event in Detroit is his fourth trip this year to the state, part of the industrial "blue wall" along with Wisconsin and Pennsylvania that were key to his 2020 win against his rival.</p>

<p>Biden's speech is expected to focus on "Project 2025", a blueprint by hardline conservatives for the first days of a Trump term that Democrats have pinned on the former president, despite the 78-year-old's denials.</p>

<p>The press conference on Thursday appeared to buy Biden some time even if it was far from a knockout blow, with three more lawmakers urging him to quit just minutes after it finished.</p>

<p>Biden said he was the "most qualified person to run for president," rejecting calls for him to step aside before the November 5 vote.</p>

<p>He acknowledged he had to "allay fears" in the Democratic party and should "pace myself a little more" after blaming jet lag and cold for his stumbling debate performance.</p>

<p>Biden also fielded a series of foreign and domestic policy questions with detailed if meandering answers and relatively few slip-ups, though he did mix up Europe and Asia.</p>

<p>But there were damaging moments on Thursday, with the Trump-Harris mixup and an earlier gaffe at the NATO summit in which he introduced Ukraine's President Volodymyr Zelensky as Russian strongman Vladimir Putin.</p>

<p>The concerns over Biden are also affecting Democratic donors, with Hollywood star and high-profile supporter George Clooney calling on Biden to step aside on Wednesday.</p>

<p>A number of other key donors have told the largest Biden campaign fund that around $90 million in pledged donations is on hold if he carries on running, the New York Times reported on Friday.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/pn27j9kg_joe-biden-_625x300_12_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Joe Biden insists that he can convince voters to back him (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/thousands-of-prisoners-to-be-released-early-to-ease-crowding-in-uk-jails-6092566]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Thousands Of Prisoners To Be Released Early To Ease Crowding In UK Jails]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/thousands-of-prisoners-to-be-released-early-to-ease-crowding-in-uk-jails-6092566]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 21:03:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Thousands of prisoners are to be released early starting September to prevent the "collapse" of the prison system, the UK's new justice minister announced on Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Thousands of prisoners are to be released early starting September to prevent the "collapse" of the prison system, the UK's new justice minister announced on Friday.</p>

<p>Shabana Mahmood said failure to do so risked the "total breakdown of law and order", with just 700 places left for men, and jails operating at 99 percent capacity since 2023.</p>

<p>England and Wales have the highest per capita prison population in Western Europe.</p>

<p>The release initiative would not apply to violent offenders serving more than four years, sex offenders, and those in prison for domestic abuse offences as well as those on life sentences.</p>

<p>The chief inspector of prisons, Charlie Taylor, said this week that urgent action was required, as prisons were at "breaking point".</p>

<p>Mahmood, appointed last week after Labour's general election win, warned in dramatic language that if prisons ran out of cell space, there could be "van-loads of dangerous people circling the country with nowhere to go".</p>

<p>"With officers unable to act, criminals could do whatever they want, without consequence. We could see looters running amok, smashing in windows, robbing shops, and setting neighbourhoods alight," she said in a speech at a prison.</p>

<p>"In short, if we fail to act now, we face the collapse of the criminal justice system. And a total breakdown of law and order."</p>

<p>Under the plans, prisoners who are eligible for automatic release after serving half their sentence will be freed earlier than normal.</p>

<p>The plans involve a temporary reduction of how long prisoners must serve behind bars, from 50 percent to 40 percent of their sentence.</p>

<p>The releases will start in September to give the Prison and Probation Service time to plan.</p>

<p>The total number of prisoners hit over 87,505 on Friday -- of whom over 83,800 were men -- leaving just 1,451 spaces available, official figures showed.</p>

<p>Since the start of 2023, the average occupancy rate in men's prisons had "routinely been higher than 99 percent", according to the Ministry of Justice.</p>

<p>Officials say the prison system needs a buffer of around 1,425 cell spaces in men's prisons at all times to deal with sudden influxes of inmates.</p>

<p>Six new prisons to create an extra 20,000 places are being built.</p>

<p>The Prison Governors' Association (PGA) said it welcomed the speed of the new measures while demanding a "full review" and that "the public must never be placed in this position again".</p>

<p>PGA chairman Mark Fairhurst said the measures would free up around 4,500-5,000 more spaces and give prisons around 12 to 18 months before further steps would be needed.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-02/c9cdh8ao_us-prison-generic-us-jail-generic-getty_625x300_24_February_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[England and Wales have the highest per capita prison population in Western Europe (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/king-charles-iii-sister-princess-anne-resumes-public-duties-after-hospitalisation-6092511]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[King Charles III's Sister Anne Resumes Public Duties After Hospitalisation]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/king-charles-iii-sister-princess-anne-resumes-public-duties-after-hospitalisation-6092511]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 20:56:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Princess Anne, the sister of British head of state King Charles III, returned to public duties Friday, weeks after she was treated in hospital after being struck by a horse.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Princess Anne, the sister of British head of state King Charles III, returned to public duties Friday, weeks after she was treated in hospital after being struck by a horse.</p>

<p>Anne, 73, presented awards and met winners at a charity horseriding event in Gloucestershire, southwestern England, in a reported phased return to public appearances.</p>

<p>The Princess Royal, as she is also known, suffered concussion and minor head injuries at her Gatcombe Park estate in Gloucestershire in late June and spent five nights in hospital in Bristol.</p>

<p>She has since been recovering at her home on the sprawling estate and following standard concussion protocols.</p>

<p>It is believed she was struck by a horse as she was walking within the protected perimeter of its grounds, which hosts equestrian events.</p>

<p>The princess's medical team said at the time her injuries were consistent with a potential impact from a horse's head or legs.</p>

<p>She is a skilled horsewoman who competed at the 1976 Montreal Olympics and is the mother of British rider Zara Tindall, who won eventing team silver at the 2012 London Olympics.</p>

<p>Anne has stepped in to represent Charles while he postponed public engagements during his cancer treatment, and rode at his official birthday parade last month.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/9rhec228_princess-anne-_625x300_28_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Princess Anne had suffered concussion and minor head injuries last month (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musks-x-developing-dislike-button-for-downvoting-replies-report-6088984]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk's X Developing 'Dislike' Button For Downvoting Replies: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musks-x-developing-dislike-button-for-downvoting-replies-report-6088984]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 20:33:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Elon Musk-run X is developing a downvoting feature which will be used to improve the ranking of replies.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Elon Musk-run X is developing a downvoting feature which will be used to improve the ranking of replies.</p>

<p>While the company hasn't announced its plans officially, recent findings suggest that the 'downvote' feature might actually resemble a 'dislike' button instead of a Reddit-style downvote icon, reports TechCrunch.</p>

<p>As per code references found in the X iOS app show a button that seems like a broken heart icon next to the microblogging platform's heart-shaped 'like' button as well as direct references to a 'downvote' feature.</p>

<p>The feature was tested by the company in 2021, ahead of Elon Musk's acquisition.</p>

<p>Earlier this month, reverse engineer Aaron Perris, @aaronp613 on X, discovered references in X's iOS app that indicated a downvote feature that appeared to be in development.</p>

<p>Now, he has found more image files in the iOS app that show the button could be styled as a broken heart as well as more direct references to the feature itself, the report mentioned.</p>

<p>Initially, the company had tested both upvoting and downvoting buttons across all posts. However, the latest tests show that X is only considering allowing downvotes on replies.</p>

<p>In June, Musk confirmed the rollout of a new feature that will hide all likes by default for X users.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/kn2mlivo_elon-musk-with-x-logo-getty-images_625x300_12_June_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The feature was tested by the company in 2021, ahead of Elon Musk's acquisition.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/oil-tanker-seized-by-iran-in-2023-bound-for-oman-port-shows-tracking-data-6092319]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Oil Tanker Seized By Iran In 2023 Bound For Oman Port: Tracking Data]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/oil-tanker-seized-by-iran-in-2023-bound-for-oman-port-shows-tracking-data-6092319]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 20:25:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Chevron-chartered oil tanker seized by Iran more than a year ago is heading toward the Sohar port in Oman, LSEG ship tracking data showed on Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Chevron-chartered oil tanker seized by Iran more than a year ago is heading toward the Sohar port in Oman, LSEG ship tracking data showed on Friday.</p>

<p>On Thursday, ship tracking data showed the vessel moving to international waters, with the destination showing as Khor Fakkan in the United Arab Emirates.</p>

<p>The Marshall Islands-flagged Advantage Sweet was boarded by Iran's military in the Gulf of Oman in April 2023 after an alleged collision with an Iranian boat.</p>

<p>There was no immediate comment from Chevron.</p>

<p>The US State Department called in March for the immediate release of the tanker.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/shjh31to_advantage-sweet-oil-tanker-reuters_625x300_12_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Marshall Islands-flagged oil tanker Advantage Sweet had been chartered by oil major Chevron]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistan-first-breast-milk-bank-in-karachi-shuts-after-clerics-deem-it-un-islamic-6092125]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Pak's First Breast Milk Bank Shuts After Clerics Deem It "Un-Islamic"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistan-first-breast-milk-bank-in-karachi-shuts-after-clerics-deem-it-un-islamic-6092125]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 19:58:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A hospital that launched the first breast milk bank for premature babies in Pakistan is negotiating for it to be reopened after clerics deemed it un-Islamic, doctors and the national Islamic council said Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A hospital that launched the first breast milk bank for premature babies in Pakistan is negotiating for it to be reopened after clerics deemed it un-Islamic, doctors and the national Islamic council said Friday.</p>

<p>The milk bank in Karachi received religious approval in December from a provincial Islamic seminary, but that approval was withdrawn almost as soon as the facility opened in June, forcing it to shut.</p>

<p>"Breast milk is the only way to improve the chances of the survival of premature babies," said Jamal Raza, a doctor and the executive director of the Sindh Institute of Child Health and Neonatology hospital, where the bank was set up.</p>

<p>"People have no idea what this is about. Only premature babies were going to be given this milk," Raza added.</p>

<p>The facility was intended to help premature babies survive in a country where the neonatal mortality rate is 39 deaths per 1,000 live births, according to the UN children's agency -- one of the highest in South Asia.</p>

<p>A religious edict, or fatwa, approving the facility was issued in December 2023 by Jamia Darul Uloom, an Islamic advisory body in the province.</p>

<p>However, the government's National Council of Islamic Ideology later questioned whether it risked breaking Islamic codes on kinship, which dictate that husband and wife cannot be breastfed by the same woman.</p>

<p>"The child's family must know who the donors are to not complicate the issue of future marriages between such families," the head of research at the council, Inamullah, who goes by one name, told AFP</p>

<p>"We are confident that the outcome will be favourable."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/qrhvq5mo_pakistan-breast-milk-bank-facebook_625x300_12_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The facility was intended to help premature babies survive]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gavin-plumb-arrested-after-undercover-us-cop-exposed-plot-to-rape-kill-uk-tv-star-holly-willoughby-6091998]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Man Arrested After Undercover US Cop Exposed Plot To Rape, Kill UK TV Star]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gavin-plumb-arrested-after-undercover-us-cop-exposed-plot-to-rape-kill-uk-tv-star-holly-willoughby-6091998]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 19:36:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A would-be attacker who planned to kidnap, rape, and murder one of the UK's top celebrities was on Friday given a life sentence with a minimum jail term of 15 years.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A would-be attacker who planned to kidnap, rape, and murder one of the UK's top celebrities was on Friday given a life sentence with a minimum jail term of 15 years.</p>

<p>Gavin Plumb, 37, was last week found guilty of planning to "ambush" television presenter Holly Willoughby, 43, at her home, before taking her to a dungeon-type room.</p>

<p>He was caught after a US undercover police officer infiltrated an online group and forwarded Plumb's posts to the FBI.</p>

<p>US law enforcement officers then handed the evidence to UK police, who raided Plumb's home in Harlow, southeast England. They found an "abduction kit", which included cable ties and chloroform.</p>

<p>Willoughby, a daytime television presenter described by Judge Edward Murray as a "well-known and well-loved public figure", said the case had had a "life-changing" impact, according to a summary of her victim impact statement read in court.</p>

<p>"It is clear, the prosecution submits, ... that the extent of the shock and fear caused by this offending has been impossible to convey," said prosecutor Alison Morgan.</p>

<p>Morgan also said the media had not reported the full extent of his plans as they were "so depraved and vile", but the court was told that Plumb had intended to harm Willoughby's husband and children.</p>

<p>Plumb, who has a string of previous convictions relating to kidnapping and false imprisonment, told the undercover police officer online that he planned to slit Willoughby's throat as he tried to convince him to join in the plot, the court heard.</p>

<p>His legal team said that he "worshipped and was obsessed" with Willoughby and was "devastated to be the cause of such pain to her".</p>

<p>Nicola Rice, a specialist prosecutor with the Crown Prosecution Service, called Plumb "a dangerous man who plotted unspeakable violence against one of the nation's most familiar faces.</p>

<p>"Despite his attempts to pass himself off as a harmless fantasist, the prosecution persuaded the jury that Plumb posed a very real threat," she added.</p>

<p>In England and Wales, life imprisonment is a sentence that lasts until a prisoner dies, but in most cases, the judge sets a minimum term, after which they become eligible for parole.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/kuvq9eeg_holly-willoughby_625x300_25_June_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[An "abduction kit" was found at the home of the man (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/imran-khans-party-pti-to-emerge-as-largest-party-in-pak-parliament-after-court-ruling-report-6091944]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Big Boost To Imran Khan's Party In Parliament After Court Ruling: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/imran-khans-party-pti-to-emerge-as-largest-party-in-pak-parliament-after-court-ruling-report-6091944]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 19:26:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ex PM Imran Khan's Pakistan Tehreek-e-Insaf will emerge as the largest party in Parliament with 109 seats after the Supreme Court on Friday ruled that it is eligible for the allocation of reserved seats for women and minorities, says a media report.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former prime minister Imran Khan's Pakistan Tehreek-e-Insaf will emerge as the largest party in Parliament with 109 seats after the Supreme Court on Friday ruled that it is eligible for the allocation of reserved seats for women and minorities, according to a media report.</p>

<p>In a major legal victory for 71-year-old Khan's Pakistan Tehreek-e-Insaf party, a 13-member full bench of the apex court headed by Chief Justice Qazi Faez Isa annulled the Peshawar High Court's decision upholding the Election Commission of Pakistan's (ECP) move to deny its share in reserved seats in the National Assembly and provincial assemblies.</p>

<p>The bench also declared the decision of the top electoral body null and void, terming it against the Constitution of Pakistan.</p>

<p>The PTI will emerge as the largest party in the National Assembly as its seats will likely soar from 86 to 109, after it gains 23 reserved seats, Geo News reported.</p>

<p>The opposition alliance in the National Assembly will also surge to a strength of 120, the report said. Currently, the combined opposition, including the PTI, has 97 members.</p>

<p>Khan's party has 86 members in the lower house, 84 of whom are on board with the Suni Ittehad Council (SIC) and two independents  party leaders Barrister Gohar Ali Khan and Omar Ayub Khan.</p>

<p>With the majority seats of the PTI in the lower house of the legislature, the ruling coalition led by Prime Minister Shehbaz Sharif's Pakistan Muslim League-Nawaz (PML-N) will continue to occupy the simple majority with the strength of 209 members. The PML-N has a total of 108 members.</p>

<p>The apex court's ruling in the keenly awaited judgment is viewed as a major setback to Prime Minister Sharif's ruling coalition, increasing pressure on it by changing the composition of the National Assembly and paving the way for the PTI's return to Parliament.</p>

<p>[The] withdrawal of election symbol cannot disqualify a political party from elections, the court declared, referring to the election commission not allowing the PTI to use the cricket bat as its election symbol.</p>

<p>The PTI was and is a political party, the bench ruled. Khan, a cricketer-turned-politician, founded the PTI in 1996.</p>

<p>The dispute about the reserved seats was related to the rejection of a SIC plea by the ECP to award its share in the 70 reserved seats in the National Assembly and another 156 in the four provincial assemblies.</p>

<p>The PTI party could not contest the February 8 elections as the ECP rejected its intra-party elections and deprived it of its iconic 'bat' symbol for contesting the elections as a party.</p>

<p>Hence, it was not eligible to claim the seats reserved for women and minorities awarded to the winning parties based on proportional representation.</p>

<p>So its candidates, who had won independently but with the support of PTI, were asked by the party's leadership to join the SIC to form a parliamentary party to claim reserved seats.</p>

<p>The joining of PTI lawmakers made the SIC prominent, which, otherwise, was a dormant entity.</p>

<p>The final ruling by the top court in the case may not change the current power structure, but changes in the overall number game in the assemblies may impact the law-making in the country.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/t32m7b7o_imran-khan-reuters_625x300_06_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-killed-as-russian-regional-airliner-crashes-near-moscow-report-6091810]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[3 Killed As Russian Regional Airliner Crashes Near Moscow: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-killed-as-russian-regional-airliner-crashes-near-moscow-report-6091810]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 19:09:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Russian regional airliner carrying three crew members crashed in a forested area near Moscow on Friday, killing all on board, Russian news agencies reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Russian regional airliner carrying three crew members crashed in a forested area near Moscow on Friday, killing all on board, Russian news agencies reported.</p>

<p>The plane, a Russian-designed Superjet 100, was carrying out a test flight after undergoing scheduled repairs and crashed a little over an hour after taking off, the TASS news agency said.</p>

<p>"According to preliminary information, three pilots were killed. All those on board," emergency services were quoted as saying by the agency.</p>

<p>The plane was headed to Moscow's Vnukovo airport, according to state media.</p>

<p>It crashed in a forested area of the Kolomensky District, a municipality about 60 kilometres (37 miles) southeast of the capital, the RIA news agency reported.</p>

<p>A plume of grey smoke could be seen rising from the crash site in photos and videos shared on social media.</p>

<p>Russian investigators have opened a criminal probe into the crash, according to the RIA news agency.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/e7rcvtag_superjet-100-afp_625x300_12_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The plane was headed to Moscow's Vnukovo airport, Russia's state media said (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/japanese-political-candidate-strips-in-video-to-win-votes-asks-viewers-if-shes-sexy-6091632]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Japan Political Candidate Strips In Video, Asks Viewers If She's ''Sexy'']]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/japanese-political-candidate-strips-in-video-to-win-votes-asks-viewers-if-shes-sexy-6091632]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 18:46:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In the footage, Ms Uchino is shown seated at a table wearing a button-up shirt as she addresses Japanese voters in an anime-style voice.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A female political candidate in Tokyo's gubernatorial election has stirred controversy after she stripped herself on the national television broadcast. In a bizarre video promoting her campaign,&nbsp;Airi Uchino of the NHK Party stripped down to a tube top and asked viewers if she was "sexy" enough to win votes, the&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/07/11/world-news/candidate-strips-in-video-to-win-votes-in-tokyo-gubernatorial-race/"><em>New York Post</em> </a>reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In the footage, Ms&nbsp;Uchino is shown seated at a table wearing a button-up shirt as she addresses Japanese voters in an anime-style voice. She then strips down to a revealing tube top, striking a pose that suggests she is topless.&nbsp;</p>

<p>''I'm so cute; please watch my campaign broadcast. Do you think I'm sexy?'', she says in the video that has <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://x.com/mrjeffu/status/1806463678247830011">gone viral on X.&nbsp;</a>She further invited viewers to add her on the messaging app LINE, promising to respond to each message personally and&nbsp;delivered the rest of her speech in a nude-coloured tube top.</p>

<p>This political stunt has raised eyebrows, with many criticising her for objectifying herself and prioritising her physical appearance over policy and leadership qualities. Many said that they felt embarrassed, while some questioned how such a spectacle could have been permitted.</p>

<p>One user wrote, ''While it is true that people strive to stand out, and our society's obsession with appearances often rewards outlandish behaviour, nevertheless, individuals who lack substance will inevitably be unmasked by the passage of time.''</p>

<p>Another commented, ''At this point, they should change the rules the race is turning into a farce and distracting people from the real issues. Democracy and all but this is not it.'' A third said, ''No matter how much you talk about freedom of speech in elections, this goes against public welfare.''</p>

<p>Seems her unconventional approach didn't work as&nbsp;Yuriko Koike, 71, secured a third consecutive four-year term in the Tokyo gubernatorial election that was held on July 7, according to&nbsp;<em><a href="https://mainichi.jp/english/articles/20240707/p2g/00m/0na/039000c" target="_blank">Mainichi</a>.&nbsp;</em>Ms Koike became Tokyo's first female governor in 2016 and won her second term in 2020.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/6sqn3rd8_airi-uchino_625x300_12_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[This unconventional approach has raised eyebrows, with many criticizing her.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>