<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Sat, 30 Nov 2024 13:24:48 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/beware-netflix-users-this-scam-can-steal-your-credit-card-details-7138717]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Beware Netflix Users, This Scam Can Steal Your Credit Card Details]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/beware-netflix-users-this-scam-can-steal-your-credit-card-details-7138717]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 30 Nov 2024 13:14:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Cybersecurity experts have alerted Netflix users against an SMS phishing campaign being used to steal account and credit card information.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Cybersecurity experts have alerted Netflix users against an SMS phishing campaign being used to steal account and credit card information. Hackers are sending this phishing text, claiming the concerned person has not paid for their subscription and that their account will be suspended soon, the <a href="https://nypost.com/2024/11/29/tech/netflix-users-warned-about-scare-scam-that-could-steal-credit-card-information/ " rel="nofollow noindex" target="_blank">New York Post </a>reported.</p>

<p>"These SMS scare campaigns targeting Netflix customers have become ubiquitous and never stop, but they vary in size and scope," said security firm Bitdefender.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"NETFLIX: There was an issue processing your payment. To keep your services active, please sign in and confirm your details at..." reads one such alert. There is a link that directs viewers to a website that looks identical to the Netflix platform and asks for their credit card number and login credentials.</p>

<p>These stolen credentials are sold to underground rings on the dark web.</p>

<p>Netflix's lack of two-factor authentication protections has made the scam easier to spread in as many as 23 countries, including the US. The streaming platform is vulnerable to spear phishing as it only relies on usernames and passwords for security.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Netflix, in a statement about the text messages scam, said, "We will never ask you to enter your personal information in a text or email. We will never request payment through a 3rd party vendor or website. If the text or email links to a URL that you don't recognize, don't tap or click it."&nbsp;</p>

<p>If you have already clicked any of these links, the streaming giant suggests changing your Netflix password to a new one that is strong and unique. It also suggests updating your password on any other websites or apps where you used the same email and password combination.</p>

<p>Bitdefender, a cybersecurity firm, advises users to avoid opening suspicious links and manually enter websites rather than clicking links without verifying in order to prevent falling for scams.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/84n3op_netflix_625x300_22_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[These stolen credentials are sold to underground rings on the dark web. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/indian-origin-man-pockets-rs-8-45-crore-lottery-after-buying-jewellery-for-wife-7139570]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Indian-Origin Man Wins Rs 8.45 Crore Lottery After Buying Jewellery For Wife]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/indian-origin-man-pockets-rs-8-45-crore-lottery-after-buying-jewellery-for-wife-7139570]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 30 Nov 2024 12:57:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Singapore High Commission in India posted a congratulatory message for Balasubramanian Chithambaram after he won the lottery.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An Indian-origin man in Singapore has become an overnight millionaire after winning a grand prize of $1 million (Rs 8.45 crore) in a lucky draw last Sunday (Nov 24). The man, identified as Balasubramanian Chithambaram won the top prize after he purchased a gold chain for his wife three months ago at the store that conducted the lucky draw. Mustafa Jewellery, the shop running the contest, took to social media to share the news of the winner that left Mr Chithambaram elated and surprised in equal measure.</p>

<p>"What an unforgettable day at Mustafa Jewellery's Million Dollar Event! On 24th November, we witnessed history being made as the grand winner of USD 1,000,000 was revealed amidst cheers and excitement!" the store captioned the post.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DC3RJBsqesm/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DC3RJBsqesm/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DC3RJBsqesm/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DC3RJBsqesm/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by Mustafa Jewellery Singapore (@mustafajewellerysg)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p></p>

<p>Notably, to be eligible for participating in the lucky draw, the customers needed to spend over Rs 15,786 on jewellery. Mr Chithambaram had bought gold ornaments worth Rs 3.7 lakh for his wife during a visit to the store.</p>

<p>“Today is also my father's fourth death anniversary. It's a blessing,” said Mr Chithambaram after winning the prize, adding that he planned to donate a portion of the money to the community as a token of gratitude.</p>

<p>The news of Mr Chithambaram winning the grand prize even reached the Singapore High Commission in India which posted a congratulatory message for him.</p>

<p>"Congratulations to Mr Balasubramanian for winning the US$ 1 million (8.5 crore rupees) lucky draw, shopping at the iconic Mustafa Center @mustafacentresg in Singapore. Crorepati dreams do come true in SG," read the message posted on X (formerly Twitter).</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Congratulations to Mr Balasubramanian for winning the US$ 1 million (8.5 crore rupees) lucky draw, shopping at the iconic Mustafa Center <a href="https://twitter.com/MustafaCentreSG?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@mustafacentresg</a> in Singapore. Crorepati dreams do come true in SG ??. ?? HC Wong<a href="https://t.co/JtgHWMZVMu">https://t.co/JtgHWMZVMu</a></p>
— Singapore in India (@SGinIndia) <a href="https://twitter.com/SGinIndia/status/1862723804637851698?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 30, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>Earlier this week, a British man won the third-largest lottery of all time by pocketing 177 million pounds (Rs 1804.16 crore) in the Euromillions jackpot. According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c154jn0gd0eo" rel="noindex, nofollow">BBC</a>, if the winner is an individual rather than a syndicate splitting the prize-he or she will immediately become richer than musicians Harry Styles and Adele, who featured on this year's Sunday Times Rich List with fortunes of 175 million pounds and 170 million pounds, respectively.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/jrshpjq8_lottery_625x300_30_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-s-defence-secretary-pick-pete-hegseth-accused-of-abuse-by-mother-in-2018-email-7138953]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Defence Pick's Mother Accuses Him Of Decades-Long Mistreatment Of Women]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-s-defence-secretary-pick-pete-hegseth-accused-of-abuse-by-mother-in-2018-email-7138953]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 30 Nov 2024 12:15:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Pete Hegseth, Donald Trump’s pick for defence secretary, faces accusations from his mother of a ‘lack of character’ due to his behaviour towards women.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The mother of Pete Hegseth, US President-elect Donald Trump's choice for Secretary of Defence, accused him of mistreating women over the years and exhibiting a lack of moral character. The 2018 email, made public by <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/11/29/us/politics/pete-hegseth-mother-email.html" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">The New York Times</a>, painted a damning picture of his character.</p>

<p>“On behalf of all the women (and I know it's many) you have abused in some way, I say...get some help and take an honest look at yourself,” Penelope Hegseth wrote.</p>

<p>She added, “You are an abuser of women — that is the ugly truth and I have no respect for any man that belittles, lies, cheats, sleeps around, and uses women for his power and ego. You are that man (and have been for years) and as your mother, it pains me and embarrasses me to say that, but it is the sad, sad truth.”</p>

<p>Penelope Hegseth, speaking to The New York Times, acknowledged that she later sent an apologetic follow-up to Pete. “I fired off that original email in anger, with emotion,” she said, attributing the tone to the difficult circumstances surrounding her son's divorce from his second wife, Samantha.</p>

<p>The email's tone was scathing as Penelope criticised Pete for his treatment of Samantha. She wrote, “I have tried to keep quiet about your character and behaviour, but after listening to the way you made Samantha feel today, I cannot stay silent. And as a woman and your mother I feel I must speak out.”</p>

<p>She added, “Sam is a good mother and a good person (under the circumstances that you created) and I know deep down you know that. For you to try to label her as ‘unstable' for your own advantage is despicable and abusive. Is there any sense of decency left in you?”</p>

<p>Towards the end, she wrote, “We still love you, but we are broken by your behaviour and lack of character.”</p>

<p>Hegseth, a former Fox News contributor and veteran of the Iraq and Afghanistan wars, has been embroiled in controversy following Trump's nomination. The accusations in the email are particularly significant in the context of Hegseth's anticipated Senate confirmation hearings, where his character will be closely scrutinised. Reports of infidelity and a rape complaint dating back to 2017, which was not pursued by authorities, have already attracted attention, according to The New York Times. Hegseth has maintained the complaint was a false accusation by a woman he had a consensual relationship with and reportedly paid a settlement to protect his career.</p>

<p>At the time, Hegseth was navigating an acrimonious divorce process. Samantha, the mother of three of his children, filed for divorce after discovering Pete had fathered a child with Jennifer Rauchet, a colleague at Fox News.</p>

<p>In response to questions about the publication of the email, Steven Cheung, a spokesperson for President-elect Trump, accused The New York Times of releasing “an out-of-context snippet” and emphasised that Penelope Hegseth had apologised for the message.</p>

<p>The former couple's divorce, which was finalised in 2019, included disputes over parenting time that required court-appointed mediation. Pete Hegseth later stated that he regretted derogatory texts sent to Samantha, pledging to communicate more respectfully moving forward.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/s80c8g9_pete-hegseth-afp_625x300_17_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hegseth is a former Fox News contributor and veteran of the Iraq and Afghanistan wars]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-jails-journalist-who-met-with-japanese-diplomats-for-espionage-7139358]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[China Jails Journalist Who Met With Japanese Diplomats For Alleged Espionage]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-jails-journalist-who-met-with-japanese-diplomats-for-espionage-7139358]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 30 Nov 2024 12:11:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Beijing court on Friday sentenced veteran Chinese state media journalist Dong Yuyu to seven years in prison on espionage charges, his family said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Beijing court on Friday sentenced veteran Chinese state media journalist Dong Yuyu to seven years in prison on espionage charges, his family said.</p>

<p>Dong, a senior columnist at the Communist Party newspaper Guangming Daily, was detained in February 2022 along with a Japanese diplomat at a Beijing restaurant.</p>

<p>The diplomat was released after a few hours of questioning, but Dong, 62, was charged with spying last year.</p>

<p>"The Beijing No. 2 Intermediate People's Court convicted Yuyu of espionage, a crime that requires that the prosecution prove that the defendant knowingly acted on behalf of 'espionage organisations' and their agents," according to a statement shared by his family with AFP.</p>

<p>According to the judgement, the Japanese diplomats Dong met with, including then-ambassador Hideo Tarumi and current Shanghai-based chief diplomat Masaru Okada, were named as agents of an "espionage organisation", the family statement added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"We are shocked that the Chinese authorities would blatantly deem a foreign embassy as an 'espionage organisation' and accuse the former Japanese ambassador and his fellow diplomats of being spies," Dong's family said.</p>

<p>On Friday, Beijing's foreign ministry spokeswoman Mao Ning responded to Dong's case by saying "China is a country ruled by law".</p>

<p>The Japanese embassy told AFP that it would not comment directly on the case.</p>

<p>But an embassy spokesperson told AFP in an email: "The diplomatic activities of Japanese diplomatic missions abroad are carried out in a legitimate manner."&nbsp;</p>

<p>In Washington, State Department Spokesman Matthew Miller condemned Dong's jailing and called for his immediate release.</p>

<p>"His arrest and today's sentencing highlight the PRC's failure to live up to its commitments under international law and its own constitutional guarantees to all its citizens, which include the right to freedom of speech and freedom of the press," Miller said in a statement referring to China by its official name, the People's Republic of China.</p>

<p>The Committee to Protect Journalists (CPJ) condemned the "unjust verdict" and called for Dong's immediate release.</p>

<p>"Interacting with diplomats is part of a journalist's job," the NGO's Asia program coordinator Beh Lih Yi said in an email to AFP.</p>

<p>"This sentencing cements China's position as the world's leading jailer of journalists," added Yi.</p>

<p>Under Chinese law, a person convicted of espionage can be jailed for three to 10 years for less severe cases or receive heavy punishment, including life imprisonment, for serious cases.</p>

<p>Dong's work has been published in the Chinese editions of The New York Times and the Financial Times.</p>

<p>He won the prestigious Nieman Fellowship at Harvard University in 2006-2007.&nbsp;</p>

<p>He was also a visiting fellow at Keio University in Japan in 2010 and a visiting professor at Hokkaido University in 2014.</p>

<p>Civil liberties and freedom of expression have dramatically receded in China under President Xi Jinping's decade-long tenure.</p>

<p>The Communist Party maintains tight restrictions on domestic media outlets, and Chinese nationals who work with foreign outlets are routinely harassed.</p>

<p>China is the worst country for jailing media workers with 44 journalists behind bars as of December last year, according to a CPJ ranking.</p>

<p>In February, a Beijing court handed a suspended death sentence to jailed dissident writer Yang Hengjun after finding the dual Chinese-Australian citizen guilty on espionage charges.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/bt3vf5r_chinese-journalist-dong-yuyu-reuters_625x300_30_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Chinese journalist Dong Yuyu won the prestigious Nieman Fellowship at Harvard University in 2006-2007]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/canadian-news-publishers-sue-openai-over-copyright-violations-7139297]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: Why ChatGPT Maker OpenAI Has Been Sued By Canada News Publishers]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/canadian-news-publishers-sue-openai-over-copyright-violations-7139297]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 30 Nov 2024 12:00:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[This marks the first lawsuit of its kind in Canada, although similar legal actions are already underway in the US.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A group of major Canadian news publishers, including The Canadian Press, Torstar, Globe and Mail, Postmedia and CBC/Radio-Canada, have initiated legal proceedings against OpenAI, accusing the company of using their content to train its AI model, ChatGPT, without proper authorisation.<br />
<br />
In a joint release on November 29, the group alleged OpenAI has been systematically violating copyright laws by collecting vast amounts of data from Canadian media sources without consent.<br />
<br />
“OpenAI is capitalizing and profiting from the use of this content, without getting permission or compensating content owners,” the statement said, reported <a href="https://apnews.com/article/ai-media-lawsuits-center-for-investigative-reporting-chatgpt-mother-jones-c48452889750479410b65a119537746c" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">AP</a>.<br />
<br />
The lawsuit argues that such practices are detrimental to the investment made in journalism, amounting to hundreds of millions of dollars, and that content created by media organisations is safeguarded by copyright law.<br />
<br />
The statement continued, “News media companies welcome technological innovations. However, all participants must follow the law, and any use of intellectual property must be on fair terms.”<br />
<br />
Generative AI, like OpenAI's ChatGPT, can produce various forms of content, including text, images, videos and computer code, based on simple input. These systems rely on training data that must first include extensive pre-existing materials.<br />
<br />
OpenAI responded, saying its models were trained using data that was publicly available. According to the AP report, the company maintained that its practices were “grounded in fair use and related international copyright principles that are fair for creators and support innovation.”<br />
<br />
The company also mentioned that it worked “closely with news publishers, including in the display, attribution and links to their content in ChatGPT search” and provided outlets with “easy ways to opt-out should they so desire.”<br />
<br />
This marks the first lawsuit of its kind in Canada, although similar legal actions are already underway in the US. For example, <a href="https://apnews.com/article/ai-media-lawsuits-center-for-investigative-reporting-chatgpt-mother-jones-c48452889750479410b65a119537746c" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">The New York Times</a> filed a case against OpenAI and Microsoft in December for using the publication's stories to train chatbots.<br />
<br />
Similarly, in April 2024, eight American newspapers filed a lawsuit against OpenAI and Microsoft, claiming the tech giants have been unlawfully using vast amounts of copyrighted news content without consent or compensation to train their AI chatbots.<br />
<br />
But some news organisations have also opted to collaborate with OpenAI by agreeing to compensation deals for their content. The Associated Press, along with The Wall Street Journal and News Corp (the publisher of the New York Post), The Atlantic, Axel Springer (Germany) and Prisa Media (Spain), as well as France's Le Monde and the Financial Times in the UK, have all secured licensing arrangements over the past year.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/p46siel_openai-generic_625x300_10_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Representational Image]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nigeria-at-least-27-dead-several-missing-after-boat-capsizes-in-niger-river-7139254]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Nigeria: At Least 27 Dead After Boat Capsizes In Niger River]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nigeria-at-least-27-dead-several-missing-after-boat-capsizes-in-niger-river-7139254]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 30 Nov 2024 11:52:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Nigerian river ferry capsized Friday killing at least 27 people and leaving many missing, officials told AFP of the latest in a series of mass drownings on the country's busy waterways.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Nigerian river ferry capsized Friday killing at least 27 people and leaving many missing, officials told AFP of the latest in a series of mass drownings on the country's busy waterways.</p>

<p>The disaster happened on the Niger, near Dambo in Kogi state, at a point where West Africa's mightiest river can be more than 600 metres (yards) across.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"It's unclear how many people were on board, people don't usually keep a record of passengers," said Sandra Musa, of the state emergency management agency. "Search and rescue is still ongoing for survivors and possible bodies."</p>

<p>Musa said 27 bodies had been recovered. Kogi State Red Cross spokesman Abubakar Abullahi said the boat reportedly had more than 50 people on board.</p>

<p>Villagers and volunteers downstream of the accident have been urged to be on the lookout for bodies.</p>

<p>"It's not clear what caused the accident," Musa said. "It could be from turbulence or from the boat hitting a snag. Boat operators don't usually have life jackets, so none of the bodies recovered had life jackets on.</p>

<p>"The age of the boat might have played a role. Usually the lifespan of boat is between five and ten years, but you see boats aged 20 years. We will have a better idea of the situation tomorrow."</p>

<p>Kogi State Governor Ahmed Usman Ododo's office issued a statement lamenting the casualties and urging private boat operators and local authorities to ensure safety improvements.</p>

<p>Ododo, it said, "was particularly concerned that most of the victims were women, petty traders and artisans who are involved in legitimate business activities to earn a living and contribute to the economy of the state."</p>

<p>Friday's tragedy was the latest in a series of boat disasters on this stretch of the Niger flowing from the northeastern border towards central Nigeria and the Gulf of Guinea.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Last month, around a 100 people were feared dead after a boat carrying 300 passengers, many of them women and children, to a Muslim festival in Niger State flipped over in the river.</p>

<p>In September, an overloaded boat sank while carrying more than 50 farmers across the Gummi River in Zamfara state. More than 40 are believed to have died.</p>

<p>In June 2023, more than 100 people died when a river boat carrying around 250 passengers capsized in the north-central state of Kwara, one of the country's deadliest waterway accidents in years.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/1gk7o3h8_boat-capsized-istock-_625x300_30_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The boat reportedly had more than 50 people on board]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/syria-bashar-al-assad-aleppo-explained-whats-happening-in-syria-how-it-could-affect-middle-east-7139248]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: What's Happening in Syria, How It Could Affect Middle East]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/syria-bashar-al-assad-aleppo-explained-whats-happening-in-syria-how-it-could-affect-middle-east-7139248]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 30 Nov 2024 11:50:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The civil war in Syria had thawed. But 13 years since the beginning of one of the worst humanitarian crises of the 21st century, a new surge in violence has reignited attention on a conflict that had faded from the world's headlines.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The civil war in Syria had thawed. But 13 years since the beginning of one of the worst humanitarian crises of the 21st century, a new surge in violence has reignited attention on a conflict that had faded from the world's headlines. Syrian rebel forces have launched a major offensive on Aleppo, Syria's once-thriving commercial hub, marking the first challenge to President Bashar al-Assad's regime in years, potentially destabilising an already destabilised Middle East.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>Why Aleppo Matters</strong></h2>

<p>Aleppo, roughly 350 km north of the capital Damascus, has been a critical battleground in the Syrian civil war. Before the conflict, it was one of Syria's largest cities, home to 2.3 million people.</p>

<p>In 2012, rebel forces seized the eastern half of Aleppo, making it a stronghold of the rebellion against President Assad. However, the balance shifted in 2016 when Syrian government forces, backed by a brutal Russian aerial campaign, recaptured the city. The siege of Aleppo became symbolic, marked by indiscriminate bombings, starvation tactics, and massive displacement. By retaking Aleppo, Assad solidified his hold over key territories, bolstered by Russian and Iranian support.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont">
<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/0ck731bg_syria-reuters-_625x300_30_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: Reuters </span></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>

<p>The rebel offensive has targeted areas surrounding Aleppo and advanced toward its outskirts. If rebels succeed in breaking through, it could put a spanner in Assad's control over the crisis-hit country and reignite intense urban warfare.</p>

<h2><strong>The Actors Behind The Offensive</strong></h2>

<p>The primary force leading the charge is Hayat Tahrir al-Sham (HTS). Once affiliated with terror group al-Qaida, HTS has rebranded itself over the years, claiming to focus on governance and military strategy in opposition-held territories. While the United States and the United Nations continue to designate HTS as a terrorist organisation, its leader, Abu Mohammed al-Golani, has sought to distance the group from its extremist roots.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/u3ptikeg_syria-reuters-_625x300_30_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: Reuters </span></p>
</div>

<p>HTS's transformation includes efforts to promote civilian governance in areas it controls, as well as limited outreach to religious minorities. Despite these changes, the group maintains a controversial reputation, accused of harbouring extremist elements and tolerating militant activities within its territory.</p>

<p>HTS is joined by several Turkish-backed factions, operating under the umbrella of the Syrian National Army. These groups have long had a complex relationship, often fighting among themselves despite their shared opposition to Assad.</p>

<h2><strong>Objectives Of The Rebel Offensive</strong></h2>

<p>In a video statement announcing the campaign, rebel military commander Lt. Col. Hassan Abdulghany described the operation as a defensive necessity.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"To push back their fire from our people, this operation is not a choice. It is an obligation to defend our people and their land," he said, according to the New York Times. "It has become clear to everyone that the regime militias and their allies, including the Iranian mercenaries, have declared an open war on the Syrian people."</p>

<p>The rebels' immediate goals include halting airstrikes on civilian areas, reclaiming territory, and cutting off critical supply routes for government forces. Their progress so far has been rapid, capturing several villages, strategic highway interchanges, and military bases in Aleppo province.</p>

<h2><strong>The Assad Regime's Response</strong></h2>

<p>Syrian state media has reported fierce resistance by government forces, claiming to have inflicted losses on rebel fighters. The Syrian military, bolstered by Russian air support, has launched intense airstrikes on opposition-held areas, including the cities of Idlib and Atareb. Civilian casualties have mounted, with rescue groups like the White Helmets reporting dozens of deaths.</p>

<p>Iran, a key ally of Assad, has also suffered losses in the offensive. Among the casualties is a senior commander of Iran's Revolutionary Guards.</p>

<p>The Assad family, a Shia offshoot, has long relied on its alliance with Iran to stay in power. This alliance has been especially beneficial since 2011, when President Assad first faced an anti-government uprising.</p>

<p>After Syria plummetted into chaos in 2011, Iran has been accused of providing around 80,000 fighting personnel to Assad's army while Russia provided air support.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>Regional Dynamics</strong></h2>

<p>The timing of this offensive comes at a time when Iran and its proxies, including Hamas and Hezbollah, are engaged in conflicts elsewhere. Israel's military campaign against Hezbollah in Lebanon and Hamas in Gaza has strained their resources. Additionally, Russia's focus on its war in Ukraine limits its capacity to provide substantial reinforcements in Syria.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ui9lsju_syria-reuters-_625x300_30_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: Reuters </span></p>
</div>

<p>Turkey, a key player in Syria, backs some of the rebel factions involved in the offensive. Israel continues its airstrikes on Iranian-linked targets within Syria, seeking to disrupt arms shipments to Hezbollah. This creates a volatile mix of overlapping conflicts.</p>

<p>The renewed fighting has had devastating consequences for Syrian civilians, particularly in opposition-held areas. The International Rescue Committee estimates that nearly 7,000 families have been displaced recently.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Northwestern Syria is home to approximately 4 million people, most of whom have been displaced multiple times during the conflict. Many live in overcrowded camps with limited access to food, water, and medical care. The resurgence of violence threatens to worsen these conditions and trigger another wave of mass displacement.</p>

<h2><strong>Implications For The Assad Regime</strong></h2>

<p>While his regime controls about 70 per cent of Syrian territory, much of this control relies on the backing of external allies like Russia and Iran.</p>

<p>Additionally, the offensive risks reigniting broader conflicts within Syria. The Islamic State, though largely defeated, still operates in the region through sleeper cells. A weakening of government control could create openings for these extremist groups to regroup and expand their activities.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/71csl97o_syria-bashar-al-assad-afp-_625x300_30_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The primary force leading the charge is Hayat Tahrir al-Sham (HTS).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-approves-320-billion-f-16-fighter-planes-radar-systems-to-taiwan-7139155]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Approves $320 Billion F-16 Fighter Planes, Radar Systems To Taiwan]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-approves-320-billion-f-16-fighter-planes-radar-systems-to-taiwan-7139155]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 30 Nov 2024 11:34:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United States on Friday said it had approved the possible sale of spare parts for F-16 fighter planes and radar systems to Taiwan, in a deal valued at $320 million.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United States on Friday said it had approved the possible sale of spare parts for F-16 fighter planes and radar systems to Taiwan, in a deal valued at $320 million.</p>

<p>The proposed sale consists of equipment in existing US military stocks, the Defense Security Cooperation Agency said in a statement.</p>

<p>"This proposed sale serves US national, economic and security interests by supporting the recipient's continuing efforts to modernize its armed forces and to maintain a credible defensive capability," the DSCA said.</p>

<p>"The proposed sale will improve the recipient's ability to meet current and future threats by maintaining the operational readiness of the recipient's fleet of F-16 aircraft."</p>

<p>China insists self-ruled Taiwan is part of its territory and opposes any international recognition of the island and its claim to be a sovereign nation.</p>

<p>The United States, while not recognising Taiwan diplomatically, is a major international backer.</p>

<p>The proposed sale includes "spare parts and support for F-16 aircraft" and "Active Electronically Scanned Array (AESA) radar spare parts and support," DSCA said.</p>

<p>The Taipei Economic and Cultural Representative Office in the United States requested the purchase and deliveries were estimated to begin next year, it added.</p>

<p>The deal was approved by the State Department, with the DSCA providing the required notification to Congress on Friday.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-10/oqvbsjto_taiwan-f16-fighter-l-chinese-h6-bomber-afp_625x300_22_October_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The US, while not recognising Taiwan diplomatically, is a major international backer.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-buys-book-on-israels-settler-colonial-conquest-palestinian-author-reacts-7139154]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden Pictured With Book On Palestine, Author Responds]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-buys-book-on-israels-settler-colonial-conquest-palestinian-author-reacts-7139154]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 30 Nov 2024 11:34:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden was spotted holding a copy of 'The Hundred Years' War on Palestine' by Columbia University professor emeritus Rashid Khalidi.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden was spotted holding a copy of 'The Hundred Years' War on Palestine' by Columbia University professor emeritus Rashid Khalidi. The outgoing President surprised one and all with his pick during a Black Friday outing in Nantucket.</p>

<p>Mr Khalidi, the author of Palestinian and Lebanese descent, <a href="https://nypost.com/2024/11/29/us-news/biden-picks-up-anti-israel-book-during-black-friday-shopping-4-years-too-late-says-author/ " rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">reacted</a> to the pictures, saying the gesture was “four years too late.”</p>

<p>'The Hundred Years' War on Palestine'<em>&nbsp;</em>frames the establishment of Israel as a “settler-colonial conquest”, which met Palestinian resistance. In the 2020 book, Mr Khalidi, known for his pointed critique of US foreign policy on Israel, criticised Biden's successor, President-elect Donald Trump, in the book, describing his administration as a “mouthpiece for Israel.” He also labelled Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's administration as “the most extreme government” in the country's history.</p>

<p>Biden has long described himself as a Zionist and his administration has faced criticism from both pro-Israel and pro-Palestinian advocates. “You don't have to be a Jew to be a Zionist. <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/im-a-zionist-how-bidens-lifelong-bond-with-israel-shapes-war-policy-4503653">I am a Zionist</a>,” he said during a meeting with Israeli President Isaac Herzog last year.</p>

<p>The book critiques the Israeli policies and staunch US support for the Jewish state, making it all the more surprising for people that Biden picked it in public.</p>

<p>While Joe Biden paused shipments of heavy munitions to Israel earlier this year, he visited the country in solidarity after the October 2023 attack. He has faced vocal backlash from pro-Palestinian activists, who have accused him of complicity in the Gaza war, branding him “Genocide Joe” in protests.</p>

<p>Mr Khalidi's book talks about the history of Palestine, calling it a prolonged colonial struggle. It critiques US media for perceived bias and prescribes a future “based on equality and justice.” The text praises the First Intifada as a “victory” for Palestinians while labelling the Second Intifada a setback.</p>

<p>The book advocates for “a path based on equality and justice” that seeks to end “the oppression of one people by another.” It also highlights discriminatory policies against Palestinians, taking into account their diverse religious backgrounds, including both Muslims and Christians.</p>

<p>Describing the Israeli-Palestinian equation as a “settler-colonial confrontation”, the book argues that such conflicts historically end in one of three ways: the full subjugation or elimination of the Indigenous population, as seen in North America; the defeat and expulsion of colonisers, as in Algeria, which he acknowledges is rare; or the dismantling of colonial supremacy through compromise and reconciliation, as in South Africa, Zimbabwe, and Ireland.</p>

<p>Earlier, <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/world-leaders-welcome-israel-hezbollah-ceasefire-deal-7115188">Joe Biden welcomed the ceasefire</a> deal between Israel and Hezbollah. In a joint statement with French President Emmanuel Macron, Biden said the truce would protect Israel from Hezbollah's threats and pave the way for "lasting calm" in the region. He also pledged the US leadership to strengthen Lebanon's military capabilities and secure a broader peace, including efforts to address the conflict in Gaza.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/9rjcjjq8_biden_625x300_30_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Joe Biden has long described himself as a Zionist.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-must-protect-minorities-ensure-fair-trial-for-hindu-monk-jaishankar-7139093]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh Must Ensure Fair Trial For Hindu Monk: S Jaishankar]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-must-protect-minorities-ensure-fair-trial-for-hindu-monk-jaishankar-7139093]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 30 Nov 2024 11:21:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India said the interim government in Bangladesh must live up to its responsibility of protecting all minorities as it expressed serious concern over the "surge" of extremist rhetoric and increasing incidents of violence against Hindus as we]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India on Friday said the interim government in Bangladesh must live up to its responsibility of protecting all minorities as it expressed serious concern over the "surge" of extremist rhetoric and increasing incidents of violence against Hindus as well as attacks on temples in the neighbouring country.</p>

<p>New Delhi also hoped that the case relating to Hindu monk Chinmoy Krishna Das, arrested in Bangladesh on sedition charge, will be dealt with in a just, fair and transparent manner.</p>

<p>External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar told Parliament that India has taken a serious note of incidents of violence against minorities in Bangladesh and that it is the primary responsibility of Dhaka to protect the life and liberty of all the citizens, including minorities.</p>

<p>The relations between India and Bangladesh have come under strain after the interim government headed by Nobel laureate Muhammad Yunus came to power following the resignation of Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina in August amid unrest.</p>

<p>India has been expressing concern over attacks on minorities, especially Hindus, in that country.<br />
"The primary responsibility for the protection of life and liberty of all citizens of Bangladesh, including minorities, rests with the government of Bangladesh," Jaishankar said, adding that the Indian high commission in Dhaka continues to monitor the situation related to minorities in that country "closely".</p>

<p>Separately, the Ministry of External Affairs (MEA) called upon Bangladesh to take all steps for the protection of minorities and hoped that the case involving arrested Chinmoy Krishna Das will be dealt with in a just, fair and transparent manner.</p>

<p>MEA spokesperson Randhir Jaiswal said India has consistently and strongly raised with the Bangladeshi government the threats and targeted attacks on Hindus and other minorities. "Our position on the matter is very clear -- the interim government must live up to its responsibility of protecting all minorities," Jaiswal said at his weekly media briefing.</p>

<p>"We are concerned at the surge of extremist rhetoric, increasing incidents of violence and provocation. These developments cannot be dismissed only as media exaggeration. We once again call upon Bangladesh to take all steps for the protection of minorities," he added.</p>

<p>Responding to a question in the Lok Sabha, Jaishankar said India is concerned over incidents of violence against Hindus and other minorities, their homes and business establishments and attacks on temples and religious places.</p>

<p>"The government has taken a serious note of these incidents and shared its concerns with the government of Bangladesh." "Reports of attacks on temples and puja mandaps also came to light during the recent Durga Puja festival in Bangladesh. The government had expressed its serious concerns regarding the attack on a puja mandap in Tantibazar, Dhaka and theft at the Jeshoreshwari Kali temple at Satkhira during Durga Puja 2024," Jaishankar said.</p>

<p>Jaishankar said that following these attacks the Bangladeshi government had issued instructions for providing special security including deployment of Army and border guards to ensure a peaceful Durga Puja celebrations.</p>

<p>On the arrest of Das, who was associated with the ISKCON (International Society for Krishna Consciousness), Jaiswal said it is India's expectation that a fair and transparent trial will be ensured in the case. "We see ISKCON as a globally well-regarded organisation with a strong record of social service," he added.</p>

<p>Jaiswal said India has also noted that the legal processes in the case are underway. "We hope and expect that these processes will deal with the case in a just, fair and transparent manner, ensuring full respect for the legal rights of all concerned." Das was arrested at Dhaka's Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport on Monday in connection with a sedition case.</p>

<p>"It is our expectation that he will get a fair and transparent trial and his legal rights will be respected," Jaiswal said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/s43j36bc_s-jaishankar-brics-summit-pti_625x300_24_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Jaishankar said India is concerned over incidents of violence against Hindus and other minorities.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/prince-harry-meghan-markle-leading-isolated-life-in-us-reveals-documentary-director-7139013]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Harry and Meghan Leading 'Isolated' Life In US, Reveals Documentary Director]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/prince-harry-meghan-markle-leading-isolated-life-in-us-reveals-documentary-director-7139013]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 30 Nov 2024 11:05:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The documentary intends to examine whether the couple had achieved "freedom" and financial independence since stepping back from royal duties.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Amid reports about the alleged rift between Prince Harry and Harry Meghan, a documentary, based on the couple's life away from the spotlight of the royal family in the UK, is set to release in Germany next month. Award-winning filmmaker Ulrike Grunewald who travelled to the Californian town of Montecito to record the couple's experiences, said they had been leading a very 'isolated' life in what was a lively setting for socialising and mingling in the who's who of America.</p>

<p>"Harry and Meghan have set the bar very high. They want to be global benefactors who bring about tangible change. So far, they have not lived up to this image at all," Ms Grunewald, who has been a royal correspondent since 1987, told <em>The Mail.</em></p>

<p>“The cultural life here is very lively but often happens in closed circles, and Harry and Meghan rarely participate. They seem to have isolated themselves a lot.”</p>

<p>A similar version was echoed by one of the neighbours named Richard Mineards who said the Sussexes were seldom seen in the town.</p>

<p>"Sometimes you see her at the farmers' market or walking a dog, but generally, you don't see much of her or him. It's a shame. This is a lovely place," Mr Mineards said.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/prince-harrys-friend-james-haskell-talks-about-dysfunctional-royal-family-7115521" rel="noindex, nofollow"><strong>Also Read | Prince Harry's Friend Talks About "Dysfunctional" Royal Family</strong></a></p>

<p>Notably, the film intends to examine whether the couple had achieved "freedom" and financial independence since stepping back from royal duties.</p>

<p>"During the year that we worked on this film, a change of strategy was recognisable in Harry and Meghan. They started out as a power duo in their new life in California," said Ms Grunewald.</p>

<p>Now they mainly appear separately, as they were unable to create a functioning image together. They have come down to earth. I was interested in whether Harry and Meghan's strategies for an independent life are working. After four years, the results are very mixed," she added.</p>

<h3><strong>Professional separation?</strong></h3>

<p>In the last week, multiple reports have claimed that the couple was exploring separate career paths, in what experts have described as 'professional separation'. While Ms Markle is reportedly aiming to launch American Riviera Orchard next year, Mr Harry is planning the second iteration of Invictus Games in Canada. The first installment took place in Dusseldorf, Germany in 2023 and invited positive reviews. However, reports suggest that it cost German taxpayers 40 million euros (Rs 357 crore), undermining the goodwill.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/eevn588_prince-harry-meghan-markle_625x300_30_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Prince Harry and Meghan Markle during an event.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fact-check-was-muhammad-yunus-daughter-arrested-for-drunk-driving-7138962]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Fact Check: Was Muhammad Yunus' Daughter Arrested For Drunk Driving?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fact-check-was-muhammad-yunus-daughter-arrested-for-drunk-driving-7138962]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 30 Nov 2024 10:56:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Muhammad Yunus, the Nobel Laureate and chief adviser of the interim government of Bangladesh, has often been in the spotlight, not just for his achievements but also for his contentious relationship with the US president-elect Donald Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Claim</strong>: The video shows Monica Yunus, daughter of Nobel Laureate Muhammad Yunus, getting arrested for drunken driving.</p>

<p><strong>Fact</strong>: The claim is false. The woman in the video is not Monica Yunus.</p>

<p><strong>Hyderabad:</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/nobel-laureate-muhammad-yunus-takes-oath-as-head-of-bangladeshs-interim-government/article68502489.ece" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank"> Muhammad Yunus</a>, the Nobel Laureate and chief adviser of the interim government of Bangladesh, has often been in the spotlight, not just for his achievements but also for his contentious relationship with the US president-elect Donald Trump.</p>

<p>The friction between the two dates to 2016 when Yunus made a significant donation to Hillary Clinton's foundation, an act that<br />
reportedly upset Trump. With Trump set to return to the White House after defeating Kamala Harris, political analysts predict that Yunus may face further challenges given his past remarks and actions.</p>

<p>Amid these ongoing developments, a set of photographs and a video have gone viral on social media, claiming to show <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.weforum.org/people/monica-yunus/" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">Monica Yunus</a>, the American-Bangladeshi music performer and daughter of Muhammad Yunus, being arrested for drunken driving.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.threads.net/@omkararoots/post/DC1GlW7TJBm?xmt=AQGzXuWbmENY-m2VIX0-aXXR6-JGt1vcCaEv7IJks-c_hA" target="_blank">A user on Threads</a> shared the images and the video with the caption, "He failed to raise his own kids n people think he is guiding muslim youth???? Trump-hater Muhammad Yunus supports gay rights. His daughter #MonicaYunus is a lesbian. She was arrested by cops in drunken state. Now can we ask those Islamists in Bangladesh to see the real identity of their 'leader'? (sic)"</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/q8sg1k08_yunus_625x300_30_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p>&nbsp;The text on the images claimed that Monica Yunus is a lesbian and was arrested for driving under the influence. The video, captioned with inflammatory remarks about Muhammad Yunus and his family, shows a woman reportedly identifying herself as 'Monica Younus' during a police interaction.</p>
</div>

<p>Similar claims can be seen <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.threads.net/@shahadatali3870/post/DCiMQJ-P6L9?xmt=AQGzsgVioYeEP50NwERADhIfv5I7HDv82jl9mHcfaldxjA" target="_blank">here</a> and <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.facebook.com/kolappan1947/posts/pfbid02ohstXB3j7gQbgQBsziH1Rd72fqaBcb2z8V17u2B3fDKxeUrG3aRqyVRjQnsdUeY1l?rdid=dGXGbq6vQLzuv7ds" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>

<h3><strong>Fact Check</strong></h3>

<p>NewsMeter found that the claim is false. The woman in the video is not Monica Yunus.</p>

<p>Monica Yunus is an internationally renowned soprano, celebrated for her artistry and contributions to arts and culture.</p>

<p>A keyword search led us to Monica Yunus' official profiles, including her <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.monicayunus.com/" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">website</a> and <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.facebook.com/YunusMonica" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">Facebook account</a>, confirming her professional identity as an opera singer and social entrepreneur.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/jhatoi88_yunuss_625x300_30_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p>We found an article published in <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.nytimes.com/2009/06/14/fashion/weddings/14YUNUS.html" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">The New York Times</a> titled ‘Monica Yunus, Brandon McReynolds' dated July 13, 2009. According to the article, Monica Yunus has been married to Brandon McReynolds since 2009.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/u8jcrcgo_bangla_625x300_30_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>&nbsp;We couldn't find any reports of Monica Yunus being arrested or being known to have been seen driving under the influence of alcohol.</p>

<p></p>

<p>To verify if the person in the video is Monica Yunus, we compared the individual's face in the viral video with publicly available photos of Monica Yunus. The comparison confirmed that the two women are different individuals.</p>

<p>Here is a comparison of images.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/d81kcu8_monica_625x300_30_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p>&nbsp;A reverse image search of the viral video led to a 1:14-hour-long <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sKLYf-cPNKE" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">YouTube video</a> titled, 'Drunk Woman Crashes her Car After a Breakup in Verona, New Jersey'. The thumbnail is the same as the images in the claim. The viral portion can be seen at the begin of the video, starting at 0:45 seconds.</p>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="315" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/sKLYf-cPNKE?si=HBqJ8G1ggLMouxI7" title="YouTube video player" width="560"></iframe>

<p>The video under investigation is the bodycam footage taken from this video.</p>
</div>
</div>

<p>According to the video caption, the incident took place on April 16, 2022, when a woman named Monica was involved in a car accident in Verona, New Jersey. The video shows the driver admitting to consuming alcohol after breaking up with her girlfriend.</p>

<p>While the woman in the video shares the name "Monica," her identity is entirely unrelated to Monica Yunus.</p>

<p>Monica Yunus's most recent <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DBgy92SJ2Yk/?igsh=Z2txYTZzNDc0andn&amp;img_index=1" target="_blank">Instagram post</a>, dated October 24, 2024, was about the celebration of "Sing for Hope." This is non-profit organization, co-founded by her and Camille Zamora, both opera singers, focuses on spreading hope through music.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/vf7f0kio_yunusd_625x300_30_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Hence, the viral claim that a set of photos and a video shows Monica Yunus, daughter of Muhammad Yunus, getting arrested for drunken driving is false. The woman in the video is not Monica Yunus, as verified through image comparisons, official profiles and reports.</p>

<p><strong>Claim Review</strong>: The video shows Monica Yunus, daughter of Nobel Laureate Muhammad Yunus, getting arrested for drunken<br />
driving.</p>

<p><strong>Claimed By</strong>: Social Media Users</p>

<p><strong>Claim Reviewed By</strong>: NewsMeter</p>

<p><strong>Claim Source</strong>: Threads and Facebook users</p>

<p><strong>Claim Fact Check</strong>: False</p>

<p><strong>Fact</strong>: The claim is false. The woman in the video is not Monica Yunus.</p>

<p><em>(This story was originally published by&nbsp;<a href="https://newsmeter.in/fact-check/nehru-slapped-for-calling-arya-samaj-members-refugees-no-picture-is-from-a-patna-party-meeting-739748">NewsMeter</a>, and republished by NDTV as part of the Shakti Collective)</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/agjfk0ag_yunus_625x300_30_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Monica Yunus is an internationally renowned soprano.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/foul-smell-at-international-space-station-how-the-situation-was-handled-7138857]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA['Toxic' Odour At International Space Station Detected. What Happened Next?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/foul-smell-at-international-space-station-how-the-situation-was-handled-7138857]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 30 Nov 2024 10:33:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Cosmonauts detected a strange odour emanating from a Russian spacecraft after it docked at the International Space Station (ISS) last weekend.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Cosmonauts detected a strange odour emanating from a Russian spacecraft after it docked at the International Space Station (ISS) last weekend. The Progress supply mission, carrying various supplies for the crew onboard the space station, was launched from Kazakhstan's Baikonur Cosmodrome on November 21, NASA said in a statement.</p>

<p>After the hatch to the Russian spacecraft was opened, they noticed an "unexpected odour and observed small droplets," <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.foxweather.com/earth-space/cosmonauts-russian-progess-cargo-delivery-iss-unwelcome-smell" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">Fox Weather</a> reported. The crew shut the hatch and sealed the rest of the Russian segment.</p>

<p>"The unpiloted Progress 90 spacecraft arrived at the space-facing port of the International Space Station's Poisk module at 9:31 a.m. EST, Saturday, November 23. The spacecraft launched at 7:22 a.m. (5:22 p.m. Baikonur time) Nov. 21, on a Soyuz rocket from the Baikonur Cosmodrome in Kazakhstan," the US space agency said.</p>

<p>On Monday, Roscosmos cosmonauts Ivan Vagner and Aleksandr Gorbunov re-opened the hatch to unpack the supplies, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/11/23/space-delivery-arrives-at-station-aboard-progress-cargo-craft/" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">NASA</a> said in another update about the mission.</p>

<p>"Flight controllers on the ground activated air scrubbing equipment as part of normal procedures, indicating that the odor likely was outgassing from materials inside the cargo spacecraft," the US space agency said, adding the crew reported the odour dissipated quickly. The cargo transfer operations proceeded as per the schedule.</p>

<p>According to NASA, the Roscosmos spacecraft delivered nearly three tons of food, fuel, and supplies for the Expedition 72 crew onboard the space station.</p>

<p>It is scheduled to remain docked at ISS for approximately six months and will depart into the Earth's atmosphere to dispose of trash loaded by the crew.</p>

<p>Along with the air scrubbing, Ivan Vagner also cleaned the ventilation system and photographed the inside of the Progress spacecraft.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/qbabbl48_russian-spacecraft-at-iss_625x300_26_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Roscosmos cosmonauts re-opened the hatch to unpack the supplies.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/luciana-curtis-us-model-family-kidnapped-at-gunpoint-in-brazil-kept-in-remote-shack-7138758]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Model, Kidnapped By Armed Men In Brazil, Released After 12 Hours]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/luciana-curtis-us-model-family-kidnapped-at-gunpoint-in-brazil-kept-in-remote-shack-7138758]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 30 Nov 2024 10:18:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A New York-based model, her husband and their 11-year-old child were abducted at gunpoint and held captive in a remote shack in Sao Paulo, Brazil, for 12 hours.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A New York-based model, her husband and their 11-year-old child were abducted at gunpoint and held captive in a remote shack in Sao Paulo, Brazil, for 12 hours. The incident occurred on November 27. Luciana Curtis and her photographer husband, Henrique Gendre, were ambushed by armed men when they left a local restaurant. The gang forced them into their own car at gunpoint and took them to a wooden shack, according to a local Sao Paulo outlet, Gazeta. The shack, described as rudimentary, reportedly contained only a mattress, a toilet and a sink.</p>

<p>“The armed criminals approached the victims outside a restaurant and took them captive,” police stated in an official release, as per the <a href="https://nypost.com/2024/11/29/world-news/new-york-based-model-and-her-family-kidnapped-held-hostage-in-brazil/" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">NY Post</a>. During their captivity, the gang reportedly coerced the couple into transferring money from their bank accounts. On November 28, the family was abandoned by their captors as police search teams closed in on the area.</p>

<p>According to the report in <a href="https://www.gazetasp.com.br/cotidiano/bandidos-sequestram-familia-apos-jantar-na-zona-oeste-de-sao-paulo/1147097/" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">Gazeta</a>, the couple's eldest daughter, noticing no one returned home for a long time, alerted her uncle, who immediately contacted the police.</p>

<p>“During the search by specialist police teams, the gang abandoned the family and fled,” police added.</p>

<p>Seeking help, the family flagged down locals in a passing truck, who escorted them to the nearest police station. There, officers from the anti-kidnapping division recorded their statements and launched an investigation. Acting on the information, they tracked down the hideout, only to discover it had already been abandoned.</p>

<p>A spokesperson for the model confirmed their safety, stating, “The family has been released and they are safe and well.”</p>

<p>Curtis, a native of Sao Paulo and daughter of British businessman Malcolm Leo Curtis, divides her time between New York, Sao Paulo and London. She gained fame in 1993 after winning the Brazilian final of the Supermodel of the World competition.</p>

<p>The 47-year-old has graced the covers of renowned fashion magazines such as Marie Claire and Cosmopolitan. Her career includes collaborations with global icons such as Beyonce and leading brands, including Harrods, H&amp;M and Victoria's Secret.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/hfhig2l8_luciana-curtis-_625x300_30_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The 47-year-old has graced the covers of fashion magazines such as Marie Claire and Cosmopolitan.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sydney-woman-kills-husband-with-drop-saw-disposes-of-body-in-30-plastic-bags-7138774]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Sydney Woman Kills Husband With Drop Saw, Disposes Of Body In 30 Bags]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sydney-woman-kills-husband-with-drop-saw-disposes-of-body-in-30-plastic-bags-7138774]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 30 Nov 2024 10:18:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Police allege she killed him on May 3 last year using knives and a power saw, and disposed of his body in plastic bags across several suburbs.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The New South Wales Supreme Court has refused bail to Nirmeen Noufl, a 53-year-old Australian woman accused of killing her 62-year-old husband, Mamdouh "Emad" Noufl. After taking control of certain finances, Noufl, who appeared in court with the help of family and friends, allegedly killed and mutilated her husband.</p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.smh.com.au/politics/nsw/wife-dismembered-husband-with-drop-saw-to-escape-abusive-marriage-20241128-p5ku7f.html"><em>the Sydney Morning Herald,</em></a> police allege that on May 3 last year, Noufl acted alone in the killing, using knives and a power saw at their Greenacre home in western Sydney. The body parts were reportedly placed in up to 30 plastic bags and discarded in bins across multiple suburbs. Noufl was arrested last month after checking herself into a mental health hospital, where police gathered what they believed to be strong circumstantial evidence against her. Her husband's remains have yet to be found.</p>

<p>"The Crown would submit that there was a personal motive for the applicant [Ms Noufl] to act on the night of the alleged offence, and that was to escape a relationship she was not happy with, that she felt trapped with," the Crown prosecutor said. The Crown submitted that when Mr Noufl gave his wife legal authority of his properties in Egypt in May, it "presented an opportunity" for her to "get out of the relationship".</p>

<p>During the court hearing, it was revealed that a witness, known as "Witness A," claimed to have seen Noufl's actions on the night of the alleged murder. Another witness testified that Noufl made statements that could be seen as admissions of guilt. The police fact sheet indicated Noufl was motivated by abuse she suffered and her husband's relationship with a woman in Egypt, to whom he had become engaged while remaining married to her.</p>

<p>A witness, identified as "Witness A," said at the court hearing that he saw Noufl's behaviour the night of the suspected murder. According to the testimony of another witness, Noufl made remarks that can be interpreted as confessions of guilt. According to the police fact sheet, Noufl was driven by the abuse she experienced and her husband's affair with a lady in Egypt, with whom he had become engaged while still being married.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/rk3a5gro_-nirmeen-noufl_625x300_30_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Police searched the Greenacre home of Nirmeen Noufl.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-woman-claims-wifi-router-overheating-set-her-home-on-fire-7138729]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Woman Claims WiFi Router 'Overheating' Set Her Home On Fire]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-woman-claims-wifi-router-overheating-set-her-home-on-fire-7138729]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 30 Nov 2024 10:08:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Florida resident Keona Huntley said she had been experiencing issues with the WiFi router for some time.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A woman in the US state of Florida has claimed that her home was destroyed in a fire that was caused by her WiFi router overheating, according to a report in <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/11/28/us-news/homeowner-issues-warning-after-wi-fi-router-sparks-fire/" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>NY Post</em></a>. Keona Huntley, who goes by the handle @yeahthatskeeee on TikTok, shared the now-viral video in the aftermath of the fire, stating that the blaze started in her bedroom where the router was kept. According to Ms Huntley, she had been experiencing issues with the device for some time and that a technician from the company responsible for it, Quantum Fibre, had visited her home on multiple occasions to sort out the problem.</p>

<p>Although the router had been replaced with a new one, the problems persisted as internet issues forced her to call the experts yet again. In the video, Ms Huntley also shared the aftermath of the fire that spread throughout the house, leaving almost everything charred. Starting in the kitchen, Ms Huntley showed the blackened walls with debris littered across the surface.</p>

<p>"We literally lost everything today. My bathroom is over there. it doesn't even look like a bathroom," said Ms Huntley. Her bedroom had been reduced to nothing but spring coils after the mattress was burned up.</p>

<p>Ms Huntley's problems have been expedited as she did not have renters insurance which means she has no way of covering the damage to her personal items.</p>

<p>“I didn't have renters insurance, and that was on me. I have to live with that guilt now that my kids don't have a home. I can't even replace their stuff," she said.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/uk-woman-fined-for-littering-cigarette-in-village-she-hadnt-visited-for-decades-7138440" rel="noindex, nofollow"><strong>Also Read | UK Woman Fined For Littering Cigarette In Village She Hadn't Visited For Decades</strong></a></p>

<h3><strong>Investigation underway</strong></h3>

<p>"Our family's world was turned upside down when we lost our home to a devastating fire. In a matter of moments, the place where we built memories, shared laughter and found comfort was reduced to ashes," Ms Huntley wrote on her GoFundMe page.</p>

<p>Ms Huntley and her family are now seeking temporary housing and essential items as the house is rebuilt. "We never imagined finding ourselves in this position, but now we are reaching out to our community, friends, and kind-hearted strangers for help," she added.</p>

<p>Although Ms Huntley is of the view that the Quantum Wi-Fi router caused the fire, the authorities have launched an investigation to confirm whether the device was defective or if it was external factors that caused the incident.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/mmfkb2j_fire_625x300_30_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Keona Huntley's charred house after the fire.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/cash-strapped-sri-lanka-records-highest-deflation-in-61-years-7138722]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Cash-Strapped Sri Lanka Records Highest Deflation In 61 Years]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/cash-strapped-sri-lanka-records-highest-deflation-in-61-years-7138722]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 30 Nov 2024 10:04:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Sri Lanka's consumer prices fell by 2.1 percent in November, the highest deflation rate recorded by the economically fragile island nation since 1961, official data showed Saturday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sri Lanka's consumer prices fell by 2.1 percent in November, the highest deflation rate recorded by the economically fragile island nation since 1961, official data showed Saturday.</p>

<p>An unprecedented financial crash in 2022 brought months of consumer goods shortages, with inflation peaking at nearly 70 percent that year.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Since then, a $2.9 billion bailout loan from the International Monetary Fund, tax hikes and other austerity measures have slowly made headway in repairing the island's economy.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Headline inflation will remain negative in the next few months, deeper than previously projected, mainly due to larger downward adjustments in energy prices and reduction in volatile food prices," Sri Lanka's central bank said in a statement.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The bank said inflation was likely to return to its target level of five percent in the coming months.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Sri Lanka had already seen deflation of 0.8 percent in October and 0.5 percent in September.</p>

<p>President Anura Kumara Dissanayake, who was elected in September, has vowed to maintain the IMF bailout programme negotiated by his predecessor that includes higher taxes and cuts to state spending.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-12/pqpaltag_sri-lanka-generic_625x300_13_December_23.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sri Lanka had already seen deflation of 0.8 percent in October.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-s-elon-musk-simple-algorithm-to-help-him-make-fewer-dumb-mistakes-7138642]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How Elon Musk Makes "Fewer Dumb Mistakes"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-s-elon-musk-simple-algorithm-to-help-him-make-fewer-dumb-mistakes-7138642]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 30 Nov 2024 09:42:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Elon Musk's algorithm is rooted in questioning requirements, simplifying processes and prioritising automation last.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Tesla CEO Elon Musk has shared his mantra to reduce errors and improve decision-making at his companies. This “simple algorithm” forms the backbone of the tech billionaire's productivity and operational efficiency strategies.</p>

<p>The method was first highlighted in a post on X (formerly Twitter), where an image of the algorithm displayed on a wall at SpaceX drew attention. Mr Musk responded to the post, explaining the rationale behind his creation.</p>

<p>“This simple algorithm that I came up with to help me make fewer dumb mistakes in the future is incredibly powerful,” he wrote.</p>

<p>The five steps of Mr Musk's algorithm are:</p>

<ul>
	<li>Make requirements less dumb</li>
	<li>Delete the part or process step</li>
	<li>Optimise</li>
	<li>Accelerate</li>
	<li>Automate</li>
</ul>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">This simple algorithm that I came up with to help me make fewer dumb mistakes in the future is incredibly powerful <a href="https://t.co/tRJhe0gy6y">https://t.co/tRJhe0gy6y</a></p>
— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1862363270931255356?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 29, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Walter Isaacson mentioned the algorithm in Mr Musk's biography and detailed each step. He&nbsp;said that Mr Musk insists every requirement be scrutinised and traced back to an individual, rather than accepting it as a directive from a vague entity such as the “legal department” or “safety department.”</p>

<p>Mr Musk also advocates deleting parts or processes wherever possible. He notes they may have to be added back later, adding that if people do not end up adding back at least 10 per cent of them, they didn't delete enough.</p>

<p>Optimisation should only come after unnecessary elements have been removed. Mr Musk warns against the common mistake of simplifying and optimising components or processes that shouldn't exist in the first place.</p>

<p>The world's richest man also encourages accelerating processes only after ensuring the first three steps have been thoroughly addressed. Reflecting on his experience, in the biography, Mr Musk noted, “In the Tesla factory, I mistakenly spent a lot of time accelerating processes that I later realised should have been deleted.”</p>

<p>Automation should be the final step in the process. Mr Musk noted that attempting to automate flawed systems early on can lead to significant inefficiencies.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/04dtmd6g_elon-musk_625x300_22_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mr Musk noted that attempting to automate flawed systems early on can lead to significant inefficiencies.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bank-accounts-of-hindu-leader-16-iskcon-members-frozen-in-bangladesh-7138607]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[After Hindu Leader's Arrest, 17 ISKCON Bank Accounts Frozen In Bangladesh]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bank-accounts-of-hindu-leader-16-iskcon-members-frozen-in-bangladesh-7138607]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 30 Nov 2024 09:33:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Bangladesh's authorities have ordered freezing for 30 days the bank accounts of 17 people associated with ISKCON, including its former member Chinmoy Krishna Das arrested this week on sedition charges, media reports said Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bangladesh's authorities have ordered freezing for 30 days the bank accounts of 17 people associated with ISKCON, including its former member Chinmoy Krishna Das arrested this week on sedition charges, media reports said Friday.</p>

<p>The move comes after the Bangladesh High Court rejected a petition seeking a ban on International Society for Krishna Consciousness (ISKCON), following the killing of a lawyer in a clash between the Hindu leader's supporters and security personnel.</p>

<p>The Bangladesh Financial Intelligence Unit (BFIU) sent these directives to different banks and financial institutions on Thursday, suspending all types of transactions related to these accounts for a month, newspaper Prothom Alo said.</p>

<p>The financial intelligence agency under the central Bangladesh Bank asked the banks and financial institutions to send information, including updated transaction statements of accounts related all businesses owned by these 17 individuals, within the next three working days, it said.</p>

<p>On October 30, a sedition case was filed against 19 people, including Das, at Chattogram's Kotwali Police Station, accusing them of disrespecting Bangladesh's national flag in Chattogram's New Market area during a rally of the Hindu community.</p>

<p>Das, a spokesperson for the Bangladesh Sammilita Sanatani Jagran Jote, was arrested from Dhaka's Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport on Monday for alleged sedition. He was denied bail and sent to jail by a Chattogram court on Tuesday, triggering protests by his supporters.</p>

<p>On Tuesday, New Delhi expressed concern over the leader's arrest and denial of bail, and asked Bangladesh to ensure the safety of Hindus and other minorities.</p>

<p>Ousted Bangladesh prime minister Sheikh Hasina too has sought the priest's release. She also condemned the killing of the lawyer during the protests over his arrest.</p>

<p>ISKCON Bangladesh refuted allegations linking it to the lawyer's killing, saying the claims were baseless and part of a malicious campaign.</p>

<p>A spokesman of the attorney general's office said a two-member High Court bench that declined to ban the ISKCON activities in Bangladesh also said the situation did not warrant the intervention of the (High) court "at this time" as the State is carrying out its job. The Bench hoped that the government would remain cautious about protecting the law and order situation and the lives and properties of the people of Bangladesh.</p>

<p>Hindus --- the community constituted about 22 per cent of Bangladesh's population during the 1971 Liberation War, now make up roughly 8 per cent - have been frequently reporting atrocities against their community members in different parts of Bangladesh.</p>

<p>There are also reports of the rise of extremist groups such as the Jamaat-e-Islami and similar ideological extremist wings.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ninval3k_isckon-priest-hindu-priest-chinmoy-krishna-das_625x300_26_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Bangladesh Financial Intelligence Unit (BFIU) sent these directives to different banks.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/uk-woman-fined-for-littering-cigarette-in-village-she-hadnt-visited-for-decades-7138440]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK Woman Fined For Littering In Village She Hadn't Visited For Decades]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/uk-woman-fined-for-littering-cigarette-in-village-she-hadnt-visited-for-decades-7138440]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 30 Nov 2024 08:54:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Natalie Walton claimed that she could not have been the accused as she is a non-smoker and has not visited the place where the offence took place.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Natalie Walton has been left confused ever since she received a fine for dropping a cigarette in a village, nearly 300 kilometres from her home -- a place she had not visited in over a decade. The fixed penalty notice (FPN), addressed to Ms Walton, was sent to her parent's house in Gravesend, Kent, accusing her of littering in nearby Swanscombe. The notice, dated November 12, stated a Dartford council officer witnessed her "committing an offence" which was also recorded on a body-worn camera, on October 29 and that she needed to pay a £75 (Rs 8,082) fine or appeal it.</p>

<p>The notice added that Ms Walton could be taken to court and if convicted, she may have to pay a fine "up to &amp; £2,500 (Rs 2,69,410) for littering".</p>

<p>"As neither the payment nor the written challenge has been received, you remain liable for the offence and prosecution proceedings in the magistrates' court may begin immediately against you," the notice added.</p>

<p>Ms Walton claimed that she could not have been the accused as she is a non-smoker and has not visited the place where the offence took place, since she was a kid. Ms Walton added she had an alibi which proved she was not even in Kent at the time of the supposed offence.</p>

<p>"I had not been to Kent for months. Dartford council were trying to fine me &amp;#163;75 for something I was not even there to do. It is just a bit bizarre. I was accused of littering a cigarette in Swanscombe which is honestly more absurd, as I do not smoke and have never been to the address they have claimed I was at," she was quoted as saying by <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.kentonline.co.uk/dartford/news/i-was-fined-for-dropping-a-cigarette-in-a-town-i-ve-never-b-316541/" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>KentOnline</em></a>.</p>

<p>"I feel like a complete victim of fraud. Someone must have stolen my identity or the council's security measures are so broken they will take a name and address with no proof."</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/watch-man-eats-banana-artwork-he-bought-for-rs-52-crore-in-auction-7138037" rel="noindex, nofollow"><strong>Watch: Man Eats Banana Artwork He Bought For Rs 52 Crore In Auction</strong></a></p>

<h3><strong>Evidence presented</strong></h3>

<p>As the controversy snowballed, Ms Walton produced her bank transactions, proving she was shopping in B&amp;M and Tesco in Staffordshire at the time of the littering incident. After her protest and examination of the evidence, the Dartford Council said Ms Walton's FPN was cancelled.</p>

<p>"When I saw the email, I was relieved and felt so much less stressed but I still have no idea how they thought it was me," she said.</p>

<p>The council, meanwhile, said the real accused had given the wrong address to the officers and pointed them towards Ms Walton.</p>

<p>"Our enforcement team requested a current photo of Ms Walton and upon receiving it was compared to the person in the footage. It was found it was not Ms Walton and the FPN has now been cancelled."</p>

<p>The council is still investigating who the real offender is but was unable to provide a photo.</p>

<p>Despite the fine being revoked, Ms Walton said the entire ordeal had left her stressed, especially when she is getting married in two weeks.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/e3kqje8o_cigarette_625x300_28_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Natalie Walton has been fined for dropping a cigarette in a town she has never been to.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>