<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Tue, 15 Oct 2024 21:09:57 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/s-jaishankar-1st-minister-in-nearly-a-decade-to-visit-pakistan-whats-expected-6795687]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Jaishankar 1st Minister In Nearly A Decade To Visit Pak. What's Expected]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/s-jaishankar-1st-minister-in-nearly-a-decade-to-visit-pakistan-whats-expected-6795687]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 15 Oct 2024 20:27:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[S Jaishankar today landed in Islamabad to attend a conclave of the SCO, in the first visit to Pakistan by an Indian minister in nearly a decade.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar today landed in Islamabad to attend a conclave of the Shanghai Cooperation Organisation (SCO), in the first visit to Pakistan by an Indian minister in nearly a decade.</p>

<p>Ilyas Mehmood Nizami, the Director General for South Asia at the Ministry of Foreign Affairs, warmly received Mr Jaishankar at Nur Khan Airbase in Islamabad, a foreign statement said.</p>

<p>Children dressed in traditional attire presented bouquets to the foreign dignitaries. A red carpet was rolled out to welcome the guests, underscoring the importance of the event, it added.</p>

<p>It is the first time in nearly nine years that India's foreign minister has travelled to Pakistan. Ties between the two neighbours have remained frosty over the issue of cross-border terrorism emanating from Pakistan. India has, on multiple occasions, clearly stated that "talks and terror cannot go hand-in-hand", and Pakistan must "stop using terrorism as an instrument of state policy by harbouring and shielding terrorists."</p>

<p>The last Indian Foreign Minister to visit Pakistan was Sushma Swaraj. She had travelled to Islamabad in December 2015 to attend a conference on Afghanistan.</p>

<p>"External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar will represent India at the meeting. India remains actively engaged in the SCO format, including various mechanisms and initiatives within the SCO framework," the Ministry of External Affairs (MEA) said in a brief statement in New Delhi.</p>

<h2><strong>'NO INDIA-PAK TALKS'</strong></h2>

<p>In his recent address at an event, Jaishankar said "like with any neighbour, India would certainly like to have good relations with Pakistan."</p>

<p>"But that cannot happen by overlooking cross-border terrorism and indulging in wishful thinking."</p>

<p>The decision to send the senior minister to Pakistan, which is the host nation for the Shanghai Cooperation Organisation Summit this time, is seen as a display of India's commitment to the SCO.</p>

<p>The foreign minister had earlier clearly stated that his visit to Islamabad was not to discuss "India-Pakistan relations", but instead, it is about the multilateral event - SCO Summit 2024. Speaking further about his visit, Mr Jaishankar had emphasised that he is travelling to Pakistan "only to be a good member of the SCO."</p>

<h3><strong>SECURITY ARRANGEMENTS</strong></h3>

<p>To ensure the safety and security of the 23rd SCO summit in Islamabad, the Pakistan Army has deployed to safeguard the event, key government buildings and the Red Zone area where state guests are staying.</p>

<p>The delegates will stay at different venues in Islamabad located within the 'Red Zone' or in its vicinity, as 14 locations in the capital have been arranged for their accommodation, Pakistani news website Dawn reported.</p>

<h3><b>SCO MEETING IN PAKISTAN</b></h3>

<p>According to the programme released by a spokesperson of Pakistan's Foreign Ministry, the dinner hosted by Prime Minister Shehbaz Sharif remains the only official engagement for the visiting leaders and delegations today.</p>

<p>The second day of the meeting will begin with Mr Sharif receiving leaders at Islamabad's Jinnah Convention Centre. The proceedings will begin following a group photograph and Prime Minister Sharif's opening remarks at the conference.</p>

<p>The signing of various documents will take place before Pakistan's Deputy Prime Minister Ishaq Dar and SCO Secretary General Zhang Ming make their media statements. It will be followed by an official luncheon hosted by the country's PM.</p>

<p>The other SCO member states are represented by the Prime Ministers of China, Russia, Belarus, Kazakhstan, Kyrgyzstan, Tajikistan and Uzbekistan as well as the First Vice President of Iran. Prime Minister of Mongolia (Observer State) and Deputy Chairman of the Cabinet of Ministers and Foreign Minister of Turkmenistan (Special Guest) will also participate in the meeting.</p>

<p>Mr Jaishankar is expected to be in Islamabad for only about 24 hours and no India-Pakistan bilateral engagement is scheduled or expected on the sidelines of the summit.</p>

<p><strong><em>(Inputs from ANI, PTI, IANS)</em></strong><br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/u26ncgk4_s-jaishankar-pakistan-visit-pti_625x300_15_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[S Jaishankar today arrived in Islamabad to attend a conclave of the Shanghai Cooperation Organisation]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-teacher-46-groomed-teen-student-before-having-sex-with-him-alleges-lawsuit-6796417]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Teacher Groomed Teen Student Before Having Sex With Him, Alleges Lawsuit]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-teacher-46-groomed-teen-student-before-having-sex-with-him-alleges-lawsuit-6796417]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 15 Oct 2024 20:16:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[On his eighth-grade graduation day, Solis took the boy into a classroom, locked the door, and coerced him into sex.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A family of a 14-year-old student has claimed in a lawsuit that a California school teacher named Michelle Christine Solis, 46, groomed and sexually assaulted their son on his graduation day at Sycamore Middle School. The sexual assault has left the boy traumatised, the family alleges.</p>

<p>According to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.sacbee.com/news/local/crime/article293790999.html" rel="nofollow, noindex"><em>Sacramento Bee</em></a>, new allegations in the lawsuit say that Solis often organised meet-ups with the student. That's not all, she also gave him a pass for recess and spent alone time with him by saying she was helping him with homework.&nbsp;</p>

<p>On his eighth-grade graduation day, Solis took the boy into a classroom, locked the door, and coerced him into sex. According to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.buttecounty.net/DocumentCenter/View/13732/July-18-2024---FORMER-GRIDLEY-TEACHER-SENTENCED-TO-PRISON-FOR-SEX-WITH-STUDENT"><em>Butte County District Attorney's Office</em></a>, the student then sent him photos of their encounter and asked the boy to delete their chats.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Rumours and copies of one of the nude photographs began to circulate in the Gridley community in October 2023. A Gridley Police investigation ensued and investigators contacted the boy and reviewed the contents of his phone, according to a press release by The Butte County District Attorney's Office. There they found communication between Solis and the boy, including two explicit photographs of Solis that matched the descriptions the boy previously provided.</p>

<p>The lawsuit further claims that the school failed to properly monitor their teacher's behaviour nor did they train other teachers to properly detect the grooming behaviour, the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/10/15/us-news/california-teacher-michelle-christine-solis-groomed-student-under-guise-of-tutoring-suit/"><em>New York Post</em></a> reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The suit is seeking "general damages and other non-economic relief" for physical, mental and emotional injuries sustained by the student.</p>

<p>Mark Boskovich, an attorney for the boy, told the local outlet that sexual abuse has traumatised the boy and had a lasting effect on him.</p>

<p>"He is back in the classroom where he had no control of the situation and felt helpless," Mr Boskovich told the Bee.</p>

<p>Solis, who has been a teacher for 20 years was sentenced to four years in prison back in July 2024. She is serving her sentence at the Central California Women's Facility in Chowchilla.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/1dgg6mco_michelle-christine-solis_625x300_15_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Solis was sentenced to four years in prison]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/most-victims-of-israeli-air-strike-in-lebanon-were-women-and-children-un-6796048]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Most Victims Of Israeli Air Strike In Lebanon Were Women And Children: UN]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/most-victims-of-israeli-air-strike-in-lebanon-were-women-and-children-un-6796048]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 15 Oct 2024 19:28:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The UN human rights office said on Tuesday it had received reports that most of the 22 victims of an Israeli air strike on a building in northern Lebanon were women and children.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The UN human rights office said on Tuesday it had received reports that most of the 22 victims of an Israeli air strike on a building in northern Lebanon were women and children.</p>

<p>"What we are hearing is that amongst the 22 people killed were 12 women and two children," UN human rights office spokesperson Jeremy Laurence told a Geneva press briefing in response to a question about a strike on Aitou on Monday.</p>

<p>"We understand it was a four-story residential building that was struck. With these factors in mind, we have real concerns with respect to IHL (International Humanitarian Law), so the laws of war, and the principles of distinction proportion and proportionality," he said, calling for an investigation.</p>

<p>At the same press briefing, the UN refugee agency's Middle East Director Rema Jamous Imseis said that new Israeli evacuation orders to 20 villages in southern Lebanon meant that over a quarter of the country was now affected.</p>

<p>"Now we have over 25% of the country under a direct Israeli military evacuation order," she said. "People are heeding these calls to evacuate, and they're fleeing with almost nothing."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/l4hegd3o_israel-strike-lebanon_625x300_15_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A damaged vehicle sits amid rubble at a site damaged by an Israeli air strike in northern Lebanon.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-accused-of-plagiarism-in-2009-book-about-being-smart-on-crime-6795921]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris Accused Of Plagiarism In Book About Being 'Smart On Crime']]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-accused-of-plagiarism-in-2009-book-about-being-smart-on-crime-6795921]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 15 Oct 2024 19:10:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US Vice President Kamala Harris is under scrutiny due to allegations of plagiarism in a book she co-authored in 2009.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US Vice President Kamala Harris is under scrutiny due to allegations of plagiarism in a book she co-authored in 2009. According to <em>Newsweek</em>, Dr Stefan Weber, a renowned 'plagiarism hunter' from Austria, has claimed that Ms Harris and co-author Joan O'C Hamilton had 27 "fragments of plagiarism" in the book <em>'Smart on Crime: A Career Prosecutor's Plan to Make Us Safer'</em>. Mr Weber and his team also alleged that the Democratic presidential nominee and her co-author copied and pasted from a Wikipedia article for the book.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.newsweek.com/kamala-harris-plagiarism-claim-smart-crime-1968831" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>Newsweek</em></a>, Mr Weber accused Ms Harris of reproducing verbatim language from sources such as news articles and studies in his report. "Kamala Harris fabricated a source reference, inventing a nonexistent page number. The self-promotional content from Goodwill Industries was copied verbatim without citing the source (Goodwill Industries was her 'primary partner' on in [sic] the 'Back on Track' program)," he said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"In many other instances, even when a source was cited with a footnote, the text was directly copied and pasted without using quotation marks. Quotation marks would have been the most transparent and honest approach, also in non-academic books. Further signs of dishonesty may be evident when sources were copied but specific details were altered, such as replacing a Subway store owner with a sandwich shop clerk (p. 124) or highlighting Southeast Asia in the context of the US gang problem (p. 184)," Mr Weber added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Further, the Austrian professor alleged that one particular mention of New York City's Midtown Community Court in the book pertains to its use of language and structure that closely mirrors a Wikipedia article, indicating a lack of proper citation and paraphrasing. Mr Weber also highlighted minor and serious infractions, claiming that some text was directly copied from sources without adequate acknowledgement. In his report, he also showed specific plagiarism allegations regarding a mention of the West Palm Beach Community Court in Ms Harris' book.</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-kamala-harris-locked-in-close-election-race-show-polls-6791543">&nbsp;Donald Trump, Kamala Harris Locked In Close Election Race, Show Polls</a></strong></p>

<p>"After copying from the Wikipedia article, she continues by copying from the PDF linked in the Wikipedia article's first reference. Although she acknowledges at the end of the book that she took examples of community courts from that report (without providing the URL), the copied sections are presented as if they were her own words. The word-for-word copying still requires quotation marks to maintain proper attribution," Mr Weber wrote.</p>

<p>He also pointed out that while some parts of the appropriate content may be cited, not enough of the original source is acknowledged, a technique known as "pawn sacrifice plagiarism".</p>

<p>Mr Weber even claimed that in 2009, Ms Harris gave a "live" interview about the book to CBS, "which in parts consisted of a prior interview for another media which in turn contains many verbatim text chunks from her book."</p>

<p>Meanwhile, reacting to the accusations, Senator JD Vance trolled Ms Harris for using Wikipedia, claiming that he at least authored his own book. "Lmao Kamala didn't even write her own book!" he tweeted.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Donald Trump Jr. also commented on the issue, writing, "Yikes! More evidence that Kamala Harris is a fraud!!!"</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/mjjmrfoo_kamala-harris_625x300_20_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Ms Harris is accused of copy-pasting from a Wikipedia article.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/maldives-president-fires-over-225-political-appointees-to-cut-costs-6795821]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Maldives President Fires Over 225 Political Appointees To Cut Costs]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/maldives-president-fires-over-225-political-appointees-to-cut-costs-6795821]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 15 Oct 2024 18:59:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Maldives president has sacked more than 225 political appointees, including ministers, in a bid to reduce the cash-strapped Indian Ocean nation's expenditure, his office said on Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Maldives president has sacked more than 225 political appointees, including ministers, in a bid to reduce the cash-strapped Indian Ocean nation's expenditure, his office said on Tuesday.</p>

<p>Mohamed Muizzu ordered the removal of those he appointed after coming to power last year as the small but strategically located nation struggles to stave off a debt crisis.</p>

<p>"This significant reduction in political appointments aligns with the president's broader efforts to streamline government operations and ensure more efficient use of public funds," a statement from Muizzu's office said.</p>

<p>Among those sacked were seven state ministers, 43 deputy ministers and 178 political directors.</p>

<p>It was not clear what functions they performed in the tiny nation of about half a million people.</p>

<p>The statement did not say how many more political appointees remained in the administration but added that the mass reduction of staff would save the country about $370,000 a month.</p>

<p>The Maldives said in September its financial troubles were "temporary" and that it had no plans to seek an International Monetary Fund bailout despite warnings of a possible sovereign default.</p>

<p>Known as a luxury holiday destination with pristine white sand beaches and secluded resorts, the Maldives has also become a geopolitical hotspot.</p>

<p>China and India are the two largest bilateral lenders to the Maldives, made up of 1,192 coral islands scattered across the equator.</p>

<p>China has pledged more funding since last year's victory by Muizzu, who thanked Beijing for its "selfless assistance" for development funds.</p>

<p>Muizzu was welcomed in New Delhi this month by Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi, who rolled out financial support to bolster Male's struggling economy.</p>

<p>Official data showed the Maldives' foreign debt at $3.37 billion in the first quarter of this year, equating to around 45 percent of gross domestic product.</p>

<p>China accounted for about 20 percent of the external debt, while India owned just under 18 percent.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-03/fn3c9kgo_maldives-president-mohamed-muizzu-ani_625x300_06_March_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Maldives president Mohamed Muizzu ordered the removal of political appointees. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-york-times-issues-cease-and-desist-notice-to-ai-startup-over-content-use-6795457]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[New York Times' "Cease And Desist" Notice To AI Startup Over Content Use]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-york-times-issues-cease-and-desist-notice-to-ai-startup-over-content-use-6795457]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 15 Oct 2024 18:19:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The New York Times has sent generative AI startup Perplexity a "cease and desist" notice demanding the company stop using its content, the Wall Street Journal reported on Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The New York Times has sent generative AI startup Perplexity a "cease and desist" notice demanding the company stop using its content, the Wall Street Journal reported on Tuesday.</p>

<p>The letter from the news publisher said the way Perplexity was using its content, including to create summaries and other types of output, violates its rights under copyright law, the report said.</p>

<p>Since the introduction of ChatGPT, publishers have been raising the alarm on chatbots which can comb the internet to find information and create paragraph summaries for the user.</p>

<p>Perplexity and the New York Times did not immediately respond to Reuters' requests for comment.</p>

<p>NYT is also tussling with OpenAI, which it had sued late last year, accusing the firm of using millions of its newspaper articles without permission to train its AI chatbot.</p>

<p>Other media firms such as The Atlantic and Vox Media have signed content licensing deals with OpenAI which give the ChatGPT-maker access to their content.</p>

<p>In the letter to Perplexity, NYT asked the company to provide information on how it is accessing the publisher's website despite its prevention efforts, according to the WSJ report.</p>

<p>Perplexity had previously assured the publisher it would stop using "crawling" technology, the report said citing the letter.</p>

<p>Earlier this year, Reuters reported multiple AI companies were bypassing a web standard used by publishers to block the scraping of their data used in generative AI systems.</p>

<p>Perplexity faced accusations from media organizations such as Forbes and Wired for plagiarizing their content, but has since launched a revenue-sharing program to address some concerns put forward by publishers.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/6eiqb848_new-york-times_625x300_15_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Pedestrians walk by the New York Times building in Manhattan, New York.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russian-man-survives-two-months-adrift-at-sea-two-others-die-in-tragic-voyage-6795353]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Kind Of Miracle": Russian Man Survives 2 Months Adrift At Sea]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russian-man-survives-two-months-adrift-at-sea-two-others-die-in-tragic-voyage-6795353]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 15 Oct 2024 18:02:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Russian man was found alive after drifting for two months on an inflatable boat while another man and a teenage boy died, prosecutors said Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Russian man was found alive after drifting for two months on an inflatable boat while another man and a teenage boy died, prosecutors said Tuesday.</p>

<p>The two men and a 15-year-old set off to the Island of Sakhalin from the far eastern Khabarovsk region on August 9, transport prosecutors said.</p>

<p>"After a time, communication with them was lost, their boat's location remained unknown," they said.</p>

<p>"On October 14 around 10:00 pm, the boat was discovered as it passed a fishing boat... Two people died, one remained alive, he is receiving medical help," prosecutors said.</p>

<p>The dinghy was found in the Sea of Okhotsk, around 1,000 kilometres (670 miles) from its starting point.</p>

<p>Prosecutors published a video showing the bearded survivor in a life jacket shouting at the fishermen: "I don't have much strength" but managing to catch a rope.</p>

<p>The survivor was named by RIA Novosti news agency as Mikhail Pichugin, while his brother Sergei, 49, and nephew Ilya, 15, died. Their bodies were on the boat.</p>

<p>Russian rescuers had mounted a search using helicopters and a plane for the men a few days after they disappeared, suspecting the boat had been carried by currents towards Kamchatka.</p>

<p>Alexei Arykov, the owner of the fishing boat that found the survivor said he was "in a serious condition, thin, but conscious," RIA Novosti reported.</p>

<p>The boat docked around 0830 GMT in the far eastern city of Magadan and the survivor was carried off on a stretcher, the news agency reported.</p>

<p>The survivor's wife Yekaterina told RIA Novosti: "It's a kind of miracle", adding that the men had taken enough food and water to last only two weeks.</p>

<p>She said her husband's weight could have helped save him, as "he weighed around 100 kilograms" (220 pounds). Russian television reported he lost 50 kilograms.</p>

<p>The brothers were from Ulan-Ude in Siberia but Mikhail Pichugin was working on Sakhalin as a driver.</p>

<p>He had invited his brother and nephew to visit and they planned a sea trip to see whales, Komsomolskaya Pravda tabloid reported, citing relatives.</p>

<p>An expert questioned by RIA Novosti recalled that in 1960, four Soviet soldiers survived 49 days adrift on a small boat in the Pacific Ocean that was found by the US aircraft carrier Keersarge.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/5o5gd6go_russia-man-adrift_625x300_15_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Russian man found alive in the Sea of Okhotsk after drifting for two months.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/air-india-delhi-chicago-diverted-to-canada-after-online-security-threat-6795199]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hoax Calls Ground 7 Flights, Air India Jet Lands At Remote Canada Airport]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/air-india-delhi-chicago-diverted-to-canada-after-online-security-threat-6795199]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 15 Oct 2024 17:41:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An Air India direct flight from New Delhi to Chicago was diverted toIqaluit Airport in Canada today following a hoax bomb threat which was posted online.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An Air India direct flight from New Delhi to Chicago was diverted to&nbsp;Iqaluit Airport in Canada today following a hoax bomb threat which was posted online. A total of 10 flights have been grounded in less than 48 hours after receiving hoax threats.</p>

<p>Today, the Air India Delhi-Chicago flight,&nbsp;Dammam-Lucknow IndiGo flight, Ayodhya-Bengaluru Air India Express,&nbsp;a SpiceJet flight from Darbhanga to Mumbai (SG116), an Akasa Air flight from Bagdogra to Bengaluru (QP 1373)&nbsp;an Alliance Air Amritsar-Dehradun-Delhi flight (9I 650) and an Air India Express flight (IX 684) from Madurai to Singapore received bomb threats.</p>

<p>Yesterday, two IndiGo and one Air India flight also received fake threats.</p>

<p>"Flight AI127 operating from Delhi to Chicago on October 15, 2024, was the subject of a security threat posted online and, as a precautionary measure, has landed at Iqaluit Airport in Canada.</p>

<p>"The aircraft and passengers are being re-screened as per the laid down security protocol. Air India has activated agencies at the airport to assist the passengers until such time that their journey can resume," the airline said.</p>

<p>As per FlightRadar24, the Air India flight AI127 flight took off from New Delhi for Chicago at 3:00 am (IST) and was scheduled to land in Chicago at 7:00 am (US Time). The aircraft is a Boeing 777.</p>

<p>At 5:38 pm (IST) the flight is still at the airport in Canada. The flight is yet to take off.&nbsp;</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/d7imq3tg_flightradar24-ai127_625x300_15_October_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: FlightRadar24.com</span></p>
</div>

<p>"We are cognisant of a situation involving flight 6E 98 from Dammam, Saudi Arabia to Lucknow. The safety and security of our passengers and crew is our highest priority and we are working closely with the relevant authorities and taking all necessary precautions as per the guidelines," IndiGo said after the flight was grounded following a fake bomb threat.</p>

<p>The SpiceJet aircraft landed safely at the Mumbai airport and was directed to an isolation bay as a precautionary measure.</p>

<p>"All passengers disembarked normally and security agencies were immediately notified. After thorough security checks, the aircraft has been cleared for further operations," a SpiceJet spokesperson said.</p>

<p>An Akasa Air spokesperson said their flight received a security alert on board.</p>

<p>"The captain followed all required emergency procedures and landed safely at the Kempegowda International Airport, Bengaluru at 13:39 hours. All passengers were deplaned and the local authorities undertook the necessary safety and security checks after which the aircraft was released for operations," the spokesperson said.</p>

<p>An Alliance Air official said all "precautionary measures" were being taken for the Amritsar-Dehradun-Delhi flight, which was undergoing security checks at the Dehradun airport.</p>

<p>The fake bomb threats were made from an unverified X handle and the Bureau of Civil Aviation Security (BCAS) is investigating the matter.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Sources in the airlines told NDTV that the threats are impacting the finances but the airlines are taking the threats seriously and following the laid out security protocol for safety.</p>

<p><strong>3 Fake Security Threats On 3 Flights</strong></p>

<p>Yesterday, t<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/3-fake-security-threats-on-3-flights-from-mumbai-impact-hundreds-of-fliers-6784697">hree international flights, two operated by IndiGo and one by Air India</a>, received fake security threats, leading to disruption in outbound international flight operations, as checks were initiated for all three planes involved. The total number of passengers across the two IndiGo flights was 258. One of the flights has already departed while the other will resume its journey this afternoon.</p>

<p>According to the Bureau of Civil Aviation Security (BCAS), a total of three planes received bomb threats. "One IndiGo plane has been permitted to fly. The two other planes will get permission to fly soon," the BCAS told NDTV.</p>

<p>The first incident involved Air India flight AI119, scheduled to fly from Mumbai to New York's JFK Airport. Following a security alert, the flight was urgently diverted to New Delhi's Indira Gandhi International (IGI) Airport early in the morning. Passengers and crew were evacuated safely, and the aircraft was taken to an isolated runway. A bomb squad and other security agencies promptly began conducting a thorough inspection.</p>

<p>"Flight AI119 operating from Mumbai to JFK on October 14 received a specific security alert and on instructions of the government's security regulatory committee was diverted to Delhi. All passengers have disembarked and are at the Delhi airport terminal," an Air India spokesperson confirmed.</p>

<p>Simultaneously, two IndiGo flights originating from Mumbai were also affected. Flight 6E1275, bound for Muscat, and Flight 6E56, heading to Jeddah, received security threats, resulting in immediate measures being taken by the airline. According to an IndiGo spokesperson, both aircraft were moved to isolated bays at Mumbai Airport, following standard operating procedures. The Muscat-bound plane has already departed.</p>

<p>"As per protocol, the aircraft was taken to an isolated bay, and mandatory security checks were promptly initiated," the spokesperson said.</p>

<p>The second affected IndiGo flight, 6E56, heading to Jeddah, followed the same protocol. The airline reiterated that safety remains its top priority, and all steps were being taken to ensure the security of passengers and crew.</p>

<p>- <em>Inputs from PTI</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/h2fqafvg_air-india-plane-iqaluit_625x300_15_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[An Air India Boeing 777 on a flight from Delhi to Chicago makes a landing at Canada's Iqaluit Airport.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-iran-conflict-we-listen-to-us-but-final-decision-will-be-ours-israel-on-iran-retaliation-6795027]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA['We Listen To US But Decision Will Be Ours': Israel On Iran Retaliation]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-iran-conflict-we-listen-to-us-but-final-decision-will-be-ours-israel-on-iran-retaliation-6795027]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 15 Oct 2024 17:22:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's office said Tuesday that Israel -- and not the United States -- will decide how it will strike back after Iran fired around 200 missiles at his country earlier this month.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's office said Tuesday that Israel -- and not the United States -- will decide how it will strike back after Iran fired around 200 missiles at his country earlier this month.</p>

<p>The comments came as a top Iranian commander, whose absence sparked rumours that he could have been killed in an Israeli strike, appeared in public for the first time in weeks.</p>

<p>Israel and the Iran-backed group Hezbollah also exchanged fire as fighting raged in Lebanon, while humanitarian groups sounded the alarm about a dire humanitarian crisis in the Gaza Strip.</p>

<p>On October 1, Iran launched a volley of about 200 missiles at Israel in response to an Israeli strike in Lebanon's capital Beirut that killed Hezbollah leader Hassan Nasrallah and Iranian general Abbas Nilforoushan.</p>

<p>Israel has vowed to respond to the attack. Biden -- whose government is Israel's top arms supplier -- has warned against striking Iran's nuclear or oil facilities in order to avoid broader war.</p>

<p>According to a Washington Post report on Monday citing unnamed US officials, Netanyahu reassured the White House that Israel was only contemplating targeting military sites.</p>

<p>A statement from Netanyahu's office on Tuesday took a different tone.</p>

<p>"We listen to the opinions of the United States, but we will make our final decisions based on our national interest," the statement said.</p>

<p>Also on Tuesday, Esmail Qaani, the head of Iran's powerful Quds Force, attended the funeral for Nilforoushan, dispelling rumours he had been killed.</p>

<p><strong>Israel and Hezbollah exchange fire</strong></p>

<p>Israel's military launched several strikes on eastern Lebanon on Tuesday, a day after Netanyahu vowed to "mercilessly strike Hezbollah in all parts of Lebanon -- including Beirut".</p>

<p>Multiple Israeli air strikes hit the eastern Bekaa Valley, putting a hospital in Baalbek city out of service, Lebanon's official National News Agency (NNA) reported.</p>

<p>"It was a violent night in Baalbek, we have not witnessed a similar one since" the 2006 war between Israel and Lebanon, 50-year-old resident Nidal al-Solh told AFP.</p>

<p>Israeli strikes have targeted Hezbollah strongholds as well as other parts of Lebanon, including a northern Christian-majority village where at least 21 people were killed on Monday, according to the health ministry.</p>

<p>Anis Abla, civil defence chief in the southern border town of Marjayoun, said that "our rescue missions are becoming more and more difficult, because the strikes are never-ending and target us".</p>

<p>At least 1,315 people have been killed in Lebanon since Israel last month escalated its bombing there, according to an AFP tally of Lebanese health ministry figures, though the real toll is likely higher.</p>

<p>The war in Lebanon has displaced at least 690,000 people, according to verified figures last week from the International Organization for Migration.</p>

<p>UNICEF and the World Food Programme on Tuesday called for more funding to address "increasing" needs in Lebanon.</p>

<p><strong>'Entirely unjustified'</strong></p>

<p>Israel says it wants to push back Hezbollah in order to secure its northern boundary and allow tens of thousands of people displaced by rocket fire since last year to return home safely.</p>

<p>Hezbollah claimed several attacks early Tuesday, including targeting Israeli troops in northern Israel with a salvo of rockets.</p>

<p>It also said it downed an Israeli Hermes 450 drone overnight, without specifying where.</p>

<p>Fighters from Hezbollah also clashed with Israeli troops in a Lebanese border village, and sent rockets towards the northern Israeli town of Kiryat Shmona, the group said.</p>

<p>Hezbollah says its strikes are also in support of Palestinian militants Hamas who attacked Israel on October 7 last year, triggering the ongoing war with Israel in the Gaza Strip.</p>

<p>Israel has faced new criticism over injuries and damage sustained by UNIFIL, the United Nations peacekeeping force which has been deployed in Lebanon since 1978, after a previous Israeli invasion.</p>

<p>Italian Prime Minister Giorgia Meloni, whose country is the second-biggest contributor of UNIFIL peacekeepers, lashed out at the Israeli attacks. The attitude of the Israeli forces was "entirely unjustified," she told the Italian Senate.</p>

<p>The UN Security Council for the first time on Monday expressed "strong concerns" over peacekeepers being wounded in Lebanon.</p>

<p>UNIFIL has refused Netanyahu's request for peacekeepers to "get out of harm's way", with UN peacekeeping chief Jean-Pierre Lacroix saying the blue helmets will stay in their positions.</p>

<p><strong>'Unimaginable fear' in Gaza</strong></p>

<p>While deploying troops into Lebanon, Israel has kept up its bombardment of Gaza where it has been at war since the Hamas attack on southern Israel.</p>

<p>That attack resulted in the deaths of 1,206 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally of official Israeli figures, including hostages killed in captivity.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory military campaign in Gaza has killed 42,344 people, the majority civilians, according to the health ministry in the Hamas-run territory. The UN has described the figures as reliable.</p>

<p>At a school-turned-shelter hit by an Israeli strike in the central Nuseirat camp, Fatima al-Azab said "there is no safety anywhere" in Gaza.</p>

<p>"They are all children, sleeping in the covers, all burned and cut up," she said.</p>

<p>In northern Gaza, the Israeli military announced it had effectively laid siege to the Jabalia area as it seeks to rout out Hamas fighters.</p>

<p>The International Committee for the Red Cross warned that "northern Gaza families are facing unimaginable fear, loss of loved ones, confusion, and exhaustion".</p>

<p>"People must be able to flee safely," the ICRC's Adrian Zimmerman said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/itlt6efc_benjamin-netanyahu-reuters_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel PM Benjamin Netanyahu' s office has vowed to respond to the attack. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-ai-forecasts-floods-but-cannot-erase-risk-of-disaster-6794905]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: AI Forecasts Floods, But Cannot Erase Risk Of Disaster]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-ai-forecasts-floods-but-cannot-erase-risk-of-disaster-6794905]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 15 Oct 2024 17:09:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[AI has supercharged weather forecasting, using a range of statistical tools to analyse years of historical data and predict patterns, and at a lower cost than traditional numerical weather predictions.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">When floods ripped through parts of Europe in September, the scale of the destruction took people by surprise. The intense rains should not have, because those had been predicted by sophisticated forecasting systems enhanced with artificial intelligence.</p>

<p>But forewarned did not mean forearmed. Though the rains were accurately predicted, the effects in the deluged areas were not - a fact that highlights the difficulties of dealing with ever more common extreme weather.</p>

<p>AI has supercharged weather forecasting, using a range of statistical tools to analyse years of historical data and predict patterns, and at a lower cost than traditional numerical weather predictions.</p>

<p>AI technology can create more specific predictions ahead of events such as urban flooding or in complex terrain such as mountainous areas.</p>

<p>For example, Google-funded GraphCast, a machine learning-based method trained directly from reanalysis data, was found to outperform traditional models. Reanalysis data relies on past forecasts rerun with modern forecasting models to provide the most complete picture of past weather and climate.</p>

<p>But there are still gaps in knowledge, in how the information in used and in investment to strengthen data gathering models, experts say.</p>

<p>"In some cases and for some variables, AI models can beat physics-based models, but in other cases vice versa," said Andrew Charlton-Perez, professor of meteorology at the University of Reading in the UK.</p>

<p>One issue is that the effectiveness of an AI model is only as good as the information it is fed. If there is little input data, or extreme events happen more frequently at different times of the year or in different regions, weather disasters become more challenging to predict.</p>

<p>"A good use of the AI-based weather forecasts would be to complement and enhance our forecasting toolbox, perhaps by allowing us to produce larger ensembles of forecasts that enable accurate assessment and interpretation of the likelihood of extreme events," Charlton-Perez added.</p>

<p><strong>COMMUNICATION IS KEY</strong></p>

<p>Since January, the European Centre for Medium-Range Weather Forecasts (ECMWF), an independent organisation that provides predictions four times per day to European countries, has been using the Artificial Intelligence/Integrated Forecasting System (AIFS).</p>

<p>This data-driven forecasting model makes multiple predictions rapidly and delivers long-term forecasts of weather events like cyclones and heatwaves.</p>

<p>The ECMWF readings ahead of the September floods were accurate, experts say.</p>

<p>Thomas Wostal, press officer for meteorological observatory GeoSphere Austria, told Context/the Thomson Reuters Foundation that their numerical models - including the ECMWF's predictions - foresaw 300-400 millimeters (11.8-15.7 inches) of rain locally, which came to pass.</p>

<p>But even with accurate forecasts, scientists say communication is key, especially in an era when climate change means extreme weather is becoming more frequent.</p>

<p>"I think what happened with (the recent floods) ... is that it's so rare - a one in 150- to 200-year event - that even if the weather models capture it, there's a reasonable degree of uncertainty," said Shruti Nath, a postdoctoral research assistant in predicting weather and climate at Oxford University.</p>

<p>"You have to produce the warning in a way that is communicative, in the degree of severity it could possibly have on people, then people could see the cost of inaction versus the cost of action is actually much greater. So then they would actually put (in) more resources," she said.</p>

<p><strong>EUROPE BEHIND THE CURVE?</strong></p>

<p>Europe faces urgent climate risks that are outpacing policies and adaptation actions, a report from the European Environment Agency has warned.</p>

<p>Extreme heat, drought, wildfires and flooding will worsen in Europe even under optimistic global warming scenarios and affect living conditions throughout the continent, the EEA says.</p>

<p>After the floods, the European commissioner for crisis management, Janez Lenarcic, said the disaster was not an anomaly.</p>

<p>"These extreme weather events that used to be once in a lifetime are now an almost annual occurrence. The global reality of climate breakdown has moved into the everyday lives of Europeans," he said.</p>

<p>Some tech entrepreneurs say Europe is not ready.</p>

<p>Jonas Torland, co-founder of Norway-based 7Analytics, which develops models for predicting floods and landslides, said governments and businesses in the United States had risk managers who were more accustomed to assessing environmental hazards, while in Europe, authorities lacked readiness.</p>

<p>"We often see substantial expenditures with minimal data support for informed decision-making", Torland, whose models are used in the cities of Oslo, Bergen and Kristiansand, told the Thomson Reuters Foundation.</p>

<p>"While AI is a crucial component of these models, unfortunately, governments are not investing in or purchasing these advanced AI solutions," he said adding that he believed governments "stick to their old data providers and consultants."</p>

<p>Data processing is also a challenge because these complex AI models need to run updates every hour as forecasts change.</p>

<p>That requires both a lot of computing power, and a lot of time - especially at more minute scales.</p>

<p>A 1-by-1 metre grid, which 7Analytics uses for its predictions, is 100 times more detailed than a 10-by-10 metre grid, but requires more than 100 times as long to process.</p>

<p>High computing power also means huge amounts of energy and water are needed, which makes AI models part of the problem because they are adding to the planet-heating emissions driving the climate emergency.</p>

<p>Some big technology companies, like Microsoft and Google, are exploring the use of nuclear power to run their huge data storage centres.</p>

<p>Other scientists stress that beyond refining their forecasting abilities, authorities need to invest in physical solutions, like developing areas where floodwater can safely be stored, and early warning systems.</p>

<p>They also need to minimise development in flood-prone areas, given the likelihood of more intense climate change-driven floods, and meet their commitments to limit emissions.</p>

<p>"It's not a question of data or technology or knowledge. It's a question of implementation, political will," Friederike Otto, a senior lecturer at Imperial College in London, said in an email response to questions.</p>

<p>"As long as the world burns fossil fuels, the root cause of climate change, extreme weather events will continue to intensify, killing people and destroying homes. To curb this trend, we need to replace oil, gas and coal with renewable energy."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/2m52t4r_flood-in-europe_625x300_15_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A drone view shows a flooded area in Poland taken on September 15, 2024.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-philippines-begin-joint-military-drills-amid-rising-tensions-with-china-6794770]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US, Philippines Begin Joint Military Drills Amid Rising Tensions With China]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-philippines-begin-joint-military-drills-amid-rising-tensions-with-china-6794770]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 15 Oct 2024 16:50:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The armed forces of the United States and Philippines began large-scale joint exercises with key allies on Tuesday that will take place in several areas in the Philippines, including those facing Taiwan and the South China Sea.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The armed forces of the United States and Philippines began large-scale joint exercises with key allies on Tuesday that will take place in several areas in the Philippines, including those facing Taiwan and the South China Sea.</p>

<p>The drills, running until October 25, come after China conducted war games around Taiwan on Monday that drew condemnation from the Taipei and US governments.</p>

<p>The military exercises will involve more than 2,000 American troops and Filipino soldiers and personnel and include island-based exercises in amphibious landings, live fire and humanitarian assistance, the Philippine Marine Corps said.</p>

<p>US allies Australia, Britain, Japan and South Korea are joining the exercises, which are taking place while joint naval drills between the Philippines, Washington and four other countries off the coast of northern Luzon are underway.</p>

<p>The armed forces drills are named KAMANDAG, an acronym in Filipino for "Cooperation of the warriors of the sea".</p>

<p>"KAMANDAG is more than just defence. It is about building trust, fostering cooperation, and reinforcing the partnerships that allow us to maintain peace and stability in the Indo-pacific," Major General Arturo Rojas, Commandant of the Philippine Marine Corps, said at the opening.</p>

<p>Rojas added KAMANDAG reflected the strong ties between the Philippines and its allies and a collective will to safeguard peace and stability in the region.</p>

<p>The Philippines and United States, which are bound by a seven-decades-old Mutual Defence Treaty, have been holding joint exercises for decades.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/gm5dvkh_philippines-south-china-sea_625x300_06_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The drills come after China conducted war games around Taiwan. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/swedish-prosecutor-confirms-rape-probe-without-naming-kylian-mbappe-6793954]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Swedish Prosecutor Confirms 'Rape' Probe Without Naming Kylian Mbappe]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/swedish-prosecutor-confirms-rape-probe-without-naming-kylian-mbappe-6793954]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 15 Oct 2024 15:10:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[On Monday, Swedish newspapers Aftonbladet and Expressen reported that a rape investigation had been opened following Mbappe's two-day visit to the Nordic capital.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Swedish prosecutors confirmed Tuesday a rape probe following media reports that French footballer Kylian Mbappe was being investigated after a visit to Stockholm but did not name the suspect.</p>

<p>On Monday, Swedish newspapers Aftonbladet and Expressen reported that a rape investigation had been opened following Mbappe's two-day visit to the Nordic capital.</p>

<p>"In response to media reports about a suspected rape in Stockholm, the prosecutor can confirm that a criminal report has been submitted to the police," Sweden's Prosecution Authority said in a statement.</p>

<p>It added that the alleged incident occurred at a hotel on October 10, but did not name a suspect and said no further information could be shared for the moment.</p>

<p>Expressen on Monday identified Mbappe as the suspect, citing anonymous sources, while Aftonbladet said Tuesday it had also had obtained information confirming Mbappe was the suspect.</p>

<p>Expressen said Mbappe was "reasonably suspected" of rape and sexual assault, the lower of two grades of suspicion in the Swedish legal system.</p>

<p>Contacted by AFP on Monday, Mbappe's entourage said it had no knowledge of a legal complaint made against him.</p>

<p>The French international was not selected for his country's latest round of Nations League matches, so visited the Swedish capital with a group of people last Thursday.</p>

<p>According to Aftonbladet, they dined at a restaurant before going to a nightclub. Mbappe and the group left Sweden on Friday.</p>

<p>Aftonbladet said the complaint was filed on Saturday after the alleged victim had sought medical attention.</p>

<p>Expressen reported Tuesday that police had seized some clothing as evidence, saying it consisted of women's underwear, a pair of black trousers and a black top.</p>

<p>On Monday, Mbappe himself claimed in a post on X that there was a link between the Aftonbladet report and his hearing before a French league committee on Tuesday, in his bitter dispute with his former club Paris Saint-Germain over what he says are unpaid wages.</p>

<p>Mbappe claims he is owed 55 million euros ($60 million) by the Qatari-owned French champions.</p>

<p>"FAKE NEWS !!!!. It's becoming so predictable, on the eve of the hearing, as if by chance," Mbappe posted.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/n2rlkmc_kylian-mbappe_625x300_15_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kylian Mbappe's entourage said it had no knowledge of a legal complaint made against him.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/one-killed-another-wounded-in-south-israel-shooting-hospital-6793882]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[One Killed, Another Wounded In South Israel Shooting: Hospital]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/one-killed-another-wounded-in-south-israel-shooting-hospital-6793882]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 15 Oct 2024 15:01:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA["A short time ago, two injured people from the shooting incident on Route 4 were taken to the hospital. One patient died on his way to the hospital," the Assuta hospital said in a statement.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>One person was killed and another wounded in a shooting attack near the southern Israeli city of Ashdod on Tuesday, a hospital said.</p>

<p>"A short time ago, two injured people from the shooting incident on Route 4 were taken to the hospital. One patient died on his way to the hospital," the Assuta hospital said in a statement.</p>

<p>Police said officers were at the scene of the shooting near the Yavne South interchange, which is about 30 kilometres (18 miles) south of the Israeli commercial hub Tel Aviv.</p>

<p>"The circumstances surrounding the incident are still under investigation, and the motive has not yet been established," police said in a statement.</p>

<p>The shooting comes just days after one person was killed and five wounded during a stabbing rampage in four different locations in the central town of Hadera on Wednesday before the assailant was "neutralised".</p>

<p>Palestinian militant group Hamas later praised the attack, saying it was a "heroic stabbing operation" and calling "for more painful strikes against the occupation".</p>

<p>And earlier this month, seven people were killed in a shooting and stabbing claimed by Hamas in Tel Aviv.</p>

<p>Palestinian militants have carried out several attacks on Israelis since October 7 last year, when Hamas attacked southern Israel, sparking war in Gaza.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/nhjcdld_israel_625x300_07_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Palestinian army has carried out several attacks on Israelis. (Representational image)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/supermoon-next-full-moon-is-hunters-moon-where-and-how-to-watch-it-6792815]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Next Full Moon Is "Hunter's Moon". Where And How To Watch It]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/supermoon-next-full-moon-is-hunters-moon-where-and-how-to-watch-it-6792815]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 15 Oct 2024 14:33:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The night sky is about to put on a spectacular show this week. The Hunter's Moon, the third of four consecutive supermoons in 2024, will rise on Thursday, October 17.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The night sky is about to put on a spectacular show this week. The Hunter's Moon, the third of four consecutive supermoons in 2024, will rise on Thursday, October 17. The full Moon, apart from being bigger and brighter than usual, also holds significance across cultures and festivals.</p>

<p><strong>The Hunter's moon</strong></p>

<p>The Hunter's moon, traditionally the first full moon after the Harvest Moon, was named by early English and American farmers for the time fields were clear of crops and hunting became easier. The Moon will reach its peak at 7:26 am EDT (4:56 pm IST) on Thursday, but you can expect it to appear full from Tuesday evening through Friday morning, reports <a href="https://science.nasa.gov/solar-system/skywatching/the-next-full-moon-is-a-supermoon-and-the-hunters-moon/">NASA</a>.</p>

<p>Just a day before the full moon, on Wednesday, October 16, the Moon will reach its perigee, the point in its orbit where it is closest to Earth.</p>

<p><strong>Why does the moon appear brighter during a supermoon?</strong></p>

<p>The moon's orbit around Earth is elliptical -- oval-shaped -- positioning it at various distances from the planet, depending on the time of the month and its location along that orbital path. The distances range from about 226,000 miles to 251,000 miles, according to NASA.</p>

<p><strong>When and where to watch</strong></p>

<p>The best time to view this supermoon is just after sunset when it hovers low above the horizon. The Moon will be visible worldwide, but the timing will differ depending on your location.</p>

<p>For India, the supermoon will reach its peak at 4:56 pm IST on Thursday, October 17, and will be visible in the evenings from October 15 through October 18. Stargazers in New Zealand and areas east of the International Date Line will get to enjoy the supermoon early on Friday, October 18, while those in the western United States will see the full moon late on Wednesday night, October 16.</p>

<p>The moon will appear full for around three days.</p>

<p><strong>Cultural significance of the Supermoon</strong></p>

<p>This October supermoon carries significant meaning across cultures:</p>

<ul>
	<li>For Hindus, this full moon is celebrated as Sharad Purnima, a harvest festival that marks the end of monsoon and is dedicated to the moon god.</li>
	<li>For Buddhists, it signifies the end of the three-month Vassa, or Buddhist Lent, observed during the rainy season.</li>
	<li>In Judaism, this full moon coincides with the start of Sukkot, a week-long festival marking the harvest and the journey of the Israelites in the wilderness.</li>
	<li>In Myanmar, it overlaps with the Thadingyut Festival of Lights, a celebration to welcome the Buddha's return from heaven.</li>
</ul>

<p>This October Hunter's Moon will provide the biggest and brightest show of the year, making it a must-see for skywatchers.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-08/dvm5sdbg_supermoon_625x300_01_August_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-canada-ties-hit-new-low-timeline-of-how-relations-soured-after-justin-trudeau-remark-on-khalistani-terrorist-hardeep-singhnijjar-6793267]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India-Canada Ties Hit New Low: Timeline Of How Relations Soured]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-canada-ties-hit-new-low-timeline-of-how-relations-soured-after-justin-trudeau-remark-on-khalistani-terrorist-hardeep-singhnijjar-6793267]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 15 Oct 2024 13:37:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The India-Canada relations nosedived after Justin Trudeau said last year that there was credible intelligence linking India's government to the killing of Khalistani terrorist Hardeep Singh Nijjar.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India and Canada have been dealing with an unprecedented diplomatic crisis after Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau alleged that Indian government agents were involved in the killing of Khalistani terrorist Hardeep Singh Nijjar in Canada. India has rejected Canada's allegations, terming it "absurd" and "politically motivated."</p>

<p>On Monday, Canada expelled six Indian diplomats and consular officials in connection with a probe of the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ndtv-explains-hardeep-singh-nijjar-killing-lawrence-bishnoi-gang-trade-talks-how-india-canada-relations-soured-6793249">killing of Nijjar in British Columbia</a> in 2023.</p>

<p>India has also announced its decision to expel six Canadian diplomats, which include Canada's Acting High Commissioner in India, Steward Ross Wheeler, Deputy High Commissioner in India Patrick Hebert and First Secretary Marie Catherine Joly.</p>

<p>Royal Canadian Mounted Police Commissioner, Mike Duheme on Monday (local time) claimed that they have information on certain criminal activity carried out by agents of the Indian government.</p>

<p>He said, "In the past few years and more recently, law enforcement agencies in Canada have successfully investigated and charged a significant number of individuals for their direct involvement in homicides, extortions and other criminal acts of violence. In addition, there have been well over a dozen credible imminent threats to life which have led to the conduct of duty to warn, by law enforcement with members of South Asian community and specifically, members of the pro-Khalistan movement."</p>

<p>In a statement on Monday, India "strongly" rejected a diplomatic communication from Canada suggesting that the Indian High Commissioner and other diplomats were "persons of interest" in an investigation and termed it as "preposterous imputations" and part of the political agenda of the Justin Trudeau government.</p>

<p>The Ministry of External Affairs (MEA) said Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau's hostility to India has long been in evidence and his government has consciously provided space to violent extremists and terrorists "to harass, threaten and intimidate Indian diplomats and community leaders in Canada".</p>

<p>The <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/indian-expels-6-canadian-diplomats-amid-spiraling-tension-6789267">India-Canada relations reached a new low</a> after Hardeep Singh Nijjar's killing in 2023. However, the history of strained ties between India and Canada extends beyond current events.</p>

<h3><strong>Events That Led To Strained Ties Between India And Canada</strong></h3>

<p><strong>February 2018:</strong> A convicted Khalistani terrorist Jaspal Atwal, who was active in the banned International Sikh Youth Federation, posed with Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau's former wife Sophie Trudeau at an event in Mumbai, during the Canadian first family's visit to India.</p>

<p>Jaspal Atwal was also invited for a formal dinner with the Canadian Prime Minister, hosted by the Canadian High Commissioner in Delhi. However, the invitation to Atwal to Trudeau's reception was rescinded. Atwal was convicted of the attempted murder of Punjab minister, Malkiat Singh Sidhu, on Vancouver Island in 1986.</p>

<p><strong>June 2023:</strong> Khalistani terrorist Hardeep Singh Nijjar was shot outside a Gurdwara in British Columbia's Surrey on June 18, 2023.</p>

<p><strong>August 2023:</strong> A Hindu temple was vandalised in Canada by extremist elements, with Khalistan referendum posters in the late hours of Saturday, Australia Today reported. The incident happened in British Columbia province in Canada.</p>

<p><strong>September 2023:</strong> Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau visited India to attend the G20 Summit on September 9-10 last year. During his bilateral talks with Trudeau on the sidelines of the G20 Summit, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/pm-modi-conveys-strong-concerns-about-anti-india-activities-of-extremist-elements-in-canada-to-justin-trudeau-4377475">Prime Minister Narendra Modi</a> raised "strong concerns" about the continuous "anti-India activities" by extremist elements in Canada, and stated that it is essential for the two countries to cooperate in dealing with such threats, according to MEA.</p>

<p>Even as Canadian PM Trudeau was in India for the G20 Leaders' summit, Khalistani secessionists held a so-called 'Referendum' in Surrey, British Columbia.</p>

<p>Designated terrorist Gurpatwant Singh Pannun was present at the gathering of the Khalistani separatists held at the Guru Nanak Singh Gurudwara in Surrey. He used intimidating language against Prime Minister Narendra Modi, External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar and other leaders.</p>

<p><strong>September 18, 2023:</strong>&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/khalistani-terrorist-hardeep-singh-nijjar-killing-canada-pm-justin-trudeaus-fresh-charge-deepens-diplomatic-row-with-india-4415993">Justin Trudeau</a> made the stunning revelation in the House of Commons that there was credible intelligence linking India's government to the killing of Hardeep Singh Nijjar outside Gurdwara.</p>

<p>In the aftermath, India swiftly retaliated by issuing a statement that denied any involvement in the issue, terming them "absurd and politically motivated."</p>

<p>The Ministry of External Affairs has said that Canada has consistently given space to anti-India extremists. According to the MEA, Canada has not been able to present any evidence to back its claims over Nijjar's killing.</p>

<p>India also suspended its visa services in Canada after Trudeau alleged the Indian government's involvement in the killing of a Khalistani terrorist in June.</p>

<p><strong>October 2023:</strong> Canada pulled out 41 diplomats from India and also halted its visa and consular services in Chandigarh, Mumbai, and Bengaluru consulates in the wake of the Union government's decision to strip them of their immunity.</p>

<p>This came after New Delhi conveyed its concerns to Ottawa over the disproportionate number of diplomats in India and sought a 'parity' in diplomatic strength.</p>

<p>Later in October, India resumed visa services in Canada for four categories after a considered review of the security situation which "takes into account some recent Canadian measures in this regard".</p>

<p>Entry visa, Business visa, Medical visa and Conference visa are four categories in which India has decided to resume visa services in Canada with effect from October 26.</p>

<p><strong>November 2023:</strong> Indian High Commissioner in Canada, Sanjay Kumar Verma said that India is only asking for "specific and relevant" evidence in the killing of Hardeep Singh Nijjar so that it can help Canada in reaching the conclusion of the investigation.</p>

<p>The National Investigation Agency (NIA) registered a case against 'listed individual terrorist' Gurpatwant Singh Pannun over his viral video threatening the passengers flying in Air India and the airlines with a global blockade and closure of its operations from November 19.</p>

<p>The NIA booked Pannun under various sections of the Indian Penal Code and Unlawful Activities (Prevention) Act, 1967. In the video, Pannun urged the Sikhs not to fly on Air India planes on and after November 19 claiming a threat to their lives if they flew on Air India. He also threatened that Air India would not be allowed to operate in the world.</p>

<p><strong>April 2024:</strong> At the Khalsa Day Celebrations that took place in Toronto, loud chants of pro-Khalistan slogans were seen being raised in the presence of Justin Trudeau, as well as opposition leader Pierre Poilievre.</p>

<p>As Trudeau was about to take the stage for his address to mark Khalsa Day, the chants were heard getting louder till he arrived and commenced his speech in the video released by Canada-based CPAC TV. NDP Leader Jagmeet Singh and Toronto Mayor Olivia Chow were also present at the event.</p>

<p><strong>May 2024:</strong> The Canadian Police arrested and charged three individuals in connection with the killing of Hardeep Singh Nijjar. The three individuals were identified as Karanpreet Singh (28), Kamalpreet Singh (22), and Karan Brar (22).</p>

<p>A few days later, the Canadian Police arrested a fourth suspect over his alleged involvement in the killing of Nijjar. The accused was identified as Amandeep Singh (22).</p>

<p><strong>June 2024:</strong> Canada's Members of Parliament from all parties observed a moment of silence for Nijjar.</p>

<p><strong>July 2024:</strong> The BAPS Swaminarayan Mandir in Edmonton fell victim to vandalism. Member of Parliament for Nepean, Chandra Arya, voiced deep concern over the escalating incidents of hate-fueled violence directed at Hindu-Canadian communities.</p>

<p><strong>October 2024:</strong> On October 15, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hardeep-singh-nijjar-killing-bishnoi-gang-canada-bishnoi-gang-linked-to-indian-government-agents-canada-cops-big-claim-6792233">Justin Trudeau</a> accused agents of the Indian government on Monday of engaging in "clandestine information-gathering techniques, coercive behavior targeting Canadians, and involvement in threatening and violent acts."</p>

<p>Citing evidence from the Royal Canadian Mounted Police (RCMP), Trudeau claimed that Indian government officials were involved in activities that posed a threat to public safety.</p>

<p>"As the RCMP Commissioner stated earlier they have clear and compelling evidence that agents of the Government of India have engaged in and continue to engage in activities that pose a significant threat to public safety. This includes clandestine information-gathering techniques, coercive behavior targeting South Asian Canadians, and involvement in a dozen threatening and violating acts, including murder. This is unacceptable," Trudeau alleged while addressing the press conference.</p>

<p>He further claimed that Canadian law enforcement had "made several attempts" to work with Indian counterparts on these matters but were "repeatedly refused."</p>

<p>Canada's Minister of Foreign Affairs Melanie Joly has said that the decision to expel Indian diplomats was based on evidence gathered by the RCMP in the Nijjar killing case and urged the Indian government to support the ongoing probe for the benefit of two nations.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/s8r2bq8_justin-trudeau-narendra-modi_625x300_15_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ndtv-explains-hardeep-singh-nijjar-killing-lawrence-bishnoi-gang-trade-talks-how-india-canada-relations-soured-6793249]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Nijjar Killing, Bishnoi Gang, Trade Talks: How India-Canada Relations Soured]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ndtv-explains-hardeep-singh-nijjar-killing-lawrence-bishnoi-gang-trade-talks-how-india-canada-relations-soured-6793249]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 15 Oct 2024 13:33:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India-Canada diplomatic ties soured further this week after allegations by Canadian federal police that "agents" of Delhi are working with organised criminals to "target (the) South Asian community... specifically pro-Khalistani elements" there.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India-Canada diplomatic ties soured further this week after allegations by Canadian federal police that "agents" of Delhi are working with organised criminals - including the Bishnoi gang linked to last week's <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/how-shooters-used-procession-firecrackers-as-cover-to-kill-baba-siddique-6782217" target="_blank">murder of ex-Maharashtra minister Baba Siddique</a> - to "target (the) South Asian community... specifically pro-Khalistani elements" in that country.</p>

<p>The allegations were preceded by each side ejecting six diplomats, including high-ranking envoys like Canada's acting High Commissioner, Stewart Wheeler, and India's High Commissioner, Sanjay Verma. Delhi later said it was pulling its staff over security concerns.</p>

<p>India issued a stern rebuttal to Canada's claims about its 'expelled' staff being 'persons of interest' in cases of alleged extortion and murder, slamming the "<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.mea.gov.in/press-releases.htm?dtl/38417" target="_blank">preposterous imputations</a>" and the "political agenda" of Prime Minister Justin Trudeau's government before an election.</p>

<p>That was followed by Mr Trudeau holding a press conference - after his police force's claims - in which he backed the cops' charges and criticised "a fundamental error" - that India thinks it can "engage in supporting criminal activity against Canadians, here on Canadian soil".</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hardeep-singh-nijjar-killing-bishnoi-gang-canada-bishnoi-gang-linked-to-indian-government-agents-canada-cops-big-claim-6792233" target="_blank">"Bishnoi Gang Linked To Indian Government Agents": Canada Cops' Claim</a></p>

<p>"Whether it be murders or extortion or other violent acts, it is absolutely unacceptable," Mr Trudeau said, claiming also that his administration had "shared our concerns" with Delhi.</p>

<p>He said Canadian police had spoken to Indian government officials but been rebuffed.</p>

<p>The allegation - that "agents of the Indian government" are colluding with organised crime bosses to target Canadian citizens - is a sharp escalation in the diplomatic row between the two countries, a row that erupted in September last year, when Mr Trudeau accused the Indian government of involvement in the killing of Khalistani terrorist Hardeep Singh Nijjar.</p>

<h3><strong>India-Canada Diplomatic Row Background</strong></h3>

<p>The India-Canada row erupted in September last year after Justin Trudeau's comment about "credible allegation" about "agents" of the Indian government being linked to the killing of Nijjar, a Canadian citizen, was shot dead outside a gurdwara in Vancouver three months earlier.</p>

<p>The "mastermind" of the Khalistani Tiger Force, a designated terror group, Nijjar was high on India's 'most wanted list' for multiple crimes; in July, anti-terror agency NIA announced a cash reward of Rs 10 lakh for his capture for the murder of a Hindu priest in Punjab's Jalandhar.</p>

<p>Responding to Canada's claims India then, as it has since, issued a firm denial, calling the allegation "absurd" and motivated", and pointing out that no evidence had been provided.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hardeep-singh-nijjar-killing-justin-trudeau-doubles-down-on-charges-after-india-canada-diplomatic-showdown-6791322#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">Trudeau Doubles Down On Charges After India-Canada Diplomatic Row</a></p>

<p>The allegations drove already tense relations - in July 2023 India served Canada a demarche asking for action against Khalistani separatists threatening its diplomats, and, in March, there were security breaches at Indian consulates in the United States and Canada - further south.</p>

<p>The Indian government took a very dim view of the attacks and expressed strong concerns about continuing anti-India activities of extremist elements in Canada". The External Affairs Ministry spoke about a "nexus" of criminal activity in that country should be a focus for both sides.</p>

<p>All of this followed an operation by police in India to track down and arrest Khalistani separatist and radical preacher Amritpal Singh, and over 100 members of his outfit, the 'Waris Punjab De'.</p>

<p>Delhi also served a demarche in 2022, asking Ottawa to stop a 'Khalistan referendum' by Gurpatwant Pannun's Sikhs For Justice, another separatist outfit branded as a terror group.</p>

<h3><strong>Trade Talks Paused, G20 Tension</strong></h3>

<p>Days before Canada's unsubstantiated claim about "agents of the Indian government" trade talks with Delhi were paused. Canada's Trade Minister, Mary Ng, then said the talks would remain paused while Mr Trudeau's government investigates the "credible allegations".</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-canada-trade-talks-mary-ng-on-paused-trade-talks-canada-minister-says-focus-on-hardeep-nijjar-case-4581447" target="_blank">On Paused Trade Talks, Canada Minister Says "Focus" On Nijjar Case</a></p>

<p>She did not confirm a direct link between Nijjar's killing and the paused trade talks.</p>

<p>The two nations have been in talks over a trade deal since 2010.</p>

<p>The halting of trade talks came shortly before Mr Trudeau flew to India for the G20 summit, which led to a few awkward moments. These included the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/technical-issue-in-justin-trudeaus-grounded-plane-fixed-delegation-to-fly-out-of-india-this-afternoon-canada-foreign-ministry-4382107" target="_blank">Canadian leader's plane being grounded</a> due to technical issues on the day of his scheduled departure - and the replacement then being diverted.</p>

<p><strong>NDTV Explains |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/india-canada-trade-talk-paused-why-relations-between-the-two-countries-have-soured-4395085" target="_blank">India-Canada Trade Talks Paused. What Happened?</a></p>

<p>Mr Trudeau's India visit also included sharp comments from Prime Minister Narendra Modi about "anti-India" activities being permitted to take place on Canadian soil.</p>

<p>He leader later said his country would "always defend freedom of expression... of conscience... of peaceful protest" but also "always prevent violence and push back against hatred."</p>

<h3><strong>Canada Parliament Honours Nijjar</strong></h3>

<p>In June, in a move that triggered a furious response from India, the Canadian Parliament observed a moment's silence on the one-year anniversary of Nijjar's death.</p>

<p>The Indian government responded with a stern statement, saying it would "naturally oppose any move giving political space to extremism and advocacy of violence".</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/we-oppose-india-on-canada-parliament-honouring-khalistani-terrorist-5938643" target="_blank">"We Oppose...": India On Canada Parliament Honouring Khalistani Terrorist</a></p>

<p>The Indian consulate in Vancouver hit back with a tribute to the 329 victims of the Air India Montreal-London flight bombed by Khalistani terrorists in 1985.</p>

<p>On that subject an Indian-origin Canada MP, Chandra Arya, said the ideology responsible for the terrorist attack is still alive among a few people in his country.</p>

<h3><strong>What Does The US Say?</strong></h3>

<p>The United States - which last month <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/completely-unwarranted-india-on-us-court-summons-over-khalistani-terrorist-6600977" target="_blank">summoned the Indian government</a> after Pannun filed a civil lawsuit, alleging a plot to murder him - has said it is "deeply concerned" by the claims and, in May this year, called on Delhi to take allegations against it "very seriously and investigate".</p>

<p>The Indian government has set up a high-level committee to inquire into the charges.</p>

<p><em><strong>With input from agencies</strong></em></p>

<p><em>NDTV is now available on WhatsApp channels. <a href="https://www.whatsapp.com/channel/0029Va4lixw7z4kcvZI9JM12">Click on the link</a> to get all the latest updates from NDTV on your chat. </em></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2018-03/pm-modi-justin-trudeau-pti_650x400_61519877647.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/over-1000-trillion-elon-musk-breaks-down-cost-of-building-multiplanetary-life-on-mars-6793120]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Over $1000 Trillion": Elon Musk On Cost Of Building A City On Mars]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/over-1000-trillion-elon-musk-breaks-down-cost-of-building-multiplanetary-life-on-mars-6793120]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 15 Oct 2024 13:15:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA["To build a city on Mars that can grow by itself likely requires at least a million tons of equipment, which would therefore require >$1000 trillion," Elon Musk, SpaceX CEO wrote on X (formerly Twitter).]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 1000X improvement in rocket and spacecraft technology can vastly bring down the cost of building a city on Mars, Elon Musk has said on social media, responding to a user's post.</p>

<p>On Monday, X user @WholeMarsBlog posted a graphic explaining the cost of launching to low earth orbit. It said, Today, launching a spacecraft is 10x cheaper than it was a decade ago.</p>

<p>They captioned it When Elon Musk enters an industry</p>

<p>In response, Elon Musk shared a long explainer with a cost breakdown and possible resolution. He pointed out that recent US Mars missions have had a cost per ton of useful load to the surface of Mars of about $1B. Moreover, it has become more, not less, expensive over time!</p>

<p>The increased cost acts as a hurdle in making life on Mars a reality. To build a city on Mars that can grow by itself likely requires at least a million tons of equipment, which would therefore require &gt;$1000 trillion, an obviously impossible number, given that US GDP is only $29T, he added.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Since your handle is Whole Mars, perhaps this lengthy reply is apropos:<br />
<br />
Getting the cost per ton to the surface of Mars low enough that humanity has the resources to make life multiplanetary requires a roughly 1000X improvement in rocket &amp; spacecraft technology.<br />
<br />
Recent US <a href="https://t.co/BdasygYS5q">https://t.co/BdasygYS5q</a></p>
 Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1846001324246319409?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 15, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>However, there is a solution. If rocket technology can be improved by 1000 times, the cost of becoming sustainably multiplanetary would drop to $1 trillion. And if this could be spread over 40 years, the cost would translate to less than $25 billion annually</p>

<p>At that cost, it becomes possible to make life multiplanetary, ensuring the long-term survival of life as we know it, without materially affecting people's standard of living on Earth, he added.</p>

<p>Musk mentioned SpaceX's Starship, designed to achieve over 1,000X improvement over existing systems. Especially after yesterday's booster catch and precise ocean landing of the ship, I am now convinced that it can work, he said.</p>

<p>On Sunday, SpaceX's Starship had its fifth test flight. Starship is referred to as the most powerful launch system ever developed, with the capacity to carry up to 100 people on long-duration, interplanetary flights.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Liftoff of Starship's fifth flight test <a href="https://t.co/D3AvQsRox2">pic.twitter.com/D3AvQsRox2</a></p>
 SpaceX (@SpaceX) <a href="https://twitter.com/SpaceX/status/1845922312207712396?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 14, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The Starship's design demonstrates reusability, a crucial factor in reducing costs.</p>

<p>Building cities on Mars will require affordable delivery of significant quantities of cargo and crew. The fully reusable Starship system uses on-orbit propellent transfer to enable the transport of up to 100 people to Mars or other distant destinations, explains SpaceX.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/jhsp7d2_elon-musk_625x300_21_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Improving rocket technology by 1000X can bring down cost of building a city on Mars to $1T: Musk]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/critics-claim-bath-and-body-works-candle-resembles-kkk-hood-company-apologises-6793040]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bath And Body Works Removes 'Snowed In' Candle. Here's Why]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/critics-claim-bath-and-body-works-candle-resembles-kkk-hood-company-apologises-6793040]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 15 Oct 2024 13:03:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The controversy erupted when a Reddit user posted an image of the candle.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bath and Body Works is facing flak for its Snowed In' candle, which, according to critics, resembles the hoods and robes of the Ku Klux Klan. Following a wave of outrage on social media, the American retail store chain removed the product from its website and physical stores.</p>

<p>At Bath &amp; Body Works, we are committed to listening to our teams and customers, and committed to fixing any mistakes we make  even those that are unintentional like this one, the company said in a statement, adding they were swiftly working to have this item removed.</p>

<p>The Ku Klux Klan (KKK) is recognised as one of the oldest and most infamous hate groups in the United States, as noted by the Southern Poverty Law Center (<a href="https://www.splcenter.org/fighting-hate/extremist-files/ideology/ku-klux-klan">SPLC</a>). Founded in the aftermath of the Civil War in 1865, the KKK was initially formed by Confederate veterans but quickly evolved into a violent organisation dedicated to maintaining white supremacy and opposing civil rights for African Americans.</p>

<p>The controversy erupted when a Reddit user posted an image of the candle, saying, I know it's one of those paper snowflakes, but I can't be the only one who sees it,' right....RIGHT??&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="reddit-embed-bq" data-embed-height="740" style="height:500px"><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/bathandbodyworks/comments/1fywv9b/interesting_design/">Interesting Design</a><br />
by<a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/SkyOk6341/">u/SkyOk6341</a> in<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/bathandbodyworks/">bathandbodyworks</a></blockquote>
<script async="" src="https://embed.reddit.com/widgets.js" charset="UTF-8"></script>

<p>The thread attracted close to 300 responses, many echoing similar thoughts.&nbsp;</p>

<p>People labelled it the klandle or Klan Krismas Kandle. Customers who attempted to order the candle after the controversy erupted reported their orders were cancelled.</p>

<p>An influencer on Instagram, who describes herself as a candle-hoarder, also shared her disapproval. Others defended the design as simply a school snowflake cutout, arguing the outrage was excessive.</p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/DA3pwTLPxKc/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DA3pwTLPxKc/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DA3pwTLPxKc/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DA3pwTLPxKc/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by @_scentsgalore</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p>The candle also <a href="https://www.ebay.com/itm/387477902147?_skw=bath+body+works+candle+snowed+in&amp;itmmeta=01JA5AN7KPZBX99185QA1DJN2P&amp;hash=item5a377b9343:g:pXwAAOSwnotnCp4R&amp;itmprp=enc%3AAQAJAAABAHoV3kP08IDx%2BKZ9MfhVJKltoa2TG8h7SFQRHNfdd8iVB4HkA%2FStq%2FLtzigPW17TnvfcHXlwtFEGv3YvZNok2ibpIdrKMSV9j6VP29e0r7RTOORF%2FEZTUIK%2BkSijYzEJl12Z7ueh873Akldc4gBdyPw2p8vd2mFp0hx%2FVpAkhcEq7j2wSl8oMXRtbL8FtC7DFThYVk8JIWQphwxT5CwZXD9bVjyyoR6J5X5NmPV7f8P4etXxjbWZ%2BHgZu855oRHfhwxa12En0Ofst0lEkuVgMWvc61sr2wbemBKmtNuxw9Hd5E28da3daChP%2FBUVV1eT49O7kFiRNZmMPnWheOQ0lrg%3D%7Ctkp%3ABFBM-PnUqtFk">surfaced on eBay</a>, with one seller listing it for $250 (Rs 21,014). Although eBay's policies prohibit listings that include racist terms or language, the candle remains available since it does not explicitly use racist language.</p>

<p>In 2022, Bath and Body Works faced criticism for releasing a product line featuring Kente cloth designs to celebrate Black History Month. Despite collaborating with organisations such as the National Urban League, the company was accused of cultural appropriation. In response, Bath and Body Works pledged to improve its diversity and inclusion efforts, including a $500,000 donation to support related initiatives.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/7pvl95q8_bath-and-body-works-candle_625x300_15_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Bath and Body Works is facing flak for its Snowed In' candle.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/la-nina-is-becoming-less-likely-australias-weather-bureau-says-6792750]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[La Nina Less Likely, Will Be Weak And Short Lived If It Comes]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/la-nina-is-becoming-less-likely-australias-weather-bureau-says-6792750]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 15 Oct 2024 12:16:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The likelihood of a La Nina weather event in coming months has decreased, Australia's weather bureau said, adding that if the phenomenon did appear, it would be weak and short-lived.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The likelihood of a La Nina weather event in coming months has decreased, Australia's weather bureau said on Tuesday, adding that if the phenomenon did appear, it would be weak and short-lived.</p>

<p>The development of La Nina and its opposite, El Nino, are of huge importance to global agriculture, with La Nina typically increasing rainfall in eastern Australia, Southeast Asia and India and reducing rainfall in the Americas.</p>

<p>"The chance of a La Nina event developing in the coming months has decreased," the Australian Bureau of Meteorology said in a two-weekly update.</p>

<p>The bureau said its in-house climate model suggests La Nina will not develop and four of the six other climate models it surveys now agree.</p>

<p>La Nina and El Nino are caused by the cooling and warming of sea surface temperatures off western South America.</p>

<p>"If a La Nina were to develop, it is forecast to be relatively weak (in terms of the strength of the sea surface temperature anomaly) and short-lived, with all models forecasting neutral values in February," the bureau said.</p>

<p>Other meteorologists have also become less confident that a La Nina will appear.</p>

<p>A U.S. government forecaster said last week there was a 60% chance of a La Nina emerging by the end of November that would persist through January-March 2025. A month earlier, it said there was a 71% chance of a La Nina forming.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/coqofl7_la-nina_625x300_15_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[La Nina typically increases rainfall in eastern Australia, Southeast Asia and India.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korea-blows-up-roads-connecting-it-to-the-south-6792637]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[North Korea Blows Up Roads Connecting It To The South]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korea-blows-up-roads-connecting-it-to-the-south-6792637]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 15 Oct 2024 11:59:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[North Korea on Tuesday blew up sections of the deeply symbolic roads connecting it to the South, Seoul's military said, adding it had conducted a "counter-fire" operation in response.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>North Korea blew up sections of the deeply symbolic roads connecting it to the South on Tuesday, Seoul's military said, adding it had conducted a "counter-fire" operation in response.</p>

<p>Pyongyang's military last week vowed to permanently seal its southern border after spending months laying mines and building anti-tank barriers in the wake of leader Kim Jong Un declaring the South his country's "principal enemy".</p>

<p>The North also accused Seoul of using drones to drop anti-regime propaganda leaflets on the capital Pyongyang, with Kim convening a security meeting to direct a plan of "immediate military action" in response, state media reported Tuesday.</p>

<p>"North Korea has detonated parts of the Gyeongui and Donghae roads north of the Military Demarcation Line," the Joint Chiefs of Staff said Tuesday, referring to inter-Korean infrastructure that once connected the two countries.</p>

<p>"There has been no damage to our military, and our forces conducted counter-fire in areas south of the MDL," it added.</p>

<p>The roads have long been shuttered, but destroying them sends a clear message that Kim is not prepared to negotiate with the South, experts said.</p>

<p>"This is a practical military measure related to the hostile dual-state system that North Korea has frequently mentioned," Yang Moo-jin, president of the University of North Korean Studies in Seoul, told AFP.</p>

<p>The North may also be looking to erect more physical barriers along the border, Yang said, adding that the road detonations could be "preparatory work."</p>

<p>South Korea's military released video footage showing North Korean soldiers in military uniforms ahead of a huge explosion, which emitted thick billowing smoke as it blew up sections of the Gyeongui road.</p>

<p>More footage, apparently from after the blasts, showed excavators digging, while soldiers worked as large red trucks arrived.</p>

<p>The Seoul military also released separate footage showing North Korea blowing up a section of the Donghae road, on the east coast.</p>

<p>South Korea's unification ministry slammed the North for what it called an "extremely abnormal" provocation, adding that Seoul had shouldered millions in costs for building the infrastructure.</p>

<p>"North Korea still has repayment obligations regarding this funding," it added.</p>

<p>China, a traditional ally of the North, called on all parties "to avoid further escalation of conflicts" on the peninsula, a foreign ministry spokeswoman said.</p>

<p><strong>Drone denial</strong></p>

<p>Seoul's military initially denied sending drones north but has subsequently declined to comment, even as Pyongyang has blamed them directly, warning it would consider it "a declaration of war" if another drone was detected.</p>

<p>Later Tuesday, the powerful sister of North Korean leader Kim Jong Un released a statement, saying Pyongyang has secured "clear evidence" that the South Korean military was behind the drones that reached Pyongyang.</p>

<p>"The provocateurs will have to pay a dear price," Kim Yo Jong said.</p>

<p>Activist groups in the South have long sent propaganda northwards, typically carried by balloons, but enthusiasts are also known to have flown small, hard-to-detect drones into the North.</p>

<p>Unlike conventional drones made of metal, the devices they used were constructed from expanded polypropylene, similar to Styrofoam, allowing them to go undetected by both South and North Korean authorities, according to enthusiasts who spoke to local media.</p>

<p>At Kim's meeting Monday, officials heard a report on the "enemy's serious provocation", said KCNA, adding Kim had "expressed a tough political and military stand".</p>

<p>The North has said the United States, which has a military alliance with South Korea, should also be held responsible.</p>

<p>North Korea has itself sent drones southwards -- in 2022, five of Pyongyang's drones crossed the border, prompting the South Korean military to fire warning shots and deploy fighter jets.</p>

<p>The jets failed to shoot down any of the drones.</p>

<p>In July, Seoul said it would deploy drone-melting lasers this year, adding the South's ability to respond to provocations would be "significantly enhanced".</p>

<p>Now, it is a question of whether "North Korea will respond by sending drones into the South or take strong action if drones infiltrate its territory again", said Cheong Seong-chang of the Sejong Institute.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/n6q5kugo_north-korea_625x300_15_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Barricades at a military checkpoint on the Tongil bridge, the road leading to North Korea's Kaesong city.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>