<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Mon, 01 Jul 2024 22:40:28 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/category-4-hurricane-beryl-makes-landfall-on-caribbean-island-of-carriacou-6012213]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Category 4 Hurricane 'Beryl' Makes Landfall On Caribbean Island]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/category-4-hurricane-beryl-makes-landfall-on-caribbean-island-of-carriacou-6012213]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 01 Jul 2024 21:34:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Beryl, the first hurricane of the 2024 Atlantic season, slammed into the Caribbean island of Carriacou, which is part of Grenada, on Monday as a powerful Category 4 storm, the National Hurricane Center said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hurricane Beryl slammed into the Caribbean island of Carriacou on Monday, producing "life-threatening conditions" including disastrous winds, according to US trackers, after the storm strengthened into a powerful Category 4 storm.</p>

<p>With the "extremely dangerous eyewall" moving over the island, which is part of Grenada, the US National Hurricane Center warned residents "not leave their shelter as winds will rapidly increase."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">1200 PM AST Jul 1 Position Update: Extremely dangerous <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Beryl?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Beryl</a> is producing catastrophic winds and life-threatening storm surge in the southern Windward Islands. For the latest information visit <a href="https://t.co/tW4KeGe9uJ">https://t.co/tW4KeGe9uJ</a> <a href="https://t.co/xgMxdNrd5W">pic.twitter.com/xgMxdNrd5W</a></p>
— National Hurricane Center (@NHC_Atlantic) <a href="https://twitter.com/NHC_Atlantic/status/1807805378140475635?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 1, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>The eye of Beryl made landfall on Carriacou Island at 1510 GMT, the NHC reported on X, adding in a bulletin that it was creating "catastrophic winds and life-threatening storm surge."</p>

<p>Posting a video showing large waves, the Office of the Prime Minister of Grenada wrote on Facebook that the tri-island state was "experiencing intense winds and damage."</p>

<p>"This is an extremely dangerous and life-threatening situation," the NHC said. "Residents should not leave their shelter and remain in place through the passage of these life-threatening conditions."</p>

<p>Experts say that such a powerful storm forming this early in the Atlantic hurricane season -- which runs from early June to late November -- is extremely rare.</p>

<p>"Only five major (Category 3+) hurricanes have been recorded in the Atlantic before the first week of July," hurricane expert Michael Lowry posted on social media platform X.</p>

<p>"Beryl would be the sixth and earliest this far east in the tropical Atlantic."</p>

<p>Grenada Prime Minister Dickon Mitchell urged citizens to quickly seek shelter and respect an island-wide curfew ordered for 7:00 pm to 7:00 am Tuesday morning.</p>

<p>Farther northeast in the Caribbean, officials in Barbados said the island was buffeted by high winds and pelting rain, but appeared to have avoided disaster, reporting no injuries so far.</p>

<p>Barbados seems to have "dodged a bullet," Minister of Home Affairs and Information Wilfred Abrahams said in a video, but nonetheless "gusts are still coming, the storm-force winds are still coming" he said, warning residents to remain inside until the all-clear.</p>

<p>Barbados, Grenada, plus Saint Vincent and the Grenadines, and Tobago were all under hurricane warnings, the NHC said, while a hurricane watch or tropical storm warnings or watches were in effect for Jamaica, Martinique, Trinidad, St Lucia, and parts of the Dominican Republic and Haiti.</p>

<p>A state of emergency was declared in Tobago, the smaller of the two islands that make up Trinidad and Tobago, with schools ordered closed on Monday, top official Farley Augustine said.</p>

<p>A meeting this week in Grenada of the Caribbean regional bloc CARICOM was postponed.</p>

<p><strong>Extreme weather</strong></p>

<p>Beryl became the first hurricane of the 2024 Atlantic season early Saturday morning and quickly strengthened to Category 4, the first ever to reach that level in June, according to NHC records.</p>

<p>A Category 3 or higher on the Saffir-Simpson scale is considered a major hurricane, and a Category 4 storm packs sustained winds of at least 130 miles per hour (209 kilometers per hour).</p>

<p>As Beryl struck Carriacou, it was packing maximum sustained winds that had increased to 150 mph, the NHC said.</p>

<p>Beryl is expected to remain powerful as it moves across the Caribbean, the NHC said, warning residents and officials in the Lesser Antilles, Hispaniola, Jamaica, the Cayman Islands and the remainder of the northwestern Caribbean to carefully monitor its progress.</p>

<p>The US National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration said in late May that it expects this year to be an "extraordinary" hurricane season, with up to seven storms of Category 3 or higher.</p>

<p>The agency cited warm Atlantic Ocean temperatures and conditions related to the weather phenomenon La Nina in the Pacific for the expected increase in storms.</p>

<p>Extreme weather events including hurricanes have become more frequent and more devastating in recent years as a result of climate change.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-09/8ujjnk48_hurricane-generic-_625x300_29_September_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Winds will rapidly increase within the eyewall. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-has-some-immunity-from-prosecution-as-ex-president-us-supreme-court-6012125]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Has Some Immunity From Prosecution As Ex President: US Supreme Court]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-has-some-immunity-from-prosecution-as-ex-president-us-supreme-court-6012125]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 01 Jul 2024 21:21:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The US Supreme Court ruled Monday that Donald Trump enjoys some immunity from prosecution as a former president, a ruling that will likely delay his trial for conspiring to overturn the 2020 election.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The US Supreme Court ruled Monday that Donald Trump enjoys some immunity from prosecution as a former president, a ruling that will likely delay his trial for conspiring to overturn the 2020 election.</p>

<p>The 6-3 decision split along ideological lines comes four months ahead of the election in which Trump is the Republican candidate to take on Democrat Joe Biden.</p>

<p>Conservative Chief Justice John Roberts, in his majority opinion, said a president enjoys "absolute immunity" from criminal prosecution for official acts taken while in office.</p>

<p>"There is no immunity for unofficial acts," Roberts said, sending the case back to a lower court to determine which of the charges facing the former president involves official or unofficial conduct.</p>

<p>The three liberal justices dissented, with Justice Sonia Sotomayor saying "never in the history of our Republic has a President had reason to believe that he would be immune from criminal prosecution if he used the trappings of his office to violate the criminal law."</p>

<p>"With fear for our democracy, I dissent," she said.</p>

<p>Trump's original trial date in the election case had been for March 4, well before his November rematch with President Joe Biden.</p>

<p>But the Supreme Court -- dominated by conservatives, including the three appointed by Trump during his term in office -- agreed in February to hear his argument for presidential immunity, putting the case on hold while they considered the matter in April.</p>

<p>Facing four criminal cases, Trump has been doing everything in his power to delay the trials at least until after the election.</p>

<p>On May 30, a New York court convicted Trump on 34 felony charges of falsifying business records to cover up a sex scandal in the final stages of the 2016 presidential campaign, making Trump the first former US president ever convicted of a crime.</p>

<p>His sentencing will take place on July 11.</p>

<p>The New York hush money case was considered the weakest of the four cases by many legal experts, but likely the only one that will see trial before the vote.</p>

<p>By filing many pre-trial motions, Trump's lawyers have managed to put on hold the three other trials, which deal with his attempts to overturn the 2020 election results and hoarding top-secret documents at his home in Florida.</p>

<p>If reelected, Trump could, once sworn in as president in January 2025, order the federal trials against him closed.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/trbnmngo_donald-trump_625x300_02_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["There is no immunity for unofficial acts," said Chief Justice (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/will-not-let-90-minutes-define-4-years-jill-biden-on-joe-bidens-debate-performance-6011464]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Won't Let 90 Minutes Define 4 Years": Joe Biden's Wife On Debate Fiasco]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/will-not-let-90-minutes-define-4-years-jill-biden-on-joe-bidens-debate-performance-6011464]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 01 Jul 2024 20:00:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[She said, "We will continue to fight," and claimed that Mr Biden "will always do what's best for the country."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After a shaky debate performance on Thursday night, political analysts and several US media organisations have been calling for US President Joe Biden to drop out of the 2024 election race. <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/democrats-rally-behind-biden-after-shaky-debate-performance-with-trump-6004687">Democratic leaders rallied behind Mr Biden</a> following his poor performance last week, as the White House denied a report he was meeting with family to assess his candidacy. Now, his wife and First Lady Jill Biden has spoken about the debate and has said that they "will continue to fight".</p>

<p>Talking to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.vogue.com/article/first-lady-jill-biden-august-2024-cover-interview"><em>Vogue </em></a>from Camp David where the family was spending the weekend, she told the magazine "will not let those 90 minutes define the four years he's been president."</p>

<p>She continued, "We will continue to fight," and claimed that Mr Biden "will always do what's best for the country."</p>

<p>Notably, President Biden's age is a particular concern with voters and there have been calls from some Democrats for him to step aside for a new candidate. Despite weak poll numbers and questions about his age, he has stuck to his plan to seek a second term.</p>

<p>On June 27, the 81-year-old's performance in the presidential debate, rekindled calls for him to step away. When responding to a question about the economy posed by a CNN anchor, the POTUS, who is often observed stuttering and freezing during public events, seemed to lose his train of thought. When asked if voters felt "worse off" under his presidency, the Democrat committed yet another error.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, President<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/i-know-i-am-not-young-man-but-joe-biden-after-poor-debate-showing-5994162"> Joe Biden said after the debate </a>that he would defeat Republican rival Donald Trump in the presidential election, giving no sign he would consider dropping out of the race. He said, "I know I'm not a young man, to state the obvious. I don't walk as easy as I used to, I don't speak as smoothly as I used to, I don't debate as well as I used to."</p>

<p>"I would not be running again if I didn't believe with all my heart and soul that I could do this job. The stakes are too high," he said at a rally.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/re7vinl_jill-and-joe-biden_625x300_01_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[President Biden's age is a particular concern with voters.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/artificial-intelligence/gemini-ai-google-ai-after-meta-ai-gemini-ai-rolls-out-inside-google-messages-6010796]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[After Meta AI, Gemini AI Rolls Out In Google Messages]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/artificial-intelligence/gemini-ai-google-ai-after-meta-ai-gemini-ai-rolls-out-inside-google-messages-6010796]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 01 Jul 2024 18:27:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[This development follows Google's recent announcement and the initial introduction of Gemini AI on other platforms like Gmail, according to GSM Arena.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Google has begun rolling out an exciting update to its Messages app, integrating Gemini AI to enhance functionality and user interaction directly within chats.</p>

<p>This development follows Google's recent announcement and the initial introduction of Gemini AI on other platforms like Gmail, according to GSM Arena.</p>

<p>The Gemini AI integration aims to streamline user experience by providing quick access to artificial intelligence capabilities without leaving the Messages app.</p>

<p>Users will notice a new floating action button positioned above the "Start chat" button in the lower-right corner of the interface, facilitating easy access to the AI service.</p>

<p>Although the feature is currently not widely available, Google assures users that Gemini AI functions similarly to its standalone counterpart on Android devices, as per GSM Arena.</p>

<p>This integration allows users to ask questions, receive information, or issue commands seamlessly while continuing their conversations within Messages.</p>

<p>It's important to note that Gemini AI respects user privacy by not scanning private conversations.</p>

<p>However, interactions with the AI chatbot are not end-to-end encrypted, prompting users to exercise caution when sharing sensitive information.</p>

<p>Google also provides options for users to manage their chat history with Gemini, allowing storage customization from default settings of 18 months up to 36 months or as low as 3 months.</p>

<p>Regarding privacy concerns, Gemini AI does not track user location beyond general details derived from IP addresses or home addresses to provide relevant information.</p>

<p>As the update continues to roll out, users can look forward to enhanced capabilities and streamlined interactions within the Messages app.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-12/1o72d03o_gemini-ai_625x300_07_December_23.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Google has announced integration of Gemini AI across platforms]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-woman-charged-with-abusing-and-starving-2-of-her-adopted-children-before-murdering-them-6010354]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Woman Charged With Starving 2 Adopted Children Before Murdering Them]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-woman-charged-with-abusing-and-starving-2-of-her-adopted-children-before-murdering-them-6010354]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 01 Jul 2024 17:30:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[During a press conference, police said they have the forensic evidence to support allegations of torture, starvation, and isolation.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 63-year-old woman in the US has been arrested and charged with killing two of her adopted children after their bodies were discovered inside a burn barrel. According to the <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.independent.co.uk/news/world/americas/crime/north-carolina-mom-charged-blake-deven-death-b2571404.html">Independent</a></em>, two of Avantae Deven's adopted children, Blake and London Deven, hadn't been seen for years.&nbsp;London was last seen in 2019, but&nbsp;her mother never reported&nbsp;her missing. Blake hasn't been seen since 2022, but Deven didn't report him missing until earlier this year.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Authorities in Fayetteville, North Carolina were alerted of the situation in 2023 after one of her surviving foster children made a mental health call to police. When cops investigated the multiple homes the family had lived in, they found remains at multiple residences.&nbsp;Detectives found a burn barrel with partial human remains inside it. Forensic tests revealed that they belonged to a female aged 15 to 19 and a male aged 7 to 10.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Investigators believe that Deven abused the children and ultimately killed and&nbsp;dismembered them.&nbsp;As per&nbsp;NBC affiliate <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.wral.com/story/avantae-deven-given-no-bond-in-first-court-appearance-could-face-death-penalty/21500933/">WRAL</a></em>, London died of starvation and neglect while testing continues on the boy's remains.</p>

<p>More chilling details released by the authorities this week revealed that the siblings, along with three other adopted children, had lived in brutal conditions while in the care of Deven. Blake and London were adopted by Deven in 2013 and 2011 respectively, according to court documents obtained by&nbsp;<em><a href="https://abc11.com/missing-fayetteville-children-blake-deven-911-call-buddhist-retreat/14735061/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">ABC11</a></em>.</p>

<p>They were kept in a small, dark room and given little to no food.&nbsp;They were allegedly able to "earn" food by writing hundreds of paragraphs to apologise for their behaviour. The children told social workers that they were also beaten at times to the point where they would have needed medical assistance.</p>

<p>During a press conference, police said they have the forensic evidence to support allegations of torture, starvation, and isolation.&nbsp;</p>

<p>''We believe he (Blake) was mentally abused and starved. His body could not sustain the inhumane treatment. Then, Avantae developed a plan to hide Blake's remains. She forced another person in the household to participate,''&nbsp;Sgt. Locklear said. London Deven died ''in the same painful way that Blake died, starvation and neglect,'' Mr Locklear added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Deven is now facing two counts of first-degree murder, concealment of death, kidnapping and felony child abuse, according to the Fayetteville Police Department.&nbsp;&nbsp;She is being held at the Cumberland County Detention Center with no bond.</p>

<p>"All of us have soft spots for children and cases with children are the most difficult that we deal with. The fact that this involves allegations of the abuse in the death of children was certainly the thing that grabbed my attention first, particularly how the allegations suggest the way they died,''&nbsp;Cumberland County District Attorney Billy West said.&nbsp;</p>

<p></p>

<p></p>

<p></p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/9gt6g9eo_avantae-deven_625x300_01_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Investigators believe that Deven abused the children and ultimately killed and dismembered them.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-police-shoot-and-kill-13-year-old-who-wielded-replica-gun-6010023]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Police Shoot And Kill 13-Year-Old Who Wielded Replica Gun]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-police-shoot-and-kill-13-year-old-who-wielded-replica-gun-6010023]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 01 Jul 2024 16:54:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Nyah Mway produced what appeared to be a handgun when the police attempted to frisk him.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 13-year-old boy was shot and killed by police in New York's Utica on June 28 after he wielded a replica gun, as per a report in <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://people.com/13-year-old-boy-shot-and-killed-by-police-in-new-york-8671733"><em>People Magazine</em></a>. Around 10 pm, Police Officer Patrick Husnay along with two other officers were patrolling an area where "at least two" robberies had taken place recently. The cops went up to Nyah Mway and another boy, also aged 13, who "were in the immediate vicinity of the previous robbery at nearly the same time of day," based on the traits of suspects in a June 27 crime, according to the release from the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.facebook.com/permalink.php?story_fbid=877233874446674&amp;id=100064802073577&amp;ref=embed_post">Utica Police Department</a>.</p>

<p>The two teenagers were the subject of an attempted citizen stop by the authorities. However, the teen escaped and produced what appeared to be a handgun when the police attempted to frisk him, according to the preliminary information.</p>

<p>The press release mentioned, "In one of the incidents that occurred on June 27th, the suspects were described as one Asian male and one dark skinned male, with one being on foot and the other on a bicycle. Based on the listed identifying factors from the robbery, officers approached Nyah Mway and the other juvenile as they matched the robbery suspects' descriptions and were in the immediate vicinity of the previous robbery at nearly the same time of day."</p>

<p>It added, "When the officers asked and went to pat frisk Nyah Mway, he immediately fled on foot. While fleeing he produced a replica GLOCK pellet gun from the front of his body, and during the 51 and 53 second mark on Officer Patterson's BWC, points the weapon directly at Officer Patterson and the other officers."</p>

<p>According to the authorities, Officer Husnay then shot the teen with his duty firearm. The 13-year-old was transported to a hospital, however, he died as a result of his injuries. The Utica Police Department released<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1Pox0_Tpfyv7Qx0NqSwsXn7x4JrhY9368"> bodycam footage</a> of the incident as well as <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/15uEANYzlhU54NuAoyNnf9FtbwdSfnbzc">pictures </a>of the pellet gun.</p>

<p>According to <em>ABC News</em>, all three cops have been sent on administrative leaves. Further, a vigil was organised after his death. Several people including his family members attended the event.</p>

<p>The 13-year-old's sister, Thoung Oo, created a GoFundMe page to "raise funds for his funeral, legal expenses to seek justice, and family expenses including counselling." She said that her brother "was returning home from an 8th grade graduation barbecue" at the time of the shooting. He was an outgoing kid who loved to go biking and play with his friends and family.</p>

<p>Ms Oo said, "He has never gotten in trouble with law enforcement before, he was a good kid. The UPD video cam, the witness testimonies, and stories they told my family don't add up, especially when they told my parents (who don't speak English at all) that there was a shoot out. We need answers."</p>

<p>Nyah had just graduated from eighth grade two days before the tragedy, according to his sister. She continued, "Because of this tragedy, I will never get to see him grow up. Nyah leaves behind our mother, father, and 3 siblings. Our family moved to America nine years ago as refugees from Myanmar to find a better life safe from law enforcement killings and ethnic cleansing. Our parents and grandparents did not flee war &amp; corrupt military to be persecuted by American police."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/kamqcc2o_us-teen_625x300_01_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Nyah had graduated from eighth grade two days before the tragedy.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/time-for-joe-to-go-former-white-house-photographer-urges-biden-to-drop-out-after-trump-debate-6009960]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Time For Joe To Go": Ex White House Photographer Urges Biden To Drop Out]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/time-for-joe-to-go-former-white-house-photographer-urges-biden-to-drop-out-after-trump-debate-6009960]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 01 Jul 2024 16:48:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[He claimed that White House aides have known for months that Joe Biden's mental health has been deteriorating but they covered it up ahead of the debate.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After a rocky debate performance on Thursday night, political analysts and several US media organisations have been calling for US President Joe Biden to drop out of the 2024 race. Now, the former White House deputy director of photography under the Biden administration&nbsp;has also joined the growing chorus.</p>

<p>In an Instagram story after the debate, Chandler West wrote, "It's time for Joe to go," <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.axios.com/2024/06/30/top-aides-shielded-biden-white-house-debate">Axios</a></em> reported.</p>

<p>"I know many of these people and how the White House operates. They will say he has a 'cold' or just experienced a 'bad night,' but for weeks and months, in private, they have all said what we saw last night—Joe is not as strong as he was just a couple of years ago. The debate was not the first bad day … it's not gonna be the last," Mr West<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://x.com/AlexThomp/status/1807388534069764154"> wrote.</a></p>

<p>He further claimed that&nbsp;White House aides have known for months that Joe Biden's mental health has been deteriorating but&nbsp;covered it up ahead of the debate.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Several unnamed current and former Biden aides told Axios that the president is mentally engaged from 10 a.m. to 4 p.m., but outside of this time frame, he is more likely to have verbal lapses and fatigue.</p>

<p>Notably, President Biden's age is a particular concern with voters and there have been calls from some Democrats for him to step aside for a new candidate.&nbsp;Despite weak poll numbers and questions about his age, he has stuck to his plan to seek a second term.</p>

<p>However, the 81-year-old president's alarming presidential debate performance on June 27, has renewed calls for him to step aside. Biden, frequently seen fumbling and freezing during public events, appeared to lose his train of thought while answering a question by a CNN anchor on the economy. The Democrat made yet another mistake while answering a question on voters feeling "worse off" under his presidency.</p>

<p>If Joe Biden withdraws his name, delegates from 50 states will have to look for a replacement at the earliest.&nbsp;Vice President Kamala Harris, California Governor Gavin Newsom, Michigan Governor Gretchen Whitmer and Pennsylvania Governor Josh Shapiro are among the names that can represent the party.&nbsp;</p>

<p></p>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/257p3v2_joe-biden-ians_625x300_29_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[President Biden's age is a particular concern with voters]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/artificial-intelligence/ai-stock-market-trading-is-ai-going-to-change-the-way-we-invest-in-stock-markets-6009735]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: Is AI Going to Change The Way We Invest In Stock Markets?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/artificial-intelligence/ai-stock-market-trading-is-ai-going-to-change-the-way-we-invest-in-stock-markets-6009735]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 01 Jul 2024 16:20:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence (AI) has made inroads on multiple fronts in our lives. And investing in stock markets is the latest one set to be transformed by advancements in AI.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Artificial Intelligence (AI) has made inroads on multiple fronts in our lives. And investing in stock markets is the latest one set to be transformed by advancements in AI. Retail investors are no longer solely reliant on human analysis by asset managers to make profit-making decisions, with AI revolutionising the investment landscape one day at a time.</p>

<p>According to American consulting firm Mercer, 9 out of 10 asset managers around the world use or intend to use AI in some capacity. This highlights the potential of AI for stock market management, the world's largest investment advisory firm said.</p>

<p>One of the obvious ways AI possesses the capability to reshape investments is the processing of financial data in real-time, giving data-based insights at a speed that's unmatched by humans. AI does not only analyse large data sets, but also recognises patterns and relationships in the data that can easily be missed by the human eye. Investment platforms like Alpha Vantage, Trade Ideas, and Macroaxis have already integrated AI tools to enhance the trading experience for its users, although at a premium charge.</p>

<p>AI can also discover unexpected connections between different financial assets (such as stocks and bonds) and other market determining factors, such as supply and demand. It can analyse non-market factors such as domain traffic for a company website to predict stock market performance.</p>

<p>AI can analyse alternative sources of data such as weather forecast and container ship movements to understand their effect on stock markets. A comparative advantage of using AI is the scalability and speed with which data can be processed.</p>

<p>Algorithmic trading, which uses mathematical models with set rules and human oversight, has been in use since the 1980s. This has been revolutionised by recent advances in AI, with AI algorithms capable of processing data in a much more efficient manner, automating decision-making and minimising human error. AI algorithms excel at processing unstructured data such as news articles and social media sentiments, assessing stock markets in real time.</p>

<p>In India, Zerodha, one of the market leaders in trading stocks, has integrated AI tools to provide personalised trading advice to its users. Other market competitors, like Upstox, have also taken to AI for integrating Chatbots. Indian firms have not yet, however, provided a real-time AI-driven solution for stock market trading. This is mainly due to the expensive nature of this technology, with a US-based web application giving these services at $300 a month for a basic subscription that allows only three daily updates.</p>

<p>Industry trends and demands suggest that India is set to take AI for its growing stock market industry, which recently hit an all-time high in market capitalisation in May this year, standing at nearly $5,000 billion.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/tqpokjj_stocks_625x300_01_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[AI powered stock market trading promises to be more reliant]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/why-europe-is-jittery-over-a-possible-return-of-trump-6009695]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: Why Europe Is Jittery Over A Possible Return Of Trump]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/why-europe-is-jittery-over-a-possible-return-of-trump-6009695]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 01 Jul 2024 16:14:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In Europe, Biden's poor showing, which dramatically increased Trump's chances of being re-elected, has stirred up a lot of anxiety about what a second Trump term could mean for Europe's security and Ukraine's future.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/kjveud4g_trump_625x300_01_July_24.jpg?im=FitAndFill,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>President Joe Biden's shaky performance against his rival, Donald Trump, in the first presidential debate on Thursday has sent shockwaves across both sides of the Atlantic. In the US, a CBS News/YouGov poll on Sunday suggested that 72% of registered voters believed Biden did not have the mental fitness to serve as President. Biden is 81 and Trump is 78, but those who watched the debate would have noticed that Biden made his rival look a lot younger. More worrying for the Democratic Party was that the poll indicated that 45% of registered Democrats wanted Biden to step aside for another candidate.</p>

<p>In Europe, Biden's poor showing, which dramatically increased Trump's chances of being re-elected, has stirred up a lot of anxiety about what a second Trump term could mean for Europe's security and Ukraine's future. A Polish news website summed up the continent's worry: "Trump proved once again that his potential victory is bad news for NATO, Ukraine, and by extension, Poland."</p>

<p>Many Europeans believe that Europe's future without a strong US embrace is uncertain. They fear that if Trump wins in the November Presidential election, Europe's security won't be guaranteed. Trump has said he would end the Russia-Ukraine war, and if it ends with the current status quo, it could be seen more as a defeat for NATO than for Ukraine.</p>

<h2><strong>NATO Summit At A Critical Juncture</strong></h2>

<p>Amidst this anxiety, leaders of the 32-member NATO alliance are meeting in Washington from July 9 to 11 to celebrate its 75th anniversary. But with the ongoing war in Ukraine and Trump's comments in Thursday's debate, there won't be much to celebrate. Trump's views on NATO and Ukraine have cast a shadow over the summit. During the debate, Trump once again chastised European NATO members for not contributing enough to the alliance's budget, an issue that is most certainly to be discussed. Also, the Russian war in Ukraine will be at the top of the agenda, including the issue of Ukraine's membership in NATO.</p>

<p>One of the main reasons European leaders are apprehensive about Trump's potential re-election is his critical stance on NATO during his presidency. He pushed for increased defence budgets among European NATO members. Although this led to some increases, it was often accompanied by harsh rhetoric and threats of withdrawing US support. Many European countries have committed to contributing 2% of their GDP to NATO's budget by the end of this year. With over 3.5% contribution, the US remains the largest contributor to the alliance.</p>

<h2><strong>The Reality Of NATO Contributions</strong></h2>

<p>In his constant complaints about Europe not paying enough for NATO, Trump misses a vital point. The reality is that the US uses NATO to maintain its authority over Europe. Critics argue that America exerts disproportionate influence within the alliance, directing its strategic priorities and military actions, hoping Europe will follow suit. Historically, whether it is the US invasion of Iraq and Afghanistan or bombings over Libya, the European members of NATO have always supported the US.</p>

<p>The US's stand on the Israel war in Gaza is fully supported by Britain and many European members of NATO. Many ordinary Europeans feel that their governments' foreign policy is subservient to the US.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>Europe's Broader Concerns</strong></h2>

<p>Europe doesn't only fear Trump's views on NATO and Ukraine - we might recall that during Trump's presidency, several key international agreements and partnerships were abandoned or renegotiated, often to the dismay of European allies. The U.S. withdrawal from the Paris Climate agreement, the Iran nuclear deal, and various trade agreements created significant rifts. European leaders, who valued these agreements for global stability and environmental protection, are concerned that Trump's re-election would lead to more isolationist policies and a diminished US role in global leadership.</p>

<p>In February, Trump stunned the US political class by saying he would "encourage" Russia "to do whatever the hell they want" to NATO allies who do not spend enough on defence. The statement created a huge controversy, and though Trump's popularity kept growing, it further exacerbated European insecurity. Many fear that Trump's transactional, isolationist, and disruptive style of governance would challenge and possibly destroy the current transatlantic relationship.</p>

<h2><strong>Historical Context And European Efforts</strong></h2>

<p>Trump, however, is not the only president to have questioned NATO's burden on the US. President Dwight Eisenhower also believed that European nations should eventually be able to defend themselves without relying on the US, suggesting that NATO should not be a permanent solution. More recently, a Republican Senator wondered when Europe would learn to stand on its own feet.<br />
Signs of Europe's Efforts to Reduce US Dependence</p>

<p>Trump's potential return to the White House has led Europe to start preparing for a "Trump-proof" NATO. Many optimists in Europe's academic circles believe the continent can become an independent force in a multipolar world, arguing that Europe has the resources to fend for itself. The continent has contributed more financially to Ukraine's war efforts than the US. Many European countries have begun investing in rebuilding their defence capabilities, which they had reduced since NATO began providing security in 1949.</p>

<p>In April, French President Emmanuel Macron advocated for a more independent European foreign policy, saying it was time for Europe to be more united and independent. In a speech at Sorbonne University in Paris, Macron said the continent was "too slow and lacks ambition" and that the 27-member European Union needs to become a superpower, defend its own borders, and speak with one voice if it wants to survive and thrive.</p>

<p>A Europe without the NATO security cover might be music to Russia's ears, but the continent could descend into chaos from internal quarrels if the US were to leave the alliance. Historically, Germany, France, and Britain were often at war, culminating in the two world wars. Since then, it has been peaceful and prosperous, thanks mainly to the US.</p>

<p>But since Trump's last time in power (2016-2020), the European Union has been working seriously on strengthening the Common Security and Defense Policy (CSDP), increasing defence budgets, and enhancing military cooperation among member states. Initiatives like the European Defense Fund (EDF) and Permanent Structured Cooperation aim to develop joint military projects and improve defence readiness. Additionally, countries such as France and Germany are advocating for a more integrated European army to ensure the continent can independently manage its security and respond to potential threats.</p>

<p>As Trump's potential re-election looms, the NATO summit will give Europe an opportunity to seek the security guarantee regardless of who the US president is. But it will be wise to start preparing to strengthen its own defence capabilities to reduce dependency on the US. One can argue that in case Trump is re-elected, it might hurt the Europeans. That is why instead of trying to strike for a Trump-proof NATO, it will be more beneficial for Europe to continue to prepare itself for a US-free NATO.</p>

<p><em>(Syed Zubair Ahmed is a London-based senior Indian journalist with three decades of experience with the Western media)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ovq0gji8_trump_625x300_01_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-origin-woman-24-dies-on-qantas-flight-from-melbourne-to-new-delhi-6009454]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Indian-Origin Woman, 24, Dies On Qantas Flight From Melbourne To New Delhi]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-origin-woman-24-dies-on-qantas-flight-from-melbourne-to-new-delhi-6009454]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 01 Jul 2024 15:41:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The incident happened on June 20 when 24-year-old Manpreet Kaur boarded the aircraft ready to fly from Melbourne to Delhi.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An Indian-origin woman, who was on her way to visit family in India for the first time in four years, died on a Qantas flight just before takeoff in Australia. The incident happened on June 20 when 24-year-old Manpreet Kaur boarded the aircraft ready to fly from Melbourne to Delhi, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.news.com.au/travel/travel-updates/incidents/woman-dies-on-international-qantas-flight/news-story/41934ac049c5f9712e37f3a2680b1e2a">news.com.au</a> reported. However, Ms Kaur suffered a&nbsp;medical episode soon after boarding the plane at Tullamarine Airport.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to a friend, the 24-year-old student reportedly ''felt unwell'' hours before arriving at the airport but managed to board the flight without any issues. But when she&nbsp;went to put on her seatbelt, Ms Kaur fell to the floor and ''died on the spot.''</p>

<p>''When she got on the plane, she was struggling to put her seatbelt on. Just before her flight started, she fell in front of her seat and died on the spot,''&nbsp;her friend Gurdip Grewal told the <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.heraldsun.com.au/subscribe/news/1/?sourceCode=HSWEB_WRE170_a_NEW&amp;dest=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.heraldsun.com.au%2Fnews%2Fvictoria%2Ftributes-flow-for-student-who-died-on-qantas-flight-at-melbourne-airport%2Fnews-story%2Faaa561d3d6ab09d15bcf3533312abdab&amp;memtype=anonymous&amp;mode=premium&amp;v21=GROUPA-Segment-2-NOSCORE">Herald Sun.</a></em></p>

<p>A Qantas spokesman said flight crew and emergency services had attempted to provide medical assistance. It is understood that she likely died of tuberculosis</p>

<p>Her roommate said Ms Kaur worked at Australia Post and wanted to become a chef. The woman's friend&nbsp;Mr Grewal launched a GoFundMe in a bid to raise money for her family.</p>

<p>''Hi, my name is Gurdip Grewal and I'm fundraising for Manpreet Kaur. She was a student from my village and going home. She died in a plane during take-off at Melbourne Airport.</p>

<p>Our dear friend Manpreet left us too soon, leaving a void in our lives that can never be filled. As we grieve her passing, we want to come together to honour her memory and support her family in their time of need. As we say our final goodbyes, every contribution, big or small, brings us closer to our goal. Your support means the world to us and Manpreet's family,'' he wrote.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Victoria Police are preparing a report for the coroner.&nbsp;A Qantas spokesperson told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.news.com.au/travel/travel-updates/incidents/woman-dies-on-international-qantas-flight/news-story/41934ac049c5f9712e37f3a2680b1e2a">news.com.au</a> that their “thoughts are with her family and loved ones”.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/l831esmo_manpreet-kaur_625x300_01_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Her roommate said Ms Kaur worked at Australia Post and wanted to become a chef.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-gaza-hospital-chief-among-palestinians-prisoners-freed-by-israel-6009173]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Gaza Hospital Chief Among Palestinians Prisoners Freed By Israel]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-gaza-hospital-chief-among-palestinians-prisoners-freed-by-israel-6009173]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 01 Jul 2024 15:06:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel released the head of Gaza's biggest hospital, who had been detained for more than seven months, among dozens of Palestinian prisoners returned Monday to the besieged territory for treatment.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel released the head of Gaza's biggest hospital, who had been detained for more than seven months, among dozens of Palestinian prisoners returned Monday to the besieged territory for treatment.</p>

<p>His release was confirmed on social media by Israel's National Security Minister Itamar Ben Gvir and by a medical source inside the Gaza Strip.</p>

<p>Al Shifa director Mohammed Abu Salmiya was detained in November.</p>

<p>Successive raids have seen the hospital where he worked largely reduced to rubble since Israel launched its assault on Gaza after the October 7 Hamas attacks on southern Israel.</p>

<p>Salmiya and the other freed detainees crossed back into Gaza from Israel just east of Khan Yunis, a medical source at the Al Aqsa hospital in Deir el-Balah told AFP.</p>

<p>Five detainees were admitted to Al-Aqsa hospital and the others were sent to hospitals in Khan Yunis, the source added.</p>

<p>An AFP correspondent at Deir el-Balah saw some detainees have emotional reunions with their families.</p>

<p>Israel's military said it was "checking" reports about the prisoner release.</p>

<p>However, National Security Minister Itamar Ben Gvir confirmed the release when he posted on X, formerly Twitter, that Salmiya's release "with dozens of other terrorists is security abandonment".</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="rtl" lang="iw">שחרור מנהל בית החולים שיפא בעזה יחד עם עוד עשרות מחבלים היא הפקרות ביטחונית. הגיע הזמן שראש הממשלה יעצור את גלנט ואת ראש השב"כ מלנהל מדיניות עצמאית מנוגדת לעמדת הקבינט והממשלה.</p>
— איתמר בן גביר (@itamarbengvir) <a href="https://twitter.com/itamarbengvir/status/1807661065464852879?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 1, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Israel has accused Hamas of using hospitals in the Gaza Strip as a cover for military operations and infrastructure.</p>

<p>The operative group, who has run the territory since 2007, denies the allegations.</p>

<p>In May, Palestinian rights groups said a senior Al-Shifa surgeon had died in an Israeli jail after being detained. Israel's army said it was unaware of the death.</p>

<p>The war started with Hamas's October 7 attack which resulted in the deaths of 1,195 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli figures.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory offensive has killed at least 37,877 people, also mostly civilians, according to data from the health ministry in Hamas-run Gaza.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/99q661t_palestinians-released-afp-_625x300_01_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Salmiya and the other freed detainees crossed back into Gaza from Israel just east of Khan Yunis.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/only-conservatives-can-give-tough-fight-to-labour-party-uk-pm-rishi-sunak-6008921]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Only Conservatives Can Give Tough Fight To Labour Party: Rishi Sunak]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/only-conservatives-can-give-tough-fight-to-labour-party-uk-pm-rishi-sunak-6008921]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 01 Jul 2024 14:36:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[British Prime Minister Rishi Sunak will on Monday say only his Conservatives can counter a Labour-led government and that a vote for Nigel Farage's right-wing Reform UK would hamper any chance of his party forming a strong opposition.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>British Prime Minister Rishi Sunak will on Monday say only his Conservatives can counter a Labour-led government and that a vote for Nigel Farage's right-wing Reform UK would hamper any chance of his party forming a strong opposition.</p>

<p>Appearing to all but concede defeat before Thursday's election, Sunak will appeal to those voters on the political right who are considering voting for Farage's party in protest at his Conservative government.</p>

<p>The Conservatives look set to be kicked out of office after 14 turbulent years, marked by Britain's vote to leave the European Union in 2016 and the cost of living crisis that followed the COVID-19 pandemic and Russia's invasion of Ukraine.</p>

<p>Opinion polls have consistently given Keir Starmer's centre-left Labour Party an around 20-point lead, with support for Reform potentially splitting the centre-right vote and the centrist Liberal Democrats further draining Conservative support.</p>

<p>Sunak will say at a rally that Reform "just won't win enough seats to oppose Labour", saying the party had previously said it would be good to get a handful of members of parliament elected.</p>

<p>"Just imagine that: Hundreds and hundreds of Labour MPs opposed by just 'one, two, three, four, five elected MPs'," Sunak will say, according to extracts of his speech.</p>

<p>"A Labour government would be bad for our country, and an unchecked Labour government would be a disaster from which it would take decades to recover."</p>

<p>Farage is one of Britain's most recognisable and divisive politicians. He has spent decades railing against the establishment and the European Union, and has in recent years campaigned for Donald Trump in the United States.</p>

<p>He entered the election in early June, vowing to supplant the Conservatives as the main party of the right.</p>

<p>Polls appear to show that Reform's support peaked in the second half of June, shortly before Farage said the West provoked Russia's invasion of Ukraine. Some of his candidates have been dropped for racist or inappropriate remarks.</p>

<p>While Britain's electoral system means Reform may win millions of votes, the party is unlikely to win more than a handful of parliamentary seats. But that could be enough to split the right in many areas and hand victory to Labour.</p>

<p>Britain will likely elect a centre-left government as much of Europe swings right, including in France where Marine Le Pen's far-right National Rally won the first round of a parliamentary election on Sunday.</p>

<p>With polls showing many voters are undecided, Sunak will make a final appeal for people to limit Labour's power if it gets into government, saying: "We Conservatives will stand up for you and make sure your voice is heard, your values represented."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/2bca973o_rishi-sunak_625x300_27_May_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[UK PM Rishi Sunak vowed to supplant the Conservatives as the main party of the right.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/indians-abroad/indian-origin-woman-charged-in-singapore-allowed-to-visit-kerala-6008823]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Indian-Origin Woman, Charged In Singapore, Allowed To Visit Kerala]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/indians-abroad/indian-origin-woman-charged-in-singapore-allowed-to-visit-kerala-6008823]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 01 Jul 2024 14:23:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A court in Singapore on Monday allowed an Indian-origin Singaporean woman, who was charged with organising a pro-Palestine procession without a permit, to leave the country to visit her grandparents in Kerala.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A court in SIngapore on Monday allowed an Indian-origin Singaporean woman, who was charged with organising a pro-Palestine procession without a permit, to leave the country to visit her grandparents in Kerala.</p>

<p>Annamalai Kokila Parvathi, 35, had organised the procession in February with two others to show support for the Palestinian cause without a permit. A permit from the authority for holding a procession is mandatory according to the law here.</p>

<p>Ms Parvathi, who is currently on bail, had applied for permission to go to Kerala to visit her grandparents there, The Straits Times newspaper reported.</p>

<p>District Judge Lorraine Ho granted the application for Ms Parvathi to leave the jurisdiction, imposing several additional conditions, including an additional bail of SGD10,000, the report said.</p>

<p>Ms Parvathi, along with two others, was charged on June 27 with one count of abetment of organising a public procession in a prohibited area under the Public Order Act. She was on bail of SGD 5,000.</p>

<p>Deputy Public Prosecutor Sunil Nair said Ms Parvathi did not demonstrate the urgency of the travel, but that the prosecution was not rejecting the application because the travel booking was made before the charges were tendered. He asked for additional bail of SGD 10,000, saying that a higher bail amount was sought as she was assessed to be of moderate flight risk, without adding details.</p>

<p>Singapore strictly regulates protests, and public demonstrations advocating causes of other countries are not allowed. The war in Gaza has been a particularly sensitive issue for the city-state that has a significant Muslim population and also maintains a close relationship with Israel.</p>

<p>Though the authorities have urged Singaporeans not to stage protests on the issue and instead participate in dialogues and donation drives, there has been deep concern about the war and some Singaporeans, particularly younger ones, have been vocal in expressing their views online and desiring to make themselves heard.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ijqv2f8o_indian-origin-woman-in-singapore-_625x300_01_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Singapore strictly regulates protests and public demonstrations,]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-political-crisis-why-the-country-has-seen-3-prime-ministers-in-3-years-6008758]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK Political Crisis: Why The Country Has Seen 3 Prime Ministers In 3 Years]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-political-crisis-why-the-country-has-seen-3-prime-ministers-in-3-years-6008758]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 01 Jul 2024 14:14:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United Kingdom will vote in the general election on July 4. A resurgent Labour Party, under the leadership of Keir Starmer, is predicted to win a majority in the House of Commons after a 14-year rule of the Conservative Party.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United Kingdom will vote in the general election on July 4. A resurgent Labour Party, under the leadership of Keir Starmer, is predicted to win a majority in the House of Commons after a 14-year rule of the Conservative Party.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Prime Minister Rishi Sunak urged voters to repose their faith in Conservatives to prevent a landslide Labour victory. Smaller parties like Reform UK, the Greens, and the Liberal Democrats are attempting to capitalise on discontent with the two main parties and attract undecided voters.</p>

<p>The election comes at a critical time for the country. The UK has seen three Prime Ministers in as many years. Before Rishi Sunak took office in October 2022, the UK was plagued by political instability, with Boris Johnson and Liz Truss preceding him.</p>

<p>Mr Johnson was elected the Prime Minister of the United Kingdom on July 24, 2019, and served until his resignation on September 6, 2022. A mass revolt by ministers, sparked by scandals, including Partygate, eventually led to his resignation.</p>

<p>Partygate refers to the political scandal surrounding parties and gatherings held at 10 Downing Street during the Covid-19 pandemic. Eighty-three attendees, including Boris Johnson, allegedly breached Covid-19 social distancing laws. The Metropolitan Police investigated and issued 126 fines, including one to Boris Johnson, for breaching Covid-19 regulations.</p>

<p>Mr Johnson resigned as an MP on June 9, 2023, after an investigation into the Partygate scandal by the Privileges Committee, which he accused of mounting a "witch hunt" against him.</p>

<p>Following Mr Johnson's resignation, Liz Truss was elected as the leader of the Conservative Party and Britain's fourth female Prime Minister after winning the Conservative Party leadership election.</p>

<p>However, she resigned as Prime Minister on October 25, 2022, just 50 days after taking office, making her the shortest-serving Prime Minister in British history.</p>

<p>The Truss government faced criticism for the way it handled the economy, including a controversial mini-budget that led to market turmoil and a decline in public trust. Her leadership was further undermined by a series of U-turns on policy and a loss of confidence among her MPs.</p>

<p>The Conservative Party was in disarray, with some MPs calling for Ms Truss' resignation and others demanding a change in leadership, which led to Rishi Sunak getting elected on October 25, 2022.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/i140sem8_rishi-sunak-liz-truss-boris-johnson_625x300_01_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The UK election comes at a critical time for the country.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-elections-when-rishi-sunak-came-to-power-two-years-ago-6007859]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ahead Of UK Polls, A Look At Rishi Sunak's Rise To The PM's Post]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-elections-when-rishi-sunak-came-to-power-two-years-ago-6007859]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 01 Jul 2024 13:38:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United Kingdom is gearing up for an intense election battle on July 4. The ruling Conservative Party, led by Prime Minister Rishi Sunak, and his rival Keir Starmer's Labour Party are locked in one of the most high-profile electoral battles.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United Kingdom is gearing up for an intense election battle on July 4. The ruling Conservative Party, led by Prime Minister Rishi Sunak, and his rival Keir Starmer's Labour Party are locked in what's said to be one of the most high-profile electoral battles globally.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In October 2022, Mr Sunak, 44, became the first Indian-origin British prime minister and the youngest occupant of the 10 Downing Street in 210 years. This happened after the country went through a major political turmoil, witnessing back-to-back resignations of two former PMs Boris Johnson and his successor Liz Truss.</p>

<p>Ahead of the crucial polls this week, let's revisit the moment Mr Sunak came to power:</p>

<p>In 2015, Mr Sunak was elected as the Conservative MP for Richmond, Yorkshire. A lifelong Brexiter, he campaigned for leaving the economic bloc, and he got his first ministerial berth under Theresa May, as number three at the newly re-named Ministry of Housing, Communities and Local Government in 2018.</p>

<p>Later, he endorsed Borish Johnson for the post of Prime Minister.</p>

<p><strong>2019 UK elections</strong></p>

<p>The Conservative Party, under the leadership of Boris Johnson, emerged victorious in the 2019 elections, bagging 365 of the 650 seats. While Johnson continued as the Prime Minister, Mr Sunak was rewarded with the job of Treasury minister under then Chancellor Sajid Javid.</p>

<p>Later, when Mr Javid resigned from the post over a power battle, Mr Sunak was promoted to the role of Chancellor. This made Sunak the first minister of Indian origin to hold one of the highest offices in the UK government.</p>

<p>Mr Sunak was praised during the COVID-19 lockdown for his series of mini Budgets that introduced measures such as the furlough scheme that went on to save many jobs and businesses. He was even pitted as a clear favourite to succeed Johnson as the Tory leader.</p>

<p>Rishi Sunak vs Liz Truss</p>

<p>In 2022, when Mr Johnson announced his decision to resign as the UK Prime Minister following a mass revolt by ministers over his leadership that was sparked by major scandals, including Partygate, both Mr Sunak and Ms Truss started their bids to succeed Johnson.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Ultimately, Ms Truss went on to win the Conservative Party leadership race and became the new British PM. However, after six weeks amid an open revolt, Ms Truss had to resign.</p>

<p><strong>Rishi Sunak becomes PM</strong></p>

<p>Mr Sunak went on to create history and became the Prime Minister of the UK in October 2022 after Penny Mordaunt, the last remaining rival in the Tory leadership contest, dropped out of the race.</p>

<p>Back then, Mr Sunak reportedly won the public support of around 200 of his Conservative MP colleagues and succeeded Truss as the new UK Prime Minister.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-10/46tnnavo_rishi-sunak-afp_625x300_25_October_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[In 2015, Mr Sunak was elected as the Conservative MP for Richmond, Yorkshire.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/boeing-to-acquire-supplier-spirit-aerosystems-for-4-7-billion-6007898]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Boeing To Acquire Fuselage Maker Spirit Aerosystems For $4.7 Billion]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/boeing-to-acquire-supplier-spirit-aerosystems-for-4-7-billion-6007898]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 01 Jul 2024 12:08:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US aircraft manufacturer Boeing said Monday it had reached a "definitive deal" to buy its subcontractor Spirit, which has faced scrutiny over production quality control in recent months.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US aircraft manufacturer Boeing said Monday it had reached a "definitive deal" to buy its subcontractor Spirit, which has faced scrutiny over production quality control in recent months.</p>

<p>"The merger is an all-stock transaction at an equity value of approximately $4.7 billion, or $37.25 per share," the company said in a statement.</p>

<p>Boeing disclosed in March that it was in talks to potentially reacquire Spirit, which it spun off in 2005 to lower costs.</p>

<p>"We believe this deal is in the best interest of the flying public, our airline customers, the employees of Spirit and Boeing, our shareholders and the country more broadly," said Boeing president and CEO Dave Calhoun.</p>

<p>He said by reintegrating Spirit, "we can fully align our commercial production systems", including safety and quality management systems, and "our workforce to the same priorities, incentives and outcomes -- centered on safety and quality".</p>

<p>Spirit AeroSystems builds fuselages and other significant parts for both Airbus and Boeing.</p>

<p>Boeing is by far Spirit's biggest customer, with around 70 per cent of its revenue coming from the American plane maker in 2023.</p>

<p>The two companies have faced intense scrutiny since a near-catastrophic incident in January when a fuselage panel blew off a 737 MAX mid-flight.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-01/h6rcpqjo_boeing-737-max-9_625x300_07_January_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Both Boeing and Spirit AeroSystems have faced intense scrutiny since the 737 MAX Crash (file)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pritam-singh-singapores-indian-origin-opposition-leader-retains-key-post-in-his-workers-party-6007800]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Singapore's Indian-Origin Opposition Leader Retains Key Post In His Party]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pritam-singh-singapores-indian-origin-opposition-leader-retains-key-post-in-his-workers-party-6007800]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 01 Jul 2024 11:55:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Singapore's Indian-origin Leader of Opposition Pritam Singh has been re-elected secretary-general of the Workers' Party (WP), ahead of the city-state's next general election.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Singapore's Indian-origin Leader of Opposition Pritam Singh has been re-elected secretary-general of the Workers' Party (WP), ahead of the city-state's next general election.</p>

<p>A total of 14 members, led by re-elected chairwoman Sylvia Lim, were voted into the Central Executive Committee (CEC) -- the top decision-making body of the Workers' Party (WP).</p>

<p>Singh, 48, was elected unopposed on Sunday. He has been WP's secretary-general since 2018.</p>

<p>"Fantastic result. We're looking forward to working with this CEC for the next two years," Singh told reporters.</p>

<p>"This wasn't about candidature, this was an internal party election, so my comments will be restricted to that," Channel News Asia quoted Singh as saying.</p>

<p>Media reports say the WP CEC, elected for two years, is set for the city-state's next general election, which has to be called by November 2025 but could be held earlier, sometime in November this year.</p>

<p>Singh was charged in court on March 19 for lying in Parliament about a case involving former WP member Raeesah Khan.</p>

<p>Khan had allegedly lied in Parliament in 2021 over a sexual assault case and accused the police of mishandling the case.</p>

<p>Singh, who has pleaded not guilty to the charges, is set to go on trial in October.</p>

<p>His trial is set for October and November, media reports said, citing court records on May 31.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ot6hbubo_pritam-singh-pti-_625x300_01_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Pritam Singh, who has pleaded not guilty to the charges, is set to go on trial in October.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/entry-fee-issued-for-mount-fuji-hikers-amid-new-crowd-control-measures-6007564]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Entry Fee Issued For Mount Fuji Hikers Amid New Crowd Control Measures]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/entry-fee-issued-for-mount-fuji-hikers-amid-new-crowd-control-measures-6007564]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 01 Jul 2024 11:12:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Mount Fuji's summer climbing season began on Monday with new crowd control measures to combat over-tourism on the Japanese volcano's most popular trail.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Mount Fuji's summer climbing season began on Monday with new crowd control measures to combat over-tourism on the Japanese volcano's most popular trail.</p>

<p>An entry fee of 2,000 yen ($13) plus an optional donation is being charged for those taking on the Yoshida Trail, and numbers are capped at 4,000 per day.</p>

<p>Online reservations have also been introduced this year by authorities concerned about safety and environmental damage on Japan's highest mountain.</p>

<p>"I really like the idea because if you respect the mountain, you have to limit the people," hiker Chetna Joshi told AFP at the trail's Fifth Station -- a busy starting point for hikers that is reachable by car.</p>

<p>The 47-year-old from India compared the crowds seen at Fuji in recent years to the "traffic jam" of climbers at the peak of Mount Everest.</p>

<p>Although windy and drizzly weather on Monday prevented hikers from reaching the summit, Joshi said ascending part way was still a "great experience".</p>

<p>"I love mountains. I think it is not giving me permission this time, that's OK. I accept it," she said.</p>

<p>Record tourist crowds are flocking to Japan post-pandemic, with many wanting to see or scale Mount Fuji.</p>

<p>The mountain is covered in snow most of the year but draws more than 220,000 visitors each July-September climbing period.</p>

<p>Many trudge through the night to see the sunrise from the 3,776-metre (12,388-foot) summit.</p>

<p>Some sleep on the trail or start fires for heat, while others attempt to complete the hike without breaks, becoming sick or injured as a result.</p>

<h3><strong>&nbsp;'Crazy adventure'&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>The once-peaceful pilgrimage site has three other main routes that will remain free to climb.</p>

<p>But the Yoshida Trail -- accessed from Tokyo relatively easily -- is the preferred option for most holidaymakers, with around 60 per cent of climbers choosing that route.</p>

<p>Each summer, reports in Japanese media describe tourists climbing Mount Fuji with insufficient mountaineering equipment.</p>

<p>The new measures were introduced "first and foremost to protect lives", governor Kotaro Nagasaki of Yamanashi prefecture has said.</p>

<p>In a reminder of the dangers, last week four bodies were found near the summit, according to local media reports.</p>

<p>"I personally feel like I've over-prepared," Geoffrey Kula, a climber from the United States, told AFP.</p>

<p>"Having looked at the forecast, being ready to swap out multiple outfits if clothes get wet and things like that. Yeah, it just seems like another crazy adventure."</p>

<h3><strong>Tourist hotspot&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Monthly visitors to Japan exceeded three million for the first time in March, and then again in April and May.</p>

<p>The tourism chief has deemed the country's ambitious goal of attracting 60 million foreign tourists well within reach, having last year welcomed more than 25 million.</p>

<p>Mount Fuji is about two hours from central Tokyo by train and can be seen for miles around.</p>

<p>The mountain is a symbol of Japan that has been immortalised in countless artworks, including Hokusai's "Great Wave".</p>

<p>But as in other tourist hotspots, such as Venice -- which recently launched a trial of entry fees for day visitors -- the influx has not been universally welcomed.</p>

<p>In May, a town near Mount Fuji mounted a large barrier at a popular viewing spot for the volcano in an attempt to deter photo-taking by an ever-growing number of tourists.</p>

<p>Residents were fed up with streams of mostly foreign visitors littering, trespassing and breaking traffic rules in their hunt for a photo to share on social media.</p>

<p>Similar woes have befallen the country's ancient capital of Kyoto, where locals have complained of tourists harassing the city's famed geisha.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/dbsr1r1_mt-fuji-tourists-reuters_625x300_01_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Monthly visitors to Japan exceeded 3 million first in March, and then again in April and May.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sampat-shivangi-indian-american-physician-elected-official-delegate-to-republican-convention-6007173]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Indian-American Physician To Be Official Delegate To Republican Convention]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sampat-shivangi-indian-american-physician-elected-official-delegate-to-republican-convention-6007173]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 01 Jul 2024 10:04:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Eminent Indian-American physician Dr Sampat Shivangi has been elected as an official delegate to the Republican National Convention in Milwaukee this month.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Eminent Indian-American physician Dr Sampat Shivangi has been elected as an official delegate to the Republican National Convention in Milwaukee this month that would formally nominate former US president Donald Trump as the party's presidential candidate.</p>

<p>Trump, 78, is the presumptive Republican Party candidate for the presidential election.</p>

<p>An influential Indian-American community leader, Dr Shivangi, has been elected as a National Delegate at the convention for the sixth time.</p>

<p>"It is a great pleasure and honour to share the news that I have been nominated and elected as (an) official delegate at the upcoming Republican National Convention to be held in Milwaukee, Wisconsin, from July 13 to July 19, 2024," Dr Shivangi said.</p>

<p>The four-day Republican National Convention (RNC) in Milwaukee, Wisconsin, would formally nominate Trump as the party's candidate for the November 5 presidential election.</p>

<p>The nomination process would be completed by Republican delegates from across the country.</p>

<p>Dr Shivangi, a lifelong member of the Republican Party and a founding member of the Republican Indian Council and the Republican Indian National Council, has been nominated as RNC delegate six consecutive times.</p>

<p>"This will be my sixth time serving as a National Delegate at the Republican National Convention to nominate the Republican Party nominee to contest the national presidential election," he said.</p>

<p>"My nomination began as early as when President George W Bush was nominated in New York, then-Senator George McCain, Governor Mitt Romney, (and) President Donald Trump in 2016 and 2020. Now again to re-elect President Donald Trump in 2024 in Milwaukee," he said.</p>

<p>He is the national president of the Indian American Forum for Political Education, one of the oldest Indian American Associations.</p>

<p>Over the past three decades, he has lobbied for several bills in the US Congress on behalf of India through his enormous contacts with US Senators and Congressmen.</p>

<p>"I feel this is a unique honour and an opportunity for an Indian American to represent the community at the national level," he said.</p>

<p>Dr Shivangi said he would be part of the luncheon hosted by Governor Tate Reeves of Mississippi in honour of the delegates at Northern Lights in Milwaukee, Wisconsin, on July 16, for the Mississippi delegates</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/mbde5b5o_dr-sampat-shivangi-linkedin-_625x300_01_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Dr Sampat Shivangi is a founding member of the Republican Indian Council.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ashwin-ramaswami-first-gen-z-indian-american-candidate-for-georgia-senate-gets-big-boost-6007039]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[First Gen Z Indian-American Candidate For Georgia Senate Gets Big Boost]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ashwin-ramaswami-first-gen-z-indian-american-candidate-for-georgia-senate-gets-big-boost-6007039]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 01 Jul 2024 09:37:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US Presidential elections: Ashwin Ramaswami, the first Gen-Z Indian-American candidate to run for a US state legislature, has been endorsed by US Senator Jon Ossoff for the Georgia state Senate seat.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ashwin Ramaswami, the first Gen-Z Indian-American candidate to run for a US state legislature, has been endorsed by US Senator Jon Ossoff for the Georgia state Senate seat.</p>

<p>Ramaswami, 24, is contesting in the Democratic Party for State Senate in District 48 in the US state of Georgia.</p>

<p>The endorsement is seen as a big boost to his maiden campaign against incumbent State Senator Shawn Still, a Republican, who has been indicted for trying to overturn the 2020 election results in Georgia.</p>

<p>Still was indicted with former president Donald Trump for the January 6, 2021, insurrection at the US Capitol.</p>

<p>"Ashwin Ramaswami would be a tireless advocate for democracy and his constituents in the Georgia State Senate," said Senator Ossoff.</p>

<p>"The contrast could not be clearer: Ashwin is a former election security expert, and he is running against a MAGA (Make American Great Again) politician alleged to have participated in an effort to steal the 2020 election when Raphael Warnock and I were on the ballot," he said.</p>

<p>"It's not an exaggeration to say that democracy is on the ballot in Senate District 48. We need Ashwin in the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ashwin-ramaswami-becomes-first-gen-z-indian-american-running-for-georgia-senate-seat-5085435">State Senate</a> - and I'm proud to stand behind him in this race," Ossoff said.</p>

<p>Thanking the Senator for the endorsement, Ramaswami said, "From delivering billions in Georgia infrastructure upgrades to tackling climate change to strengthening our cybersecurity - Senator Ossoff has been a champion for Georgia." "But those successes only go so far if they're eroded by far-right Republicans like my opponent at the state level," he said.</p>

<p>"I'm so grateful to earn Senator Ossoff's support, and I look forward to working with him in the fight to expand healthcare access, invest in housing options, and protect our elections from extremists who seek to undermine them," he added.</p>

<p>Senator Ossoff is a member of the Senate Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs (HSGAC), which oversees the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA).</p>

<p>Ramaswami left his job in election security at CISA to run against Still.</p>

<p>According to the latest finance report, he has outraised his opponent, raising more than USD 280,000 in his grassroots campaign.</p>

<p>Ramaswamy graduated from Georgetown University in May. If elected, he would be the youngest ever elected representative in the State of Georgia and the first Indian American to win this position in Georgia.</p>

<p>Ramaswami's parents immigrated to the US from Tamil Nadu in 1990. Generation Z (also known as Zoomers) encompasses those born between 1997 and 2012.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/stuhsvl_ashwin-ramaswami-x_625x300_01_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Ashwin Ramaswami, 24, is contesting for State Senate in Georgia for US Elections 2024.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>