<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Wed, 20 Nov 2024 21:15:23 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/we-cant-support-unconditional-us-vetoes-gaza-ceasefire-call-at-un-7065762]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["We Can't Support Unconditional...": US Vetoes Gaza Ceasefire Call At UN]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/we-cant-support-unconditional-us-vetoes-gaza-ceasefire-call-at-un-7065762]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 20 Nov 2024 20:59:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United States on Wednesday vetoed a UN Security Council push to call for a ceasefire in Gaza that Washington said would have emboldened Hamas.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United States on Wednesday vetoed a UN Security Council push to call for a ceasefire in Gaza that Washington said would have emboldened Hamas.</p>

<p>"We made clear throughout negotiations we could not support an unconditional ceasefire that failed to release the hostages," said US Ambassador to the United Nations Robert Wood.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/1qvfgfig_gaza-reuters_625x300_28_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/after-us-missile-ukraine-fires-uks-storm-shadow-into-russia-report-7065709]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[After US Missile, Ukraine Fires UK's 'Storm Shadow' Into Russia: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/after-us-missile-ukraine-fires-uks-storm-shadow-into-russia-report-7065709]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 20 Nov 2024 20:50:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ukraine's armed forces fired British cruise missiles at military targets inside Russia for the first time, a Western official familiar with the matter said, as the 1,000-day conflict enters a new phase.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ukraine's armed forces fired British cruise missiles at military targets inside Russia for the first time, a Western official familiar with the matter said, as the 1,000-day conflict enters a new phase.</p>

<p>The UK approved the use of Storm Shadow missiles in response to Russia deploying North Korean troops in its war against Ukraine, a move the British government considered to be an escalation, according to the person, who spoke on condition of anonymity because of the sensitivity of the matter.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The issue dominated the Group of 20 leaders' summit in Brazil this week after US President Joe Biden gave the go-ahead for Ukraine to fire long-range ATACMS missiles at Russian targets. But Starmer didn't publicly back the move, despite long being seen as an advocate, leading to questions about whether his government would allow the use of British-made Storm Shadows.</p>

<p>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskiy has long called for Western governments to bolster military support, including allowing the use of long-range missiles to hit targets in Russia that are crucial to Vladimir Putin's war effort.</p>

<p>Storm Shadow debris was found in Russia's Kursk region to the north of Ukraine and two missiles were intercepted over Yeysk, a Black Sea port in the southern Krasnodar region, according to the Telegram channel Rybar, which has connections to the army and more than 1.3 million subscribers. The information couldn't be independently verified.</p>

<p>US Treasuries pared declines after the latest missile launch was announced.</p>

<p>It comes a day after the Russian Defense Ministry said Ukraine had used Western-supplied ATACMS for the first time to strike a military facility inside Russia.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/jcghstvc_storm-shadow-missile-ukraine_625x300_13_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Storm Shadow debris was found in Russia's Kursk region to the north of Ukraine.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-un-watchdog-said-on-israels-claim-of-destroying-irans-secret-nuke-site-7065603]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What UN Watchdog Said About Israel Destroying Iran's 'Top Secret Nuke Site']]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-un-watchdog-said-on-israels-claim-of-destroying-irans-secret-nuke-site-7065603]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 20 Nov 2024 20:31:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[UN nuclear watchdog chief Rafael Grossi said Wednesday that the agency did not consider Iran's Parchin site "a nuclear facility" after Israel claimed it hit Tehran's nuclear programme in a strike last month.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>UN nuclear watchdog chief Rafael Grossi said Wednesday that the agency did not consider Iran's Parchin site "a nuclear facility" after Israel claimed it hit Tehran's nuclear programme in a strike last month.</p>

<p>"We don't have any information that would confirm (the) presence of nuclear material" in Parchin, even though the site "could have been involved in the past in some activities," Grossi told reporters&nbsp;in Vienna.</p>

<p>"But as far as the IAEA is concerned, we do not see this as a nuclear facility," he said.</p>

<p>"I leave it to those military decision makers to judge and characterise places," he added.</p>

<p>On Monday, Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said that Israel's late October attack on Iran damaged "a component" of the Islamic Republic's nuclear programme.&nbsp;</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Image Posted On X By @TheGoodISIS" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/famt62ko_iran-top-secret-nuclear-site-parchin-taleghan-twitter_625x300_20_November_24.jpg" title="Image Posted On X By @TheGoodISIS" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><small><em>Image Posted On X By @TheGoodISIS</em></small></p>
</div>

<p>"It has been published that a certain component of their nuclear programme was hit in this attack," Netanyahu told the Israeli parliament.</p>

<p>"The programme itself and its ability to operate here have not yet been thwarted," he added.</p>

<p>US news portal Axios reported that the attack on Iran had "destroyed an active<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-military-destroys-top-secret-iranian-nuclear-weapons-lab-report-7033453" target="_blank"> top secret nuclear weapons research facility</a> in Parchin", quoting unidentified US and Israeli officials.</p>

<p>The site is some 50 kilometres (31 miles) southeast of Tehran.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Israel has repeatedly accused Iran of wanting to acquire an atomic bomb, a claim Tehran has denied.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/fl16v0vg_iran-to-secret-nuclear-site-parchin-taleghan-twitter_625x300_20_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel has repeatedly accused Iran of wanting to acquire an atomic bomb]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/google-may-be-forced-to-sell-its-chrome-browser-heres-why-7065231]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Google May Be Forced To Sell Its Chrome Browser. Here's Why]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/google-may-be-forced-to-sell-its-chrome-browser-heres-why-7065231]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 20 Nov 2024 19:41:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The US Department of Justice (DoJ) reportedly wants the court to order Alphabet Inc. to sell off the Chrome browser to dismantle the monopoly Google has over the internet search market and related advertising.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Alphabet Inc.'s Google might have to sell Chrome, the world's most widely used browser. The US Department of Justice (DoJ) reportedly wants the court to order Alphabet Inc. to sell off the browser to dismantle the monopoly Google has over the internet search market and related advertising. Google, meanwhile, said that if it is forced to sell Chrome, the move would harm its consumers and businesses.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Last month, the Department of Justice filed papers in the court saying it was considering enforcing "structural remedies" to prevent Google from using some of its products. On Wednesday, the antitrust enforcers will propose the measure to a judge, according to a report by Bloomberg.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Chrome holds almost 90 per cent share of the global search engine market as of October, according to StatCounter. Moreover, it controls about 61 per cent of the US market.</p>

<h2><strong>Case Against Google's Monopoly</strong></h2>

<p>The DoJ brought the case against Google during US president-elect Donald Trump's first four-year term. In a landmark ruling in August, Judge Amit Mehta ruled that Google operates an online search monopoly and has been considering what remedies or penalties to impose.</p>

<p>Since then, prosecutors have suggested several potential ways forward in the case, including ending billions of dollars with exclusive agreements that Google has with Apple and other companies to remain the default search engine on their tablets and smartphones, and divesting parts of its business, such as its Android operating system.</p>

<p>On Wednesday, the DoJ is likely to go ahead with several of those proposals, including one that requires Google to divest its Chrome browser. The antitrust officials, along with states that have joined the case, are also planning to recommend that federal judge Amit Mehta impose data licensing requirements on Google, the Bloomberg reported quoting sources.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Should a sale proceed, Chrome would be worth "at least USD 15 - USD 20 billion, given it has over 3 billion monthly active users," according to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://mercury.bloomberg.com/news/SN5JQ9DWRGG000" rel="No Follow, No Index" target="_blank">Bloomberg </a>Intelligence analyst Mandeep Singh.&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>Google's Response</strong></h3>

<p>Google has called the proposal 'radical' and said it would harm its consumers and businesses in the US and also shake American competitiveness in artificial intelligence.</p>

<p>Previously, the company has denied operating a monopoly in the online search market. Responding to the DoJ's filing in October, Google has said that "splitting off" parts of its business like Chrome or Android would "break them".</p>

<p>"Breaking them off would change their business models, raise the cost of devices, and undermine Android and Google Play in their robust competition with Apple's iPhone and App Store," <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cy4g193qezno" rel="No Follow, No Index" target="_blank">BBC </a>quoted the company as saying.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Now, Google is reportedly planning an appeal after US District Judge Amit Mehta makes his final ruling by August 2025. The company will have a chance to make its proposal in December.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/k09plus8_google-reuters_625x300_20_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Google Chrome holds almost 90 per cent share of the global search engine market]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trumps-return-bringing-china-india-closer-india-us-advocacy-group-head-7065111]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump's Return Bringing India-China Closer: India-US Advocacy Group Head]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trumps-return-bringing-china-india-closer-india-us-advocacy-group-head-7065111]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 20 Nov 2024 19:26:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[During his presidential election campaign, Trump proposed a 60 per cent tariff on goods from China -- and a tariff of up to 20 per cent on every other US import.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>China is trying to improve ties with India in an attempt to ease pressure from the incoming Trump administration, the head of a top India-centric US business advocacy and strategic group said on Tuesday.</p>

<p>During his presidential election campaign, Trump proposed a 60 per cent tariff on goods from China -- and a tariff of up to 20 per cent on every other US import.</p>

<p>Mukesh Aghi, president of the US-India Strategic and Partnership Forum (USISPF), said: "So, we are seeing an early impact of the Trump administration coming in that has created pressure on China to ease dealing with India. So that's why border patrolling has been agreed upon. Direct flights have been agreed upon."</p>

<p>"They will also issue more visas to Chinese coming to India. You are seeing the impact of Trump coming in having a positive impact on the India-China relationship," he further said.</p>

<p>Last month, India announced that it had reached an agreement with China on patrolling along the Line of Actual Control (LAC) in eastern Ladakh, in a breakthrough in ending the over four-year-long military standoff.</p>

<p>"The calculation on the part of the Chinese was that Trump was coming in. The relationship with the US will get stressful. So, why have multiple fronts of this stressful relationship? 'Let's at least ease the partnership or potential relationship with India itself'," Aghi told PTI in an interview.</p>

<p>India is likely to play an important role in Trump's "America First" policy by offering a place for secure sourcing while the new administration plans to move manufacturing away from China and create jobs in the US, he added.</p>

<p>"Efforts by the Trump administration to put in tariffs so it can put pressure on companies to move manufacturing back to the US, it's not going to happen overnight. It took almost 40 years for manufacturing to move out of the US. The challenge we have is we don't have enough skills. We don't have enough manpower to help us from that perspective. So, the transition will take time," Aghi said.</p>

<p>"That's where India can play a pivotal role by saying, 'Yes, we'll help you move manufacturing back to the US but we will also manufacture a lot of these components in India' and they become part of the global supply chain. It helps you because you're not dependent geopolitically on a risk factor in China but you depend on a friend. I see the concept of secure sourcing becoming much more pivotal and stronger than outsourcing or friend-shoring itself," the USISPF boss added.</p>

<p>"You will see India's role becoming much more pivotal as you look at building America first. At the same time, Atmanirbhar Bharat also within that supply chain becomes very critical," he said.</p>

<p>Aghi also claimed that corporate America was "very happy" with the election results.</p>

<p>"They feel Trump understands how challenging it is to run and grow businesses. He will hopefully bring the taxes down for corporations, which will help them to become much more profitable and grow the business itself. The corporate community welcomes the new administration, which is the Trump administration," he said.</p>

<p>"The market has gone up. What's interesting is also that the dollar has become stronger. That shows the confidence in the incoming administration by corporate America," Aghi said.</p>

<p>Responding to a question on the impact of the elections on the India-US relationship, the business leader said it was not just dependent on administrations.</p>

<p>"It is dependent on the geopolitical alignment between the two countries. It's dependent on economics. It's dependent on trade. It's dependent on people to people. When you look at geopolitics, India-US is aligned, especially with China itself," he said.</p>

<p>"We are seeing a tremendous amount of activities taking place between the two countries, under the umbrella of Quad with Japan and Australia. On the trade side, you have USD 200 billion in trade, which is expected to keep growing. On the technology side, what we're seeing is Indians are building a lot of US technology in India itself. The global capability centres are generating a substantial amount of IP (intellectual property) for US companies," said the USISPF chief.</p>

<p>Aghi also said the five million Indian-Americans generated almost 6 per cent of the US's GDP while only being 1 per cent of the population.</p>

<p>"The Trump administration will come in looking at how you create jobs in the US. That's where India has to play a very strong role by saying, 'Yes, we will support the US plus one strategy'. Will that interfere with India's strategy of Atmanirbhar Bharat? No. I think both can coexist and support each other for mutual success," he noted.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ujo0i4l_modi-xi-jinping-reuters_625x300_20_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[China is trying to improve ties with India in an attempt to ease pressure from the Trump administration]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/vladimir-putins-chilling-new-nuclear-doctrine-what-it-says-7065052]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Vladimir Putin's Chilling New Nuclear Doctrine - What It Says]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/vladimir-putins-chilling-new-nuclear-doctrine-what-it-says-7065052]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 20 Nov 2024 19:18:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Titled "Basic Principles of State Policy on Nuclear Deterrence", Vladimir Putin approved changes to the nuclear doctrine on Tuesday, chilling rules by which the country would now use its atomic arsenal.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Titled "Basic Principles of State Policy on Nuclear Deterrence", Vladimir Putin approved changes to the nuclear doctrine on Tuesday, chilling rules by which the country would now use its atomic arsenal.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The big change in the doctrine now says that an attack from a non-nuclear state backed by a nuclear state will be viewed by Russia as a joint attack on it.</p>

<p>Although the new changes were proposed in September, the document was approved only on Tuesday - which was coincidentally the 1,000th day of the Russo-Ukrainian War.</p>

<p>This development took place after the Biden administration had made a significant policy change, allowing Ukraine to use US-made ATACMS missiles to strike targets inside Russia for the first time.</p>

<p>This decision came just two months before President Joe Biden hands over power to Donald Trump, who has expressed scepticism about US military aid to Ukraine.</p>

<p>Now, even a large attack with missiles, drones or aircraft could be met with a nuclear response. The nuclear doctrine will also be extended to Russia's close ally Belarus.</p>

<p>Moreover, any attack from a state which is a member of a coalition would be seen as aggression from the entire group.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Although Putin has threatened to use nuclear weapons earlier, Ukraine has dismissed it as "nuclear sabre-rattling" to discourage its allies from providing support.</p>

<p>However, Sergey Lavrov, Russia's Foreign Minister has said that "we strongly are in favour of doing everything to not allow nuclear war to happen".</p>

<p>Russia has signed a declaration at the G20 Summit in Rio de Janeiro along with the other countries, about which Lavrov said, "clearly said we want to move towards a world free of nuclear weapons".</p>

<p>Kremlin spokesperson Dmitry Peskov has said that the doctrine should go through a "deep analysis" and that it is a "very important text".</p>

<p>On the other hand, Matthew Miller said, "I'm unfortunately not surprised by the comments the Kremlin has made around the publication of this new, revised document," and that since the start of the war, Russia has tried to "coerce and intimidate both Ukraine and other countries around the world through irresponsible nuclear rhetoric and behaviour."</p>

<p>Tatiana Stanovaya, a political scientist, of the Carnegie Russia and Eurasia Center, said, "the current situation offers Putin a significant temptation to escalate" and that Putin offers the West two choices "'Do you want a nuclear war? You will have it,' or 'Let's end this war on Russia's terms,'" she posted on X.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/dg0ait4_vladimir-putin-reuters_625x300_20_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Vladimir Putin approved changes to the nuclear doctrine on Tuesday]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/will-trumps-doge-be-a-failed-experiment-7064954]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: Will Trump's DOGE Be A Failed Experiment?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/will-trumps-doge-be-a-failed-experiment-7064954]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 20 Nov 2024 19:01:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In his first term, the OAI received flak for influencing Trump's government policies. The office was silently closed during the transition after President Joe Biden took charge in 2021. Would DOGE meet the same fate?]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont">
<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/p9khknjg_doge_625x300_20_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>

<p>The US president-elect, Donald Trump, recently appointed tech billionaire Elon Musk and biotech investor Vivek Ramaswamy to lead the new DOGE (Department of Government Efficiency) in his second administration.</p>

<p>On their selection, Trump said that the “two wonderful Americans” shall “dismantle government bureaucracy, slash excess regulations, cut wasteful expenditures, and restructure federal agencies” through the newly formed department. However, Trump made it clear that the pair would act in an advisory capacity and that the DOGE would not be an official government department.</p>

<p>With this announcement, Trump created a seemingly important role for his ‘buddy' Musk, who supported him with his time and money during the presidential campaign. Ramaswamy ran as a Republican candidate for President earlier this year against Trump, before dropping out and endorsing him. Since his re-election, Trump has been busy naming his core team with his loyalists, overriding concerns about impartiality and conflicting interests.</p>

<p>Both Musk and Ramaswamy have companies with ongoing government contracts. Even as advisors, they will have occasions to further their business interests directly or indirectly, and this will not attract US government conflict of interest laws.</p>

<p>Both Republican and Democratic presidents have in the past adopted different approaches to make the government efficient and to cut spending. In fact, a similar attempt was made in Trump 1.0, with the OAI (Office of American Innovation) set up under his son-in-law Jared Kushner to “make government operate like a business”. However, the OAI saw little success.</p>

<h2><strong>What Exactly Is DOGE?</strong></h2>

<p>The concept of DOGE was suggested by Trump in early September during the election campaign. At one of the meetings, Trump said that in 2022, “fraud and improper payments alone cost taxpayers an estimated hundreds of billions of dollars”. Then, just days after his win, Trump declared that Musk and Ramaswamy would work with the White House and Office of Management &amp; Budget to tackle "massive waste and fraud" in $6.5 trillion of annual government spending.</p>

<p>Not much is known about the official composition and functioning of the newly announced DOGE, or about its funding. Since it won't be a government department, it will not require the US Congress's approval for its creation.</p>

<p>Trump expects Musk and Ramaswamy's work to conclude by no later than July 4, 2026, which will also be the 250th anniversary of the Declaration of Independence. On November 14, an X account for DOGE said that the group was ‘‘accepting resumes from super high-IQ small-government revolutionaries willing to work 80+ hours per week on unglamorous cost-cutting". In a separate post, Musk said "compensation is zero”.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>Why Many Are Sceptical</strong></h2>

<p>The eventual goal of DOGE is to rationalise federal operations and cut significant government spending by at least $2 trillion, which would mean substantial reductions across all programmes, including essential services like Social Security and Medicare, potentially antagonising millions of voters. However, experts are sceptical about DOGE's success.</p>

<p>“The chances of DOGE succeeding are slim because of several reasons. The bureaucracy is too entrenched for any major gains in reducing the federal workforce; in any case, their salaries are a very small part of the budget,” says Uma Purushothaman, Associate Professor, US Studies, School of International Studies, JNU. DOGE can provide recommendations to the White House but actually lacks direct authority to make spending cuts or regulatory changes. “The US Constitution gives Congress 'the power of the purse'. This means that any change or reduction in allocation will have to go through Congress, where Trump has a very slim majority,” says Purushothaman. “And it is quite possible that some Republicans in both houses might not want to support some of these reforms,” she adds.</p>

<h2><strong>Castles In The Air?</strong></h2>

<p>Instead of comparing the DOGE experiment with other past presidents' similar initiatives that were largely unsuccessful, it would be better to compare it with the OAI conceived during Trump's first term.</p>

<p>The OAI was a part of the White House office lasting from 2017 until 2021. Under the leadership of Kushner, the group was to be the link between the American technology industry and the Trump administration. It was supposed to reform the federal bureaucracy with “new thinking and real change” to tackle the country's hardest problems. From workforce shortages and infrastructure challenges to reforming prisons and addressing the opioid crisis, the tasks were enormous.</p>

<p>However, other than carrying out IT modernisation in the government and organising the CEO summit, attended by Amazon's Jeff Bezos, Apple's Tim Cook, Microsoft's Satya Nadella, IBM's Ginni Rometty and more, there isn't much to report about it. The OAI definitely received flak for influencing Trump's government policies. The office was silently closed during the transition after President Joe Biden took charge in 2021. Would DOGE meet the same fate?</p>

<p>“The DOGE's aims are too ambitious, whether in terms of money or time. It is unlikely that DOGE will succeed at this scale or within this time frame. Yes, it will probably suffer the same fate as the Office of American Innovation, especially if the next administration is a Democratic one,” says Purushothaman.</p>

<p>The DOGE epitomises yet another exploratory method of governance in the US – one where businessmen would apply their corporate experiences to resolve public sector issues. Whether this will lead to any meaningful changes or remain largely symbolic, only time will tell. Until then, the world can't dodge the DOGE stories.</p>

<p><em>(The author is Contributing Editor, NDTV)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/dpi50emo_doge_625x300_20_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/indian-american-researcher-unveils-how-ancient-egyptians-built-the-pyramids-7064748]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Indian-American Researcher Unveils How Ancient Egyptians Built The Pyramids]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/indian-american-researcher-unveils-how-ancient-egyptians-built-the-pyramids-7064748]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 20 Nov 2024 18:39:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Rajan Hooda, an Indian-origin researcher from the University of Chicago, has proposed a groundbreaking theory on how the ancient Egyptians built the pyramids.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Egyptian pyramids, iconic ancient masonry structures, have long fascinated people with their immense size and intricate design. For centuries, the question "How did the Egyptians build the pyramids?" has remained one of history's greatest unsolved mysteries. Now, Rajan Hooda, an Indian-origin researcher from the University of Chicago, claims to have cracked the code behind the construction of these colossal monuments. His breakthrough comes after over 50 years of dedicated research into the methods used by the ancient Egyptians.</p>

<p>In his new research paper, Hooda introduces the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.htpwb.com/"><em>'Theory of The Conjoint Solution and The Shrinking Dual L Notch Ramps'</em></a>, a revolutionary approach that offers unprecedented insight into the ancient pyramids' construction methodology. The 20-page research paper not only proposes a new method of construction but also provides what Mr Hooda asserts is irrefutable evidence for this ancient engineering feat.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/fv11u8d8_egyptian-pyramids_625x300_20_November_24.jpeg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Mr Hooda remembers being captivated as an eight-year-old when he first heard of 'one of the great mysteries in the history of mankind-a puzzle unsolved for the past 4500 Years'. He describes his work as "a labour of love and persistence that took me more than 50 years until I was finally able to put the last painstaking pieces of this immense three-dimensional jigsaw puzzle into place."</p>

<p>Calling the prevailing ideas structurally untenable, such as the use of an exterior ramp that was larger than the pyramid or a complex interior tunnel ramp, Mr Hooda's 'L Notch Ramp' is built like a cut-out notch within the footprint of each layer of stones. He theorises that the pyramid was constructed like a "layer cake," comprising of 210 layers of stones. As he explains, "when the lowest layer of stones was completed, a small portion in one corner was left incomplete to create a small rising ramp from the ground to the top of the first layer-a height of 4.5 feet. This ramp was now used to transport stones needed to build the second layer. Like before, a small part of the second layer was left incomplete to extend the existing ramp from the top of the first layer to the top of the second layer of stones.</p>

<p>This was now used to transport stones to build the third layer. This process was repeated 209 times till the pyramid was finished. Then, starting from the top, the highest level of the ramp was removed, and the missing stones of level 209 were put into place to finish this level. This reverse process of ramp removal and placement of missing stones was repeated 209 times, ending with the lowest level being completed last." Because the ramp used is neither an exterior ramp nor an interior one, he calls it the 'L Notch Ramp' since it is built like a cut-out notch within the footprint of each layer of stones.</p>

<p>"The Egyptians would have constructed Dual L Notch Ramps for efficiency, one for taking stones up and a smaller one for workers descending after delivering stones. This method solves the riddle of ramp logistics, and since the 2 ramps were finally removed, there was no evidence left of how the pyramids were built-which is why it remained an enduring mystery for millennia," Hooda said in a news release.</p>

<p>Hooda's findings could finally provide answers to the puzzle of how the massive stone blocks were moved and assembled with remarkable precision, shedding new light on one of humanity's most enduring architectural marvels.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/i7p703bg_how-ancient-egyptians-built-the-pyramids_625x300_20_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[This theory provides new insights into the pyramid construction process.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-new-zealands-biggest-protest-35-000-maoris-take-to-the-streets-heres-why-7064297]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Why 35,000 Marched On New Zealand Streets To Protest For Maori Rights]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-new-zealands-biggest-protest-35-000-maoris-take-to-the-streets-heres-why-7064297]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 20 Nov 2024 17:43:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Indigenous "Haka" chants boomed across New Zealand's capital Wellington, as tens of thousands of people rallied against a bill that critics say would alter the core of the nation's founding treaty and dilute the rights of Maori people.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Indigenous "<em>Haka</em>" chants boomed across New Zealand's capital Wellington, as tens of thousands of people rallied against a bill that critics say would alter the core of the nation's founding treaty and dilute the rights of Maori people. The <em>Hikoi mo te Tiriti </em>march began ten days ago in the country's far north, where bare-chested men draped in traditional feather cloaks along with horse riders waving the red, white and black Maori flags, marched towards the capital in one of the country's biggest protests in recent decades.</p>

<p>The hikoi march culminated outside New Zealand's Parliament on Tuesday, where an estimated 35,000 people demonstrated, calling for lawmakers to reject the Treaty Principles Bill-- introduced by the libertarian ACT New Zealand party earlier this month. The bill reportedly seeks to redefine the Treaty of Waitangi - an agreement between the British and many, but not all, Maori tribes in 1840 that covers issues including land and cultural rights.</p>

<p>Although the legislation has almost no chance of passing as most parties in the island nation have committed to voting it down, its mere introduction has triggered a political upheaval in the country and reignited a debate on Indigenous rights.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>Maoris And Their History In New Zealand</strong></h2>

<p>The Maoris are considered the original settlers of the two large islands now known as New Zealand. They reportedly came from East Polynesia 1300s on canoe voyages and settled on the then-uninhabited islands. Over centuries, they developed their own distinct culture and language. As of today, they are spread throughout New Zealand as part of different tribes.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Maoris called the two islands where they resided Aotearoa. British colonisers, who took control of the islands in 1840 under the treaty, renamed it &nbsp;New Zealand. New Zealand gained independence from the Britishers in 1947.&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>Treaty of Waitangi</strong></h3>

<p>As the British Crown took control of New Zealand, it signed the Treaty of Waitangi (also called <em>Te Tiriti o Waitangi</em> or just <em>Te Tiriti</em>)-- the founding document with around 500 Maori chiefs, or rangatira.</p>

<p>As per a report by Al Jazeera, the document was originally presented as a measure to resolve differences between the Maori and the British. However, the English and te reo versions of the treaty feature some stark differences, because of which Maoris reportedly continued to suffer injustice in New Zealand even after independence.</p>

<p>As per the reo Maori version of the treaty, Maori chiefs have "rangatiratanga" or &nbsp;"self-determination", which gives Maori people the right to govern themselves. However, the English translation says Maori chiefs "cede to Her Majesty the Queen of England absolutely and without reservation all the rights and powers of Sovereignty", according to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2024/11/19/tens-of-thousands-protest-new-zealand-maori-rights-bill" rel="No Follow, No Index" target="_blank">Al Jazeera</a> report.</p>

<p>However, the English version does give Maoris "full exclusive and undisturbed possession of their Lands and Estates Forests Fisheries". Despite that, by the time New Zealand gained independence, 90 per cent of Maori land was reportedly taken by the British Crown.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In 1975, the government formed the Waitangi Tribunal, a permanent body to adjudicate treaty matters. The tribunal reportedly tried to remedy treaty breaches and navigate differences between the treaty's two texts.</p>

<h3><strong>The Treaty Principles Bill</strong></h3>

<p>As per the official data, currently, there are 978,246 Maori in New Zealand, constituting around 19 per cent of the nation's 5.3 million population. The Te Pati Maori, or the Maori Party, represents them in Parliament and holds six of the 123 seats there.&nbsp;</p>

<p>MP David Seymour, who is a Maori himself, introduced the Treaty Principles Bill in Parliament. He is a member of the ACT Party, a minor partner in New Zealand's coalition government.&nbsp;Mr Seymour has long railed against affirmative action policies designed to help Maori.</p>

<p>As per Mr Seymour's party, the Treaty of Waitangi has been misinterpreted for decades leading to the formation of a dual system for New Zealanders, where Maori are given special treatment. The Treaty Principles Bill seeks to end the "division by race", by giving specific definitions to the treaty's principles. These principles would then be applied to all New Zealanders, whether Maori or not.</p>

<p>Incumbent Prime Minister Christopher Luxon has voiced his opposition to Seymour's bill, meaning it is all but doomed to fail when it comes to a parliamentary vote. But former conservative prime minister Jenny Shipley said just putting it forward threatened to "divide New Zealand in a way that I haven't lived through in my adult life".&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>Why Is The Bill Controversial?</strong></h3>

<p>After the bill was presented for debate in parliament last week, 22-year-old Maori Party MP Hana-Rawhiti Maipi-Clarke ripped it in half and launched into a haka. The visuals of her demonstrations were widely shared on social media sparking one of the largest Maori demonstrations in New Zealand's recent history. &nbsp;</p>

<p>Many critics of the bill -- including some of New Zealand's most respected lawyers -- see it as an attempt to strip long-agreed rights from the country's Maori population.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"It's not the best way to have a conversation. We will not accept unilateral change to a treaty that involves two parties," Ngira Simmonds, a key advisor to New Zealand's Maori queen, told news agency AFP.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"There is a better way," he added.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/k2rvjpd8_maori-protest-new-zealand-afp_625x300_20_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Maori Tribe's hikoi march culminated outside New Zealand's Parliament on Tuesday.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/lion-2-bears-40-ducks-putin-gifts-dozens-of-animals-to-north-korea-7064178]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Lion, 2 Bears, 40 Ducks: Putin Gifts Dozens Of Animals To North Korea]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/lion-2-bears-40-ducks-putin-gifts-dozens-of-animals-to-north-korea-7064178]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 20 Nov 2024 17:30:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russian President Vladimir Putin has gifted North Korea dozens of animals, including a lion and two bears, as a sign of friendship between Moscow and Pyongyang, Russian officials said Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russian President Vladimir Putin has gifted North Korea dozens of animals, including a lion and two bears, as a sign of friendship between Moscow and Pyongyang, Russian officials said Wednesday.</p>

<p>The two countries have deepened political, military and cultural ties amid Russia's offensive on Ukraine, with Putin and North Korean leader Kim Jong Un repeatedly professing their personal camaraderie.</p>

<p>"An African lion, two brown bears, two domestic yaks, five white cockatoos, 25 pheasants of various species and 40 mandarin ducks were transferred from the Moscow Zoo to the Pyongyang Zoo," Russia's natural resources ministry said in a post on Telegram.</p>

<p>It posted a video of the animals in cargo boxes being unloaded off a government plane, and another of the lion in its new enclosure at the Pyongyang Zoo.</p>

<p>Putin previously gifted Kim 24 purebred horses, known to be Kim's favourite, while Kim sent Putin a pair of local dogs.</p>

<p>The two countries, both under heavy Western sanctions, signed a mutual defence pact earlier this year that obligates them to provide immediate military assistance if the other is invaded.</p>

<p>Western capitals, as well as Ukraine and South Korea, say North Korea has recently deployed more than 10,000 of its troops to Russia, to be sent into combat against Kyiv's forces.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ksed4kkg_putin_625x300_20_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Putin previously gifted Kim 24 purebred horses, known to be Kim's favourite.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rajnath-singh-chinese-defence-minister-meet-first-since-ladakh-disengagement-7064141]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Avoid Galwan-Type Incident": Rajnath Says At Meet With Chinese Counterpart]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rajnath-singh-chinese-defence-minister-meet-first-since-ladakh-disengagement-7064141]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 20 Nov 2024 17:28:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Defence Minister Rajnath Singh today met his Chinese counterpart Dong Jun for bilateral talks in Vientiane, Lao PDR. The two leaders met for the first time since the military disengagement in Ladakh.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Defence Minister Rajnath Singh today met his Chinese counterpart Dong Jun for bilateral talks in Vientiane, Lao PDR. The two leaders met for the first time since the military disengagement in Ladakh. At the meeting Defence Minister Rajnath Singh told Mr Dong that "Galwan-type incidents must be avoided".</p>

<p>They reviewed the situation at the Line of Actual Control and the disengagement in areas where the two sides were in a standoff for more than four years.</p>

<p>The meeting took place on the sidelines of a conclave of the 10-nation ASEAN grouping.</p>

<p>Indian and Chinese militaries had completed the disengagement exercise in last two friction points at Demchok and Depsang late last month. Regular patrolling by troops of both sides also resumed in the two areas after a gap of almost four-and-a-half years.</p>

<p>The military standoff in the upper Himalayan region of Ladakh were mainly in five regions along the Line of Actual Control or LAC - Galwan, Pangong, Gogra Hot Springs, Depsang, and Demchok.</p>

<p>Ties between India and China had taken a severe hit and had come to an abrupt halt after the military clash in Galwan Valley in June 2020. It took four years of diplomatic and military-level talks between both sides to finally come to an agreement to reinstate the status quo to what it was before the stand-off in 2020. The agreement to disengage finally happened on October 21 this year and both militaries completed the process to move back to pre-2020 status by October 31.</p>

<p>Rajnath Singh began his three-day visit to Laos on Wednesday, primarily to attend a meeting of the ASEAN Defence Ministers' Meeting Plus, which is a platform comprising the 10-nation ASEAN and its eight dialogue partners - India, China, Australia, Japan, New Zealand, South Korea, Russia and the United States.</p>

<p>Laos is hosting the meeting in its capacity as the current Chair of the forum.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/nefngen_rajnath-chinese-defence-minister-dong-jun_625x300_20_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Defence Minister Rajnath Singh today met his Chinese counterpart Dong Jun.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/92-year-old-uk-man-charged-with-womans-1967-rape-and-murder-7063776]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[92-Year-Old UK Man Charged With Woman's 1967 Rape And Murder]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/92-year-old-uk-man-charged-with-womans-1967-rape-and-murder-7063776]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 20 Nov 2024 16:45:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 92-year-old man has been charged in the UK with the murder and rape of a woman almost six decades ago, British police said Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 92-year-old man has been charged in the UK with the murder and rape of a woman almost six decades ago, British police said Wednesday.</p>

<p>Louisa Dunne, 75, was found dead by a neighbour inside her home in the southwestern English city of Bristol in June 1967.</p>

<p>Her cause of death was recorded as strangulation and asphyxiation.</p>

<p>The case remained cold for 57 years until nonagenarian Ryland Headley, of Ipswich in eastern England, was arrested on Tuesday and subsequently charged.</p>

<p>The arrest came after Avon and Somerset police began reviewing the case last year, which included further forensic examination of items relating to the case.</p>

<p>"This development marks a hugely significant moment in this investigation," the force's detective inspector Dave Marchant said in a statement.</p>

<p>"We've updated Louisa's family about this charging decision and a specialist liaison officer will continue to support them in the coming days, weeks and months."</p>

<p>Headley appeared in court in Bristol via video-link on Wednesday and was remanded in custody. He was not asked to enter pleas to the two charges.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/2hmhj068_uk-police_625x300_12_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Her cause of death was recorded as strangulation and asphyxiation. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mehmet-oz-who-is-dr-oz-trumps-pick-for-medicare-heres-all-you-need-to-know-7063698]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Who Is Dr Oz, Trump's Pick For Medicare? Here's All You Need To Know]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mehmet-oz-who-is-dr-oz-trumps-pick-for-medicare-heres-all-you-need-to-know-7063698]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 20 Nov 2024 16:37:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Oz is another addition to the unconventional health team after Trump tapped Robert F Kennedy Junior as secretary of the Department of Health and Human Services.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump has picked Mehmet Oz, a Turkish-American doctor to lead the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Service - an agency that is responsible for the healthcare of millions of Americans.</p>

<p>Before landing here, Oz had been a trained cardiothoracic surgeon, after which he found fame on The Oprah Winfrey Show and then proceeded to host his own show - The Dr Oz Show, an Emmy-winning TV show that was aired for 13 seasons and made him a household name.</p>

<p>Oz is another addition to the unconventional health team after Trump tapped Robert F Kennedy Junior as secretary of the Department of Health and Human Services.</p>

<p>However, he has always pushed for insurance for all, a stance commonly held by progressives, including Bernie Sanders and Kamala Harris. "It should be mandatory that everybody in America have health care coverage. If you can't afford it, we have to give it to you," he told The Seattle Times.</p>

<p>Interestingly, Oz has been accused of promoting "miracle" cures and malaria drugs like hydroxychloroquine and chloroquine in the early days of the pandemic to cure Covid-19, which experts believe do nothing against the virus.</p>

<p>He has time and again gravitated towards "pseudoscience" in his shows, promoting homoeopathy and alternative medicine and blurring the line between science and endorsements. He has also been accused of recommending unproven pills that would "literally flush fat from your system" and "push fat from your belly".</p>

<p>It is notable to mention that a 2014 British Medical Journal study said that his medical recommendations were based on evidence just 46 per cent of the time.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Despite that, Trump said in a statement that, "There may be no Physician more qualified and capable than Dr. Oz to Make America Healthy Again."</p>

<p>"Women, in particular, are drawn to Dr. Oz for his advice and counsel. I have seen this many times over the years. They know him, believe in him, and trust him," Trump said while endorsing Oz. He even made an appearance on Oz's show and said that his wife, Melania Trump was a big fan of the show.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Senator Patty Murray, a Washington Democrat who used to lead the Senate health committee, said in a statement, "Even putting aside the raft of alarming pseudoscience Dr. Oz has previously endorsed, it is deeply disappointing to see someone with zero qualifications being announced to head up such a critical agency."<br />
<br />
In a post on X, Lawrence Gostin, the director of O'Neill Institute mentioned that, "Dr Oz is unfit to run CMS. He peddles conspiracy theories on vaccines &amp; fake cures. He profits from fringe medical ideas. By nominating RFK Jr &amp; Mehmet Oz, Trump is giving his middle finger to science. Having worked for 40 years in public health, it's utterly disheartening."</p>

<p>Nevertheless, Oz stopped performing surgeries in 2018 but still holds a physician licence. He also tried his hand in politics in 2022, when he lost to John Fetterman while running for Senate in Pennsylvania with the help of Donald Trump.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/c2b2fin_dr-mehmet-oz-afp_625x300_20_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Oz has been accused of promoting "miracle" cures and pseudoscience.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-47-foot-endangered-fin-whale-washes-ashore-in-alaska-draws-massive-crowd-7063614]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Video: Endangered Fin Whale Washes Ashore In Alaska, Draws Massive Crowd]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-47-foot-endangered-fin-whale-washes-ashore-in-alaska-draws-massive-crowd-7063614]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 20 Nov 2024 16:29:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The colossal carcass, comparable in length to a college basketball court, drew a huge crowd as hundreds of locals flocked to the shore to catch a glimpse.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 47-foot-long (14.3 meters) female fin whale, an endangered species, was discovered dead near a coastal trail in Anchorage, Alaska's largest city, over the weekend. The colossal carcass, comparable in length to a college basketball court, drew a huge crowd as hundreds of locals flocked to the shore to catch a glimpse.&nbsp;Barbara Mahoney, a NOAA biologist examining the whale, told&nbsp;the<em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.adn.com/alaska-news/wildlife/2024/11/18/biologists-onlookers-continue-examining-a-nearly-50-foot-fin-whale-that-washed-ashore-on-anchorages-mudflats/" rel="nofollow, noindex"> Anchorage Daily News&nbsp;</a></em>the whale was likely 1 to 3 years old.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/DCgBCYsxlWN/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DCgBCYsxlWN/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DCgBCYsxlWN/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DCgBCYsxlWN/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by Marc Lester (@marclesterphoto)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p></p>

<p>On Sunday, a team of experts from the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration&nbsp;and Alaska Veterinary Pathology Services launched an investigation into the fin whale's death. To prevent the carcass from drifting away, they anchored it to the shore and began collecting valuable tissue samples. "We've got some urine and some heart tissues ... and additional blood and baleen samples," Ms Mahoney said.</p>

<p>However, determining the exact cause of death remains a daunting task, even with laboratory analysis, due to factors like decomposition and the lack of visible injuries, noted an expert.&nbsp;</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">A whale was found washed up in Alaska.<br />
<a href="https://t.co/TSiBoeomrb">pic.twitter.com/TSiBoeomrb</a></p>
— FearBuck (@FearedBuck) <a href="https://twitter.com/FearedBuck/status/1859102213290750344?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 20, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p><strong>What are Fin Whales?</strong></p>

<p>Fin whales, the world's second-largest whale species, can grow up to 85 feet (25.9 meters) in length and weigh a staggering 40-80 tons, according to NOAA Fisheries.&nbsp;"Fin whales are typically found in deep, offshore waters of all major oceans, primarily in temperate to polar latitudes. They are less common in the tropics. They occur year-round in a wide range of locations, but the density of individuals in any one area changes seasonally," the NOAA Fisheries states on its website. "Most migrate from the Arctic and Antarctic feeding areas in the summer to tropical breeding and calving areas in the winter. The location of winter breeding grounds is not known."</p>

<p>Despite their impressive size, fin whales face numerous and varied threats. Ship strikes, entanglement in fishing gear, and underwater noise pollution pose significant risks to their well-being. Moreover, the impacts of climate change further exacerbate the vulnerability of these incredible creatures.&nbsp;</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/g5n3jaqg_fin-whale_625x300_20_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Fin whales, the world's second-largest whale species, can grow up to 85 feet]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/g20-climate-declaration-its-only-words-7063603]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: G20 Climate Declaration: It's Only Words...]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/g20-climate-declaration-its-only-words-7063603]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 20 Nov 2024 16:27:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The declaration's call for circular economies and waste reduction is undermined by its refusal to confront the unsustainable consumption patterns of high-income countries.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/gfoovvh8_g20_625x300_19_November_24.jpeg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>The G20 Rio de Janeiro Leaders' Declaration aspires to chart a bold course for addressing the climate crisis. While it emphasises sustainable, inclusive, and resilient growth, its lofty rhetoric is undermined by significant gaps, contradictions, and a failure to address systemic barriers. The declaration risks being another aspirational statement that falls short of driving meaningful global action.<br />
The statement's language is filled with promises to “encourage”, “recognise”, and “cooperate”. However, it stops short of binding commitments or enforceable mechanisms. Reiterating the Paris Agreement goals without concrete actions or timelines does little to mitigate the worsening climate crisis. This vagueness perpetuates a familiar pattern in global climate diplomacy, where lofty ambitions remain unfulfilled.</p>

<h2><strong>The Absence Of Water</strong></h2>

<p>Despite the call for a “whole-of-economy” change, the declaration lacks a clear framework for implementing its commitments. For instance, its pledge to triple renewable energy capacity globally by 2030 is not supported by actionable steps to address financing gaps or infrastructure challenges.</p>

<p>One of the Declaration's most glaring omissions is the absence of water as a central theme. The global hydrological cycle, critical to achieving the Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs), is treated as an afterthought, siloed under Water, Sanitation, and Hygiene (WASH). This ignores the role of water as a global common good, central to tackling hunger, poverty, and climate resilience. Addressing water issues demands an economy-wide transformation, not fragmented policies relegated to specific sectors.</p>

<p>Achieving the Paris Agreement's goals requires more than pledges; it demands a robust green industrial strategy. Yet, the declaration fails to recognise the importance of aligning industrial policies with sustainability goals. Trade frameworks, particularly through the World Trade Organization (WTO), need reform to enable equitable participation in green growth. Without systemic changes, developing nations will remain marginalised in the global energy transition.</p>

<h2><strong>Blame Where Due</strong></h2>

<p>The declaration's call for reforming the international financial system lacks substance, failing to address the stark realities faced by developing nations. In 2022 alone, these countries spent a record $443.5 billion servicing external public and publicly guaranteed debt, diverting essential resources away from critical sectors such as health, education, and environmental initiatives. For the 75 poorest nations eligible for the World Bank's International Development Association (IDA) financing, the situation is graver, with $88.9 billion paid in debt servicing that same year. This escalating burden underscores the systemic inequities of a financial system that leaves vulnerable countries with dwindling fiscal space to tackle pressing development and climate needs.</p>

<p>The availability of concessional financing—essential for sustainable development in low-income nations—remains grossly insufficient. While developed countries provided $115.9 billion in climate finance in 2022, finally surpassing the $100 billion annual target set for 2020, this milestone arrived years too late to address the urgency of the climate crisis. Moreover, accessing these funds continues to be fraught with bureaucratic hurdles and inequitable mechanisms, leaving many developing nations unable to finance necessary adaptation and mitigation strategies effectively. This systemic failure reflects the financial system's prioritisation of creditor interests over the needs of the most vulnerable.</p>

<h2><strong>Rhetoric Over Action</strong></h2>

<p>These challenges directly impact global climate action, as developing countries are left to bear the dual burden of servicing debt and facing the catastrophic consequences of climate change. Without access to timely and adequate financing, these nations are forced into a cycle of underinvestment in sustainable projects and reliance on expensive market loans. The result is an unsustainable debt spiral that undermines not only their economic stability but also the global ambition to achieve climate goals. The declaration's emphasis on scaling up green finance “from billions to trillions” ignores these entrenched barriers, offering little more than rhetorical commitments.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The declaration misses an opportunity to demand structural reforms in multilateral development banks and central banks to align their strategies with Nationally Determined Contributions (NDCs) and SDG goals. Central banks and financial regulators, critical players in managing climate risks, are barely mentioned. Their mandates should be expanded to account for climate risks, ensuring that financial systems support sustainable development rather than perpetuate inequities. Furthermore, the demand for critical minerals to support renewable energy transitions risks turning resource-rich developing nations into mere suppliers, exacerbating environmental degradation and human rights violations. The declaration fails to address these risks or propose equitable mechanisms for resource governance.<br />
Despite reiterating the principle of common but differentiated responsibilities (CBDR), the declaration does little to address the structural inequalities that burden low- and middle-income countries.</p>

<h2><strong>Missed Opportunities</strong></h2>

<p>Historical emitters are not held accountable for their disproportionate contributions to climate change, and there are no specific commitments from high-income nations to scale up climate finance or emissions reductions.</p>

<p>The failure to prioritise just transitions is another missed opportunity. While the declaration references this principle, it offers no actionable steps to support vulnerable communities or ensure equity in the global energy transition.</p>

<p>The declaration represents a significant missed opportunity to address the escalating climate crisis with the urgency and specificity it demands. It acknowledges the necessity of adaptation and the establishment of a Loss and Damage Fund but fails to provide a concrete framework for implementation. This oversight leaves vulnerable nations, particularly those in the Global South, to bear the brunt of climate impacts without adequate financial or technical support. Despite the urgency highlighted at the United Nations COP29 climate talks in Baku, where financial mechanisms to support poorer nations were central, the G20's commitments remain nebulous and lack actionable substance.</p>

<h2><strong>Migration Remains A Blindspot</strong></h2>

<p>The absence of any mention of climate-induced migration is inexcusable. According to the World Bank, climate change could displace up to 216 million people within their own countries by 2050, creating an unprecedented humanitarian crisis. From the sinking islands of the Pacific to desertification in Africa, millions are already being forced from their homes. Yet, the G20 remains silent. This omission reveals a troubling disregard for the socio-economic fallout of climate change and a failure to acknowledge the human cost of inaction.</p>

<p>The declaration's call for circular economies and waste reduction is undermined by its refusal to confront the unsustainable consumption patterns of high-income countries. G20 nations are responsible for approximately 75% of global waste and the majority of natural resource consumption, yet the document avoids binding commitments to curb these excesses. The emphasis on recycling and reuse is commendable but hollow without a corresponding reduction in overall consumption.</p>

<p>The G20 Rio Declaration positions itself as a comprehensive roadmap for addressing the climate crisis but falls short of its promise. Its reliance on vague commitments, lack of enforceable mechanisms, and failure to address systemic inequities reveal it as more performative than transformative.</p>

<p>To drive meaningful action, future G20 presidencies, particularly South Africa's, must prioritise actionable commitments that address structural barriers to sustainability and equity. Bold leadership, systemic reform, and binding targets are essential to turn these aspirations into reality. Without these, the declaration risks becoming another footnote in the history of missed opportunities in global climate governance.<br />
&nbsp;<br />
<em>(Aditya Sinha is OSD, Research, Economic Advisory Council to the Prime Minister)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/gfoovvh8_g20_625x300_19_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/asteroid-2024-pt5-earths-second-moon-set-to-disappear-wont-return-until-2055-7063428]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Earth's 'Second Moon' Set To Disappear, Won't Return Until 2055]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/asteroid-2024-pt5-earths-second-moon-set-to-disappear-wont-return-until-2055-7063428]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 20 Nov 2024 16:05:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The space visitor is about 33 feet wide, which might sound scary - but Nasa notes that it "does not pose a hazard to Earth".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Nicknamed as a "mini moon" or "second moon," asteroid 2024 PT5 was first seen on August 7 by a NASA-sponsored asteroid detecting system. This bus-sized asteroid is currently approaching the end of its close visit to Earth and will vanish until 2055. The asteroid was momentarily trapped by Earth's gravity and became a "mini moon" between September 29 and November 25. Stargazers and space enthusiasts have been delighted by this unusual occurrence, but because of its small size and dim brightness, the asteroid was not visible to the naked eye. Most people were not able to see it because only professional telescopes can detect it.</p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://metro.co.uk/2024/11/18/you-only-have-a-few-days-left-to-see-the-earths-second-moon-22016807/"><em>The Metro,</em></a> the mini-moon is only 3,760,000 km from Earth. That certainly might sound like a lot-or at least how far the sofa from the TV remote can feel sometimes-but it's barely a stone's throw in the world of space.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/science/earths-second-moon-to-be-visible-today-all-about-asteroid-2024-pt5-6674585"><strong>Also Read | Earth's 'Second Moon' To Be Visible Today. All About Asteroid 2024 PT5</strong></a></p>

<p>'Mini' is also the key word here. Asteroid 2024 PT5 is only 37 feet or so long-the size of a bus. The mini-moon is roughly 11,400,000 feet. Our new lunar neighbour has travelled far to reach us. Experts think it hails from the Arjuna asteroid belt, a ring of primordial crumbs 93 million miles from the Sun.</p>

<p>NASA officials speculate it might be a fragment of the Earth's Moon itself from an ancient impact that has by pure chance found its way back.PT5 was first picked up by Complutense University of Madrid scientists using a powerful NASA-funded telescope in Sutherland, South Africa, as per <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://metro.co.uk/2024/11/18/you-only-have-a-few-days-left-to-see-the-earths-second-moon-22016807/"><em>the news outlet.</em></a><br />
<br />
'Mini-moons' are celestial objects like asteroids or comets that do drive-by visits to the Earth. Though some were later revealed by astronomers to be diminutive space junk like satellite scraps or lost rockets.</p>

<p><strong>Asteroid 2024 PT5</strong></p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/planetarydefense/2024/10/02/nasa-to-track-asteroid-2024-pt5-on-next-close-pass-january-2025/"><em>NASA,</em></a> Asteroid 2024 PT5 was first observed on August 7, 2024, by the Sutherland, South Africa, telescope of the University of Hawai'i's Asteroid Terrestrial-impact Last Alert System (ATLAS), which is funded by NASA. Estimated to be about 33 feet (10 meters) wide, the asteroid does not pose a hazard to Earth.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/92712ajo_asteroid-2024-pt5_625x300_20_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The near-Earth asteroid 2024 PT5 was first observed on August 7. (Representative Image)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/screams-eerie-laughter-north-koreas-new-weapons-against-south-korea-7063163]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Screams, Eerie Laughter: North Korea's New Weapons Against South Korea]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/screams-eerie-laughter-north-koreas-new-weapons-against-south-korea-7063163]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 20 Nov 2024 15:28:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Gunshots, screams, eerie laughter: South Korea's border island Ganghwa is being bombarded nightly with blood-curdling sounds, part of a new campaign by the nuclear-armed North that is driving residents to despair.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Gunshots, screams, eerie laughter: South Korea's border island Ganghwa is being bombarded nightly with blood-curdling sounds, part of a new campaign by the nuclear-armed North that is driving residents to despair.</p>

<p>Before it started, 56-year-old Kim Yun-suk fell asleep to the hum of insects and woke to the chirping of birds. Now, she is kept awake every night by what sounds like the soundtrack of a low-budget horror movie at top volume.</p>

<p>"The peaceful sounds of nature... have now been drowned out," Kim told AFP.</p>

<p>"All we hear is this noise."</p>

<p>The campaign is the latest manifestation of steadily declining ties between the two Koreas this year, which have also seen Pyongyang test ever more powerful missiles and bombard the South with trash-carrying balloons.</p>

<p>Since July, North Korea has been broadcasting the noises in huge chunks almost every day from loudspeakers along the border.</p>

<p>The northern point of Ganghwa -- an island in the Han river estuary on the Yellow Sea -- is only about two kilometres (a mile) from the North.</p>

<p>When AFP visited, the nighttime broadcast included what sounded like the screams of people dying on the battlefield, the crack of gunfire, bombs exploding, along chilling music that started at 11:00 pm.</p>

<p>In the almost pitch-black fields, sinister noises echoed as the stars in the clear night sky shone beautifully alongside the coastal road lights, creating a stark and unsettling contrast.</p>

<p>North Korea has done propaganda broadcasts before, said 66-year-old villager Ahn Hyo-cheol, but they used to focus on criticising the South's leaders, or idealising the North.</p>

<p>Now "there were sounds like a wolf howling, and ghostly sounds", he said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"It feels unpleasant and gives me chills. It feels bizarre."</p>

<p>Ganghwa county councillor Park Heung-yeol said that the new broadcasts were "not just regime propaganda -- it's genuinely intended to torment people".</p>

<p>- Torture -&nbsp;</p>

<p>Experts said the new broadcasts almost meet the criteria for a torture campaign.</p>

<p>"Almost every regime has used noise torture and sleep deprivation," Rory Cox, a historian at the University of St Andrews, told AFP.</p>

<p>"It is very common and leaves no physical scarring, therefore making it deniable."</p>

<p>Exposure to noise levels above 60 decibels at night increases the risk of sleep disorders, experts said, but AFP tracked levels of up to 80 decibels late at night on Ganghwa during a recent trip.</p>

<p>"I find myself taking headache medicine almost all the time," An Mi-hee, 37, told AFP, adding that prolonged sleep deprivation due to the noise has also led to anxiety, eye pain, facial tremors and drowsiness.</p>

<p>"Our kids can't sleep either, so they've developed mouth sores and are dozing off at school."</p>

<p>Distraught and desperate, An travelled to Seoul and got on her knees to beg lawmakers at the National Assembly to find a solution, breaking down in tears as she described the island's suffering.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"It would actually be better if there were a flood, a fire, or even an earthquake, because those events have a clear recovery timeline," An said.</p>

<p>"We have no idea if this will go on until the person in North Korea who gives the orders dies, or if it could be cut off at any moment. We just don't know."</p>

<p><strong>- '70s horror flick' -</strong></p>

<p>The noise tormenting Ganghwa island residents appeared to be a rudimentary mix of clips from a sound library, typically common at any TV or radio broadcasters, audio experts told AFP.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The sound effects are "like something found in a South Korean horror film in the 70s and 80s," said sound engineer Hwang Kwon-ik.</p>

<p>The two Koreas remained technically at war since the 1950 to 1953 conflict ended in an armistice not a peace treaty.</p>

<p>North Korean leader Kim Jong Un this year declared Seoul his "principal enemy" and has ramped up weapons testing and built closer military ties with Russia.</p>

<p>The isolated and impoverished North is known to be extremely sensitive about its citizens gaining access to South Korean pop culture.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Some experts have suggested the latest broadcasts could be aimed at preventing North Korean soldiers from hearing the South's own propaganda broadcasts, which typically feature K-pop songs and international news.</p>

<p>In August, just weeks after South Korea resumed K-pop broadcasts in response to Pyongyang floating trash-carrying balloons south, a North Korean soldier defected by crossing the heavily fortified border on foot.</p>

<p>But Lee Su-yong, an audio production professor at the Dong-Ah Institute of Media and Arts, said "if there is sound coming towards the North that you want to mask, then the sound (you use to cover it) must also be directed toward the North."</p>

<p>"It seems less about masking noise and more about inflicting pain on people in the South," he told AFP.</p>

<p>Choi Hyoung-chan, a 60-year-old resident, said the South Korean government had failed to protect vulnerable civilians on the frontier.</p>

<p>"They should come here and try to live with these sounds for just ten days," he told AFP, referring to officials in Seoul.</p>

<p>"I doubt they could even endure a single day."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/g92gt0i_south-korea-border-village_625x300_20_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Since July, North Korea has been broadcasting the noises in huge chunks almost every day.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/theyre-trying-to-kill-me-andhra-maid-alleges-torture-in-kuwait-7062986]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["They're Trying To Kill Me": Andhra Maid Alleges Torture In Kuwait]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/theyre-trying-to-kill-me-andhra-maid-alleges-torture-in-kuwait-7062986]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 20 Nov 2024 15:05:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A woman from Andhra Pradesh, working as a house help in Kuwait has accused her employers of torture. The woman, a native of Kakinada district, recorded a video explaining her ordeal and sent it to her relatives.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A woman from Andhra Pradesh, working as a house help in Kuwait has accused her employers of torture. The woman, a native of Kakinada district, recorded a video explaining her ordeal and sent it to her relatives.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In a tearful video, Gara Kumari, a widow and mother of three, cried for help: "They are not giving me proper food. they are trying to kill me. Please save me and send me back to my children."</p>

<p>Ms Kumari, from Yallamelli village in Gandepalli, married Venkatesh of Ramavaram village in Jaggampeta 19 years ago. After her husband's death five years ago, she was left to care for their two daughters and a son alone. Despite working tirelessly in her village, her income was insufficient to meet her family's needs.</p>

<p>In search of a better livelihood, Ms Kumari sought the assistance of an agent, M Sudhakar, from Palakollu. With his help, she travelled to Kuwait seven months ago to work as a domestic help in Kuwait, leaving her children in her mother's care.</p>

<p>What began as a bid to secure a better future soon turned into a nightmare. Ms Kumari's video describes physical and emotional abuse, denial of proper food, and a threat to her life.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The video has gone viral, causing a stir in Kakinada district. Relatives and villagers are pressing authorities for swift action to rescue Ms Kumari and ensure her safe return to India.The role of the agent who facilitated her travel, M Sudhakar, is also under scrutiny.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/p36cc43_andhra-maid-kuwait-_625x300_20_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[In a tearful video, Gara Kumari, a widow and mother of three, cried for help.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/single-cell-could-be-capable-of-learning-study-7062789]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Single Cell Could Be Capable Of 'Learning': Study]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/single-cell-could-be-capable-of-learning-study-7062789]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 20 Nov 2024 14:57:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Cells, such as those making up human bodies, might be capable of 'learning', once deemed exclusive to complex creatures with brains, including birds and mammals, a new study has suggested.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Cells, such as those making up human bodies, might be capable of 'learning', once deemed exclusive to complex creatures with brains, including birds and mammals, a new study has suggested.</p>

<p>Habituation is a simple form of learning in which one's response to a certain trigger lessens with repeated exposure. It is how one learns to ignore things happening often, such as the ticking of a clock. Habituation can also help people confront their fears.</p>

<p>The study offered "compelling evidence" that even single-cell creatures such as amoebae, as well as the cells in human bodies, could show habituation similar to that seen in complex organisms with brains and nervous systems, said researchers, led by those at Harvard Medical School, US, and the Centre for Genomic Regulation, Spain.</p>

<p>The results, published in the journal Current Biology, added to a small but growing body of evidence in this field and deepen our understanding of how learning and memory work at the most basic level of life, they said.</p>

<p>"This finding opens up an exciting new mystery for us: How do cells without brains manage something so complex?" said senior author Jeremy Gunawardena, an associate professor of systems biology at Harvard Medical School.</p>

<p>Gunawardena's team had earlier documented evidence of a single-celled ciliate displaying avoidance behaviour, similar to that observed in animals when they encounter unpleasant situations. A ciliate uses hairs on its surface for moving and eating.</p>

<p>The findings suggested that a single cell is capable of behaviour more complex that what is currently appreciated, the researchers said.</p>

<p>For the study, the researchers used computer models to analyse how molecules inside ciliates and cells of mammals respond to different patterns of stimulation, or something that triggers a physical or behavioural change.</p>

<p>They found four networks of molecules that displayed hallmarks of habituation, usually seen in animal brains. Each of the molecule networks were found to have two forms of "memory" storage that captured information learned from the environment.</p>

<p>Further, one of the memory form was found to decay much faster than the other -- a form of memory loss necessary for habituation, the researchers noted.</p>

<p>If single cells can "remember", it could also help explain how cancer cells develop resistance to chemotherapy or how bacteria become resistant to antibiotics -- situations where cells seem to "learn" from their environment, they said.</p>

<p>However, these possibilities would need to be explored with real-world biological data, the team said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/tqbk0v4o_cells_625x300_30_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The study offered "compelling evidence" that even single-cell creatures such as amoebae.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/im-a-celebrity-star-tulisa-reveals-she-is-demisexual-what-is-it-7062674]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA['I'm A Celebrity' Star Tulisa Reveals She Is Demisexual. What Is It]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/im-a-celebrity-star-tulisa-reveals-she-is-demisexual-what-is-it-7062674]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 20 Nov 2024 14:28:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Tulisa said it makes her feel "physically sick" to imagine sleeping with or dating someone she doesn't have a connection with.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>UK singer and television personality Tulisa has revealed that she identifies as "demisexual". The revelation happened during a discussion about her personal life in an episode of '<em>I'm A Celebrity</em>' on Tuesday. Tulisa, a former '<em>X Factor</em>' judge, is one of the 10 stars who flew to Australia to compete in the series, <em>The Independent</em> reported. The teammates started talking about dating during a break when Tulisa revealed she is a celibate. The 36-year-old shared she is a demisexual and has been celibate for over three years.</p>

<p>"Even though I've been on there, I've never gone on an actual date with anyone on there. I'm proper guarded," Tulisa said about avoiding dating apps.</p>

<p>"I feel like I'm demisexual, I need to have a really close emotional bond with someone... I need actual depth. I'm a slow, slow burner," she added.</p>

<p>Tulisa said it makes her feel "physically sick" to imagine sleeping with or dating someone she doesn't have a connection with. "This is my temple, you cannot enter!"</p>

<p>Talking about relationship, Tulisa said, "I actually do enjoy being single, I enjoy being on my own."</p>

<h3><strong>What is demisexuality?</strong></h3>

<p>It is a sexual orientation in which a person experiences sexual attraction only after forming a deep emotional connection with someone, as per <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.independent.co.uk/arts-entertainment/tv/news/tulisa-im-a-celeb-dating-b2650039.html" rel="noindex,nofollow"><em>The Independent</em></a>.</p>

<p>It is not clear how many people in the world are demisexual. The outlet said that the term was coined in 2006 on a web forum devoted to asexuality.</p>

<p>A 2021 British census said that 0.06 per cent of people in the UK identify as asexual.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/cjsgsdno_actor-tulisa_625x300_20_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Tulisa said she enjoys being single.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>