<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Thu, 17 Oct 2024 17:57:51 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/gods-problem-now-us-mans-hilarious-obituary-for-his-father-goes-viral-6811324]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["God's Problem Now": US Man's Hilarious Obituary For His Father Goes Viral]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/gods-problem-now-us-mans-hilarious-obituary-for-his-father-goes-viral-6811324]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 17 Oct 2024 17:55:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An obituary for a 74-year-old US man who died after falling and hitting his head has gone viral, with his son letting the public know that he is "God's problem now".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An obituary for a 74-year-old US man who died after falling and hitting his head has gone viral, with his son letting the public know that he is "God's problem now". Robert Boehm died on October 6 and his son, Charles Boehm, recalled the life of his father in the most unconventional and hilarious ways. He candidly told the public who his father really was. But he clarified that it was not out of disrespect. Instead, it was a more honest tribute to the man who raised him, and a chance for his small town of Clarendon, Texas, to laugh once more with the beloved fellow resident.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Robert Adolph Boehm, in accordance with his lifelong dedication to his own personal brand of decorum, muttered his last unintelligible and likely unnecessary curse on October 6, 2024, shortly before tripping backward over 'some stupid mother****ing thing' and hitting his head on the floor," the obituary read, per Robertson Funeral Directors' Facebook post.&nbsp;</p>

<p><iframe allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="true" frameborder="0" height="539" scrolling="no" src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/post.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2FRobertsonfuneraldirectors%2Fposts%2Fpfbid0yKNZQcQd26sD84KyQMHepcaBZkAXYbutCYVTq4DfmDUVTboUVddptsk6JjZTUiirl&amp;show_text=true&amp;width=500" style="border:none;overflow:hidden" width="500"></iframe></p>

<p>In the obituary, Mr Charles recapped his father's life from start to finish. He wrote that his father's 1950 birth "God immediately and thankfully broke the mold and attempted to cover up the evidence". He also joked that his Catholic father managed to get his mother pregnant three times in five years, allowing him to avoid getting drafted to fight in the Vietnam War. &nbsp;</p>

<p>"Raised Catholic, Robert managed to get his wife Dianne pregnant (three times) fast enough to just barely miss getting drafted into the Vietnam War by fathering Michelle, John, and Charlotte between 1967 and 1972. Much later, with Robert possibly concerned about the brewing conflict in Grenada, Charles was born in 1983," the obituary read.</p>

<p>"This lack of military service was probably for the best, as when taking up shooting as a hobby in his later years, he managed to blow not one, but two holes in the dash of his own car on two separate occasions, which unfortunately did not even startle, let alone surprise, his dear wife Dianne, who was much accustomed to such happenings in his presence and may have actually been safer in the jungles of Vietnam the entire time," it continued.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Mr Charles also recalled that his father who worked as a "semi-professional truck driver" had a penchant for collecting antique weaponry, as well as harmonicas. The latter caused "his beloved dogs to howl continuously at odd hours of the night to entertain his many neighbours, and occasionally to give to his many, many, many grandchildren and great-grandchildren to play loudly during long road trips with their parents," the son lamented.</p>

<p>Mr Charles also noted that his mother and Robert's wife, Dianne, had passed away in February. The loss was jokingly framed as "God finally showed mercy upon" her so that she could get "the heck out of there for some well-earned peace and quiet," their son wrote.</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/x-user-advising-people-to-invest-in-sips-instead-of-buying-car-sparks-debate-6804790">&nbsp;X User Advising People To Invest In SIPs Instead Of Buying Car Sparks Debate</a></strong></p>

<p>"Without Dianne to gleefully entertain, Robert shifted his creative focus to the entertainment of you, the fine townspeople of Clarendon, Texas. Over the last eight months, if you have not met Robert or seen his road show yet, you probably would have soon. We have all done our best to enjoy/weather Robert's antics up to this point, but he is God's problem now," the obituary concluded.&nbsp;</p>

<p>This humour-filled obituary has gone viral on social media. Reacting to this, one user wrote, "Best obituary I've ever read! Thanks for your *almost* service Sir!" "His legacy is his children that understood him enough to write the best obituary EVER!" expressed another.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"I truly wish more obituaries were written like this, telling the story of someone's life with making it truly a reflection of them," commented a third user. "I can only hope that mine is half as good. I felt like I both missed out on knowing him, and yet also knew him personally by how amazing this was written. What an honor! My condolences to the family," said one user.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/pagpk1r_robert-adolph-boehm_625x300_17_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[In the obituary, Mr Charles recapped his father's life from start to finish.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/19-palestinians-killed-after-israeli-strike-hits-school-says-gaza-ministry-6811048]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[19 Palestinians Killed After Israeli Strike Hits School, Says Gaza Ministry]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/19-palestinians-killed-after-israeli-strike-hits-school-says-gaza-ministry-6811048]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 17 Oct 2024 17:21:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[At least 19 Palestinians including children were killed on Thursday after an Israeli strike hit a school in Jabalia in the northern Gaza Strip that is sheltering displaced people, a Gaza health ministry official told Reuters.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At least 19 Palestinians including children were killed on Thursday after an Israeli strike hit a school in Jabalia in the northern Gaza Strip that is sheltering displaced people, a Gaza health ministry official told Reuters.</p>

<p>Dozens were also injured in the strike, said the official, Medhat Abbas, adding: "There is no water to extinguish the fire. There is nothing."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/ok538n0g_gaza_625x300_17_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Dozens were also injured in the strike, said an official (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/cc1-man-named-in-us-indictment-in-khalistani-terrorist-gurpatwant-singh-pannun-case-no-longer-government-employee-india-6810995]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Man Named In Terrorist Pannun Case No Longer Government Employee: India]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/cc1-man-named-in-us-indictment-in-khalistani-terrorist-gurpatwant-singh-pannun-case-no-longer-government-employee-india-6810995]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 17 Oct 2024 17:15:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India has confirmed the US' assertion that a person identified as 'CC1' in a US Department of Justice indictment on an alleged assassination plot of Khalistani terrorist Gurpatwant Singh Pannun is no longer employed by the Indian government.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India has confirmed the United States' assertion that a person identified as 'CC1' in a US Department of Justice indictment on an alleged assassination plot of Khalistani terrorist Gurpatwant Singh Pannun is no longer employed by the Indian government.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The US State Department had said it had been informed about this by Indian officials who are members of an inquiry committee.</p>

<p>"We've received an update from them on the investigation that they have been conducting. It was a productive meeting. They did inform us that the individual who was named in the Justice Department indictment is no longer an employee of the Indian government... We are satisfied with the cooperation," State Department spokesman Matthew Miller told reporters.</p>

<p>At a press conference on Thursday, Ministry of External Affairs Spokesperson Randhir Jaiswal confirmed that the person named in the indictment is no longer an employee of the government of India.&nbsp;</p>

<p>To a follow-up question on who the Indian official is and who are the people who have gone to the United States, Mr Jaiswal said, "I have confirmed that this gentleman is not part of the Government of India setup, he's not an employee, beyond that I don't have anything to share with you. Regarding the people who have gone to the United States, these are members of the high-level inquiry committee that had been set up in November 2023 to look into the inputs that were shared by the US."</p>

<p>"We have taken these inputs very seriously and we remain engaged with the US side on this matter. Two members of the high-level committee have travelled there and held meetings with the US side," he added.</p>

<p>In November last year, UK newspaper Financial Times had reported that the US had foiled a plot to kill Pannun, who heads the radical outfit, Sikhs for Justice, and holds dual citizenship of the US and Canada. Officials in the Joe Biden administration had later confirmed this.</p>

<p>Both the US and India have said that the allegations and the indictment will not affect the upward trajectory of the ties between the two countries. &nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/d10hkbbo_pannun3_625x300_18_June_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Ministry of External Affairs said that the inputs shared by the US have been taken very seriously.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/wanted-canada-to-extradite-bishnoi-gang-members-india-on-diplomatic-row-6810487]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Wanted Canada To Extradite Bishnoi Gang Members": India On Diplomatic Row]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/wanted-canada-to-extradite-bishnoi-gang-members-india-on-diplomatic-row-6810487]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 17 Oct 2024 16:17:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In the backdrop of ongoing diplomatic tensions between India and Canada, India has raised concerns over Canada's handling of criminals linked to organised crime.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In the backdrop of ongoing diplomatic tensions between <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-canada-diplomatic-row-justin-trudeau-admits-canada-has-only-intel-no-evidence-in-nijjar-killing-6807798">India and Canada</a>, India has raised concerns over Canada's handling of criminals linked to organised crime. Ministry of External Affairs spokesperson Randhir Jaiswal today alleged Canada's reluctance to extradite individuals associated with the Lawrence Bishnoi gang, a notorious criminal organisation based in India, involved in crimes in Canada.</p>

<p>"We find it really strange that people we asked to be deported, Canada cops are now claiming that these people are committing crimes in Canada, for which India is being blamed," Mr Jaiswal stated.&nbsp;On India's extradition requests, Mr Jaiswal said "26 are pending for a decade or more. Several probational requests are pending too."</p>

<p><strong>READ </strong>| <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-canada-diplomatic-row-justin-trudeau-admits-canada-has-only-intel-no-evidence-in-nijjar-killing-6807798">Justin Trudeau's Big Admission Amid India-Canada Diplomatic Showdown</a></p>

<p>Since September 2023, diplomatic ties between India and Canada have worsened, largely triggered by the killing of Khalistani terrorist Hardeep Singh Nijjar in Canada. Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau publicly accused India of being involved in the killing, a claim which India has categorically rejected. Mr Jaiswal reaffirmed India's position during a recent press briefing, stating that despite multiple allegations from Canada, there remains "no shred of evidence" linking the Indian government to Nijjar's murder.</p>

<p>"We have made our position very clear through various press releases. Since September 2023, there has been no evidence provided, and just last night, we issued another press release reiterating our stance," Mr Jaiswal said. "So far Canada has not given any evidence to back their allegations. &nbsp;Their allegations are politically motivated. &nbsp;Clear pattern to smear India for reasons best known to them."</p>

<p>In addition to rejecting the accusations, India recently withdrew its diplomats from Canada, citing safety concerns, after which Canada expelled several Indian officials, further straining the relationship.</p>

<p><strong>READ </strong>| <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-pak-match-soon-cricket-comes-up-in-s-jaishankars-islamabad-visit-6809377">"Inaccurate Reports": Centre On Cricket Coming Up In S Jaishankar's Pakistan Visit</a></p>

<p>"We value our strong trade ties with Canada and our people-to-people links, especially given the large number of Indian students in Canada. But the current situation has been precipitated entirely by the Trudeau government," Mr Jaiswal explained, adding that Canada benefits from these relations, and India has shown restraint despite the provocative steps taken by Ottawa.</p>

<h3><strong>Ex-Raw Officer 'No Longer Employed'</strong></h3>

<p>On a related note, the United States Department of Justice (DOJ) today named a former Research and Analysis Wing (RAW) officer, referred to as 'CC1,' in its indictment over a failed plot to assassinate another Khalistani terrorist, Gurpatwant Singh Pannun. The United States confirmed that this individual is "no longer employed by the Indian government."</p>

<p>Mr Jaiswal today corroborated the US claim by confirming that the individual is no longer an Indian government employee.</p>

<p><strong>READ </strong>| <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/as-we-had-said-no-evidence-whatsoever-india-on-justin-trudeaus-deposition-6806506">"As We Had Said, No Evidence Whatsoever": India On Justin Trudeau's Deposition</a></p>

<p>US State Department spokesperson Matthew Miller, during a press briefing, confirmed that both India and the US are conducting separate but coordinated investigations into the plot. Miller said that a "productive meeting" had taken place between the Indian inquiry committee and US officials.</p>

<h3><strong>Justin Trudeau's Admission&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>In a startling admission during a public inquiry, Prime Minister Trudeau admitted that Canada had no "hard evidentiary proof" to support allegations linking Indian government agents to the killing of Nijjar last year.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Speaking during a public inquiry into alleged foreign interference in Canada's federal electoral processes and democratic institutions, Mr Trudeau revealed that his claims about India's involvement were based on intelligence rather than conclusive evidence.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"I was briefed on the fact that there was intelligence from Canada, and possibly from Five Eyes allies that made it fairly clear, incredibly clear, that India was involved in this... Agents of the government of India were involved in the killing of a Canadian on Canadian soil," he said.</p>

<p>Nijjar, a designated terrorist by India's National Investigation Agency in 2020, was shot dead outside a gurdwara in Surrey, British Columbia, in June 2023. The Royal Canadian Mounted Police (RCMP) later stated that six Indian diplomats were allegedly part of a plot to murder Nijjar. The Canadian Police also suggested that the Bishnoi gang was connected to Indian government agents.</p>

<p>Mr Trudeau explained that Canada had the option to go public with the allegations during the G20 summit held in New Delhi in September 2023 but chose not to.</p>

<p>"Our response was, well, it's within your security agencies," Mr Trudeau said, recounting Canada's exchanges with India. "At that point, it was primarily intelligence, not hard evidentiary proof. So we said, let's work together and look into your security services."</p>

<p>Mr Trudeau added that he confronted Prime Minister Narendra Modi during the G20 summit, claiming that Canada was aware of India's alleged involvement. According to Mr Trudeau, PM Modi's response was to express concern about individuals in Canada critical of the Indian government, requesting that they be arrested.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/e1e9ifjo_trudeau-bishnoi_650x400_15_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[In addition to rejecting the accusations, India recently withdrew its diplomats from Canada.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/meta-fires-24-employees-for-misusing-25-meal-credits-on-toothpaste-detergent-6810327]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Meta Fires Employees For Using $25 Meal Credits On Toothpaste, Detergent]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/meta-fires-24-employees-for-misusing-25-meal-credits-on-toothpaste-detergent-6810327]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 17 Oct 2024 16:00:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The misuse of these benefits, which included sending meals home when employees weren't in the office, resulted in a formal HR investigation and subsequent firings.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Meta Platforms, Inc, an American multinational technology conglomerate that owns and operates Facebook, Instagram, Threads, and WhatsApp, reportedly fired 24 employees at its Los Angeles offices for using their $25 meal credits to purchase items such as toothpaste, laundry detergent, and wine glasses, according to <em>The Guardian.</em></p>

<p>The company, which employs over 70,000 people, fired employees last week after an inquiry showed that they were misusing the system, including sending meals home when they were not in the office, according to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2024/oct/17/meta-fires-staff-free-meal-vouchers-buy-household-goods"><em>the news site.</em></a> One unnamed worker on a $400,000 (308,070 pounds) salary claimed to have spent their meal credits on household goods and groceries like toothpaste and tea.</p>

<p>"On days where I would not be eating at the office, like if my husband was cooking or if I was grabbing dinner with friends, I figured I ought not to waste the dinner credit," the employee wrote on Blind, an anonymous messaging platform.</p>

<p>According to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ft.com/content/7d1a2738-2518-4ddb-811b-8abf9a745590"><em>Financial Times,</em></a> which first reported the story, the worker admitted the breach when approached as part of a human resources investigation into the practice and was later fired. "It was almost surreal that this was happening," the person wrote.</p>

<p>Free food has always been one of the benefits of working for a huge IT company. Meta is placed 91st on <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.forbes.com/companies/meta-platforms/?list=powerful-brands">Forbes</a>' list of the world's greatest employers (2024).</p>

<p>The company was founded by Mark Elliot Zuckerberg, Dustin Moskovitz, Chris R Hughes, Andrew McCollum, and Eduardo P. Saverin on February 4, 2004 and is headquartered in Menlo Park, CA.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/c99ca29o_meta-generic_625x300_17_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Meta employees allegedly spent their $25 credits on non-food items.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/italy-makes-it-illegal-to-seek-surrogacy-abroad-6810138]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Italy Makes It Illegal To Seek Surrogacy Abroad]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/italy-makes-it-illegal-to-seek-surrogacy-abroad-6810138]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 17 Oct 2024 15:34:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Italy's parliament made it illegal on Wednesday for couples to go abroad to have a baby via surrogacy -- a pet project of Prime Minister's Giorgia Meloni party which activists say is meant to target same-sex partners.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Italy's parliament made it illegal on Wednesday for couples to go abroad to have a baby via surrogacy -- a pet project of Prime Minister's Giorgia Meloni party which activists say is meant to target same-sex partners.</p>

<p>Since taking office in 2022 Meloni has pursued a highly conservative social agenda, looking to promote what she sees as traditional family values, making it progressively harder for LGBTQ couples to become legal parents.</p>

<p>The upper house Senate voted into law a bill proposed by Meloni's Brothers of Italy party by 84 votes to 58. The bill was already approved by the lower house last year.</p>

<p>The legislation extends a surrogacy ban already in place in Italy since 2004 to those who go to countries such as the United States or Canada, where it is legal, imposing jail terms of up to two years and fines of up to 1 million euros ($1.09 million).</p>

<p>"Motherhood is absolutely unique, it absolutely cannot be surrogated, and it is the foundation of our civilisation," Brothers of Italy senator Lavinia Mennuni said during the parliamentary debate.</p>

<p>"We want to uproot the phenomenon of surrogacy tourism."</p>

<p>Earlier this year, Meloni called surrogacy an 'inhuman' practice that treated children as supermarket products, echoing a position expressed by the Catholic Church.</p>

<p>On Tuesday, demonstrators gathered near the Senate voicing their outrage at the bill, saying the government was lashing out at LGBTQ people and damaging those who wanted to have children despite the fact Italy has a sharply declining birth rate.</p>

<p>"If someone has a baby, they should be given a medal. Here instead you are sent to jail... if you don't have children in the traditional way," Franco Grillini, a long-time activist for LGBTQ rights in Italy, told Reuters at the demonstration.</p>

<p>Rainbow Families President Alessia Crocini said 90% of Italians who choose surrogacy are heterosexual couples but they mostly do so in secret, meaning the new ban would de facto affect only gay couples who cannot hide it.</p>

<p>The clampdown on surrogacy comes against the backdrop of falling birthrates, with national statistics institute ISTAT saying in March that births had dropped to a record low in 2023 -- the 15th consecutive annual decline.</p>

<p>"This is a monstrous law. No country in the world has such a thing," said Grillini, referring to the government's move to prevent Italians from taking advantage of practices that are perfectly legal in some countries.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/rgjlpjm8_italy-surrogacy-ban-protests_625x300_17_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The legislation extends a surrogacy ban already in place in Italy since 2004]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/massive-door-spotted-in-antarctica-sparks-theories-what-scientists-say-6810088]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Massive Door" Spotted In Antarctica Sparks Theories. What Scientists Say]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/massive-door-spotted-in-antarctica-sparks-theories-what-scientists-say-6810088]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 17 Oct 2024 15:31:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Eagle-eyed users on Reddit first spotted the mysterious structure on Google Maps at the coordinates 69°00’50″S 39°36’22″E.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An unusual ice formation near Japan's Showa Station in East Antarctica has sparked wild theories across the internet. This rectangular shape, resembling a massive doorway, has led some to speculate about its origins, with suggestions ranging from a secret Nazi base to Bigfoot's vacation home.</p>

<p>Eagle-eyed users on Reddit first spotted the mysterious structure on Google Maps at the coordinates 69°00'50″S 39°36'22″E. One user asked, “Massive door in Antarctica?” Another suggested, “Just a blown-off Boeing door,” referencing a recent midair incident, while yet another joked, “Wonder if they get door dash there.”</p>

<blockquote class="reddit-embed-bq" data-embed-height="740" style="height:500px"><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/conspiracy/comments/1bjxevc/massive_door_in_antarctica_32024/">Massive door in Antarctica? 3/20/24</a><br />
by<a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/realg00n/">u/realg00n</a> in<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/conspiracy/">conspiracy</a></blockquote>
<script async="" src="https://embed.reddit.com/widgets.js" charset="UTF-8"></script>

<p>Scientists have since weighed in with a more grounded explanation. Bethan Davies, a professor of glaciology at the University of Newcastle, examined the coordinates using Google Earth Pro and historical imagery. She clarified, “This is an iceberg that became grounded and is now stuck and melting out [in place]. You can see many other icebergs in the area,” as per the <a href="https://nypost.com/2024/10/15/science/mysterious-doorway-discovered-in-antarctic-ice-via-google-maps-and-conspiracy-theorists-have-wild-ideas/">NY Post</a>.</p>

<p>Adding to this, Professor Martin Siegert, co-director of the Imperial College London's Grantham Institute on Climate Change and the Environment, said, “This is simply ice flow around a solid subglacial obstacle, influenced also by melting and refreezing of ice and by katabatic winds.” He emphasised that the ice in the region is quite thin, allowing for a strong influence of the bedrock on ice flow.</p>

<p>Glaciologist Richard Smellie pointed out that the formation likely resulted from a rocky ridge being exposed due to a lowering of the ice, contributing to the “doorway” appearance. He noted, “There are two prominent parallel snow tails forming the sides of the ‘doorway,'” indicating the predominant wind direction.</p>

<p>Mr Smellie added that with a good imagination, there is a weak and totally false door-like appearance overall. "I am pretty sure it's just a natural phenomenon and nothing to get excited about."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/vji48rcg_mysterious-antarctica-door_625x300_17_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[According to experts, this is just a "natural phenomenon"]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chinas-hackers-and-celebrities-fuel-taiwan-pressure-campaign-report-6809989]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[China's Hackers And Celebrities Fuel Taiwan Pressure Campaign: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chinas-hackers-and-celebrities-fuel-taiwan-pressure-campaign-report-6809989]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 17 Oct 2024 15:13:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In addition to military pressure, China is reportedly using hackers and celebrities to undermine Taiwan's commitment to self-rule.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A few days ago, Taiwan detected a record 153 Chinese military aircraft flying over the self-ruled island following a day of large-scale drills. The aircraft were seen on Tuesday (2200 GMT Monday), the defence ministry said in a statement, the most in a single day.</p>

<p>Beijing deployed fighter jets, drones, warships, and coast guard boats to encircle Taiwan on Monday, with Taiwan responding by dispatching "appropriate forces" and placing its outlying islands on heightened alert. Taiwan condemned China's actions as "irrational and provocative," and the US called them "unwarranted."</p>

<p>Now, in addition to military pressure, China has now adopted a new tactic by employing hackers and celebrities to influence public opinion in Taiwan and undermine its commitment to self-rule, according to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.wsj.com/world/asia/china-employs-hackers-and-celebrities-to-undermine-taiwan-435a3fd5"><em>Wall Street Journal </em></a>report.</p>

<p>As per the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.wsj.com/world/asia/china-employs-hackers-and-celebrities-to-undermine-taiwan-435a3fd5"><em>WSJ report,</em></a> more than 90,000 cyberattack attempts on Taiwan were detected in August, with targets including government infrastructure. It was the highest number since a surge two years earlier during a controversial visit to the island by then-US House Speaker Nancy Pelosi.</p>

<p>Taiwan officials say China has gone so far as to enlist Taiwanese celebrities in its cause.</p>

<p>"One of the ways they do this is by inviting well-known Taiwanese figures-whether they're from the arts, entertainment, or politics-to share pro-unification views," said Tsai Ming-yen, the head of Taiwan's National Security Bureau, after some celebrities posted maps of the Monday drills and expressed support for Beijing's "One China" policy.</p>

<p>According to a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.wsj.com/world/asia/china-employs-hackers-and-celebrities-to-undermine-taiwan-435a3fd5"><em>WSJ report,</em></a> officials in Taiwan say China's media campaign includes spreading disinformation designed to weaken U.S. confidence in the island's ability to defend itself. One message that circulated online during Monday's drills alleged that a Taiwanese naval captain had been drinking all night on Sunday. The investigation bureau of Taiwan's Justice Ministry said the claim was false.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/8j5qjtc8_cyber-crime_625x300_09_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[China has launched over 90,000 cyberattacks in August.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sean-diddy-combs-now-accused-of-revenge-rape-over-tupac-shakur-murder-claims-6808108]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Rapper Diddy Raped Woman As "Payback" Over Tupac Shakur Murder Claims]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sean-diddy-combs-now-accused-of-revenge-rape-over-tupac-shakur-murder-claims-6808108]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 17 Oct 2024 15:11:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Music mogul Sean "Diddy" Combs, who is in federal custody following multiple charges of racketeering and sex trafficking, has now been accused of raping a woman as "payback" after she suggested his involvement in rapper Tupac Shakur's murder.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Music mogul Sean “Diddy” Combs, who is in federal custody following multiple charges of racketeering and sex trafficking, has now been accused of raping a woman as "payback" after she suggested his involvement in rapper Tupac Shakur's murder. The woman, in her lawsuit filed in California on Tuesday, claimed that Combs even threatened to slash her face with a knife over the comments, <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c5y5m53g1ejo">BBC</a> reported.</p>

<p>In her lawsuit, the woman claimed she came on Combs' radar after meeting one of his friends at a bar in 2018. At the venue, the person was "attempting to impress" people by reportedly making video calls to Combs. But the woman refrained from taking part because she believed Combs "had something to do with" Shakur's murder.</p>

<p>She claimed he overheard her comment at the bar and said she would have to "pay" for it. Nearly a month later, Combs' friend asked her to help with his cancer drugs and she later visited him at his residence. However, the music mogul unexpectedly turned up there and then approached her with a knife. Holding it on the right side of her face, he threatened her to give a "'Glasgow smile' in retaliation for her previous statements".<br />
<br />
He tore her clothes and "violently" raped her using a TV remote control, as per the court documents. Further, she stated that Combs told her that her life was in his hands and that she would never be seen again if he wished.</p>

<p>This didn't stop there. The woman claimed she was raped by multiple people until she "had no control over her body nor could she move her body".</p>

<p>Eventually, when she tried to escape, the woman got confronted by Combs, who allegedly offered her money to mention that whatever happened was consensual and she was not raped. When he ran towards the neighbours' houses to seek help, gunshots were fired towards her, the lawsuit states.</p>

<p>Since the neighbours had already called the police after hearing the disturbance next door, the woman said she informed the Contra Costa Sheriff's Department how she was gang-raped by Combs and others. However, she alleged that no further action was taken in this matter.<br />
<br />
Three weeks after the incident, she went to the hospital where the staff called police officials. The victim said none of her reports led to any investigation.</p>

<p>Besides Combs, she sued six other people over sexual assault, kidnapping, and false imprisonment and is demanding a trial in the case.</p>

<p>Combs has denied all the charges against him. He earlier claimed that he did not have any involvement in the shooting incident that took the life of Shakur in Las Vegas in 1996. The case remains a mystery to date. However, a person named Duane "Keffe D" Davis -- a former gang member -- was charged with the murder in 2023. Previously, Davis alleged that he was offered $1 million by Combs for a hit on the late rapper.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/34g2r8_sean-diddy-combs_625x300_09_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Besides Combs, she sued six other people over sexual assault.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/jaishankar-makes-it-clear-at-sco-pakistan-is-now-just-a-sideshow-for-india-6809706]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: Jaishankar Makes It Clear: Pakistan Is Now Just A Sideshow For India]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/jaishankar-makes-it-clear-at-sco-pakistan-is-now-just-a-sideshow-for-india-6809706]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 17 Oct 2024 14:34:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[For the Modi government, there is neither any incentive nor any interlocutor on the other side to merit a change in its approach.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/ln1dupdo_pakistan_625x300_17_October_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>After generating days of excitement in the media, the Shanghai Cooperation Organisation (SCO) summit finally concluded with External Affairs Minister S. Jaishankar making a quick visit to Islamabad. For all the speculation about India and Pakistan, in the end, what the 23rd meeting of the Council of Heads of Government (CHG) of the SCO will likely be remembered for is perhaps Jaishankar's sunglasses. In this age of intense social media scrutiny, a small clip, now viral, of Jaishankar sporting his sunglasses in style became symbolic of India's confidence in dealing with Pakistan. Hilarious though this might seem, all that is left of Pakistan in Indian foreign policy imagination today is decoding our diplomats' style and body language.</p>

<p>But, of course, in sending Jaishankar to Islamabad for the SCO summit, New Delhi was also sending out a message about keeping its engagement with its SCO partners intact. Last year, when Bilawal Bhutto Zardari visited Goa to participate in the SCO meeting, he became the first Pakistani foreign minister to visit India since 2011. And now, Jaishankar was the first Indian foreign minister to visit Pakistan in around a decade. These visits though were largely inconsequential in the wider scheme of bilateral ties between the two neighbours.</p>

<h2><strong>Terrorism Continues To Upset Things</strong></h2>

<p>Established in 2001 and including Russia, China, India, Pakistan, Kazakhstan, Kyrgyzstan, Tajikistan, Uzbekistan, and Iran, the SCO is a Eurasian grouping that started out as a platform to deal with regional security challenges like extremism and terrorism. It later expanded to facilitating trade and investment and strengthening economic ties.</p>

<p>Since its inception, the SCO has prioritised the fight against terrorism, separatism, and extremism, as stated in Article 1 of its charter. India has focused on eliminating terrorism and terrorist groups along its northwest border while also promoting connectivity and socio-economic development across Eurasia. However, despite the SCO's goals, some member states have leveraged terrorism as an instrument of foreign policy, exacerbating tensions in Eurasia and against India.</p>

<p>Shifting geopolitical interests among the member countries have hindered the SCO's effectiveness in tackling state-sponsored terrorism. New Delhi has consistently advocated for greater cooperation on counterterrorism and has raised concerns about state-sponsored terrorism, particularly regarding Pakistan-based groups. But this has seen limited success. Furthermore, the differing views on achieving a peaceful, prosperous, and stable Afghanistan underscore the challenges faced by this Eurasian organisation, as member states often prioritise their own interests over a collective vision for peace in the region.</p>

<h2><strong>The 'Three Evils'</strong></h2>

<p>At the meeting in Islamabad, Jaishankar reminded the SCO about its original mandate and the need to adhere to the fundamentals. "It is axiomatic that development and growth require peace and stability. And as the Charter spelt out, this means being firm and uncompromising in countering the 'three evils'. If activities across borders are characterised by terrorism, extremism and separatism, they are hardly likely to encourage trade, energy flows, connectivity and people-to-people exchanges in parallel," Jaishankar underlined for the gathering.</p>

<p>If Pakistan was the target above, China was also not spared when he stated, "...Cooperation must be based on mutual respect and sovereign equality, recognise territorial integrity and sovereignty and be built on genuine partnerships, not unilateral agendas. SCO cannot progress if we cherry-pick global practices, especially of trade and transit." In line with its stated policy, India refused to endorse China's "One Belt One Road" initiative, thereby standing out in the SCO, where other members reaffirmed their support for China's connectivity initiative.</p>

<h2><strong>SCO Meet Was About Central Asia, Not Pakistan</strong></h2>

<p>Challenges from Pakistan and China notwithstanding, Central Asia remains an important foreign policy priority for India. Jaishankar's visit to Islamabad was a testament to that. Since becoming a full member in 2017, India has prioritised combating terrorism, and it continues to advocate for stronger counterterrorism measures and greater cooperation among member states to address this pressing issue. India's approach also focuses on connectivity and socio-economic development across Eurasia, aligning with its broader foreign policy objectives. Initiatives like the International North-South Transport Corridor and the Chabahar Port project demonstrate New Delhi's commitment to enhancing trade and connectivity within the region.</p>

<p>But the relationship with Pakistan is unlikely to change any time soon. It was only months back that Jaishankar had declared that the "era of uninterrupted dialogue" with Pakistan was over. "Actions have consequences, and as far as Jammu and Kashmir is concerned, Article 370 is done [away with]. The issue now is what kind of relationship we can contemplate with Pakistan. We are not passive; whether events take a positive or negative direction, we will react," he had suggested. For the Modi government, there is neither any incentive nor any interlocutor on the other side to merit a change in its approach. By visiting Islamabad, Jaishankar was signalling to the SCO members that New Delhi remains committed to the regional grouping despite the challenges it faces within. Pakistan was merely a sideshow.</p>

<p><em>(Harsh V. Pant is Vice President – Studies and Foreign Policy, at Observer Research Foundation, and Professor of International Relations at King's College London.)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/5n7dc188_jaishankar_625x300_17_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/2-mumbai-bound-international-flights-receive-bomb-threats-6809691]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[2 Mumbai-Bound International Flights Receive Bomb Threats]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/2-mumbai-bound-international-flights-receive-bomb-threats-6809691]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 17 Oct 2024 14:31:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The pattern of domestic airlines receiving bomb threats to their flights continued for the fourth day as two international flights, one each of Vistara and IndiGo, were targeted similarly on Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The pattern of domestic airlines receiving bomb threats to their flights continued for the fourth day as two international flights, one each of Vistara and IndiGo, were targeted in the similar manner on Thursday.</p>

<p>Earlier on Wednesday, seven flights of IndiGo, SpiceJet and Akasa received similar bomb threats.</p>

<p>Prior to that, nearly a dozen flights operated by Indian carriers received similar threats on Monday and Tuesday.</p>

<p>On Thursday a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/vistara-frankfurt-mumbai-flight-makes-emergency-landing-after-bomb-threat-6808170">Mumbai-bound Vistara flight</a> with 147 persons on board was immediately taken to security checks on its arrival from Frankfurt following the Boeing 787 aircraft receiving a bomb threat, according to the airline.</p>

<p>At the same time, an IndiGo flight operating from Istanbul in Turkiye for Mumbai also received a bomb threat and was taken to an isolation bay here for the security agencies to carry out a comprehensive security check.</p>

<p>"The Vistara flight UK 028 operating from Frankfurt to Mumbai on October 16, 2024 was subject to a security threat received on social media," the airline said.</p>

<p>As per the protocol, all relevant authorities were immediately informed, it said, adding the aircraft safely landed at the Chhatrapati Shivaji Maharaj International Airport, Mumbai.</p>

<p>"It was taken to the isolation bay where all customers were disembarked. We are fully cooperating with the security agencies to complete the mandatory security checks," Vistara said in the statement.</p>

<p>There were 134 passengers and 13 crew on board the aircraft, a source said.</p>

<p>The aircraft, which departed for Mumbai from Frankfurt on Wednesday at 8.20 pm (local time), made an emergency landing here at around 7.45 am on Thursday, the source said.</p>

<p>IndiGo in a statement said, "Flight 6E 18, operating from Istanbul to Mumbai, received a security-related alert. Upon landing, the aircraft was isolated, and all passengers were safely disembarked." The airline worked closely with the relevant authorities, and standard operating procedures were followed, it said.</p>

<p>IndiGo, however, did not share other details.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/fkcdpj18_vistara_625x300_01_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Two international flights, one each of Vistara and IndiGo, received bomb threats.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-pak-match-soon-cricket-comes-up-in-s-jaishankars-islamabad-visit-6809377]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Inaccurate Reports": Centre On Cricket Coming Up In S Jaishankar's Pak Visit]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-pak-match-soon-cricket-comes-up-in-s-jaishankars-islamabad-visit-6809377]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 17 Oct 2024 13:42:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Centre rejected reports on cricket featuring in talks between External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar and his Pakistani counterpart Ishaq Dar in Islamabad.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Centre rejected reports on cricket featuring in talks between External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar and his Pakistani counterpart Ishaq Dar in Islamabad.&nbsp;The Ministry of External Affairs in its briefing said the "reports are not accurate".&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Centre said no bilateral meeting happened during the SCO summit except with Mongolia. MEA spokesperson Randhir Jaiswal said "No pull aside meeting took place either", only "general talks happened during dinner and nothing else."&nbsp;S Jaishankar and Ishaq Dar reportedly sat next to each other during lunch.</p>

<p>Earlier, reports surfaced that Mr Jaishankar and Mr Dar had met and talked about a possible India-Pakistan cricket match soon. The two cricketing rivals have not played any bilateral series since 2012 when Pakistan toured India for a T20I and ODI series.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, India has not played any match in Pakistan since the 2008 Asia Cup due to tensions between the two countries arising out of the Mumbai terror attacks. Pakistan has made three tours to India since 2008 but India hasn't sent its team to Pakistan due to security concerns.</p>

<p>The two teams have played against each other in ICC tournaments in India and abroad, but&nbsp;Pakistan wants India to send its team for the ICC Champions Trophy, set to be hosted by the neighbouring nation next February.</p>

<p>Top officials of the England and Wales Cricket Board had recently told the PCB that organising the Champions Trophy without India would be meaningless since it would impact the ICC's revenue.</p>

<p>Mr Jaishankar was in Islamabad for the Shanghai Cooperation Organisation (SCO) meeting of Heads of Government, which marked the first Pakistan visit by an Indian foreign minister since 2015.</p>

<p>During his visit, Mr Jaishankar met Prime Minister Sharif at the multilateral event but did not hold any bilateral with Pakistan. Mr Jaishankar had clarified that India-Pakistan ties won't feature during his Islamabad visit since it was for the SCO summit.</p>

<p>At the SCO summit, he delivered a strong and veiled message aimed at Pakistan, stating that cooperation in areas like trade is unlikely to flourish if cross-border activities are characterised by terrorism.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/hkckchho_jaishankar-shehbaz-sharif_625x300_17_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[S Jaishankar and Ishaq Dar sat next to each other during the lunch.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-court-orders-arrest-warrant-for-ex-prime-minister-sheikh-hasina-6809213]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh Court Orders Arrest Warrant For Ex-Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-court-orders-arrest-warrant-for-ex-prime-minister-sheikh-hasina-6809213]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 17 Oct 2024 13:22:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Bangladeshi court on Thursday ordered an arrest warrant for exiled ex-leader Sheikh Hasina, who fled to India in August after she was toppled from power by a student-led revolution.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Bangladeshi court on Thursday ordered an arrest warrant for exiled ex-leader Sheikh Hasina, who fled to India in August after she was toppled from power by a student-led revolution.</p>

<p>"The court has... ordered the arrest of former prime minister Sheikh Hasina and to produce her in court on November 18," Mohammad Tajul Islam, chief prosecutor of Bangladesh's International Crimes Tribunal, told reporters on Thursday.</p>

<p>Hasina's 15-year rule saw widespread human rights <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-violence-quota-protests-5-more-murder-cases-filed-against-sheikh-hasina-total-cases-now-71-report-6430267">abuses</a>, including the mass detention and extrajudicial killings of her political opponents.</p>

<p>"Sheikh Hasina was at the helm of those who committed massacres, killings and crimes against humanity from July to August", Islam said, calling it a "remarkable day".</p>

<p>Hasina, 77, has not been seen in public since fleeing Bangladesh, and her last official whereabouts are at a military airbase near India's capital New Delhi.</p>

<p>Her presence in India has infuriated Bangladesh.</p>

<p>Dhaka has revoked her diplomatic passport, and the countries have a bilateral extradition treaty which would permit her to return to face criminal trial.</p>

<p>A clause in the treaty, however, says extradition might be refused if the offence is of a "political character".</p>

<p>Hasina's government created the deeply contentious ICT in 2010 to probe atrocities during the 1971 independence war from Pakistan.</p>

<p>The United Nations and rights groups criticised its procedural shortcomings, and it became widely seen as a means for Hasina to eliminate political opponents.</p>

<p>Several cases accusing Hasina of orchestrating the "mass murder" of protesters are being probed by the court.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/81hfi6o_sheikh-hasina_625x300_07_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sheikh Hasina's 15-year rule saw widespread human rights abuses, including extrajudicial killings. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-2024-saying-what-was-reported-donald-trump-stands-by-claims-of-immigrants-eating-pets-6809059]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Saying What Was Reported": Trump Stands By Claims Of Immigrants Eating Pets]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-2024-saying-what-was-reported-donald-trump-stands-by-claims-of-immigrants-eating-pets-6809059]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 17 Oct 2024 13:00:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump on Wednesday stood by debunked claims that immigrants in Ohio were eating pets, telling Latino voters during a town hall he was "just saying what was reported."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump on Wednesday stood by debunked claims that immigrants in Ohio were eating pets, telling Latino voters during a town hall he was "just saying what was reported."</p>

<p>Trump in recent weeks has amplified a false claim that has gone viral that Haitian immigrants in Springfield, Ohio, were stealing residents' pets or taking wildlife from parks for food.</p>

<p>There have been no credible reports of Haitians eating pets, and officials in Ohio - including Republicans - have repeatedly said the story is untrue.</p>

<p>At a town hall hosted by Univision, an undecided Latino Republican voter from Arizona, a battleground state, asked Trump whether he truly believed that immigrants were eating pets.</p>

<p>"I was just saying what was reported. All I do is report," Trump replied during the event held in Miami. "I was there, I'm going to be there and we're going to take a look."</p>

<p>Trump added that "newspapers" had also reported on the claim, without naming any or providing any details.</p>

<p>Trump, who has not yet travelled to Springfield, has previously said he would conduct mass deportations of Haitian immigrants from the Ohio city, even though the majority of them are in the US legally.</p>

<p>The city has faced bomb threats since Trump began repeating the false accusations about Haitians.</p>

<p>In the final weeks before the Nov. 5 election, Trump is increasingly resorting to darker and more violent language about illegal immigration, an issue that opinion polls show resonates with many voters, especially Republicans.</p>

<p>He is competing against Democrat Kamala Harris for key votes from the growing Latino population. Latino voters have typically backed Democrats, but the Trump campaign is hoping to win over more Latino voters, especially men, on the back of economic discontent.</p>

<p>Harris led Trump by eight percentage points - 47% to 39% - among Hispanic voters in Reuters/Ipsos polling conducted between Sept. 11 and Oct. 7.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/bdehpaas_donald-trump_625x300_17_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Trump has amplified a false claim that Haitian immigrants in Ohio were stealing residents' pets for food.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/texas-man-with-autism-faces-death-penalty-due-to-alleged-child-murder-6808975]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Texas Man With Autism Faces Death Penalty Due To Alleged Child Murder]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/texas-man-with-autism-faces-death-penalty-due-to-alleged-child-murder-6808975]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 17 Oct 2024 12:50:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Texas pardons board rejected a clemency appeal on Wednesday from an autistic man on death row whose murder conviction was based on what his lawyers say was a misdiagnosis of "shaken baby syndrome."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Texas pardons board rejected a clemency appeal on Wednesday from an autistic man on death row whose murder conviction was based on what his lawyers say was a misdiagnosis of "shaken baby syndrome."</p>

<p>Robert Roberson, 57, is scheduled to die by lethal injection at the state penitentiary in Huntsville on Thursday for the February 2002 death of his two-year-old daughter, Nikki.</p>

<p>The Texas Board of Pardons and Paroles took up Roberson's case on Wednesday and declined by a 6-0 vote to recommend that Texas Governor Greg Abbott grant clemency.</p>

<p>Abbott is unable to grant clemency without a recommendation from the board, but he can grant a 30-day reprieve of Roberson's death sentence.</p>

<p>Gretchen Sween, one of Roberson's attorneys, urged the governor to grant the reprieve "so we can continue to pursue Mr Roberson's innocence claim."</p>

<p>"We pray that Governor Abbott does everything in his power to prevent the tragic, irreversible mistake of executing an innocent man," Sween said.</p>

<p>Roberson's case has drawn the attention of the Innocence Project, which works to reverse wrongful convictions, as well as best-selling American novelist John Grisham, Texas lawmakers and medical experts.</p>

<p>Also among those seeking to halt his execution is the man who put him behind bars -- Brian Wharton, the former chief detective in the town of Palestine.</p>

<p>"Knowing everything that I know now, I am firmly convinced that Robert is an innocent man," Wharton said at a recent press conference organized by Roberson's supporters. "The system failed Robert."</p>

<p>Grisham, author of the legal thrillers "The Firm" and "A Time to Kill," also appeared at the event and said: "What's amazing about Robert's case is that there was no crime."</p>

<p>Roberson's lawyers say the diagnosis of shaken baby syndrome, made at the hospital where his chronically ill daughter died, was erroneous and the cause of death was in fact pneumonia, which was aggravated when doctors prescribed improper medication.</p>

<p>Sween, Roberson's attorney, said there is "overwhelming new medical and scientific evidence" that shows that the little girl died of "natural and accidental causes, not abuse."</p>

<p>According to his lawyers, Roberson would be the first person executed in the United States based on a conviction of shaken baby syndrome.</p>

<h3><strong>'Unscientific'&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>According to Kate Judson of the Center for Integrity in Forensic Sciences, more than 30 parents and caregivers in 18 US states have been exonerated after being wrongfully convicted using "unscientific" shaken baby testimony.</p>

<p>Sween said Roberson's autism spectrum disorder, which was not diagnosed until 2018, contributed to his arrest and conviction.</p>

<p>"It is quite possible that Mr Roberson would not be on death row today, but for his autism," she said.</p>

<p>Sween said staff at the hospital where his daughter was admitted did not know he had autism and "judged his flat affect as a sign of guilt."</p>

<p>A bipartisan group of 86 Texas state lawmakers has also urged clemency for Roberson, citing the "voluminous new scientific evidence" that casts doubt on his guilt.</p>

<p>There have been 19 executions in the United States this year.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/63v1bdt_robert-robertson-x_625x300_17_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Roberson's autism spectrum disorder, was not diagnosed until 2018, leading to his arrest and conviction.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-a-first-us-uses-advanced-b-2-stealth-bombers-against-houthis-in-yemen-6808836]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[In A First, US Uses Advanced B-2 Stealth Bombers Against Houthis In Yemen]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-a-first-us-uses-advanced-b-2-stealth-bombers-against-houthis-in-yemen-6808836]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 17 Oct 2024 12:28:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United States launched a series of airstrikes on Wednesday evening targeting key underground weapons storage facilities controlled by Iran-backed Houthi rebels in Yemen.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United States launched a series of airstrikes on Wednesday evening targeting key underground weapons storage facilities controlled by Iran-backed <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/houthis-saudi-arabia-israel-explained-who-are-houthis-the-group-that-hijacked-an-india-bound-ship-4588672">Houthi rebels</a> in Yemen. The strikes, carried out by B-2 Spirit stealth bombers, marked the first-ever use of these advanced aircraft against Houthi targets since the beginning of US involvement in the Yemen conflict.</p>

<p>The US Department of Defense confirmed that five Houthi weapons storage sites, deeply buried underground, were struck in the mission. According to US Defense Secretary Lloyd Austin, these facilities housed advanced conventional weapons used by the Houthis to threaten civilian and military vessels operating in the Red Sea and Gulf of Aden.</p>

<h3><strong>Deployment Of B-2 Bombers</strong></h3>

<p>The B-2 Spirit bomber, known for its stealth capabilities and heavy payload, is capable of delivering a far greater volume of ordnance compared to fighter jets. The B-2 offers the US military an unparalleled ability to strike high-value targets that are either deeply fortified or well-concealed.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Mr Austin explained that the strikes were authorised at the direction of President Joe Biden. "This was a unique demonstration of the United States' ability to target facilities that our adversaries seek to keep out of reach, no matter how deeply buried or fortified," Mr Austin stated.</p>

<h3><strong>Growing Regional Tensions</strong></h3>

<p>The timing of the strikes comes amid heightened tensions in the Middle East, with US allies, particularly Israel, facing ongoing threats from Iran and its various regional proxies. The Houthis, operating from Yemen, have consistently launched attacks on commercial shipping and military vessels, disrupting one of the world's most critical maritime trade routes. In recent months, these attacks have escalated, with the group claiming responsibility for launching ballistic and cruise missiles as well as drones against US Navy ships and international vessels.</p>

<p>The Houthis' activities in the Red Sea and Gulf of Aden, targeting vessels with weaponry that originated from these underground storage sites, have raised alarms about the security of global trade routes and the potential for environmental catastrophes. In August, a Greek-flagged vessel came under attack, leading to an oil spill and serious environmental concerns.</p>

<p>In September, the Houthis escalated their campaign, launching approximately two dozen ballistic and cruise missiles, as well as drones, aimed at three US Navy destroyers. Although none of these missiles struck their targets, the attacks prompted increased military activity from US forces in the region.&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>Houthi Attacks Tied To Regional Conflicts</strong></h3>

<p>The Iran-backed Houthis have framed their actions as part of a broader alignment with groups like Hamas and Hezbollah, who are actively engaged in ongoing conflicts with Israel. Following an attempted missile strike deep inside Israel in September, the Houthis have openly declared their support for these groups. While the missile ultimately fragmented in mid-air and caused no injuries, Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu warned the Houthis would "pay a heavy price" for their actions. In retaliation, Israeli airstrikes targeted Houthi positions in Yemen shortly after the incident.</p>

<p><strong>READ </strong>| <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/houthis-israel-yemen-how-yemens-houthi-rebels-get-hold-of-ballistic-missiles-to-attack-israel-6576154">How Yemen's Houthi Rebels Got Hold Of Ballistic Missiles To Attack Israel</a></p>

<p>In the following weeks, the Houthis have continued launching missiles and drones toward Israel, further complicating the regional security landscape. These actions, combined with continued Houthi assaults on international shipping, have drawn significant military responses from the United States and its allies.</p>

<p>Wednesday's strike on Houthi facilities adds to a series of US military actions aimed at curbing the Houthis' growing arsenal and degrading their operational capabilities. US Central Command (CENTCOM) confirmed that there were no immediate civilian casualties from the latest strikes. Over the past year, the US has increased its military presence in the region, including the deployment of advanced naval assets such as carrier strike groups, amphibious ready groups, and guided missile destroyers, along with air support in the form of fighter jets and attack aircraft.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/4843vf98_b2-bomber-afp-_625x300_17_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[CENTCOM confirmed that there were no immediate civilian casualties from the latest strikes.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/un-report-says-1-1-billion-people-in-acute-poverty-6808703]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UN Report Says 1.1 Billion People In Acute Poverty]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/un-report-says-1-1-billion-people-in-acute-poverty-6808703]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 17 Oct 2024 12:08:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[More than one billion people are living in acute poverty across the globe, a UN Development Program report said, with children accounting for over half of those affected.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>More than one billion people are living in acute poverty across the globe, a UN Development Program report said Thursday, with children accounting for over half of those affected.</p>

<p>The paper published with the Oxford Poverty and Human Development Initiative (OPHI) highlighted that poverty rates were three times higher in countries at war, as 2023 saw the most conflicts around the world since the Second World War.</p>

<p>The UNDP and the OPHI have published their Multidimensional Poverty Index annually since 2010, harvesting data from 112 countries with a combined population of 6.3 billion people.</p>

<p>It uses indicators such as a lack of adequate housing, sanitation, electricity, cooking fuel, nutrition and school attendance.</p>

<p>"The 2024 MPI paints a sobering picture: 1.1 billion people endure multidimensional poverty, of which 455 million live in the shadow of conflict," said Yanchun Zhang, chief statistician at the UNDP.</p>

<p>"For the poor in conflict-affected countries, the struggle for basic needs is a far harsher and more desperate battle," Zhang told AFP.</p>

<p>The report echoed last year's findings that 1.1 billion out of 6.1 billion people across 110 countries were facing extreme multidimensional poverty.</p>

<p>Thursday's paper showed that some 584 million people under 18 were experiencing extreme poverty, accounting for 27.9 percent of children worldwide, compared with 13.5 percent of adults.</p>

<p>It also showed that 83.2 percent of the world's poorest people live in Sub-Saharan Africa and South Asia.</p>

<p>Sabina Alkire, director of the OPHI, told AFP that conflicts were hindering efforts for poverty reduction.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"At some level, these findings are intuitive. But what shocked us was the sheer magnitude of people who are struggling to live a decent life and at the same time fearing for their safety –- 455 million," she said.</p>

<p>"This points to a stark but unavoidable challenge to the international community to both zero in on poverty reduction and foster peace, so that any ensuing peace actually endures," Alkire added.</p>

<p>India was the country with the largest number of people in extreme poverty, which impacts 234 million of its 1.4 billion population.</p>

<p>It was followed by Pakistan, Ethiopia, Nigeria and the Democratic Republic of the Congo. The five countries accounted for nearly half of the 1.1 billion poor people.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2016-12/poverty-generic_650x400_71481815480.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[India has the largest number of people in extreme poverty, impacting 234 million]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-urges-israel-to-allow-aid-access-to-gaza-amid-humanitarian-crisis-6808694]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[WHO Urges Israel To Allow Aid Access To Gaza Amid Humanitarian Crisis]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-urges-israel-to-allow-aid-access-to-gaza-amid-humanitarian-crisis-6808694]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 17 Oct 2024 12:05:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Amid the chaos, WHO and its partners launched the second round of a polio vaccination campaign on Monday, aiming to immunise over half a million children, Xinhua news agency reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The World Health Organization (WHO) urged Israel to grant access to Gaza, where escalating violence has blocked humanitarian missions from delivering critical food and medical supplies.</p>

<p>Amid the chaos, WHO and its partners launched the second round of a polio vaccination campaign on Monday, aiming to immunise over half a million children, Xinhua news agency reported.</p>

<p>"The total number of children who received a second dose of polio vaccine in Gaza after two days of vaccination is 156,943," WHO chief Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus wrote on X on Wednesday.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Escalating violence in the north of <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Gaza?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Gaza</a> has blocked humanitarian missions from reaching people with food and medical supplies. Meanwhile, health care continues to be attacked.<br />
<br />
We ask Israel to give <a href="https://twitter.com/WHO?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@WHO</a> and our partners access to the north so we can reach those who desperately… <a href="https://t.co/DVwvn7J2vM">pic.twitter.com/DVwvn7J2vM</a></p>
— Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus (@DrTedros) <a href="https://twitter.com/DrTedros/status/1846632479014203602?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 16, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>However, ongoing violence threatens the campaign's goal of vaccinating at least 90 per cent of the children, a critical target to halt the virus's spread. In addition to polio vaccines, children are receiving vitamin A supplements to strengthen their immunity.</p>

<p>WHO highlighted the severity of the situation, reporting that out of 54 scheduled United Nations missions to Gaza in October, only one has been completed, with the rest either cancelled or obstructed due to the conflict.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/2f4g9i6o_gaza-polio-vaccination_625x300_16_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[WHO aims to administer polio vaccine to atleast 90% of the children in Gaza.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/india-canada-row-when-fiction-is-as-important-as-facts-6808464]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: India-Canada Showdown: When Fiction Is As Important As Facts]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/india-canada-row-when-fiction-is-as-important-as-facts-6808464]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 17 Oct 2024 11:32:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[What has compelled Canada to make public its investigations in the Nijjar assassination case and hold India responsible? Has there been a slight or a breach of trust, intended or otherwise, behind the scenes that a public show is to be put up?]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/cbi4u6gg_justin_625x300_17_October_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>"We're not so different, you and I. We've both spent our lives looking for the weakness in one another's systems. Don't you think it's time to recognize there is as little worth on your side as there is on mine?"</p>

<p>Those who've been rooting for Gary Oldman playing Jackson Lamb, the instantly unlikeable boss of the good-for-nothings of MI5, the British intelligence agency, in Apple's <em>Slow Horses</em>, may not even remember this line the actor delivered playing another spy boss in another spy thriller: as George Smiley in<em> Tinker Tailor Soldier Spy,</em> a 2011 film based on John la Carre's book.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Addressed to Smiley's Russian counterpart, Karla, this line, emblematic of the film's politics, was celebrated and decried in equal measure for creating an equivalence between the US and the USSR during the Cold War. Going by the recent media stories and diplomatic activity, George Smiley could have very well said it about India and Canada today.</p>

<h2><strong>Blow Hot, Blow Cold</strong></h2>

<p>New Delhi and Ottawa have expelled each other's top diplomats, following the Canadian Prime Minister's latest accusation of the Indian establishment being directly involved in the assassination of a Sikh separatist on Canadian soil. India, on the other hand, has not only denied it but also mounted a counterattack on Canada for nurturing anti-India groups within its territory.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Fall is not fair weather for India-Canada relations. Exactly one year ago, the two countries were engaged in similar diplomatic acrimony over the same assassination. Khalistan, after nuclear proliferation, has been their proverbial bee in the bonnet for several decades. With the exception of the lull during the turn of the millennium, the issue has stayed alive and volatile. It is not going anywhere in a hurry.</p>

<p>Canada's soft approach towards anti-India outfits was once attributed solely to its domestic politics: the country is home to the largest Sikh diaspora, with around 7,70,000 of them living there. The current strain in the relationship, however, may not just be about Canada's vote bank politics or India's internal affairs involving resistance from a sect of Sikhs. There is, quite clearly, an emergence of bilateral antagonism now. Are the rapprochement personnel doing their job well? Or, more provocatively, are the spies doing theirs?</p>

<h2><strong>Flashbacks From 1975</strong></h2>

<p>Realistically speaking, assassinations on foreign soil are not a no-go zone, even with declared enemies, if the assassins are smart. The morality and legality of such actions is another story. What, then, has compelled Canada, a limited ally, to make public its investigations in the Nijjar assassination case and hold India responsible? Has there been a slight or a breach of trust, intended or otherwise, behind the scenes that a public show is to be put up? Are there bad-faith actors at work on either side, or is it sheer incompetence? It could be either or both, but as venerable Canadian writer Margaret Atwood reminds us, "Stupidity is the same as evil if you judge by the results". Therefore, it's the breakdown of bilateral ties that matters, much more than the nitty-gritty of what caused it.&nbsp;</p>

<p>This escalation of diplomatic tensions between India and Canada is beginning to loosely resemble another controversial diplomatic event that occurred half a century ago: the breakdown of the then newly forged Australia-North Korea relations. On October 30, 1975, Pyongyang recalled its diplomats from Canberra, citing the host country's 'unfriendly attitude' and 'intolerable provocative acts' in a communication sent via commercial mail. Less than ten days later, Australian diplomats were ousted from Pyongyang on November 8 on account of 'unfriendly behaviour' and 'abuse of diplomatic immunity'.</p>

<p>The actors and the times are different, but the problem is the same. This inability to smoothen out the rough edges time and again reflects poorly on the political and diplomatic leaders of India and Canada. What are long bilateral ties worth if they cannot withstand such events? Both Ottawa and New Delhi have engaged in the game of provocation and reconciliation. The classic blow-hot, blow-cold approach. To what end, though?&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>A Lesson From<em> Bridge Of Spies</em></strong></h2>

<p>Coming back to George Smiley's wisdom, looking for weaknesses in the other is a zero-sum game. This isn't the Cold War yet, but as India grows in stature, the chances of this game intensifying will increase correspondingly. India and Canada are not directly engaged in any military-territorial jostling, so these flare-ups have an even more limited scope. Both are citing long-term national security concerns, and other countries like the UK and the US are trying to broker 'peace' by urging India to cooperate in the investigation.</p>

<p>Diplomacy is an exercise in sifting fact from fiction but addressing both because both matter, even if unequally. Another popular culture reference to demonstrate it comes from <em>Bridge of Spies</em>, a 2014 film about the famous spy exchange between the US and USSR. James Donovan (Tom Hanks), a lawyer representing a Russian spy called Rudolf Abel (Mark Rylance), tells him, "The case against you matters. Making them prove it matters. The fiction is: whether you did it or not doesn't matter. The state has to prove it, that you're a spy".</p>

<p>Before anyone condescends about taking lessons from fiction, remember, apart from John la Carre, celebrated writers like Ian Fleming and Graham Greene once served in MI6.&nbsp;</p>

<p><em>(Nishtha Gautam is a Delhi-based author and academic.)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/kkm9j03o_justin_625x300_17_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/menendez-brothers-killed-parents-to-avoid-abuse-relatives-urge-their-release-6808424]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Menendez Brothers Killed Parents To Avoid Abuse, Relatives Urge Their Release]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/menendez-brothers-killed-parents-to-avoid-abuse-relatives-urge-their-release-6808424]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 17 Oct 2024 11:26:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Relatives of Lyle and Erik Menendez on Wednesday pleaded for the release of the long-imprisoned brothers as US prosecutors review new evidence concerning the infamous 1989 murder of their parents.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Relatives of Lyle and Erik Menendez on Wednesday pleaded for the release of the long-imprisoned brothers as US prosecutors review new evidence concerning the infamous 1989 murder of their parents.</p>

<p>The grisly shotgun slayings of wealthy music mogul Jose Menendez and his wife Kitty in their Beverly Hills home -- and their sons' subsequent, televised murder trials -- became the subject of a media frenzy. A hit Netflix series has recently sparked fresh interest in the case.</p>

<p>The brothers, aged 21 and 18 at the time of the murders, tearfully testified they killed their parents for fear of their own lives after years of sexual abuse by their father.&nbsp;</p>

<p>They were convicted of first-degree murder and have been serving life sentences in prison without possibility of parole since their sentencing in 1996.</p>

<p>"As details of Lyle and Eric's abuse came to light, it became clear that their actions, while tragic, were the desperate response of two boys trying to survive the unspeakable cruel(ty) of their father," their 92-year-old aunt Joan VanderMolen said Wednesday.</p>

<p>"Lyle and Erik have already paid a heavy price, discarded by a system that failed to recognize their pain," she told a news conference attended by some 30 relatives.</p>

<p>Their initial trial, starting in 1993, was one of the first televised murder cases to make daily headlines around the world. It ended in a mistrial due to a deadlocked jury, but they were found guilty in a second trial.</p>

<p>Prosecutors argued they conspired to murder their parents in order to inherit their $14 million fortune.</p>

<p>Last year, the brothers' attorneys filed a court petition setting out new evidence which they said demonstrates Jose Menendez's history of sexual abuse.</p>

<p>Among the new evidence is a letter Erik wrote to a cousin months before the murders, saying "I've been trying to avoid dad. It's still happening... Every night I stay up thinking he might come in."</p>

<p>Former Latino boy band member Roy Rossello said in a documentary series released last year that he was drugged and raped by Jose Menendez in the 1980s.</p>

<p>The brothers' attorneys have called for a resentencing, which could see their clients released from prison given the lengthy time already spent behind bars.</p>

<p>Prosecutors said in a statement Wednesday that Los Angeles's criminal justice system "has developed a more modern understanding of sexual violence since the Menendez brothers first faced prosecution."&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Today, our office acknowledges that sexual violence is a pervasive issue affecting countless individuals -- of all gender identities," they wrote, confirming the case is being reviewed on multiple fronts.</p>

<p>Earlier this month, Los Angeles district attorney George Gascon told reporters he had "a moral and an ethical obligation to review what is being presented to us."</p>

<p>His comments came two weeks after the release on Netflix of the crime drama "Monsters: The Lyle and Erik Menendez Story." The streaming giant also put out a documentary film, "The Menendez Brothers," last week.</p>

<p>Gascon, who is running for re-election on a criminal reform platform, acknowledged the initial Netflix show resulted in a large number of calls to his office about the case.</p>

<p>A hearing is scheduled for November 26.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/aqk3mbmg_menendez-brothers-x_625x300_17_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Their initial trial, starting in 1993, made headlines across the world.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>