<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Sep 2024 21:10:30 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/woman-walks-past-twin-brothers-grave-for-years-discovers-it-in-landfill-for-babies-6513592]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Woman Walks Past Brothers' Grave For Years, Discovers 'Landfill for Babies']]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/woman-walks-past-twin-brothers-grave-for-years-discovers-it-in-landfill-for-babies-6513592]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Sep 2024 21:10:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The shocking find was made by a woman who had spent decades searching for her twin brothers who passed away in 1962.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A shocking discovery has been made in a British cemetery. In Royton Cemetery in Oldham, a mass grave containing more than 300 bodies-mostly those of stillborn babies and small children-has been discovered, according to <em>The Metro.</em> The remains of 145 stillborn infants, 128 babies and young children, and 29 adults were discovered within the 12-by-12-foot burial. These people's remains have been buried at the unmarked burial site for a long time.</p>

<p>The person who discovered them was a woman who had spent decades trying to find the graves of her twin brothers, who had passed away in 1962. While the other twin died soon after birth, the first twin was stillborn. After searching, the woman found the mass burial.</p>

<p>"I live near the cemetery, and I used to walk through it with my mother all the time, and we had no idea they were buried there," she told the MailOnline. "I get upset speaking about it because my mother died and is buried in the same cemetery, but she never knew they were there."</p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://metro.co.uk/2024/09/06/bodies-babies-children-found-mass-grave-21558406/"><em>The Metro,</em></a> up until the 1980s, parents of stillborn children were kept in the dark by doctors over the fate of their lost children-many were taken away without the parents ever knowing where they were buried, typically in mass graves. Bereaved parents were instead told their child was buried alongside a 'nice person' that same day.</p>

<p>"My brothers were only a year older, and I have one younger brother, but I saw growing up how the grief affected my parents without any support," Sarah said.</p>

<p>The boys weren't on any official records, so Sarah spent years in a 'merry-go-round' of genealogy companies, council officials, and coroners to find them.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/faoqb2jg_royton-cemetery_625x300_07_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The discovery reveals a past practice of burying stillborn children without informing parents.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/super-typhoon-yagi-makes-landfall-in-vietnam-kills-4-6513191]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Super Typhoon Yagi Makes Landfall In Vietnam, Kills 4]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/super-typhoon-yagi-makes-landfall-in-vietnam-kills-4-6513191]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Sep 2024 20:03:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Asia's most powerful storm this year made landfall in northern Vietnam on Saturday, the meteorological agency said, killing at least four people after tearing through China's island of Hainan and the Philippines.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Asia's most powerful storm this year made landfall in northern Vietnam on Saturday, the meteorological agency said, killing at least four people after tearing through China's island of Hainan and the Philippines.</p>

<p>Super Typhoon Yagi hit island districts of north Vietnam around 1 p.m. (0600 GMT), generating winds of up to 160 kph (99 mph) near its centre, having lost power from its peak of 234 kph (145 mph) in Hainan a day earlier.</p>

<p>The government said that as of 5 p.m. four people had died and 78 had been injured by the typhoon. At least another dozen were missing at sea, according to state media.</p>

<p>Yagi had already claimed the lives of at least two people in Hainan and 16 people in the Philippines, the first country it hit, having formed east of the archipelago earlier in the week.</p>

<p>Vietnam's coastal city of Haiphong, an industrial hub with a population of 2 million people that hosts factories from foreign multinationals and local carmaker VinFast, was among the hardest-hit by winds with speeds of up to 90 kph.</p>

<p>As the typhoon approached, the city experienced widespread power outages on Saturday, authorities said, as did at least three other northern provinces.</p>

<p>In Haiphong, the strong winds smashed windows and waves were as much as three meters high when they hit the coast, according to a Reuters witness.</p>

<p>Metal roofing sheets were blown away, pictures and footage on local media showed. The government said thousands of trees had fallen and many houses were damaged across northern Vietnam.</p>

<p>Earlier in Hainan, which has a population of more than 10 million, the storm felled trees, flooded roads and cut power to more than 800,000 homes.</p>

<p><strong>AIRPORTS CLOSED</strong></p>

<p>Vietnam evacuated more than 50,000 people from coastal towns and deployed 450,000 military personnel, the government said.</p>

<p>It also suspended operations for several hours at four airports on Saturday, including Hanoi's Noi Bai, the busiest in the north, which cancelled more than 300 flights.</p>

<p>High schools were also closed in 12 northern provinces, including in the capital Hanoi, which has a population of 8.5 million.</p>

<p>Authorities in the capital suspended public transport on buses and its two elevated metro lines on Saturday afternoon, state media reported. The meteorological agency has warned of risks of heavy flooding in the city centre.</p>

<p>Hanoi resident Nguyen Manh Quan, 40, said: "The wind is strong enough to blow a person over," while Dang Van Phuong, also 40, said: "I've never seen a storm like this, you can't drive in these winds."</p>

<p>Typhoons are becoming stronger, fuelled by warmer oceans, amid climate change, scientists say.</p>

<p>Last week, Typhoon Shanshan slammed into southwestern Japan, the strongest storm to hit the country in decades.</p>

<p>Yagi is named after the Japanese word for goat and the constellation of Capricornus.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/hbnnboc8_typhoon-yagi-vietnam_625x300_07_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[At least another dozen were missing at sea in Vietna, according to state media.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-uk-spy-chiefs-make-1st-appearance-together-amid-gaza-ukraine-crises-what-they-said-6513147]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US, UK Spy Chiefs Make 1st Appearance Together Amid Gaza, Ukraine Crises]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-uk-spy-chiefs-make-1st-appearance-together-amid-gaza-ukraine-crises-what-they-said-6513147]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Sep 2024 19:57:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The head of the CIA, who is also the chief U.S. negotiator seeking an end to the Gaza war and release of hostages held by Hamas, said a more detailed ceasefire proposal would be made in the next several days.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The head of the CIA, who is also the chief U.S. negotiator seeking an end to the Gaza war and release of hostages held by Hamas, said a more detailed ceasefire proposal would be made in the next several days.</p>

<p>CIA Director William Burns was speaking at a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ft.com/content/56d16869-f9e1-4c82-8022-5f8d2044c5cd" rel="No follow, no index" target="_blank">Financial Times</a> event in London alongside Richard Moore, head of Britain's MI6 foreign spy agency, the first time they had appeared together publicly.</p>

<p>After 11 months of conflict in Gaza, Burns is working for the United States with Qatar and Egypt to secure a ceasefire, and said there was ongoing work on "texts and creative formulas" for finding a proposal which satisfies both parties.</p>

<p>"We will make this more detailed proposal, I hope in the next several days, and then we'll see," he said. &nbsp;</p>

<p>He added that it was a question of political will and he hoped leaders on both sides recognised "the time has come finally to make some hard choices and some difficult compromises".</p>

<p>Hamas attacked Israel on Oct. 7 killing 1,200 people and taking about 250 hostages, according to Israeli tallies, while Israel's retaliatory offensive in Gaza has killed nearly 41,000 Palestinians, Gaza's health authorities have said, largely levelling the coastal enclave.</p>

<p>Burns and Moore had written a joint op-ed in the FT newspaper on Saturday before the event which highlighted the pair's joint efforts to help Ukraine in its war against Russia.</p>

<p><iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="400" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rp5PeoAW6mI?si=6dvEFnHHR1QBSqcJ&amp;start=440" title="YouTube video player" width="650"></iframe></p>

<p>They said "staying the course" in backing Ukraine was more important than ever and they vowed to further their cooperation there.</p>

<p>Discussing Ukraine's offensive into the Kursk region of Russia where Kyiv has seized land, Moore called it an "audacious and bold" move to try and change the game.</p>

<p>"It's too early to say how long the Ukrainians will be able to hang on in there (in Kursk)," he added.</p>

<p>While Burns called the offensive a "significant tactical achievement" for the Ukrainians, he added that he did not see any evidence that Russian President Vladimir Putin's grip on power was weakening.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/b8eupn3c_mi6-chief-richard-moore-cia-chief-william-burns-financial-times-summit_625x300_07_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[CIA Director William Burns and MI6 chief Richard Moore spoke at the Financial Times summit]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/1st-bird-flu-case-without-animal-contact-confirmed-in-us-6512976]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[1st Bird Flu Case Without Animal Contact Confirmed In US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/1st-bird-flu-case-without-animal-contact-confirmed-in-us-6512976]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Sep 2024 19:28:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A person in the state of Missouri has become the first in the United States to test positive for bird flu without a known exposure to infected animals, authorities said on Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A person in the state of Missouri has become the first in the United States to test positive for bird flu without a known exposure to infected animals, authorities said on Friday.</p>

<p>The adult patient, who has underlying conditions, was admitted to hospital on August 22, received antiviral medications against influenza, then recovered and was discharged, according to statements from the Centers for Control and Disease Prevention (CDC) and the Missouri Department of Health and Senior Services.</p>

<p>As the patient's flu type appeared suspicious on an initial test, it was sent for additional testing in state and federal laboratories, which revealed it was H5, also known as avian flu or bird flu.</p>

<p>The CDC said it had not identified any transmission to the patient's close contacts or any other person.</p>

<p>Scientists have voiced concern about the growing number of mammals becoming infected by bird flu, even if cases in humans remain rare.</p>

<p>They fear a high rate of transmission could facilitate a mutation of the virus, which could enable it to be passed from one human to another.</p>

<p>Contacted by AFP, the World Health Organization said on Saturday it was "encouraging that the national disease surveillance system has identified this case, that the patient received antiviral treatment, and that no further cases have been detected among close contacts".</p>

<p>"It is critical that investigations into the patient's exposure are continued, as indicated by national and state authorities, to inform further prevention and response activities," said Dr Maria Van Kerkhove, the WHO's director of epidemic and pandemic preparedness and prevention.</p>

<p>"WHO strongly supports US efforts for surveillance of zoonotic influenza across human, environmental and animal sectors," Van Kerkhove continued.</p>

<p>"It is important to understand the circulation of avian influenza in poultry, wild birds and other animals in the state," she said of Missouri.</p>

<p>"Stronger disease surveillance in animals is essential to protect animal and human health."</p>

<p><strong>No animal contact</strong></p>

<p>The person who tested positive for bird flu was the 14th to do so in the US this year, and the first without known contact with animals.</p>

<p>Indeed, "no H5 infection in dairy cattle has been reported in Missouri," said the Missouri health department, though "some H5 cases in commercial or backyard flocks and wild birds have been reported."</p>

<p>All previous bird flu cases in the United States have been among farmworkers, including the very first, in 2022.</p>

<p>Bird flu is most commonly found in wild birds and poultry, but has more recently been detected in mammals, with an outbreak in cattle seen across the country this year.</p>

<p>It can occasionally infect humans through close contact or contaminated environments.</p>

<p>While the CDC continues to assess the risk to the public as low, "circumstances may change quickly as more information is learned", it said.</p>

<p>In the decades since H5 has been found in humans, there have been rare cases where an animal source cannot be identified.</p>

<p>But there has so far not been evidence of sustained human-to-human transmission, which would significantly increase the threat level.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/mb1heeog_bird-flu-generic-reuters_625x300_10_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Bird flu is most commonly found in wild birds and poultry (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/typhoon-gaemi-leaves-behind-heartbreaking-images-of-pets-left-to-perish-6512724]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Typhoon Gaemi Leaves Behind Heartbreaking Images Of Pets Left To Perish]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/typhoon-gaemi-leaves-behind-heartbreaking-images-of-pets-left-to-perish-6512724]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Sep 2024 18:44:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Animal abuse has long been a major concern for animal rights activists in the Philippines, which is home to some 23.29 million dogs.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A disturbing finding has surfaced following Typhoon Gaemi, which was one of the most destructive storms to hit Southeast Asia in recent times. The Philippines was devastated by the strong typhoon that struck in July, leaving behind extensive damage. The storm's rage left a path of destruction, with tens of thousands being evacuated and many dozen reported dead.</p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://metro.co.uk/2024/09/07/flooding-caused-super-typhoon-leaves-dogs-homeless-dying-21498843/"><em>The Metro,</em></a> in the middle of the mayhem, Ashley Fruono, PETA Asia's director of animal assistance programs, discovered a terrible scene: dogs who had been abandoned and were either held in cages or fastened to lampposts outside the wrecked homes of their owners. These creatures were abandoned and allowed to weather the storm on their own, even in spite of the dire circumstances and the pressing necessity for evacuation.</p>

<p>"I'll never forget seeing the decomposing bodies of dogs in cages or attached to their chains with a look of horror on their faces. They were subjected to an almost unimaginably horrific death-that was completely preventable," Ashley told <em>The Metro.</em></p>

<p>The news portal further reported, citing a report from the worldwide kennel club registry, the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.fci.be/en/statistics/ByNco.aspx?iso=PH">Federation Cynologique Internationale</a>, that animal abuse has long been a major concern for animal rights activists in the Philippines, which is home to some 23.29 million dogs. Around 12,000,000 people own a dog. Yet there were at least 3,000 cases of animal maltreatment in 2020 alone, the Philippine animal welfare non-profit, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.caraphil.org/">Compassion and Responsibility for Animals</a> (CARA), found.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">A resident in Marikina City, Philippines, posted a video on Wednesday showing a dog struggling to reach a safer area through the floodwaters caused by Super Typhoon Gaemi (CarinaPH) ?<a href="https://t.co/fsUEE63JLh">pic.twitter.com/fsUEE63JLh</a></p>
— Volcaholic ? (@volcaholic1) <a href="https://twitter.com/volcaholic1/status/1816105443111895412?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 24, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>"Cruelty to animals is a huge concern in the Philippines," Ashley, 38, who is from British Columbia, Canada, but has lived in the Philippines for 17 years, said.</p>

<p>"While we've noticed that, thanks to increased social media use, locals are more aware of animal welfare concerns and more caring than a decade or so ago, the problem is still huge, especially in impoverished areas where it may be more difficult to keep dogs inside due to crowded living conditions," Ashley said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/bp2mq88_animals_625x300_07_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Rescuers save animals from typhoon's flooding.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uae-crown-prince-sheikh-khaled-bin-mohamed-bin-zayed-al-nahyan-to-meet-pm-narendra-modi-on-september-9-details-here-6512431]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[With Crown Prince's Visit On Monday, A Generational Shift In India-UAE Ties]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uae-crown-prince-sheikh-khaled-bin-mohamed-bin-zayed-al-nahyan-to-meet-pm-narendra-modi-on-september-9-details-here-6512431]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Sep 2024 17:53:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India and the UAE aim to deepen ties and enhance their Comprehensive Strategic Partnership as the Crown Prince of Abu Dhabi, Sheikh Khaled bin Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan, arrives in India on an official visit on September 9-10.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India and the United Arab Emirates (UAE) aim to deepen ties and enhance their Comprehensive Strategic Partnership as the Crown Prince of Abu Dhabi, Sheikh Khaled bin Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan, arrives in India on an official visit on September 9-10.</p>

<p>Abu Dhabi's Crown Prince is visiting India at the invitation of Prime Minister Narendra Modi. This would be his first visit to New Delhi as the Crown Prince.</p>

<p>He is being accompanied by top ministers from the UAE as well as a business delegation, the Ministry of External Affairs has said.</p>

<p>The Crown Prince of Abu Dhabi - the next King - will meet PM Narendra Modi on Monday. It is the first time India is officially engaging with the next generation of royalty and government from the UAE, highlighting the importance India gives to its ties with the UAE.</p>

<p>Apart from his meeting with PM Modi, the Crown Prince will also call on President Droupadi Murmu.</p>

<p><strong>THE CROWN PRINCE'S SCHEDULE</strong></p>

<p>On September 9, the Crown Prince's day will begin with a visit to Rajghat to pay tribute to Mahatma Gandhi.</p>

<p>Later in the day, the Crown Prince will meet Prime Minister Narendra Modi and the two leaders would hold discussions on a wide range of areas concerning bilateral cooperation. This would likely be followed by a joint press conference where several agreements or MoUs will be exchanged.</p>

<p>Besides bilateral issues, the two leaders are also expected to have a detailed discussion on the overall situation arising out of the Israel-Hamas conflict.</p>

<p>The Crown Prince will also call on President Droupadi Murmu at the Rastrapati Bhavan.</p>

<p>On September 10, the Crown Prince will visit Mumbai to participate in a Business Forum, in which top business leaders from both countries will participate.</p>

<p><strong>INDIA-UAE PARTNERSHIP</strong></p>

<p>Since the landmark visit by PM Modi to UAE in August 2015, the first by an Indian Prime Minister in 34 years, bilateral relations between the two countries have elevated to a Comprehensive Strategic Partnership.</p>

<p>Both countries signed a Comprehensive Economic Partnership Agreement or CEPA in February 2022 and a Local Currency Settlement (LCS) System in July 2023 to promote the use of Indian Rupee and AED (United Arab Emirates Dirham) for cross-border transactions.</p>

<p>India is the UAE's second-largest trading partner, while the UAE is India's largest trading partner in the Arab world. Total trade between India and the UAE is projected to reach USD 100 billion by the end of the decade. The bilateral trade between the two countries in 2022-23 was about USD 85 billion, according to official data.</p>

<p>The UAE is also among the top four investors in India in terms of Foreign Direct Investments or FDI in 2022-23.</p>

<p>"India and UAE share historically close and friendly ties. In recent years, the Comprehensive Strategic Partnership between India and UAE has deepened in a wide range of areas, including political, trade, investment, connectivity, energy, technology, education, and culture," the MEA said.</p>

<p>"The Crown Prince's visit will further reinforce strong India-UAE bilateral relations and open avenues for partnership in new and emerging areas," it added.</p>

<p>The Indian community, which numbers over 3.5 million, plays an essential role in the UAE. Their contributions to the economy and cultural landscape of the UAE underscores the deep connections between the nations.</p>

<p>UAE was a special invitee for the G20 Summit in New Delhi during India's Presidency.</p>

<p>With India's active support, the UAE also joined the Shanghai Cooperation Organisation or SCO as dialogue partner in May 2023. The UAE also joined the BRICS forum as a member on January 1 with India's support.</p>

<p>In 2023, the India-UAE-France (UFI) trilateral was also formally launched.</p>

<p>UAE is the fifth-largest supplier of crude oil to India, accounting for around 8% of India's total crude imports. It also ranks first among destinations for India's exports in the West Asia region.</p>

<p>As a significant player in the Organisation of Islamic Cooperation or OIC grouping, the UAE's support is crucial for India in navigating regional challenges, particularly concerning its relations with Pakistan.</p>

<p>The Crown Prince, Sheikh Khaled's visit underscores the UAE's commitment to deepening economic and strategic ties with India. It marks the beginning of a new chapter in India-UAE relations, characterised by collaboration and opportunity.</p>

<p><strong>RECENT VISIT, STRENGTHENING TIES</strong></p>

<p>In February this year, PM Modi went for an official visit to the UAE, where he held discussions with UAE President Sheikh Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan on the India-UAE bilateral relationship and witnessed the exchange of eight agreements.</p>

<p>Sheikh Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan, 63, is the father of the Crown Prince Sheikh Khaled&nbsp;Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan, 42, who is visiting India this week.</p>

<p>PM Modi and President Al Nahyan welcomed the MoU for creation of an inter-governmental framework between India and the UAE on the India-Middle East-Europe Economic Corridor, also called IMEEC, which reflected the lead taken by the UAE and India in furthering regional connectivity.</p>

<p>The two leaders further endorsed the efforts from both sides to strengthen the strong economic and commercial cooperation and explore new areas of collaboration. They welcomed the strong growth witnessed in the UAE-India trade relations since the entry into force of the Comprehensive Economic Partnership Agreement (CEPA)</p>

<p>During his visit, PM Modi inaugurated the majestic Bochasanwasi Akshar Purushottam Swaminarayan Sanstha (BAPS) Mandir, the first Hindu temple in Abu Dhabi, UAE.</p>

<p>The temple is located in Abu Dhabi's Abu Mureikhah district. The grand temple, built on a 27-acre campus, the land for which, was gifted by the UAE government.</p>

<p>He also addressed the Indian community at an event titled 'Ahlan Modi', which was attended by over 65,000 people.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/2hc6lqis_pm-modi-uae-crown-prince-sheikh-khaled-bin-mohamed-bin-zayed-al-nahyan_625x300_07_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[UAE Crown Price Sheikh Khaled bin Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan will meet PM Modi in New Delhi]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/caleb-wu-footballer-sets-world-record-with-skills-that-helped-him-overcome-suicide-struggle-6512207]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Footballer Sets World Record With Skills That Helped Him Overcome Suicide]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/caleb-wu-footballer-sets-world-record-with-skills-that-helped-him-overcome-suicide-struggle-6512207]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Sep 2024 17:16:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Caleb Wu, a 22-year-old soccer player from Hartford, Connecticut, has set a world record for the most alternating football touches on a treadmill in 30 seconds, achieving 75 touches.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Caleb Wu, a passionate soccer player from Hartford, Connecticut, has made headlines by setting a new world record for the most alternating football (soccer) touches with the feet on a treadmill in 30 seconds, according to <em>Guinness World Records.</em> Wu, who scored an amazing 75 touches overall, believes that the activity helped him recover from a serious depressive episode.</p>

<p>The 22-year-old Wu has undergone a major transformation and discovered a fresh purpose in football. His struggle with mental health almost cost him his life, so achieving this milestone is very personal to him. With its demanding skills and rhythmic juggling, football became a source of courage and solace for him in his lowest moments.</p>

<p>Wu shared his motivation behind the record attempt: "I always had a passion for soccer, I did a lot of juggling tricks and soccer/football freestyle.</p>

<p><iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="315" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/g1orPy6c6FE?si=9H4o5xHzjQ1qiSUS" title="YouTube video player" width="560"></iframe></p>

<p>"My teammates challenged me as they showed me a video of someone trying and failing to do it so I wanted to prove them wrong - and it was a fun challenge. I was inspired because when I was younger I almost took my life and I wanted to make the most of my abilities and prove to myself that I can do awesome things," he told&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.guinnessworldrecords.com/news/2024/9/soccer-player-breaks-record-with-sporting-skills-that-saved-him-from-suicide"><em>Guinness World Records.</em></a></p>

<p>"I also wanted to inspire others to show them that they're capable of overcoming obstacles," he said.</p>

<p>Caleb also had to deal with racism during his formative years, from school classmates who would call him names.</p>

<p>He explained: "There were the common stereotypes and people would say Asians are only good at math. I wanted to show them I could compete as an athlete and was able to play college soccer for four years and was a captain for one year.</p>

<p>"I also became the first sponsored Division 3 Athlete and first sponsored college soccer player."</p>

<p>He added: "I overcame my struggles through finding a passion and wanting to inspire and help others who also struggle.</p><p><div class='table-div suicide'><table class='table'><thead><tr><th colspan='2'>Helplines</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>Vandrevala Foundation for Mental Health</td><td><a href='tel:+919999666555'>9999666555</a> or <a href='mailto:help@vandrevalafoundation.com'>help@vandrevalafoundation.com</a> </td></tr><tr><td>TISS iCall</td><td><a href='tel:+912225521111'>022-25521111</a> (Monday-Saturday: 8 am to 10 pm)</td></tr> <tr><td colspan='2'>(If you need support or know someone who does, please reach out to your nearest mental health specialist.)</td></tr></tbody></table></div></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/opuor5jg_caleb-wu_625x300_07_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[This accomplishment is deeply personal for Caleb Wu, who has battled severe depression.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/illegaly-owned-13-foot-burmese-python-rescued-from-new-york-home-6512069]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Illegally-Owned 13-Foot Burmese Python Rescued From New York Home]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/illegaly-owned-13-foot-burmese-python-rescued-from-new-york-home-6512069]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Sep 2024 16:50:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A massive Burmese python was rescued from a New York Home last week. The snake was 13 feet 2 inches (4 meters) long, weighed 80 pounds (36 kg) and was getting too big to handle for the owner, the New York Post reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A massive Burmese python was rescued from a New York Home last week. The snake was 13 feet 2 inches (4 meters) long, weighed 80 pounds (36 kg) and was getting too big to handle for the owner,<a href="https://nypost.com/2024/09/05/us-news/snake-owner-realizes-his-13-foot-burmese-python-was-getting-too-big/"> the New York Post reported</a>. Jeff Hull, an Environment Conservation Police Officer (ECO), recognised the snake as a Burmese python by a feature on its head that resembled an arrow.</p>

<p>According to a Facebook post by the New York State Department of Environmental Conservation (DEC), "On August 28th, 2024, Environment Conservation Police Officer (ECO) Jeff Hull responded to a complaint of a subject with a large snake that the complainant didn't believe to be legal. After seeing a picture of the snake, ECO Hull was able to identify it by the arrowhead-like design on its head as a Burmese python."</p>

<p>It added, "Burmese pythons are illegal to possess in the state of New York without a permit."&nbsp;</p>

<p>When ECO Hull arrived at the residence, the thirteen feet long <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/watch-panic-grips-family-after-9-foot-king-cobra-found-in-karnataka-home-6489201">snake </a>was kept in a four-to-five-foot aquarium. The snake's anonymous owner claimed he "was not prepared for how fast the animal would grow and that he recognized he could no longer care for it."&nbsp;</p>

<p>The owner was given tickets for both keeping wildlife as a pet and having dangerous species in the house without a permit. The snake was then taken out of the house and given to Fort Rickey Discovery Zoo in Rome, New York, which has the permits to house the snake.</p>

<p><iframe allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="true" frameborder="0" height="607" scrolling="no" src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/post.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2FNYSDEC%2Fposts%2Fpfbid0259uFUKxy72cXcdH3kczDkSSVwkx2UUH9UWxNR6PQCSvQd4Nqx1QEYqiZvgXJuNXQl&amp;show_text=true&amp;width=500" style="border:none;overflow:hidden" width="500"></iframe></p>

<p>Native to Southeast Asia, Burmese pythons are becoming a popular pet choice in the US. In Florida, they are an invasive species that feeds on local fauna.</p>

<p>The maximum length of a Burmese python is 16 feet (5 meters). The albino Burmese python captured in New York was yellow in colour and had a head pattern resembling an arrow.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/irqc75e_burmese-python-rescued_625x300_07_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Burmese pythons are becoming a popular pet choice in the US.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistan-admits-militarys-direct-role-in-kargil-war-1999-what-its-army-chief-said-6512023]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Pak Admits Military's Direct Role In Kargil? What Its Army Chief Said]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistan-admits-militarys-direct-role-in-kargil-war-1999-what-its-army-chief-said-6512023]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Sep 2024 16:46:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In what is being seen as a first-of-its kind confession by the General Headquarters (GHQ) in Rawalpindi, Chief of Army Staff (COAS) General Syed Asim Munir has admitted Pakistani military's direct role in the 1999 Kargil war against India.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In what is being seen as a first-of-its kind confession by the General Headquarters (GHQ) in Rawalpindi, Chief of Army Staff (COAS) General Syed Asim Munir has admitted Pakistani military's direct role in the 1999 Kargil war against India.</p>

<p>During his Defence Day speech on Friday, Munir mentioned Kargil along with the three wars with India while paying homage to what he termed as sacrifices rendered through martyrdom by soldiers of the Pakistan Armed forces.</p>

<p>"Certainly Pakistani nation is a powerful and brave nation, which understands the value of freedom and knows how to sustain it. 1948, 1965, 1971, the Kargil war between Pakistan and India, or the war in Siachen, thousands sacrificed their lives and were martyred for the safety and security of the country," he told the gathering at the GHQ.</p>

<p>Munir's statement is being seen as a first of its kind confession by a sitting Army Chief on direct role of the military in the Kargil war, a position Islamabad has refrained from taking for the past 25 years.</p>

<p>So far, Pakistan had denied its involvement in the 1999 war and claimed that it was an action taken by "freedom fighters" of Kashmir.</p>

<p>Former Army Chief General Pervaiz Musharraf always claimed that the Kargil operation was a successful localized action.</p>

<p>During an interview, Musharraf had stated that then Prime Minister Nawaz Sharif was not taken into confidence and many decisions taken by the armed forces along the volatile Line of Control (LoC) with India did not even require approval of the army chief.</p>

<p>However, Musharraf had admitted the role of Pakistan Army's 10 core FCNA (Force Command Northern Areas) in the entire operation.</p>

<p>"Initially, there was a mujahideen activity in the area. Later on FCNA decided to man the 150 mile vacant area of the Line of Control (LoC). For this, there is no need to get approval or permission from anyone," said Musharraf.</p>

<p>Mushahid Hussain Syed, who was the Information Secretary under Prime Minister Nawaz Sharif during 1999, also detailed about his government being informed about the Kargil operation through an official communication by the then DGMO (Director General Military Operations).</p>

<p>"When Kargil happened, the formal intimation and briefing that was given to Prime Minister Nawaz Sharif, was given on 17th May 1999 by the DGMO. Before that, voices from India had started to come and there was a realization that something was happening along the Line of Control," said Syed in an interview.</p>

<p>Experts maintain that the Kargil operation will remain a success story for some and a big blunder and mistake for many others. They maintain that Musharraf's claim of FCNA's involvement, which is part of the 10 Core of Pakistan Army and manages Kashmir and the northern areas of the country, is enough confession to endorse the fact, reiterated by the current army chief.</p>

<p>It also remains a fact that many bodies of Pakistan Army soldiers in Kargil were not brought back, prompting their families to raise questions over the reluctance of the Pakistani government and the army to own them.</p>

<p>"Those officers, who came to meet us, we kept asking them to try and bring the bodies of their loved ones back. I believe that they should have tried harder. But they didn't," said Itrat Abbas, brother of late Captain Farhat Haseeb, the army officer martyred in Kargil, confirming that officers and soldiers of Pakistan Army were deployed in Kargil.</p>

<p>Rehana Mehboob, mother of late Captain Ammar Hussain, admitted that she kept getting calls from the Army Unit and friends of her son during the Kargil war, adding that then Army Chief Pervaiz Musharraf did not even own the operation.</p>

<p>The above-mentioned statements by families and then government officials along with the then army chief are enough evidence to maintain that while then PM Sharif was kept in the dark, the army's chain of command was fully on board about the Kargil operation.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-11/380lhme_asim-munir-pak-army-chief-650_625x300_24_November_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Pakistan's General Syed Asim Munir has admitted Pakistani military's direct role in Kargil war]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-year-old-critical-after-shooting-self-in-face-with-mothers-gun-in-us-6511928]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[3-Year-Old Critical After Shooting Self In Face With Mother's Gun In US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-year-old-critical-after-shooting-self-in-face-with-mothers-gun-in-us-6511928]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Sep 2024 16:28:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A three-year-old boy shot himself in the face with his mother's gun in the US state of Michigan. The incident took place at around 4:30 pm (local time) at St. Patrick Avenue near Elmo Street, local media reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A three-year-old boy shot himself in the face with his mother's gun in the US state of Michigan. The incident took place at around 4:30 pm (local time) at St. Patrick Avenue near Elmo Street, local media reported.</p>

<p>As per preliminary investigation, the mishap occurred after the boy's mother came home from work and put her gun down on the dresser, Detroit Police Department chief James White said.</p>

<p>The child soon got hold of the unsecured gun and accidentally shot himself. The bullet grazed his face, but the child is expected to survive. However, his condition remains critical as of Friday night.</p>

<p>"A three-year-old toddler roaming around, they see you put the gun down, they are probably gonna pick it up just like anything else," <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/detroit/news/3-year-old-boy-injured-after-reportedly-shooting-himself-detroit/">CBS News</a> quoted James White as saying.</p>

<p>Although there was a locked gun box inside the house, it was not used at the time of the shooting.</p>

<p>"It only takes a minute, less than a minute, seconds. You have to secure these weapons," White said.</p>

<p>Police are now investigating whether the child's mother had a license for the gun. With Michigan's gun storage law coming into effect earlier this year, police said they were further looking forward to charging the woman with improper storage of a firearm, reports added.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the nearby resident stated that those owning guns should lock their weapons responsibly to put an end to such incidents.</p>

<p>Lorenzo Hardy, who stays a few doors away from where the shooting took place, said he understands what the child may now encounter next.</p>

<p>"It is the trauma, it is the thing that a three-year-old has to live with for the rest of his life... It's really sad that a child gets to hold a gun; it's ridiculous," Hardy said.</p>

<p>Detroit Police are further investigating the matter.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-11/3eb3kf1_us-police-generic_625x300_14_November_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Detroit Police are further investigating the matter. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukraine-says-russia-launched-67-drones-in-massive-overnight-attack-6511441]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ukraine Says Russia Launched 67 Drones In Massive Overnight Attack]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukraine-says-russia-launched-67-drones-in-massive-overnight-attack-6511441]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Sep 2024 14:59:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ukraine's air force said today that Russia launched a total of 67 long-range Shahed drones in a mass overnight attack, 58 of which it was able to shoot down.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ukraine's air force said today that Russia launched a total of 67 long-range Shahed drones in a mass overnight attack, 58 of which it was able to shoot down.</p>

<p>The air force said in a statement on the Telegram messaging app that air defence units were scrambled into action in 11 regions across Ukraine.</p>

<p>Drone debris was found next to the parliament building in the capital Kyiv, the legislature said in a separate statement it posted on its official Telegram page along with several photographs.</p>

<p>It is rare for a Russian missile or drone to get so far into central Kyiv, as the city is protected by a network of Soviet-era and Western-donated air defence systems.</p>

<p>The hilltop government quarter in the city centre is perhaps the best-defended site in Ukraine, as it also houses the offices of the president, cabinet and the central bank.</p>

<p>The pictures on Telegram showed at least four pieces of debris scattered on the ground near the parliament building. One piece lay at the foot of the steps to the building's main entrance, while another hunk of metal looked riddled with shrapnel.</p>

<p>Reuters correspondents in Ukraine's capital, Kyiv, heard a series of explosions shortly after 3 a.m. (0000 GMT) on Saturday, some of which resounded loudly around the city centre, waking up its residents.</p>

<p>Since the start of its invasion in February 2022, Moscow has launched thousands of missiles and Shahed drones into Ukraine.</p>

<p>The Iranian-designed drone has been used by Russia since September 2022 as a cheap, more expendable alternative to missiles, which are expensive and harder to manufacture.</p>

<p>The propeller-powered Shahed flies at less than 200 km per hour (125 miles per hour) but can be tricky for conventional air defence systems to track because it flies low and emits far less heat than a missile.</p>

<p>Kyiv's air force said the drones were launched from two border regions in Russia as well as from the Russian-occupied peninsula of Crimea.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/gteputhk_russia-drone-strike-on-ukraine-reuters_625x300_07_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Ukrainian personnel use searchlights as they search for drones over the city during Russian drone strike]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/24-year-old-satellite-to-burn-up-over-pacific-ocean-on-earth-re-entry-6511245]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[24-Year-Old Satellite To Burn Up Over Pacific Ocean On Earth Re-Entry]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/24-year-old-satellite-to-burn-up-over-pacific-ocean-on-earth-re-entry-6511245]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Sep 2024 14:23:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[After 24 years diligently studying Earth's magnetic field, a satellite will mostly burn up over the Pacific Ocean on Sunday during a "targeted" re-entry into the atmosphere, in a first for the European Space Agency as it seeks to reduce space debris.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After 24 years diligently studying Earth's magnetic field, a satellite will mostly burn up over the Pacific Ocean on Sunday during a "targeted" re-entry into the atmosphere, in a first for the European Space Agency as it seeks to reduce space debris.</p>

<p>Since launching in 2000, the Salsa satellite has helped shed light on the magnetosphere, the powerful magnetic shield that protects Earth from solar winds -- and without which the planet would be uninhabitable.</p>

<p>According to the ESA, Salsa's return home will mark the first-ever "targeted" re-entry for a satellite, which means it will fall back to Earth at a specific time and place but will not be controlled as it re-enters the atmosphere.</p>

<p>Teams on the ground have already performed a series of manoeuvres with the 550-kilogram (1,200-pound) satellite to ensure it burns up over a remote and uninhabited region of the South Pacific, off the coast of Chile.</p>

<p>This unique re-entry is possible because of Salsa's unusual oval-shaped orbit. During its swing around the planet, which takes two and half days, the satellite strays as far as 130,000 kilometres (80,000 miles), and comes as close as just a few hundred kilometres.</p>

<p>Bruno Sousa, head of the ESA's inner solar system missions operations unit, said it had been crucial that Salsa came within roughly 110 kilometres during its last two orbits.</p>

<p>"Then immediately on the next orbit, it would come down at 80 kilometres, which is the region in space already within the atmosphere, where we have the highest chance (for it) to be fully captured and burned," he told a press conference.</p>

<p>When a satellite starts entering the atmosphere at around 100 kilometres above sea level, intense friction with atmospheric particles -- and the heat this causes -- starts making them disintegrate.&nbsp;</p>

<p>But some fragments can still make it back down to Earth.</p>

<h2>Fear of 'cascading' space junk</h2>

<p>The ESA is hoping to pinpoint where Salsa, roughly the size of a small car, re-enters the atmosphere to within a few hundred metres.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Because the satellite is so old, it does not have fancy new tech -- like a recording device -- making tracking this part tricky.</p>

<p>A plane will be flying at an altitude of 10 kilometres to watch the satellite burn up -- and track its falling debris, which is expected to be just 10 percent of its original mass.</p>

<p>Salsa is just one of four satellites that make up the ESA's Cluster mission, which is coming to an end. The other three are scheduled for a similar fate in 2025 and 2026.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The ESA hopes to learn from these re-entries which type of materials do not burn up in the atmosphere, so that "in the future we can build satellites that can be totally evaporated by this process," Sousa said.</p>

<p>Scientists have been sounding the alarm about space junk, which is the debris left by the enormous number of dead satellites and other missions that continue orbiting our planet.</p>

<p>Last year the ESA signed a "zero debris" charter for its missions from 2030.&nbsp;</p>

<p>There are two main risks from space junk, according to the ESA's space debris system engineer Benjamin Bastida Virgili.</p>

<p>"One is that in orbit, you have the risk that your operational satellite collides with a piece of space debris, and that creates a cascading effect and generates more debris, which would then put in risk other missions," he said.</p>

<p>The second comes when the old debris re-enters the atmosphere, which happens almost daily as dead satellite fragments or rocket parts fall back to Earth.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Designing satellites that completely burn up in the atmosphere will mean there is "no risk for the population," Bastida Virgili emphasised.</p>

<p>But there is little cause for alarm. According to the ESA, the chance of a piece of space debris injuring someone on the ground is less than one in a hundred billion.</p>

<p>This is 65,000 times lower than the odds of being struck by lightning.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/acn0u3h_satellite-generic_625x300_07_April_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-ukraines-dragon-drone-rains-molten-metal-on-russian-positions-6510999]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Video: Ukraine's 'Dragon Drone' Rains Molten Metal On Russian Positions]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-ukraines-dragon-drone-rains-molten-metal-on-russian-positions-6510999]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Sep 2024 13:35:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Fire rained on Russian-held positions in the occupied Kharkiv region when Ukrainian drones dropped thermite incendiary bombs, burning trees and reportedly some Russian military vehicles.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Fire rained on Russian-held positions in the occupied Kharkiv region when Ukrainian drones dropped thermite incendiary bombs, burning trees and reportedly some Russian military vehicles. Footages of fire-spewing 'Dragon Drone' have emerged on various Telegram channels.</p>

<p>A Telegram channel named Khorne Group shared the undated footage of a low-flying drone dropping thermite - A mixture of aluminium powder and iron oxide that burns at a very high temperature. The molten metal can quickly burn trees, fortifications and metals, rendering military vehicles, and armour useless.</p>

<p>The 60th Mechanized Brigade of Ukraine shared drone footage of the thermite bombing and said, "Strike Drones are our wings of vengeance, bringing fire straight from the sky! They become a real threat to the enemy, burning his positions with an accuracy that no other weapon can achieve. When our "Vidar" works - the Russian woman will never sleep." These weapons are considered one the most dangerous in the world.</p>

<p>Vidar is associated with the god of vengeance in Scandinavian mythology.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">The Ukrainian military began using the Dragon drone, which burns the area underneath with thermite ??? Thermite is a mixture of burning granules of iron oxide and aluminum. About 500 grams of thermite mixture can be placed under a standard FPV drone. The chemical reaction is… <a href="https://t.co/3XIzc3LLHN">pic.twitter.com/3XIzc3LLHN</a></p>
— Anastasia (@Nastushichek) <a href="https://twitter.com/Nastushichek/status/1831763026959016265?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 5, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The use of incendiary bombs - munitions that are designed to cause fire - has brought focus on their potential use on civilian populations, and establishments apart from the military. <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-ukraine-war-terrifying-video-shows-firebombs-raining-down-in-ukraines-donetsk-3191332">In 2023</a>, Russia used thermite bombs over the eastern Ukrainian town of Vuhledar after the defeat in a tank battle. The Russians spew thermite over the border town.</p>

<p>The Russians reportedly used 122mm Grad 9M22S rockets launched from the Soviet-era B-21 multi-rocket launcher system with a thermit warhead.</p>

<p>Several videos have emerged where Russian and Ukrainian troops have used such weapons on the frontline. Thermite, unlike conventional bombs that rely on a blast effect, generated intense heat. It is widely used in welding steel, iron, and railway tracks.</p>

<p>"The widespread use of thermite bombs increases the likelihood of these weapons being deployed in populated areas. The result could be catastrophic, with horrific injuries and loss of life among civilians," Dr Iain Overton, Executive Director of Action on Armed Violence (AOAV), a British advocacy group, said.</p>

<p>Ignition of thermite is slow and it requires very high temperature to ignite. These temperatures cannot be reached with conventional black powder fuses or nitrocellulose rods. They are often achieved by Magnesium metal strips that are used as fuses.</p>

<h2><strong>Use Of Incendiary Bombs In The Past</strong></h2>

<p>World War I was witness to incendiary weapons when Germans and the Allied troops used such munitions against their adversary. The American Thermite Hand Grenade Mark I and the French Model 1916 incendiary grenades were weapons used during World War 1.</p>

<p>The Germans developed B1.3E, 1938, incendiary bombs just before World War 2. The Luftwaffe (German Air Force) used it extensively to bomb British cities. The Imperial War Museum said, "During 1940-41, the Luftwaffe caused serious damage by dropping large quantities of incendiary bombs on British towns and cities, either using containers that were carried on bomb racks and released to open at a predetermined point, or from very large containers holding up to 700 bombs that remained on the aircraft."</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="A German B1E 1 kg incendiary aircraft bomb" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/mot8s698_german-b1e-bomb_625x300_07_September_24.jpg?im=FitAndFill,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="A German B1E 1 kg incendiary aircraft bomb" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">A German B1E 1 kg incendiary aircraft bomb<br />
<span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: Image credit: <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.iwm.org.uk/collections/item/object/30021484" rel="no index, no follow">Imperial War Museum © IWM (MUN 3291)</a></span></p>
</div>

<p>The Allied troops used Napalm - a flammable mixture of gasoline and a gelling agent - for bombings and throwing flames. The US used Napalm to target Japanese cities. Almost 60% of Tokyo was burnt during the Napalm bombings. It has been massively used since its creation in 1942.</p>

<p>During the Vietnam War, the use of Napalm and The Dow Chemical Company which produced it, caught the world's attention on how dangerous such weapons when unleashed on civilians which caused severe burns.</p>

<h2><strong>International Regulations On Use Of Incendiary Weapons</strong></h2>

<p>Efforts to address the issue of incendiary weapons started in the 1970s, notably with a growing concern over the use of napalm. <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://disarmament.unoda.org/convarms/incendiary-weapons/">In 1972, the UN General Assembly</a> adopted a resolution referring to incendiary weapons as 'a category of arms viewed with horror'.</p>

<p>In 1980, the Convention on Prohibitions or Restrictions on the Use of Certain Conventional Weapons Which May Be Deemed to Be Excessively Injurious or to Have Indiscriminate Effects was adopted with the aim to ban or restrict the use of certain types of weapons considered to cause unnecessary or unjustifiable suffering to combatants or to indiscriminately affects civilians.</p>

<p>The Protocol on prohibitions or restrictions on the use of incendiary weapons (Protocol III) aims at protecting civilians and civilian objects from the use of this type of weapons. It prohibits targeting civilians and restricts targeting military objects located within populated areas. The Protocol also prohibits the use of incendiary weapons on forest or other plants unless the vegetation is used to conceal military objects.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/njjti3k_thermite-bomb_625x300_07_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The use of incendiary bombs - munitions that are designed to cause fire.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-a-taxi-driver-in-el-salvador-got-rich-with-bitcoin-6510512]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How A Taxi Driver In El Salvador Got Rich With Bitcoin]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-a-taxi-driver-in-el-salvador-got-rich-with-bitcoin-6510512]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Sep 2024 12:05:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Napoleon Osorio is proud of being the first taxi driver to have accepted payment in bitcoin in the first country in the world to make the cryptocurrency legal tender: El Salvador.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Napoleon Osorio is proud of being the first taxi driver to have accepted payment in bitcoin in the first country in the world to make the cryptocurrency legal tender: El Salvador.</p>

<p>He credits President Nayib Bukele's decision to bank on bitcoin three years ago with changing his life.</p>

<p>"Before I was unemployed... and now I have my own business," said the 39-year-old businessman, who uses an app to charge for rides in bitcoin and now runs his own car rental company.</p>

<p>Three years ago the leader of the Central American nation took a huge gamble when he put bitcoin into legal circulation in a bid to revitalize El Salvador's dollarized, remittance-reliant economy.</p>

<p>He invested hundreds of millions of dollars of taxpayer money in the cryptocurrency, despite warnings about volatility risks from global institutions.</p>

<p>Osorio credited the US founder of the NGO My First Bitcoin, John Dennehy, with encouraging him to accept payment in the cryptocurrency.</p>

<p>He now has 21 drivers working for his Bit-Driver brand and has made enough profit from the currency's rise to be able to buy four rental vehicles.</p>

<p>A divorced father of two teenagers, he also no longer struggles to pay for their education.</p>

<p>Launching bitcoin as legal tender on September 7, 2021, Bukele said he wanted to bring the 70 percent of Salvadorans who do not use banks into the financial system and promptly began plowing public money in cryptocurrencies.</p>

<p>To spur Salvadorans to use bitcoin he created the Chivo Wallet app for sending and receiving bitcoin free of charge and gave $30 to each new user.</p>

<p>His grand ambitions for bitcoin fell foul of the International Monetary Fund (IMF), which hesitated to grant El Salvador a $1.3 billion loan because of its official use of the cryptocurrency.</p>

<p>In August, however, the IMF announced a preliminary loan agreement with El Salvador, while saying it needed to mitigate "potential risks."</p>

<p>- Offered as 'option' -</p>

<p>While Osorio has grown relatively wealthy with bitcoin, a study by the University Institute for Public Opinion showed that 88 percent of Salvadorans had yet to use it.</p>

<p>"From the beginning... it was clear that it was clearly an ill-advised measure that the population rejected," the director of the institute, Laura Andrade, told AFP.</p>

<p>One-quarter of Salvadoran GDP comes from remittances sent home by family members, mostly from the United States.</p>

<p>But in 2023 only one percent of the transfers were made in cryptocurrencies.</p>

<p>In an interview with Time magazine in August, Bukele acknowledged that while "you can go to a McDonald's, a supermarket, or a hotel and pay with Bitcoin" it had "not had the widespread adoption we hoped for."</p>

<p>He added that "the positive aspect is that it is voluntary; we have never forced anyone to adopt it. We offered it as an option, and those who chose to use it have benefited from the rise in Bitcoin."</p>

<p>He also confirmed that he had around $400 million in bitcoin that is kept in a public "cold storage wallet" -- a way of storing bitcoin offline.</p>

<p>Bitcoin's fortunes have been mixed.</p>

<p>This week it was trading at around $52,000, down from a peak of $73,616 on March 13. In November 2022 it fell as low as $16,189.</p>

<p>Independent economist Cesar Villalona told AFP that Bukele himself had hobbled bitcoin's take-up by stripping it of the usual functions of a currency.</p>

<p>"Bukele... said: there will be no salary in bitcoin, there will be no pensions in bitcoin, there will be no savings in bitcoin and there will be no price in bitcoin, and in so doing took away the three functions of money," Villalona said.</p>

<p>Luis Contreras, an instructor at My First Bitcoin, told AFP many Salvadorans were simply afraid of making the switch.</p>

<p>The organization has taken cryptocurrencies into public schools, teaching around 35,000 students to use bitcoin so far.</p>

<p>Contreras says the hardest thing about training people on bitcoin "is their fear of new things, which creates a fear of technology" as well as "the fear of moving from a classic currency in the current economy to one that is totally digital and decentralized."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/n9q3jtg4_napoleon-ostorio_625x300_07_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-where-donald-trumps-criminal-trials-stand-ahead-of-us-polls-6510127]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: Where Donald Trump's Criminal Trials Stand Ahead Of US Polls]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-where-donald-trumps-criminal-trials-stand-ahead-of-us-polls-6510127]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Sep 2024 10:48:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The year 2024 was set to be a judicial minefield for Donald Trump, with some thinking the former president could be behind bars before the November 5 presidential election.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The year 2024 was set to be a judicial minefield for Donald Trump, with some thinking the former president could be behind bars before the November 5 presidential election.</p>

<p>However, the Republican candidate has managed to delay three of the four trials until after the election, despite facing 88 criminal charges in total.</p>

<p>He pulled it off via an array of appeals and other tactics by his army of lawyers, including a broad immunity ruling by the US Supreme Court.</p>

<p>He was only found guilty in the least serious case, which involved falsifying business records to cover up hush money payments made to porn star Stormy Daniels.</p>

<p>The latest good news for Trump came Friday, when a judge officially delayed his sentencing in that case to November 26 -- weeks after the US presidential election.</p>

<p>Here's an overview of how his legal woes look currently.</p>

<h2>Challenging the 2020 election results</h2>

<p>Donald Trump faces federal charges for his illegal attempts to reverse the results of the 2020 election won by US President Joe Biden.</p>

<p>Special prosecutor Jack Smith has charged Trump with the likes of "conspiracy to defraud the United States" and "obstructing an official proceeding," among others.</p>

<p>Although Trump is not directly accused of the Capitol insurrection on January 6, 2021, Smith has alleged he stirred up violence and chaos.</p>

<p>The trial was initially set to begin March 4 in Washington, with Trump facing a potential sentence of decades in prison if found guilty.</p>

<p>However, the case was delayed significantly when the Supreme Court decided to rule on presidential immunity, issuing a decision in July that Trump had broad protection for "official acts" as president.</p>

<p>Smith filed a revised indictment in late August accounting for the ruling, but now has to restart the battle with Trump's legal team about the trial's timeline.</p>

<p>The judge in the case, Tanya Chutkan, acknowledged during a hearing Thursday that it would be impossible to set a new trial date in the two months before the election.</p>

<h2>The 2020 election in Georgia</h2>

<p>The former Republican president also faces charges in the southeastern US state of Georgia for alleged election interference, including a phone call where he asked a local official to "find" him 11,000 missing votes -- the margin by which he lost the state to Joe Biden in 2020.</p>

<p>Trump had to visit an Atlanta prison to get his mug shot taken for the case, a humiliating first for a former US president.</p>

<p>However, the progress of the case suffered when it came out that the local prosecutor, Fani Willis, had an intimate relationship with an investigator she hired for it, Nathan Wade.</p>

<p>Trump's lawyers advocated for the case to be dismissed due to the conflict of interest, and the Supreme Court's ruling on presidential immunity has not helped either.</p>

<p>As a result, the trial, which was initially supposed to start on August 5, has been officially paused while the matter winds through the court system for months to come.</p>

<h2>The classified documents at Mar-a-Lago</h2>

<p>In another federal case under special prosecutor Jack Smith, Trump faces accusations of retaining top-secret documents at his private residence in Mar-a-Lago, Florida.</p>

<p>He is also accused of attempting to destroy evidence of the retention. The most serious charges carry a prison sentence of 10 years.</p>

<p>Though originally set to go to trial on May 20, Trump scored a victory when Judge Aileen Cannon -- who was appointed by the former president -- stopped criminal proceedings on July 15, based on allegations that Smith had been appointed illegally.</p>

<p>Smith appealed the decision at the end of August to get the case back on track, but given the pace of federal appellate courts, it will likely be months before a decision is made.</p>

<h2>The hush money sentencing</h2>

<p>The financial crimes case in New York was the only one that made it to trial for Trump, taking place from mid-April until the end of May.</p>

<p>Despite claims by Trump the trial was "rigged," a jury found Trump guilty of 34 counts of falsifying business records to make hush money payments to porn star Stormy Daniels in order to avoid a scandal right before the 2016 presidential election.</p>

<p>Facing up to four years in prison, Trump was originally set to be sentenced in September.</p>

<p>However, on Friday, Judge Juan Merchan postponed the hearing until three weeks after the election, offering reprieve for the Republican candidate.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/q5p67c08_donald-trump-reuters_625x300_06_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/cant-rule-out-criminal-act-russian-spy-beluga-whale-found-dead-in-norway-6510082]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Russian Spy" Beluga Whale Had Multiple Bullet Wounds: Animal Rights Group]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/cant-rule-out-criminal-act-russian-spy-beluga-whale-found-dead-in-norway-6510082]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Sep 2024 10:36:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Nicknamed 'Hvaldimir,' the beluga whale became popular in Norway after the unusual harness on it sparked speculations that it was trained as a spy by Russia.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The beluga whale, found dead in a bay on the southwestern coast of Norway, was killed by gunfire and had "multiple bullet wounds," animal rights groups have said. It rose to fame in the European country after the unusual harness on it sparked speculations that it was trained as a spy by Russia. The whale was found dead on August 31.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
Organisations like NOAH and One Whale said a complaint was filed with the Norwegian police seeking a "criminal investigation."<br />
<br />
The white beluga whale first appeared off the coast in the Finnmark region of Norway in 2019. It was given the nickname 'Hvaldimir', combining a pun on the Norwegian word for whale -- hval -- and its purported ties to Russia, AFP reported.<br />
<br />
On Monday, the carcass of Hvaldimir was taken to a local branch of the Norwegian Veterinary Institute for autopsy. Reports are expected in three weeks, a spokesperson said.<br />
<br />
After witnessing Hvaldimir's body, Regina Crosby Haug, the head of One Whale, said that it had "multiple bullet wounds around his body". The organisation was established to track the beluga, which over the years has become a celebrity in the country.<br />
<br />
In a statement, NOAH director Siri Martinsen said that injuries on Hvaldimir's body were "alarming and of a nature that cannot rule out a criminal act — it is shocking".<br />
<br />
The beluga whale was estimated to be around 15 to 20 years old, reports said. Usually, a beluga whale can survive anywhere between 40 and 60 years.<br />
<br />
After finding Hvaldimir back in 2019, the marine biologists in Norway removed the man-made harness, which had a mount suited for an action camera as well as the world's 'Equipment St. Petersburg' printed on plastic clasps in English.<br />
<br />
The Norwegian officials claimed the beluga whale might have escaped an enclosure. Further, it said it could have been trained by the Russian Navy as Hvaldimir appeared to be accustomed to humans.<br />
<br />
Moscow has not reacted to these speculations.<br />
<br />
Marine Mind, another organisation, which was tracking Hvaldimir's movements, said the beluga whale's body was found floating in the water at around 2:30 PM (local time) on August 31.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/pvlb0bmo_spy-whale-_625x300_01_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The white beluga whale first appeared off the coast in the Finnmark region of Norway in 2019]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/prince-hisahito-becomes-japans-1st-royal-male-to-turn-18-in-40-years-6510031]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Prince Hisahito Becomes Japan's 1st Royal Male To Turn 18 In 40 Years]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/prince-hisahito-becomes-japans-1st-royal-male-to-turn-18-in-40-years-6510031]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Sep 2024 10:30:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prince Hisahito, the son of Crown Prince Akishino, turned 18 on Friday and joined the Imperial family as an adult. With this, Hisahito became the first male member of the family to reach adulthood in 39 years, reported Japan Times.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prince Hisahito, the son of Crown Prince Akishino, turned 18 on Friday and joined the Imperial family as an adult. With this, Hisahito became the first male member of the family to reach adulthood in 39 years, <a href="http://https://www.japantimes.co.jp/news/2024/09/06/japan/prince-hisahito-turns-18/">reported Japan Times</a>. It is a major milestone for the family that has governed the country for over a millennium but faces the same issues as the rest of the country: a rapidly ageing and declining population.<br />
<br />
Hisahito is the nephew of Japanese Emperor Naruhito and is second in line to the throne after his father Crown Prince Akishino, who reached adulthood in 1985.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
"I hope to learn more through each and every experience, absorbing various aspects and growing through them," the prince said in a statement released by the Imperial Household Agency.<br />
<br />
He conveyed his gratitude to his parents and sisters, Mako Komuro, who left the imperial family after getting married, and Princess Kako. He also shared his desire to work hard for his future. "I want to cherish my remaining time at high school," Hisahito added.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
According to the agency, Prince Hisahito is a third-year student at the University of Tsukuba's Senior High School at Otsuka in Tokyo. While the custom is to hold a Coming-of-Age Ceremony and a press conference to mark the occasion, his ceremony has been postponed to the spring of 2025, or later. The ceremony will take place after his high school graduation to avoid interference with his academic pursuits.<br />
<br />
Hisahito is the youngest member of the 17-member, all-adult imperial family, which only has four men. His position as the last heir apparent presents a challenge to Japanese society, which forbids women from taking the throne.<br />
<br />
The 1947 Imperial House Law only permits a man to ascend to the throne and requires female royal members who marry commoners to renounce their royal position.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
Aside from Hisahito and the crown prince Akishino, Prince Hitachi, the 88-year-old childless uncle of the emperor, is the only other successor to the Chrysanthemum Throne.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/akcp51k8_prince-hisahito_625x300_07_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/weaponising-joy-how-kamala-harris-plans-to-beat-trump-at-his-own-game-6509981]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Weaponising "Joy": How Kamala Harris Plans To Beat Trump At His Own Game]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/weaponising-joy-how-kamala-harris-plans-to-beat-trump-at-his-own-game-6509981]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Sep 2024 10:15:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US presidential hopeful Kamala Harris appears to be taking a leaf out of rival Donald Trump's playbook by focusing on evoking emotion, rather than explaining policy, on the campaign trail -- and she's hoping her appeal to "joy" will help her beat him]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US presidential hopeful Kamala Harris appears to be taking a leaf out of rival Donald Trump's playbook by focusing on evoking emotion, rather than explaining policy, on the campaign trail -- and she's hoping her appeal to "joy" will help her beat the Republican at his own game.</p>

<p>Since taking over from President Joe Biden at the top of the Democratic Party's ticket in July, Harris has had to run her campaign in fast-forward, with just months to go before the November election.</p>

<p>With few exceptions she has avoided press conferences, interviews and lengthy discussions on policy. Instead, her official coronation at the Democratic National Convention focused on one pervasive theme: "joy."</p>

<p>And the vibe-heavy approach appears to be working.</p>

<p>While Biden was lagging behind Trump, Harris has pulled back into the race, with the two candidates running neck-and-neck in six key battleground states, according to the latest polls.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The shift to evoking a primarily emotional message, experts say, is effective political strategy.</p>

<p>"We think we think like scientists, carefully and objectively weighing the evidence and facts before us," said Jennifer Mercieca, a communications professor at Texas A&amp;M University.</p>

<p>"But we actually think like lawyers, building a case for our preferred position."</p>

<p>The appeal to so-called emotional truths -- things that "feel true," even if they are not rooted in empirical evidence -- is powerful, she said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"When speakers try to persuade based on affective truth it's harder to hold them accountable because it's difficult to argue against a feeling."</p>

<h2>Moving away from Biden</h2>

<p>The shift from Biden's campaign -- which presented an argument based heavily on Trump being "a threat to democracy" -- has been striking.</p>

<p>Since he dropped out, a New York Times/Siena poll "found that anger and resignation had been subsiding among voters of both parties, while joy had jumped."</p>

<p>Mashail Malik, an assistant professor of government at Harvard University, said Harris's shift can be explained by the "exhaustion" that negative emotions can cause.</p>

<p>"I think fear was failing to fully inspire a wider range of potential Democratic voters, many of whom are exhausted from the negativity that had so overtaken the news cycle," she said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The messaging about joy seems designed to alleviate some of this exhaustion and to offer an alternative to fear."</p>

<p>Moreover, she argues, it offers a way for Harris to differentiate herself from her current boss Biden.</p>

<p>That gets much harder when drilling down on issues, rather than atmospherics.</p>

<p>On US support for Israel's war in Gaza, for example, Harris has tried to satisfy Democratic critics mostly through a shift in tone on the massive loss of civilian Palestinian life. That, however, is not likely to heal the small but significant rift in the party.</p>

<h2>Trump's appeals</h2>

<p>Republican candidate Trump has been using appeals to emotions for years, with his speeches often heavy on rhetoric and light on facts -- or filled with outright fictions.</p>

<p>This campaign, the former president has focused on what he calls an "invasion" of migrants into the United States. He calls US cities "war zones."</p>

<p>"Kamala Harris will deliver crime, chaos, destruction and death," he said in a recent campaign speech in Michigan.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In an August 27 interview with talk show host Phil McGraw, Trump repeated a frequent line from his stump speech: "If she wins, they're going to destroy our country."</p>

<p>The apocalyptic messaging might be misleading but it speaks to emotions that Trump's supporters consider true.</p>

<p>Malik said Trump's appeals to pride and resentment are "very similar to populist leaders around the world, including not only in Europe but also in Latin America and South Asia."</p>

<p>"It's a familiar story," she said. "And it usually doesn't end well."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/425dmocs_kamala-harris-reuters_625x300_30_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-stops-foreign-adoptions-of-its-children-after-3-decades-6504302]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[China Stops Foreign Adoptions Of Its Children After 3 Decades]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-stops-foreign-adoptions-of-its-children-after-3-decades-6504302]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Sep 2024 09:51:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[China will no longer send children overseas for adoption, the government said, overturning a more than three-decade rule that was rooted in its once strict one-child policy.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>China will no longer send children overseas for adoption, the government said, overturning a more than three-decade rule that was rooted in its once strict one-child policy.</p>

<p>More than 160,000 Chinese children have been adopted by families across the world since 1992, when China first opened its doors to international adoption.</p>

<p>Around 82,000 of these children, mostly girls, have been adopted in the United States, according to China's Children International (CCI).</p>

<p>On Thursday, Foreign Ministry Spokeswoman Mao Ning said the Chinese government had adjusted its cross-border adoption policy to be "in line" with international trends.</p>

<p>"Apart from the adoption of a child or stepchild of blood relatives of the same generation who are within three generations of foreigners coming to China to adopt, China will not send children abroad for adoption," Mao said.</p>

<p>"We express our appreciation to those foreign governments and families, who wish to adopt Chinese children, for their good intention and the love and kindness they have shown," she added.</p>

<p>It was not immediately clear what would happen to families who were in the process of adopting children from China.</p>

<p>The rule change comes as Chinese policymakers struggle to encourage young couples to get married and have children after the population fell for two consecutive years.</p>

<p>China has one of the lowest birth rates globally and has been trying to incentivise young women to have children. Many, however, have been put off by the high cost of childcare, worries over job security and their future outlook as growth in the world's second largest economy slows.</p>

<p>China implemented a rigorous one-child policy from 1979-2015 to reduce its population. When families were restricted to having only one child, many opted to keep male children, who are traditionally expected to be the main caregivers for their families, and give up females for adoption.</p>

<p>&nbsp;&nbsp; China's move to halt international adoptions comes after the Netherlands in May banned its citizens from adopting children from foreign countries. In Denmark, people will no longer be able to adopt children from abroad after the only adoption agency said it was stopping operations.</p>

<p></p>

<p>(Reporting by Farah Master and the Beijing newsroom; editing by Miral Fahmy)</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/foqjprv8_china-children_625x300_07_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-why-helium-leaks-delayed-boeing-starliner-astronauts-return-6509846]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: Why Helium Leaks Delayed Boeing Starliner Astronauts' Return]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-why-helium-leaks-delayed-boeing-starliner-astronauts-return-6509846]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Sep 2024 09:48:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Two NASA astronauts aboard Boeing's Starliner will stay on the International Space Station for months because of a faulty propulsion system whose problems included helium leaks.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Two NASA astronauts aboard Boeing's Starliner will stay on the International Space Station for months because of a faulty propulsion system whose problems included helium leaks. Back on Earth, SpaceX's Polaris Dawn mission has been delayed because of helium issues on ground equipment.</p>

<p>Boeing's Starliner spacecraft landed uncrewed in a New Mexico desert late on Friday.</p>

<p>Past missions have that have been affected by pesky helium leaks include ISRO's Chandrayaan 2 and ESA's Ariane 5. Why do spacecraft and rockets use helium, and what is so tricky about it?</p>

<h2>WHY HELIUM?</h2>

<p>Helium is inert - it does not react with other substances or combust - and its atomic number is 2, making it the second lightest element after hydrogen.</p>

<p>Rockets need to achieve specific speeds and altitude to reach and maintain orbit. A heavier rocket requires more energy, not only increasing fuel consumption but also needing more powerful engines, which are more expensive to develop, test, and maintain.</p>

<p>Helium also has a very low boiling point (-268.9°C or -452°F), allowing it to remain a gas even in super-cold environments, an important feature because many rocket fuels are stored in that temperature range.</p>

<p>The gas is non-toxic, but cannot be breathed on its own, because it displaces the oxygen humans need for respiration.</p>

<h2>HOW IS IT USED?</h2>

<p>Helium is used to pressurize fuel tanks, ensuring fuel flows to the rocket's engines without interruption; and for cooling systems.</p>

<p>As fuel and oxidiser are burned in the rocket's engines, helium fills the resulting empty space in the tanks, maintaining the overall pressure inside.</p>

<p>Because it is non-reactive, it can safely mingle with the tanks' residual contents.</p>

<h2>IS IT PRONE TO LEAKS?</h2>

<p>Helium's small atomic size and low molecular weight mean its atoms can escape through small gaps or seals in storage tanks and fuel systems.</p>

<p>But because there is very little helium in the Earth's atmosphere, leaks can be easily detected - making the gas important for spotting potential faults in a rocket or spacecraft's fuel systems.</p>

<p>In May, hours before Boeing's Starliner spacecraft made an initial attempt to launch its first astronaut crew, tiny sensors inside the spacecraft detected a small helium leak on one of Starliner's thrusters that NASA spent several days analysing before deeming it low-risk.</p>

<p>Additional leaks were detected in space after Starliner launched in June, contributing to NASA's decision to bring Starliner back to Earth without its crew.</p>

<p>The frequency of helium leaks across space-related systems, some engineers say, have highlighted an industry-wide need for innovation in valve design and more precise valve-tightening mechanisms.</p>

<h2>ARE THERE ALTERNATIVES?</h2>

<p>Some rocket launches have experimented with gases such as argon and nitrogen, which are also inert and can sometimes be cheaper. Helium, however, is much more prevalent in the industry.</p>

<p>Europe's new Ariane 6 rocket ditched the helium of its predecessor Ariane 5 for a novel pressurization system that converts a small portion of its primary liquid oxygen and hydrogen propellants to gas, which then pressurizes those fluids for the rocket engine.</p>

<p>That system failed in space during the final phase of Ariane 6's otherwise successful debut launch in July, adding to the global rocket industry's long list of pressurization challenges.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/al1jc96g_boeing-starliner_625x300_05_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>