<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Sat, 29 Jun 2024 18:02:12 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pak-court-asks-pmo-to-refrain-intelligence-agencies-from-interfering-in-any-judicial-matters-5996177]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Stop Interference In Judiciary By Agencies Like ISI: Pak Court To PM Office]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pak-court-asks-pmo-to-refrain-intelligence-agencies-from-interfering-in-any-judicial-matters-5996177]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 29 Jun 2024 17:52:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A top Pakistani court on Saturday directed the Prime Minister's Office to issue directives to the country's powerful intelligence agencies, including ISI, and ask them not to approach any judge or member of their staff to obtain favourable verdicts.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A top Pakistani court on Saturday directed the Prime Minister's Office to issue directives to the country's powerful intelligence agencies, including Inter-Services Intelligence (ISI), and ask them not to approach any judge or member of their staff to obtain favourable verdicts.</p>

<p>The intelligence agencies, especially ISI, Military Intelligence (MI) and Intelligence Bureau (IB) have been accused by several judges of pressuring them through different means to get desired verdicts, especially in the cases of the former prime minister and founder of Pakistan Tehreek-e-Insaf Imran Khan, his party leaders and supporters.</p>

<p>Almost all -- six of eight judges of the Islamabad High Court -- and a couple of judges of the anti-terrorism courts in Punjab have written to the chief justice of Pakistan and chief justice of the Lahore High Court (LHC), respectively, drawing their attention towards the intelligence agencies' open interference in judicial matters .</p>

<p>Some of them had complained that their family members were picked up by intelligence agencies to put pressure on them (judges).</p>

<p>Lahore High Court Justice Shahid Karim on Saturday issued written directions to the Prime Minister's Office on the complaint of an ATC judge in the Sargodha district of Punjab against harassment by the personnel of ISI.</p>

<p>"The prime minister is responsible and answerable for the actions of intelligence agencies as they come under his command. Instructions shall go out by the Prime Minister's Office to all civil or military agencies, including the ISI and IB, regarding strict directions not to approach or contact any judge whether of the superior judiciary or subordinate judiciary or any member of their staff for any purpose in the future," the judge said in his written order. Similar directions have also been issued for the Punjab police.</p>

<p>The court said the inspector general and police chief would be held personally responsible and contempt proceedings would be initiated in case of non-implementation of its order.</p>

<p>The LHC also directed ATC judges across Punjab to "download call-recording applications on their mobile phones to have the record of all such calls (from intelligence agencies) made to influence judicial proceedings." The Sargodha ATC judge was scheduled to hear the cases of some PTI leaders including opposition leader in the National Assembly Omar Ayub when he was told that a senior ISI officer wanted to meet him at his chamber. As the judge refused, several harassment incidents targeted at his family took place in the following days.</p>

<p>PTI spokesperson Raoof Hasan said as part of a malicious and well-thought-out plot the mandate-thief government and its handlers are coercing the judiciary into making decisions of their choice.</p>

<p>"The trend of holding judges and their family members hostage and occupying the courts are being used as new tactics to prevent the courts from delivering justice, as such brazen interference in judicial affairs has already been described by six judges of the Islamabad High Court in their letter," he said.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2019-07/att9hsso_court-generic_625x300_27_July_19.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The directions were given by the Lahore High Court.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/instagram-suffer-major-outage-globally-including-in-india-5995822]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Instagram Suffer Major Outage Globally, Including In India]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/instagram-suffer-major-outage-globally-including-in-india-5995822]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 29 Jun 2024 14:11:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Meta-owned Instagram on Saturday suffered a major outage globally, including in India, as thousands of users were unable to load Reels and access other options.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Meta-owned Instagram on Saturday suffered a major outage globally, including in India, as thousands of users were unable to load Reels and access other options.</p>

<p>As per website outage tracking website Downdetector, over 6,500 users reported issues with accessing the platform in India at the peak of an outage at around 12.02 p.m.</p>

<p>About 58 per cent reported problems with the feed, 32 per cent with the app, and 10 per cent with server connection.</p>

<p>Users from Delhi, Jaipur, Lucknow, Mumbai, Ahmedabad, Kolkata, Hyderabad, Bengaluru, Chennai, and others faced issues with the app.</p>

<p>Users took to X to vent their frustration as they were unable to log in to the app, load Reels, and others.</p>

<p>"Everyone going towards Twitter to check if Instagram is down," a user wrote.</p>

<p>"I thought my Instagram got hacked cuz there's no way my fyp looks like this. It's all brain rot usually #instagramdown," another user said.</p>

<p>One more user stated, "Me going to Twitter to check if it's only my Instagram that's down, or we all are suffering #instagramdown".</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-02/qqv8pi2_instagram-generic-unsplash_625x300_23_February_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[About 58 per cent reported problems with the feed.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/turbulence-at-washington-post-with-pressure-for-profit-from-jeff-bezos-5995338]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Turbulence At Washington Post With Pressure For Profit From Jeff Bezos]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/turbulence-at-washington-post-with-pressure-for-profit-from-jeff-bezos-5995338]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 29 Jun 2024 12:41:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The prestigious Washington Post is in crisis, with pressure on from owner Jeff Bezos to change its money-losing ways.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The prestigious Washington Post is in crisis, with pressure on from owner Jeff Bezos to change its money-losing ways.</p>

<p>The Post's managing editor abruptly resigned; a chosen successor withdrew under fire, and a boss has been targeted in the newspaper's columns.</p>

<p>At the heart of the storm is "WaPo"'s new CEO, Briton William Lewis, who was given a mission by Amazon founder Bezos when he appointed him last autumn.</p>

<p>Lewis was asked to turn around a newspaper that continues to pile up Pulitzer Prizes half a century after the Watergate scandal it instigated, but which has lost $77 million in 2023 despite job cuts and the disappearance of its Sunday supplement.</p>

<p>However, the former journalist, who made history in the late 2000s with a scoop on the expenses of British MPs when he was editor of the Daily Telegraph, is finding his position increasingly vulnerable.</p>

<p>For weeks now, revelations have multiplied about his role, when he was working for the Murdoch family's conservative media group about 12 years ago, in a scandal of illegal phone tapping by the tabloid The News of the World.</p>

<p>On Friday, Lewis was at the center of an investigation by his own journalists.</p>

<p>According to the Washington Post, he gave the go-ahead in 2011 for the destruction of thousands of emails, fueling suspicions that he was destroying evidence, which he denies.</p>

<p><strong>"Trump Bump"</strong></p>

<p>As the US presidential election approaches, the affair is poisoning the atmosphere at a long-vaunted newspaper that is "not doing well economically," Northeastern University journalism professor Dan Kennedy tells AFP.</p>

<p>The Post was among trusted news outlets that benefited from the upheaval that marked Trump's four years in the White House which ended with his loss to President Joe Biden.</p>

<p>The Post "was seen as a place that offered really tough, truth-telling coverage" of Trump, according to the professor.</p>

<p>Trump's departure from the White House meant fewer attention-grabbing stories to keep readers engaged.</p>

<p>"When Donald Trump left the White House, the Trump bump that helped a lot of newspapers disappeared," Kennedy said.</p>

<p>"And the Post was hit especially hard."</p>

<p>By the end of 2022, the Post would have 2.5 million subscribers compared with 3 million subscribers when Biden took office in early 2021, according to the Wall Street Journal.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, rival New York Times has grown to more than 10 million subscribers, the fruit of a strategy to diversify into fun topics such as games, food, and lifestyle while still serving up hard news.</p>

<p>US media quoted Lewis as telling editorial staff in early June that he "can't sugarcoat it anymore" -- the paper has lost a lot of money and people's interest in its articles.</p>

<p><strong>Third News Team</strong></p>

<p>The day before that editorial meeting, Post journalists learned of the resignation of editor-in-chief Sally Buzbee.</p>

<p>Buzbee is said to have disagreed with Lewis's strategy to split the editorial department into three divisions: news, opinion, and a new third unit devoted to social media and service journalism.</p>

<p>The contours of this "third newsroom" remain unclear, but it seems aimed at reviving readership in a leap into the unknown for the newspaper.</p>

<p>Within the Murdoch family group, Lewis was the boss of the Wall Street Journal (2014-2020), another flagship of the US press.</p>

<p>However, articles in the New York Times and the Post pointed to questionable methods employed under his watch and that of former colleague Robert Winnett, whom Lewis chose to replace Buzbee.</p>

<p>Published allegations include paying informants, using data from hacked phones, or intermediaries using phony identification to get information.</p>

<p>Winnett withdrew from consideration for the post following those revelations.</p>

<p>Professor Kennedy believes Lewis has no choice but to leave the Post because he has lost the confidence of the team there.</p>

<p>"The body is rejecting the transfusion," Post veteran David Maraniss wrote on his Facebook page, adding he didn't know anyone who thinks the situation can stand as it is.</p>

<p>"If he can't inspire the staff (...) the Post will sail without direction and its best people will leave," Kennedy said of Lewis.</p>

<p>For many observers, the outcome of the crisis lies in the hands of billionaire Bezos, who bought the Post for $250 million in 2013.</p>

<p>So far, Bezos has backed his CEO.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-12/8hiqlajg_the-washington-post_625x300_06_December_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Post's managing editor resigned while a boss has been targeted in the paper's columns]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-shares-stage-with-elton-john-to-celebrate-lgbtq-milestone-5995250]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Joe Biden Shares Stage With Elton John To Celebrate LGBTQ Milestone]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-shares-stage-with-elton-john-to-celebrate-lgbtq-milestone-5995250]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 29 Jun 2024 12:30:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden paid tribute to LGBTQ pioneers and British music legend Elton John performed his hits as the pair inaugurated on Friday a historical site in New York City celebrating the 1969 "Stonewall riots".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden paid tribute to LGBTQ pioneers and British music legend Elton John performed his hits as the pair inaugurated on Friday a historical site in New York City celebrating the 1969 "Stonewall riots".</p>

<p>Appearing sharper than he did in a disastrous debate against Donald Trump the night before, 81-year-old Biden praised those who revolted on June 28, 1969 against yet another police raid on the Greenwich Village gay bar Stonewall Inn -- a foundational moment in the fight for LGBTQ rights.</p>

<p>"You marked a turning point for civil rights in America and inspired the hearts of millions around the world. To this day, Stonewall remains a symbol of a legacy of leadership for the LGBTQ+ community, especially trans women of color," he said.</p>

<p>"We remain in a battle for the soul of America," Biden added, before introducing John to the stage.</p>

<p>The six nights of the Stonewall riots marked the birth of the modern gay rights movement. Gay Pride was born in their wake.</p>

<p>The bar still exists and was designated a national monument by former president Barack Obama in 2016.</p>

<p>Since Friday, a small, free museum has been added where visitors can learn about the site's history.</p>

<p>"Just as Americans visit Independence Hall, Liberty Bell or the Statue of Liberty to embrace the history of our country, now we can pay homage to a place where we began to fight for our freedom, our rights, our equality," said Mark Segal, who was part of the revolt at Stonewall.</p>

<p>Elton John, himself an LGBTQ icon, told attendees: "The job isn't done."</p>

<p>The 77-year-old musician concluded a triumphant farewell tour last year, but returned to the stage on Friday to treat guests to a short recital.</p>

<p>He dedicated the classic "Don't Let the Sun Go Down on Me" to his friend Larry Kramer, one of the co-founders of the Act Up organization, and to "all the LGBTQ+ people that have gone before us and have paved the way for where we are now."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/4o647798_joe-biden-elton-john-afp_625x300_29_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Elton John with Joe Biden at the Stonewall National Monument Visitor Center]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/can-joe-biden-be-replaced-as-democratic-presidential-nominee-the-best-way-is-5995140]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Can Biden Be Replaced As Democratic Presidential Nominee? Best Way Is...]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/can-joe-biden-be-replaced-as-democratic-presidential-nominee-the-best-way-is-5995140]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 29 Jun 2024 12:01:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Within minutes of the conclusion of this weeks presidential debate between Joe Biden and Donald Trump, it became clear to many that the 81-year-old Biden may not be capable of winning the general election in November.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Within minutes of the conclusion of this week's presidential debate between Joe Biden and Donald Trump, it became clear to many that the 81-year-old Biden may not be capable of winning the general election in November.</p>

<p>His inability to clearly communicate during the 90-minute debate earned harsh criticism from across the US political spectrum, most notably among Democrats.</p>

<p>Van Jones, a former official in the Obama administration and CNN analyst, <a href="https://sg.news.yahoo.com/ex-obama-adviser-van-jones-045230154.html?guccounter=1">said</a> about Biden:</p>

<blockquote>
<p>He had a test to meet tonight to restore confidence in the country and of the base, and he failed to do that.</p>

<p>We're still far from our convention. And there is time for this party to figure out a different way forward.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Biden did land a few blows on his predecessor over Trump's various personal indiscretions and the January 6 2021 insurrection on the US Capitol, saying at one point, “you've got the morals of an alley cat”.</p>

<p>But it was not enough to persuade many sceptics that Biden is capable of fighting off the Trump campaign, not to mention performing the duties of US commander-in-chief and the hardest job in the world for another four years.</p>

<p>If polls over the weekend show Biden is losing support after his dreadful debate performance, which seems highly likely, the move to replace him as the Democrats' candidate will become even more intense and, ultimately, irresistible.</p>

<p>How would this play out in the next few weeks?</p>

<h2>Persuading Biden to step aside</h2>

<p>Even with the withering criticism from his party, Biden remains in control of his fate. He won <a href="https://www.nationalreview.com/corner/reminder-biden-has-3894-or-99-of-pledged-dnc-delegates/">99% of the pledged delegates</a> in the Democratic primary process earlier this year, meaning he is entitled to the nomination. As a result, any decision to move to a different candidate starts with Biden himself.</p>

<p>Absent dramatic health news or his removal under the 25th amendment to the Constitution, which <a href="https://thehill.com/homenews/house/4746165-speaker-johnson-cabinet-biden-25th-amendment/">allows for such action</a> by the vice president and a majority of his cabinet if the president is “unable to discharge the powers and duties of his office”, Biden would have to agree to step down as the party's nominee.</p>

<p>We should be realistic here: Biden is a very stubborn man. You don't get to be the president of the United States without being enormously self-confident. Biden may not be the smartest or most talented politician, but he is dogged and relentless in his ambitions.</p>

<p>He ran for president twice before his success in 2020. He didn't let a <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2024/05/14/biden-nearly-died-an-aneurysm-risky-surgery-changed-his-life/">brain aneurysm</a>, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/1987/09/18/us/biden-admits-plagiarism-in-school-but-says-it-was-not-malevolent.html">plagiarism charges</a>, <a href="https://abcnews.go.com/US/timeline-hunter-biden-legal-political-scrutiny/story?id=102293605">familial dramas</a> or <a href="https://www.history.com/this-day-in-history/joe-biden-loses-first-wife-and-daughter-in-tragic-car-accident">personal tragedy</a> stop him seeking the highest office in the land. The day after the debate with Trump, he shook his fist at a campaign event in North Carolina and asserted, “When you get knocked down, you get back up”.</p>

<p>Persuading Biden to step down would require collaboration with his wife, First Lady Jill Biden. “Dr Jill”, as she is known, has taken a hands-on role in managing the president's daily life and public appearances.</p>

<p>There are very few Democratic Party elders who can be influential with the Bidens. The list probably starts and stops with former President Barack Obama and former House Speaker Nancy Pelosi. If those two go to the first lady and forcefully urge Biden's withdrawal, it could be very difficult to resist.</p>

<h2>How could Biden save face?</h2>

<p>If Biden withdraws from the race before the Democratic convention in mid-August, his delegates could then vote for a new nominee at the event. Potential nominees include Vice President Kamala Harris, California Governor Gavin Newsom, Michigan Governor Gretchen Whitmer and Pennsylvania Governor Josh Shapiro.</p>

<p>Notably, except for Harris, none of these candidates has been vetted publicly during the Democratic primary process for the world's most scrutinised job.</p>

<p>If Biden were to withdraw from the race after the convention, a special meeting of the members of the Democratic National Committee <a href="https://democrats.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/2024-Call-for-Convention.pdf">would decide on the new nominee</a>. This committee includes around <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/2024-election/can-democrats-replace-joe-biden-ballot-rcna159374">500 leading party members</a> from all US states and territories. (Whitmer is one of three vice chairs.)</p>

<p>A question senior Biden confidants might be asking themselves is, which scenario offers Biden a more graceful and successful exit?</p>

<p>He may want to anoint a successor and he would want to choose the method that offers him the most control. That may be the convention route, where he at least can claim the allegiance of his primary delegates.</p>

<p>This would require an announcement in the next few weeks. The sooner the better, so as to build as much public support as possible for a new nominee. Biden could salvage a significant amount of his reputation if his handpicked successor then defeated Trump in November.</p>

<p>Things look grim for Democrats right now, but in the long run, they may be in a strong position. Trump is very unpopular with most Americans. The 2021 insurrection remains a massive stain on his legacy. His vote ceiling among probable voters in November is still likely below 50%.</p>

<p>Veteran Obama strategist David Axelrod <a href="https://thehill.com/homenews/campaign/4745498-biden-debate-trump-challenge/">warned Republicans</a> after the debate:</p>

<blockquote>
<p>If, for whatever reason, there's a change at the top of the ticket, you guys are in trouble with Donald Trump. Because the guy who was up there tonight is not a guy who's going to inspire people.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>A tough and nimble Democratic candidate who can communicate clearly could be very successful in November.<!-- Below is The Conversation's page counter tag. Please DO NOT REMOVE. --><img alt="The Conversation" height="1" referrerpolicy="no-referrer-when-downgrade" src="https://counter.theconversation.com/content/233637/count.gif?distributor=republish-lightbox-basic" style="border: none !important; box-shadow: none !important; margin: 0 !important; max-height: 1px !important; max-width: 1px !important; min-height: 1px !important; min-width: 1px !important; opacity: 0 !important; outline: none !important; padding: 0 !important" width="1" /><!-- End of code. If you don't see any code above, please get new code from the Advanced tab after you click the republish button. The page counter does not collect any personal data. More info: https://theconversation.com/republishing-guidelines --></p>

<p><em><span>(<strong>Author:</strong> <a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/lester-munson-1476430">Lester Munson</a>, Non-Resident Fellow, United States Studies Centre, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/university-of-sydney-841">University of Sydney</a>)</span></em></p>

<p><em><span>(<strong>Disclosure Statement:</strong> </span>Lester Munson receives funding from the U.S. Studies Centre at the University of Sydney. He is affiliated with BGR Group, a Washington, D.C., consulting firm and is a former Republican official in the George W. Bush administration and on Capitol Hill)</em></p>

<p><em>This article is republished from <a href="https://theconversation.com">The Conversation</a> under a Creative Commons license. Read the <a href="https://theconversation.com/the-most-realistic-way-to-replace-joe-biden-as-the-democratic-presidential-nominee-allow-him-a-graceful-exit-233637">original article</a>.</em><br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/257p3v2_joe-biden-ians_625x300_29_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The most realistic way to replace Biden as Democratic presidential nominee - Allow him a graceful exit]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/michelle-obama-to-replace-joe-biden-us-senators-bold-prediction-5994892]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Michelle Obama To Replace Joe Biden? US Senator's Bold Prediction]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/michelle-obama-to-replace-joe-biden-us-senators-bold-prediction-5994892]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 29 Jun 2024 11:17:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former First Lady Michelle Obama will replace President Joe Biden as the Democratic nominee, US Senator Ted Cruz (R-Texas) has predicted.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former First Lady Michelle Obama will replace President Joe Biden as the Democratic nominee, US Senator Ted Cruz (R-Texas) has predicted. Cruz claims Biden will be replaced at the Democratic National Convention in August, just three months before the election.</p>

<p>The prediction comes after the first presidential debate where Biden's performance was widely criticised by political analysts and news organisations. Some strategists are reportedly discussing ways to replace Biden on the ballot.</p>

<p>Democrats are reportedly “panicked” and actively discussing replacing Biden on the ticket, citing his “hoarse and halting voice”, “unclear” answers and “struggle” to finish his thoughts, according to the <a href="https://messaging-custom-newsletters.nytimes.com/dynamic/render?campaign_id=9&amp;emc=edit_nn_20240628&amp;instance_id=127433&amp;isViewInBrowser=true&amp;nl=the-morning&amp;paid_regi=1&amp;productCode=NN&amp;regi_id=217325255&amp;segment_id=170785&amp;te=1&amp;uri=nyt%3A%2F%2Fnewsletter%2F3a2a8a39-27c8-558a-90ce-8e95b2f8f337&amp;user_id=57b084e23490cb23c6e08fcd268739c6 ">NYT</a> and <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2024/06/27/biden-democrats-replacement-00165672 ">Politico</a>. Some are even “pushing for him to drop out of the race”,&nbsp; and “replacing him on the ticket.”</p>

<p>Cruz shared his thoughts on his podcast, saying the Democratic Party will likely replace&nbsp;Biden with Michelle Obama due to his poor debate performance. “The odds are north of 80% that the Democratic Party will remove Joe Biden from the ticket and replace him with Michelle Obama because Biden did so disastrously badly tonight that Democrats across the country are in utter freefall and complete panic,” he said.</p>

<p>After the presidential debate on Thursday, leaders from both parties share their thoughts on social media. While Biden supporters attributed his poor performance to a cold, Republicans were more critical.</p>

<p>Nikki Haley, former presidential candidate, posted on X, "Mark my words... Biden will not be the Democratic nominee. Republicans, get your guard up!"</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Mark my words….Biden will not be the Democrat nominee. Republicans, get your guard up!</p>
— Nikki Haley (@NikkiHaley) <a href="https://twitter.com/NikkiHaley/status/1806524623913123859?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 28, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Vivek Ramaswamy, a potential VP pick for Trump, shared a series of critical tweets about Biden's debate performance. He suggested that the Democratic Party is using Biden as a "sacrificial lamb" and implied that they should replace him with a different nominee.&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">The game is now more obvious than ever: the Democrat Party served up an old man as their sacrificial lamb tonight.</p>
— Vivek Ramaswamy (@VivekGRamaswamy) <a href="https://twitter.com/VivekGRamaswamy/status/1806496866181251288?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 28, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Meanwhile, former US President Barack Obama has come out in support of Joe Biden, urging Americans to remember the core values at stake in the election. "Bad debate nights happen, trust me, I know," Obama said, downplaying Biden's poor debate performance.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Bad debate nights happen. Trust me, I know. But this election is still a choice between someone who has fought for ordinary folks his entire life and someone who only cares about himself. Between someone who tells the truth; who knows right from wrong and will give it to the…</p>
— Barack Obama (@BarackObama) <a href="https://twitter.com/BarackObama/status/1806758633230709017?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 28, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>He added that the election is still a choice between two fundamentally different candidates: one who has fought for ordinary people his entire life and another who only cares about himself.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-03/vsu9b0i8_michelle-obama_625x300_08_March_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/khamenei-protege-sole-moderate-neck-and-neck-in-iran-presidential-race-5994835]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Khamenei Protege, Sole Moderate Neck And Neck In Iran Presidential Race]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/khamenei-protege-sole-moderate-neck-and-neck-in-iran-presidential-race-5994835]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 29 Jun 2024 11:01:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A low-key moderate and a protege of Iran's supreme leader are neck-and-neck in the vote count in snap presidential elections marked by voter apathy over economic hardships and social restrictions.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A low-key moderate and a protege of Iran's supreme leader are neck-and-neck in the vote count in snap presidential elections marked by voter apathy over economic hardships and social restrictions.</p>

<p>More than 14 million votes have been counted so far from Friday's vote, of which the sole moderate candidate Massoud Pezeshkian had won over 5.9 million votes and his hardline challenger former nuclear negotiator Saeed Jalili over 5.5 million, provisional results by the interior ministry showed.</p>

<p>Some insiders said the turnout was around 40%, lower than expected by Iran's clerical rulers, while witnesses told Reuters that polling stations in Tehran and some other cities were not crowded.</p>

<p>Iran's Tasnim news agency said a run-off election was "very likely" to pick the next president following the death of Ebrahim Raisi in a helicopter crash last month.</p>

<p>If no candidate wins at least 50% plus one vote from all ballots cast, including blank votes, a run-off between the top two candidates is held on the first Friday after the result is declared.</p>

<p>The election coincides with escalating regional tension due to the war between Israel and Iranian allies Hamas in Gaza and Hezbollah in Lebanon, as well as increased Western pressure on Iran over its fast-advancing nuclear programme.</p>

<p>While the election is unlikely to bring a major shift in the Islamic Republic's policies, its outcome could influence the succession to Ayatollah Ali Khamenei, Iran's 85-year-old supreme leader, in power since 1989.</p>

<p>The clerical establishment sought a high turnout to offset a legitimacy crisis fuelled by public discontent over economic hardship and curbs on political and social freedom.</p>

<p>The next president is not expected to usher in any major policy shift on Iran's nuclear programme or support for militia groups across the Middle East, since Khamenei calls all the shots on top state matters.</p>

<p>However, the president runs the government day-to-day and can influence the tone of Iran's foreign and domestic policy.</p>

<p>Pezeshkian's views offer a contrast to those of Jalili, advocating detente with the West, economic reform, social liberalisation, and political pluralism.</p>

<p>A staunch anti-Westerner, Jalili's win would signal the possibility of an even more antagonistic turn in the Islamic Republic's foreign and domestic policy, analysts said.</p>

<p><strong>LIMITED CHOICES</strong></p>

<p>The election was a contest among a tightly controlled group of three hardline candidates and one low-profile moderate loyal to the supreme leader. A hardline watchdog body approved only six from an initial pool of 80 and two hardline candidates subsequently dropped out.</p>

<p>"Based on unconfirmed reports, the election is very likely heading to a second round ... Jalili and Pezeshkian will compete in a run-off election," Tasnim reported.</p>

<p>Critics of the clerical establishment say that low turnouts in recent years show the system's legitimacy has eroded. Turnout was 48% in the 2021 presidential election and a record low of 41% of people voted in a parliamentary election in March.</p>

<p>All candidates have vowed to revive the flagging economy, beset by mismanagement, state corruption, and sanctions re-imposed since 2018 after the U.S. ditched Tehran's nuclear pact.</p>

<p>"I think Jalili is the only candidate who raised the issue of justice, fighting corruption and giving value to the poor. ... Most importantly, he does not link Iran's foreign policy to the nuclear deal," said Farzan, a 45-year-old artist in the city of Karaj.</p>

<p><strong>DIVIDED VOTERS</strong></p>

<p>Pezeshkian, faithful to Iran's theocratic rule, is backed by the reformist faction that has largely been sidelined in Iran in recent years.</p>

<p>"We will respect the hijab law, but there should never be any intrusive or inhumane behaviour toward women," Pezeshkian said after casting his vote.</p>

<p>He was referring to the death of Mahsa Amini, a young Kurdish woman, in 2022 while in morality police custody for allegedly violating the mandatory Islamic dress code.</p>

<p>The unrest sparked by Amini's death spiralled into the biggest show of opposition to Iran's clerical rulers in years.</p>

<p>Pezeshkian attempted to revive the enthusiasm of reform-minded voters who have largely stayed away from the polls for the last four years as a mostly youthful population chafes at political and social curbs. He could also benefit from his rivals' failure to consolidate the hardline vote.</p>

<p>In the past few weeks, Iranians have made wide use of the hashtag #ElectionCircus on X, with some activists at home and abroad calling for a boycott, saying a high turnout would only serve to legitimise the Islamic Republic.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/f8k44mrg_iran-presidential-polls-reuters_625x300_29_June_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Presidential candidate Saeed Jalili votes at a polling station]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/astronaut-sunita-williams-may-have-to-wait-months-in-space-what-nasa-is-planning-now-5994474]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Sunita Williams May Have To Wait Months In Space. What NASA Is Planning Now]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/astronaut-sunita-williams-may-have-to-wait-months-in-space-what-nasa-is-planning-now-5994474]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 29 Jun 2024 11:01:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Projected to last only days, the first crewed test flight of Boeing's Starliner spacecraft with two astronauts onboard faces uncertainty with no exact return to Earth announced.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Projected to last only days, the first crewed test flight of Boeing's Starliner spacecraft with two astronauts onboard faces uncertainty with no exact return to Earth announced.</p>

<p>NASA's Commercial Crew Program manager, Steve Stich has said that the US space agency is considering extending the duration of Starliner's mission from 45 days to 90 days, CNN reported.</p>

<p>Officials have repeatedly hinted that the Starliner, which faced issues with helium leaks and thruster outages heading to the International Space Station in early June, will be safe to bring astronauts including indian-origin Sunita 'Suni' Williams and Butch Wilmore home.</p>

<p>On Friday, Stich said that NASA is considering extending the maximum length of Starliner's mission from 45 days to 90 days and there is no firm return date on the horizon, according to CNN report.</p>

<p>Addressing a briefing on Friday, the NASA official said, "We're just looking at the timeline to execute (the test in New Mexico) and then review the data." He further said, "And that's what's really the long pole, I would say, determining a landing date."</p>

<p>Stich added, "We're not in a rush to come home."</p>

<p>Part of that desired extension is due to the ground tests that Boeing and NASA plan to conduct in New Mexico, seeking to better understand why some of the Starliner's thrusters unexpectedly failed during the first leg of its journey.</p>

<p>Stich and Mark Nappi, vice president and program manager of the Commercial Crew Program for Boeing, also said that engineers are still not certain about the reason behind the Starliner's problems.</p>

<p>Nappi said that part of the aim is conducting the ground tests while the vehicle is still in space is to try to whittle down possible reasons why the thrusters malfunctioned.</p>

<p>Mark Nappi said, "So, if (the test in New Mexico) comes back and gives us all the answers, then we can just undock and come home."</p>

<p>He added, "If it comes back and says, 'Here's 80 per cent of the answer. And if you just run one more docked hot fire (test on the Starliner in orbit), then you can get 100 per cent of the answers' -- then we want (Starliner) to be there so that we can get that information."</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Williams and Wilmore have integrated with the rest of the crew currently aboard the International Space Station and are conducting routine tasks.</p>

<p>Several more helium leaks were identified while the craft was heading to the International Space Station, along with the thruster issues. The Starliner's service module, a cylindrical attachment at the bottom of the spacecraft that provides much of the vehicle's power during flight, faced several issues, CNN reported.</p>

<p>As per the design, the service module will not survive the return to Earth. The module is jettisoned and destroyed as the Starliner spacecraft reenters the atmosphere and that's the reason why Boeing and NASA teams then opted to leave the Starliner spacecraft safely docked with the space station while they worked to learn as much as possible about those issues.</p>

<p>It is not clear yet whether NASA will extend the maximum mission length to 90 days. Stich said officials must clear the battery life of the Starliner for that purpose. Although he noted that the batteries are being recharged at the space station, they should operate the same way after 90 days as they will for the first 45 days.</p>

<p>The spaceflight industry frequently experiences cost overruns, delays and unmet deadlines. However, Boeing has faced challenges that have stood out, particularly when the Starliner program is directly compared with SpaceX's Crew Dragon, CNN reported.</p>

<p>Crew Dragon, which falls under the same NASA Commercial Crew Program for astronaut transportation, completed its first test flight in 2020 and has been carrying out routine missions ever since.</p>

<p>SpaceX did not have the benefit of designing the Crew Dragon spacecraft off the back of its Cargo Dragon vehicle, which for years sent supplies to the International Space Station before its successor started operating while Boeing designed Starliner from scratch.</p>

<p>Nappi said, "We've got a really good test flight that's been accomplished so far, and it's being viewed rather negatively."</p>

<p>In the latest update regarding the ongoing space mission, the Expedition 71 crew members on Friday packed a US cargo craft, cleaned up the International Space Station, studied techniques of futuristic piloting, and carried out eye exams.</p>

<p>NASA's Boeing Crew Flight Test astronauts spent the day reconfiguring a space botany facility. In its live blog, NASA stated, " Robotics controllers are scheduled to detach the Cygnus space freighter from the Unity module on July 12 and release it into Earth orbit for disposal over the South Pacific Ocean ending a five-and-a-half-month mission at the orbital lab."</p>

<p>NASA Flight Engineer Matthew Dominick spent most of the time on Friday on loading trash and discarding gear inside the Cygnus with assistance from fellow NASA astronauts Jeanette Epps and Tracy C Dyson. Canadarm2 robotic arm captured the Cygnus on February 1, with more than 8200 pounds of science experiments and crew supplies.</p>

<p>Epps operated standard medical imaging gear found in an optometrist's office on Earth and peered into Dyson's eyes. She examined the cornea, retina, and lens of Dyson to help flight surgeons understand and counteract microgravity's effect on crew vision.</p>

<p>Earlier, Dyson collected and stowed excess space station hardware for disposal. During the day, NASA Flight Engineer Mike Barratt routed cables and reprogrammed communications systems inside the Columbus laboratory module.</p>

<p>He stowed hardware and components used earlier in the week for advanced orbital plumbing in the Tranquility module's bathroom. Mike Barratt refilled supply kits in Columbus' two Human Research Facility racks with biomedical gear, including sample tubes and needles.</p>

<p>On Friday, Starliner's Commander and Pilot, Butch Wilmore and Sunita Williams in Kibo conducted space botany work. They removed the Plant Habitat growth chamber from Kibo's EXPRESS rack, replaced its camera and carbon dioxide sensors, then reinstalled the research device.</p>

<p>In the liveblog, NASA said, "NASA and Boeing continue to evaluate Starliner's propulsion system performance before returning to Earth from the orbiting lab. NASA and Boeing leaders participated in a media teleconference today to discuss Starliner and station operations."</p>

<p>"NASA is now targeting the end of July for the next spacewalk outside the space station. This change allows teams on the ground to continue to troubleshoot and understand the water leak in the service and cooling umbilical unit that forced an early end to a spacewalk on Monday, June 24," it added.</p>

<p>Flight Engineer Nikolai Chub practiced planetary spacecraft and robotic piloting techniques future crew members and conducted two sessions of an investigation exploring ways to create new materials on the lunar surface.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Flight Engineer Alexander Grebenkin worked throughout the day inventorying medical kits and cleaning fans inside the Rassvet module and Station Commander Oleg Kononenko replaced thermal components in Roscosmos' life support hardware.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/nc9v6568_sunita-williams_625x300_25_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Boeing Starliner with Sunita Williams onboard could wait months in space before return.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/morgan-stanley-says-pm-gati-shakti-scheme-gives-india-an-edge-over-china-5987478]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Morgan Stanley Says PM Gati Shakti Scheme Gives India An Edge Over China]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/morgan-stanley-says-pm-gati-shakti-scheme-gives-india-an-edge-over-china-5987478]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 29 Jun 2024 09:54:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Morgan Stanley has stated that the PM Gati Shakti scheme has succeeded in giving a new fillip to India's infrastructure development and multi-modal connectivity across highways, railways and ports that has spurred economic growth.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Global investment bank and financial company Morgan Stanley has stated that the PM Gati Shakti scheme has succeeded in giving a new fillip to India's infrastructure development and multi-modal connectivity across highways, railways and ports that has spurred economic growth.</p>

<p>According to the report, India has scaled up its infrastructure strongly over the last decade, with higher investment that is also better targeted and potentially more productive.</p>

<p>"We expect India's infrastructure investment to steadily increase from 5.3 per cent of GDP in FY24 to 6.5 per cent of GDP by FY29. Indeed, this implies that infrastructure investments are expected to register a strong 15.3 per cent CAGR, resulting in cumulative spending of USD 1.45 trillion over the next five years. In our view this will help to lift the investment rate, leading to a sustained period of high productive growth."</p>

<p>Interestingly, the report also states that "contrary to popular perception, India's physical infrastructure scale already compares favourably to China's when viewed in the context of GDP differential."</p>

<p>The report cites the World Bank's Logistics Index Report, 2023, which records that the average Container Dwell Time in Indian ports was three days compared to four days for countries like the UAE and South Africa, seven days for the USA, and 10 days for Germany.</p>

<p>Indian Ports "turnaround time" has reached 0.9 days, which is better than the USA (1.5 days), Australia (1.7 days), Singapore (1.0 days), etc. 6. In F24, ports overall cargo growth was 7 per cent, with 53 per cent of cargo handled by major ports (government-owned).</p>

<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi launched the PM Gati Shakti National master plan for infrastructure development in October 2021. It brings 16 ministries including Railways and Highways together on a digital platform for integrated planning and coordinated implementation of multi-modal connectivity projects. It is conceived as a transformative approach for economic growth and sustainable development with roads, railways, airports, ports, mass transport, waterways and logistics infrastructure constituting "7 engines " to pull the economy forward in unison.</p>

<p>According to the Morgan Stanley Report, initiatives under PM Gati Shakti are yielding results. Under the PM Gati Shakti scheme so far, cumulatively 101 projects worth Rs 60,900 crore have been identified for implementation in the ports and shipping sectors.</p>

<p>As of April 2023, 26 projects, worth Rs 8,900 crore have been completed, 42 projects worth Rs 15,340 crore are under development, and 33 projects worth Rs 36,640 crore are under implementation.</p>

<p>The Ministry of Ports, Shipping, and Waterways (MoPSW) is also implementing a comprehensive port connectivity plan in coordination with the highways and railways ministries.</p>

<p>The Morgan Stanley report says under the Sagarmala programme, 220 projects worth Rs 1.12 lakh crore have been completed and 231 projects worth Rs 2.21 lakh crore are under implementation while 351 projects worth Rs 2.07 lakh crore are at the evaluation stage.</p>

<p>Similarly, National Waterways are also being developed as a more efficient and environment-friendly means of transport for both cargo and passengers.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/rg1hed9s_narendra-modi-pm-gati-shakti-masterplan-ani_625x300_29_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A Morgan Stanley report said PM Gati Shakti scheme has scaled up Indias infra, spurred growth]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/xi-jinping-lauds-indias-panchsheel-agreement-jawaharlal-nehrus-non-alligned-movement-5989801]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Xi Jinping Lauds India's 'Panchsheel' Pact, Nehru's Non-Alligned Movement]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/xi-jinping-lauds-indias-panchsheel-agreement-jawaharlal-nehrus-non-alligned-movement-5989801]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 29 Jun 2024 09:25:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Xi Jinping highlighted the relevance of the 5 Principles of Peaceful Coexistence, which gained traction with the Non-Aligned Movement, to end the present-day conflicts and sought to expand influence in the Global South amid its tussle with the West.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Chinese President Xi Jinping highlighted the relevance of the Five Principles of Peaceful Coexistence, which gained traction with the Non-Aligned Movement, to end the present-day conflicts and sought to expand influence in the Global South amid its tussle with the West.</p>

<p>Xi Jinping, 71, invoked the Five Principles of Peaceful Coexistence, termed as 'Panchsheel' by India, at a conference in Beijing to mark its 70th anniversary and also sought to juxtapose them with his new concept of Global Security Initiative envisaging a shared future for mankind.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.mea.gov.in/Uploads/PublicationDocs/191_panchsheel.pdf" target="_blank">The 'Panchsheel' pointers</a> were first formally enunciated in the Agreement on Trade and Intercourse between the Tibet region of China and India signed on April 29, 1954, according to the Ministry of External Affairs.</p>

<p>'Panchsheel' or The five principles formed part of the legacy of the then Prime Minister Jawaharlal Nehru and his Chinese counterpart Zhou Enlai in their unsuccessful quest to find a solution to the vexed boundary issue.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="President Rajendra Prasad, VP S. Radhakrishnan and PM Nehru with Zhou Enlai at Rashtrapati Bhavan June 26, 1954" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/59vk22s8_rajendra-prasad-s-radhakrishnan-nehru-zhou-enlai_625x300_29_June_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="President Rajendra Prasad, VP S. Radhakrishnan and PM Nehru with Zhou Enlai at Rashtrapati Bhavan June 26, 1954" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">President Rajendra Prasad, VP S. Radhakrishnan and PM Nehru with Zhou Enlai at Rashtrapati Bhavan June 26, 1954<br />
<span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: Photo Credit - mea.gov.in</span></p>
</div>

<p>"The Five Principles of Peaceful Coexistence answered the call of the times, and its initiation was an inevitable historic development. The Chinese leadership in the past specified the Five Principles in their entirety for the first time, namely, 'mutual respect for sovereignty and territorial integrity', 'mutual non-aggression', 'mutual non-interference in each other's internal affairs', 'equality and mutual benefit', and 'peaceful coexistence'," Xi Jinping said.</p>

<p>"They included the Five Principles in the China-India and China-Myanmar joint statements which jointly called for making them basic norms for state-to-state relations," Xi said at the conference where the invitees included former Sri Lankan President Mahinda Rajapaksa and several political leaders and officials from various countries closely associated with China over the years.</p>

<p>'Panchsheel', the Five Principles of Peaceful Coexistence were born in Asia (India) but quickly ascended to the world stage. In 1955, more than 20 Asian and African countries attended the Bandung Conference, Xi Jinping recalled in his address.</p>

<p>The Non-Aligned Movement, founded by Jawaharlal Nehru, that rose in the 1960s adopted the 'Panchsheel' or Five Principles as its guiding principles.</p>

<p>"The Five Principles have set a historic benchmark for international relations and international rule of law," he said, highlighting their relevance to ending the present-day conflicts.</p>

<p>They fully conform with the purposes and principles of the UN Charter, with the evolving trend of international relations of our times, and with the fundamental interests of all nations, Xi said and sought to juxtapose them with his new concepts of Global Security Initiative (GSI) which advocates for joint security of nations and the 'Vision of Building a Community with a Shared Future for Mankind'.</p>

<p>Xi, who commenced his unprecedented third five-year term in power last year, has been advocating several initiatives, including his billion-dollar pet project the Belt and Road Initiative (BRI), to enhance China's global influence.</p>

<p>Under the BRI, Beijing has made huge investments in infrastructure projects in smaller countries which in subsequent years attracted allegations of debt diplomacy as many countries struggled to pay back loans taken from China.</p>

<p>Also, facing increasing strategic competition from the US and EU, China in recent years jostled with India and other developing countries to consolidate its influence in the Asian, African and Latin American countries, largely termed as Global South.</p>

<p>China will establish a Global South Research Centre to better support Global South-South cooperation, Xi said.</p>

<p>China will provide 1,000 'Five Principles of Peaceful Coexistence Scholarship of Excellence,' 1,00,000 training opportunities to Global South countries in the next five years, and also launch a 'Global South Youth Leaders' programme, he said.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/9q5um73c_zhou-enlai-jawaharlal-nehru-mao-zedong_625x300_29_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[(L-R) Amb. Raghavan, Zhou Enlai, PM Jawaharlal Nehru, Chairman Mao Zedong in Beijing, Oct 19, 1954]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/insufficient-evidence-28-defendants-acquitted-in-panama-papers-trial-5994270]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Insufficient Evidence: 28 Defendants Acquitted In Panama Papers Trial]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/insufficient-evidence-28-defendants-acquitted-in-panama-papers-trial-5994270]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 29 Jun 2024 08:54:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Panamanian court on Friday acquitted 28 people charged with money laundering at the center of the "Panama Papers" scandal, the court said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Panamanian court on Friday acquitted 28 people charged with money laundering at the center of the "Panama Papers" scandal, the court said.</p>

<p>Judge Baloisa Marquinez "acquitted 28 people accused... of money laundering" relating to the now-defunct Panamanian law firm Mossack Fonseca, the court said in a statement.</p>

<p>Among those acquitted were the firm's founders, Jurgen Mossack and Ramon Fonseca. The latter died in May in a Panamanian hospital.</p>

<p>During the trial, which was held in Panama City in April, the prosecution asked for 12 years in prison for the duo, the maximum sentence for money laundering.</p>

<p>However, Marquinez found that evidence collected from the law firm's servers had not been gathered in line with due process, raising doubts about its "authenticity and integrity".</p>

<p>The judge also ruled that "the rest of the evidence was not sufficient and conclusive to determine the criminal responsibility of the defendants," the court statement said.</p>

<p>Leaked documents from Mossack Fonseca in 2016 revealed how many of the world's wealthy stashed assets in offshore companies, triggering scores of investigations around the globe.</p>

<p>Others implicated included former British premier David Cameron, football star Lionel Messi, Argentina's then-president Mauricio Macri and Spanish filmmaker Pedro Almodovar, to name but a few.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-10/mpojkr1k_court-generic-fourt-files-generic-files-in-court-pixabay_625x300_11_October_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The judge also ruled that "the rest of the evidence was not sufficient" in the case (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/5-billion-people-suffered-extreme-heat-in-june-619-million-in-india-alone-report-5988933]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[5 Billion People Suffered Extreme Heat In June, 619 Million In India Alone]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/5-billion-people-suffered-extreme-heat-in-june-619-million-in-india-alone-report-5988933]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 29 Jun 2024 08:32:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Nearly five billion people globally, including 619 million from India, experienced climate-change-driven extreme heat over nine days in June, according to a new analysis by an independent group of scientists based in the US.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Nearly five billion people globally, including 619 million from India, experienced climate-change-driven extreme heat over nine days in June, according to a new analysis by an independent group of scientists based in the US.</p>

<p>The report by Climate Central said that the blistering heat in June impacted 619 million people in India, 579 million in China, 231 million in Indonesia, 206 million in Nigeria, 176 million in Brazil, 171 million in Bangladesh, 165 million in the US, 152 million in Europe, 123 million in Mexico, 121 million in Ethiopia, and 103 million in Egypt.</p>

<p>"More than 60 per cent of the world population faced extreme heat that was made at least three times more likely by climate change during June 16-24," it said.</p>

<p>Andrew Pershing, chief program officer at Climate Central, said, "More than a century of burning coal, oil, and natural gas has given us an increasingly dangerous world. The heat waves around the world this summer are unnatural disasters that will become more common until carbon pollution stops." Climate Central's Climate Shift Index (CSI) determines the influence of climate change on temperatures around the globe.&nbsp; "Between June 16-24, 4.97 billion people experienced extreme heat reaching CSI levels of at least 3, indicating that climate change made these temperatures at least three times more likely to occur," the report said.</p>

<p>India, which experienced one of its hottest and longest heat waves, recorded more than 40,000 suspected heat stroke cases and over 100 heat-related deaths. The intense heat overwhelmed the water supply system and power grids, with Delhi grappling with a severe water crisis.</p>

<p>According to the India Meteorological Department, around 40 per cent of the country recorded double the number of heatwave days than usual during the April to June period. Temperatures breached 50 degrees Celsius in parts of Rajasthan, with nighttime temperatures hovering around 35 degrees Celsius in many places.</p>

<p>In Delhi, which logged 40 consecutive days of temperatures above 40 degrees Celsius since May 13, there have been around 60 heat-related deaths this year, according to media reports.</p>

<p>In Saudi Arabia, at least 1,300 people died from heat-related illnesses during the annual Haj pilgrimage. Temperatures were extremely high, with some cities surpassing 50 degrees Celsius.&nbsp; Climate Central's analysis found that the city of Mecca experienced temperatures made at least three times more likely due to climate change every day since May 18, and five times more likely since May 24.&nbsp; A previous analysis by climate scientists at Climameter, an EU-funded initiative, found that climate change made the heat wave in Saudi Arabia up to 2.5 degrees Celsius hotter.</p>

<p>The US suffered two back-to-back heat episodes during the last two weeks of June.&nbsp; The first heat wave affected the southern part of the country, Mexico, and countries in Central America.&nbsp; In Mexico, at least 125 people died, with temperatures reaching 52 degrees Celsius in the Sonora state on June 21. A study by the World Weather Attribution group found that climate change made the extreme heat of May and June 35 times more likely.</p>

<p>In Egypt, high temperatures nearing 50 degrees Celsius have been recorded in recent days. In the southern province of Aswan, at least 40 people have died.&nbsp; The high temperatures have caused a surge in energy consumption across the country, forcing the government to impose daily power cuts to avoid overloading the electrical grid.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2019-07/buv5taes_heat-wave-reuters_625x300_02_July_19.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[India experienced one of its hottest and longest heat waves globally. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/i-know-i-am-not-young-man-but-joe-biden-after-poor-debate-showing-5994162]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["I Know I'm Not Young Man, But...": Joe Biden After Poor Debate Showing]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/i-know-i-am-not-young-man-but-joe-biden-after-poor-debate-showing-5994162]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 29 Jun 2024 08:22:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Biden said on Friday he intended to defeat Republican rival Donald Trump in the November presidential election, giving no sign he would consider dropping out of the race after a feeble debate performance that dismayed his fellow Democrats.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>President Joe Biden said on Friday he intended to defeat Republican rival Donald Trump in the November presidential election, giving no sign he would consider dropping out of the race after a feeble debate performance that dismayed his fellow Democrats.</p>

<p>"I know I'm not a young man, to state the obvious," an ebullient Biden said at a rally one day after the head-to-head showdown with his Republican rival, which was widely viewed as a defeat for the 81-year-old president.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"I don't walk as easy as I used to, I don't speak as smoothly as I used to, I don't debate as well as I used to," he said, as the crowd chanted "Four more years."</p>

<p>"I would not be running again if I didn't believe with all my heart and soul that I could do this job. The stakes are too high," &nbsp;Biden said.</p>

<p>Biden's verbal stumbles and occasionally meandering responses in the debate heightened voter concerns that he might not be fit to serve another four-year term and prompted some of his fellow Democrats to wonder whether they could replace him as their candidate for the Nov. 5 U.S. election.</p>

<p>Campaign spokesperson Michael Tyler said there were no conversations taking place about that possibility. "We'd rather have one bad night than a candidate with a bad vision for where he wants to take the country," he told reporters aboard Air Force One.</p>

<p>The campaign held an "all hands on deck" meeting on Friday afternoon to reassure staffers that Biden was not dropping out of the race, according to two people familiar with the meeting.</p>

<p>Though Trump, 78, put forward a series of falsehoods throughout the debate, the focus afterward was squarely on Biden, especially among Democrats.</p>

<p>Hakeem Jeffries, the Democratic Party leader in the U.S. House of Representatives, avoided answering directly when asked whether he still had faith in Biden's candidacy.</p>

<p>"I support the ticket. I support the Senate Democratic majority. We're going to do everything possible to take back the House in November. Thank you, everyone," he told reporters.</p>

<p>Some other Democrats likewise demurred when asked if Biden should stay in the race. "That's the president's decision," Democratic Senator Jack Reed told a local TV station in Rhode Island.</p>

<p>But several of the party's most senior figures, including former presidents Bill Clinton and Barack Obama, said they were sticking with Biden.</p>

<p>"Bad debate nights happen. Trust me, I know. But this election is still a choice between someone who has fought for ordinary folks his entire life and somebody who only cares about himself," former Democratic President Barack Obama wrote on X.</p>

<p>The New York Times editorial board, which endorsed Biden in 2020, called on him to drop out of the race to give the Democratic Party a better chance of beating Trump by picking another candidate. "The greatest public service Mr. Biden can now perform is to announce that he will not continue to run for re-election," the editorial said.</p>

<p>The Biden campaign said it raised $14 million on Thursday and Friday and posted its single best hour of fundraising immediately after the Thursday night debate. The Trump campaign said it raised $8 million on the night of the debate.</p>

<p>One possible bright spot for Biden: preliminary viewership data showed that only 48 million Americans watched the debate, far short of the 73 million who watched the candidates' last face-off in 2020.</p>

<p>Biden, already the oldest American president in history, faced only token opposition during the party's months-long nominating contest, and he has secured enough support to guarantee his spot as the Democratic nominee.</p>

<p>Trump likewise overcame his intra-party challengers early in the year, setting the stage for a long and bitter general election fight.</p>

<p>If Biden were to step aside, the party would have less than two months to pick another nominee at its national convention, which starts on Aug. 19 - a potentially messy process that could pit Kamala Harris, the nation's first Black female vice president, against governors and other officeholders whose names have been floated as possible replacements.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>TRUMP TARGETS VIRGINIA</strong></p>

<p>At an afternoon rally in Chesapeake, Virginia, Trump told supporters that he had a "big victory against a man looking to destroy our country."</p>

<p>"Joe Biden's problem is not his age," Trump said. "It's his competence."</p>

<p>Trump advisers said they thought the debate would bolster their chances in Democratic-leaning states like Virginia, which has not backed a Republican presidential candidate since 2004.</p>

<p>Beforehand, some Trump supporters said they were struck by Biden's poor performance. "I'm scared they are going to replace him and put up somebody more competitive," said Mike Boatman, who said he had attended more than 90 Trump rallies.</p>

<p>Trump fundraisers said they were fielding enthusiastic calls from donors. "Anyone who raises money knows there's a time to go to donors, and this is one of those watershed moments," said Ed McMullen, who served as ambassador to Switzerland during Trump's presidency.</p>

<p>Questions about Trump's fitness for office have also arisen over his conviction last month in New York for covering up a hush money payment to a porn star, his efforts to overturn the 2020 election and his chaotic term in office.&nbsp;</p>

<p>He is scheduled to be sentenced on July 11, just days before his party convenes to formally nominate him. He still faces three other criminal indictments, though none appears likely to reach trial before November.</p>

<p>Biden's shaky performance in the debate drew stunned global reactions on Friday, prompting public calls for him to step aside and likely leaving some of America's closest allies steeling for Trump's return.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/f6nmtplg_joe-biden-file-afp_625x300_17_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Joe Biden is the oldest American president in history (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/australian-pm-says-he-his-family-threatened-by-teen-terrorist-report-5994014]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Australian PM Says He, His Family Threatened By Teen Terrorist: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/australian-pm-says-he-his-family-threatened-by-teen-terrorist-report-5994014]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 29 Jun 2024 07:37:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Australia's Prime Minister Anthony Albanese has revealed he and his family were threatened by an accused teenage terrorist.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Australia's Prime Minister Anthony Albanese has revealed he and his family were threatened by an accused teenage terrorist.</p>

<p>Albanese said on Friday that he and his family were among those threatened in an extremist manifesto in which 19-year-old Jordan Patten allegedly outlined his intention to kill Members of Parliament from the governing Labour Party, Xinhua news agency reported.</p>

<p>"There is no place for extremism in Australia. That documentation that was made is very concerning, including threats not just to Labor MPs but to others, to my family," he told reporters in Canberra.</p>

<p>Patten was on Wednesday arrested by the Joint Counter Terrorism Team (JCTT) in the city of Newcastle -- nearly 100 km north of Sydney -- after allegedly entering the office of Tim Crakanthorp, a Labour MP in the New South Wales state parliament, armed with knives and tactical equipment.</p>

<p>He has been charged with one count of preparing for, or planning, a terrorist act.</p>

<p>Authorities said that following Patten's arrest, they became aware of the manifesto that expresses anti-immigration, anti-Semitic and Islamophobic views and a list of grievances against the Labour Party and Albanese.</p>

<p>"It's another reason why families should be off-limits from the media. It's something that is of concern. I applaud the security agencies and police for the swift action they undertook," Albanese said.</p>

<p>Under Australian law anyone found guilty of preparing for, or planning, a terrorist act can be sentenced to imprisonment for life.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-05/9qc1027k_anthony-albanese-_625x300_23_May_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["There is no place for extremism in Australia," Anthony Albanese said (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bad-debate-nights-happen-barack-obamas-feeble-support-for-ex-veep-and-president-joe-biden-5993980]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Bad Debate Nights Happen": Obama's Feeble Support For Ex-Veep Biden]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bad-debate-nights-happen-barack-obamas-feeble-support-for-ex-veep-and-president-joe-biden-5993980]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 29 Jun 2024 07:21:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A fired-up Joe Biden came out swinging Friday as he tried to make up for a disastrous debate performance against Donald Trump, insisting he was the right man to win November's US presidential election.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A fired-up Joe Biden came out swinging Friday as he tried to make up for a disastrous debate performance against Donald Trump, insisting he was the right man to win November's US presidential election.</p>

<p>Biden's appearance at a campaign rally in the battleground state of North Carolina came amid rumblings in his alarmed Democratic Party about replacing the 81-year-old as their nominee -- and shortly before the nation's most influential newspaper urged him to step aside.</p>

<p>"I don't walk as easy as I used to. I don't speak as smoothly as I used to. I don't debate as well as I used to," Biden admitted to supporters in unusually confessional remarks.</p>

<p>"But I know how to tell the truth. I know how to do this job," he said to huge cheers, vowing, "When you get knocked down, you get back up."</p>

<p>Biden's team was in damage-control mode after Thursday's debate when he often hesitated, tripped over words, and lost his train of thought -- exacerbating fears about his ability to serve another term.</p>

<p>He had hoped to allay qualms about his advanced age, and to expose Trump as a habitual liar.</p>

<p>But the president failed to counter his bombastic rival, who offered up a largely unchallenged reel of false or misleading statements about everything from the economy to immigration.</p>

<p>On Friday, Biden delivered the lines Democrats wished they had heard in the televised debate.</p>

<p>"Did you see Trump last night? My guess is he set -- and I mean this sincerely -- a new record for the most lies told in a single debate," Biden said.</p>

<p>"Donald Trump is a genuine threat to this nation. He's a threat to our freedom. He's a threat to our democracy. He's literally a threat for everything America stands for."</p>

<p>Trump also returned to the campaign trail Friday, speaking at a rally in Virginia and launching his familiar attacks on Biden in a rambling speech.</p>

<p>"It's not his age, it's his competence," Trump said.</p>

<p>"The question every voter should be asking themselves today is not whether Joe Biden can survive a 90-minute debate performance, but whether America can survive four more years of crooked Joe Biden."</p>

<p><strong>A New Democrat?</strong></p>

<p>Trump addressed the chances of Biden being replaced by another candidate, saying "I don't really believe that because he does better in polls than any of the (other) Democrats."</p>

<p>So far, no senior Democratic figure has publicly called on Biden to withdraw, with most toeing a party line about sticking with the existing ticket.</p>

<p>"I will never turn my back on President Biden," California Governor Gavin Newsom, who has figured prominently on lists of possible replacement candidates, said immediately after the debate.</p>

<p>Forcing a change in the ticket would be politically fraught, and Biden would have to decide himself to withdraw to make way for another nominee before the party convention next month.</p>

<p>Biden overwhelmingly won the primary votes, and the party's 3,900 delegates heading to the convention in Chicago are beholden to him.</p>

<p>If he exits, the delegates would have to find a replacement.</p>

<p>"Bad debate nights happen," Biden's former boss, Barack Obama, wrote on X.</p>

<p>But the election is "still a choice between someone who has fought for ordinary folks his entire life and someone who only cares about himself."</p>

<p>The show of Democratic loyalty and Biden's defiance in North Carolina were not enough for The New York Times, however.</p>

<p>The daily newspaper slammed Biden's campaign as a "reckless gamble" in the face of the threat posed by Trump, with its editorial board -- which is separate from the newsroom -- calling for the president to stand aside.</p>

<p>The "greatest public service Mr. Biden can now perform is to announce that he will not continue to run for re-election," it said.</p>

<p>A logical -- but not automatic -- candidate to take Biden's place would be his vice president, Kamala Harris, who loyally defended his debate performance.</p>

<p>As the Democrats scrambled, Trump allies sought to project calm assurance.</p>

<p>US House Speaker Mike Johnson, a senior Republican figure, said it was clear Biden was not "up to the job."</p>

<p>"Donald Trump is the only man on that stage that's qualified and capable of serving as the next president," he said. "The election cannot get here soon enough."</p>

<p>A second debate is scheduled for September 10.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-01/51cljedo_obama-biden-twitter_625x300_20_January_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Barack Obama came out in support for his former Veep Joe Biden after the first Presidential debate (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-pm-rishi-sunak-hurt-after-far-right-party-campaigners-racist-slurs-for-him-5993694]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK PM "Hurt" After Far-Right Party Campaigner's Racist Slurs For Him]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-pm-rishi-sunak-hurt-after-far-right-party-campaigners-racist-slurs-for-him-5993694]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 29 Jun 2024 05:49:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[British Prime Minister Rishi Sunak on Friday reacted to a racist slur targeted at him, saying it made him "hurt and angry".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;British Prime Minister Rishi Sunak on Friday reacted to a racist slur targeted at him, saying it made him "hurt and angry".</p>

<p>Speaking to reporters on the general election campaign trail, Sunak said his two daughters, Krishna and Anoushka, had to see and hear Reform UK activists who campaigned for party leader Nigel Farage "calling me a Paki".</p>

<p>"It hurts, and it makes me angry," the 44-year-old British Indian leader said, adding that Farage has questions to answer.</p>

<p>Sunak noted: "I don't repeat those words lightly. I do so deliberately because this is too important not to call out clearly for what it is.</p>

<p>"When you see Reform candidates and campaigners, seemingly using racist and misogynistic language and opinions seemingly without challenge, I think it tells you something about the culture within the Reform Party." He was speaking after a campaigner for the far-right Reform UK was filmed using the slur considered racist towards people of South Asian heritage, forcing the party's leader and general election candidate Nigel Farage to condemn the actions as "appalling".</p>

<p>Reform UK is fielding hundreds of candidates in the July 4 election on an anti-immigration stance with the hope of posing a major challenge for the incumbent Conservative Party, which is heavily trailing in the polls. However, with the election called earlier than expected, the party has been unable to fully vet all its campaigners and one of them – Andrew Parker – was filmed by an undercover reporter from Channel 4.</p>

<p>"The appalling sentiments expressed by some in these exchanges bear no relation to my own views, those of the vast majority of our supporters or Reform UK," Farage said in a statement.</p>

<p>The same activist was also heard suggesting army recruits with guns should be posted to "just shoot" illegal migrants landing on UK beaches. Speaking at a campaign event on Thursday, Farage said that "one or two people let us down and we let them go" but added that "in most cases they're just speaking like ordinary folk".</p>

<p>The 60-year-old divisive politician is making his eighth attempt to be elected to Parliament after seven failed bids. This time, polls suggest a comfortable lead for him in the race to represent the seaside town of Clacton-on-Sea.</p>

<p>While Reform is likely to win only a handful of seats, at most, in the 650-seat House of Commons, Farage says his goal is to get a foothold and lead the "real" Opposition to a Labour Party government – which is widely expected to succeed the Sunak-led Tories after the general election. The British Indian leader has, meanwhile, warned voters that a vote for Reform UK was effectively a vote in favour of a tax-raising Labour Party. He has also hit back at Farage's own controversial statements claiming that the West had provoked Russian President Vladimir Putin into attacking Ukraine.</p>

<p>"What he said was wrong, it was completely wrong. It plays into Putin's hand," Sunak told 'The Telegraph'.</p>

<p>"This is the guy [Putin] who used nerve agents on British streets, he's doing deals with North Korea. That is who we're talking about here. This kind of appeasement is very damaging not just for our security, but the security of our allies that depend on us and it emboldens Putin further," he said.</p>

<p>Senior Tories are worried that disaffected party supporters switching to Reform UK could cost them seats and hand Labour a "super-majority" in the election.</p>

<p>Sunak attempted to reach out to this disaffected set of voters in the last week before the election with a plea that a "Labour government isn't just something that you buy that if you decide you don't like you can take back to the shop and return it".</p>

<p>"It's going to have profound consequences for you and your family, potentially for decades if they change the system to stay in power that long. So you should think very carefully about the choice at this election because it has consequences," he said.</p>

<p>It comes as his party continues to battle the betting scandal engulfing the Tories, with his chief of staff said to be assisting with the Gambling Commission's ongoing inquiries into possible cheating behind some candidates betting on a July election date based on insider knowledge.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/2bca973o_rishi-sunak_625x300_27_May_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[It hurts, and it makes me angry," the 44-year-old British Indian leader Rishi Sunak said.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-supreme-court-rules-in-favor-of-january-6-rioters-5993659]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Supreme Court Rules In Favor Of January 6 Rioters]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-supreme-court-rules-in-favor-of-january-6-rioters-5993659]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 29 Jun 2024 05:36:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prosecutors overstepped in charging January 6 rioters with obstruction for trying to prevent certification of the 2020 presidential election, the US Supreme Court said Friday, throwing hundreds of cases into doubt.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prosecutors overstepped in charging January 6 rioters with obstruction for trying to prevent certification of the 2020 presidential election, the US Supreme Court said Friday, throwing hundreds of cases into doubt.</p>

<p>The matter was brought to the court through an appeal by former police officer Joseph Fischer, a supporter of former president Donald Trump who entered the Capitol in Washington with hundreds of others on January 6, 2021.</p>

<p>Writing the opinion for the majority, Chief Justice John Roberts said prosecutors' interpretation of the law would "criminalize a broad swath of prosaic conduct, exposing activists and lobbyist(s) to decades in prison."</p>

<p>The government "must establish that the defendant impaired the availability or integrity for use in an official proceeding of records, documents, objects, or other things used in an official proceeding, or attempted to do so," he wrote.</p>

<p>The case was decided 6-3, with Ketanji Brown Jackson joining with the court's conservatives. Amy Coney Barrett, appointed by Trump, penned the dissent, which was joined by liberal judges Sonia Sotomayor and Elena Kagan.</p>

<p>It now heads back to a lower court, which will decide whether Fischer's indictment can still stand in light of the narrower interpretation of "obstruction."</p>

<p>In all, 52 rioters have been convicted and sentenced only on obstruction charges, with 27 currently incarcerated, the Department of Justice said in a statement. Some 249 people were charged with obstruction in addition to another felony or misdemeanor.</p>

<p>"The vast majority of the more than 1,400 defendants charged for their illegal actions on January 6 will not be affected by this decision," said Attorney General Merrick Garland.</p>

<p><strong>- Meaning of 'otherwise' -</strong></p>

<p>At the core of the case was how to interpret the word "otherwise" in the relevant statute, the Sarbanes-Oxley Act, which was enacted after the destruction of documents in the 2001 Enron scandal.</p>

<p>This imposes up to 20 years in prison for whoever corruptly tampers with documents in an attempt to prevent them from being used in official proceedings, or "otherwise obstructs, influences, or impedes any official proceeding, or attempts to do so."</p>

<p>The word "otherwise" grants prosecutors excessive latitude, allowing them to pursue charges that far exceed the scope of Congress's initial purpose, the majority said.</p>

<p>"The peaceful transfer of power is a fundamental democratic norm, and those who attempted to disrupt it in this way inflicted a deep wound on this Nation," wrote Jackson, concurring with the court's conservatives. "But today's case is not about the immorality of those acts."</p>

<p>In her dissent, Barrett said the fact that the joint session by Congress on January 6 was an official proceeding was not in dispute.</p>

<p>"Given these premises, the case that Fischer can be tried for 'obstructing, influencing, or impeding an official proceeding' seems open and shut," she wrote, accusing the majority of performing "textual backflips to find some way -- any way" to narrow the reach of the relevant subsection.</p>

<p>This case also has potentially significant implications for Trump, who faces four felony charges brought by Special Counsel Jack Smith over his alleged efforts to overturn the results of the 2020 election.</p>

<p>The Republican presidential candidate is charged with conspiracy to defraud the United States, conspiracy to obstruct an official proceeding and obstruction of an official proceeding -- the session of Congress held to certify Biden's victory.</p>

<p>He is also charged with conspiracy to deny Americans the right to vote and to have their votes counted.</p>

<p>But this case is on hold until the Supreme Court rules on Trump's claims he is immune from criminal prosecution, which the judges are now expected to deliver on Monday.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-06/gqsn3b4_capitol-hill-reuters_625x300_08_June_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[At least 4 were died as supporters of Trump violently occupied the US Capitol on January 6, 2021.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/11-palestinians-killed-in-israeli-bombing-in-rafah-5993625]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[11 Palestinians Killed In Israeli Bombing In Rafah]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/11-palestinians-killed-in-israeli-bombing-in-rafah-5993625]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 29 Jun 2024 05:21:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[At least 11 Palestinians were killed by an Israeli attack on tents housing displaced individuals in western Rafah, Gaza's southernmost city, Palestinian security and medical sources said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At least 11 Palestinians were killed by an Israeli attack on tents housing displaced individuals in western Rafah, Gaza's southernmost city, Palestinian security and medical sources said.</p>

<p>The Israeli army fired artillery shells and bullets at the tents in the Al-Mawasi area, Xinhua news agency reported on Friday.</p>

<p>The shelling began on Thursday overnight following the advancement of Israeli tanks near the area, security sources told Xinhua.</p>

<p>The bombing operations led to a state of panic and fear among the displaced people, who left their tents and fled towards the areas in southwest of Khan Younis, according to local sources and eyewitnesses.</p>

<p>Medical sources told Xinhua that 11 Palestinians were killed and more than 40 others sustained varying injuries as a result of the bombing, all of whom were transferred to the hospital.</p>

<p>Al-Mawasi is an open sandy area on the seashore extending from the southwest of the city of Deir al-Balah in the centre of the Gaza Strip through western Khan Younis to the west of Rafah.</p>

<p>The area lacks infrastructure, sewage networks, electricity lines, communications networks, and the Internet, leading to difficult living conditions for the displaced individuals residing there.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/lm4cgl08_rafah-airstrike_625x300_27_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The shelling began on Thursday overnight following the advancement of Israeli tanks near the area.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-york-times-editorial-board-calls-on-biden-to-leave-presidential-race-5993541]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[New York Times Editorial Board Calls On Biden To Leave Presidential Race]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-york-times-editorial-board-calls-on-biden-to-leave-presidential-race-5993541]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 29 Jun 2024 04:57:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[America's most influential newspaper, The New York Times, called in an editorial Friday for President Joe Biden to step aside and allow another Democrat to challenge Donald Trump for the White House in November.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>America's most influential newspaper, The New York Times, called in an editorial Friday for President Joe Biden to step aside and allow another Democrat to challenge Donald Trump for the White House in November.</p>

<p>Describing Biden as "the shadow of a great public servant," the newspaper's editorial board -- which is separate from its newsroom -- said Thursday's debate between the president and Trump proved the 81-year-old "failed his own test."</p>

<p>His determination to run again is a "reckless gamble," it said, adding: "the greatest public service Mr. Biden can now perform is to announce that he will not continue to run for re-election."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/k726d10o_joe-biden_625x300_21_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The newspaper said that President Biden to step aside and allow another Democrat to challenge Trump.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/turkey-removed-from-money-laundering-grey-list-5993480]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Turkey Removed From Money Laundering Grey List]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/turkey-removed-from-money-laundering-grey-list-5993480]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 29 Jun 2024 04:35:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The global financial crime watchdog Financial Action Task Force (FATF) had removed Turkey from its "grey list" of countries that require special scrutiny, the country's Finance and Treasury Ministry said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;The global financial crime watchdog Financial Action Task Force (FATF) had removed Turkey from its "grey list" of countries that require special scrutiny, the country's Finance and Treasury Ministry said.</p>

<p>"As a result of the steps taken in the right direction, Turkey has been removed from the grey list," said the Ministry on Friday in a statement.</p>

<p>The result will further enhance confidence in the country's financial system and support Turkey's efforts to achieve the objectives of its economic program, it added as reported by Xinhua news agency.</p>

<p>In this regard, the administrative and technical capabilities of Financial Crimes Investigation Board and other relevant institutions will be further enhanced, and legal and administrative regulations will be promptly implemented as needed, the Ministry stressed.</p>

<p>"With this development, international investors' confidence in our country's financial system has become even stronger," Turkish Vice President Cevdet Yilmaz said on the social media platform X.</p>

<p>"The decision will have extremely positive consequences for both our financial sector and our real sector," he added.</p>

<p>Turkey was placed on the FATF grey list in 2021 due to concerns about money laundering and terrorist financing in the country</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/recep-tayyip-erdogan-afp_625x300_1529890404709.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Turkey was placed on the FATF grey list in 2021 due to concerns about terrorist financing in the country.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>