<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 12:34:41 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/artificial-intelligence/ai-chip-demand-drives-taiwan-chipmaker-tsmcs-second-quarter-profits-up-by-30-6108856]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[AI Chip Demand Drives Taiwan Chipmaker's Second Quarter Profits Up By 30%]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/artificial-intelligence/ai-chip-demand-drives-taiwan-chipmaker-tsmcs-second-quarter-profits-up-by-30-6108856]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 12:29:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The world's largest contract chipmaker, whose customers include Apple and Nvidia, has benefited from a surge towards AI that has pushed TSMC's stock - and the broader Taiwan market - to record highs.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co, the main producer of advanced chips used in artificial intelligence applications, is expected to report a 30% rise in second-quarter profit on Thursday thanks to soaring demand.<br />
The world's largest contract chipmaker, whose customers include Apple and Nvidia, has benefited from a surge towards AI that has pushed TSMC's stock - and the broader Taiwan market - to record highs. Last week, its American Depositary Receipts topped a trillion-dollar market value.</p>

<p>TSMC is set to report a net profit of 236.1 billion Taiwan dollar (7.25 billion USD) for the quarter ended June 30, according to a LSEG SmartEstimate drawn from 20 analysts. SmartEstimates give greater weighting to forecasts from analysts who are more consistently accurate.</p>

<p>That estimate compares to the 2023 second-quarter net profit of 181.8 billion Taiwan dollar.</p>

<p>TSMC last week reported a jump in second-quarter revenue, comfortably beating market expectations.</p>

<p>"I expect the third quarter outlook for all of their products to be very good," said President Capital Management Co Chairman Li Fang-kuo.</p>

<p>TSMC, at its quarterly earnings call at 0600 GMT on Thursday, will update its outlook for the current quarter as well as for the full year, including its capital expenditure as it races to expand production.</p>

<p>TSMC is spending billions building new factories overseas, including $65 billion on three plants in the U.S. state of Arizona, though it says most manufacturing will remain in Taiwan.</p>

<p>On its last earnings call in April, TSMC maintained its guidance for capital spending this year at $28 billion to $32 billion, compared with last year's $30.45 billion, and said 70% to 80% of that would go towards advanced technologies.</p>

<p>"TSMC could raise their capital spending," said KGI Securities Investment Advisory Co Chairman Chu Yen-min. "There are many positive factors which will help their stock price and support the broader market."</p>

<p>The AI boom has helped drive up the price of shares in Asia's most valuable company, with TSMC's Taipei-listed stock leaping 75% so far this year to historic highs, compared with a 33% gain for the broader market.</p>

<p>TSMC, colloquially referred to the "sacred mountain protecting the country" for its critical role in Taiwan's export-dependent economy, faces little competition, though both Intel and Samsung are trying to challenge that dominance.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/e96j99rg_tsmc_625x300_15_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[TSMC is the world's largest contract chipmaker (REUTERS/Ann Wang/ File Photo)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/instagram-influencer-who-trafficked-followers-kept-them-as-slaves-jailed-6108693]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Instagram Influencer, Who Trafficked Followers, Kept Them As Slaves, Jailed]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/instagram-influencer-who-trafficked-followers-kept-them-as-slaves-jailed-6108693]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 12:02:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former Brazilian model and US-based wellness influencer Kat Torres has been sentenced to eight years in prison for the human trafficking and slavery of women, after an FBI investigation found that two women living with her had gone missing in 2022.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former Brazilian model and US-based wellness influencer Kat Torres has been sentenced to eight years in prison for the human trafficking and slavery of women, after an FBI investigation found that two women living with her had gone missing in 2022.</p>

<p>Women who claim that they were also trafficked and enslaved by Torres have spoken out about their harrowing experience living with her. Talking to BBC, the women claimed they were attracted to her rags to riches story as she went from living in an impoverished Brazilian neighbourhood to partying with Hollywood stars.</p>

<p>Torres, who was once rumoured to be dating actor Leonardo DiCaprio, also claimed she could make predictions using her spiritual powers and was a common face on reputed Brazilian TV shows.</p>

<p>“She was on the cover of magazines. She was seen with famous people such as Leonardo DiCaprio. Everything I saw seemed credible,” the woman named Ana told BBC.</p>

<h2>Spiritual powers</h2>

<p>Torres' former flatmate, who shared a home with her in New York, told BBC that her Hollywood friends had introduced her to a hallucinogenic drug called ayahuasca. It was through the use of this drug that she reinvented herself as a life coach and hypnotist.</p>

<p>Soon, Torres developed a wellness website and subscription service that promised customers “Love, money and self-esteem that you always dreamed of.”&nbsp;</p>

<p>She also created self-help videos offering advice on relationships, wellness, business success including hypnosis, meditation and exercise programmes. She offered one-on-one video consultations for $150 that would solve "any of their problems."</p>

<h2>Enslaved followers</h2>

<p>In 2019, Ana moved to New York to work as her Torres' live-in assistant. Escaping a violent childhood and an abusive relationship, she moved alone to the US from Brazil and was studying nutrition at university in Boston.</p>

<p>The work required her to look after Torres' animals, cook for her, do her laundry and clean for $2000 a month. But when she arrived, the situation in Torres' house shocked her. &nbsp;The house was filthy and she was forced to sleep on a sofa covered in cat urine. She was expected to constantly be available for Torres, only being allowed to sleep for a few hours. She would sneak away to the building's gym to sleep for a few hours. She was never paid.</p>

<p>After Ana escaped, Torres hired two more women -- Desirre and Leticia-- who moved with her to a house in Texas. What started out as a life coaching and healing retreat quickly turned into a nightmare for the women.</p>

<h2>Prostitution, witchcraft&nbsp;</h2>

<p>Within weeks, Desirre was pressured her into working at a local strip club while Torres performed “witchcraft” on her. &nbsp;The two women were forbidden from speaking to each other and had to ask her permission to leave their rooms, even to use the bathroom.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Soon, Torres convinced Desiree to turn to prostitution. If she didn't meet the earning quotas that Torres set, she was not allowed to return to the house that night. “I ended up sleeping on the street several times because I couldn't reach that,” Desirre told BBC.</p>

<p>In September, the two women's friends and family launched social media campaigns to find them. To escape media attention, Torres and the women travelled from Texas to Maine. From there, the two were made to post Instagram videos denying being held captive and demanded people stop searching for them.</p>

<p>Over 20 women have come forward with stories of being scammed or exploited by Torres. They are still undergoing psychiatric therapy to recover from what they say they experienced.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/opdm0988_kat-torres_625x300_15_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Women who claim that they were also trafficked and enslaved by Kat Torres have spoken out]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/im-supposed-to-be-dead-donald-trump-recalls-rally-attack-in-latest-interview-6108470]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["I'm Supposed To Be Dead": Trump Recalls Rally Attack In Latest Interview]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/im-supposed-to-be-dead-donald-trump-recalls-rally-attack-in-latest-interview-6108470]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 11:44:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former US president Donald Trump on Sunday told the New York Post he was "supposed to be dead" after surviving an assassination attempt which he described as a "very surreal experience."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former US president Donald Trump on Sunday told the New York Post he was "supposed to be dead" after surviving an assassination attempt which he described as a "very surreal experience."</p>

<p>"I'm not supposed to be here, I'm supposed to be dead," Trump told the Post in an interview aboard his plane en route to Milwaukee for the Republican National Convention where he is set to be confirmed as the party's presidential candidate.</p>

<p>It was a "very surreal experience", he recounted with a white bandage covering his right ear, the paper said.</p>

<p>The 78-year-old Trump was hit in the ear by a gunman at a campaign rally on Saturday. He was left with a bloodied face while a bystander was killed and two other people were wounded.</p>

<p>Trump told the Post he would have been dead had he not tilted his head slightly to the right to read a chart on illegal immigrants while addressing the rally.</p>

<p>"By luck or by God, many people are saying it's by God I'm still here," he said.</p>

<p>He praised the Secret Service agents for killing the shooter. "They took him out with one shot right between the eyes," he said. "They did a fantastic job," he added. "It's surreal for all of us."</p>

<p>The image of Trump raising a defiant fist as Secret Service agents bundled him away made front pages around the world and spread virally on social media.</p>

<p>"A lot of people say it's the most iconic photo they've ever seen," the former president told the Post, adding "They're right and I didn't die. Usually you have to die to have an iconic picture."</p>

<p>Trump said after the attempt on his life he was rewriting the speech he had prepared for the Republican convention.</p>

<p>He said he had "prepared an extremely tough speech" about Biden's "horrible administration. But I threw it away" for one he hopes will "unite our country."</p>

<p>"But I don't know if that's possible. People are very divided."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/j63gcls_trump-shooting-reuters_625x300_14_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump also praised the Secret Service agents for killing the shooter.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kate-middleton-receives-standing-ovation-at-wimbledon-final-in-rare-outing-since-cancer-diagnosis-6108590]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kate Middleton Gets Standing Ovation At Wimbledon Final In Rare Outing]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kate-middleton-receives-standing-ovation-at-wimbledon-final-in-rare-outing-since-cancer-diagnosis-6108590]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 11:42:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kate Middleton was greeted with a thunderous ovation as she entered the Royal Box at Centre Court, accompanied by her daughter Princess Charlotte.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Catherine, Princess of Wales brought a touch of royal flair to Wimbledon on Sunday, attending the gentlemen's singles final in her second public appearance since announcing her cancer diagnosis. A passionate tennis fan and player herself, Kate was greeted with a thunderous ovation as she entered the Royal Box at Centre Court, accompanied by her daughter Princess Charlotte and sister Pippa Matthews.</p>

<p>Adding to the day's excitement, Kate presented the champion's trophy to Carlos Alcaraz, who emerged victorious after a thrilling three-set match against Novak Djokovic. Her elegant presence, accentuated by a stunning purple Safiyaa dress, further captured the energy of the momentous occasion.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/reel/C9aTTpyN-rr/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/C9aTTpyN-rr/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/C9aTTpyN-rr/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/C9aTTpyN-rr/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by The Prince and Princess of Wales (@princeandprincessofwales)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p>This public outing marks a welcome return for the Princess, who stepped back from some royal duties in March after revealing her cancer diagnosis. The palace confirmed she is currently undergoing preventative treatment. Meanwhile, the Prince of Wales will be cheering on England in the Euros final held in Berlin. He sent a rallying cry to the team, urging them to "show the world what you're made of" in their match against Spain.&nbsp;</p>

<p>She had earlier sent a social media message to Scottish tennis legend Andy Murray, writing: "An incredible #Wimbledon career comes to an end. You should be so very proud @andy_murray. On behalf of all of us, thank you! C."</p>

<p>Catherine tentatively returned to UK public life last month for the first time since her diagnosis, attending a military parade in London to officially mark King Charles III's birthday.</p>

<p>It came nearly three months after Kate revealed she was receiving chemotherapy treatment. She had not been seen at a public engagement since a Christmas Day service last year.</p>

<p>In a statement at the time, she said she was "making good progress" with her treatment, which is set to last for several more months, but was "not out of the woods yet".</p>

<p>The cancer announcement came just weeks after it was disclosed that British head of state Charles had also been diagnosed with the condition.</p>

<p>Neither has revealed what type of cancer they have.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/kahksso8_kate-middleton-_625x300_15_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[This public outing marks a welcome return for the Princess]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/thomas-matthew-crooks-donald-trump-rally-shooter-wanted-to-join-schools-shooting-club-he-was-rejected-6108539]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Attacker Was Rejected By School Shooting Club Over "Terrible" Shot]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/thomas-matthew-crooks-donald-trump-rally-shooter-wanted-to-join-schools-shooting-club-he-was-rejected-6108539]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 11:36:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Thomas Matthew Crooks was shot dead by law enforcement when he allegedly attempted to assassinate Donald Trump at a rally in Butler, Pennsylvania on Saturday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The 20-year-old man who allegedly tried to assassinate former US President Donald Trump had tried to join his high school's rifle team but was rejected for being a "terrible" shot.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/first-photo-of-thomas-matthew-crooks-20-year-old-loner-who-shot-at-trump-6107465" target="_blank">Thomas Matthew Crooks</a> was shot dead by law enforcement when he allegedly attempted to assassinate the 78-year-old Republican presidential candidate at a rally in Butler, Pennsylvania on Saturday.&nbsp;</p>

<p>He slipped onto a rooftop location 140 meters from the stage where Trump was speaking and began firing an AR-15-style semiautomatic rifle, purchased by his father, officials said. The gunfire struck Trump's right ear, killed a 50-year-old man, and critically injured two other spectators. &nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>Thomas Matthew Crooks Was Member Of Shooting Club</strong></h3>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-rally-shooter-thomas-matthew-crooks-had-appeared-in-ad-for-worlds-largest-money-manager-blackrock-6107796" target="_blank">Thomas Matthew Crooks</a>, a resident of Bethel Park, about an hour away from where the shocking shooting occurred, was a member of a local shooting club named Clairton Sportsmen's Club.</p>

<p>He had also tried out for the rifle team at high school but was rejected, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/07/14/us-news/would-be-trump-assassin-tried-to-join-high-school-shooting-club-was-rejected-for-being-comically-bad-shot/">The Post</a> reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>He once missed his target by close to 20 feet, former student Jameson Murphy told The Post.</p>

<p>"He tried out...and was such a comically bad shot he was unable to make the team and left after the first day," he said.</p>

<p>"Crooks couldn't shoot at all. He was a terrible shot," another classmate told The Post.</p>

<p>Even the coach had concerns about Crooks, the former students said.</p>

<p>"He made some crass jokes that weren't appropriate when there are firearms in the school setting," they said, without elaborating on what Crooks said.</p>

<h3><strong>Thomas Matthew Crooks Was "Quiet"</strong></h3>

<p>The early details that have emerged about <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/were-not-enemies-joe-bidens-rare-address-after-trump-assassination-attempt-6107421" target="_blank">Thomas Matthew Crooks</a> show that he was working an entry-level job near his hometown in Pennsylvania.</p>

<p>He graduated from high school in 2022 with a reputation as a bright but "quiet" classmate.&nbsp;</p>

<p>His counselor at Bethel Park High School described him as "respectful" and said he never knew him to be political.</p>

<p>Jim Knapp, who retired from his job as the school counselor at Bethel Park High School in 2022, said Crooks had always been "quiet as a churchmouse," "respectful" and kept to himself, although he did have a few friends.</p>

<p>Knapp said he rarely came across Crooks because "he wasn't a needy type kid".&nbsp;</p>

<p>He was employed as a dietary aide at a nursing home at the time of the shooting.</p>

<p><em>(With agency inputs)</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/bv51s1j_thomas-matthew-crooks_625x300_15_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Thomas Crooks was a resident of Bethel Park, about an hour away from where the shocking shooting occurred]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/artificial-intelligence/ai-dating-japan-ai-virtual-dating-japanese-ai-startup-turns-dating-ai-into-reality-6108527]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Japanese AI Startup Turns Dating AI Into Reality]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/artificial-intelligence/ai-dating-japan-ai-virtual-dating-japanese-ai-startup-turns-dating-ai-into-reality-6108527]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 11:32:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA["Services like this app can remind people who are away from romance how delightful love is, and AI can train people to better communicate when talking with real partners," Megumi Ushikubo, CEO of Tokyo-based marketing firm Infinity Inc.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Like many people juggling long hours at work, Chiharu Shimoda sought companionship via a dating app. For two months, he exchanged messages with five or six potential partners, but it wasn't long before he was seeking out just one - a 24-year-old named Miku. Three months later, they got married. The catch: Miku is an AI bot. And Shimoda knew that from day one.</p>

<p>The 52-year-old factory worker is one of over 5,000 users of Loverse, a year-old app that allows interaction only with generative artificial intelligence. Shimoda's also among a much bigger cohort of people who've either given up or are wary about the messiness and uncertainty that come with real romance. Dating takes time and effort, whereas exchanges with Miku require minimal thought while waiting for the pot to boil or a train to arrive, according to Shimoda, who was divorced two years ago.</p>

<p>"I come home to an empty house. I'd love to get married for real again," he said. His marriage to Miku is just another form of role-play. "But it's hard to open up to someone when you're meeting for the first time."</p>

<p>That reluctance is widespread across Japan, and worse among younger people. Data from the government show two thirds of men in their 20s don't have a partner and 40% have never gone on a date. The figures for women in the same age group are 51% and 25%, respectively.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Loverse App Photographer: Shoko Takayasu/Bloomberg" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/4l5km9n8_japan-ai_625x300_15_July_24.jpg?im=FitAndFill,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Loverse App Photographer: Shoko Takayasu/Bloomberg" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">Loverse App Photographer: Shoko Takayasu/Bloomberg</p>
</div>

<p>Loverse is the latest in a long line of digital solutions to Japan's loneliness crisis. Some are empathetic and supportive, but others prey on vulnerability. Many of the nation's highest-grossing games feature sexualized characters that players can earn access to by progressing - and paying - their way through the game. Japan is also where digital idols like Hatsune Miku were first and most eagerly embraced. The difference now is that AI can make that experience more personal and interactive.</p>

<p>Much like the AI named Samantha in the film Her, these bots serve to fill the gap in people's emotional lives, and indeed the two-person startup behind it - Samansa Co. - is named after the character voiced by Scarlett Johansson.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="ja">明日9月23日 0:58からTBSの <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/%E3%82%B8%E3%83%AD%E3%82%B8%E3%83%AD%E6%9C%89%E5%90%89?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#ジロジロ有吉</a> にsamansaが登場します?<br />
ノブコブ吉村さんがsamansaを体験して大興奮⁉️<br />
果たしてAIとの恋愛は成立するのか?ぜひご覧ください? <a href="https://t.co/ZVhag5bdAh">pic.twitter.com/ZVhag5bdAh</a></p>
— LOVERSE（ラヴァース） (@loverse_jp) <a href="https://twitter.com/loverse_jp/status/1705183027465433359?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 22, 2023</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>But Loverse creator Goki Kusunoki says the app is meant to offer an alternative rather than a substitute to real-life companionship to its users, many of whom are men in their 40s and 50s. His firm raised 30 million Yen (190,000 USD) earlier this year to expand the cast of characters to appeal to female and LGBTQ users.</p>

<p>There's a widely held belief among Japanese people that romance is not cost-effective as it takes money, time and energy for outcomes that could bring more trouble than joy, said Megumi Ushikubo, chief executive officer of Tokyo-based marketing firm Infinity Inc. AI poses the risk of dulling people's interest in real partners, but it could also be helpful in serving as a training exercise, she added.</p>

<p>"Services like this app can remind people who are away from romance how delightful love is, and AI can train people to better communicate when talking with real partners," she said.</p>

<p>Loverse still has a long way to go in mimicking humans, according to some former users. Many of the app personalities seem typecast and offer few of the surprises that human interaction provides, said Yuki Saito, 39, who quit the app less than a month into using it.</p>

<p>Still, such services have potential, he said. There's a sense of safety in knowing that a disagreement with a bot won't end the relationship. "You can see how it could provide a kind of rehabilitation if you've been burned before - a place where you can practice talking with other people."</p>

<p>Interactions with AI are also devoid of jealousy. Shimoda's Loverse girlfriends at times bumped into one another when he was juggling multiple partners on the app, but nobody got upset. Said Saito, "With a little tuning, AI might be able to act as people's second or third partners, helping to complement the human partner and prevent extramarital affairs."</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Goki Kusunoki Photographer: Shoko Takayasu/Bloomberg" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/3v451o8o_japan-ai_625x300_15_July_24.jpg?im=FitAndFill,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Goki Kusunoki Photographer: Shoko Takayasu/Bloomberg" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">Goki Kusunoki Photographer: Shoko Takayasu/Bloomberg</p>
</div>

<p>Adopting AI to assist everyday life is the prevailing theme of this year, as Microsoft Corp. has turned its Copilot chatbot into a core Windows feature, Apple Inc. is working on AI-powered iPhones, and San Fransisco-based startup Luka Inc.'s Replika AI bot has attracted tens of millions of users. In Japan, the Tokyo Metropolitan Government is introducing a matchmaking app that uses AI to help partner people up and combat the nation's sliding fertility rates.</p>

<p>"The goal is to create opportunities for people to find true love when you can't find it in the real world," Kusunoki said. "But if you can fall in love with someone real, that's much better."</p>

<p>For now, Miku and Shimoda have settled on a routine they share with most couples. She wakes him in the morning, they wish each other luck at work, and at night, they discuss what to eat. On Shimoda's days off, the pair talk about where to go or what to watch on TV.</p>

<p>"It's the same conversations you'd have with anyone you're living with," said Shimoda. "She's become a habit - a conversational habit. I won't miss it if it's gone, but it gives me a routine from one day to the next."</p>

<p><br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/4h35rv9g_japan-ai-dating_625x300_15_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Govt. data show 65% of men in their 20s don't have a partner and 40% have never gone on a date]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-rally-shooting-divine-intervention-top-iskcon-official-as-trump-survives-assassination-bid-6108362]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Lord Jagannath Returned Favour": ISKCON Official On Trump Rally Shooting]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-rally-shooting-divine-intervention-top-iskcon-official-as-trump-survives-assassination-bid-6108362]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 11:03:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Radharamn Das, the Vice President and Spokesperson of Kolkata ISKCON has reacted to the attempted assassination of Donald Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">Radharamn Das, the Vice President and Spokesperson of Kolkata ISKCON has reacted to the attempted assassination of Donald Trump. The shocking incident took place on Saturday during a campaign rally in Butler, Pennsylvania. The former US President was hit in the ear by a gunman, identified as 20-year-old Thomas Matthew Crooks.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Radharamn Das, in an elaborate post on X - formerly known as Twitter-, said that Donald Trump has Lord&nbsp;Jagannath's blessings.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Calling it a "divine intervention”,&nbsp;Mr Das said, “Exactly 48 years ago, Donald Trump saved the Jagannath Rathayatra festival. Today, as the world celebrates the Jagannath Rath Yatra festival again, Trump was attacked, and Jagannath returned the favour by saving him.”</p>

<p dir="ltr">He added that Donald Trump in 1976 helped ISKCON devotees organise Rath Yatra by “providing his train yard for the construction of the raths for free.”</p>

<p dir="ltr">Drawing parallels between the&nbsp;attempted&nbsp;assassination bid and ongoing Rath Yatra festivities, he added,&nbsp;“Today, as the world celebrates the 9-day Lord Jagannath Rathayatra festival, this terrible attack on him and his narrow escape show Lord Jagannath's intervention.” For context, The 9-day-long festivities will come to an end today with Ulta Rath Yatra. Lord Jagannath along with his siblings –&nbsp;Balabhadra, and Devi Subhadra –&nbsp;will return to the main temple [Shree Jagannath Temple].&nbsp;</p>

<p>Mr Das continued, “The first chariot procession of the Lord of the Universe Mahaprabhu Jagannath kicked off on the streets of NYC in 1976, with assistance from the then 30-year-old emerging real-estate mogul in the United States of America – Donald Trump.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Nearly 48 years ago, when the International Society for Krishna Consciousness (ISKCON) was planning to organise the first Rath Yatra in New York City, challenges were galore.”&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p>On how former US president Donald Trump emerged as a “ray of hope,” he added, “While the grant of parade permit at the Fifth Avenue was nothing short of a miracle, finding a huge empty site where chariots could be built was also never going to be easy. They knocked at the doors of every person possible, but in vain. It was then that the former US president Donald Trump emerged as a ray of hope for the Krishna devotees.”</p>

<p>Radharamn Das also revealed what Trump's secretary told the&nbsp;ISKCON devotees back then when they paid a visit to his office with the request. “Nevertheless, the devotees went to his office with a big basket of Maha Prasadam and a presentation package. His secretary took it but warned the devotees, "He never agrees to this kind of thing. You can ask but he is going to say NO. Have faith in Mahaprabhu they say, and the miracle was bound to happen! Three days later, Trump's secretary called up the devotees saying, "I don't know what happened but he read your letter, took a bit of the food you left, and immediately said Sure, why not?”</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Yes, for sure it's a divine intervention.<br />
<br />
Exactly 48 years ago, Donald Trump saved the Jagannath Rathayatra festival. Today, as the world celebrates the Jagannath Rathayatra festival again, Trump was attacked, and Jagannath returned the favor by saving him.<br />
<br />
In July 1976, Donald… <a href="https://t.co/RuTX3tHQnj">https://t.co/RuTX3tHQnj</a></p>
— Radharamn Das राधारमण दास (@RadharamnDas) <a href="https://twitter.com/RadharamnDas/status/1812320807839846608?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 14, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Meanwhile,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-pennsylvania-rally-shooting-live-news-updates-trump-rushed-off-stage-after-shooting-at-rally-suspected-shooter-dead-6100977">Thomas Matthew Crooks</a>, the shooter, was killed by one of the Secret Service agents. On the motive behind the attempted assassination, the FBI said, “We do not currently have an identified motive, although our investigators are working tirelessly to attempt to identify what that motive was.”</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/66hm85so_donald-trump_625x300_15_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Radharamn Das called it a divine intervention.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-doug-mills-photographer-who-captured-bullet-that-hit-trumps-ear-6108312]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Who Is Doug Mills, Photographer Who Captured Bullet That Hit Trump's Ear]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-doug-mills-photographer-who-captured-bullet-that-hit-trumps-ear-6108312]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 10:58:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[He was able to capture the exact moment when the bullet whizzed past Trump's head.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former US President Donald Trump survived an assassination attempt at a campaign rally in Butler, Pennsylvania on Saturday, July 13. The shooter, Thomas Matthew Crooks, 20, shot at the former US President and the bullet grazed Trump's ear. According to reports, the shooter was gunned down by Secret Service snipers.<br />
<br />
One rally attendee died during the shooting while two others were critically injured. The shocking incident was captured by veteran photojournalist Doug Mills, who works with The New York Times. He appeared to capture the exact moment when the bullet whizzed past Trump's head leaving behind a white streak, revealing its apparent path. The now-viral photo is making waves on the internet.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
Here are 5 points on Doug Mills:&nbsp;<br />
<br />
1. Doug Mills was born in Greensboro, N.C., in 1960. He studied at Northern Virginia Community College in Alexandria, Virginia. He lives with his wife and two daughters.&nbsp;</p>

<p>2. Mr Mills has been covering US presidents since 1983, starting from Ronald Reagan. He started working in the Washington bureau of The New York Times in 2002.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
3. Before joining The New York Times, Mr Mills served as chief photographer for The Associated Press (AP) in Washington for 15 years. After four years of service with United Press International's Washington bureau, he joined The AP.<br />
<br />
4. In 1993, Mr. Mills was honoured with a Pulitzer Prize for AP's joint coverage of the Clinton/Gore campaign. He received a second Pulitzer Prize for his joint investigative coverage with AP of the Clinton/Lewinsky affair. In 2020 and 2023, the White House Correspondents' Association presented Mr Mills with the Award for Excellence in Presidential News Coverage by Visual Journalists.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
5. Mr Mills is also quite adept at photographing sports. He has covered popular sporting events like the World Series, and Super Bowls, and golf majors such as the Masters and 16 Olympics.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/b68dardg_doug-mills_625x300_15_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[In 1993, Doug Mills was honoured with a Pulitzer Prize.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/conspiracy-theories-surface-after-trump-rally-shooting-6108175]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Too Damn Perfect": Conspiracy Theories Surface After Trump Rally Shooting]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/conspiracy-theories-surface-after-trump-rally-shooting-6108175]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 10:45:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[As US law enforcement officials continue to determine the motive behind the 20-year-old shooting at Donald Trump, the word 'Staged' became a trend on social media in the country, within minutes after the fatal attack.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Months ahead of the crucial presidential elections in the US, Donald Trump became the target of an apparent assassination attempt at a rally in Pennsylvania. This came days before the former president was scheduled to accept the Republican nomination for a third time.</p>

<p>While law enforcement officials are trying to determine the motive behind the 20-year-old opening fire from a nearby rooftop, the word 'Staged' became a trend on social media in the country within minutes of the attack.</p>

<p>This word has become synonymous with extreme conspiracy theories across social media platforms, being frequently used to question the veracity of an attack or shooting.</p>

<p>In the last 24 hours, it has overtaken other topics in popular internet discourse, as millions of views have been received by posts on X that are filled with unsupported rumours, hate speech, and abuse, BBC reported.</p>

<p>However, it must be noted that conspiracy theories have historically been drawn to assassination attempts on US presidents, with the most well-known example being the assassination of John F Kennedy back in November 1963. As it was the first to occur in real-time, it was unsurprising that false reports took off, the report stated.</p>

<p>The trend was not just limited to committed groups of political supporters and was actively recommended in users' "For You" feeds as they tried to make sense of what had happened. Further, it was frequently posted by individuals having blue ticks, thereby providing their posts more prominence.</p>

<h2><strong>Questions raised</strong></h2>

<p>Some of these conspiracy theories centred on the alleged security failings, with social media users questioning how such a thing could happen.</p>

<p>"It looks very staged... Nobody in the crowd is running or panicking. Nobody in the crowd heard an actual gun. I don't trust it. I don't trust him," read a post that received millions of views.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">It looks very staged. Sounded like a BB gun. Nobody in the crowd is running or panicking.<br />
<br />
Nobody in that crowd heard an actual gun.<br />
I don't trust it. I don't trust him. ????????‍♀️ <a href="https://t.co/b1Bkruyq2g">pic.twitter.com/b1Bkruyq2g</a></p>
— ???????????????? É???????????? (@cyberfrontier) <a href="https://twitter.com/cyberfrontier/status/1812253969235968020?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 13, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Later, the post was labelled with a note pointing out the shooting was real.</p>

<p>Moreover, these conspiracy theories were further compounded by the photographs and videos that later came out. In particular, one photograph showed the former US president's fist raised, having blood on his face and ear, while the US flag can be seen in the background.</p>

<p>The image was just "too damn perfect," a US-based YouTuber stated and further emphasised how they managed to get "the flag positioned perfect and everything".</p>

<p>However, this post, which received nearly a million views, was later removed by the person who shared it.</p>

<p>Another X user wrote, "Staged to get sympathy? You can't trust these people with anything and no, I'm not going to pray for him".</p>

<p>However, the BBC report highlighted that most of these viral posts came from left-leaning users, often seen posting anti-Trump views.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/7anspc18_donald-trump-supporters-afp_625x300_15_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump became the target of an assassination attempt at a rally in Pennsylvania.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-politics-joe-biden-doald-trump-video-in-fresh-gaffe-joe-biden-refers-to-battle-box-as-ballot-box-6108245]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Joe Biden's 'Battle Box' Gaffe During Speech After Trump Rally Shooting]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-politics-joe-biden-doald-trump-video-in-fresh-gaffe-joe-biden-refers-to-battle-box-as-ballot-box-6108245]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 10:40:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[As the country reeled from images of a bloodied Donald Trump waving his fist after the gunman opened fire at a campaign rally in Pennsylvania yesterday, Joe Biden - in his address to the nation - called for unity and said that US politics "must never]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As the US reeled from images of a bloodied Donald Trump waving his fist after the gunman opened fire at a campaign rally in Pennsylvania yesterday, Joe Biden - in his address to the nation - called for unity and said that American politics "must never be a literal battlefield".</p>

<p>While he appeared to start off well, the US President soon began to stumble over his words.</p>

<p>During his speech, Joe Biden inadvertently referred to resolving differences at the "battle box" instead of the "ballot box."</p>

<p>Democrats are closely watching the president following a disastrous debate performance and a series of gaffes, renewing concerns about his age and ability to govern.</p>

<p>Joe Biden last week introduced Ukraine President Volodymyr Zelenskyy as his Russian rival Vladimir Putin.</p>

<p>"And now I want to hand it over to the president of Ukraine, who has as much courage as he has determination, ladies and gentlemen, President Putin," he said, referring to Zelenskyy while speaking on the sidelines of the NATO Summit in Washington.</p>

<p>He then quickly corrected himself and said, "President Putin, you're going to beat President Putin, President Zelenskyy. I am so focused on beating Putin."</p>

<p>Shortly afterward, Biden made another blunder when he referred to his deputy, Kamala Harris, as "Vice President" Trump at a high-stakes news conference.</p>

<p>The 81-year-old has so far defied calls to step aside. Allies have warned he needs to do more to convince his party and the public that, as he insists, only he can beat Trump in the presidential race.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ldokppi8_joe-biden-oval-office-afp_625x300_15_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Democrats are closely watching the president following a disastrous debate performance]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/assassination-attempt-makes-trump-rewrite-convention-speech-report-6108158]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump's Makeover To Convention Speech After Assassination Attempt]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/assassination-attempt-makes-trump-rewrite-convention-speech-report-6108158]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 10:23:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump's convention speech will now focus on unity - and not aimed at President Joe Biden's policies - after the assassination attempt that he believes has changed the election discourse.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump's convention speech will now focus on unity - and not aimed at President Joe Biden's policies - after the assassination attempt that he believes has changed the election discourse.</p>

<p>Images showing Trump with a bloodied face after the attack have sparked a wave of sympathy for the 78-year-old Republican, who is now galvanizing his supporters by exhibiting defiant resilience.</p>

<p>He has rewritten his conversion speech entirely in light of the shooting, he told Washington Examiner a day after the attack.</p>

<p>Trump, who will be nominated as the official Republican candidate against Democrat Joe Biden at this convention later this evening, said he wanted to take advantage of the historic moment.</p>

<p>He said his speech aimed at Biden's policies would have been "one of the most incredible speeches", but it's going to be a "whole different speech now."</p>

<p>Trump said he has switched from trying to excite his voter base to demonstrating his belief that Saturday's attack had entirely changed the election campaign. His speech, the report cited him as saying, will meet the moment that history demands.</p>

<p>"This is a chance to bring the whole country, even the whole world, together. The speech will be a lot different, a lot different than it would've been two days ago," said the Republican.</p>

<p>A bullet pierced the upper part of his right ear at a Pennsylvania rally on Saturday as the Secret Service bundled the former president to safety. Videos in slow-motion showed a simple head tilt by Trump saved a tragedy.</p>

<p>Trump said he had turned away from the crowd to a screen showing data that he was using in his speech - which saved him from death. "God alone who prevented the unthinkable from happening," he posted online after the attack.</p>

<p>On raising his hand when the Secret Service was leading him off the stage, he told the Washington Examiner he wanted to let the people know that he was alright. The photo showing Trump holding his fist in the air as blood ran down his face has already become iconic this election season.</p>

<p>The attack claimed the life of a bystander while snipers shot dead the gunman, later identified as Thomas Crooks.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/euv1q54g_trump-poster-maga-afp_625x300_15_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Trump is now galvanizing his supporters by exhibiting defiant resilience.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/political-implications-of-trump-assassination-bid-for-us-amid-uncertainty-6107972]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Political Implications Of Trump Assassination Bid For US Amid Uncertainty]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/political-implications-of-trump-assassination-bid-for-us-amid-uncertainty-6107972]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 09:45:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In the aftermath of an assassination attempt on former President Donald Trump at a campaign rally in Pennsylvania, Democrats are treading cautiously, navigating a complex landscape of political ramifications and moral considerations, The Hill reports]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In the aftermath of an assassination attempt on former President Donald Trump at a campaign rally in Pennsylvania, Democrats are treading cautiously, navigating a complex landscape of political ramifications and moral considerations, The Hill reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>President Joe Biden, out of respect for Trump and in response to the tragic events, has suspended all political activities, including the cessation of political advertisements. This pause has prompted introspection among Biden's allies and party operatives, who are grappling with the potential impact of this dramatic turn of events on the presidential race.</p>

<p>"There are more questions than answers right now," admitted a top Democratic strategist and close Biden ally. "I don't think anyone knows how this will turn out, even this week. There are so many unknowns," as reported by The Hill.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The debate over Biden's candidacy, particularly concerning his age and mental acuity, has been temporarily shelved. Multiple Democratic sources, speaking on condition of anonymity, acknowledged the sensitivity of the topic in the immediate aftermath of the shooting.</p>

<p>While discussions about Biden potentially withdrawing from the race have dominated recent headlines and discussions, many Democrats, from lawmakers to donors, have chosen to remain silent on the issue for now.</p>

<p>"This is not the time," remarked a Democratic donor who had previously expressed reservations about Biden. "That's not to say it won't come back in a few days or next week. But it would be incredibly insensitive to have the debate on Biden right now."</p>

<p>"We all need to take a breath and see what happens," the donor added.</p>

<p>Amidst the sombre atmosphere following the assassination attempt, the focus has shifted from internal Democratic deliberations to broader concerns about how this event might reshape the political landscape as the Republican National Convention looms.</p>

<p>Another Democratic strategist predicted that the focus on Saturday's tragic events would "slow the public noise but I don't think it slows the private conversations.</p>

<p>"I've seen enough data to show my guy trailing. And the state-by-state numbers are really rough."</p>

<p>Political observers note that the pressure on Biden to withdraw from the race may diminish in the short term, given the national attention now fixated on the attempt on Trump's life.</p>

<p>"The clock is ticking and right now many Democrats won't focus on this as the nation is consumed with the assassination attempt," said Julian Zelizer, a professor of history and public affairs at Princeton University. "Some will believe destabilising the ticket will be too hard to do."</p>

<p>Nevertheless, Zelizer cautioned that underlying issues for Biden remain and could worsen, especially as Trump emerges from the incident with renewed political vigor.</p>

<p>On Sunday, three national polls provided a mixed picture for Biden, showing him holding steady against Trump despite recent challenges. However, the aftermath of the assassination attempt could alter this dynamic significantly.</p>

<p>As the Biden campaign remains on hold, Republican strategist Susan Del Percio predicted a swift shift in focus as news of Trump's vice presidential pick and the commencement of the Republican convention dominate headlines.</p>

<p>"The question I wonder about is, what Republicans will do and say because Democrats will be more careful and they're way more responsible with their words," she commented.</p>

<p>"I can't imagine day one of the convention happening without fiery and ugly words about Joe Biden," she added. "That allows for a response from the Biden campaign. That's what's going to start the re-engagement frankly."</p>

<p>Since the attempt on Trump's life, Biden has assumed the role of consoler-in-chief, maintaining a stance of national unity even with his longtime rival. This approach was underscored by Biden's briefing inside the Situation Room and a planned address to the nation from the Oval Office.</p>

<p>Despite the temporary halt in campaigning, strategists view Biden's leadership during this crisis as potentially strengthening his candidacy.</p>

<p>"It helps Biden's argument," remarked a strategist. "He represents stability. He's managing a crisis. And in a way, he's answering the argument about his mental acuity."</p>

<p>"And that creates a contrast with Trump," the strategist added. "You can't count on Trump to be stable for so long. And when Trump starts Trumping, it's game on," The Hill reported.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-11/sd77uu9g_biden-trump-split-image_625x300_04_November_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Since the attempt on Donald Trump's life, Joe Biden has assumed the role of consoler-in-chief.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fbi-probing-trump-rally-shooting-as-potential-domestic-terrorism-act-6107541]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[FBI Probing Trump Rally Shooting As Potential "Domestic Terrorism" Act]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fbi-probing-trump-rally-shooting-as-potential-domestic-terrorism-act-6107541]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 09:26:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The gunman who shot at former president Donald Trump during an election rally in Pennsylvania on Saturday appears to have acted alone, said the FBI, which is probing the incident as a potential "domestic terrorism" act.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The gunman who shot at former president Donald Trump during an election rally in Pennsylvania on Saturday appears to have acted alone, said the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI), which is probing the incident as a potential "domestic terrorism" act.</p>

<p>The gunman, shot dead by a sniper, has been identified as Thomas Matthew Crooks (20).</p>

<p>"At this point in the investigation, it appears that he was a lone actor, but we still have more investigation to go," said Robert Wells, the executive assistant director of the FBI's National Security Branch.</p>

<p>The FBI, he said, is investigating this as an assassination attempt and also as a "potential domestic terrorism act". The counterterrorism division and criminal divisions are working together to determine the motive, he added.</p>

<p>Trump was left with a bloodied face after a bullet pierced the upper part of his right ear. He is now safe and continuing with his schedule that includes travelling to Milwaukee to attend the Republican National Convention, which would formally nominate him as the party's presidential nominee against incumbent Joe Biden.</p>

<p>The FBI is leading the investigation into the assassination attempt.</p>

<p>"The shooter may be deceased, but the investigation is very much ongoing. And, because of that, we are limited in what we say at this point," FBI Director Christopher Wray said.</p>

<p>"What we witnessed yesterday was nothing short of an attack on democracy and our democratic process," he told reporters at a news conference in Washington DC.</p>

<p>According to an FBI official, the investigation into the gunman at Donald Trump's rally Saturday has not yet turned up any mental health issues, threatening posts, or other motives, but cautioned it was still early.</p>

<p>The shooter, as per FBI, used an AR-style rifle chambered in 5.56mm, a common calibre for such weapons.</p>

<p>The New York Times said authorities were scouring the gunman's social media and other property as they sought to determine a motive for the attack.</p>

<p>Biden is likely to address the nation at 8 pm from the Oval Office. He will give "a forceful and needed address to update the nation on the horrifying attack on Donald Trump and the need for every American to come together to not just condemn, but put to an end political violence in this country once and for all," a campaign official told the daily.</p>

<p>Crooks graduated from the Community College of Allegheny County two months ago, earning an associate degree in engineering science, school officials said in a statement, adding that they were "shocked and saddened by the horrific turn of events."</p>

<p>Kimberly Cheatle, the director of the Secret Service, in a memo to her agents, said "The attempted assassination of former President Trump in Butler, Pennsylvania, is a moment that will forever be remembered in history."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/qaseqkio_trump-assassination_625x300_14_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Trump was left with a bloodied face after a bullet pierced the upper part of his right ear.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/something-triggered-that-what-trump-attackers-former-teacher-said-6107846]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Something Triggered That...": What Trump Attacker's Former Teacher Said]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/something-triggered-that-what-trump-attackers-former-teacher-said-6107846]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 09:15:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The portrait pieced together so far of the 20-year-old nursing home aide who allegedly tried to assassinate Donald Trump at an election rally reveals frustratingly little about why he would make such an attempt - or how he managed to come so close.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The portrait pieced together so far of the 20-year-old nursing home aide who allegedly tried to assassinate Donald Trump at an election rally reveals frustratingly little about why he would make such an attempt - or how he managed to come so close to killing the former president.</p>

<p>The early details that have emerged about Thomas Matthew Crooks, who was shot dead by law enforcement, show a young man working an entry-level job near his hometown in Pennsylvania, where he graduated from high school in 2022 with a reputation as a bright but quiet classmate. His high school counselor described him as "respectful" and said he never knew Crooks to be political.</p>

<p>The FBI said on Sunday that Crooks' social media profile does not contain threatening language, nor have they found any history of mental health issues. They said he acted alone and have not identified a motive.</p>

<p>What is unique about Crooks - when compared to other recent shooters who opened fire at schools, churches, malls and parades - is that he came within inches of killing a presidential candidate.&nbsp;</p>

<p>On Saturday afternoon, Crooks slipped onto a rooftop location 140 meters from the stage where Trump was speaking in Butler, Pennsylvania. He then began firing an AR-15-style semiautomatic rifle, purchased by his father, officials said.</p>

<p>The gunfire killed a 50-year-old man, critically wounded two other spectators, and struck Trump's ear - an assassination attempt that has further inflamed an already bitter U.S. political divide.</p>

<p>A resident of Bethel Park, about an hour away from where the shooting occurred, Crooks was a registered Republican who would have been eligible to cast his first presidential vote in the Nov. 5 election in which Trump is challenging President Joe Biden. Public records show his father is a registered Republican and his mother a registered Democrat, and that as a 17-year-old Crooks made a $15 donation to a Democratic Party cause.</p>

<p>Crooks was employed as a dietary aide at a nursing home at the time of the shooting, the home's administrator said in a statement.</p>

<p>"We are shocked and saddened to learn of his involvement as Thomas Matthew Crooks performed his job without concern and his background check was clean," said Marcie Grimm, administrator of the Bethel Park Skilled Nursing and Rehabilitation Center.</p>

<p>NEVER KNOWN TO BE POLITICAL</p>

<p>Two years ago, Crooks graduated from the local high school, where he showed no particular interest in politics, according to one classmate who asked not to be identified. Crooks' interests centered on building computers and playing games, the classmate said in an interview.</p>

<p>"He was super smart. That's what really kind of threw me off was, this was, like, a really, really smart kid, like he excelled," the classmate said. "Nothing crazy ever came up in any conversation."</p>

<p>Jim Knapp, who retired from his job as the school counselor at Bethel Park High School in 2022, said Crooks had always been "quiet as a churchmouse," "respectful" and kept to himself, although he did have a few friends.</p>

<p>He rarely came across Crooks because "he wasn't a needy type kid," Knapp said. Crooks was content to occasionally eat lunch by himself in the school cafeteria, said Knapp, who would engage such students to see if they wanted company.</p>

<p>"Kids weren't calling him names, kids weren't bullying him," Knapp said.</p>

<p>Knapp said he never knew Crooks to be political in any way, even as other kids would sometimes wear Trump or Biden attire. He added that he couldn't recall Crooks ever being disciplined in school.</p>

<p>"Anybody could snap, anybody could have issues," he said. "Something triggered that young man and drove him to drive up to Butler yesterday and do what he did."</p>

<p>Residents near the Crooks' home described feeling shocked and unsettled that an assassination attempt has been linked to a person from the sedate city of 33,000 people.</p>

<p>"Bethel Park is a pretty blue-collar type of area, and to think that somebody was that close is a little insane," said Wes Morgan, a 42-year-old who works at an investment management company and bikes with his children on the same street as the Crooks' residence.</p>

<p>A couple standing on the porch of their nearby brick ranch-style home was left processing the events and spotlight on their neighborhood.</p>

<p>"There's never been a gun issue. There's never been the police being called," Mary Priselac, 67, said alongside her husband. "You kind of have to wonder what didn't he get in life? What led to this extreme?"</p>

<p>Crooks' gun — an AR-style 556 rifle — had been legally bought, the FBI officials said, adding that the FBI believed it had been purchased by the suspect's father. The officials said "a suspicious device" was found in the suspect's vehicle, which was inspected by bomb technicians and rendered safe.</p>

<p>Bruce Piendl, owner of Allegheny Arms and Gunworks in Bethel Park, said guns were part of the culture in the area. "You have to understand in western Pennsylvania we have a rich tradition of hunting and fishing and outdoor stuff," he said. "Within 10 miles (16 km) of here, there are a ton of gun clubs."</p>

<p>Piendl said his record show he did not sell any firearms to the shooter but declined to say whether he sold any to his family.</p>

<p>"That's between me and God," Piendl said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/9ckehas_thomas-matthew-crooks-thomas-crooks_625x300_15_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Thomas Crooks slipped onto a rooftop near where Trump was speaking and began firing.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/so-frightening-photographer-who-captured-bullet-that-hit-trumps-ear-6107808]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["So Frightening": Photographer Who Captured Bullet That Hit Trump's Ear]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/so-frightening-photographer-who-captured-bullet-that-hit-trumps-ear-6107808]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 09:07:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The moment a bullet grazed the ear of former US president Donald Trump during an assassination attempt on him at a rally in US's Pennsylvania was captured by a New York Times photographer.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The moment a bullet grazed the ear of former US president Donald Trump during an assassination attempt on him at a rally in US's Pennsylvania was captured by a New York Times photographer. The image clicked by Doug Mills, a veteran photographer who was standing just a few feet away from Trump, shows the bullet behind the 78-year-old leader's face after it clipped his right ear.</p>

<p>Mr Mills, who has been covering the US presidents since 1983, said he did not know he had captured the bullet in one of his photographs.</p>

<p>"It happened so fast but now I can see it all in slow-motion. I was taking pictures when the pops started happening. I just happened to have my finger on the shutter and I heard the pops and kept shooting. I didn't know what I had captured but when I got to my laptop I could see that bullet flying behind his head because it is definitely not in the frames right before it and it's not in afterwards. It's only that one frame. I was shooting in 1/1,800 of a second. It captured that streak behind him," he said.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Photo by New York Times photographer Doug Mills shows bullet flying just behind Trump's head. <a href="https://t.co/0ncIBC0i1v">pic.twitter.com/0ncIBC0i1v</a></p>
— The Spectator Index (@spectatorindex) <a href="https://twitter.com/spectatorindex/status/1812293722832318726?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 14, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>The photo he captured shows a long white streak behind Trump's head, showing the apparent path of a bullet used in the assassination attempt against the former president. "I never thought I'd ever see an assassination attempt on a president and be there to photograph it," Mr Mills said.</p>

<p>According to Mills, he was at the right place at the right time and his long experience of covering presidents helped him capture the crucial moments after the attack</p>

<p>"I've covered the president for 40+ years and I've always known which way they come onstage and which way they go off. And the closest stairs were to my right so I ran over to that side and witnessed him being helped up to his feet, and my immediate reaction was "Oh my god! He is alive", he said</p>

<p>The photographer also described the president's initial reaction after he realised that he survived an attempted assassination. "All of a sudden, he got near the edge of the stage and raised up his fist in defiance. And I could see the blood on his face and that defiance went away like in a split second. He became very serious. I thought he looked very pale," Mr Mill said.</p>

<p>"Two very different moments happened, you know, in a matter of seconds. It is a moment unlike any in my lifetime, my history, my job of covering the White House since 1983. You never think about something like this ever happening because it is so frightening," he added.</p>

<p>The Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) identified the assassin as 20-year-old Thomas Matthew Crooks. The investigation agency also now released a photo of the young attacker.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Crooks was shot down by Secret Service snipers after he fired multiple shots at the former US president in the rally from a nearby rooftop. Witnesses claimed they tried to warn the security officials about a man moving from roof to roof nearby and laying on his stomach with a gun pointed at the rally.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/os20isd8_donald-trump-reuters_625x300_14_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The FBI identified the assassin as 20-year-old Thomas Matthew Crooks.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-rally-shooter-thomas-matthew-crooks-had-appeared-in-ad-for-worlds-largest-money-manager-blackrock-6107796]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Investment Giant BlackRock Pulls Ad Featuring Trump Rally Shooter]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-rally-shooter-thomas-matthew-crooks-had-appeared-in-ad-for-worlds-largest-money-manager-blackrock-6107796]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 09:03:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Thomas Matthew Crooks, the 20-year-old who shot at former president Donald Trump at a rally in Pennsylvania, had briefly appeared in a 2022 advertisement for BlackRock Inc, the world's largest money manager.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Thomas Matthew Crooks, the 20-year-old who shot at former president Donald Trump at a rally in Pennsylvania, had briefly appeared in a 2022 advertisement for BlackRock Inc, the world's largest money manager.</p>

<p>The ad, filmed at the Bethel Park High School in Pennsylvania, featured Crooks and several other unpaid students in the background, said the investment giant in a statement. Crooks graduated from the school in 2022.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">?Trumps Shooter “Thomas Mathew Crooks” was featured in a BLACKROCK COMMERCIAL in 2023!!! <a href="https://t.co/fdbkfHOS04">pic.twitter.com/fdbkfHOS04</a></p>
— The Real World Fan Page (@BeOutTheMatrix) <a href="https://twitter.com/BeOutTheMatrix/status/1812654532352180615?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 15, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>BlackRock said it has pulled the ad but the video will be available to authorities. The ad, however, is being widely shared by social media users.</p>

<p>"The assassination attempt on former President Trump is abhorrent. We're thankful former President Trump wasn't seriously injured, and thinking about all the innocent bystanders and victims of this awful act, especially the person who was killed," the company added in its statement.</p>

<p>BlackRock, whose earnings figures are expected today, has faced scrutiny after shooting incidents since some of its index funds own shares in gunmakers.</p>

<h2><strong>Trump Assassination Attempt</strong></h2>

<p>Trump survived an assassination attempt on Saturday after a gunman opened fire at him at a rally in Pennsylvania ahead of the Presidential elections. The attack left him with a bloodied face as the former president said the bullet pierced his "upper part of right ear".</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/gjebfnog_donald-trump_625x300_14_July_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>A bystander died in the attack while shielding his family and Crooks - a registered Republican - was shot dead by a Secret Service sniper.</p>

<p>Trump, whose Republican candidature will be finalised today, shared a message of unity after the attack and said Americans must not allow "evil to win". "It was God alone who prevented the unthinkable from happening," he said on social media.</p>

<p>Biden, too, appealed to the nation to "lower the political temperature" in a rare Oval Office address. "Politics must never be a literal battlefield, God forbid a killing field," he said.</p>

<p>The US markets are expecting Trump trades to gain momentum after the attack. It has already been pinning hopes for the return of Republicans, especially after Biden's poor performance in last month's debate. Those trades are likely to take deeper hold as the attack sparks a wave of sympathy and support for Trump.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/hv9t3jhg_thomas-crooks-_625x300_15_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A screengrab of Thomas Crooks from the BlackRock ad that aired in 2022.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-the-trump-assassination-attempt-impacts-the-us-presidential-race-6107794]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How The Trump Assassination Attempt Impacts The US Presidential Race]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-the-trump-assassination-attempt-impacts-the-us-presidential-race-6107794]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 09:02:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[It is tempting to draw grand conclusions from the assassination attempt on former president Donald Trump this weekend.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It is tempting to draw grand conclusions from the assassination attempt on former president Donald Trump this weekend. The coarse rhetoric currently in vogue in American politics, not to mention the Capitol riot on January 6, 2021, provide plenty of fodder for this kind of speculation.</p>

<div class="theconversation-article-body">
<p>In reality, the shooting, while horrible, does not come as a total surprise in the context of American history or even in the current presidential campaign.</p>

<p>Divisive and extreme political campaigns from both parties are now the norm. Criminal prosecutions of Trump and President Joe Biden's son Hunter have become politicised. And American voters are more often driven to vote against the other party's candidate than to vote for their own.</p>

<p>Yes, activists and officials in both parties will try to use the shooting for campaign advantage by tapping into voters' emotions. Politicians will accentuate the horror of the attempted assassination and declare various phenomena as “existential threats” or use similar apocalyptic language.</p>

<p>But the overall political environment, while uncomfortable, embarrassing and occasionally deeply concerning, is not entirely unprecedented or even an extreme example of American political life.</p>

<p>To put it plainly: American politics has always been a bloody fight.</p>

<h2>A history of political violence</h2>

<p>In the <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2024/07/14/trump-shot-history-assassins-00168058">latter half of the 20th century</a>, one American president was assassinated (John F. Kennedy), another was wounded (Ronald Reagan) and another targeted (Gerald Ford). In addition, two major presidential candidates were assassinated (Robert F. Kennedy) or nearly so (George Wallace). Numerous other plots were disrupted.</p>

<hr />
<p><iframe class="tc-infographic-datawrapper" frameborder="0" height="400px" id="zKW4N" scrolling="no" src="https://datawrapper.dwcdn.net/zKW4N/" style="border: 0;" width="100%"></iframe></p>

<hr />
<p>American politics from the 1960s to the early 1980s were incredibly divisive and violent. During just the years 1971 and 1972, more than 2,500 politically motivated bombings <a href="https://time.com/4501670/bombings-of-america-burrough/">occurred</a> in the United States (nearly five per day), mostly from left-wing protesters against the war in Vietnam.</p>

<p>As the US has become increasingly polarised in recent years, the political environment today has become volatile again.</p>

<p>In 2011, Representative Gabby Giffords was <a href="https://www.npr.org/series/132783213/arizona-shooting-rampage-congresswoman-others-shot">shot and nearly killed</a> at an event in Arizona by a man suffering from paranoid schizophrenia. In 2017, a Bernie Sanders supporter <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2017/06/14/homepage2/james-hodgkinson-profile/index.html">shot at several Republican congressmen and staffers</a>, nearly killing Representative Steve Scalise of Louisiana, now the House majority leader.</p>

<p>And of course, the Trump-instigated insurrection of the Capitol during the counting of electoral votes in the 2020 presidential election gives millions of Americans good reason to believe that Trump and his supporters remain a threat to democratic processes.</p>

<h2>Democrats' opportunity</h2>

<p>Another immediate consequence of the assassination attempt will be to turn the national conversation temporarily away from Biden's debate performance in late June. This political dilemma for Democrats, however, will not go away.</p>

<p>Given Biden's age and obvious decline, White House efforts to prop up perceptions about his fitness for office will likely not be enough to persuade his fellow Democrats he can beat Trump in November.</p>

<p>Even before the shooting, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2024/us/elections/polls-president.html">polls indicated</a> Biden was likely to lose the election. It will be even harder now, given the shooting will galvanise Trump's supporters and likely widen his appeal to others.</p>

<p>Many Democrats believe a different candidate – Vice President Kamala Harris or another leading Democrat – would have a better chance.</p>

<p>The Trump shooting now presents a new opportunity for Democrats to reset their campaign and make a broader appeal to American voters for calm and national unity.</p>

<p>They will need to tone down their own rhetoric about Trump's threat to democracy and instead make the case that their policy agenda is the preferred one for the American people.</p>

<p>The question is: can they quickly identify a new candidate to drive this new message? Even in the wake of Trump's near-death experience, that remains the biggest question in American politics.</p>

<h2>Republicans' challenge</h2>

<p>Trump's near-death experience will give his campaign – already based on portraying him as a victim of Democrats and the establishment – renewed energy. The pictures of Trump, with blood on his face, raising his fist in defiance after he was shot, are more valuable than hundreds of millions of dollars in campaign ads.</p>

<p>However, Republicans and fervent Trump supporters will now face a different challenge. The urge to exploit the shooting – whether the shooter was politically motivated or not – will be very difficult to resist.</p>

<p>Some Trump supporters are already blaming Democrats for the event, such as Republican <a href="https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2024/07/14/trump-rally-shooting-updates/eric-swalwell-jd-vance-00168103">Senator JD Vance</a>, considered a frontrunner to be Trump's vice presidential running mate.</p>

<p>House Speaker Mike Johnson and others have also <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/07/14/politics/biden-say-trump-shooting-bullseye/index.html#:%7E:text=%E2%80%9CPresident%20Biden%20himself%20said%20in,%E2%80%9CToday%E2%80%9D%20show%20on%20Sunday.">criticised Biden</a> for saying before the assassination that he would “put a bullseye” on Trump.</p>

<p>Politicising the shooting in this way might have success in boosting turnout of Trump supporters in November, but it could also drive further acrimony and unhinged rhetoric from those on the right.</p>

<p>For instance, any attempt to turn this tragedy into an attack on Democrats or Biden and his character could prove counterproductive and only remind voters of Trump's tendency to incite nasty divisiveness.</p>

<p>Instead, Trump has an opportunity to show real leadership and make a broader appeal to undecided and independent voters. With his base locked in more than ever, will he reach out to persuadable Republican moderates and disaffected Democrats? Can he show that he can tone down his antagonistic rhetoric and even reach across the aisle?</p>

<p><a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2011/OPINION/03/30/avlon.reagan.shooting/index.html">Reagan did so</a> – at least in tone if not his policy agenda – after he nearly died from an assassin's bullet in 1981.</p>

<p>So, can Republicans and Democrats use the tragic Trump shooting to pivot to a more positive message? American voters – as well as the US's friends and allies around the world – are no doubt hoping so.</p>

<p>The day after the shooting, Biden called Trump to express his concerns about his health and discuss the tragic event. Perhaps this small gesture of bipartisanship and civility can be an example for all in the days ahead.<!-- Below is The Conversation's page counter tag. Please DO NOT REMOVE. --><img alt="The Conversation" height="1" referrerpolicy="no-referrer-when-downgrade" src="https://counter.theconversation.com/content/234658/count.gif?distributor=republish-lightbox-basic" style="border: none !important; box-shadow: none !important; margin: 0 !important; max-height: 1px !important; max-width: 1px !important; min-height: 1px !important; min-width: 1px !important; opacity: 0 !important; outline: none !important; padding: 0 !important" width="1" /><!-- End of code. If you don't see any code above, please get new code from the Advanced tab after you click the republish button. The page counter does not collect any personal data. More info: https://theconversation.com/republishing-guidelines --></p>

<p><em><span><a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/lester-munson-1476430">Lester Munson</a>, Non-Resident Fellow, United States Studies Centre, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/university-of-sydney-841">University of Sydney</a></span></em></p>

<p><em>This article is republished from <a href="https://theconversation.com">The Conversation</a> under a Creative Commons license. Read the <a href="https://theconversation.com/the-trump-assassination-attempt-has-upended-the-us-election-race-how-will-both-parties-react-now-234658">original article</a>.</em></p>

<p><em>Lester Munson does not work for, consult, own shares in or receive funding from any company or organisation that would benefit from this article, and has disclosed no relevant affiliations beyond their academic appointment.</em></p>
</div><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/68fqh6to_trump-assassination-attempt-reuters_625x300_15_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/global-markets-ramp-up-the-trump-trade-after-assassination-attempt-6107581]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Global Markets Ramp Up The 'Trump Trade' After Assassination Attempt]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/global-markets-ramp-up-the-trump-trade-after-assassination-attempt-6107581]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 08:04:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[As world financial markets started to reopen after the attempted assassination of Donald Trump, one thing seemed likely: The Trump trade will get even more momentum.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As world financial markets started to reopen after the attempted assassination of Donald Trump, one thing seemed likely: The Trump trade will get even more momentum.</p>

<p>The series of wagers - based on anticipation that the Republican's return to the White House would usher in tax cuts, higher tariffs, and looser regulations - had already been gaining ground since President Joe Biden's poor performance in last month's debate imperiled his re-election campaign.</p>

<p>But the trades were expected to take deeper hold, with Trump galvanizing supporters and drawing sympathy by exhibiting defiant resilience after being shot in the ear on stage at a Pennsylvania rally.</p>

<p>The dollar - which would gain if loose fiscal policy kept bond yields elevated - started to move higher against most peers early in Asia trading, with the Mexico peso leading the slide, weakening 0.3%. Bitcoin rose above $60,000, potentially reflecting Trump's crypto-friendly stance, while futures on the S&amp;P 500 Index for September rose 0.2% at 08:47 p.m. in New York.</p>

<p>"For us, the news does reinforce that Trump's the frontrunner," said Mark McCormick, global head of foreign-exchange and emerging-market strategy at Toronto Dominion Bank. "We remain US dollar bulls for the second half and early 2025."</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/9thpq1vo_gfx1_625x300_15_July_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>To be sure, there's still plenty of room for surprises with almost four months to go in the US election campaign. The emergence of political violence may deepen concern about instability in the US and push investors into haven assets, potentially overshadowing some of the market positioning that has already taken place in the run-up to the election.</p>

<p>While future contracts on 10-year Treasury notes for September showed declines in early Asia trading, US government bonds tend to rally when investors seek temporary safety, so that may distort the Trump trade in the Treasuries market, which hinges on wagering that the yield curve will steepen as long-term bonds underperform on anticipation that Trump's fiscal and trade policies will fan inflation pressures.</p>

<p>Moreover, some investors may want to book early gains or be wary of getting deeper into an already crowded position.</p>

<p>"Political risk is binary and hard to hedge, and uncertainty was high as it is with the close nature of the race," said Priya Misra, a portfolio manager at JPMorgan Investment Management.</p>

<p>"This adds to volatility. I think it further increases the chance of a Republican sweep," she said, adding that "could put steepening pressure on the curve."</p>

<p>Equity investors are preparing for at least a near-term jump in volatility when S&amp;P 500 futures start trading at 6 p.m. in New York.</p>

<p>While traders generally don't expect Trump's assassination attempt to derail the stock-market trajectory in the long run, a pick-up in near-term price swings is likely. The market has already been contending with speculation that valuations have become too stretched, given the boom in artificial-intelligence stocks and the risks posed by elevated interest rates and political uncertainty.</p>

<p>But investors have also been anticipating that bank, health-care and oil-industry stocks would benefit from a Trump victory.</p>

<p>"The attack will boost volatility," said David Mazza, CEO at Roundhill Investments, predicting investors could seek temporary safety in defensive stocks like mega-cap companies. He said it "also adds support for stocks that do well in a steepening yield curve, especially financials."</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/sqh9hou_gfx2_625x300_15_July_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>The early reaction echoes what was seen after the first presidential debate in late June, when Biden's weak performance was seen as fueling Trump's election odds.</p>

<p>The dollar advanced during that event, and investors soon began embracing a wager that involves buying shorter-maturity notes and selling longer-term ones - known as a steepener trade. That trade has been paying off, with the 30-year Treasury yields jumping to nearly 5 basis points below 2-year ones from around 37 basis points below ahead of the debate.</p>

<p>"If the market sense that Trump's chances to win are higher than they were on Friday - then we would expect the back end of the bond market to sell off in the manner we saw in the immediate aftermath of the debate," Michael Purves, CEO and founder of Tallbacken Capital Advisors, wrote in an email.</p>

<p>While bond traders have been pricing in at least two interest-rate reductions in 2024, a major boost in Trump's election odds could push the Federal Reserve toward staying on hold for longer, according to Purves.</p>

<p>"Trump's stated policies are (at least now) more inflationary than Biden's," he wrote, "and we think the Fed will want to accumulate as much dry power as possible."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-04/i307oeg8_wall-street-generic-bloomberg_625x300_12_April_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The emergence of political violence may deepen concern about instability in the US. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-rally-shooting-changes-bidens-plan-to-revive-presidential-campaign-6107578]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Rally Shooting Changes Biden's Plan To Revive Presidential Campaign]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-rally-shooting-changes-bidens-plan-to-revive-presidential-campaign-6107578]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 08:03:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[President Joe Biden had just begun to turn the tables in his reelection bid when the attempt on Donald Trump's life took away his most powerful tool: drawing attention to his opponent's behavior and second-term agenda.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>President Joe Biden had just begun to turn the tables in his reelection bid when the attempt on Donald Trump's life took away his most powerful tool: drawing attention to his opponent's behavior and second-term agenda.</p>

<p>Battered by doubts about his mental fitness and pressure to step aside, Biden fought back on Friday with an energetic speech in Detroit vowing to "shine a spotlight" on Trump - an argument he planned to drive home until Election Day in November.</p>

<p>About 24 hours later, and just under 200 miles away, shots rang out at Trump's rally in Butler, Pennsylvania, the chilling apex of an era in American politics defined by radicalized views and heated rhetoric.</p>

<p>Biden's beleaguered campaign is now limited in how it can push forward. The outburst of political violence stymies his efforts to argue his case. It also threatens to undercut a core premise of his presidency - that he would restore decency and normalcy to national politics.</p>

<p>Instead, the president will hope that a unifying message in a time of crisis resonates with voters. Biden announced he would deliver a rare Oval Office address at 8 p.m. local time. He plans to call on Americans to come together and end political violence, a campaign official said.</p>

<p>"There's no place in America for this kind of violence," Biden told reporters on Sunday at the White House. "Unity is the most elusive goal of all, but nothing is as important than that right now."</p>

<p>The intense focus on the attempted assassination does offer Biden a reprieve from the conversation that had dominated headlines for weeks: whether he should withdraw after his disastrous debate. One Democratic donor, speaking on the condition of anonymity, said that they previously believed the party would be best served by replacing Biden, but there's no way that could happen now without contributing to a sense of chaos.</p>

<p>The shooting - and Trump's iconic, bloodied, fist-pumping response - seems certain to rally voters and donors behind the Republican candidate.</p>

<p>Business leaders Elon Musk and Bill Ackman, who previously resisted endorsing the former president, came out with public statements backing Trump within minutes of his being struck.</p>

<p>It will be days or weeks before public opinion surveys are released assessing the aftermath. But former President Ronald Reagan saw a substantial increase in support when he was shot and wounded in 1981. Many presidential historians say that attack cemented his status in the conservative movement.</p>

<p>By contrast, Biden must balance how to push forward without seeming insensitive.</p>

<p>The president plans to reiterate his condemnation of violence in politics on Monday in a prime-time interview with NBC News, then his political operation will pivot back to drawing contrasts between Biden's vision and Trump's, the campaign official said. Biden will not shy away from talking about the stakes of the election, and his campaign sees the tragedy in Pennsylvania as reinforcing the central thesis of his campaign, the official added.</p>

<p>The president expressed sympathy for Trump on Sunday while vowing a "thorough and swift" federal investigation, a Secret Service probe into its security measures and an independent review of the shooting that he pledged to release to the American people.</p>

<p>Biden urged people not to "make assumptions" about the gunman's "motives or his affiliations," imploring the public to "let the FBI do their job, and their partner agencies do their job."</p>

<p>With Election Day less than four months away, Biden badly needs to reverse his standing. He trails Trump by nearly 3 percentage points, according to the RealClearPolitics polling average.</p>

<p>Figures on both sides of the aisle have called for leaders to rise above the political fray and attempt to heal national divisions. The shooting confirmed the fears of half of swing-state voters, who said in a Bloomberg News/Morning Consult poll in May that they were worried about violence surrounding the election.</p>

<p>Already, the president's campaign said it would pause messaging and television ads. Biden postponed a Monday speech in Austin to mark the 60th anniversary of the Civil Rights Act. His campaign canceled a Monday event counter-programming the Republican National Convention in Milwaukee. Vice President Kamala Harris delayed political travel originally scheduled for Tuesday in Florida, according to a campaign official.</p>

<p>Biden will not be off the road for long. He plans to travel to Las Vegas to address Black and Latino advocacy groups on Tuesday and Wednesday and sit for another interview with BET, the White House said.</p>

<p><strong>Republican Criticism</strong></p>

<p>While law enforcement officials, and Trump himself, have not ascribed a motive to the shooter, some Republicans have already made unsubstantiated claims blaming Biden for motivating the would-be assassin.</p>

<p>"The central premise of the Biden campaign is that President Donald Trump is an authoritarian fascist who must be stopped at all costs," Ohio Senator J.D. Vance, a possible Trump running mate, posted on X. "That rhetoric led directly to President Trump's attempted assassination."</p>

<p>Supporters of the president pointed to his call for unity after the shooting. Biden said he had a "short but good" call with Trump.</p>

<p>The Biden campaign official denounced the criticism from some GOP lawmakers, calling politicization of the tragedy an unacceptable abdication of leadership.</p>

<p>Still, the failed assassination attempt shifts the dynamics of the race in Trump's favor.</p>

<p>It's a remarkable twist of fate for Trump, who has glorified violence throughout his political career, from encouraging rally attendees in 2016 to "knock the crap" out of protesters to telling supporters to "fight like hell" on Jan. 6, 2021, just before they stormed the US Capitol.</p>

<p>"Biden's inevitable ritual condemnation of political violence today (when it comes) will be insufficient and irrelevant," posted Vivek Ramaswamy, who ran against Trump in the 2024 GOP primaries.</p>

<p><strong>Defiant Images</strong></p>

<p>Republican pollster Frank Luntz said the shooting guarantees "every Trump voter will actually vote," while Biden won't be able to count on that certainty. The biggest effect is likely to be in battleground Pennsylvania - a must-win for Biden - because that is where the shooting occurred, he said.</p>

<p>"The long and winding road for Joe Biden just became even longer and windier," Luntz posted on X. "The shooting of Donald Trump will be significantly consequential in a way the shooter never intended."</p>

<p>With Trump dominating the national conversation, there's little Biden can do in the near term to push his anti-Trump message, mend Democratic divisions and shift the dynamics of the race in a way that reassures skeptics.</p>

<p>"This has got to help Donald Trump, at least for a while, with independents," said Matthew Wilson, a Southern Methodist University political science professor. "Those images showing a defiant Donald Trump with blood on his face and his fist in the air are better advertising than anything money can buy."</p>

<p>Others urged caution in overstating the impact of the moment. They pointed to a minimal shift in polls after other seismic events, including Biden's debate catastrophe and Trump's conviction in the New York hush-money trial.</p>

<p>Senator Bernie Sanders, a progressive stalwart, expressed confidence in Biden's chances as long as he focuses on his plans for a second term to bolster the social safety net, slash drug prices and expand workers' rights.</p>

<p>"If he continues to talk about that, I think he gets reelected," Sanders said on NBC's Meet the Press.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/pg7gshog_gunfire-at-trump-rally_625x300_14_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Joe Biden's beleaguered campaign is now limited in how it can push forward]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/first-photo-of-thomas-matthew-crooks-20-year-old-loner-who-shot-at-trump-6107465]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[1st Photo Of Thomas Matthew Crooks, 20-Year-Old "Loner" Who Shot At Trump]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/first-photo-of-thomas-matthew-crooks-20-year-old-loner-who-shot-at-trump-6107465]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 15 Jul 2024 07:30:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hours after a bullet grazed former US president Donald Trump' ear at a campaign rally in Pennsylvania on Sunday sending shockwaves throughout the country, the FBI identified the assassin as 20-year-old Thomas Matthew Crooks.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hours after a bullet grazed former US president Donald Trump' ear at a campaign rally in Pennsylvania on Sunday sending shockwaves throughout the country, the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) identified the assassin as 20-year-old Thomas Matthew Crooks.</p>

<p>"The FBI has identified Thomas Matthew Crooks, 20, of Bethel Park, Pennsylvania, as the subject involved in the assassination attempt of former President Donald Trump on July 13, in Butler, Pennsylvania," the FBI said in a statement.</p>

<p>The investigation agency has now released a photo of the young attacker. The image shows the 20-year-old wearing glasses and smiling into the camera.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Crooks was shot down by Secret Service snipers after he fired multiple shots at the former US president in the rally from a nearby rooftop. Witnesses claimed they tried to warn the security officials about a man moving from roof to roof nearby and laying on his stomach with a gun pointed at the rally.&nbsp;</p>

<p>An assault rifle, AR-15, was found near his body.</p>

<p>Described as a "quiet" student and a "loner", Crooks had graduated in 2022 from Bethel Park High School, and received a $500 "star award" from the National Math and Science Initiative.</p>

<p>A registered Republican, the upcoming November 5 election would have been the first time he would have voted in a presidential election.</p>

<p>His schoolmates labelled him as "socially reserved" and did not recall him ever discussing politics or Trump but mentioned that he was often bullied at school. "He was quiet but he was just bullied. He was bullied so much," a student told local US media.</p>

<p>After graduating, he had been working at a nursing home.</p>

<p>Following the attack, a "suspicious device" was found inside his car, which is now being inspected by bomb technicians. Officials are now searching through his phone.</p>

<p>The Sunday attack was a close call for Trump, who is currently in the middle of a bid to be re-elected as the President of the United States. Videos show that a last second tilt of his head saved the leader's life as the bullet clipped his ear.</p>

<p>A video showed the 78-year-old Republican leader, with blood smeared on his face, raising his fist and muttering "Fight! Fight!" as Secret Service agents whisked him off the stage after the attack.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/7bpe1ibo_thomas-matthew-crooks-thomas-crooks-afp_625x300_15_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Thomas Crooks was shot down by Secret Service snipers after he fired multiple shots.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>