<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Sun, 25 Aug 2024 13:58:37 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/22-killed-as-bus-falls-into-valley-in-pakistan-6413847]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[22 Killed As Bus Falls Into Valley In Pakistan]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/22-killed-as-bus-falls-into-valley-in-pakistan-6413847]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 25 Aug 2024 13:22:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[At least 22 people were killed when the bus they were travelling in plunged into a ravine in Pakistan on Sunday, rescue officials said.The accident occurred near the town of Azad Pattan.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At least 22 people were killed when the bus they were travelling in plunged into a ravine in Pakistan on Sunday, rescue officials said.&nbsp;The accident occurred near the town of Azad Pattan.</p>

<p>"22 dead till now, including 15 men, six women and one child," said Farooq Ahmed, a spokesperson for Rescue 1122 emergency services in Punjab.</p>

<p>Muhammad Usman Gujjar, another spokesperson for the rescue service, told AFP that "initial information suggests that a vehicle fell into a ravine".&nbsp;</p>

<p>Road accidents with high fatalities are common in Pakistan, where safety measures are lax, driver training is poor and transport infrastructure often decrepit.</p>

<p>On Saturday, the bodies of 28 pilgrims who died in a bus crash in Iran were returned to Pakistan.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The bus was carrying 51 Pakistani pilgrims to Iraq for the Arbaeen commemoration, one of the biggest events of the Shiite calendar, when it overturned and caught fire in front of a checkpoint in Yazd province on Tuesday night, Iranian state TV reported.</p>

<p>The head of Iran's traffic police, Teymour Hosseini, cited a brake failure and the steep road as the reasons for the crash.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-02/gep9jf6g_pakistan-police-_625x300_06_February_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Representational Image]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladeshs-ex-textile-and-jute-minister-golam-dastagir-gazi-arrested-6413594]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ex Bangladesh Minister Arrested Amid Crackdown On Awami League Leaders]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladeshs-ex-textile-and-jute-minister-golam-dastagir-gazi-arrested-6413594]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 25 Aug 2024 12:39:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Bangladesh's former textile and jute minister Golam Dastagir Gazi has been arrested as the police take stern measures against officials and ministers of the ousted prime minister Sheikh Hasina's Awami League government, according to media reports.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bangladesh's former textile and jute minister Golam Dastagir Gazi has been arrested as the police take stern measures against officials and ministers of the ousted prime minister Sheikh Hasina's Awami League government, according to media reports on Sunday.</p>

<p>The 76-year-old leader was detained late Saturday night from a house in the Piergoli area of the capital Dhaka around 3 am, The Daily Star newspaper quoted Paltan police station officer-in-charge Mollah Mohammad Khalid Hussain as saying.</p>

<p>The Dhaka Metropolitan Police detained him and brought him to the Detective Branch (DB) office, according to The Dhaka Tribune.</p>

<p>Gazi was kept at the DB office as the police station is badly damaged following recent violence, Hussain said, adding that a group of people besieged the house after knowing his location there.</p>

<p>However, the police officer did not provide any details regarding the case for which he was arrested.</p>

<p>Earlier, a case of murder was filed against 105 individuals, including Hasina and Gazi, at Rupganj police station in Narayanganj.</p>

<p>Gazi was elected MP from Rupganj-1 constituency in Narayanganj in the 12th parliamentary elections held in January with Awami League's boat symbol.</p>

<p>On Saturday, a Dhaka court placed Salman F Rahman, private industry affairs adviser to Hasina, former law minister Anisul Huq, former social welfare minister Dipu Moni and two others on different terms of remand for interrogation in four murder cases.</p>

<p>Apart from the three, former chief whip ASM Feroz and former army officer Major General Ziaul Ahsan were also placed on remand in murder cases.</p>

<p>Cases have been filed against many officials or ministers of the ousted Hasina-led government after she resigned and fled to India on August 5 following massive protests against the quota reform system in Bangladesh.</p>

<p>Most leaders of the Awami League have gone into hiding since Hasina's resignation.</p>

<p>Many Hasina-led Awami League party members are in jail after the new interim government led by Nobel Laureate Muhammad Yunus took charge on August 8 following the fall of the previous government.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/qfne501_golam-dastagir-gazi-bangladesh-minister_625x300_25_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The police did not provide any details regarding the case for which Golam Dastagir Gazi was arrested.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/i-made-a-big-mistake-former-alaska-airlines-pilot-who-tried-to-shut-down-planes-engines-6413466]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Made A Big Mistake": Former US Pilot Who Tried To Shut Off Plane's Engines]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/i-made-a-big-mistake-former-alaska-airlines-pilot-who-tried-to-shut-down-planes-engines-6413466]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 25 Aug 2024 12:11:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[He attributed his actions to a mental breakdown, stating that he had been struggling with depression and had ingested psychedelic mushrooms 48 hours before the incident.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a recent interview with <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://abcnews.go.com/US/former-alaska-airlines-pilot-shut-engines-flight-shares/story?id=113066835">ABC's "Good Morning America," </a>Joseph Emerson, a 44-year-old off-duty Alaska Airlines pilot, broke his silence about the shocking incident that occurred on October 22, 2023. Mr Emerson, who was seated in the cockpit's jump seat, allegedly attempted to shut down the plane's engines by activating the fire suppression system while the aircraft was airborne. He attributed his actions to a mental breakdown, stating that he had been struggling with depression and had ingested psychedelic mushrooms 48 hours before the incident.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In the latest interview, Mr Emerson opened up about the emotional triggers that led him to consume the psychedelic mushrooms, revealing that he had spent the previous weekend reminiscing about his best friend, Scott, who died a few years back. He began to lose touch with reality and began thinking he was "trapped" on an "imaginary" plane.</p>

<p id="mntl-sc-block_11-0">''What I thought was, 'This is going to wake me up. I know what those levers do in a real airplane and I need to wake up from this. You know, it's 30 seconds of my life that I wish I could change, and I can't,'' Mr Emerson said, per <em>ABC.</em></p>

<p>"There was a feeling of being trapped, like, 'Am I trapped in this aeroplane and now I'll never go home?'' he added.</p>

<p>When the plane landed, Emerson was taken into custody by Port of Portland police and charged with 83 counts of attempted murder.&nbsp;Moments after he was removed from that cockpit, he sent his wife Sarah a text message.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"I made a big mistake," the message read.</p>

<p>He spent the next 45 days in jail before he was granted bond. The murder charges against him now have been dropped, but the former pilot still faces over 80 state and federal charges.&nbsp;He was released from custody in December and is awaiting trial.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"At the end of the day, I accept responsibility for the choices that I made. They're my choices. What I hope through the judicial processes is that the entirety of not just 30 seconds of the event, but the entirety of my experience is accounted for as society judges me on what happened. And I will accept what the debt that society says I owe,'' Mr Emerson said.</p>

<p>The former pilot has now started a&nbsp;nonprofit organization called <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.clearskiesaheadnonprofit.org/">Clear Skies Ahead</a>, which aims to provide vital support to pilots struggling with mental health issues, such as depression, anxiety, and substance abuse.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-10/id6mgn88_alaska-airline-pilot-joseph-emerson-1200_625x300_24_October_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[He was released from custody in December and is awaiting trial.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-years-on-us-still-hunts-attackers-who-killed-americans-during-afghanistan-exit-6413253]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[3 Years On, US Still Hunts Attackers Who Killed Americans During Afghan Exit]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-years-on-us-still-hunts-attackers-who-killed-americans-during-afghanistan-exit-6413253]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 25 Aug 2024 11:27:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Three years after the suicide bomber attack at Afghanistan's Abbey Gate that killed 13 US service personnel and about 170 Afghan civilians, the network behind the perpetrator is "pretty degraded" but not eliminated, the Pentagon said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Three years after the suicide bomber attack at Afghanistan's Abbey Gate that killed 13 US service personnel and about 170 Afghan civilians, the network behind the perpetrator is "pretty degraded" but not eliminated, the Pentagon's civilian commando chief said.</p>

<p>"A lot of allied and partner disruptions" of the ISIS-K network have reduced its "capability to conduct such an attack," Christopher Maier, assistant secretary for special operations and low-intensity conflict, said in a brief interview after a breakfast meeting with reporters Friday.</p>

<p>President Joe Biden promised on the day of the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/video/satellite-image-offers-rare-insight-into-kabul-airport-blast-targets-599477">attack outside Hamid Karzai International Airport</a> that "we will not forgive, we will not forget, we will hunt you down and make you pay." Maier said "we are in the process of doing that," and "we have made significant dents in this network that conducted the Abbey Gate attack."</p>

<p>The attack three years ago next Monday marked a devastating low point in an operation that critics have lambasted as chaotic even as 124,000 Afghans were evacuated amid the US exit from Afghanistan and the Taliban takeover of the country.</p>

<p>Republicans have seized on the attack to blast Biden's foreign policy. During his acceptance speech at the Republican National Convention in July, former President Donald Trump said US standing in the world "began to unravel with the disastrous withdrawal from Afghanistan, the worst humiliation in the history of our country."&nbsp;</p>

<p>Trump forged a February 2020 deal with the Taliban, but not the Afghan government, that set an initial timetable for US troop withdrawals from Afghanistan, which Biden modified. Trump and the Republican Party blame Biden - and now Vice President Kamala Harris, the Democratic nominee to succeed him - for how the withdrawal was carried out.&nbsp;</p>

<p>During the breakfast with reporters, Maier said "we continue to assess that Abbey Gate" was the work of "more than one individual" who benefited from the ISIS-K infrastructure. Since then, he said, the US and partners "have had clear cases where we've been able to disrupt the network that was associated with Abbey Gate."&nbsp;</p>

<p>"One of the things we have been able to benefit from is Central Asian countries more attuned from the threat from Afghanistan," he said. "Some of the recent plots that have been foiled point to direct support from some of these partners," he said, without naming the countries involved.</p>

<p>The House Foreign Affairs Committee plans to release its review of the withdrawal from Afghanistan early next month.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-08/5r0ugnto_kabul-rocket-attack_625x300_30_August_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/vladimir-putin-played-with-donald-trumps-ego-insecurities-says-his-former-aid-hr-mcmaster-6413102]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Putin "Played" With Trump's "Ego, Insecurities", Says His Former Aid]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/vladimir-putin-played-with-donald-trumps-ego-insecurities-says-his-former-aid-hr-mcmaster-6413102]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 25 Aug 2024 10:55:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The new behind-the-scenes details from HR McMaster, Donald Trump's second national security adviser, come as Americans are set to decide whether the former president should return to the White House.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump was determined during his presidency to cozy up to Vladimir Putin despite Russia's interference in US democracy and objections by advisers, a former top aide claims in a new book, according to an excerpt published Saturday.</p>

<p>The new behind-the-scenes details from HR McMaster, Trump's second national security adviser, come as Americans are set to decide whether the former president should return to the White House and as US officials warn of fresh foreign election meddling.</p>

<p>"After over a year in this job, I cannot understand Putin's hold on Trump," McMaster, in an excerpt from his memoir published in the Wall Street Journal, says he told his wife in March 2018.</p>

<p>A former lieutenant-general, McMaster became Trump's national security adviser in February 2017, and says that from the beginning, discussions of Vladimir Putin and Russia "were difficult to have with the president."</p>

<p>He says Trump connected "all topics involving Russia" to the federal investigation into Moscow's interference in the 2016 election and possible ties with Trump's campaign, a probe which would dog his entire presidency.</p>

<p>US officials have warned this year of new efforts by foreign powers, including Russia and Iran, to meddle in the November election, in which Trump is facing Vice President Kamala Harris.</p>

<p>McMaster says an "overconfident" president Trump sought early in his administration to improve relations with Russia by building a personal rapport with Putin.</p>

<p>But the Russian president, "a ruthless former KGB operator, played to Trump's ego and insecurities with flattery," McMaster says.</p>

<p>"Trump had revealed his vulnerability to this approach, his affinity for strongmen and his belief that he alone could forge a good relationship with Putin," he added.</p>

<p>McMaster detailed several instances of friction with Trump over his approach toward Putin, with the disagreements ultimately leading to his dismissal.</p>

<p>Following Putin's election to a fourth term in March 2018, McMaster says Trump wanted to congratulate him by phone, but that he explained to the president that the vote had been rigged.</p>

<p>A call was scheduled nonetheless.</p>

<p>Before Trump called Putin, McMaster says he warned him about the conversation potentially being spun by the Kremlin as tacit support of the election process and to boost Russia's image, in tatters at the time over an assassination attempt on UK soil.</p>

<p>He said he asked Trump: "As Russia tries to delegitimize our legitimate elections, why would you help him legitimize his illegitimate election?"</p>

<p>Trump nonetheless called Putin and congratulated him, and then requested the Russian president be invited to the White House.</p>

<p>Trump's aversion to McMaster, he said, "was because I was the principal voice telling him that Putin was using him and other politicians in both parties in an effort to shake Americans' confidence in our democratic principles, institutions and processes."</p>

<p>McMaster was replaced just days later by John Bolton, who was also fired about a year-and-a-half later.</p>

<p>While Trump had four national security advisers during his term, President Joe Biden has had one since taking office in 2021.</p>

<p>"With Donald Trump, most everybody gets used up, and my time had come," McMaster wrote.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/3k00lti_donald-trump-vladimir-putin_625x300_25_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[File photo]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-was-fuad-shukr-hezbollah-commander-whose-death-sparked-todays-confict-6413101]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Who Was Fuad Shukr, Hezbollah Commander Whose Death Sparked Today's Conflict]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-was-fuad-shukr-hezbollah-commander-whose-death-sparked-todays-confict-6413101]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 25 Aug 2024 10:54:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Lebanon- based militant group Hezbollah fired a large number of missiles at Israel on Sunday, retaliating for the assassination of their senior commander Fuad Shukr in Beirut last month.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lebanon- based militant group Hezbollah fired a large number of missiles at Israel on Sunday, retaliating for the assassination of their senior commander Fuad Shukr in Beirut last month.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Hezbollah and Israel have been exchanging fire since October 7, while avoiding a major escalation. While both sides had avoided a major escalation, tensions rose significantly after a missile strike in the Israeli-occupied Golan Heights killed 12 people. While Hezbollah denied involvement in that attack, Israel responded with targeted airstrikes, assassinating Fuad Shukr and Hamas leader Ismail Haniyeh.&nbsp;</p>

<p>On Sunday, the Iranian-backed movement said the attack was a response to Israel's actions and announced that they had completed the "first phase" of its retaliation against the Jewish State, reported Reuters.</p>

<p><strong>Who was Hezbollah commander Fuad Shukr?</strong></p>

<p>Fuad Shukr, also known by the alias "Al-Hajj Mohsin", was a senior commander in Hezbollah, a militant group based in Lebanon, widely regarded as a terrorist organisation by several countries, including the United States and Israel. Shukr was among the founding members of Hezbollah during the Israeli invasion of Lebanon in 1982. He was part of the generation of Lebanese Shi'ites who aligned with Iran's Revolutionary Guards to establish the group.&nbsp;</p>

<p>He was a close associate of Imad Mughniyeh, Hezbollah's former military commander who was assassinated in Damascus in 2008. Shukr's prominence in the group grew after Mughniyeh's death.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The US accused Shukr of playing a central role in the 1983 bombing of the US Marine barracks in Beirut, which killed 241 US military personnel. This attack is one of the deadliest against American forces in the Middle East. The US government had placed a bounty of up to $5 million on Shukr's head through its Rewards for Justice program.</p>

<p>Fuad Shukr served as a senior military commander in Hezbollah's forces in southern Lebanon and was a member of the group's highest military body, the Jihad Council. He played a key role in Hezbollah's military operations in Syria, particularly in supporting President Bashar al-Assad during the Syrian civil war. Hezbollah's involvement in Syria was crucial to Assad's survival during the conflict's early years.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Fuad Shukr was also a special adviser to Hezbollah's leader, Sayyed Hassan Nasrallah, and was a member of the Shura Council, a key decision-making body within the organisation.</p>

<p>On July 30, <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-hezbollah-commander-fuad-shukr-targeted-by-israel-in-beirut-6226900">Fuad Shukr was targeted</a> by an Israeli airstrike in Beirut. Following the airstrike, Lebanese security sources reported that Shukr was critically injured. His death was later confirmed by Israeli broadcast reports.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/vaq4qse8_fuad-shukr-afp_625x300_25_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/humanity-is-killing-the-great-barrier-reef-warns-report-6413023]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Humanity Is Killing The Great Barrier Reef, Warns Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/humanity-is-killing-the-great-barrier-reef-warns-report-6413023]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 25 Aug 2024 10:36:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Great Barrier Reef will continue to deteriorate, largely due to climate change, and the window to secure its future is rapidly closing. That is the sobering conclusion of a major new report into the state of the reef.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="theconversation-article-title">The Great Barrier Reef will continue to deteriorate, largely to climate change, and the window to secure its future is rapidly closing. That is the sobering conclusion of a major new report into the state of the reef.</p>

<div class="theconversation-article-body">
<p>The <a href="https://www2.gbrmpa.gov.au/our-work/outlook-report-2024">report was released</a> by the Great Barrier Reef Marine Park Authority. It confirms what scientists have long known: humanity is killing the Great Barrier Reef, and other reefs around the world, by failing to curb the greenhouse gas emissions that cause global warming.</p>

<p>Earlier this year, I visited parts of the southern Great Barrier Reef where mass coral bleaching and death <a href="https://theconversation.com/new-drone-imagery-reveals-97-of-coral-dead-at-a-lizard-island-reef-after-last-summers-mass-bleaching-233325">had just occurred</a>. The picture was devastating. Vast swathes of coral were bleached a ghostly white. It was interspersed with bright flashes of pink and blue: a final, heartbreaking release of coral pigment as the organism makes a <a href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/PL00006956">last-ditch effort to survive</a>. I've since learned much of that coral is now dead.</p>

<h3><strong>Climate change is not the only threat</strong></h3>

<p>The report said climate-driven disturbances are compounding the effects of other chronic damage to the reef from:</p>

<ul>
	<li>unsustainable fishing</li>
	<li>pollution</li>
	<li>sediment runoff</li>
	<li>outbreaks of crown-of-thorns starfish.</li>
</ul>

<p>Among other key findings of the report were that:</p>

<ul>
	<li>most populations of marine turtles have declined</li>
	<li>species such as seabirds, sharks, rays, dugongs and seagrasses have recovered in some areas and plateaued or declined in others</li>
	<li>populations of estuarine crocodiles are recovering</li>
	<li>many species in decline are listed as threatened or protected.</li>
</ul>

<h3><strong>Strong leadership is needed</strong></h3>

<p>I first visited the Great Barrier Reef in 1980, as a university student. My interest in it has never waned. It's one of those incredible bits of nature that defies description.</p>

<p>The reef's World Heritage listing is proof of its outstanding global value. Australians love and feel pride in this vast and stunning place. The reef supports the livelihoods and wellbeing of many, including Traditional Owners who have cared for it over thousands of generations. It sustains all of us: economically, culturally and spiritually.</p>

<p>You might see a photo of healthy-looking coral and think the reef must be doing well. But I have seen the problem first-hand over many years. The reef is suffering badly – and every fraction of a degree of global warming compounds the harm.</p>

<p>Humanity must take urgent action to limit global temperature rise. But we are failing. We are failing the Great Barrier Reef and indeed, coral reefs across the planet.</p>

<p>There was a time when governments and reef managers were not willing to admit the extent of the problem. I don't think that's the case anymore. As the report states:</p>

<blockquote>
<p>2024 opens a new chapter for the reef. Future warming already locked into the climate system means that further degradation is inevitable. This is the sobering calculus of climate change.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Climate change is a global problem, but Australia is undeniably part of it. This nation <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/article/2024/aug/12/australian-fossil-fuel-exports-ranked-second-globally-for-climate-damage-with-no-plan-for-reduction#:%7E:text=Australian%20fossil%20fuel%20exports%20in,thermal%20coal%20exports%20in%202022.">cannot export fossil fuels</a> to be burnt overseas if we want to save the Great Barrier Reef. Dealing with this will take strong political leadership, from the prime minister down.</p>

<p>Humanity has all the facts in front of us. Earth is in an unchartered time of very rapid change. If we don't respond, we will lose the Great Barrier Reef.<!-- Below is The Conversation's page counter tag. Please DO NOT REMOVE. --><img alt="The Conversation" height="1" referrerpolicy="no-referrer-when-downgrade" src="https://counter.theconversation.com/content/237441/count.gif?distributor=republish-lightbox-basic" style="border: none !important; box-shadow: none !important; margin: 0 !important; max-height: 1px !important; max-width: 1px !important; min-height: 1px !important; min-width: 1px !important; opacity: 0 !important; outline: none !important; padding: 0 !important" width="1" /><!-- End of code. If you don't see any code above, please get new code from the Advanced tab after you click the republish button. The page counter does not collect any personal data. More info: https://theconversation.com/republishing-guidelines --></p>

<p><em><span><a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/ove-hoegh-guldberg-2012">Ove Hoegh-Guldberg</a>, Professor, School of the Environment, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/the-university-of-queensland-805">The University of Queensland</a></span></em></p>

<p><em>This article is republished from <a href="https://theconversation.com">The Conversation</a> under a Creative Commons license. Read the <a href="https://theconversation.com/humanity-is-failing-official-report-warns-our-chance-to-save-the-great-barrier-reef-is-fast-closing-237441">original article</a>.</em></p>
</div><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-03/ruskmtsg_great-barrier-reef_625x300_08_March_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Humanity is killing the Great Barrier Reef by failing to curb the greenhouse gas emissions (file).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pavel-durov-arrest-explained-the-case-against-telegram-ceo-that-got-him-arrested-in-france-6412839]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: The Case Against Telegram CEO That Got Him Arrested In France]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pavel-durov-arrest-explained-the-case-against-telegram-ceo-that-got-him-arrested-in-france-6412839]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 25 Aug 2024 09:58:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Pavel Durov, the CEO of the popular messaging app Telegram, was arrested by French police on Saturday evening at Le Bourget airport.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pavel Durov, the CEO of the popular messaging app Telegram, was arrested by French police on Saturday evening at Le Bourget airport, located just north of Paris. The 39-year-old Franco-Russian billionaire, who had arrived from Baku, Azerbaijan, is expected to appear in court on Sunday to face serious allegations, sources informed AFP.</p>

<p><strong>Why was Pavel Durov arrested?</strong></p>

<p>The arrest comes as part of a preliminary investigation headed by France's OFMIN (Office for Preventing Violence Against Minors). The office had issued a warrant for Mr Durov's arrest, citing allegations that include money laundering, drug trafficking and the sharing of child sexual abuse content on Telegram. The platform's lack of moderation and its alleged use by criminal groups have been central to the investigation.</p>

<p>Local news outlets BFMTV and TF1 reported that the investigation focused on Telegram's potential exploitation by criminal entities, as well as Mr Durov's alleged failure to implement effective measures to prevent illegal activities on the platform.</p>

<p>American commentator Tucker Carlson stated that the Telegram CEO was arrested for refusing to "censor the truth."</p>

<p>"Pavel Durov sits in a French jail tonight, a living warning to any platform owner who refuses to censor the truth at the behest of governments and intel agencies," he wrote on X.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Pavel Durov left Russia when the government tried to control his social media company, Telegram. But in the end, it wasn't Putin who arrested him for allowing the public to exercise free speech. It was a western country, a Biden administration ally and enthusiastic NATO member,… <a href="https://t.co/F83E9GbNHC">https://t.co/F83E9GbNHC</a></p>
— Tucker Carlson (@TuckerCarlson) <a href="https://twitter.com/TuckerCarlson/status/1827460234887008277?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 24, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p><strong>'Russia's Mark Zuckerberg'</strong></p>

<p>Pavel Durov, often referred to as "Russia's Mark Zuckerberg", has a long history of defying government demands. Before founding Telegram, he created Vkontakte (VK), Russia's largest social network, but was forced to leave the country in 2014 after refusing to comply with government orders to hand over data on Ukrainian protesters. Since then, Mr Durov has lived in various countries, eventually settling in Dubai, where Telegram is headquartered.</p>

<p>His stance on privacy and his refusal to censor content on Telegram have made him a controversial figure. In an interview earlier this year with Tucker Carlson, Mr Durov stressed on his commitment to keeping Telegram "neutral" and free from geopolitical influence.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Ep. 94 The social media app Telegram has over 900 million users around the world. Its founder Pavel Durov sat down with us at his offices in Dubai for his first on-camera interview in almost a decade. <a href="https://t.co/NEb3KzWOg8">pic.twitter.com/NEb3KzWOg8</a></p>
— Tucker Carlson (@TuckerCarlson) <a href="https://twitter.com/TuckerCarlson/status/1780355490964283565?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 16, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p><strong>'Enough of Telegram's impunity'</strong></p>

<p>On Saturday, one of the investigators said that they were surprised Durov came to Paris knowing he was a wanted man. "Enough of Telegram's impunity", the investigator stated, as per AFP.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Russia's Foreign Ministry announced that it is taking steps to "clarify" the situation, particularly whether the founder of Telegram has indeed been detained. Pavel Durov, who became a naturalised French citizen in August 2021, also holds citizenship in the United Arab Emirates.</p>

<p><strong>About Telegram</strong></p>

<p>Telegram is known for its end-to-end encryption and commitment to user privacy. It has become one of the most downloaded apps globally, with nearly one billion users. Its focus on security has made it a preferred platform for users who prioritise privacy, but this same feature has also made it attractive to criminal organisations and extremist groups.</p>

<p>In recent years, Telegram has faced criticism for allowing the spread of disinformation, extremist content and illegal activities, including far-right activism that has sparked violence. Despite these controversies, the platform remains popular, particularly in regions like Russia, Ukraine and other former Soviet states, including in conflict zones, where it serves as a vital tool for communication.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/2j54hml8_pavel-durov_625x300_25_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-backed-hezbollah-says-it-launched-over-320-katyusha-rockets-at-israel-6412837]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iran-Backed Hezbollah Says It Launched Over 320 Katyusha Rockets At Israel]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-backed-hezbollah-says-it-launched-over-320-katyusha-rockets-at-israel-6412837]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 25 Aug 2024 09:54:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hezbollah said Sunday it had launched more than 320 rockets at Israel overnight, targeting a string of military positions, even as Israel's military said it was carrying out pre-emptive strikes against the group.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hezbollah said Sunday it had launched more than 320 rockets at Israel overnight, targeting a string of military positions, even as Israel's military said it was carrying out pre-emptive strikes against the group.</p>

<p>"The number of Katyusha rockets launched until now is more than 320... towards enemy positions," a Hezbollah statement said, adding it had targeted 11 Israeli bases and barracks.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The group said the "first phase has ended with total success", adding that this phase sought to "target Israeli barracks and positions to facilitate the passage of attack drones towards targets" deep inside Israel.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/57tp90ko_israel-hezbollah-afp-_625x300_25_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[hezbollah said it had targeted 11 Israeli bases and barracks.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hezbollah-war-conflict-live-updates-israel-strikes-lebanon-to-prevent-large-scale-hezbollah-attack-as-middle-east-tensions-rise-6412787]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Highlights: Israel Declares 48-Hour Emergency After Hezbollah Strikes]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hezbollah-war-conflict-live-updates-israel-strikes-lebanon-to-prevent-large-scale-hezbollah-attack-as-middle-east-tensions-rise-6412787]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 25 Aug 2024 09:46:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel today announced that it was conducting pre-emptive strikes in Lebanon after detecting preparations for "large-scale" attacks by the Iran-backed group Hezbollah.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel today announced that it was conducting <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/hezbollah-announces-large-scale-attack-israel-begins-pre-emptive-strikes-6412664#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">pre-emptive strikes in Lebanon</a> after detecting preparations for "large-scale" attacks by the Iran-backed group Hezbollah. The country, which is already at war with <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/they-hit-me-all-over-my-body-says-israeli-woman-noa-argamani-held-captive-by-hamas-6406659" target="_blank">Hamas</a> in Gaza, warned its citizens to expect incoming missiles and drones launched by Hezbollah and declared a 48-hour nationwide state of emergency.</p>

<p>Lebanon-based <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hezbollah-war-self-defence-israel-says-fired-on-lebanon-to-prevent-hezbollah-attack-6412754#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">Hezbollah</a> said it had launched large-scale rockets and drones toward Israel in an "initial response" to the killing of its commander Fuad Shukr last month.</p>

<p>Fighters also targeted "a number of enemy positions and barracks and Iron Dome platforms... with a large number of rockets", it said.</p>

<p>The Middle East has been on edge for weeks after Hezbollah and Iran vowed to respond to an Israeli strike in Beirut that killed a senior commander of the group as well as the assassination in Tehran of Hamas's political leader, also blamed on Israel.</p>

<h2><strong>Here are highlights on the Israel-Hezbollah conflict:</strong></h2>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/11dto4h_israelhezbollah-conflict_625x300_25_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Middle East has been on edge for weeks]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hezbollah-war-self-defence-israel-says-fired-on-lebanon-to-prevent-hezbollah-attack-6412754]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Self-Defence": Israel Says Fired On Lebanon To Prevent Hezbollah Attack]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hezbollah-war-self-defence-israel-says-fired-on-lebanon-to-prevent-hezbollah-attack-6412754]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 25 Aug 2024 09:40:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel today said that is launched strikes inside Lebanon as a "self-defence act" to prevent a Hezbollah attack on civilians, Israel Defense Forces spokesperson Daniel Hagari said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel today said that is launched strikes inside Lebanon as a "self-defence act" to prevent a Hezbollah attack on civilians, Israel Defense Forces spokesperson Daniel Hagari said. The military also warned Israelis to expect incoming missiles and drones launched by Hezbollah, with air alert sirens sounding across the country's north.</p>

<p>The IDF claimed that they had information that Hezbollah was preparing to fire missiles and rockets toward Israeli territory.</p>

<p>"The IDF identified the Hezbollah terrorist organization preparing to fire missiles and rockets toward Israeli territory. In response to these threats, the IDF is striking terror targets in Lebanon. Israeli Air Force fighter jets are currently striking targets belonging to the Hezbollah terrorist organization that posed an imminent threat to the citizens of the State of Israel," IDF said in a statement.</p>

<p>Israel's international Ben Gurion airport has canceled all take-offs and landings for several hours, the country's airport authority said.</p>

<p>“Due to the security situation, the morning departures from Ben Gurion International Airport will be postponed, and will not take off in the next few hours,” the authority said. “Flights en route to Ben Gurion will be directed to land at alternative airports in the region.”</p>

<p>The Middle East has been on edge for weeks after Hezbollah and Iran vowed to respond to an Israeli strike in Beirut that killed a senior commander of the group as well as the assassination in Tehran of Hamas's political leader, also blamed on Israel.</p>

<p>The strikes came as negotiators were meeting in Cairo in a last-ditch effort to conclude a halt to fighting in Gaza and a return of Israeli and foreign hostages in exchange for Palestinian prisoners.</p>

<p>Hezbollah fired missiles at Israel immediately after the October 7 attacks by Hamas gunmen on Israel. Hezbollah and Israel have been exchanging fire constantly ever since, while avoiding a major escalation as war rages in Gaza to the south.</p>

<p>That precarious balance appeared to shift after the strike in the Golan Heights, for which Hezbollah denied responsibility, and the subsequent assassination of Fuad Shukr, a senior military commander in Beirut.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/cht5q98c_israel-lebanon_625x300_25_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-declares-48-hour-nationwide-emergency-as-hezbollah-announces-large-scale-attacks-6412697]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Declares Emergency As Hezbollah Announces "Large-Scale" Attacks]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-declares-48-hour-nationwide-emergency-as-hezbollah-announces-large-scale-attacks-6412697]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 25 Aug 2024 09:25:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Lebanon-based Hezbollah announced on Sunday large-scale rocket and drone launches towards Israel in an "initial response" to a top commander's killing.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Defence Minister Yoav Gallant announced a 48-hour nationwide state of emergency from 06:00 am (0300 GMT) Sunday after the Israeli military launched what it called pre-emptive strikes in Lebanon.</p>

<p>"The declaration on the state of emergency enables the IDF (Israeli military) to issue instructions to the citizens of Israel, including limiting gatherings and closing sites where it may be relevant," Gallant said, in a statement issued by his office.</p>

<p>Lebanon-based Hezbollah announced on Sunday large-scale rocket and drone launches towards Israel in an "initial response" to a top commander's killing, after Israel's military said it was carrying out a series of pre-emptive strikes against the group.</p>

<p>"In the context of the initial response" to the killing of its commander Fuad Shukr last month, Hezbollah said it "began an air attack with a large number of drones" targeting deep into Israel, a statement from the group said. Fighters also targeted "a number of enemy positions and barracks and Iron Dome platforms... with a large number of rockets", it said, adding that "military operations will take some time to complete".</p>

<p>The Middle East has been on edge for weeks after Hezbollah and Iran vowed to respond to an Israeli strike in Beirut that killed a senior commander of the group as well as the assassination in Tehran of Hamas's political leader, also blamed on Israel.</p>

<p>In a message addressed to the residents of southern Lebanon early Sunday morning, the Israeli military said: "We are monitoring Hezbollah's preparations to carry out large-scale attacks on Israeli territory near your homes. You are in danger. We are attacking and eliminating Hezbollah threats.</p>

<p>"Anyone who is near areas where Hezbollah operates should leave immediately to protect themselves and their families," the message posted on Telegram said.</p>

<p>In a separate statement released shortly before 5:00 am (0100 GMT), the military said its jets were striking targets in Lebanon "that posed an imminent threat" to Israelis.</p>

<p>Announcing the strikes in a video released at the same time, military spokesperson Daniel Hagari said that "Hezbollah will soon fire rockets, and possibly missiles and UAVs, towards Israeli territory".</p>

<p>"From right next to the homes of Lebanese civilians in the south of Lebanon, we can see that Hezbollah is preparing to launch an extensive attack on Israel, while endangering the Lebanese civilians" he added, urging civilians there "to move out of harm's way".</p>

<p>"Hezbollah's ongoing aggression risks dragging the people of Lebanon, the people of Israel, and the whole region into a wider escalation."</p>

<p>Prime Minister Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu would hold a security cabinet meeting at 0400 GMT, his office said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/m68ipus_hezbollah_625x300_25_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[File photo]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-faces-uphill-battle-to-win-back-muslim-votes-in-swing-state-6412361]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris Faces Uphill Battle To Win Back Muslim Votes In Swing State]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-faces-uphill-battle-to-win-back-muslim-votes-in-swing-state-6412361]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 25 Aug 2024 07:55:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In key US swing state Michigan, Democratic voters of Arab and Middle Eastern heritage say Kamala Harris is going to have to win them back after they were alienated by President Joe Biden's handling of Israel's military offensive in Gaza.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In key US swing state Michigan, Democratic voters of Arab and Middle Eastern heritage say Kamala Harris is going to have to win them back after they were alienated by President Joe Biden's handling of Israel's military offensive in Gaza.</p>

<p>The town of Dearborn, home to 110,000 people and a cultural hub for Arab Americans, could play a decisive role in deciding the fate of the battleground state in November's presidential election.</p>

<p>Members of the community interviewed by AFP said they were willing to hear what the vice president had to say and weigh their options -- a marked change from the outright hostility towards Biden.</p>

<p>"We are in a listening mode right now," said Osama Siblani, publisher of The Arab American News.</p>

<p>Accepting the Democratic presidential nomination at the party's convention on Thursday, Harris pledged to get a Gaza ceasefire "done" and ensure Palestinians realize their right to "dignity, security, freedom and self-determination."</p>

<p>But there was outrage among pro-Palestinian delegates that their request for a speaker spot at the convention was rejected. The group Muslim Women for Harris-Walz said the decision sent a "terrible message" and announced it was disbanding and withdrawing its support from the campaign.</p>

<p>Harris, who has vowed "not to be silent" about the suffering of Palestinians, recently met with members of the national "Uncommitted" movement that led the charge against Biden during the Democratic primary process.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Although she made no firm promises, leaders said she impressed them with a show of empathy.</p>

<p>At the forefront of concerns are Israel's 10 months of military operations in Gaza, which have devastated the Palestinian enclave since the war began in response to Hamas's attack on Israel on October 7, 2023.</p>

<h3><strong>Growing influence&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Michigan, home to the "big three" automakers -- Ford, General Motors and Chrysler -- has long been an essential stop for White House aspirants.</p>

<p>Economic downturns in the 1970s led many to leave the so-called "Rust Belt" state, just as unrest in the Middle East brought new waves of Lebanese, Iraqi, Yemeni, and Palestinian immigrants.</p>

<p>"We're a global city, where nearly 55 per cent of our residents are of Arab background," said Dearborn Mayor Abdullah Hammoud in a recent interview. "For many of us, when you talk about what's happening in Gaza, these are our family and our friends."</p>

<p>Famous as the birthplace of Henry Ford, Dearborn appears at first glance just like any small US city, with its wide thoroughfares and strip malls.&nbsp;</p>

<p>But it is also home to the Islamic Center of America -- the largest mosque in the country -- and countless Middle Eastern supermarkets, eateries, and coffee shops.</p>

<p>When Siblani first started his newspaper in the mid-1980s, he remembers the then-mayor campaigned on a platform to address the "Arab problem."&nbsp;</p>

<p>But as the community's numbers grew, and the children of blue-collar factory workers took up positions as lawyers, doctors, and businesspeople, so too did their political influence.</p>

<h3><strong>'Lesser of two evils'&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Historically socially conservative, Arab and Muslim Americans heavily favoured George W. Bush in the 2000 election.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Years of the US "War on Terror" -- which saw wars in the Middle East and Afghanistan, and Muslim American communities put under stricter law enforcement scrutiny -- swung them firmly to the Democratic camp.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In 2018, southeast Michiganders elected Rashida Tlaib, the first Palestinian-American in Congress -- a milestone for the community.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Three Arab-American mayors have also recently been elected in suburbs known for historic racism towards non-whites.</p>

<p>Angered by former president Donald Trump's travel ban on Muslim countries, support for Israeli settlements in the occupied West Bank, and more, Dearborn voters overwhelmingly backed Biden in 2020, helping secure Michigan for the Democrats by a slim margin.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Residents here are tired, however, of being asked to vote for the "lesser of two evils" and instead want candidates who will deliver on demands, such as a permanent ceasefire and an end to the supply of weapons to Israel.</p>

<p>"I think VP Harris has a window of opportunity," said Faye Nemer, a community activist and CEO of the MENA American Chamber of Commerce. "She can either continue President Biden's legacy or set her own agenda."</p>

<p>Arab Americans in Dearborn have been impressed by Harris's pick of Tim Walz as her running mate. Walz has taken a conciliatory approach to opponents of the war, unlike Pennsylvania Governor Josh Shapiro, who took a hard line against college protesters.</p>

<p>But demands are hardening.</p>

<p>"We don't want crumbs anymore," declared Soujoud Hamade, a business lawyer and long-time Democrat, who vowed to vote for Green Party candidate Jill Stein if Harris did not deliver on the campaign trail.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/gs5frbgs_kamala-harris_625x300_23_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kamala Harris has vowed not to be silent about the suffering of Palestinians (file).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/top-us-scientist-anthony-fauci-hospitalised-for-west-nile-virus-now-recovering-at-home-6412331]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Top US Scientist Hospitalised For West Nile Virus, Now Recovering At Home]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/top-us-scientist-anthony-fauci-hospitalised-for-west-nile-virus-now-recovering-at-home-6412331]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 25 Aug 2024 07:44:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The West Nile virus is mainly transmitted through the bite of infected mosquitoes.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dr Anthony Fauci, the former top U.S. infectious disease expert, was hospitalised for about a week after being infected with West Nile virus and is now recovering at home. Dr Fauci is expected to recover fully, according to his spokesperson.</p>

<p>''Tony Fauci has been hospitalised with a case of West Nile virus. He is now home and is recovering. A full recovery is expected,'' a spokesperson said in a statement Saturday.</p>

<p>According to the<em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/health/2024/08/24/fauci-west-nile-virus/"> Washington Post,</a></em> he likely contracted the disease from a mosquito bite in his backyard and spent a week in the hospital after developing fever, chills, and severe fatigue.</p>

<p>Dr Fauci, 83, was the director of the National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases for nearly four decades before he retired in 2022. He emerged as the prominent public figure leading the US government's response to the COVID-19 pandemic, providing guidance, expertise, and reassurance to the nation during a time of unprecedented crisis.</p>

<p>Following his departure from government service, Dr Fauci assumed a new role as a university professor at Georgetown University last summer.</p>

<p><strong>What is&nbsp;West Nile virus?</strong></p>

<p>The West Nile virus (WNV) is a viral infection that primarily affects birds but can also be transmitted to humans through the bite of infected mosquitoes. It is named after the West Nile region of Uganda where it was first identified in 1937. While some might experience flu-like symptoms. In rare cases, it may be fatal and affect your brain or the spinal cord.</p>

<p>It is the most common mosquito-borne illness in the continental United States, typically spreading during the summer and fall months when mosquito activity is at its peak. About 216 cases of West Nile virus have been reported in 33 states this year,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.cdc.gov/west-nile-virus/data-maps/current-year-data.html" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">according to the CDC</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Most people who become infected with WNV do not develop any symptoms, but around 20% may experience flu-like symptoms such as fever, headache, body aches, joint pains, vomiting, diarrhoea, or rash.</p>

<p>In rare cases, the virus can cause severe illness including inflammation of the brain or spinal cord, leading to potentially fatal conditions such as encephalitis or meningitis.</p>

<p>There is no vaccine or specific treatment for West Nile.</p>

<p></p>

<p></p>

<p></p>

<p data-apitype="text" data-contentid="4MFMRHPHTVF5PLXPOD7WIIM2MM" data-el="text" data-scroll-measured="true" data-scroll-pos="3" data-testid="drop-cap-letter" dir="null"></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-06/puntic2_anthony-fauci-reuters_625x300_22_June_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[He is expected to recover fully, according to his spokesperson.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/why-boeings-starliner-will-return-to-earth-without-sunita-williams-butch-wilmore-6412302]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Why Starliner Will Return Without Sunita Williams And How Musk Will Help Her]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/why-boeings-starliner-will-return-to-earth-without-sunita-williams-butch-wilmore-6412302]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 25 Aug 2024 07:37:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Indian-origin astronaut Sunita Williams and her NASA colleague Butch Wilmore will now return home with billionaire Elon Musk's SpaceX next year.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Indian-origin astronaut Sunita Williams and her NASA colleague Butch Wilmore, who arrived at the International Space Station (ISS) aboard crisis-hit Boeing's Starliner in June, will return home with billionaire Elon Musk's SpaceX next year. The two veteran astronauts were launched to the ISS on June 5 for what was expected to be an eight-day test mission. Their homecoming, however, was delayed for weeks by thruster malfunctions of the Boeing spacecraft, and NASA announced Saturday they will return to Earth in February next year. Starliner will return to Earth uncrewed.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/astronauts-sunita-williams-barry-butch-wilmore-in-space-for-80-days-will-return-february-next-year-says-nasa-6410618#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">NASA</a> administrator Bill Nelson said the decision to keep the two astronauts on the space station and return the Starliner uncrewed "is the result of our commitment to safety," adding, "Our core value is safety."&nbsp;</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Sunita Williams and Butch Wilmore at the International Space Station" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/37do7ds8_sunita-williams_625x300_25_August_24.jpeg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Sunita Williams and Butch Wilmore at the International Space Station" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">Sunita Williams and Butch Wilmore at the International Space Station<br />
<span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: x.com/BoeingSpace</span></p>
</div>

<p>"Space flight is risky even at its safest and even at its most routine," he told reporters. "A test flight, by nature, is neither safe nor routine."&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>Boeing's Starliner Setbacks</strong></h3>

<p>After years of delays, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-boeings-starliner-mission-to-send-sunita-williams-barry-butch-wilmore-on-space-faced-setbacks-6412177#pfrom=home-ndtv_topstories" target="_blank">Boeing's Starliner</a> finally lifted off on June 5 carrying Sunita Williams and Butch Wilmore, both former military test pilots, to the space station. But a day later, as Starliner was approaching the ISS, NASA and Boeing identified helium leaks and experienced issues with the spacecraft's reaction control thrusters.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Hugs all around! The Expedition 71 crew greets Butch Wilmore and <a href="https://twitter.com/Astro_Suni?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Astro_Suni</a> aboard <a href="https://twitter.com/Space_Station?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Space_Station</a> after <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Starliner?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Starliner</a> docked at 1:34 p.m. ET on June 6. <a href="https://t.co/wQZAYy2LGH">pic.twitter.com/wQZAYy2LGH</a></p>
— Boeing Space (@BoeingSpace) <a href="https://twitter.com/BoeingSpace/status/1798804195681947719?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 6, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Five of Starliner's 28 thrusters failed during flight and it sprang several leaks of helium, which is used to pressurize the thrusters. It was still able to dock with the space station, which has housed rotating crews of astronauts for over two decades.</p>

<p>NASA, however, feared the capsule would not be able to achieve the thrust necessary to return to Earth and decided to transfer the two astronauts to a SpaceX mission and return the Starliner empty.</p>

<p>"The uncrewed return allows NASA and Boeing to continue gathering testing data on Starliner during its upcoming flight home, while also not accepting more risk than necessary for its crew," the US space agency said.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">NASA will return <a href="https://twitter.com/BoeingSpace?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@BoeingSpace</a>'s <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Starliner?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Starliner</a> to Earth without <a href="https://twitter.com/NASA_Astronauts?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@NASA_Astronauts</a> Butch Wilmore and Suni Williams aboard the spacecraft.<br />
<br />
The uncrewed return allows NASA and Boeing to continue gathering testing data on Starliner during its upcoming flight home, while also not… <a href="https://t.co/wkXX0qQXkq">pic.twitter.com/wkXX0qQXkq</a></p>
— NASA Commercial Crew (@Commercial_Crew) <a href="https://twitter.com/Commercial_Crew/status/1827400923154366799?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 24, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Starliner will now undock from the ISS without a crew in early September.</p>

<h3><strong>How Elon Musk's SpaceX Will Help Sunita Williams, Butch Willmore</strong></h3>

<p>In what is seen as a rare reshuffling of NASA's astronaut operations, Sunita Williams and Butch Willmore will now return to Earth on <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sunita-williams-barry-wilmore-boeing-starliner-why-nasa-picked-elon-musks-spacex-to-bring-back-astronauts-from-space-6410789#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">Elon Musk's SpaceX</a> Crew Dragon spacecraft.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Under the new plan, the SpaceX Crew-9 mission will take off in late September after the Starliner has headed earthward, freeing a docking port on the ISS.</p>

<p>It, however, will carry only two passengers instead of the originally planned four to make room for Ms Williams and Mr Wilmore.</p>

<p>The SpaceX vehicle will then in February bring back the two stranded colleagues with its crew members.</p>

<p><em>(With agency inputs)</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/fev0vbs8_sunita-williams_625x300_25_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sunita Williams and Butch Wilmore arrived at International Space Station aboard Boeing Starliner in June]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-pavel-durov-telegram-ceo-arrested-in-france-6412272]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Who Is Pavel Durov, Telegram CEO Arrested In France]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-pavel-durov-telegram-ceo-arrested-in-france-6412272]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 25 Aug 2024 07:29:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Pavel Durov, the billionaire founder and CEO of the Telegram messaging app, was arrested at the Bourget airport outside Paris on Saturday evening, French local media said, citing unnamed sources.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pavel Durov, the billionaire founder and CEO of the Telegram messaging app, was arrested at the Bourget airport outside Paris on Saturday evening, French local media said, citing unnamed sources.<br />
They said the investigation was focused on a lack of moderators on Telegram, and that police considered that this situation allowed criminal activity to go on undeterred on the messaging app.</p>

<p>Telegram did not immediately respond to a Reuters request for comment. The French Interior Ministry and police had no comment. Russia's Foreign Ministry said it was taking steps to "clarify" the situation and questioned whether Western non-governmental organizations (NGOs) would seek his release..</p>

<h3><strong>What is known about Durov and Telegram:</strong></h3>

<p>* Russian-born Durov, 39, is the founder and owner of messaging app Telegram, a free-to-use platform that competes with other social media platforms such as Facebook's WhatsApp, Instagram, TikTok and WeChat. The platform aims to surpass one billion active monthly users within a year.</p>

<p>* Telegram is influential in Russia, Ukraine and the republics of the former Soviet Union. It has become a critical source of information on Russia's war in Ukraine, used heavily by both Moscow and Kyiv officials. Some analysts call the app "a virtual battlefield" for the war.</p>

<p>* Durov, whose fortune was estimated by Forbes at $15.5 billion, left Russia in 2014 after refusing to comply with government demands to shut down opposition communities on his VKontakte social media platform, which he sold.</p>

<p>* Russian and French media say Durov became a French citizen in 2021. He moved himself and Telegram to Dubai in 2017.</p>

<p>* "I would rather be free than to take orders from anyone," Durov told US journalist Tucker Carlson in April about his exit from Russia and search for a home for his company which included stints in Berlin, London, Singapore and San Francisco.</p>

<p>* In the same interview, Durov said that, beyond money or Bitcoin, he had no major property such as real estate, jets or yachts, as he wanted to be free.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/v8sfdk8g_telegram-ceo-pavel-durov-reuters-_625x300_25_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Telegram CEO Pavel Durov left Russia in 2021.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-boeings-starliner-mission-to-send-sunita-williams-barry-butch-wilmore-on-space-faced-setbacks-6412177]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How Boeing's Mission To Send Sunita Williams On Space Faced Setbacks]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-boeings-starliner-mission-to-send-sunita-williams-barry-butch-wilmore-on-space-faced-setbacks-6412177]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 25 Aug 2024 06:52:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The decision to transfer the crew of Boeing's Starliner to a SpaceX mission after the spacecraft malfunctioned is just the latest twist in a long saga that has undermined the credibility of the US aerospace giant.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The decision to transfer the crew of Boeing's Starliner to a SpaceX mission after the spacecraft malfunctioned is just the latest twist in a long saga that has undermined the credibility of the US aerospace giant.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Here is a recap of the setbacks and delays on Starliner's journey to fly a crew to the International Space Station -- and how it was unable to bring them back again.</p>

<h3><strong>2014: Nasa awards contract</strong></h3>

<p>A decade ago NASA chose two companies, Boeing and SpaceX, to each develop a new spacecraft capable of transporting its astronauts to the International Space Station (ISS).&nbsp;</p>

<p>The US space agency asked both to be ready for 2017, as it sought to end its dependence on the Russian spacecraft it had used to ferry astronauts to the ISS since the end of the space shuttle program in 2011.</p>

<p>Boeing was awarded a $4.2 billion contract, against SpaceX's $2.6 billion. At the time, billionaire Elon Musk's young company was widely seen as the underdog against Boeing's aerospace might.&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>2019: Failed unmanned flight</strong></h3>

<p>During the first unmanned flight in December 2019, the capsule failed to set itself on the right trajectory and returned to Earth prematurely after two days, without reaching the ISS.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The problem was due to a clock that was eleven hours late, preventing the capsule from firing its thrusters at the scheduled time.&nbsp;</p>

<p>NASA then realized that another software problem could have led to a catastrophic collision.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The manufacturer was given a long list of recommendations and modifications to make.</p>

<h3><strong>2021: False hope</strong></h3>

<p>In August 2021, when the rocket was already on the launch pad for another attempt at flight, unexpected moisture caused a chemical reaction that blocked the opening of some of the capsule's valves.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The capsule returned to the factory for inspection over a period of several months.</p>

<p>The delay was in stark contrast to the progress being made by SpaceX, which had been successfully transporting astronauts to the ISS since 2020.&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>2022: First (unmanned) success</strong></h3>

<p>In May 2022, Starliner finally completed its first unmanned test flight.</p>

<p>Despite a few glitches -- including a propulsion system problem detected in flight, but with no adverse consequences -- the capsule lifted off, reached the ISS where it remained docked for several days, and returned safely to Earth.&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>2023: New worries, new delays</strong></h3>

<p>Starliner's nascent momentum was arrested in 2023 when new problems emerged, delaying preparations for its first manned flight.</p>

<p>One concerned the design of the parachutes that would slow the capsule as it re-entered the atmosphere. It was modified and new tests carried out.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The other was even more surprising: adhesive tape, used over several meters to wrap electrical cables inside the capsule, proved to be flammable and had to be removed.&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>2024: First manned flight goes awry</strong></h3>

<p>The big day finally arrived on June 5, 2024: the capsule lifted off with two astronauts -- Barry "Butch" Wilmore and Sunita "Suni" Williams -- for the first time, a final test mission to prove it was safe before beginning regular operations to the ISS.</p>

<p>But leaks of helium, the gas used to create pressure in the propulsion system, were discovered in flight.</p>

<p>Several thrusters then failed before the capsule docked with the ISS, although all but one were eventually reignited.&nbsp;</p>

<p>NASA feared the capsule would not be able to achieve the thrust necessary to return to Earth.&nbsp;</p>

<p>As a result, the space agency took a radical decision: to transfer the two astronauts to a SpaceX mission and return Starliner empty.</p>

<p>Analysis of the flight will determine the path forward -- and how long any new delays will last.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Boeing has already gone $1.6 billion over budget on the program.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/j537v0c_sunita-williams_625x300_25_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Boeing's Starliner lifted off with Barry "Butch" Wilmore and Sunita "Suni" Williams on June 5]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-struggles-to-keep-media-spotlight-in-battle-with-kamala-harris-6411983]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Struggles To Keep Media Spotlight In Battle With Kamala Harris]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-struggles-to-keep-media-spotlight-in-battle-with-kamala-harris-6411983]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 25 Aug 2024 05:41:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump, touting plans on taxes and health, tried on Friday to turn the page on a week in which he was overshadowed by Kamala Harris and struggled to focus on policy issues instead of personal attacks on his opponent in the US presidential race.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump, touting plans on taxes and health, tried on Friday to turn the page on a week in which he was overshadowed by Kamala Harris and struggled to focus on policy issues instead of personal attacks on his opponent in the US presidential race.</p>

<p>From a lectern at a Mexican restaurant in Las Vegas, the Republican candidate spoke about his plan to eliminate taxes on tips to waiters and other service employees. He discussed his campaign's efforts to court Hispanic voters in Nevada, a battleground state that could help determine the Nov. 5 election, and nationwide.</p>

<p>The tax proposal, a pillar of Trump's economic agenda, is the kind of issue his advisers have been pressing him to focus on, rather than his frequent personal attacks against Vice President Kamala Harris' looks, Black and Indian heritage and intelligence, warning they could turn off the moderate voters he needs to win.</p>

<p>At an event in Arizona later, the former president repeated his tax pledge, while promising to set up a commission to investigate presidential assassination attempts. He also said he would install a panel to investigate "an increase in chronic health problems and childhood diseases."</p>

<p>Both proposals are apparent concessions to independent presidential candidate Robert F. Kennedy Jr., who endorsed Trump at the event after dropping out of the race.</p>

<p>Trump's comments come one day after Kamala Harris accepted the Democratic Party's presidential nomination with a muscular speech that laid down broad foreign policy principles and sharp contrasts with Trump with 11 weeks left until Election Day.</p>

<p>Trump sought to counter-program the four-day convention with events of his own around the country, hoping to steal some media attention from Kamala Harris. However, his speeches on foreign policy, the economy and crime did little to dislodge the spotlight from Kamala Harris and received little attention - a stunning turnabout for a politician used to dominating headlines.</p>

<p>The Republican and his aides hope Thursday's boisterous convention finale marks the end of the honeymoon period for Kamala Harris, who emerged as the Democratic candidate little more than a month ago, after President Joe Biden exited the race and endorsed her.</p>

<p>During Kamala Harris' acceptance speech in Chicago, Trump attacked her with dozens of posts on his Truth Social platform, calling her a liar, a Marxist and "Comrade Kamala Harris." One post simply asked: "IS SHE TALKING ABOUT ME?"</p>

<p>William Rosenberg, a political science professor at Drexel University, said Trump's personal attacks on Kamala Harris underscored his frustration with having to face a biracial woman, a task complicated by his history of making racist remarks.</p>

<p>"His anger and his words speak volumes," Rosenberg said. "He's navigating a path which is full of problems for him."</p>

<p>Kamala Harris has surged in the polls since entering the race, with polling aggregator website FiveThirtyEight putting her ahead of Trump in six of seven battleground states.</p>

<p>She is also outraising her Republican counterpart. Her campaign told the Federal Election Commission this week that it raised $204 million last month, compared to $48 million reported to the body by Trump's main fundraising group.</p>

<p>One question still to be answered is whether Kamala Harris will also outpace Trump on the trail in the coming weeks. Biden, 81, made relatively few campaign stops, easing pressure on Trump to travel more around the country. That may now change with Harris, 59.</p>

<p>Trump, 78, will travel to Detroit on Monday to address a conference of the National Guard Association of the United States and is scheduled to give a speech at a conservative women's group's annual summit in Washington on Friday.</p>

<p>Campaign spokesperson Karoline Leavitt said Trump would hold at least one additional campaign stop between those two events, without providing details.</p>

<p>The Kamala Harris campaign has not yet released details of her movements for next week.</p>

<p>Leavitt blamed the media for focusing their stories on Trump's personal attacks, which she said made up a fraction of his otherwise policy-heavy rallies and speeches.</p>

<p>At a speech event on Wednesday in Asheboro, North Carolina, billed as one on national security, Trump said he had rejected the recommendations of his advisers to focus on policy, and he insulted Kamala Harris and other Democrats in personal terms.</p>

<p>He again recounted those conversations with advisers at the rally in Arizona on Friday.</p>

<p>"My geniuses, they get paid a fortune - actually not that much - but I call up my people, I say, 'They're knocking the hell out of me, and you say I shouldn't get personal. I have to get personal, don't I?'" Trump said to applause.</p>

<p>An outside adviser to Trump told Reuters on condition of anonymity that several advisers had told the former president that a continued focus on insults rather than policy could doom his chances in November.</p>

<p>Republican strategist Doug Heye said Trump could still win the race, which he predicted would be close, but to do that he should focus on inflation, illegal immigration and other issues that polling show many voters give him higher marks on.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ugf3uu1g_trump-harris-_625x300_22_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US Presidential elections will be held in November this year (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/suspected-german-festival-stabber-who-killed-3-arrested-6411953]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Suspected German Festival Stabber Who Killed 3 Arrested]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/suspected-german-festival-stabber-who-killed-3-arrested-6411953]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 25 Aug 2024 05:35:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[German police on Saturday arrested the suspected killer behind a knife rampage that left three people dead at a street festival, an attack claimed by the Islamic State group.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>German police on Saturday arrested the suspected killer behind a knife rampage that left three people dead at a street festival, an attack claimed by the Islamic State group.</p>

<p>The unidentified assailant fled after striking in the western town of Solingen late on Friday, sparking a day-long manhunt.</p>

<p>"We have just arrested the true suspect," North Rhine-Westphalia region interior minister Herbert Reul said on public television late Saturday evening.</p>

<p>"The man we have been looking for all day has since a short time ago been in detention," he said, adding that police found evidence to convict him.</p>

<p>In a statement on Telegram, IS's Amaq propaganda arm said that "the perpetrator of the attack on a gathering of Christians in the city of Solingen in Germany yesterday was a soldier of the Islamic State".</p>

<p>IS said the attack was carried out as "revenge for Muslims in Palestine and everywhere", in an apparent reference to Israel's war with Palestinian group Hamas in the Gaza Strip.</p>

<p>The claim has yet to be verified. German officials had earlier said that "a terrorist motive cannot be excluded" for the act.</p>

<p>A police spokesman earlier told AFP that officers had arrested a man in a raid at a hostel for asylum seekers, not far from the scene of Friday's attack.</p>

<p>Earlier on Saturday, a prosecutor said a first person was arrested: a 15-year-old suspected of failing to report a criminal act.</p>

<p>Witnesses had allegedly seen the teen discussing the attack just before it happened with a man who could be the killer, said Markus Caspers, prosecutor of Duesseldorf, just west of Solingen.</p>

<p>The people killed were men of 56 and 67 years of age and a 56-year-old woman, officials said.</p>

<p>"The victims were completely unknown with no known ties between them," Caspers told a press conference.</p>

<p>Four of the wounded were in a "serious" condition, officials said, revising down an earlier estimate of five.</p>

<p>Chancellor Olaf Scholz said the perpetrator "must be caught quickly and punished".</p>

<p>The attacker struck as thousands of people gathered for the first night of a "Festival of Diversity", part of a series of events to mark Solingen's 650th anniversary.</p>

<p><strong>High terror alert</strong></p>

<p>Germany has been on high alert for possible Islamist attacks after a series of atrocities.</p>

<p>Since the outbreak of the war in Gaza on October 7, the risk of Islamist plots has "worsened considerably", Interior Minister Nancy Faeser said, warning that "the threat posed by Islamist terrorism remains high".</p>

<p>Jihadists have carried out several attacks in Germany in recent years, the deadliest being a truck rampage at a Berlin Christmas market in 2016 that killed 12.</p>

<p>A police officer was killed and five people were wounded in a knife attack at a far-right rally in the city of Mannheim in May, with an Islamist motive suspected.</p>

<p>Friday's killing started as thousands of people had gathered in front of a stage for the first night of the three-day festival.</p>

<p>Witness Lars Breitzke told the Solinger Tageblatt newspaper he was a few metres away from the attack, not far from the stage, and "understood from the expression on the singer's face that something was wrong".</p>

<p>"And then, a metre away from me, a person fell," said Breitzke, who at first thought it was someone who had had too much to drink.</p>

<p>When he turned around, he saw other people lying on the ground amid pools of blood.</p>

<p>Solingen mayor Tim-Oliver Kurzbach said the whole city was in "shock, horror and great grief".</p>

<p>Faeser called for the country to "remain united" as she denounced "those who want to stir up hatred" during a visit to the site of the tragedy. "Let us not be divided", she said.</p>

<p><strong>Series of knifings</strong></p>

<p>Solingen is a city of some 150,000 people located between Duesseldorf and Cologne.</p>

<p>Up to 75,000 visitors had been expected to attend the "Festival of Diversity".</p>

<p>After the attack, "people left the scene in shock, but calmly," Philipp Mueller, one of the organisers, told the newspaper, adding that the rest of the festival was cancelled.</p>

<p>Scholz's centre-left coalition faces regional elections next week in the east of the country, where the far-right AfD is leading strongly in the polls.</p>

<p>Germany took in more than a million asylum seekers in 2015-2016 at the height of Europe's migrant crisis.</p>

<p>The influx was deeply divisive in Germany and fuelled the popularity of the AfD.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/irump6t_germany-festival-stabbing-victims_625x300_25_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The people killed were men of 56 and 67 years of age and a 56-year-old woman, officials said.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/telegram-chief-pavel-durov-arrested-at-french-airport-report-6411921]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Telegram Chief Pavel Durov Arrested For 'Lack Of Moderation' On App]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/telegram-chief-pavel-durov-arrested-at-french-airport-report-6411921]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 25 Aug 2024 05:26:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Telegram chief executive Pavel Durov is expected to appear in court Sunday after being arrested by French police at an airport near Paris for alleged offences related to his popular messaging app, sources told AFP.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Telegram chief executive Pavel Durov is expected to appear in court Sunday after being arrested by French police at an airport near Paris for alleged offences related to his popular messaging app, sources told AFP.</p>

<p>The Franco-Russian billionaire, 39, was detained at Le Bourget airport north of the French capital on Saturday evening, one of the sources said, speaking on condition of anonymity.</p>

<p>Durov had arrived from Baku, in Azerbaijan, another source close to the case said.</p>

<p>France's OFMIN, an office tasked with preventing violence against minors, had issued an arrest warrant for Durov in a preliminary investigation into alleged offences including fraud, drug trafficking, cyberbullying, organised crime and promotion of terrorism, one of the sources said.</p>

<p>Durov is accused of failing to take action to curb the criminal use of his platform.</p>

<p>"Enough of Telegram's impunity," said one of the investigators, adding they were surprised Durov came to Paris knowing he was a wanted man.</p>

<h3><strong>Platform of 'privacy'&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>The encrypted messaging app, based in Dubai, has positioned itself as an alternative to US-owned platforms, which have been criticised for their commercial exploitation of users' personal data.</p>

<p>Telegram has committed to never disclosing any information about its users.</p>

<p>In a rare interview given to right-wing talk show host Tucker Carlson in April, Durov said he got the idea to launch an encrypted messaging app after coming under pressure from the Russian government when working at VK, a social network he created before selling it and leaving Russia in 2014.</p>

<p>He said he then tried to settle in Berlin, London, Singapore and San Francisco before choosing Dubai, which he praised for its business environment and "neutrality".</p>

<p>People "love the independence. They also love the privacy, the freedom, (there are) a lot of reasons why somebody would switch to Telegram," Durov told Carlson.</p>

<p>He said at the time that the platform had more than 900 million active users.</p>

<p>By basing itself in the United Arab Emirates, Telegram has been able to shield itself from moderation laws at a time when Western countries are pressuring large platforms to remove illegal content.</p>

<p>Telegram allows groups of up to 200,000 members, which has led to accusations that it makes it easier for false information to spread virally, as well as for users to disseminate neo-Nazi, paedophilic, conspiratorial and terrorist content.</p>

<p>Competitor messaging service WhatsApp introduced worldwide limits on message forwarding in 2019 after it was accused of enabling the spread of false information in India that led to lynchings.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/2u92qbao_pavel-durov_625x300_25_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mr Durov was expected to appear in court on Sunday. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>