<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 07:19:58 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-unrest-live-updates-nobel-laureate-muhammad-yunus-named-chief-adviser-of-interim-government-6280732]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Nobel Laureate Muhammad Yunus Named Chief Adviser Of Bangladesh Interim Government: Updates]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-unrest-live-updates-nobel-laureate-muhammad-yunus-named-chief-adviser-of-interim-government-6280732]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 07:19:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Nobel Peace Prize laureate Muhammad Yunus was named chief adviser of Bangladesh's interim government on Tuesday, a day after Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina resigned and fled the country following a violent crackdown on a student-led uprising.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Nobel Peace Prize laureate Muhammad Yunus was named chief adviser of Bangladesh's interim government on Tuesday, a day after Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina resigned and fled the country following a violent crackdown on a student-led uprising.</p>

<p>Muhammad Yunus was appointed to the post by Bangladesh President Mohammed Shahabuddin after he held meetings with student leaders and chiefs of the three military services, local media reported late on Tuesday, citing a statement and officials from the president's office.</p>

<p>Student protesters had threatened more demonstrations if parliament was not dissolved.</p>

<p>The movement that toppled Hasina rose out of demonstrations against public sector job quotas for families of veterans of Bangladesh's 1971 independence war, seen by critics as a means to reserve jobs for allies of the ruling party.</p>

<p>About 300 people were killed and thousands injured in violence that had ripped through the country since July.</p>

<h3><strong>Here are the LIVE updates on Bangladesh unrest:</strong><br />
&nbsp;</h3>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/n344til8_bangladesh-parliament-unrest-reuters_625x300_07_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Bangladesh Unrest Updates: About 300 people were killed and thousands injured in violence.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-unrest-nobel-laureate-muhammad-yunus-to-lead-bangladesh-after-shunning-politics-6280701]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Nobel Laureate Muhammad Yunus To Lead Bangladesh After Shunning Politics]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-unrest-nobel-laureate-muhammad-yunus-to-lead-bangladesh-after-shunning-politics-6280701]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 07:09:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Bangladesh is pinning its hopes on one of the nation's most acclaimed intellectuals to bring stability to a country scarred by coups and political upheaval.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bangladesh is pinning its hopes on one of the nation's most acclaimed intellectuals to bring stability to a country scarred by coups and political upheaval.</p>

<p>Muhammad Yunus, whose work alleviating poverty won him a Nobel Peace Prize, was named the head of a new interim government on Tuesday following the sudden ouster of Sheikh Hasina as prime minister this week. Though he's mostly stayed away from politics, Yunus is one of Bangladesh's most famous faces and brings considerable clout with Western elites.</p>

<p>Restoring normalcy to Bangladesh won't be a small feat for Yunus. Over the past few weeks, clashes between protesters and security personnel cost the lives of more than 300 people, one of the worst outbreaks of violence in the South Asian nation's history. And while Hasina lifted millions out of poverty through garment exports, economic growth has lately stalled in Bangladesh, prompting the International Monetary Fund to step in with bailout funds.</p>

<p>The military-backed appointment of Yunus to temporarily lead Bangladesh is a remarkable turn of events for the economist. Over the past couple of years, Yunus has spent much of his time inside Dhaka's courtrooms, fighting about 200 charges against him and his associates, including allegations of money laundering and graft. He and his supporters say Hasina's government was behind the legal pressure and perhaps saw him as a threat to her power. She denied those accusations.</p>

<p>Yunus, 84, is best known for founding Grameen Bank and pioneering microcredit - providing tiny business loans to the world's poorest people, most of them women. Though he's spent much of his life in the public eye, politics is largely unexplored terrain. In 2007, the Bangladeshi government splintered, and the military seized power. Yunus, who'd never run for office, considered forming a new party to fill the vacuum, but ultimately scrapped the idea within a few weeks.</p>

<p>"I feel very uncomfortable with politics," he said in an interview earlier this year.</p>

<p>Yunus brings star power to the role and is a popular choice with many Western governments. His supporters span industries and continents. Over the years, he's cultivated friendships with European royals, business titans like Richard Branson and the Clintons, who helped Yunus expand his microcredit initiatives to the US. His friends say he's a rare visionary with a genuine commitment to Bangladesh and uplifting the poor.</p>

<p>"He is the voice of the people left behind," said Paul Polman, a former chief executive of Unilever Plc and a close friend. "He's a moral leader. He's not somebody who likes to talk about himself. He likes to talk about the people he serves."</p>

<p>That reputation has endeared him to many in Bangladesh, including the military, which had previously supported his first foray into politics. After winning the Nobel Peace Prize in 2006, thousands of Bangladeshis crowded venues just to hear him speak. Many still bow and touch their hearts when they see him. Over the past decade, Yunus has focused on expanding dozens of social businesses, including ones that offer free health care, vocational training and phone services to poorer Bangladeshis.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Muhammad Yunus in his office in Dhaka." id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/4dhpif0g_muhammad-yunus-bloomberg_625x300_07_August_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Muhammad Yunus in his office in Dhaka." /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">Muhammad Yunus in his office in Dhaka.<br />
<span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: Bloomberg</span></p>
</div>

<p>Whether Yunus pivots more deliberately into politics - or simply fills a hole before elections are held - remains unclear. As protesters swarmed Dhaka's streets in recent weeks, Yunus spoke out publicly against the violence and characterized Hasina's crackdown as a threat to democracy - but he made no mention of ambitions to take a more formal role in shaping a new government.</p>

<p>"I'm not a politician," he said in the interview earlier this year. "This is the last thing I will ever do."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/b23juut8_muhammad-yunus-bloomberg_625x300_07_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Muhammad Yunus is one of Bangladesh's most famous faces.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/google-antitrust-ruling-may-pose-20-billion-risk-for-apple-report-6280471]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Google Antitrust Ruling May Pose $20 Billion Risk For Apple: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/google-antitrust-ruling-may-pose-20-billion-risk-for-apple-report-6280471]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 05:47:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Apple's lucrative deal with Google could be under threat after a U.S. judge ruled that the Alphabet-owned search giant was operating an illegal monopoly.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Apple's lucrative deal with Google could be under threat after a U.S. judge ruled that the Alphabet-owned search giant was operating an illegal monopoly.</p>

<p>A potential remedy for Google to avoid antitrust actions could involve terminating the agreement, which makes its search engine a default on Apple devices, Wall Street analysts said on Tuesday.</p>

<p>Google pays Apple $20 billion annually, or about 36% of what it earns from search advertising made through the Safari browser, for the privilege, according to Morgan Stanley analysts.</p>

<p>If the deal is undone, the iPhone maker could take a 4-6% hit to its profit, the analysts estimated.</p>

<p>The pact runs until at least September 2026 and Apple has the right to unilaterally extend it for another two years, according to media reports in May that cited a document filed by the Department of Justice in the antitrust case.</p>

<p>"The most likely outcome now is the judge rules Google must no longer pay for default placement or that companies like Apple must proactively prompt users to select their search engine rather than setting a default and allowing consumers to make changes in settings if they wish," Evercore ISI analysts said.</p>

<p>Apple's shares were trading flat on Tuesday, underperforming a recovery in the broader market after Monday's global selloff. Alphabet was little changed, after falling 4.5% in the previous session.</p>

<p>"The message here is that if you've got a dominant market position with a product, you'd better avoid the use of exclusive agreements and make sure any agreement you make gives the buyer free choice to substitute away," said Herbert Hovenkamp, a professor of law at the University of Pennsylvania.</p>

<p>To be sure, the "remedy" phase could be lengthy, followed by potential appeals to the U.S. Court of Appeals, the District of Columbia Circuit and the U.S. Supreme Court. The legal wrangling could play out into 2026.</p>

<p><strong>AI TILT</strong></p>

<p>Still, if the tie-up is scrapped, Apple will have several options including offering customers alternatives such as Microsoft Bing to customers, or potentially a new search product powered by OpenAI.</p>

<p>Analysts agree that the ruling will speed up Apple's move towards AI-powered search services. It recently announced that it would bring OpenAI's ChatGPT chatbot to its devices.</p>

<p>In a shift away from exclusive deals that would help Apple ward off regulatory scrutiny, the company has said it is also in talks with Google to add the Gemini chatbot and plans to add other AI models as well.</p>

<p>Apple is also revamping Siri with AI technology, giving it more control to handle tasks that had proven tricky in the past such as writing emails and interacting with messages.</p>

<p>While those efforts are expected to make little money in the coming years, they could help capitalize on the new technology.</p>

<p>"Apple could see this as a temporary setback, especially since it earns a lot from the Google search deal, but it is also an opportunity for them to pivot to AI solutions for search," said Gadjo Sevilla, analyst at Emarketer.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-01/ahh14fto_google-apple-logo-reuters_625x300_28_January_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[If the deal is undone, the iPhone maker could take a 4-6% hit to its profit, the analysts estimated.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-calls-to-swiftly-eliminate-new-hamas-chief-yahya-sinwar-6280440]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Calls To "Swiftly Eliminate" New Hamas Chief]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-calls-to-swiftly-eliminate-new-hamas-chief-yahya-sinwar-6280440]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 05:32:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel's foreign minister called on Tuesday to "swiftly eliminate" Yahya Sinwar, who was appointed by Hamas as the group's new political leader replacing Ismail Haniyeh who was killed in Tehran last week.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel's foreign minister called on Tuesday to "swiftly eliminate" Yahya Sinwar, who was appointed by Hamas as the group's new political leader replacing Ismail Haniyeh who was killed in Tehran last week.</p>

<p>"The appointment of arch-terrorist Yahya Sinwar as the new leader of Hamas, replacing Ismail Haniyeh, is yet another compelling reason to swiftly eliminate him and wipe this vile organisation off the face of the Earth," Foreign Minister Israel Katz said in a statement on social media site X.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/n6di67mg_israel-katz_625x300_07_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel's foreign minister called on Tuesday to "swiftly eliminate" Yahya Sinwar.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musks-x-sues-advertisers-over-boycott-6280356]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Now It Is War": Elon Musk's X Sues Advertisers Over Boycott]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musks-x-sues-advertisers-over-boycott-6280356]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 05:01:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Elon Musk's X sued an advertising group and several large corporations on Tuesday accusing them of causing billions of dollars of losses by "illegally" boycotting the social media platform.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Elon Musk's X sued an advertising group and several large corporations on Tuesday accusing them of causing billions of dollars of losses by "illegally" boycotting the social media platform.</p>

<p>"We tried peace for 2 years, now it is war," the billionaire founder of Tesla and SpaceX said on X, which he acquired in late 2022.</p>

<p>The antitrust suit, filed in a federal court in Texas, targets the World Federation of Advertisers (WFA), Unilever, Mars, CVS Health and Orsted, a Danish energy company.</p>

<p>It accuses WFA, through an initiative known as the Global Alliance for Responsible Media (GARM), of conspiring with the companies and others to "collectively withhold billions of dollars in advertising revenue" from X, formerly Twitter.</p>

<p>A number of advertisers left Twitter following Musk's takeover amid concerns about the level of content moderation under the new ownership and Musk's own controversial musings on the site.</p>

<p>X CEO Linda Yaccarino, in a video posted on the platform on Tuesday, said X was the victim of a "systematic illegal boycott."</p>

<p>"They conspired to boycott X which threatens our ability to thrive in the future," Yaccarino said. "No small group of people should be able to monopolize what gets monetized."</p>

<p>X is seeking a jury trial and unspecified damages.</p>

<p>According to The New York Times, citing internal company documents, X earned $114 million in revenue in the United States in the second quarter of this year, down 25 percent from the first quarter and down 53 percent from the same period last year. &nbsp;</p>

<p>The lawsuit was filed one day after Musk filed suit in California against OpenAI, accusing its co-founders Sam Altman and Greg Brockman of betraying the artificial intelligence company's founding mission.</p>

<p>Musk invested in the San Francisco-based OpenAI in 2015 but left three years later.</p>

<p>He is accusing OpenAI, Altman and Brockman of fraud, conspiracy and false advertising.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/8trrs42_elon-musk_625x300_15_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["We tried peace for 2 years, now it is war," X CEO Elon Musk said in a post.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/deeply-concerned-about-reports-of-violence-in-bangladesh-us-6280301]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Deeply Concerned About Reports Of Violence In Bangladesh: US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/deeply-concerned-about-reports-of-violence-in-bangladesh-us-6280301]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 04:42:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United States has expressed deep concerns about the continued violence in Bangladesh including attacks on members of religious or political groups.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;The United States has expressed deep concerns about the continued violence in Bangladesh including attacks on members of religious or political groups.</p>

<p>"We are deeply concerned about continued reports of violence in Bangladesh - including violence directed at members of religious or political groups. We are equally concerned about reports of violence against police and law enforcement," a State Department spokesperson told PTI on Tuesday.</p>

<p>"We repeat our call for de-escalation on all sides and a return to calm. This is not a time for retribution or revenge," the spokesperson said in response to a question. "As a friend and partner to the Bangladeshi people, the United States will continue to support Bangladesh's democratic aspirations and promote respect for human rights for all," said the spokesperson.</p>

<p>Bangladesh is going through an unprecedented crisis with Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina, who was in power for 15 years, resigning and fleeing the country after a protest against a jobs quota scheme snowballed into a massive agitation against her and her government. More than 300 people have died during the past few tumultuous weeks.</p>

<p>The Hindu American Foundation (HAF) said reports about such incidents including ransacking, and in some cases burning, of Hindu temples have come from across Bangladesh.</p>

<p>While the full extent to which religious minorities are being targeted in this greater unrest is not yet fully clear, the picture is deeply concerning, the HAF said in a statement.</p>

<p>"These attacks are heartbreaking, but unsurprising. It is well documented that prior to the toppling of Sheikh Hasina's government, Bangladesh's Hindu population has been targeted and harassed in sections of the country for many years now," HAF director of Policy Research Anita Joshi said.</p>

<p>"The Bangladesh military is reportedly forming an interim government, and so we urge local law enforcement and military leadership to ensure the safety of all Bangladesh's religious minorities, protecting their homes, business, and places of worship in this moment of turmoil," Mr Joshi said.</p>

<p>"The HAF has also called on the US State Department to work with Bangladesh's military leaders and interim government to immediately protect religious minorities from violence as the country seeks to restore order," Mr Joshi said.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/8qd6fj9g_bangladesh-protests-afp-_625x300_05_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Bangladesh Unrest: More than 300 people have died during the past few tumultuous weeks.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/will-not-tolerate-attacks-on-troops-in-middle-east-warns-us-6280240]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Will Not Tolerate" Attacks On Troops In Middle East, Warns US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/will-not-tolerate-attacks-on-troops-in-middle-east-warns-us-6280240]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 04:29:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United States will not tolerate attacks on American troops in the Middle East, Defense Secretary Lloyd Austin said Tuesday, after rocket fire in Iraq wounded seven US per]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United States will not tolerate attacks on American troops in the Middle East, Defense Secretary Lloyd Austin said Tuesday, after rocket fire in Iraq wounded seven US personnel.</p>

<p>The Monday attack was the third in just over three weeks on Ain al-Assad base in western Iraq, which hosts American troops as well as other personnel from the US-led coalition against the Islamic State jihadist group.</p>

<p>"Make no mistake, the United States will not tolerate attacks on our personnel in the region," Austin told a news conference in Annapolis.</p>

<p>A US defense official said earlier in the day that the attack wounded five American military personnel and two contractors, all of whom are in stable condition.</p>

<p>A Pentagon statement on a call between Austin and his Israeli counterpart Yoav Gallant described the rocket fire as an "Iran-aligned militia attack on US forces" and said the two agreed that it "marked a dangerous escalation."</p>

<p>Such attacks were frequent early in the war between Israel and Hamas Palestinian militants in Gaza, but until recently had largely halted.</p>

<p>The latest rocket fire comes as fears grow of an attack by Iran and its allies on Israel in retaliation for the killing of top Hamas and Hezbollah figures in strikes either blamed on or claimed by Israel.</p>

<p>The killings are among the most serious series of tit-for-tat attacks that have heightened fears of a regional conflagration stemming from the Gaza war.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-01/bu1pmqlg_lloyd-austin_625x300_23_January_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US Defense Secretary Lloyd Austin warned Tuesday after seven troops injured in rocket attack in Iraq.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-unrest-mob-sets-hindu-musician-rahul-anandas-house-on-fire-in-dhaka-6280212]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Mob Sets Hindu Musician Rahul Ananda's House On Fire In Dhaka]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-unrest-mob-sets-hindu-musician-rahul-anandas-house-on-fire-in-dhaka-6280212]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 04:17:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The house of Hindu musician Rahul Ananda was looted and set on fire by an angry mob following the fall of Sheikh Hasina's government. The mob attacked the musician's residence, located in Dhaka's Dhanmondi 32, on Monday afternoon.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The house of Hindu musician Rahul Ananda was looted and set on fire by an angry mob following the fall of Sheikh Hasina's government in Bangladesh. The mob attacked the musician's residence, located in Dhaka's Dhanmondi 32, on Monday afternoon.</p>

<p>According to reports, Mr Ananda, his wife, and their son managed to escape the attack unharmed but the attackers looted whatever they could find in the artist's house.</p>

<p>The mob stole valuable items and destroyed the home, including Ananda's extensive collection of over 3,000 handmade musical instruments.</p>

<p>Speaking with The Daily Star, a Bangladeshi English-language daily newspaper, a close family source of Mr Ananda said that the attackers first broke the gate and then began ravaging the house.</p>

<p>"They took everything from furniture and mirrors to valuables. After that, they torched the whole house along with Rahul da's musical instruments," the family source told the newspaper.</p>

<p>Musician, lyricist, and singer Rahul Ananda runs a popular folk band in Dhaka called Joler Gaan.</p>

<p>Attacks on minorities, including Hindus, in Bangladesh have intensified a day after the prime minister was ousted following mass protests over a controversial job quota in government services.</p>

<p>According to news agency AFP, several houses, businesses, and religious sites have been torched and vandalised in the last two days by violent protesters.</p>

<p>Amid the violence against minorities in Bangladesh, Foreign Minister S Jaishankar said on Tuesday that New Delhi was "monitoring the situation with regard to the status of minorities."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/5fe1n7b8_rahul-ananda_625x300_07_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Musician, lyricist, and singer Rahul Ananda runs a popular folk band in Dhaka called Joler Gaan.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pak-citizen-arrested-in-alleged-iran-plot-to-kill-us-official-politician-6279791]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Pak Citizen Arrested In Alleged Iran Plot To Kill US Official, Politician]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pak-citizen-arrested-in-alleged-iran-plot-to-kill-us-official-politician-6279791]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 01:58:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Pakistani man with ties to Iran has been arrested for allegedly plotting to assassinate a US official in retaliation for the US killing of Revolutionary Guards commander Qassem Soleimani, the Justice Department said Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Pakistani man with ties to Iran has been arrested for allegedly plotting to assassinate a US official in retaliation for the US killing of Revolutionary Guards commander Qassem Soleimani, the Justice Department said Tuesday.</p>

<p>Asif Raza Merchant, 46, allegedly sought to hire a hitman to assassinate a politician or a US government official in the United States, the department said in a statement.</p>

<p>"For years, the Justice Department has been working aggressively to counter Iran's brazen and unrelenting efforts to retaliate against American public officials for the killing of Iranian General Soleimani," Attorney General Merrick Garland said.</p>

<p>Soleimani, the architect of Iran's foreign military operations, was killed in a US drone strike in Baghdad in January 2020. Iranian officials have repeatedly vowed to take "revenge" for the killing.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The Justice Department will spare no resource to disrupt and hold accountable those who would seek to carry out Iran's lethal plotting against American citizens," Garland said.</p>

<p>The intended victim was not identified but the attorney general said no evidence has emerged to link Merchant with the July 13 assassination attempt against former president Donald Trump in Butler, Pennsylvania.</p>

<p>FBI Director Christopher Wary said the Pakistani national had "close ties to Iran" and that the alleged murder-for-hire plot was "straight out of the Iranian playbook."</p>

<p>Another FBI official said the assassins Merchant allegedly tried to hire were in fact undercover FBI agents.</p>

<p>Merchant was arrested on July 12 as he planned to leave the country.</p>

<p>In August 2022, the United States charged a member of the Revolutionary Guards with plotting to assassinate former US National Security Advisor John Bolton.</p>

<p>The Justice Department said Shahram Poursafi, who remains at large, had offered to pay an individual in the United States $300,000 to kill Bolton.</p>

<p>Iran has dismissed the claim that it had plotted to kill Bolton as "fiction."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/op07qhu_-us-department-of-justice-_625x300_30_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A Pakistani man with ties to Iran has been arrested for allegedly plotting to assassinate a US official.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nobel-laureate-muhammad-yunus-to-lead-bangladesh-interim-government-6279601]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Nobel Laureate Muhammad Yunus To Lead Bangladesh Interim Government]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nobel-laureate-muhammad-yunus-to-lead-bangladesh-interim-government-6279601]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:56:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Bangladesh's Nobel-winning microfinance pioneer Muhammad Yunus has been tapped to lead an interim government after the ouster of prime minister Sheikh Hasina, the country's presidency announced early Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bangladesh's Nobel-winning microfinance pioneer Muhammad&nbsp;Yunus has been tapped to lead an interim government after the ouster of prime minister Sheikh Hasina, the country's presidency announced early Wednesday.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The decision "to form an interim government with Yunus as its chief" was taken at a meeting of President Mohammed Shahabuddin, military leaders and the heads of the Students Against Discrimination group, Shahabuddin's press office said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Nahid Islam, a leader of the student group, confirmed the decision to reporters after three hours of talks at the presidential palace.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The president has asked the people to help ride out the crisis. Quick formation of an interim government is necessary to overcome the crisis," Shahabuddin's office said in a statement.</p>

<p>Shahabuddin also sacked the national police chief in the wake of deadly protests that sparked Hasina's departure and named a replacement, his office said.</p>

<p>Islam called the talks "fruitful" and said that Shahabuddin had agreed that the interim government "will be formed within the shortest time" possible.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/8v0rqhuo_muhammad-yunus-reuters_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Muhammad Yunus won the 2006 Nobel Peace Prize for providing tiny loans to the rural poor.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/families-of-people-killed-in-bangladesh-protests-place-11-point-demands-6279480]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Families Of People Killed In Bangladesh Protests Place 11-Point Demands]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/families-of-people-killed-in-bangladesh-protests-place-11-point-demands-6279480]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:25:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Families of the persons killed in Bangladesh's student protests on Tuesday placed 11-point demands, including rehabilitation by providing jobs, before the interim government,]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Families of the persons killed in Bangladesh's student protests on Tuesday placed 11-point demands, including rehabilitation by providing jobs, before the interim government which is set to be formed to replace the ousted Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina's regime.</p>

<p>The death count in the massive protests following Hasina-led government's announcement of the quota system in jobs has risen to 440, with more than 200 people killed in the renewed spell of violence towards the weekend as violent clashes erupted between police and mostly student protesters.</p>

<p>A statement, signed by Harun-ur Rashid, the convener of a proposed "Committee on Families of Injured and Killed in Anti-Discriminatory Student Movement", said an initiative has been taken to collect accurate data on the families of the students, children, youth, elderly, men and women who were injured and killed in the violence.</p>

<p>The demands include providing Tk2,000-3,000 per month as a grant for all students from pre-primary to Masters based on age under a "Food-Card" programme, unemployment allowance of Tk3,000 to job aspirants, formation of an inquiry committee consisting of armed forces and students for the treatment of the injured in the anti-discrimination student movement and the speedy rehabilitation of the affected families, the Dhaka Tribune newspaper reported.</p>

<p>The demands also include direct government scholarships to students in private universities, changing the name of the educational institution established after various individuals of the Sheikh Hasina family and naming those after the martyrs Pilkhana Shaheed army officer, and also in memory of the martyrs killed in various movements and anti-discriminatory student protests.</p>

<p>Inclusion of the neutral ex-army and police force members of the peacekeeping mission in the United Nations on an urgent basis to improve the ongoing law and order situation and also the inclusion of Bangladesh National Cadet Corps (BNCC) and Bangladesh Scouts as their partners, the committee demanded.</p>

<p>The demand also included taking a quick initiative to recover all the illegal weapons used in the movement in the past days, consideration of redeployment of all categories of honest and efficient officers-employees who were deprived of promotion/compulsory retirement due to oppression and discrimination during the previous government.</p>

<p>Speedy recovery of money of big defaulters and money smuggled abroad, the speedy trial of big defaulters and money smugglers in military courts, and the inclusion of at least one person in the interim government from the active student families of the anti-quota movement, the injured families and families of those killed, it said.</p>

<p>The committee offered its deepest condolences to the bereaved families of those killed and injured in the movement and congratulated the army officers and soldiers at all levels of the armed forces, including the chief of the Bangladesh Army.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, in a video message issued by the police headquarters' media and public relations division on Tuesday, Inspector General of Police Chowdhury Abdullah Al Mamun urged leaders of all political parties and the Students Against Discrimination to make a call for not carrying out attacks on the police members and their establishments.</p>

<p>He said the army men have been assisting the police to ensure their security.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/jem8luuo_bangladesh-protest-_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The demands also include direct government scholarships to students in private universities. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-hamas-chief-named-following-ismail-haniyehs-assassination-6279281]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hamas Names New Chief After Ismail Haniyeh's Killing]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-hamas-chief-named-following-ismail-haniyehs-assassination-6279281]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 23:41:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hamas named Gaza Strip chief Yahya Sinwar as its new political leader on Tuesday, a week after his predecessor Ismail Haniyeh's killing in Tehran which has sent regional tensions soaring.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hamas named Gaza Strip chief Yahya Sinwar as its new political leader on Tuesday, after his predecessor Ismail Haniyeh's was killed in Tehran last week, sending regional tensions soaring.</p>

<p>"The Islamic Resistance Movement Hamas announces the selection of leader Yahya Sinwar as the head of the political bureau of the movement," a statement from the group said.</p>

<p>Minutes after the announcement, Hamas's armed wing, the Ezzedine Al-Qassam Brigades, said it fired a barrage of rockets from the Gaza Strip towards Israel.</p>

<p>The Israeli military and officials accuse Sinwar of being one of the masterminds of the October 7 attack on Israel, making him one of the country's most wanted operatives.</p>

<p>His appointment as the new chief of Hamas comes less than a week after Haniyeh was killed in Tehran.</p>

<p>Iran and Hamas have blamed Israel for his assassination. Israel has declined to comment on the killing.</p>

<p>Hamas's October 7 attack resulted in the death of 1,198 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on official Israeli figures.</p>

<p>During the attack, Hamas also seized 251 people, 111 of whom are still held captive in Gaza, including 39 the military says are dead.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory military campaign in Gaza has so far killed at least 39,653 people, according to the health ministry in the Hamas-run territory, which does not provide details on civilian and operative deaths.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/c59v6a28_hamas-leader-yehya-alsinwar_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chinese-academic-convicted-of-acting-as-foreign-agent-in-us-6279223]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Chinese Academic Convicted Of Acting As Foreign Agent In US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chinese-academic-convicted-of-acting-as-foreign-agent-in-us-6279223]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 23:31:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Wang Shujun was a naturalised US citizen.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Chinese academic was convicted on Tuesday of illegally acting as a foreign agent in the United States by collecting information about New York-based activists supporting democracy in China and sharing his findings with Beijing.</p>

<p>A jury found Wang Shujun guilty on four counts including acting as a foreign agent without notifying the US attorney general and lying to US authorities, following a week-long trial in Brooklyn federal court.</p>

<p>Federal prosecutors said Wang, a naturalised US citizen, portrayed himself as a fierce opponent of the ruling Chinese Communist Party to gain the trust of Hong Kong pro-democracy activists, advocates for Taiwanese independence and campaigners for Uyghur and Tibetan rights.</p>

<p>Prosecutors said Wang was actually spying on the activists and sharing his findings with four officials in China's Ministry of State Security (MSS), an intelligence service.</p>

<p>"He was living a double life," prosecutor Nina Gupta said in her closing argument on Monday. "That double life has now been revealed."</p>

<p>Wang, who emigrated to the United States in 1994, was arrested in March 2022.</p>

<p>Defense lawyer Zachary Margulis-Ohnuma said Wang spoke to the intelligence officials about the pro-democracy movement to win their support and promote social change, and was not acting as their agent.</p>

<p>"Why would a guy who devoted his life to toppling the Chinese regime try to help the Chinese regime?" Margulis-Ohnuma said in his summation on Monday.</p>

<p>The US Department of Justice has in recent years cracked down on what it calls "transnational repression" by US adversaries such as China and Iran.</p>

<p>That term refers to the surveillance, intimidation and in some cases attempted repatriation or murder of activists against those governments.</p>

<p>Last year, a former New York City police sergeant was convicted of acting as a Chinese agent by intimidating a US-based fugitive to return to his homeland and face charges.</p>

<p>US prosecutors have also charged four Chinese intelligence officers who allegedly acted as Wang's handlers. Those officers are at large and believed to be in China.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/889t6t5_chinese-academic-spy-reuters_625x300_06_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US Department of Justice has cracked down on what it calls "transnational repression" by US adversaries]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-army-confirms-death-of-last-missing-person-from-october-7-attack-6279222]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Army Confirms Death Of Last Missing Person From October 7 Attack]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-army-confirms-death-of-last-missing-person-from-october-7-attack-6279222]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 23:31:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Israeli military confirmed on Tuesday that Bilha Yinon, the last person listed as missing from the October 7 Hamas attack, was killed by militants that day.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Israeli military confirmed on Tuesday that Bilha Yinon, the last person listed as missing from the October 7 Hamas attack, was killed by Hamas that day.</p>

<p>"Today, IDF (Israel army) representatives officially informed the family of Bilha Yinon that she is no longer alive," the military said in a statement.</p>

<p>The Israeli military and investigators had carried out an extensive search for her, the statement said.</p>

<p>"As part of this effort, evidence was discovered in the area of Yinon's house that, after complex testing, enabled the verification of her identity," it said.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">We are devastated to share that Bilha Yinon who is the last person missing since October 7th has been confimed as dead.<br />
<br />
She was murdered alongside her husband Yaakov on October 7.<br />
<br />
May Bilha and Yaakov's memory be a blessing ? <a href="https://t.co/J6UR9OVmLl">pic.twitter.com/J6UR9OVmLl</a></p>
— Israel ישראל (@Israel) <a href="https://twitter.com/Israel/status/1820879796848791664?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 6, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Based on forensic evidence, Israeli experts determined that she was killed on October 7, the military added.</p>

<p>Hamas attacked southern Israeli communities on that day, resulting in the death of 1,198 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on official Israeli figures.</p>

<p>Hamas also seized 251 people, 111 of whom are still held captive in Gaza, including 39 the military says are dead.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory military campaign in Gaza has so far killed at least 39,653 people, according to the health ministry in the Hamas-run territory, which does not provide details on civilian and operative deaths.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/fsqgfopg_bilha-yinon_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Israeli military and investigators had carried out an extensive search for her]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/discovery-of-tiny-arm-bone-sheds-light-on-mysterious-hobbit-humans-6279069]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Discovery Of Tiny Arm Bone Sheds Light On Mysterious ''Hobbit'' Humans]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/discovery-of-tiny-arm-bone-sheds-light-on-mysterious-hobbit-humans-6279069]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 23:07:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The discovery of a tiny arm bone suggests that an ancient human dubbed "hobbits" only shrank down to their diminutive size after they arrived on an Indonesian island a million years ago, scientists said on Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The discovery of a tiny arm bone suggests that an ancient human dubbed "hobbits" only shrank down to their diminutive size after they arrived on an Indonesian island a million years ago, scientists said on Tuesday.</p>

<p>Much about the pint-sized Homo floresiensis has been shrouded in mystery since the first fossils suggesting their existence were found on the island of Flores in 2003.</p>

<p>These tool-using hominins are believed to have been living on the island as recently as 50,000 years ago, when our own species homo sapiens was already walking the Earth, including in nearby Australia.</p>

<p>From some 60,000-year-old teeth and a jawbone found in an island cave, scientists had previously estimated the hobbits were around 1.06 metres (3.5 feet) tall.</p>

<p>But the discovery of part of an upper arm bone as well as some teeth at an open-air island site on the island suggests some hobbits stood just one metre tall around 700,000 years ago, according to a study in the journal Nature Communications.</p>

<p>The bone was so small, that at first the international team of researchers thought it must have been from a child.</p>

<p>Study co-author Adam Brumm, an archaeologist at Australia's Griffith University, told AFP that it was the smallest humerus fossil of an adult hominin ever found.</p>

<h3><strong>'Truly epic'</strong></h3>

<p>The discovery could tip the scales in a heated debate among scientists about how H.floresiensis became so small.</p>

<p>One side argues that the hobbits -- nicknamed after the little heroes in JRR Tolkien's fantasy novels -- descended from an already small earlier hominin which arrived on Flores around a million years ago.</p>

<p>Others believe that it was our ancestor Homo erectus, which were roughly our size and had spread throughout Asia, that became trapped on the island, only to then evolve into the smaller H.floresiensis over the next 300,00 years.</p>

<p>The researchers behind the latest discovery believe it strongly supports the latter theory.</p>

<p>These ancient humans "reduced drastically in body size according to a well known evolutionary phenomenon known as island dwarfism," Brumm said.</p>

<p>Under this process, larger animals tend to shrink over time to adapt to their limited surroundings.</p>

<p>The tropical island was home to other smaller-than-normal mammals, including a cow-sized relative of the elephant.</p>

<p>The newly discovered teeth also look like smaller versions of those from Homo erectus, the researchers said.</p>

<p>"If we are correct, it seems that Homo erectus was somehow able to cross formidable deep-sea barriers to reach isolated islands like Flores," Brumm said.</p>

<p>"We don't know how they were doing this," he said, adding that "accidental 'rafting' on tsunami debris" was one possibility.</p>

<p>Once these ancient humans were trapped on the island, they managed to survive for hundreds of thousands of years, evolving into "strange new forms," Brumm said.</p>

<p>Mark Moore, an archaeologist at Australia's University of New England not involved in the study, said the discovery means "we can now confidently say" that the Homo erectus theory is the more likely scenario.</p>

<p>Moore, who has studied the stone tools used by the hobbits, told AFP that this "technology did not shield our cousin species from the forces of biological evolution".</p>

<p>That the hobbits changed so much over just 300,000 years was "a reminder of the power of natural selection," he added.</p>

<p>"The evolutionary story of this group of hominins is truly epic."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/kn94i4j8_hobbit-humans_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The newly discovered teeth also look like smaller versions of those from Homo erectus]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-2024-biden-calls-kamala-harris-pick-for-vice-president-tim-walz-a-great-decision-6279068]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Powerful Voice For People": Biden On Kamala Harris' Vice President Pick]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-2024-biden-calls-kamala-harris-pick-for-vice-president-tim-walz-a-great-decision-6279068]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 23:07:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden said Tim Walz would be a "powerful voice for working people and America's great middle class."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden on Tuesday praised the selection of Minnesota Governor Tim Walz as Kamala Harris's running mate, saying they would be a "powerful voice for working people and America's great middle class."</p>

<p>"The first major decision a party nominee makes is their choice for vice president. And Kamala Harris has made a great decision in choosing Governor Tim Walz to be her running mate," Biden posted on X.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/mi5arts_tim-walz-and-biden-afp_625x300_06_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Biden said Tim Walz would be a "powerful voice for working people and America's great middle class."]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/regained-freedom-after-sheikh-hasina-ouster-bangladeshis-dream-of-better-future-6278690]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[After Sheikh Hasina's Ouster, Bangladeshis Dream Of Better Future]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/regained-freedom-after-sheikh-hasina-ouster-bangladeshis-dream-of-better-future-6278690]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 22:04:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[One day after the military took control of Bangladesh following the ouster of the prime minister, the parliament in the capital Dhaka was busy with protesters coming to celebrate.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>One day after the military took control of Bangladesh following the ouster of the prime minister, the parliament in the capital Dhaka was busy with protesters coming to celebrate.</p>

<p>More than a month of deadly protests in which at least 422 people were killed culminated Monday in the deadliest day of violence and the end of the autocratic rule of Sheikh Hasina, who fled by helicopter to India.</p>

<p>"It's the freedom of the young generation," said student Parvez Hossain, 30, among the crowds in front of the building, which was empty of lawmakers after parliament was dissolved.</p>

<p>Protesters stormed the building on Monday, jumping on tables and setting off what appeared to be smoke bombs.</p>

<p>Hossain spoke of his hope for a new start and idealism for a better future.</p>

<p>"Now we have regained the freedom of Bangladesh," he said. "We want to build the country in a new way again."</p>

<p>The unrest began last month with student-led protests against civil service job quotas and escalated into mass demonstrations calling for Hasina, who had been in power since 2009, to quit.</p>

<p>But while busy streets and open shops in Dhaka gave the initial appearance that daily life was nearly back to business as usual, at least 10 people were killed on Tuesday, and security remained a concern.</p>

<p>The charred ruins of offices of the former ruling party and looted houses of those seen loyal to Hasina showed the scale of bitter violence in the chaos at the end of her rule.</p>

<p>That included violence against police who reported revenge attacks by those who blamed officers for trying to crush protests with deadly force.</p>

<h3><strong>'Anger of the people'</strong></h3>

<p>Police unions said their members had gone on strike Tuesday "until the security of every member of the police is secured".</p>

<p>The union also apologised for police actions against the protesters.</p>

<p>With the police on strike, citizens took it upon themselves to direct traffic, with students standing at junctions and bringing some order to the stream of cars.</p>

<p>Nazrul Islam, 60, who works in pharmaceuticals, said students had lit the spark to allow people to protest wider grievances.</p>

<p>"With the students' protest, the anger of the people also burst. It was impossible to stop this wave," he said.</p>

<p>"Everyone had a hidden anger. Now we just want that no dictator can come to power again."</p>

<p>Some businesses and homes owned by Hindus -- a group seen by some in the Muslim-majority nation as close to Hasina -- were also attacked, witnesses said.</p>

<p>Bangladeshi rights groups, as well as US and European Union diplomats, said Tuesday they were "very concerned" about reports of attacks on religious, ethnic and other minority groups.</p>

<p>Curious citizens, meanwhile, picked through the ransacked interior of Hasina's palace in Dhaka, clicking photographs in front of her trashed furniture and marvelling at the opulent luxury.</p>

<p>Bangladesh's new leadership now rests on the powerful army who have said they will form an interim government.</p>

<p>But whatever the future may be, 60-year-old bicycle rickshaw taxi driver Nurul Islam said he was pleased Hasina was gone.</p>

<p>"People didn't have any peace for the last 15 years," he said, pausing to rest in the bustling street.</p>

<p>"She was not elected even by the people's votes; rather, she captured power as a dictator."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/doatd29g_bangladesh-protest_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Bangladesh's new leadership now rests on the powerful army]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ultra-orthodox-anti-draft-protesters-break-into-israeli-army-base-6278456]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ultra-Orthodox Anti-draft Protesters Break Into Israeli Army Base]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ultra-orthodox-anti-draft-protesters-break-into-israeli-army-base-6278456]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 21:31:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Dozens of ultra-Orthodox Jews protesting against compulsory military service for their community broke into an army base near Tel Aviv on Tuesday, the military said in a statement.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dozens of ultra-Orthodox Jews protesting against compulsory military service for their community broke into an army base near Tel Aviv on Tuesday, the military said in a statement.</p>

<p>"Over the past few hours, dozens of protestors attempted to break into the Tel Hashomer base during protests that took place outside of the base", a military statement said.</p>

<p>The demonstrators "managed to infiltrate the Adjutant Corps Monument adjacent to the base fence" before being cleared out by police, it said.</p>

<p>Tel Hashomer, located east of Tel Aviv, is the largest base for newly enlisted army recruits in Israel.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said it "condemns this violent behaviour and insists that the protestors be brought to justice".</p>

<p>"The enlistment of ultra-orthodox citizens is an operational necessity and is being conducted in accordance with the law", and the military is "determined" to press ahead with it, the statement added</p>

<p>Historically exempt from compulsory military service, ultra-Orthodox seminary students are being called up while Israel's war in Gaza and a potential conflict with Hezbollah on the northern border sap resources and fuel resentment of those who do not have to serve.</p>

<p>The call-ups follow a ruling in June by Israel's top court that exemptions from mandatory service for ultra-Orthodox men were discriminatory and that the state must draft them.</p>

<p>Under longstanding arrangements, ultra-Orthodox Jews, who make up about 13 percent of Israel's 10 million population, had not been subject to the draft.</p>

<p>Members of the largely insular community, where young men of recruitment age typically study in Jewish seminaries, have taken to the streets to protest conscription, leading to clashes with police in Jerusalem.</p>

<p>Ultra-Orthodox men had already clashed with police outside Tal Hashomer on Monday before being dispersed or physically carried away.</p>

<p>In July, one leading ultra-Orthodox rabbi, Dov Lando, urged Yeshiva students to ignore the summons orders, writing in the Yated Neeman daily that it was "war" against religious Jews.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/6bqqoldo_israel-flag_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-2024-tim-walz-says-honor-of-a-lifetime-to-be-kamala-harriss-vice-president-pick-6278344]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Tim Walz Says "Honor Of A Lifetime" To Be Kamala Harris's Veep Pick]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-2024-tim-walz-says-honor-of-a-lifetime-to-be-kamala-harriss-vice-president-pick-6278344]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 21:18:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA["I'm all in. It reminds me a bit of the first day of school. So, let's get this done, folks!" Walz said on X.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kamala Harris's newly unveiled running mate Tim Walz said Tuesday it was "the honor of a lifetime" to be the Democratic Party's vice presidential candidate for the US election in November.</p>

<p>"I'm all in. It reminds me a bit of the first day of school. So, let's get this done, folks!" Walz said on X.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/phkib1e_tim-walz-afp_625x300_06_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Tim Walz said it was "honor of a lifetime" to be the Democratic Party's vice presidential candidate]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-aircraft-fly-at-low-altitude-over-beirut-breaking-sound-barrier-6277717]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Panic In Beirut As Israeli Warplanes Break Sound Barrier Thrice]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-aircraft-fly-at-low-altitude-over-beirut-breaking-sound-barrier-6277717]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 19:48:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli warplanes swooped low over the Lebanese capital Beirut on Tuesday, setting off a series of sonic booms that rattled windows across the city minutes before the head of Lebanon's Hezbollah was set to give an address.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli warplanes swooped low over the Lebanese capital Beirut on Tuesday, setting off a series of sonic booms that rattled windows across the city minutes before the head of Lebanon's Hezbollah was set to give an address.</p>

<p>The loud booms sent residents rushing to open their windows to prevent the glass from shattering, or standing on their balconies to get a glimpse of the planes flying over. There was no comment from the Israeli military.</p>

<p>In the capital's southern suburbs, a Hezbollah stronghold, members and supporters of the Lebanese armed group had gathered to watch a televised speech by its leader to mark the one-week anniversary of Israel's killing of a senior military commander.</p>

<p>As he began, Sayyed Hassan Nasrallah said the sonic booms were intended to provoke those gathered for the memorial.</p>

<p>The strike that killed commander Fuad Shukr was the second time Israel had struck the southern suburbs in 10 months of hostilities between Hezbollah and the Israeli military that are taking place in parallel with the Gaza war.</p>

<p>Hezbollah earlier on Tuesday said it launched a swarm of attack drones at two military sites near Acre in northern Israel and also attacked an Israeli military vehicle in another location.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said a number of hostile drones were identified crossing from Lebanon and one was intercepted.</p>

<p>Israeli medical officials said seven people were evacuated to hospital, to the south of the coastal city of Nahariya, one in critical condition.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said an initial investigation indicated the injuries were caused by an interceptor that "missed the target and hit the ground, injuring several civilians." It said the incident was still under review.</p>

<p>Reuters journalists saw one impact site near a bus stop on a main road outside Nahariya.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said in a statement sirens sounded around Acre, but that turned out to be a false alarm. It said its air force struck two Hezbollah facilities in south Lebanon.</p>

<p>Fears are rising that the Middle East could tip into full-blown war following vows by Hezbollah to avenge Shukr's killing, and by Iran to respond to the assassination in Tehran last week of the head of Palestinian group Hamas.</p>

<p>A Hezbollah source told Reuters that "the response to the assassination of commander Fuad Shukr has not yet come".</p>

<p>Earlier on Tuesday, four Hezbollah fighters were killed in a strike on a home in the Lebanese town of Mayfadoun, nearly 30 km (19 miles) north of the border, medics and a security source said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/i0gaa9mo_israel-lebanon_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israeli warplanes flew low over the Lebanese capital]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>