<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 12:19:41 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sundar-pichai-on-why-google-invests-so-heavily-on-free-meals-to-employees-6845072]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Sundar Pichai On Why Google Invests So Heavily On Free Meals To Employees]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sundar-pichai-on-why-google-invests-so-heavily-on-free-meals-to-employees-6845072]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 12:19:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Google CEO Sundar Pichai has revealed why the company invests so heavily in its famous free meal policy. Contrary to popular belief, Mr Pichai explained these meals were not just perks, adding they served a deeper purpose.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Google CEO Sundar Pichai has revealed why the company invests so heavily in its famous free meal policy. Contrary to popular belief, Mr Pichai explained these meals were not just perks, adding they served a deeper purpose.</p>

<p>"I can recall several times, when I was working at Google early on, being in cafes, meeting someone else, talking and getting excited about something. So, it sparks creativity," Mr Pichai shared in an interview on Bloomberg's The David Rubenstein Show.</p>

<p>Sundar Pichai, who started working at Google as a Product Manager in 2004, said that some of the most brilliant ideas emerge during these communal meals.</p>

<p><strong>Read |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/food/google-employee-gives-a-glimpse-into-her-daily-work-meal-in-viral-video-6255425">Google Employee Gives A Glimpse Into Her Daily Work Meal In Viral Video</a></p>

<p>The CEO added that this collaborative environment, where employees gather over food, helps foster innovation. "The benefit that comes out of it dwarfs the cost," Mr Pichai remarked, saying the free meals weren't a financial burden but a long-term investment in creativity and community building.</p>

<p>Beyond the free meals, Mr Pichai noted that Google's employee-friendly initiatives positively impacted workplace dynamics. With over 1,82,000 employees globally, the tech giant attracts top talent, with approximately 90 per cent of job candidates accepting offers.</p>

<p>Discussing what Google looks for in potential hires, Mr Pichai said that criteria vary depending on the role. For engineering positions, he said, it was important to find skilled programmers who can adapt to new challenges. "We are really looking for 'superstar software engineers," he added.</p>

<p>Apart from complimentary meals, Google offers extensive health insurance, flexible remote work options, paid time off and wellness programmes, making it one of the most attractive workplaces in the industry.</p>

<p>However, despite the benefits, Sundar Pichai acknowledged that not all of Google's perks have remained intact in recent years. In 2023, the company announced plans to streamline its offerings, including reducing the hours of some office cafes and consolidating micro kitchens. However, he noted that Google's benefits still rank among the most generous in Silicon Valley, influencing other companies to adopt similar initiatives.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-04/2omc9mog_sundar-pichai_625x300_26_April_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sundar Pichai said Google's employee-friendly initiatives positively impact workplace dynamics. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/do-academics-respond-more-to-mails-from-melissa-or-rahul-study-reveals-6845266]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Do Academics Respond More To Mails From "Melissa" Or "Rahul"? Study Says...]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/do-academics-respond-more-to-mails-from-melissa-or-rahul-study-reveals-6845266]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 12:16:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A new research shows Australian academics responded differently to potential PhD students, depending on whether they were called "Melissa" or "Rahul".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Universities are supposed to be places where all students can learn, free from discrimination. A key part of this ideal is academics welcoming all students to study and research, regardless of their racial background.</p>

<div class="theconversation-article-body">
<p>But as our <a href="https://doi.org/10.22230/ijepl.2024v20n1a1401">new research</a> shows, Australian academics responded differently to potential PhD students, depending on whether they were called “Melissa” or “Rahul”.</p>

<h2><strong>Racism on campus</strong></h2>

<p>Many <a href="https://www.ubcpress.ca/the-equity-myth">overseas</a> and <a href="https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2014.969224">Australian studies</a> have shown racism is both a historical and ongoing problem for universities.</p>

<p>A <a href="https://findanexpert.unimelb.edu.au/news/13920-most-of-australia's-uni-leaders-are-white--male-and-grey.-this-lack-of-diversity-could-be-a-handicap">2020 Australian study</a> showed universities tend to be run by older, white men. A <a href="https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2021.1905361">2021 UK study</a> showed academics from different cultural backgrounds face racism at work.</p>

<p>But there has been less specific attention paid to those trying to become academics.</p>

<p>The main way people start an academic career is via a doctoral degree. In the Australian system, before a student is accepted they usually require an established academic to agree to supervise them. So a student's initial communication with a potential supervisor is very important.</p>

<figure class="align-center "><img alt="A group of young people sit around a table looking at a laptop. Books and papers are on the table." sizes="(min-width: 1466px) 754px, (max-width: 599px) 100vw, (min-width: 600px) 600px, 237px" src="https://images.theconversation.com/files/626389/original/file-20241017-17-9xxvfc.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;fit=clip" srcset="https://images.theconversation.com/files/626389/original/file-20241017-17-9xxvfc.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=400&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=1 600w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/626389/original/file-20241017-17-9xxvfc.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=30&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=400&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=2 1200w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/626389/original/file-20241017-17-9xxvfc.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=15&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=400&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=3 1800w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/626389/original/file-20241017-17-9xxvfc.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=503&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=1 754w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/626389/original/file-20241017-17-9xxvfc.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=30&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=503&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=2 1508w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/626389/original/file-20241017-17-9xxvfc.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=15&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=503&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=3 2262w" />
<figcaption><span class="caption">To start a PhD, students usually need to have a supervisor lined up.</span> <span class="attribution"><a class="source" href="https://www.shutterstock.com/image-photo/multiracial-group-young-students-studying-together-522965350">Jacob Lund/Shutterstock</a></span></figcaption>
</figure>

<h2><strong>How we set up our research</strong></h2>

<p>To investigate whether racism is playing a role at the entrance point to PhD study, in 2017 we sent about 7,000 emails from fictitious students to academics based at the main campuses of Australia's Group of Eight universities (billed as Australia's top research universities).</p>

<p>These are the Australian National University, Monash University, University of Adelaide, University of New South Wales, University of Melbourne, University of Sydney, University of Western Australia and University of Queensland.</p>

<p>We emailed staff ranked senior lecturer or above, as these are the levels most likely to be supervising PhD students. Academics were identified by university websites, and we sent emails to everyone who fit our rank criteria across all disciplines.</p>

<p>In this process, we found 70% of relevant academics were male and 84% were white. This did not improve in the more senior ranks – more than 68% of professors were white men.</p>

<h2><strong>What did the email say?</strong></h2>

<p>The emails asked for an meeting to talk about potential PhD supervision.</p>

<p>They were identical apart from the senders' names. These names were tested to be associated with male and female and with white-European, Indigenous, South Asian, Chinese and Arab identities. Recipients were randomly allocated to different name groups.</p>

<p>The emails indicated the sender was an Australia-based student with fluent English. It conveyed an interest in the recipient's research and urgency in meeting because the sender was only on campus for several days. It also noted “I have recently finished my honours degree” (a common path into a PhD in Australia) and was sent from a University of Sydney email address.</p>

<figure class="align-center "><img alt="A close up of hands typing on a laptop keyboard." sizes="(min-width: 1466px) 754px, (max-width: 599px) 100vw, (min-width: 600px) 600px, 237px" src="https://images.theconversation.com/files/626390/original/file-20241017-17-rp6zw0.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;fit=clip" srcset="https://images.theconversation.com/files/626390/original/file-20241017-17-rp6zw0.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=401&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=1 600w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/626390/original/file-20241017-17-rp6zw0.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=30&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=401&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=2 1200w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/626390/original/file-20241017-17-rp6zw0.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=15&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=401&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=3 1800w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/626390/original/file-20241017-17-rp6zw0.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=503&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=1 754w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/626390/original/file-20241017-17-rp6zw0.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=30&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=503&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=2 1508w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/626390/original/file-20241017-17-rp6zw0.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=15&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=503&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=3 2262w" />
<figcaption><span class="caption">We emailed about 7,000 senior academics as part of our study.</span> <span class="attribution"><a class="source" href="https://www.shutterstock.com/image-photo/close-image-woman-hands-typing-on-1936676008">Tipa Patt/Shutterstock</a></span></figcaption>
</figure>

<h2><strong>What did we find?</strong></h2>

<p>Responses agreeing to a meeting or requesting further information were categorised as “positive”. Those who declined a meeting were “non-positive”. Automated replies and those who did not reply were “non-responses”.</p>

<p>Of 6,928 emails sent, 2,986 (43.1%) received a reply within 24 hours and 2,469 (35.6%) received a positive reply. There were 3,942 (56.9%) non-responses and 517 (7.5%) non-positive responses (declining a meeting).</p>

<p>We initially planned to give academics a week to respond, but after IT at one university noticed several staff had received emails with identical text, we ended the experiment after 24 hours.</p>

<p>From here, the results were stark: emails from names associated with non-white racial groups received significantly fewer responses and positive replies than those from names typically associated with white individuals.</p>

<p>An email from “Melissa Smith” was far more likely to get a positive response than an identical email from “Grace Chen Jinyan” (six percentage points lower) or “Omar al-Haddad” (nine percentage points lower).</p>

<p>The most dramatic gap was in the positive response rates to Melissa Smith, compared with “Rahul Kumar”. The rate of positive responses to Melissa was 12 percentage points higher than for Rahul.</p>

<p>Overall, our statistical analysis showed the white-sounding names averaged a 7% higher reply rate and a 9% higher positive response rate than the non-white sounding names. Both these findings were highly <a href="https://hbr.org/2016/02/a-refresher-on-statistical-significance">statistically significant</a>, meaning we can be very confident the results were not due to chance.</p>

<p>Of course, some faculty members may simply have been unable to meet with the student, or may have missed the email. However, given the randomisation used, it is reasonable to assume bias explains the gap in responses to students with different names.</p>

<p>This is alarming because it suggests racial bias is quietly influencing who gets a foot in the door of academia even before formal admissions processes begin.</p>

<h2><strong>Silver linings</strong></h2>

<p>One seemingly positive finding was academics at the more junior end of our study group appeared to show less bias towards students of different backgrounds.</p>

<p>For academics at senior lecturer or associate professor levels, Melissa was 10.5% more likely to receive a positive response than Rahul, while the corresponding figure for full professors was 14.7%.</p>

<p>However, junior academics often have <a href="https://educ.sites.olt.ubc.ca/files/2022/09/Literature-Review-Equity-in-Faculty-Hiring-UBC-Faculty-of-Education-2022.pdf">little institutional power</a> or much of a say on hiring. More research is needed to explore whether generational change is achievable (albeit painfully slow).</p>

<p>We also found that, unlike <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2014/05/11/opinion/sunday/professors-are-prejudiced-too.html">similar US studies</a>, there was no significant bias against female students. In fact, there was some evidence of positive bias, or preference, for female students.</p>

<figure class="align-center "><img alt="A group of people, including young women sit in rows listening to a speaker at the front." sizes="(min-width: 1466px) 754px, (max-width: 599px) 100vw, (min-width: 600px) 600px, 237px" src="https://images.theconversation.com/files/626392/original/file-20241017-17-wcaw7y.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;fit=clip" srcset="https://images.theconversation.com/files/626392/original/file-20241017-17-wcaw7y.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=400&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=1 600w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/626392/original/file-20241017-17-wcaw7y.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=30&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=400&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=2 1200w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/626392/original/file-20241017-17-wcaw7y.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=15&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=400&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=3 1800w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/626392/original/file-20241017-17-wcaw7y.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=503&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=1 754w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/626392/original/file-20241017-17-wcaw7y.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=30&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=503&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=2 1508w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/626392/original/file-20241017-17-wcaw7y.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=15&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=503&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=3 2262w" />
<figcaption><span class="caption">Our study found academics did not discriminate against potential candidates based on gender.</span> <span class="attribution"><a class="source" href="https://www.shutterstock.com/image-photo/business-entrepreneurship-symposium-speaker-giving-talk-1908799612">Matej Kastelic/ Shutterstock</a></span></figcaption>
</figure>

<h2><strong>Backlash to our study</strong></h2>

<p>We based our study on a <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2014/05/11/opinion/sunday/professors-are-prejudiced-too.html">peer-reviewed study carried out in the United States</a>, and followed a research ethics protocol approved by our university.</p>

<p>However, minutes after academics received our follow-up email telling them they had been part of a research study (part of our ethics protocol), the backlash began.</p>

<p>The University of Sydney, our home institution at the time, received more than 500 inquiries about the study. While some were curious or supportive, the majority were complaints. These were primarily about our use of deception (a <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0191308509000239">well-researched and supported method</a> of studying bias). Megan MacKenzie, the more junior author (at the time a senior lecturer), received calls threatening her with consequences for her career.</p>

<p>Although unpleasant, the reaction was revealing. It reinforces <a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1111/ssqu.12985">other research</a> on how defensive racial majorities can be when they believe they are suspected of bias. It also complements work <a href="https://journals.sfu.ca/ijepl/index.php/ijepl/article/view/1303">showing internal resistance</a> to diversity efforts in higher education.</p>

<h2><strong>What can we do?</strong></h2>

<p>Universities pride themselves on <a href="https://www.chronicle.com/article/is-meritocracy-hurting-higher-education/">being meritocracies</a>, where the best ideas and brightest minds rise to the top. But our study suggests racial bias is undermining this principle by influencing who is even considered for an academic career.</p>

<p>There is growing acknowledgement racism is a significant problem on Australian university campuses (as well as <a href="https://humanrights.gov.au/our-work/race-discrimination/publications/anti-racism-framework-perspectives-multicultural">in broader society</a>). In May, the <a href="https://humanrights.gov.au/our-work/race-discrimination/projects/study-racism-australian-universities">federal government asked</a> the Australian Human Rights Commission to study the prevalence and impact of racism at Australian universities.</p>

<p>But this study is not due to deliver its final report until June 2025, and any ensuing action will be further away still.</p>

<p>What can be done now to tackle this issue?</p>

<p>First, universities need to acknowledge academia remains overwhelmingly white and male, in spite of efforts to increase diversity.</p>

<p>Second, universities also need to acknowledge the existence of racial bias, the need for ongoing research into how it operates in higher education and the most effective strategies to tackle it.<!-- Below is The Conversation's page counter tag. Please DO NOT REMOVE. --><img alt="The Conversation" height="1" referrerpolicy="no-referrer-when-downgrade" src="https://counter.theconversation.com/content/241352/count.gif?distributor=republish-lightbox-basic" style="border: none !important; box-shadow: none !important; margin: 0 !important; max-height: 1px !important; max-width: 1px !important; min-height: 1px !important; min-width: 1px !important; opacity: 0 !important; outline: none !important; padding: 0 !important" width="1" /><!-- End of code. If you don't see any code above, please get new code from the Advanced tab after you click the republish button. The page counter does not collect any personal data. More info: https://theconversation.com/republishing-guidelines --></p>

<p><span>(<strong>Author:&nbsp;</strong><a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/megan-mackenzie-1466320">Megan MacKenzie</a>, Professor and Simons Chair in International Law and Human Security, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/simon-fraser-university-1282">Simon Fraser University</a> and <a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/benjamin-e-goldsmith-1172998">Benjamin E. Goldsmith</a>, Professor of Political Science, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/australian-national-university-877">Australian National University</a>)</span></p>

<p><em>(This article is republished from <a href="https://theconversation.com">The Conversation</a> under a Creative Commons license. Read the <a href="https://theconversation.com/are-academics-more-likely-to-answer-emails-from-melissa-or-rahul-the-answer-may-not-surprise-you-241352">original article</a>.)</em></p>
</div><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/rm11grs_university_625x300_22_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Representational Image]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ndtv-world-summit-sunil-bharti-mittal-heard-own-ai-voice-it-asked-for-large-fund-transfer-6845145]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Sunil Bharti Mittal Heard Own AI Voice. It Asked For Large Fund Transfer]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ndtv-world-summit-sunil-bharti-mittal-heard-own-ai-voice-it-asked-for-large-fund-transfer-6845145]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 11:57:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence (AI) will shape the future of the global economy and geopolitics, said Bharti Enterprises chairman, Sunil Mittal, at the NDTV World Summit, adding that AI has its risks, particularly the potential for misuse.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Artificial Intelligence (AI) will shape the future of the global economy and geopolitics, said Bharti Enterprises chairman, Sunil Mittal, at the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://special.ndtv.com/ndtv-world-summit-2024-167/#pfrom=home-ndtvworld_world%20site">NDTV World Summit</a>, adding that AI has its risks, particularly the potential for misuse. Mr Mittal, who heads India's second-largest telecom firm, Bharti Airtel, recounted a personal experience illustrating AI's potential dangers.&nbsp;</p>

<p>He described an incident where a senior finance official in Dubai received a fraudulent call that mimicked his voice, directing a large fund transfer. But the vigilant official detected the fraud in time. Upon hearing the voice recording himself, Mr Mittal admitted he was "stunned" by the accuracy, warning that future misuse could extend to digital signatures and even visual impersonation on video calls.</p>

<p>"And anyone who would not have been vigilant may have done something about it," Mr Mittal said. "We'll have to protect our societies from the evils of AI, and yet we have to use the goodness of AI because those companies, and nations that will not adopt AI will be left behind. So this is a conundrum for every time you get a new technology into place, there are pluses and minuses. I remain very optimistic about the benefit of AI that the human race will achieve and be able to do jobs which are otherwise very difficult to perform."</p>

<p>Mr Mittal said that AI is already transforming operations within Bharti Airtel. Routine and repetitive tasks, such as those in call centres and workforce management, are being replaced by AI, leading to greater efficiency but also reducing traditional jobs.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Just 10 years back, every time a customer had to be onboarded onto a mobile phone, there was a physical form to be filled out. There were runners on scooters and more bikes who would take those forms to a different centre. From there, they would fax it to another place...in 10 years' time, it seems like a joke today," Mr Mittal said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Barti Group chief said that rapid advancements in AI will impact everything from global economies to geopolitics.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"AI will be one of the most important drivers of economy, politics, and geopolitics. But there will be misuse as well, and we will need to be more vigilant," Mr Mittal said. "Nation states will have to come up with guardrails. One will have to be vigilant, society will have to be protected from the evils of AI. I remain very optimistic of the various use of AI."&nbsp;</p>

<p><br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2017-09/sunil-mittal-ndtv_650x400_41506497896.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mr Mittal said that AI is already transforming operations within Bharti Airtel.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/wall-street-journal-new-york-post-sue-perplexity-ai-for-copyright-infringement-6845139]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Wall Street Journal Sues Perplexity AI For Copyright Infringement]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/wall-street-journal-new-york-post-sue-perplexity-ai-for-copyright-infringement-6845139]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 11:55:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Wall Street Journal and the New York Post filed a lawsuit in a US court on Monday against AI company Perplexity AI, alleging massive copyright infringement and trademark violations.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Wall Street Journal and the New York Post filed a lawsuit in a US court on Monday against AI company Perplexity AI, alleging massive copyright infringement and trademark violations. Perplexity is one of Silicon Valley's hottest startups, whose AI powered search engine is often mentioned as a potential disruptor to Google.</p>

<p>The lawsuit in a federal court in New York accuses Perplexity of illegally copying and reproducing copyrighted content from The Wall Street Journal and the New York Post to power its AI-driven "answer engine."</p>

<p>Perplexity.ai is a question-answering platform known for its minimalist and conversational interface.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Unlike ChatGPT or Anthropic's Claude, Perplexity's tool provides up-to-date answers that often include links to source materials, allowing users to verify information.</p>

<p>And unlike a classic search engine, Perplexity provides ready-made answers on its webpage making it unnecessary for users to click through to the source website.</p>

<p>According to the complaint, this constituted a "massive freeriding" on protected content that allowed the company to divert readers and revenue from the Wall Street Journal and New York Post.</p>

<p>"Unlike the business model of a traditional internet search engine, Perplexity's business model does not drive business toward content creators. To the contrary, it usurps content creators' monetization opportunities for itself," the lawsuit alleged.</p>

<p>Perplexity, which is backed by Amazon-billionaire Jeff Bezos and AI juggernaut Nvidia, did not immediately respond to a request for comment.</p>

<p>The complaint also accused Perplexity of damaging the publishers' brands by attributing false information to their publications.</p>

<p>The publishers seek injunctive relief and statutory damages up to $150,000 per infringement.</p>

<p>The plaintiffs are also requesting the destruction of any database containing their copyrighted works.</p>

<p>The move follows similar allegations by The New York Times, which has sent a cease and desist letter to Perplexity, which is a first step towards a lawsuit.</p>

<p>In a similar case, the Times filed a lawsuit last year against OpenAI, accusing the ChatGPT-maker of stealing content to train its powerful AI with copyrighted material.</p>

<p>News Corp, the owner of The Wall Street Journal and the Post, has signed a content agreement with OpenAI and the suit alleged that Perplexity ignored requests to enter into such partnerships.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/bbvk8rio_perplexity-ai_625x300_22_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Perplexity is backed by Amazon-billionaire Jeff Bezos and AI juggernaut Nvidia (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chase-strangio-the-first-openly-transgender-lawyer-to-argue-at-us-supreme-court-6845085]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Chase Strangio: The First Openly Transgender Lawyer To Argue At US Top Court]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chase-strangio-the-first-openly-transgender-lawyer-to-argue-at-us-supreme-court-6845085]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 11:49:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Chase Strangio, 41, represents a group of transgender people who pursued a lawsuit challenging the measure that prohibits some medical treatments.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An American Civil Liberties Union lawyer will make history in December as the first openly transgender attorney to argue before the US Supreme Court, opposing Tennessee's Republican-backed law banning gender-affirming medical care for transgender minors.</p>

<p>The ACLU's Chase Strangio, 41, represents a group of transgender people who pursued a lawsuit challenging the measure that prohibits medical treatments including hormones and surgeries for minors experiencing gender dysphoria.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In one of the most consequential cases of the court's current nine-month term, the nine justices will hear arguments on December 4 in an appeal by President Joe Biden's administration of a lower court's decision upholding Tennessee's ban.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Supreme Court on Monday ordered that the argument time for the ban's challengers be divided between the Justice Department and attorneys representing the original plaintiffs who sued the state. Strangio will present the arguments for these plaintiffs at the lectern in the ornate courtroom.&nbsp;</p>

<p>ACLU Legal Director Cecillia Wang called Strangio the leading US legal expert on transgender rights.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"He brings to the lectern not only brilliant constitutional lawyering, but also the tenacity and heart of a civil rights champion," Wang said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Strangio, who joined the ACLU in 2013, is the co-director of its LGBTQ &amp; HIV Project, helping the organization oppose state laws targeting transgender people, including 12 legal challenges against the laws like the one at issue before the Supreme Court.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Strangio has represented people in high-profile cases including transgender student Gavin Grimm, who fought a Virginia school board to use the bathroom corresponding with his gender identity, and Chelsea Manning, a transgender former U.S. soldier who served time in prison for leaking classified documents.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to the Justice Department, Tennessee is one of 22 states that have passed measures targeting medical interventions for adolescents with gender dysphoria. That is the clinical diagnosis for significant distress that can result from an incongruence between a person's gender identity and the sex they were assigned at birth.</p>

<p>Lawmakers supporting the restrictions have called the treatments experimental and potentially harmful. Medical associations, noting that gender dysphoria is associated with higher rates of suicide, have said gender-affirming care can be life-saving, and that long-term studies show its effectiveness.</p>

<p>Several plaintiffs - including two transgender boys, a transgender girl and their parents - sued in Tennessee to defend the treatments they have said improved their happiness and wellbeing. The Justice Department intervened in the lawsuit to also challenge the law.</p>

<p>The challengers contend that banning care for transgender youth violates the U.S. Constitution's 14th Amendment &nbsp;promise of equal protection by discriminating against these adolescents based on sex and transgender status.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In a written filing, the Justice Department highlighted that one of the law's "declared purposes is to enforce gender conformity and discourage adolescents from identifying as transgender."</p>

<p>The state asked the Supreme Court to let the law stand.</p>

<p>"Tennessee lawfully exercised its power to regulate medicine by protecting minors from risky, unproven gender-transition interventions," Tennessee Attorney General Jonathan Skrmetti said in a filing.</p>

<p>A federal judge blocked the law in Tennessee in 2023, finding that it likely violates the 14th Amendment. In a 2-1 decision in 2023, the Cincinnati-based 6th U.S. Circuit Court of Appeals reversed the judge's preliminary injunction.</p>

<p>The Supreme Court has confronted several cases in the past decade implicating LGBT rights. In 2015, it legalized same-sex marriage nationwide. In 2020, it ruled that a landmark federal law forbidding workplace discrimination protects gay and transgender employees. In 2023, it decided in a case from Washington state that the constitutional right to free speech allows certain businesses to refuse to provide services for same-sex weddings.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/0ea6ft8g_chase-strangio-_625x300_22_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Chase Strangio has represented people in high-profile cases]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/dont-risk-war-with-russia-georgias-richest-person-bidzina-ivanishvili-tells-voters-ahead-of-polls-6845022]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Don't Risk War With Russia: Georgia's Richest Person Tells Voters]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/dont-risk-war-with-russia-georgias-richest-person-bidzina-ivanishvili-tells-voters-ahead-of-polls-6845022]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 11:39:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Bidzina Ivanishvili's presence looms large over this small European country caught been Russia and the West and an election that could shape its destiny.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Georgia's saviour. Russia's stooge. Philanthropist. Oligarch. Bidzina Ivanishvili has been called all these things, and more. The billionaire, Georgia's richest person and the founder of its ruling party, is seldom seen in public and, of late, almost exclusively behind bulletproof glass. Yet his presence looms large over this small European country caught been Russia and the West and an election that could shape its destiny.</p>

<p>Ivanishvili can gaze down on downtown Tbilisi from a massive steel-and-glass clifftop mansion that rears about 60 metres over the capital, complete with helipad. He indulges exotic passions like keeping sharks and zebras and collecting rare trees.</p>

<p>The 68-year-old is viewed by many friends and foes alike as Georgia's most powerful figure, or eminence grise, even though he hasn't held public office for over a decade. He has cast Saturday's election as an existential fight to prevent a "Global War Party" in the West pushing Georgia into a ruinous conflict with former overlord Russia, like he says it did with Ukraine.</p>

<p>"Georgia and Ukraine were not allowed to join NATO and were left outside," he said in a rare public appearance at a pro-government rally in Tbilisi on Apr. 29.</p>

<p>"All such decisions are made by the Global War Party, which has a decisive influence on NATO and the European Union and which only sees Georgia and Ukraine as cannon fodder."</p>

<p>While most of Georgia's 3.7 million people are keen to move closer to the West by joining the EU and NATO, and largely don't trust Russia, opinion polls show, Ivanishvili's message resounds with many who want to avoid Ukraine's fate at all costs.</p>

<p>Memories are fresh of a 2008 war with Russia over the Moscow-backed breakway regions of South Ossetia and Abkhazia, which lasted five days and ended in Georgia's defeat.</p>

<p>Oleg Machavariani's home is only six miles from South Ossetia. The 75-year-old retired civil servant fears a rerun of history should the staunchly pro-Western and anti-Russian opposition win power.</p>

<p>"I think the first thing that will happen is that we'll get sucked into war."</p>

<p>Ivanishvili's Georgian Dream is on course to become the country's most popular party in the election, opinion polls indicate, though it is set to lose ground nationally since 2020 when it won a narrow majority in parliament.</p>

<p>Ivanishvili, who was strongly pro-Western throughout his party's first decade in power, was not available to be interviewed for this article, while Georgian Dream says it remains committed to integration with the West, and to a pragmatic policy towards neighbouring Russia.</p>

<p>Reuters interviews with several former close associates of the billionaire, as well as voters on both sides of the spectrum and Georgia experts, offer a window into the influence wielded by this mysterious magnate in the South Caucasus nation.</p>

<h3><strong>'THE CONSOLIDATION OF POWER IS HUGE'</strong></h3>

<p>Allies in the highest halls of power speak of him in near-messianic terms.</p>

<p>"When the people had lost all hope forever, a man appeared who gave it back to them," two-time former Prime Minster Irakli Garibashvili said of Ivanishvili's initial election win in 2012, after which he served as premier for one year.</p>

<p>Garibashvili was among a string of officials who heaped praise on Ivanishvili, the party's honorary chair, in speeches at a rally in September when - unlike the tycoon - they weren't shielded by bulletproof glass. Current premier Irakli Kobakhidze said Ivanishvili had sacrificed everything, including his wellbeing, to deliver Georgia from political enemies.</p>

<p>Ivanishvili spent much of the 1990s in Russia, founding banking, metals and telecoms companies and growing wealthy in the chaotic aftermath of the collapse of the Soviet Union.</p>

<p>His political opponents paint a picture of a power-hungry oligarch who wields dangerous control over former Soviet state Georgia. Many dub his party "Russian Dream". Some brand him a Kremlin asset, without presenting evidence for this.</p>

<p>"He has turned Georgia into a private company, of which he is the 100% owner," said Gia Khukhashvili, Ivanishvili's former top political adviser, who helped him launch Georgian Dream before their relationship broke down in 2014 when Khukhashvili accused him of retaining power from behind the scenes.</p>

<p>Giorgi Gakharia, who served as a Georgian Dream prime minister from 2019-21 and resigned after accusing Ivanishvili of interfering in government matters, echoed the critique.</p>

<p>"The consolidation of power is huge," said Gakharia, who now leads the For Georgia party, one of four main blocs of Georgia's splintered opposition running in the Oct. 26 election.</p>

<p>"There is not even one independent institution anymore in this country," said Gakharia, who listed the heads of Georgia's central bank, electoral commission, state audit office and judiciary as all being ultimately answerable to the magnate.</p>

<p>"All these people are directly connected with Ivanishvili. They are loyal to him."</p>

<p>Georgia's justice ministry, audit office and central bank didn't respond to requests for comment. The electoral commission said suggestions it was influenced by the ruling party were "unfounded and detrimental to the integrity of the electoral process."</p>

<h3><strong>'180-DEGREE TURN' ON WEST RHETORIC</strong></h3>

<p>Since Russia's full-scale invasion of Ukraine in February 2022, Ivanishvili has all but reversed Georgia's long-standing alignment with the West, one which he himself championed while prime minister in 2012-13.</p>

<p>This year, the Georgian Dream government has pushed through bills on "foreign agents", which requires organisations receiving more than 20% of funding from abroad to register as such, and cracked down on LGBT rights, decisions praised by Moscow and denounced by critics as anti-democratic and Russian-inspired.</p>

<p>The moves, along with increased anti-Western rhetoric from Tbilisi, have led to the U.S. and EU suspending some aid to Georgia and the bloc freezing the country's membership application.</p>

<p>Giorgi Margvelashvili, Georgia's president in 2013-18 and a close colleague of Ivanishvili in opposition and the early years in power, said the billionaire had appeared sincerely pro-Western while in frontline politics.</p>

<p>He described him as a calm, strategic thinker who sought to balance a pro-EU and NATO policy with an imperative to avoid provoking Georgia's vast northern neighbour.</p>

<p>Margvelashvili said there had nonetheless been a new hostility in Ivanishvili's anti-West rhetoric since the Ukraine war, a shift which seemed to him deeply out of character.</p>

<p>"We can only speculate what forced Bidzina Ivanishvili into this kind of political turmoil," Margvelashvili said. "Suddenly changing the rhetoric 180 degrees is not his style."</p>

<p>NATO agreed at a 2008 Budapest summit that Georgia would eventually become a member. That was a few months before the war with Russia, and little progress has been made since.</p>

<p>Many Georgians are wary of the ordeal of Ukraine, where the pro-Western Maidan protests of 2013-2014 ousted a pro-Russian government before Moscow annexed Crimea and began supplying arms to separatists in the country's east.</p>

<p>Russian officials have repeatedly said they don't interfere with sovereign states and have accused the West of meddling in Georgian politics. Russia's foreign spy chief Sergei Naryshkin said this month he was sure Georgians would make the "correct" choice and vote for "healthy, patriotic forces".</p>

<p>Ex-adviser Khukhashvili said Ivanishvili had told him that he left Russia after Putin's rise to power in 2000, believing the president would crack down on politically ambitious businessmen. Khukhashvili said Ivanishvili's shift in foreign policy since the Ukraine conflict was an attempt to spare himself and Georgia from Putin's wrath.</p>

<p>Ivanishvili himself took a big hit in the West in 2020, when a rogue banker at Credit Suisse embezzled about $1 billion of his cash. Though much of the money has been recovered, his allies have cited the case as proof that he is under "de facto" U.S. sanctions. The U.S. has repeatedly said that Ivanishvili hasn't been sanctioned.</p>

<h3><strong>LET 'ORDINARY PEOPLE' LEAD GEORGIA</strong></h3>

<p>Natalie Sabanadze, a former Georgian ambassador to the EU, told Reuters Georgian Dream also drew strength from the unpopularity of the opposition, which has struggled to shake off its association with the divisive figure of former Georgian leader Mikheil Saakashvili, who ruled until 2012 and is now serving a six-year jail term for abuse of power.</p>

<p>Despite deteriorating relations with the West, the ruling party can still rely on a "status-quo factor", especially among rural and public-sector workers, said Sabanadze, a senior research fellow at London think-tank Chatham House.</p>

<p>Indeed, in the poor, rural western part of Georgia where Ivanishvili grew up, he's revered by many locals as a philanthropist. Levan Ivanashvili, district mayor in the town of Sachkhere, pointed out projects financed by the favourite son: three schools, a football stadium, swimming pool, hospital and hotel, as well as a restoration of the historic castle.</p>

<p>Other voters have had enough.</p>

<p>"Mr Ivanishvili has done positive things for Georgia in the past, but he has declined, Georgia under him is declining," Nikoloz Shurgaia said at an opposition rally in Tbilisi. "Let a new generation of politicians, ordinary people, lead Georgia to a better future."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/fk78p9so_bidzina-ivanishvili_625x300_22_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Bidzina Ivanishvili is viewed by many friends and foes alike as Georgia's most powerful figure]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ndtv-world-summit-vibrant-market-for-carbon-credits-soon-6845020]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[NDTV World Summit: Vibrant Market For Carbon Credits Soon?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ndtv-world-summit-vibrant-market-for-carbon-credits-soon-6845020]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 11:38:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India will open up the possibility of monetizing carbon credits, said e-mobility expert Mustafa Wajid, hinting at a vibrant trade of carbon credits between different sectors in the near future.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India will open up the possibility of monetizing carbon credits, said e-mobility expert Mustafa Wajid, hinting at a vibrant trade of carbon credits between different sectors in the near future. Speaking on Day 2 of the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world">NDTV World Summit</a>, the co-founder of e-mobility firm BILLIONe said the government's vision is to create a carbon market just like the stock market.</p>

<p>His remarks came at a panel discussion on 'Aligning Profit With Purpose', also attended by Gagandeep Sethi, Senior Vice-President, Integrated Operations and Sustainability and Responsibility, Pernod Ricard India, and Ajay Pillai, Partner - Sustainability and Climate Change, Deloitte.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ndtv-world-summit-2024-live-updates-indias-g20-sherpa-amitabh-kant-british-envoy-lindy-cameron-to-speak-on-day-2-6843569"><strong>NDTV World Summit: Live Coverage</strong></a></p>

<p>"Carbon credits will come. Good organisations that can adapt their processes will generate carbon credits. And there will always be a sector generating carbon debits, for example, the cement and steel industries. There will be a very vibrant market with people wanting to buy carbon credits," said Mr Wajid, citing the example of Tesla which sold carbon credits to its rivals.</p>

<p>Mr Wajid said policies are being drafted for the trade of carbon credits, but its implementation won't be without challenges. "The process to create a carbon market is on. Policies are being drafted and we are very optimistic to see it kicking off in 2026. What we did with stock markets, we can do with the carbon markets," he said.</p>

<p>"De-carbonisation and sustainability can be monetized in the future, and can add to a company's bottomlines," he added.</p>

<p><strong>Opinion | </strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/voluntary-carbon-credits-what-india-can-do-to-become-a-market-leader-5598834">Voluntary Carbon Credits: What India Can Do To Lead The Market</a></p>

<p>The three industry experts also brainstormed over how to overcome sustainability-related challenges.</p>

<p>Mr Pillai listed the challenges to the implementation of ESG, or Environmental, Social, and Governance factors in the production process across sectors. These include quality and availability of data, lack of awareness and expertise, and lack of intent. "We want to imbibe sustainability as part of our business model," he added.</p>

<p>Mr Sethi said he has found, in his personal experience, that the first few steps towards sustainability is profit neutral.</p>

<p><strong>Read |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/why-teslas-sporty-and-trendy-robotaxi-design-is-puzzling-industry-experts-6773568">Why Tesla's Sporty And Trendy Robotaxi Design Is Puzzling Industry Experts</a></p>

<p>"Steps like a sustainable switch of fuels hardly come with a cost. It's only profit. But to have ESG at the design stage itself and re-engineering is where the largest investment will come in. We need policy support and regulatory support to make the correct decisions, but there is a lot to be done till that stage," he added.</p>

<p>Mr Pillai echoed similar views: making sustainability part of the overall business, like water conservation or handling waste. "Initially, there is a capital investment, but if you are looking at your business for a longer term, sustainability is needed. The faster you adapt it, the better you are ready for future," he added.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/g9b1q03g_ndtv-world-summit-panel-discussion_625x300_22_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bhutanese-pm-tshering-tobgay-on-how-india-moulded-him-i-will-tell-you-secret-6842132]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["I Will Tell You Secret...": Bhutanese PM On How India Moulded Him]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bhutanese-pm-tshering-tobgay-on-how-india-moulded-him-i-will-tell-you-secret-6842132]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 11:32:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Bhutanese Prime Minister Tshering Tobgay shared deep personal insights into his connection with India during his speech at the 'NDTV World Summit 2024: The India Century.']]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bhutanese Prime Minister Tshering Tobgay shared deep personal insights into his connection with India during his speech at the 'NDTV World Summit 2024: The India Century.'</p>

<p>He revealed that not only was he born in India, but his formative years in the country played a significant role in shaping his dedication to serving Bhutan, its people, and its king.</p>

<p>"I'll tell you a secret, in fact, my Bhutanese colleagues here also don't know; I was born in India. 1965, I was born in Kalimpong. My father was serving in Kalimpong, my parents were serving - I was born there, right?" <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/global-south-looks-to-indias-leadership-bhutan-pm-at-ndtv-world-summit-6838260">Mr Tobgay said</a>.</p>

<p>"What moulded me to serve my king, my country, and my people would have been not necessarily Pittsburgh and Harvard, but Dr Graham's homes in Kalimpong in West Bengal. I studied 11 years in India, and you asked me how 4 years in America has moulded me!"</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/will-further-strengthen-our-ties-with-india-bhutan-pm-after-meeting-gautam-adani-6179082">Mr Tobgay</a> went on to emphasise the long-standing educational connections between Bhutan and India. He shared how many Bhutanese, himself included, were educated in Indian schools due to the lack of institutions in Bhutan at the time.</p>

<p>"From kindergarten school, from baby class till class 10, I studied in India, as indeed many other Bhutanese studied in India those days, because we did not have enough schools in Bhutan. But when we did establish schools, we did not have enough teachers, and those teachers came from India," he added.</p>

<p>"I do believe they have taught us well, because we have been able to go back home and serve our King and country and our people."</p>

<p>When asked about India's growing global influence, particularly in the 21st century, Mr Tobgay was quick to praise the country's economic strength and leadership on the world stage. "The world needs India, and I'm very happy that you identify this century as India's century.</p>

<p>You asked me about Prime Minister Modi and his historic third term - why do you call it India's century? For many reasons! India has the largest population in the world - 1.45 billion. It's growing. It's projected to reach 1.6 billion."</p>

<p>Mr Tobgay also pointed out India's economic prowess and consumer base, noting, "India has a booming economy - it's crossed 3 trillion US Dollars. It should have crossed 5 trillion US Dollars had it not been for COVID. India has the biggest consumer base. India has almost 35 million successful people in the diaspora throughout the world, particularly in the advanced countries."</p>

<p>"By every measure, yes, this is India's century. But by one measure you stand out, and that is leadership. India's leadership, and trust in that leadership," he concluded.</p>

<p>The summit marked another milestone in reflecting on India's role not only as a regional power but also as a global leader, poised for further growth in the decades to come.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/etsqd4q_bhutan-prime-minister-dasho-tshering-tobgay_625x300_21_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Tshering Tobgay pointed out India's economic prowess and consumer base.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-south-korea-a-new-way-to-buy-groceries-flying-shopping-cart-6844957]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[In South Korea, A New Way To Buy Groceries: "Flying Shopping Cart"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-south-korea-a-new-way-to-buy-groceries-flying-shopping-cart-6844957]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 11:27:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[South Korean researchers have developed a transport drone flying on multiple flexible rotors that self-correct to stay level in flight and can be used as a "flying shopping cart" to carry goods over uneven terrain such as stairs.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>South Korean researchers have developed a transport drone flying on multiple flexible rotors that self-correct to stay level in flight and can be used as a "flying shopping cart" to carry goods over uneven terrain such as stairs.</p>

<p>The prototype developed by a Seoul National University of Science and Technology team has a cargo platform mounted on top of a multi-rotor drone and is handled by a person using gentle force to guide the hovering aircraft.</p>

<p>Members of the team demonstrated the hovering platform with a handle bar much like one on a push shopping cart moving objects up and down stairs and loading boxes on top as it hovered mid-air and maintained its balance by using a centre of mass estimation algorithm.</p>

<p>To move objects over uneven terrain or stairs when a wheeled cart cannot, the drone responds to human control with what the developers call a physical human-robot interaction technique that anticipates human intentions for smooth flight, said Lee Seung-jae, professor of mechanical system design engineering.</p>

<p>But the broader focus of Lee's team is not on developing a shopping cart to be used over steps, but instead on applications that would use a drone with reliable horizontal stability without pitching and rolling.</p>

<p>"The Palletrone can be more than a flying shopping cart," he said, referring to the name the team gave the prototype by joining the words pallet, which is the platform for cargo on top, and drone.</p>

<p>Lee's team has tested a platform to carry objects up to 3 kg (6.6 lbs), and concedes commercial applications for cargo transportation at such a small weight easily carried by humans is limited.</p>

<p>Still, the mechanism that allows the drone to change directions in flight without banking and to maintain level attitude has applications for delivering sensitive or fragile payloads, Lee said.</p>

<p>But Lee's team is looking further ahead for the technology's potential use for uncrewed "flying taxis" carrying humans and for drones to be "refuelled" mid-air, by changing batteries so the aircraft do not need to return to base for a fresh charge.</p>

<p>Multi-rotor drones are inherently limited in speed and range compared to fixed-wing drones but have better control and manoeuvrability, including the ability to hover in flight.</p>

<p>They have been used to deliver cargo, food and medical supplies, but commercial applications have been limited largely because it is impractical to increase the size of the battery enough to transport a heavier payload over a longer distance.</p>

<p>Seoul Tech's work was published in IEEE Robotics and Automation Letters this year, the publication of the Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers based in New York.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/vp03ravg_south-korea-flying-shopping-cart-reuters-_625x300_22_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Members of the team demonstrated the hovering platform with a handle bar.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/2-men-accused-of-killing-air-india-bombing-suspect-plea-guilty-6844828]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[2 Men, Accused Of Killing Air India Bombing Suspect, Plead Guilty]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/2-men-accused-of-killing-air-india-bombing-suspect-plea-guilty-6844828]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 11:04:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Two men accused of killing Ripudaman Singh Malik, a Sikh man acquitted in the tragic 1985 Air India Kanishka terrorist bombing case, have pleaded guilty to second-degree murder in a Canadian court, according to media reports.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Two men accused of killing Ripudaman Singh Malik, a Sikh man acquitted in the tragic 1985 Air India Kanishka terrorist bombing case, have pleaded guilty to second-degree murder in a Canadian court, according to media reports. Tanner Fox and Jose Lopez entered the pleas in the British Columbia (BC) Supreme Court on Monday on the eve of their trial for the killing of 75-year-old Malik, who was shot several times outside his family business on the morning of July 14, 2022.</p>

<p>Malik was shot dead in Surrey, British Columbia in 2022. He and co-accused Ajaib Singh Bagri were acquitted in 2005 of mass murder and conspiracy charges related to the two bombings in 1985 that killed 331 people.</p>

<p>In the court in New Westminster on Monday, both Fox and Lopez pleaded guilty to the lesser charge of second-degree murder, the Global News reported.</p>

<p>The court heard an agreed statement of facts that revealed the two men had been hired to kill Malik, the report added.</p>

<p>"What we know from the agreed statement of facts is that there was some type of financial incentive that was involved in the commission of this crime, but in terms of any other specifics, it is another one of those situations where unfortunately it is just something that we as people on the outside will probably never know," Lopez' lawyer Gloria Ng told Global News.</p>

<p>"One of the things we certainly have in the forefront of our minds is the youth of our client - Lopez is a very young man and we are certainly hopeful with prospects for rehabilitation." In a statement, Malik's family described him as a "father, brother, husband and grandfather as well as a tireless community leader," the Canadian Broadcasting Corporation reported on Monday.</p>

<p>"While we are grateful that the shooters are being brought to justice, we know that nothing will erase the pain that we have gone through losing a family member in this way," the family said.</p>

<p>"However, the work is not complete. Tanner Fox and Jose Lopez were hired to commit this murder. Until the parties responsible for hiring them and directing this assassination are brought to justice, the work remains incomplete." The family called on the killers to "co-operate with the Royal Canadian Mounted Police (RCMP) in bringing those that hired you to justice." Crown and defence lawyers have agreed that Fox and Lopez should not be eligible for parole for 20 years. And they will next appear in court on October 31 for sentencing.</p>

<p>The 1985 Air India bombing is among the worst terrorist attacks in Canadian history and in the history of the airline.</p>

<p>On June 23, 1985, Air India flight 182, carrying 329 people, including 268 Canadian citizens and 24 Indian citizens, flew from Toronto and stopped in Montreal from where it was en route to London and then onwards to its final destination Bombay.</p>

<p>The plane was flying 31,000 feet above the Atlantic Ocean when a suitcase bomb exploded in the front cargo, killing all on board.</p>

<p>Another bomb was meant to be planted in an Air India flight scheduled to take off from Japan but it exploded at Tokyo's Narita airport killing two baggage handlers.</p>

<p>Inderjit Singh Reyat was convicted on various charges and spent 30 years in prison for helping to make the bombs, and for lying during trials, including Malik's. He was released in 2016 after serving two-thirds of his perjury sentence.</p>

<p>Reyat was the only person convicted for the Kanishka bombing.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-07/fel7na5g_ripudaman-singh_625x300_16_July_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Ripudaman Singh Malik was shot dead in Surrey, British Columbia in 2022]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-india-china-border-patrol-agreement-and-why-it-is-important-6844560]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India-China Border Patrol Agreement: What It Means, Why It Is Important]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-india-china-border-patrol-agreement-and-why-it-is-important-6844560]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 10:26:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In a significant diplomatic breakthrough four years after the Galwan Valley clash, India and China have reached a patrolling arrangement along the Line of Actual Control.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a significant breakthrough four years after the Galwan Valley clash, India and China have reached a patrolling arrangement along the Line of Actual Control.&nbsp;Shortly after Foreign Secretary Vikram Misri announced this, adding that it can lower the tension between the neighbors, External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar said at NDTV World Summit that Indian and Chinese soldiers would be able to patrol the border area in the way they did before the May 2020 face-off.</p>

<p>Here's what this agreement means and why it's important</p>

<p><strong>De-escalation: </strong>The agreement signals a move towards de-escalation in a region where both countries have stationed tens of thousands of troops. Reversion to the patrolling norms of 2020 reduces the chances of skirmishes or escalation due to close military encounters.</p>

<p><strong>Stabilisation: </strong>This agreement helps stabilise the situation along the LAC by potentially reducing confrontations at friction points such as Depsang Plains and Demchok. Stability along LAC could foster a better environment for broader negotiations on boundary issues.</p>

<p><strong>Confidence-building</strong>: The resumption of patrolling as per pre-2020 terms is a confidence-building measure. It indicates a mutual willingness on both sides to return to a status quo that they found acceptable before the recent tensions. This also paves the way for further dialogue.</p>

<p><strong>Political Implications: </strong>The agreement might facilitate higher-level diplomatic interactions, like possible meetings between leaders at international forums, and enhance bilateral relations outside military confrontations. For India, this could mean better management of its border infrastructure development without an immediate threat of conflict. As for China, it may reflect a strategic choice to stabilise its border with India amid other global tensions.</p>

<p><strong>The Galwan Clash Backdrop</strong></p>

<p>In a major escalation along the Line of Control, Indian and Chinese troops clashed in the Galwan Valley on June 15, 2020. This incident was the first deadly confrontation in the region since 1975 and resulted in casualties on both sides. While 20 Indian soldiers died in the clash, there are varying claims regarding the number of Chinese casualties. Border infrastructure developments and differing perceptions of the LAC had triggered the clash.&nbsp;Following the clash, both sides engaged in de-escalation talks amid heightened tensions in bilateral ties.</p>

<p><strong>The Other Friction Points</strong></p>

<p>Besides Galwan, there are at least four other friction points along the Line of Actual Control. These are all disputed areas where Indian and Chinese soldiers fought in the 1962 war.</p>

<p><strong>Demchok: </strong>Demchok is split by the LAC. India controls the western part. The eastern side is under the control of China, which also claims the western part. The dispute hinges on historical treaties and the precise alignment of the LAC along the Charding Nullah. Recent talks aim at disengagement.</p>

<p><strong>Pangong: </strong>About 50 per cent of Pangong Lake area is in Tibet (under Chinese control), 40 per cent in Ladakh and 10 per cent is disputed. Discrepancies in LAC perceptions lead to military standoffs and buffer zones, with ongoing construction and strategic positioning reflecting the tensions and claims by both nations.</p>

<p><strong>Hot Springs: </strong>Located near Gogra Post, the Hot Springs area is significant for India due to its strategic location which facilitates surveillance over LAC. India's control over this region enhances its defence posture, providing vantage points for monitoring movements in Aksai Chin, thus playing a crucial role in border security dynamics.</p>

<p><strong>Depsang: </strong>Depsang plains are critical for India due to their strategic access to the Daulat Beg Oldie (DBO) airstrip and the Darbuk-Shyok-DBO road. Control over Depsang prevents Chinese forces from threatening these vital logistics lines, making it essential for India's northern border defence and military mobility.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2018-03/india-china-border-doklam_650x400_81522061523.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[In a big breakthrough, India and China have reached a patrolling arrangement along LAC]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/watch-donald-trumps-heartfelt-interaction-with-indian-origin-couple-at-mcdonalds-goes-viral-6844409]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Watch: Trump's Heartfelt Interaction With Indian Couple At McDonald's]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/watch-donald-trumps-heartfelt-interaction-with-indian-origin-couple-at-mcdonalds-goes-viral-6844409]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 10:00:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An Indian-origin couple's heartfelt interaction with former US President Donald Trump is going viral on social media.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An Indian-origin couple's heartfelt interaction with former US President Donald Trump is going viral on social media. The Republican presidential candidate on Sunday visited a McDonald's and served french fries while he was campaigning in Pennsylvania. He wore a black-and-yellow apron over his white shirt and red tie as he served fries and interacted with customers. It was while working at the takeout counter that he was greeted with a cheerful "namaste" by an energised Indian-origin couple. As the former president handed the Indian national his order, the excited customer exclaimed, "Thank you, Mr. President!"&nbsp;</p>

<p>"You made it possible for ordinary people like us to be here," the Indian-origin man told Mr Trump. He continued to express gratitude and repeatedly called Mr Trump "Mr President". At the end, the lady sitting next to the man also quipped, "Thank you for taking the bullet for us".&nbsp;</p>

<p>Sharing the video on X, user Hodge Twins wrote, "Listen to this Indian dude that pulls up. All Americans love Trump."&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Watch the video below:&nbsp;</strong></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Listen to this Indian dude that pulls up<br />
<br />
All Americans love Trump <a href="https://t.co/x0RHCP6OtI">pic.twitter.com/x0RHCP6OtI</a></p>
— Hodgetwins (@hodgetwins) <a href="https://twitter.com/hodgetwins/status/1848074352102695080?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 20, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The video surfaced on social media on Sunday. Since then, the clip has accumulated nearly 8 million views.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Reacting to the video, one user wrote, "That man and his wife are so genuine; they will remember this forever." "This is so sweet and so precious, It just makes me tear up," expressed another.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"I love this so much. I'm sure it was obvious when they got in the drive through something was going on. But can you even imagine pulling up to see Trump giving you your food. Really brings a smile even to me on the other end of this screen," commented a third.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-rapper-sean-diddy-drugged-and-raped-13-year-old-girl-lawsuit-claims-6843642">US Rapper Sean Diddy Drugged And Raped 13-Year-Old Girl, Lawsuit Claims</a></strong></p>

<p>Meanwhile, Donald Trump's McDonald's stunt was intended as a jibe at Kamala Harris, who has often talked about working at the fast-food chain in her youth. Taking a swipe at Ms Harris, who turned 60 on Sunday, he said he is running against somebody who said she worked at Mcdonald's, but it turned out to be a "phoney story". "I've now worked for 15 minutes more than Kamala" at McDonald's, he said.</p>

<p>In response, Kamala Harris's spokesperson,<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/2024-election/trump-tries-troll-harris-serving-french-fries-mcdonalds-rcna176294"> Joseph Costello</a>, remarked that Mr Trump's trip to the fast-food restaurant highlighted what a second term under him would entail: "taking advantage of workers for his own benefit."</p>

<p>"When Trump feels desperate, all he knows how to do is lie. He can't understand what it's like to have a summer job because he was handed millions on a silver platter, only to blow it," said Ian Sam, spokesperson for Ms Harris' campaign.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/mu8cmp48_trump-meets-indian-couple_625x300_22_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The video has accumulated nearly 8 million views.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/teen-kills-five-of-family-at-home-in-us-arrested-police-6844233]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Teen Kills Five Of Family At Home In US. Arrested: Police]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/teen-kills-five-of-family-at-home-in-us-arrested-police-6844233]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 09:54:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Authorities in Washington state have taken a 15-year-old boy into custody in connection with a fatal shooting that claimed the lives of five people at a home near Seattle.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Authorities in Washington state have taken a 15-year-old boy into custody in connection with a fatal shooting that claimed the lives of five people at a home near Seattle.</p>

<p>The shooting occurred early Monday morning in Fall City, located east of Seattle after multiple 911 calls were made reporting the incident, according to a police spokesperson.</p>

<p>King County Sheriff's Office spokesperson, Mike Mellis, said during a media briefing on Monday afternoon that officers discovered five bodies upon entering the residence. The victims included two adults and three teenagers, though their identities have not yet been released.</p>

<p>The police swiftly arrested one teenage suspect, while another person who was injured was transported to a hospital for medical treatment. The department noted that a neighbour had administered first aid before emergency responders arrived.</p>

<p>"Once we recovered the bodies, we knew this was a hugely significant crime scene," Mellis said.</p>

<p>The police also revealed that the victims were members of the same family, though it remains unconfirmed whether all of them were directly related. The Sheriff's Office is continuing its investigation to determine a motive for the attack.</p>

<p>The teenage suspect is currently being held at King County's juvenile detention facility. According to Mellis, the teen is expected to appear in court for an initial hearing on Tuesday or Wednesday, as confirmed by the county Prosecuting Attorney's Office.</p>

<p>Incidents of teen shootings have been on the rise in the US. Recently, a 14-year-old boy was charged with murder for fatally shooting four people, including two students and two teachers, at Apalachee High School in Georgia.</p>

<p>While polls indicate that a majority of Americans support stricter regulations on firearm purchases and usage, efforts to impose additional restrictions continue to face strong opposition from powerful gun ownership lobby groups, and legislative action has repeatedly stalled.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/1neck6oo_us-police-generic_625x300_30_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The police revealed that the victims were members of the same family.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/japan-general-election-shigeru-ishiba-fighting-uphill-battle-heres-whats-at-stake-6844228]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Japan's Ishiba Fighting Uphill Battle In Elections, Here's What's At Stake]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/japan-general-election-shigeru-ishiba-fighting-uphill-battle-heres-whats-at-stake-6844228]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 09:28:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Japan is heading for a general election on October 27, with new prime minister Shigeru Ishiba still appearing to be fighting an uphill battle.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Japan's general election on Sunday will be a test for new prime minister Shigeru Ishiba, who is seeking to solidify his position atop a scandal-plagued party.</p>

<p>His gamble to call a snap election after winning a close-fought contest last month to lead the ruling Liberal Democratic Party (LDP) could backfire in a fluid election, however, as opinion polls show the party could cede seats to the opposition.</p>

<p>Here are some key factors to watch:</p>

<h3><strong>What's at stake?</strong>&nbsp;</h3>

<p>Ishiba inherited a fractured party struggling to shake off a scandal over undocumented funds after predecessor Fumio Kishida cleared out tainted ministers, disbanded influential factions and stepped down himself, in a bid to regain public trust.</p>

<p>But Ishiba still appears to be fighting an uphill battle.</p>

<p>While some polls project the LDP and its coalition partner Komeito will maintain their majority, a weekend poll by the Asahi newspaper showed they may struggle, with the LDP potentially losing 50 of the 247 seats it now has.</p>

<p>If Ishiba misses his own target of retaining a majority for the ruling coalition, questions are likely to be asked about his capability as premier at a time of economic uncertainty and increasing tension with neighbours China, Russia and North Korea.</p>

<h3><strong>Who are the main parties?</strong></h3>

<p>The LDP has ruled Japan for almost all of the post-war era, and holds a majority in the 465-seat lower house. Its long-time coalition partner is Komeito, a party backed by a large Buddhist lay group that has often lent crucial campaign support to the LDP.</p>

<p>Although the LDP's popularity hit a low of 25.5% in June - the lowest since it regained power in 2012 - it remains the most popular party in a fragmented political landscape, with backing from 35.1% of respondents in a mid-October poll by public broadcaster NHK.</p>

<p>While the LDP still has strong support, the main opposition Constitutional Democratic Party of Japan (CDPJ) is making inroads. The Asahi poll estimated the CDPJ could grab as many as 140 seats in the election, up from 98.</p>

<h3><strong>What are the top issues?</strong></h3>

<p>The economy and inflation are critical for voters, the NHK poll showed, with the slush fund scandal also a concern.</p>

<p>In a sign of the pain of rising living costs, food and daily necessities topped the list of items on which the respondents said they increased spending from a year ago, a quarterly survey by the Bank of Japan showed in early October.</p>

<p>Ishiba has told ministers to draw up a fresh economic package to cushion the blow to households from the rising costs of living.</p>

<p>The opposition CDPJ has announced plans to increase welfare spending, including free university education.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/cs56gkpo_shigeru-ishiba_625x300_22_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Shigeru Ishiba inherited a fractured party struggling to shake off a scandal over undocumented funds]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/harvey-weinstein-72-diagnosed-with-bone-marrow-cancer-report-6844217]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Harvey Weinstein Diagnosed With Bone Marrow Cancer: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/harvey-weinstein-72-diagnosed-with-bone-marrow-cancer-report-6844217]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 09:26:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Disgraced Hollywood movie producer Harvey Weinstein has been diagnosed with a form of bone marrow cancer, US media reported Monday, a month after he was indicted on a new sex crime charge.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Disgraced Hollywood movie producer Harvey Weinstein has been diagnosed with a form of bone marrow cancer, US media reported Monday, a month after he was indicted on a new sex crime charge. Weinstein, 72, has chronic myeloid leukemia and is undergoing treatment in a New York prison, according to NBC News and ABC News, citing sources.</p>

<p>His diagnosis comes after a string of health issues for the once powerful entertainment mogul, who appeared pale and visibly frail during a brief court appearance in September.&nbsp;</p>

<p>He underwent emergency heart surgery last month, after which his representative said he was "out of danger at the moment."</p>

<p>Weinstein is serving a 16-year prison sentence after being convicted on rape charges in California.</p>

<p>He was also convicted in New York in 2020 of the rape and sexual assault of an actress and of forcibly performing oral sex on a production assistant.</p>

<p>He was sentenced to 23 years in prison in that case.</p>

<p>However, a New York appeals court overturned the verdict in April, ruling that the trial judge had allowed testimony in error from accusers who were not directly involved with the charges facing Weinstein.&nbsp;</p>

<p>A retrial in the case had been aimed for November, though prosecutors had deemed that "unrealistic."</p>

<p>Allegations against Weinstein helped launch the #MeToo movement in 2017, a watershed moment for women fighting sexual misconduct.</p>

<p>More than 80 women accused him of harassment, sexual assault or rape, including prominent actors Angelina Jolie, Gwyneth Paltrow and Ashley Judd.</p>

<p>Weinstein has claimed any sexual relations in question were consensual.</p>

<p>In 1979, Weinstein and his brother Bob co-founded prominent Hollywood film studio Miramax Films.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Their hits included 1994's "Pulp Fiction" and 1998's "Shakespeare in Love," for which Weinstein shared a best picture Oscar.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/eag2dt7o_harvey-weinstein-afp_625x300_12_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Harvey Weinstein underwent emergency heart surgery last month]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/pm-modi-emplanes-for-brics-summit-says-india-values-close-cooperation-within-brics-6843917]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["India Values Close Cooperation Within BRICS": PM Modi Emplanes For Russia]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/pm-modi-emplanes-for-brics-summit-says-india-values-close-cooperation-within-brics-6843917]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 09:08:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India values close cooperation within BRICS which has emerged as an important platform for dialogue and discussion on a range of key issues concerning global developmental agenda, Prime Minister Narendra Modi said on Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India values close cooperation within BRICS which has emerged as an important platform for dialogue and discussion on a range of key issues concerning global developmental agenda, Prime Minister Narendra Modi said on Tuesday.</p>

<p>PM Modi made comments in a statement before embarking on a two-day visit to the Russian city of Kazan to attend the 16th summit of the BRICS grouping.</p>

<p>"The expansion of BRICS with the addition of new members last year has added to its inclusivity and agenda for the global good," he said.</p>

<p>Being hosted by Russia, the summit is being seen as an attempt by non-Western powers to project their clout amid the conflict in Ukraine and the escalating situation in West Asia.</p>

<p>PM Modi is set hold a series of bilateral meetings including with Russian President Vladimir Putin and Chinese President Xi Jinping on the margins of the BRICS (Brazil-Russia-India-China-South Africa).</p>

<p>It will be the first summit of the grouping after it was expanded at its summit in Johannesburg last year.</p>

<p>"India values the close cooperation within BRICS which has emerged as an important platform for dialogue and discussion on issues concerning the global developmental agenda, reformed multilateralism, climate change, economic cooperation, building resilient supply chains, promoting cultural and people to people connect, among others," PM Modi said in his departure statement.</p>

<p>PM Modi said his visit to Kazan will further reinforce the 'Special and Privileged Strategic Partnership' between India and Russia.</p>

<p>The prime minister visited Moscow in July during which he held summit talks with President Putin.</p>

<p>"Building upon the annual summit held in July 2024 in Moscow, my visit to Kazan will further reinforce the Special and Privileged Strategic Partnership between India and Russia," PM Modi said.</p>

<p>"I look forward to meeting other leaders from BRICS as well," he said.</p>

<p>In a post on 'X', PM Modi said he was looking forward to extensive discussions on a wide range of subjects at the summit.</p>

<p>The BRIC, as a formal grouping, started after the meeting of the leaders of Russia, India and China in St. Petersburg in 2006. It was agreed to expand BRIC into BRICS with the inclusion of South Africa in 2010.</p>

<p>Last year's expansion was the first such exercise since 2010. The new members included Egypt, Ethiopia, Iran and the United Arab Emirates.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/jsj3mptg_pm-modi-ani-twitter_625x300_22_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[PM Modi said he was looking forward to extensive discussions on a wide range of subjects at the summit.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/italian-surfer-36-dies-after-being-impaled-by-swordfish-in-indonesia-6844071]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Italian Surfer, 36, Dies After Being Impaled By Swordfish In Indonesia]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/italian-surfer-36-dies-after-being-impaled-by-swordfish-in-indonesia-6844071]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 08:55:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[36-year-old Italian surfer Giulia Manfrini has died after being fatally impaled by a swordfish during a freak incident in Indonesia.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>36-year-old Italian surfer Giulia Manfrini has died after being fatally impaled by a swordfish during a freak incident in Indonesia. According to <em>ABC Australia</em>, Ms Manfrini was surfing at a popular surf break off the West Coast of Sumatra, Indonesia, when the accident occurred. She was fatally injured after a swordfish speared her in the chest while she surfed in the waters off Ombak Bengbeng, near Masokut Island. She reportedly had a 5cm deep stab wound on the left side of her chest.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Ms Manfrini, a surf coach and founder of the surf travel agency AWAVE, was well-known in the local surfing community, the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.abc.net.au/news/2024-10-21/surfer-killed-by-swordfish-off-sumatra-indonesia/104498760">outlet </a>reported. Lahmudin Siregar, acting head of the Mentawai Islands' Disaster Management Agency, said the swordfish "unexpectedly jumped towards Manfrini and pierced her chest".</p>

<p>Separately, James Colston, Co-Founder of AWAVE Travel said Ms Manfrini "touched countless people within the surf world" both in Europe and worldwide. "Her kindness, care and positivity were remembered by all that met her and she will be dearly missed," he said.</p>

<p>Frankie Smithurst, from surf charter operator Naga Laut Mentawai Blue, said she would be remembered for her "overflowing excitement for life". "Giulia will be forever known by her huge heart which matched her huge smile, an extremely selfless person who truly loved life," he told the outlet.&nbsp;</p>

<p>At the time of the incident, two of Ms Manfrini's friends were nearby. They provided first aid and rushed her to a nearby health care centre, but she could not be saved despite their efforts. Medical reports later revealed that she suffered a 5cm deep wound to her chest and showed signs of drowning.</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-rapper-sean-diddy-drugged-and-raped-13-year-old-girl-lawsuit-claims-6843642">US Rapper Sean Diddy Drugged And Raped 13-Year-Old Girl, Lawsuit Claims</a></strong></p>

<p>Following the news of her demise, Fabio Giulivi, the mayor of Venaria Reale, Ms Manfrini's hometown, expressed the community's sorrow over her tragic death in a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.facebook.com/fabiogiulivisindaco/posts/pfbid037c1RhyaJDYwNXT1Grw53YdeufyhJgkcZDaUTcr7L9w5tqb172wjaYZM5yeSUndfdl">Facebook post</a>, noting the support for her grieving family.</p>

<p>"Giulia, just 36 years old and from Venaria, had long pursued her twin dreams: her love of surfing and opening a travel agency for sports holidays," he wrote. "The news of her death has left us all in shock and makes us feel powerless in the face of such a devastating tragedy that took her life far too soon," he added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Ms Manfrini's Instagram page has also been flooded with emotional tributes. "The sea, that gave you so much, has taken your life. Rest in peace," wrote one user.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Our whole community in Portugal is heartbroken alongside you as we hear of the sad news. She loved life, and we spent (our) last evening (together) picking pomegranates and talking about making fig jam and what other fruit we would harvest together next year. She became like my new Italian daughter, and oh how we will miss her. We can only say how much she got out of her short life, and she filled it completely," her former volleyball coach wrote.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/hibh1ai_giulia-manfrini-_625x300_22_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Giulia Manfrini was a surf coach and founder of the surf travel agency AWAVE.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-vs-donald-trump-campaigns-take-up-pace-in-final-stages-of-election-6843983]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris, Donald Trump Pick Up Pace In Final Stages Of US Election]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-vs-donald-trump-campaigns-take-up-pace-in-final-stages-of-election-6843983]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 08:32:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[As the election draws closer, Kamala Harris has been sharpening her attacks on Donald Trump's fitness for office, often calling him "unstable" or "unhinged".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Democratic presidential candidate Kamala Harris and her Republican rival, Donald Trump, delivered radically different messages on the US campaign trail on Monday as they sought to win over undecided voters in the two weeks before Election Day.</p>

<p>Vice President Harris, campaigning alongside Republican former lawmaker Liz Cheney, attempted to convince conservative, suburban women in three Midwestern battleground states that former President Trump was a threat to abortion rights, national security and democracy.</p>

<p>As the election draws closer, Harris has been sharpening her attacks on Trump's fitness for office, often calling him "unstable" or "unhinged" and questioning his temperament.</p>

<p>"In many, many ways Donald Trump is an unserious man, but the consequences of him being president of the United States are brutally serious," Harris, 60, said at an event in Malvern, Pennsylvania, one of seven battleground states expected to decide the winner of the Nov. 5 election.</p>

<p>Trump, 78, frequently rejects any notion that he is a threat to democracy, arguing it is Democrats who are the real threat because of the criminal investigations he and his allies have faced for their attempts to overturn his 2020 election loss.</p>

<p>While Harris was suggesting Trump was unfit for office, the former president was questioning the Biden administration's competence.</p>

<p>During one of several stops on Monday in ultra-competitive North Carolina, Trump urged supporters in the hurricane-battered mountains to go to the polls despite the hardships they were facing.</p>

<p>He also renewed his criticisms of the emergency management agency FEMA and sought to relate to working-class supporters by praising his nonstop efforts on his own behalf.</p>

<p>"I've done 52 days without a day off, which a lot of these people would respect," Trump said at a lectern backed by rubble from massive floods that hit the area last month.</p>

<p>With opinion polls showing a close race, the two candidates are picking up the pace, their frenzied campaign schedules underlining the importance of small pockets of voters that could put either candidate over the top.</p>

<h3><strong>God and Conscience</strong></h3>

<p>Trump ended his day at an evangelical Christian event in Concord, North Carolina, telling a crowd he likes to think that during the failed assassination attempt against him on July 13 in Butler, Pennsylvania, he was saved by being "knocked to the ground by a supernatural hand."</p>

<p>In his remarks, he avoided using some of the off-color rhetoric he has been using in recent speeches. He said as he looks back on his life, "I now recognize that it's been the hand of God leading me to where I am today."</p>

<p>Evangelical leader Franklin Graham offered a prayer that Trump be elected.</p>

<p>"Rallies and positive poll numbers are not going to win this election," Graham said. "It's going to be God."</p>

<p>Trump's visit to North Carolina coincided with concerns among his Republican allies that crippling damage from storm Helene will depress turnout in the battleground state's conservative mountain regions.</p>

<p>The area hit hardest by Helene is deeply Republican. Trump won about 62% of the vote in 2020 in the 25 counties declared to be a disaster area after Helene, while Biden won about 51% in the remainder of the state, according to a Reuters analysis.</p>

<p>"Obviously, we want them to vote but we want them to live and survive and be happy and healthy, because this is really a tragedy," Trump said at a campaign stop in Swannanoa, population 5,300, after touring areas destroyed by the storm.</p>

<p>At an event with Harris in Royal Oak, Michigan, Cheney sought to give Republicans who are on the fence permission to support the Democrat without worry of reprisal.</p>

<p>"I certainly have many Republicans who will say to me, 'I can't be public.' They do worry about a whole range of things, including violence, but they'll do the right thing," Cheney said. "And I would just remind people, if you're at all concerned, you can vote your conscience and not ever have to say a word to anybody."</p>

<p>Later, in Brookfield, Wisconsin, Cheney described herself as "pro-life" but said she was troubled by state abortion restrictions that had prevented women from getting the care they needed.</p>

<p>Cheney and her father Dick Cheney, who was vice president under President George W. Bush and is still vilified by many Democrats for his defense of the U.S. invasion of Iraq, are staunch conservatives and two of the most prominent Republicans to have endorsed Harris.</p>

<p>In a post on his Truth Social platform on Monday, Trump called Liz Cheney "dumb as a rock" and a "war hawk." He accused her of wanting to go to war with "every Muslim country known to mankind" just like her father, who he called "the man that ridiculously pushed Bush to go to war in the Middle East."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/rdakscf8_kamala-harris-and-donald-trump_625x300_22_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Opinion polls shows a close race between Kamala Harris and Donald Trump]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-kills-hezbollah-finance-chief-in-syria-managed-main-source-of-income-6843838]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Managed Main Source Of Income": Israel Kills Hezbollah Finance Chief]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-kills-hezbollah-finance-chief-in-syria-managed-main-source-of-income-6843838]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 07:51:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Israeli army said Monday that the latest commander responsible for funding the Lebanese Hezbollah group was "eliminated" in Syria.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Israeli army said Monday that the latest commander responsible for funding the Lebanese Hezbollah group was "eliminated" in Syria. The man, whose name was not released, headed the Iran-backed Hezbollah's Unit 4400 that is "responsible for the transfers and the amount of funds" to the group through Tehran's oil sales, army spokesman Rear Admiral Daniel Hagari said in a statement.</p>

<p>The commander was "eliminated" in Syria "a few hours ago", he added.</p>

<p>The unit was previously led by Mohammed Jafar Ksir, also known as Sheikh Salah, Hagari said.</p>

<p>"He managed the terrorist organisation's main source of income for years, until we eliminated him in a targeted attack on the capital (Beirut) in early October," he said.</p>

<p>Earlier Monday, Syria's defence ministry announced the death of two people in a strike attributed to Israel and targeting a car in Damascus.</p>

<p>The Syrian Observatory for Human Rights reported that a strike targeted a non-Syrian man who was driving his car in a neighbourhood where a memorial was being held for Hamas leader Yahya Sinwar, who was killed by Israel last week in Gaza.</p>

<p>Unit 4400 is charged with transporting Iranian oil to Syria, which is then sold in Lebanon.</p>

<p>Its value "is about tens of millions of dollars", Hagari said.</p>

<p>Hamas ally Hezbollah has been firing rockets daily into northern Israel in support of the Palestinian Islamist movement since the war was triggered by Hamas's October 7, 2023 attack on Israel.</p>

<p>Israel, which has been conducting a ground offensive for nearly a month to push Hezbollah from its northern border, has in recent days ramped up its drive to hit the Iranian-backed group's finances.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/kttp0688_israeli-strike-in-syria_625x300_22_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hezbollah commander responsible for funding group killed in Syria]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/naked-chat-blackmail-59-people-in-hong-kong-duped-into-undressing-during-video-chats-6843812]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[59 People In Hong Kong Tricked Into Undressing During Video Chats]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/naked-chat-blackmail-59-people-in-hong-kong-duped-into-undressing-during-video-chats-6843812]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 07:49:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[According to the police, the scam typically involves extortionists - often women - luring male victims into undressing during video chats and then secretly recording the acts.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In the past week, an alarming extortion scam has targeted 59 Hong Kong residents, including four women, resulting in losses exceeding HK$1.9 million (US$244,430), <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3282979/naked-chat-blackmail-4-women-among-59-hongkongers-duped-undressing-during-video-chats">South China Morning Post</a></em> reported. According to the police, who revealed the figures on their CyberDefender Facebook page, the scam typically involves extortionists - often women - luring male victims into undressing during video chats and then secretly recording the acts.</p>

<p>The scammers then use the footage to coerce victims into payment by threatening to share the videos online or with their relatives and friends. In some cases, scammers also pose as charming, high-income, educated men to target women on social media. They use flattery and sweet talk to gain trust, manipulating victims by learning about their personal interests and lives.</p>

<p>''They use sweet talk to learn about the victims' personal lives and interests to manipulate them. In the past week, police received 59 cases of naked-chat blackmail, with scammers extorting more than HK$1.9 million. Four cases involved female victims,'' the force said.</p>

<p>In the first half of this year, students comprised 20% of the 1,102 victims, with fraudsters pocketing over HK$31 million. Comparing year-over-year data, reports of "naked-chat blackmail" surged 50% from 1,402 in 2022 to 2,117 in 2023, while losses doubled from HK$22 million to HK$44 million.</p>

<p>Moreover, deception cases in Hong Kong have increased by 12% from 21,798 to 24,407 between January and July this year. Losses skyrocketed 50% to HK$5.14 billion during the same period. Law enforcement responded by arresting over 6,000 suspects linked to scams and related activities this year.</p>

<p>The police are now cautioning citizens to exercise vigilance when meeting people online. They emphasise the importance of verifying identities and profiles, avoiding intimate activities on video chats, and reporting suspicious activities immediately.</p>

<p>Recently, a few Hong Kong men fell prey to a romance scam that used deepfake artificial intelligence to lure its victims into parting with more than $46 million. As per CNN, the suspects aged 21 to 34, were mostly well-educated, with many of them digital media and technology graduates allegedly recruited by the gang after attending local universities.&nbsp;The suspects allegedly worked with IT specialists overseas to build a fake cryptocurrency platform, where the victims were coerced to make investments, police said.&nbsp;</p>

<p></p>

<p></p>

<p></p>

<p data-qa="Component-Component" datatype="p"></p>

<p data-qa="Component-Component" datatype="p"></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/qq3kd518_phone_625x300_22_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The police are now cautioning citizens to exercise vigilance when meeting people online.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>