<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Mon, 18 Nov 2024 05:42:19 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladeshs-muhammad-yunus-will-ask-india-to-send-back-sheikh-hasina-7042619]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Will Ask India To Send Back Sheikh Hasina": Bangladesh's Muhammad Yunus]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladeshs-muhammad-yunus-will-ask-india-to-send-back-sheikh-hasina-7042619]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 17 Nov 2024 23:53:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Bangladesh's Chief Adviser Muhammad Yunus said on Sunday that the interim government will seek the extradition of deposed prime minister Sheikh Hasina, who fled to India after the fall of her government following a mass protest movement in August.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bangladesh's Chief Adviser Muhammad Yunus said on Sunday that the interim government will seek the extradition of deposed prime minister Sheikh Hasina, who fled to India after the fall of her government following a mass protest movement in August.</p>

<p>In an address to the nation on the completion of 100 days of the interim government, Yunus also said that his government has been continuing its all-out efforts to ensure the security of all citizens, including religious minorities.</p>

<p>"We must ensure justice in every killing...We will also ask India to send back fallen autocrat Sheikh Hasina," Yunus was quoted as saying by the state-run BSS news agency.</p>

<p>His remarks indicate a U-turn as in an interview with the UK-based Financial Times newspaper last month, Yunus said his government would not immediately seek Hasina's extradition from India.</p>

<p>Yunus, who assumed office on August 8, claimed that about 1500 people, including students and workers, were killed while 19,931 others were wounded during the protest against the Hasina government.</p>

<p>"Our government is very careful to collect information on every death," he said, adding that the government made arrangements for treatment of the injured in various specialized hospitals, including 13 hospitals in Dhaka.</p>

<p>Hasina, 77, resigned and fled to India following massive protests by students and others against her government over a controversial quota system in government jobs.</p>

<p>She landed at the Hindon airbase near Delhi on August 5. She was believed to have been shifted later to an unspecified location and has not been seen in public since then.</p>

<p>Hasina and her party leaders face accusations of ordering brutal suppression of the Anti-Discrimination Students Movement, resulting in numerous casualties during the July-August protests.</p>

<p>Yunus said his government is investigating every incident in a few cases where religious minorities were subjected to violence.</p>

<p>"We have tried our best so that any citizen of the country, not only Hindu community members, doesn't become a victim of violence. We will continue these efforts," he said in his address to the nation.</p>

<p>He said Bangladesh was a completely insecure country when the interim government assumed office.</p>

<p>Yunus said an attempt was made to spread unnecessary fear among the religious minorities.</p>

<p>"In some cases, they have also been subjected to violence. But all the hype about it was completely exaggerated. Those little cases of violence that took place were mainly political," he said.</p>

<p>But ill efforts were made to make the country unstable again by giving religious colour to these events, he said, adding that the government dealt with the situation firmly with the cooperation of all.</p>

<p>He said that after two months of assumption of office by his government, Durga Puja was celebrated in around 32,000 puja mandaps across the country.</p>

<p>He said the government took extensive security preparations during the Durga Puja so that the Hindu community members celebrate the festival smoothly.</p>

<p>Hindus constitute just about 8 per cent of the 170 million Bangladesh population. The minority Hindu community members have faced regular vandalism of their businesses and destruction of temples during and since the protest erupted, resulting in the ouster of Prime Minister Hasina.</p>

<p>Yunus also said that the Election Commission (EC) will be formed soon while an election roadmap will be announced after competing reforms in the electoral system.</p>

<p>"Once the electoral reforms are decided, you will get the election roadmap very soon," he said.</p>

<p>Noting that there is a question in everyone's mind about when the elections will be held, Yunus said the government has started taking necessary steps to hold the elections.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/5qfr3vp_sheikh-hasina_625x300_06_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sheikh Hasina resigned and fled to India following massive protests against her government. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukraine-announces-power-restrictions-after-massive-russian-attack-7042576]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ukraine Announces Power Restrictions After "Massive" Russian Attack]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukraine-announces-power-restrictions-after-massive-russian-attack-7042576]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 17 Nov 2024 23:45:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ukraine said it would introduce nationwide emergency power restrictions Monday after a "massive" Russian attack further damaged its already fragile energy grid ahead of a much-feared winter, with 9 civilians also killed across the country on Sunday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ukraine said it would introduce nationwide emergency power restrictions Monday after a "massive" Russian attack further damaged its already fragile energy grid ahead of a much-feared winter, with nine civilians also killed across the country on Sunday.</p>

<p>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky said Moscow launched 120 missiles and almost 100 drones, targeting Kyiv as well as southern, central and far-western corners of the country.</p>

<p>Civilians were killed in the Mykolaiv, Lviv, Kherson, Dnipropetrovsk and Odesa regions in what officials in the capital called one of the biggest barrages in the almost three-year Russian invasion.</p>

<p>The devastation comes at a time when Moscow has been steadily advancing in Ukraine's east and with the imminent return of Donald Trump to the White House, raising fears over the future of US support for Kyiv.</p>

<p>"A hellish night," the spokesman for Ukraine's air force, Yuriy Ignat, said on social media, adding that Kyiv had downed "144 targets".</p>

<p>The country's grid operator Ukrenergo said it would apply emergency measures in all regions on Monday.</p>

<p>"Tomorrow, November 18, all regions will be forced to apply consumption restriction measures," Ukrenergo posted on social media. "The reason for the temporary return of restrictions is the damage to power facilities during today's massive missile and drone attack."</p>

<p>Almost three years of war with Russia has already destroyed half of Ukraine's energy production capacity, Zelensky has warned.</p>

<p>With the harsh Ukrainian winter fast approaching, the country is already suffering from major energy shortfalls, while its outmanned and outgunned forces have been ceding ground to the Kremlin's troops for weeks.</p>

<p>The giant attack followed two days after German Chancellor Olaf Scholz called Russian leader Vladimir Putin for the first time in almost two years, urging the Kremlin chief to end Moscow's devastating offensive.</p>

<p><strong>'True response'</strong></p>

<p>Kyiv had slammed Scholz for reaching out to Putin, and said Sunday that the attack was the Kremlin's real answer.</p>

<p>"This is war criminal Putin's true response to all those who called and visited him recently," Ukrainian Foreign Minister Andriy Sybiga said after the attack.</p>

<p>"We need peace through strength, not appeasement."</p>

<p>Scholz on Sunday defended the call and insisted that Berlin's backing for Kyiv was unwavering.</p>

<p>"Ukraine can count on us," he said before flying to a G20 meeting in Brazil, promising that "no decision will be taken behind Ukraine's back" on ending the conflict.</p>

<p>But Poland's Prime Minister Donald Tusk joined the backlash on Sunday.</p>

<p>"No one will stop Putin with phone calls. The attack last night, one of the biggest in this war, has proved that telephone diplomacy cannot replace real support from the whole West for Ukraine," Tusk wrote on X.</p>

<p>The strikes caused extensive power cuts across the country, with fears of a precarious winter to come.</p>

<p>"A massive attack on our country," Zelensky said.</p>

<p>"Over the past week, the aggressor used nearly 140 missiles of various types, more than 900 guided aerial bombs, and over 600 strike drones," he said, accusing Moscow of trying to "intimidate us with cold and blackouts".</p>

<p><strong>Civilian deaths across Ukraine</strong></p>

<p>AFP journalists heard explosions in the early morning in Kyiv and close to Sloviansk in the Donetsk region.</p>

<p>Moscow, meanwhile, said it had hit all its targets, claiming it had targeted an "essential energy infrastructure supporting the Ukrainian military-industrial complex".</p>

<p>But civilian deaths were reported across the country.</p>

<p>Officials in Kherson said a 51-year-old woman was killed by a drone.</p>

<p>In the southern Mykolaiv region, local leader Vitaliy Kim said two women were killed in a night attack and seven people -- including two children -- were wounded.</p>

<p>The death count included two employees of the state railway company Ukrzaliznytsia in the city of Nikopol, who were killed when a depot was hit, the Dnipropetrovsk region's governor Sergiy Lysak and the operator said. Three others were wounded in the bombing.</p>

<p>Two people were also killed in the Odesa region, where a teenager was wounded.</p>

<p>Russian drones also made their way to Zakarpattia, a mountainous region rarely targeted, with officials saying fragments fell in the village of Pavshyno, near the border with Hungary and Slovakia.</p>

<p>The head of the Lviv region, Maksym Kozytsky, said a 66-year-old woman was killed in her car in Sheptytsky, a village around 20 kilometres (12 miles) from the Polish border.</p>

<p>That prompted NATO-member Poland to scramble fighter jets and mobilise all available forces on Sunday in response.</p>

<p>Warsaw puts its armed forces on alert whenever attacks against its neighbouring country are deemed likely to create a danger for its own territory.</p>

<p><strong>Two killed in Russia</strong></p>

<p>In the border Kursk region, where Kyiv has held onto swathes of Russian land since the summer, Russian officials said a Ukrainian drone strike killed a local journalist.</p>

<p>Kursk leader Alexei Smirnov said Yulia Kuznetsova, editor of the local "People's Paper", was killed in the Bolshesoldatskiy district as she "took archives to her editorial office".</p>

<p>The West and Ukraine says thousands of North Korea soldiers are in Russia, with some in the Kursk region, to reinforce Moscow's forces.</p>

<p>Russia also said a man was killed by a Ukrainian drone in its border Belgorod region.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/9odbjsn8_ukraine_625x300_17_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Ukraine's grid operator said it would apply emergency measures in all regions on Monday]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pregnant-pak-woman-killed-chopped-into-pieces-by-in-laws-over-witchcraft-suspicion-7042526]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Pregnant Pak Woman Killed, Chopped Into Pieces Over "Witchcraft" Suspicion]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pregnant-pak-woman-killed-chopped-into-pieces-by-in-laws-over-witchcraft-suspicion-7042526]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 17 Nov 2024 23:37:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In a shocking incident, a pregnant woman was killed allegedly by her mother-in-law who along with her three accomplices chopped her body in dozens of pieces before dumping it in a drain in the Punjab province of Pakistan, police said on Sunday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a shocking incident, a pregnant woman was killed allegedly by her mother-in-law who along with her three accomplices chopped her body in dozens of pieces before dumping it in a drain in the Punjab province of Pakistan, police said on Sunday.</p>

<p>The incident took place last week in Daska, Sialkot district, some 100 km from Lahore.</p>

<p>Police arrested four suspects including the mother-in-law Sughran Bibi, her daughter Yasmin, her grandson Hamza and distant relative Navid.</p>

<p>Zara Qadir, who was in her 20s, went missing last week. Later police found the chopped body of a woman in three sacks which was identified as Zara.</p>

<p>Zara, the daughter of a police officer, married Qadir Ahmad four years ago and the couple had a three-year-old son. Zara after marriage had gone to Saudi Arabia to her husband who works there. A few months ago, she had returned to Pakistan.</p>

<p>Senior police officer Omar Farooq told reporters on Sunday that the suspects confessed to having killed and dismembered the body of Zara.</p>

<p>"In her confessional statement, Sughran Bibi said that she suspected Zara of allegedly practising 'witchcraft'. Besides, her son Qadir had started sending money directly to Zara in her bank instead to his mother." "The four suspects smothered Zara with a pillow while she was asleep. After that they burnt her face and chopped off her body into dozens of pieces before dumping it in a drain in three sacks," the police officer said and added Zara was also pregnant.</p>

<p>"On Zara's father's statement that he suspected Sughran for claiming that she had run away with her lover upon her disappearance, we interrogated her (Sughran) who confessed to her crime," Farooq said.</p>

<p>He said Sughran was also the sister of Zara's father.</p>

<p>"This is a case of extreme jealousy as the mother-in-law and her daughter not only killed Zara but in cold blood dismembered her body into pieces in hatred," he said and Sughran and Yasmin were of the view that because of Zara's good looks Qadir was playing into her hands and ignoring them.</p>

<p>A murder case has been registered against the suspects.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/b9rika7_pakistan-police_625x300_26_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The incident took place last week in Daska, some 100 km from Lahore. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/xi-vows-to-work-with-trump-administration-as-he-held-final-talks-with-biden-7042475]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Xi Vows To Work With Trump Administration As He Held Final Talks With Biden]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/xi-vows-to-work-with-trump-administration-as-he-held-final-talks-with-biden-7042475]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 17 Nov 2024 23:26:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Chinese President Xi Jinping vowed on Saturday to work with the incoming US administration of Donald Trump as he held his final talks with outgoing President Joe Biden on conflicts from cyber crime to trade, Taiwan, the South China Sea and Russia.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Chinese President Xi Jinping vowed on Saturday to work with the incoming US administration of Donald Trump as he held his final talks with outgoing President Joe Biden on conflicts from cyber crime to trade, Taiwan, the South China Sea and Russia.</p>

<p>Biden met Xi for about two hours at a hotel where the Chinese leader was staying, on the sidelines of the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation forum in Lima, Peru, for their first talks in seven months.</p>

<p>"China's goal of a stable, healthy and sustainable China-US relationship remains unchanged" after Trump's election, Xi said as he met Biden, acknowledging "ups and downs" between the countries. "China is ready to work with the new US administration to maintain communication, expand cooperation and manage differences."</p>

<p>Biden told Xi that the two leaders have not always agreed but their discussions have been "frank" and "candid."</p>

<p>Two months before Trump returns to the White House, US officials see magnified risks of conflict during the transition. Biden told Xi that maintaining leader-to-leader talks would be vital even after he left office, said Biden national security adviser Jake Sullivan.</p>

<p>The president-elect has vowed to adopt blanket 60% tariffs on US imports of Chinese goods as part of a package of "America First" trade measures. Beijing opposes those steps. The Republican also plans to hire several hawkish voices on China in senior roles, including US Senator Marco Rubio as secretary of state and Representative Mike Waltz as national security adviser.</p>

<p>Biden has aimed to lower tensions with China, and there were few signs of a breakthrough on the major issues.</p>

<p>But Biden and Xi did agree that human beings, not artificial intelligence, should make decisions over the use of nuclear weapons, according to the White House, the first time the countries are known to have raised the issue.</p>

<p>The US and Chinese presidents also talked about North Korea, an ally of China whose deepening ties with Russia and deployment of troops in Moscow's war with Ukraine have raised concerns in Washington, Beijing and European capitals.</p>

<p>"President Biden pointed out that the (People's Republic of China's) publicly stated position with respect to the war in Ukraine is there should be no escalation, no broadening the conflict, and the introduction of (Democratic People's Republic of Korea) troops runs foursquare against that," said Sullivan.</p>

<p>"He also pointed out that the PRC does have influence and capacity, and should use it to try to prevent a further escalation or further expansion of the conflict with the introduction of even more DPRK forces."</p>

<p><strong>MAJOR ISSUES</strong></p>

<p>Other major issues raised at the meeting included a recent China-linked hack of the telephone communications of US government and presidential campaign officials, stepped-up pressure by Beijing on Taiwan and in the South China Sea, as well as Chinese support for Russia. Biden also raised the cases of Americans he believes are wrongly detained in China.</p>

<p>On Taiwan, the leaders appear to have had a sharp exchange. Biden called for an end to Beijing's "destabilizing" military activity around the island, the White House said.</p>

<p>Xi said the "'Taiwan independence'â€‚separatist activities" of Taiwanese President Lai Ching-te were incompatible with peace and stability there, according to the Chinese foreign ministry. Lai plans to stop in the US state of Hawaii and maybe Guam on a sensitive visit that is sure to anger Beijing in the coming weeks, Reuters reported on Friday.</p>

<p>Taiwan's foreign ministry thanked Biden for his comments, and said China was the troublemaker.</p>

<p>"China's persistent military provocations around Taiwan are the greatest source of damage to regional peace and stability and a major threat to global economic prosperity," it said in a statement.</p>

<p>Taiwan's former Economy Minister Lin Hsin-i met Biden at the summit on Friday and invited him to visit Taiwan in the near future.</p>

<p>China views democratically governed Taiwan as its own territory. The US is Taiwan's most important international backer and arms supplier, despite the lack of formal diplomatic recognition. Taiwan rejects China's sovereignty claims.</p>

<p>At the same time, Beijing's economy is taking a stiff hit from Biden's steps on trade, including a plan to restrict US investment in Chinese artificial intelligence, quantum computing and semiconductors, and export restrictions on high-end computer chips. Biden has described those steps as necessary for US national security reasons and said they do not impede most trade.</p>

<p>During the meeting, Xi said no evidence supported the claim of Chinese involvement in cyber attacks, according to Chinese state media. He also told Biden that Washington should not get involved in disputes in the Spratly Islands, the subject of a dispute between China and the US-allied Philippines.</p>

<p>Beijing has rejected a 2016 ruling by The Hague-based Permanent Court of Arbitration, which said its expansive maritime claims over the South China Sea had no legal basis, in a case that was brought by Manila.</p>

<p>"When the two countries treat each other as partner and friend, seek common ground while shelving differences and help each other succeed, our relationship would make considerable progress," Xi told Biden through an interpreter. "But if we take each other as rivals or adversary, pursue vicious competition, and seek to hurt each other, we would roil the relationship or even set it back."</p>

<p>The two leaders also privately reflected back on the blunt-spoken dynamics of their long relationship, said Sullivan, the US national security adviser.</p>

<p>Shen Dingli, a Shanghai-based international relations scholar, said China wants to ease tensions during the transition period. "China definitely does not want relations with the United States to be thrown into turmoil before Trump formally takes office," said Shen.</p>

<p>Pacific Rim leaders gathered at the APEC summit are assessing the implications of Trump's return to power on Jan. 20. The South American summit offers new signs of the challenges to the United States' power in its own backyard, where China is on a charm offensive.</p>

<p>Xi, who arrived in Lima on Thursday, plans a week-long diplomatic blitz in Latin America that includes a refurbished free-trade agreement with Peru, inaugurating the massive Chancay deep-water port there and being welcomed in Brazil's capital next week for a state visit. China also announced plans to host the APEC summit in 2026.</p>

<p>China is seeking Latin America's metal ores, soybeans and other commodities, but US officials worry they may also be looking for new US-adjacent military and intelligence outposts. Chinese state-backed media has called those accusations a smear.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/p3i9s3ko_biden-xi-jinping_625x300_17_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Biden has aimed to lower tensions with China]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/will-hold-the-much-anticipated-election-once-muhammad-yunus-7042400]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Will Hold The Much-Anticipated Election Once...": Muhammad Yunus]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/will-hold-the-much-anticipated-election-once-muhammad-yunus-7042400]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 17 Nov 2024 23:11:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Bangladesh's interim leader Muhammad Yunus begged the country's "patience" to prepare for much-awaited elections in a speech to the nation marking 100 days in power since a student-led revolution.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bangladesh's interim leader Muhammad Yunus begged the country's "patience" to prepare for much-awaited elections in a speech to the nation marking 100 days in power since a student-led revolution.</p>

<p>The 84-year-old Nobel Peace Prize winner was appointed to lead the government as "chief advisor" on August 9, days after the student-led uprising that ended Sheikh Hasina's 15 years of iron-fisted rule.</p>

<p>Yunus, a microfinance pioneer, is leading a temporary administration, to tackle what he has called the "extremely tough" challenge of restoring democratic institutions in the South Asian nation of some 170 million people.</p>

<p>Vowing an election commission will be formed "within a few days", Yunus said he could not give a timeframe for elections, saying it was dependent on a raft of election and constitutional reforms.</p>

<p>"I promise that we will hold the much-anticipated election once the necessary and essential reforms are complete," he said in the broadcast.</p>

<p>"I request your patience until then. We aim to build an electoral system that will endure for decades. For this, we need some time."</p>

<p>Yunus said his administration was also focused on ensuring those guilty of cracking down on the protests to oust Hasina faced justice, and said he had spoken to Karim Khan, chief prosecutor of the International Criminal Court.</p>

<p>Bangladesh has issued an arrest warrant for 77-year-old Hasina -- last seen arriving in neighbouring India after fleeing by helicopter as crowds entered her palace.</p>

<p>Hasina has been summoned to appear in court in Dhaka on Monday to face charges of "massacres, killings, and crimes against humanity", but she remains in exile in India.</p>

<p>Several of her former government ministers, who were detained and held in custody, are expected in court to face similar charges.</p>

<p>"We have already taken initiatives to try those responsible for enforced disappearances, murders, and the mass killings during the July-August uprising," Yunus said.</p>

<p>Crisis Group analyst Thomas Kean has called the challenge facing Yunus "monumental", warning of that "cracks are emerging in the fragile alliance" that pushed him into power.</p>

<p>"For now, Yunus and his colleagues have widespread support, but popular expectations are double-edged", the thinktank said in report on Thursday.</p>

<p>"If the interim administration falters in making reforms, the outcome is likely to be an early election with little progress; in the worst-case scenario, the military could assume power."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/j4vjvr9g_muhammad-yunus-afp_625x300_19_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Muhammad Yunus is leading a temporary administration in Bangladesh (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/2-soldiers-killed-in-israeli-attack-says-lebanon-army-7042319]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[2 Soldiers Killed In Israeli Attack, Says Lebanon Army]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/2-soldiers-killed-in-israeli-attack-says-lebanon-army-7042319]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 17 Nov 2024 22:58:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Lebanese army said an Israeli attack on Sunday killed two soldiers, accusing Israel of directly targeting their position in south Lebanon where the Israeli military is fighting Hezbollah.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Lebanese army said an Israeli attack on Sunday killed two soldiers, accusing Israel of directly targeting their position in south Lebanon where the Israeli military is fighting Hezbollah.</p>

<p>"The Israeli enemy directly targeted an army centre" in Mari in the Hasbaya area, causing "the death of one of the soldiers and the wounding of three others, one of whom is in critical condition", the army said in a statement.</p>

<p>A separate statement shortly afterwards said "a second soldier" had died of his wounds.</p>

<p>Israeli fire has killed more than a dozen Lebanese soldiers since all-out war between Israel and the Iran-backed Hezbollah group erupted in September, according to an AFP tally of official announcements.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/0l9f7oj8_lebanon-army_625x300_17_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israeli fire has killed over a dozen Lebanese soldiers since September (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-on-historic-trip-to-amazon-amid-fears-over-trumps-climate-stance-7042268]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden On Historic Trip To Amazon Amid Fears Over Trump's Climate  Stance]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-on-historic-trip-to-amazon-amid-fears-over-trumps-climate-stance-7042268]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 17 Nov 2024 22:47:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden began an historic trip to the Amazon rainforest on Sunday to promote his record on fighting climate change amid fears that Donald Trump will roll back his green policies.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden began an historic trip to the Amazon rainforest on Sunday to promote his record on fighting climate change amid fears that Donald Trump will roll back his green policies.</p>

<p>Biden landed in the Brazilian city of Manaus, in the heart of the world's largest jungle, on the last leg of a valedictory South American before handing the keys of the White House to Trump in January.</p>

<p>The 81-year-old, the first sitting US president to visit the Amazon, will fly over the rainforest by helicopter, visit a museum and meet Indigenous and local leaders working to protect the Amazon.</p>

<p>From Manaus he will continue on to Rio de Janeiro for a G20 summit starting Monday.</p>

<p>Ahead of his Amazon visit, the White House announced that the US had hit its target of increasing bilateral climate financing to $11 billion a year.</p>

<p>It said that the figure reached this year was six times what the US was providing at the start of Biden's term in 2021 and made "the United States the largest bilateral provider of climate finance in the world."</p>

<p>"The fight against climate change has been a defining cause of President Biden's leadership and presidency," the White House said.</p>

<p>Biden arrived in Brazil from Peru, where he attended his last summit with Asia-Pacific leaders.</p>

<p>He has cut a diminished figure on his tour. All eyes in Lima were on Chinese President Xi Jinping who was received with greater fanfare.</p>

<p>At a meeting with Biden, the Chinese leader said he hoped for a "smooth transition" in relations with the future Trump administration.</p>

<p>Trump has pledged to reverse Biden's policies and could again pull the United States, the world's second-biggest polluter, out of the landmark 2015 Paris Agreement on combatting carbon emissions, as he did during his first term.</p>

<p>On Saturday, he nominated a fracking magnate and noted climate change skeptic, Chris Wright, as his energy secretary.</p>

<p><strong>Amazon fires</strong></p>

<p>The Amazon, spanning nine countries, is crucial to the fight against climate change due to its ability to absorb planet-warming carbon dioxide from the atmosphere.</p>

<p>But it is also one of the areas most vulnerable to climate change and environmental degradation.</p>

<p>This year it experienced the worst wildfires in nearly two decades, fuelled by a severe drought blamed in part by climate experts on global warming.</p>

<p>A recent study showed that the Amazon rainforest had lost an area about the size of Germany and France combined to deforestation in four decades.</p>

<p>Brazil's President Luiz Inacio Lula da Silva has pledged to put a stop to illegal Amazon deforestation by 2030.</p>

<p>Experts have warned that a second Trump presidency could undo progress on the transition to green energy made under Biden, giving heavy polluters like China and India an excuse to scale back their own efforts.</p>

<p>During his campaign, Trump pledged to "drill, baby, drill" and increase fossil fuel extraction. He even brushed off climate change just days before the vote.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/lkememvo_biden-in-amazon_625x300_17_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Biden is the first sitting US president to visit the Amazon]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-doctor-injects-girlfriend-with-anaesthesia-20-times-in-6-hours-to-treat-insomnia-she-dies-7041910]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[China Doctor Injects Partner With Anaesthesia To Treat Insomnia, She Dies]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-doctor-injects-girlfriend-with-anaesthesia-20-times-in-6-hours-to-treat-insomnia-she-dies-7041910]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 17 Nov 2024 21:35:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[He caused his girlfriend's death by attempting to treat her insomnia with repeated anaesthetic injections.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a shocking incident in southwestern China's Sichuan province, an anesthesiologist, identified by his surname Qu, has been implicated in a tragic case involving his partner, Chen, a pharmaceutical sales representative. According to the <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3286714/china-doctor-kills-insomniac-girlfriend-injecting-anaesthetics-20-times-6-hours">South China Morning Post</a></em>, he caused his girlfriend's death by attempting to treat her insomnia with repeated anaesthetic injections. He administered the anaesthesia more than 20 times&nbsp;in six hours,&nbsp;leading to her death. This incident has sparked significant online outrage in China, with many slamming the doctor's actions despite his claims of trying to help.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Notably, the two met through an online dating platform in the summer of 2022. Qu, who works at a hospital in Jinjiang County, Leshan, allegedly administered propofol, a powerful anaesthesia, to Chen in hotel rooms on multiple occasions between September 2023 and March 2024. Chen had requested the medication to alleviate her insomnia.</p>

<p>On March 6, Qu administered approximately 1,300 mg of propofol to Chen, through her ankle over six hours, from 11 pm to 5 am. He provided 20+ doses, followed by an additional 100 mg for her to use later. Upon returning to the hotel, Qu discovered Chen had died.&nbsp;A medical examination confirmed that the cause of her death was acute propofol intoxication.</p>

<p>Qu promptly reported the incident to authorities, confessed to his actions, and later provided financial compensation of 400,000 yuan (US$55,000) to Chen's relatives, who forgave him.</p>

<p>A Shanghai-based representative from a leading propofol manufacturer told The Post that propofol is not intended for treating insomnia and that the dosages used in this case drastically exceeded safe limits.</p>

<p data-qa="Component-Component" datatype="p">"Propofol is a short-acting general anaesthetic used primarily for inducing and maintaining general anaesthesia and sedation. Typically, clinical doses for anaesthesia induction are 1.5-2.5 mg per kilogram of body weight. For maintenance of anaesthesia, the doses usually range from 4-12 mg per kilogram, while sedation doses vary from 1.5-4.5 mg per kilogram, adjusted according to the procedure and patient's age," the employee explained.</p>

<p data-qa="Component-Component" datatype="p">She added, "An injection dose of 1,300 mg is significantly higher than standard treatment protocols. Fatalities from excessive use of anaesthetics like this are not uncommon. Besides, drug abuse, apart from safety issues, can lead to addiction."</p>

<p data-qa="Component-Component" datatype="p">On November 1, the People's Court of Renshou County in Sichuan Province delivered a verdict, sentencing anesthesiologist Qu to two and a half years in prison for negligent homicide.</p>

<p>The court took into account mitigating factors, including, Qu's voluntary surrender to authorities, his full confession, financial compensation to the victim's family and the family's forgiveness.&nbsp;These factors contributed to a relatively lenient sentence.&nbsp;</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/7gd9kmo8_china-doctor_625x300_17_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[He was sentenced to two and a half years in prison for negligent homicide.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sudha-murty-praises-son-in-law-rishi-sunaks-good-indian-cultural-values-7041811]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Sudha Murty Praises Son-In-Law Rishi Sunak's "Good Indian Cultural Values"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sudha-murty-praises-son-in-law-rishi-sunaks-good-indian-cultural-values-7041811]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 17 Nov 2024 21:12:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Well-known author and Rajya Sabha MP Sudha Murty has spoken of her pride in son-in-law Rishi Sunak, a British citizen with "good Indian cultural values" imbibed from his parents' upbringing in the UK.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well-known author and Rajya Sabha MP Sudha Murty has spoken of her pride in son-in-law Rishi Sunak, a British citizen with "good Indian cultural values" imbibed from his parents' upbringing in the UK.</p>

<p>Sudha Murty joined Rishi Sunak and her daughter Akshata Murty as the guest of honour at Bharatiya Vidya Bhavan's annual Diwali gala in London on Saturday evening.</p>

<p>The parents of the British Indian former prime minister, Usha and Yashvir Sunak, were also in the audience as Bhavan UK students showcased a variety of Indian classical music and dance forms.</p>

<p>"I always believe when you are abroad, your parents must do two things: one is good education, which gives you wings in return and you can fly anywhere and settle; the second is great culture, your origin which is Indian origin or roots which you can get at Bharatiya Vidya Bhavan along with your parents," said Sudha Murty, delivering her keynote address.</p>

<p>"I want to congratulate Ushaji, my sambandhi and a good friend of mine, who gave her son Rishi Sunak, former prime minister, a great route to identify with the culture, making him a proud British citizen as well as [having] good Indian cultural values," she said.</p>

<p>The philanthropist went on to appeal to the British Indian community to enable the work of Bhavan UK's cultural activities, "mentally, physically and financially".</p>

<p>"You must send your children here to understand Indian culture because when you grow old you go towards your roots... that gap is addressed by Bharatiya Vidya Bhavan, so you have to help them in every way to survive," said the staunch supporter of the cultural centre over the years.</p>

<p>Indian High Commissioner to the UK, Vikram Doraiswami, reflected upon Murty's writings which inspire readers to be true to themselves because our "origin story matters" as he went on to trace the pan-Indian message of Diwali.</p>

<p>"The Krishna story is relevant to Diwali in the south, just as the 'Ramayana' story and the return of Lord Ram to Ayodhya from Lanka is connected to the Diwali story of the north and the story of Kali Puja is connected with the story of Diwali in the east," he said.</p>

<p>"Diwali connects up with the Sikh tradition, with the Jain and Buddhist traditions too. It tells us that light also means there is no such thing as a single certainty because in the light you recognise the diversity of the human condition, the diversity of everything we live with. So, in a world in which we spend our time fighting about certainties, it is a really good idea to look at Diwali as an opportunity to consider how so many things look differently in the light." Subhanu Saxena, chairman of The Bhavan UK, and Executive Director Dr M.N. Nandakumara opened the event with Vedic chants as they highlighted the cultural centre's many achievements over the years as a centre of excellence in Indian arts, music, dance, Yoga and languages, offering over 120 classes across 23 different subject areas.</p>

<p>Rishi Sunak and Akshata Murty presented mementoes to the team behind the centre's many activities since the 1970s.</p>

<p>Its students and teachers showcased their Kuchipudi, Kathak and Bharatanatyam skills at the annual Diwali celebration as they appealed for donations from the British Indian community to enhance their summer school and scholarship offerings.</p>

<p>"The Bhavan UK is a great organisation promoting Indian culture and deserves our full support," said NRI industrialist Lord Swraj Paul, one of the many supporters of the centre.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/k076u0vg_rishi-sunak_625x300_17_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sudha Murty congratulated Rishi's mother saying she gave him a great route to identify with the culture.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/prime-minister-narendra-modi-announces-20-tons-of-humanitarian-aid-to-flood-hit-nigeria-7041367]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[PM Modi Announces 20 Tons Of Humanitarian Aid To Flood-Hit Nigeria]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/prime-minister-narendra-modi-announces-20-tons-of-humanitarian-aid-to-flood-hit-nigeria-7041367]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 17 Nov 2024 19:51:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Narendra Modi on Sunday extended condolences to the people of Nigeria for the loss of lives due to the devastating floods that hit the country last month and announced to send 20 tons of humanitarian aid to support the relief efforts.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi on Sunday extended condolences to the people of Nigeria for the loss of lives due to the devastating floods that hit the country last month and announced to send 20 tons of humanitarian aid to support the relief efforts.</p>

<p>"On behalf of 140 crore Indians, I express condolences over the loss of lives due to flood in Nigeria last month. In support of relief works, India is sending 20 tons of humanitarian aid," PM Modi said during a meeting with Nigerian President Bola Ahmed Tinubu in Abuja.</p>

<p>Ahead of the PM's visit, India had also sent 15 tons of humanitarian aid to Nigeria as the country reels under devastating floods.</p>

<p>PM Modi during his address also expressed his heartfelt gratitude to the Nigerian President for his "personal commitment" to strengthening the strategic partnership between India and Nigeria and highlighted the milestones achieved.</p>

<p>"I express gratitude for your personal commitment to strengthening strategic relations between India and Nigeria. I am happy that last year, under the chairmanship of India, Nigeria joined the G20 Summit for the first time as a guest country... It is delightful that Nigeria has been accorded the status of a partner country in BRICS. I congratulate Nigeria on this important achievement. According to me, this is a very historic," PM Modi said.</p>

<p>"As it was said right now, an Indian PM is visiting here after 17 years. It is a matter of great joy for me that right at the beginning of my third tenure, I received the opportunity to visit Nigeria. I am very grateful for this," he said.</p>

<p>He further said, "We give high priority to our strategic partnership with Nigeria. Defence, energy, economy, technology, health, education, culture, etc. are the sectors in which our cooperation is strong... We are working together to overcome many challenges like terrorism, drugs and smuggling and will continue to do so with more strength. The more than 60,000 members of the Indian community living in Nigeria have played an important role in our relations."</p>

<p>PM Modi also expressed his heartfelt gratitude to Nigeria for the National Honor bestowed upon him, stating it as an honour for the 140 crore people of India and the centuries-old relations between the two nations.</p>

<p>"This honour is not only mine, but this is the honour of 140 crore Indians, it is the honour of India and Nigeria's centuries-old relations, this is the honour of those relations. I am very thankful to Nigeria, your government and the people of the country for this honour," PM said.</p>

<p>Notably, Nigeria will honour PM Modi with the Grand Commander of the Order of the Niger (GCON). This makes PM Modi the second foreign dignitary to receive this honour. Queen Elizabeth is the only other foreign dignitary who was awarded the GCON, in 1969. This will be the 17th such international award conferred to PM Modi by a country.</p>

<p>Notably, PM Modi met with Nigerian President Bola Ahmed Tinubu at the Presidential Villa in Abuja on Sunday.</p>

<p>The two leaders held a meeting at the President's House in Abuja.</p>

<p>Earlier, Tinubu also expressed his eagerness to welcome Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi on his historic first visit to Nigeria.</p>

<p>Sharing a post on X, the Nigerian President wrote, "I look forward to welcoming Prime Minister Narendra Modi on his first visit to Nigeria, which is also the first visit by an Indian Prime Minister to our dear country since 2007. Our bilateral discussions will seek to expand the strategic partnership between both countries and enhance cooperation in critical sectors. Welcome to Nigeria, PM Modi @narendramodi."</p>

<p>Notably, PM Modi on Sunday arrived in Nigeria on the first leg of his three-nation tour.</p>

<p>Upon his arrival, PM Modi was warmly welcomed by Nyesom Ezenwo Wike, Minister for Federal Capital Territory in Abuja, the capital city of the Federal Republic of Nigeria.</p>

<p>Wike presented PM Modi with the 'Key to the City' of Abuja. The key symbolises the trust and honour bestowed on the PM by the people of Nigeria.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi is on a three-nation tour to Nigeria, Brazil and Guyana scheduled from November 17 to November 21.</p>

<p>PM Modi issued a statement indicating his first stop in Nigeria, following President Bola Ahmed Tinubu's invitation, aimed at strengthening strategic ties between both countries.</p>

<p>"At the invitation of President Bola Ahmed Tinubu, this will be my first visit to Nigeria, which is our close partner in the West African region. My visit will be an opportunity to build upon our Strategic Partnership that is based on shared belief in democracy and pluralism. I am also eagerly looking forward to meeting the Indian community and friends from Nigeria who have sent me warm welcome messages in Hindi," the statement said.</p>

<p>India and Nigeria enjoy warm, friendly, and deep-rooted bilateral relations.</p>

<p>The visit by PM Modi is the first visit by a Prime Minister of India to Nigeria in 17 years.</p>

<p>India is emerging as a development partner of Nigeria on two fronts - by offering developmental assistance through concessional loans and by offering capacity-building training programmes.</p>

<p>India and Nigeria have been strategic partners since 2007 with growing economic, energy and defence collaboration. More than 200 Indian companies have invested over USD 27 billion in important sectors in Nigeria. India and Nigeria also share a strong development cooperation partnership.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ecr0nbt_pm-modi-nigeria_625x300_17_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[PM Modi during his address also expressed his heartfelt gratitude to the Nigerian President.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/senators-demand-investigation-into-elon-musks-alleged-russian-involvement-7041296]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Senators Demand Investigation Into Elon Musk's Alleged Russian Involvement]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/senators-demand-investigation-into-elon-musks-alleged-russian-involvement-7041296]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 17 Nov 2024 19:42:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The lawmakers want the Pentagon and Justice Department to probe whether Musk's relationships with a US adversary compromise national security, especially given his major government contracts.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Top Senate Democrats - Rhode Island Senator Jack Reed and New Hampshire Senator Jeanne Shaheen are calling for an investigation into Elon Musk's alleged ties with Russian President Vladimir Putin and his top officials.&nbsp;</p>

<p>They sent a letter to Attorney General Merrick Garland and Defence Department Inspector General Robert Storch raising "serious questions regarding Mr Musk's reliability as a government contractor and a [security] clearance holder".</p>

<p>The lawmakers want the Pentagon and Justice Department to probe whether Musk's relationships with a US adversary compromise national security, especially given his major government contracts.</p>

<p>Musk's reported "multiple, high-level conversations" with Putin since 2022 have raised eyebrows, despite the Kremlin's denial, according to The Wall Street Journal.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The billionaire's response to the accusations was fiery, vowing to "nuke" those behind the claims on his X platform, "going to find out who's making these accusations and nuke them".</p>

<p>Reed and Shaheen question Musk's reliability as a government contractor and security clearance holder, citing his alleged communications with Putin's deputy chief of staff, Sergei Kiriyenko.</p>

<p>The senators highlight Russia's space ambitions as a direct threat to US national security. They're concerned that Musk, with his top-secret level clearance, doesn't report his foreign government contacts, unlike others with similar clearances. SpaceX's deep involvement in US defense and intelligence infrastructure adds to the concerns.</p>

<p>Musk's ties to the US government extend beyond contracts; he backed Trump's 2024 election bid and participated in diplomatic efforts, including calls with Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky, Turkish President Tayyip Erdogan and meeting Argentinian President Javier Milei in Trump's Florida home.</p>

<p>However, his recent visit to the Iranian UN ambassador's residence in New York has sparked controversy, with Iran's foreign minister denying the meeting took place.</p>

<p>The investigation request underscores growing scrutiny of Musk's foreign connections and their implications for US national security.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/eta35gmg_elon-musk-reuters_625x300_17_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Musk's reported "multiple, high-level conversations" with Putin since 2022 have raised eyebrows]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/woman-goes-to-doctor-for-sore-throat-only-to-find-shes-pregnant-with-quadruplets-7040921]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Woman Visits Doctor For Sore Throat, Finds She's Pregnant With Quadruplets]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/woman-goes-to-doctor-for-sore-throat-only-to-find-shes-pregnant-with-quadruplets-7040921]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 17 Nov 2024 18:40:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The odds of conceiving spontaneous quadruplets are less than one in 500,000.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Katelyn Yates, a 20-year-old nursing assistant from Illinois, visited a hospital on April 1, expecting to get treatment for her sore throat. Instead, she received life-changing news that she was pregnant with quadruplets. Ms Yates shared her incredible story with <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.today.com/parents/family/mom-goes-hospital-finds-pregnant-quadruplets-rcna179200">Today</a></em>, recounting how her hospital visit started with throat pain that led doctors to recommend an X-ray.&nbsp;As a precautionary measure, doctors also asked Yates to take a pregnancy test before the X-ray, since radiation can be harmful to a fetus. Surprisingly, her pregnancy test came back positive, and her human chorionic gonadotropin (hCG) levels were "off the charts," indicating multiple fetuses.</p>

<p>Notably, hCG is a hormone produced by the placenta during pregnancy, detectable by blood tests around 11 days after conception and urine tests about 12-14 days after conception. Typically, hCG levels double every 72 hours, peaking between 8-11 weeks of pregnancy before levelling off.</p>

<p>Ms Yates thought it was an April Fool's Day joke at first, but reality soon set in. His fiance, Julian Bueker, was overjoyed when he heard the news, which helped calm her nerves.&nbsp;As Yates' pregnancy advanced, complications arose, leading to a diagnosis of preeclampsia, a condition characterised by high blood pressure after 20 weeks. She endured debilitating symptoms, including difficulty breathing, liver complications and kidney issues.&nbsp;</p>

<p>At 28 weeks and 4 days, Yates underwent an emergency C-section at HSHS St. John's Hospital in Springfield, Illinois, delivering quadruplets on October 17.&nbsp;The smallest baby was Elizabeth, who weighed 1 pound 2 ounces; while Max, the largest of the bunch, weighed 2 pounds, 6 ounces.</p>

<p>However, all four babies are doing remarkably well, gaining weight and growing. "They're doing phenomenal. They are gaining weight and growing. Elizabeth is about six grams away from reaching two pounds," she told <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.today.com/parents/family/mom-goes-hospital-finds-pregnant-quadruplets-rcna179200">Today.&nbsp;</a></em></p>

<p>The odds of conceiving spontaneous quadruplets are less than one in 500,000, according to the<a href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC6571448/#B1" target="_blank">&nbsp;Journal of Family and Reproductive Health</a>.&nbsp;As per the Mayo Clinic, various factors contribute to premature birth. A woman's previous experiences with pregnancy, such as having had a premature birth or abortion, can increase the risk. Additionally, underlying health issues like uterine abnormalities, high blood pressure, and diabetes can also play a role.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/oa4eclp8_pregnancy_625x300_17_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[HCG is a hormone produced by the placenta during pregnancy, detectable by blood tests]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/cop29-no-progress-at-cop29-in-matters-critical-for-developing-nations-says-india-7040916]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["No Progress At COP29 In Matters Critical For Developing Nations": India]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/cop29-no-progress-at-cop29-in-matters-critical-for-developing-nations-says-india-7040916]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 17 Nov 2024 18:38:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[At COP29 in Baku, India expressed frustration with developed countries for not seriously discussing how to support climate action in developing nations, saying it is impossible to tackle climate change without financial and technological help.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At COP29 in Baku, India expressed frustration with developed countries for not seriously discussing how to support climate action in developing nations, saying it is impossible to tackle climate change without financial and technological help.</p>

<p>Delivering a statement in the closing plenary of the subsidiary bodies' meeting on the Mitigation Work Programme (MWP) on Saturday, India said developed countries, which have historically contributed the most to greenhouse gas emissions and have more resources and the ability to act on climate change, have repeatedly delayed climate action and continuously shifted goalposts.</p>

<p>"We have seen no progress in matters critical for developing countries (during the last week). Our part of the world is facing some of the worst impacts of climate change with far lower capacity to recover from those impacts or to adapt to the changes to the climatic system for which we are not responsible," said India's deputy lead negotiator Neelesh Sah.</p>

<p>He said the MWP is meant to help, not punish, and must respect each country's right to set its own climate goals based on its unique needs and circumstances.</p>

<p>Neelesh Sah said that if there are no means of implementation -- financial support, technology, and capacity-building -- developing and low-income economies cannot cut greenhouse gas emissions and adapt to its effects.</p>

<p>"How can we discuss climate action when it is being made impossible for us to act even as our challenges in dealing with the impacts of climate change are increasing?" the Indian negotiator said.</p>

<p>India said developed countries with the highest capacity to take climate action had "continuously shifted goals, delayed climate action, and consumed a highly disproportionate share of the global carbon budget".</p>

<p>"We now have to meet our developmental needs in a situation where the carbon budget is depleting and the impacts of climate change are increasing. We are being asked to increase mitigation ambition by those who have shown no such ambition -- neither in their mitigation efforts nor in providing the means of implementation." "The bottom-up approach is being attempted to be made into a top-down approach, in turn attempting to turn the whole mandate of the MWP and the principles of the Paris Agreement upside down. For the past week, at the 'finance COP', we have been frustrated by the unwillingness of developed countries to engage on this issue," Sah said.</p>

<p>At COP29, countries are discussing how the MWP -- created two years ago at COP27 in Sharm el-Sheikh, Egypt, to help support mitigation -- should work and what it should focus on.</p>

<p>Consultations on the MWP have remained tense, with developing countries saying that it was meant to help nations share ideas, experiences, and solutions for cutting emissions.</p>

<p>They argue that it was not supposed to create new targets or force any country to take specific actions.</p>

<p>On the other hand, developed countries want the MWP to push for stronger, more immediate action from all countries.</p>

<p>Overall, a new climate finance package to help developing nations reduce greenhouse gas emissions and adapt to climate change is the top priority of this year's UN climate talks.</p>

<p>In 2009, developed countries promised to provide USD 100 billion every year by 2020 to support climate action in developing countries, but this goal was only met in 2022.</p>

<p>Of the money provided, about 70 per cent came as loans, which increased the financial burden on low-income countries already struggling with the impacts of climate change.</p>

<p>With climate impacts worsening, developing countries need at least USD 1.3 trillion every year in financial support.</p>

<p>They argue this should come from developed countries' government funding, not from the private sector, which is driven by profit and not accountable to the UN climate process.</p>

<p>There has been little progress on this issue during the talks, with developed countries pushing for the climate finance package to be a "global investment goal", including money from all sectors -- public, private, domestic, and international.</p>

<p>"Climate finance cannot be changed into an investment goal when it is a unidirectional provision and mobilisation goal from the developed to the developing countries. The Paris Agreement is clear on who is to provide and mobilise the climate finance - it is the developed countries," India's lead negotiator Naresh Pal Gangwar said on Thursday during a high-level dialogue on climate finance.</p>

<p>Some developed countries led by the EU and the US argue the global economic landscape has shifted significantly since 1992. They suggest nations that have become wealthier since then, like China and some Gulf states, should also contribute to the new climate finance goal.</p>

<p>Developing countries view this as an attempt to shift responsibility from those who have historically benefited from industrialisation and contributed the most to greenhouse gas emissions.</p>

<p>They argue that expecting them to contribute, especially when many are still grappling with poverty and inadequate infrastructure amid worsening climate impacts, undermines the principle of equity.</p>

<p>The potential withdrawal of the US and Argentina from the Paris Agreement has significantly affected the morale of negotiators at COP29.</p>

<p>However, countries like China, the UK, and Brazil have taken a strong leadership role, offering hope for a much-needed deal to maintain confidence in the multilateral diplomatic system.</p>

<p>Negotiators are now looking for a strong signal from G20 heads of governments who will meet at Rio De Janeiro in Brazil on November 18-19.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/u9j09i_cop29_625x300_04_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[At COP29, countries are discussing how the MWP should work and what it should focus on. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-spokesman-killed-in-israeli-strike-on-beirut-report-7040828]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hezbollah Spokesman Killed In Israeli Strike On Beirut: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-spokesman-killed-in-israeli-strike-on-beirut-report-7040828]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 17 Nov 2024 18:24:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Lebanese security source said Hezbollah spokesman Mohammed Afif was killed in an Israeli strike Sunday in central Beirut that hit the Lebanese branch of the Syrian Baath party.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Lebanese security source said Hezbollah spokesman Mohammed Afif was killed in an Israeli strike Sunday in central Beirut that hit the Lebanese branch of the Syrian Baath party.</p>

<p>"The strike on Ras al-Nabaa killed Hezbollah media relations official Mohammed Afif," the security source said, requesting anonymity as they were not authorised to brief the media.</p>

<p>Ali Hijazi, secretary-general of the Lebanese branch of the Baath party, "confirmed the death of Hezbollah media official" Afif, the official National News Agency reported.</p>

<p>The Israeli army declined to comment, but Afif is the latest in a long line of Hezbollah officials killed since Israel on September 23 began heavily bombarding Hezbollah strongholds after almost a year of cross-border exchanges with the Iran-backed group over the Gaza war.</p>

<p>Lebanon's health ministry said the strike killed one person and wounded three others, adding that the toll was provisional and that work was ongoing to remove rubble from the site of the strike.</p>

<p>Afif was part of the inner circle of longtime Hezbollah chief Hassan Nasrallah, who was killed in an Israeli strike in September.</p>

<p>For years, Afif had been responsible for Hezbollah's media relations, providing information to local and foreign journalists, often under the cover of anonymity.</p>

<p>The NNA said the strike by "enemy aircraft" caused "great destruction", reporting an unspecified number of people "trapped under the rubble" in Ras al-Nabaa, an area near the French embassy and a university.</p>

<p>It said "one of the residents of a neighbouring building had received a warning call urging evacuation but it was not taken seriously".</p>

<p>Afif joined Hezbollah at a young age and first came to prominence as information director for Hezbollah's television channel Al-Manar when the group and Israel went to war in 2006.</p>

<p>After Nasrallah's assassination, Afif had held several press conferences in Beirut's southern suburbs, including one last month in which he announced Hezbollah had launched a drone targeting the residence of Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu.</p>

<p>That press conference was cut short when the Israeli army warned it would strike a building nearby.</p>

<p>"Bombardments have not scared us, so how would threats?" Afif said defiantly as journalists hurriedly collected their microphones from the table.</p>

<p>Hezbollah officials killed in previous Israeli strikes include not only Nasrallah but also Hashem Safieddine, tipped as the former chief's successor.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/5fduuho_beirut-afp_625x300_17_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The strike targeted Lebanese branch of the Syrian Baath party, said Lebanese security source]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/saudi-executes-over-100-foreigners-in-2024-report-7040603]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Saudi Executes Over 100 Foreigners In 2024: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/saudi-executes-over-100-foreigners-in-2024-report-7040603]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 17 Nov 2024 17:45:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Saudi Arabia has executed more than 100 foreigners this year, according to an AFP tally indicating a sharp increase which one rights group said was unprecedented.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Saudi Arabia has executed more than 100 foreigners this year, according to an AFP tally indicating a sharp increase which one rights group said was unprecedented.</p>

<p>The latest execution, on Saturday in the southwestern region of Najran, was of a Yemeni national convicted of smuggling drugs into the Gulf kingdom, the official Saudi Press Agency reported.</p>

<p>That brought to 101 the number of foreigners executed so far in 2024, according to the tally which is compiled from state media reports.</p>

<p>This is almost triple the figures for 2023 and 2022, when Saudi authorities had put to death 34 foreigners each year, according to AFP tallies.</p>

<p>The Berlin-based European-Saudi Organisation for Human Rights (ESOHR) said this year's executions had already broken a record.</p>

<p>"This is the largest number of executions of foreigners in one year. Saudi Arabia has never executed 100 foreigners in a year," said Taha al-Hajji, the group's legal director.</p>

<p>Saudi Arabia has faced persistent criticism over its use of the death penalty, which human rights groups have condemned as excessive and out of step with efforts to soften its forbidding image and welcome international tourists and investors.</p>

<p>The oil-rich kingdom executed the third highest number of prisoners in the world after China and Iran in 2023, according to Amnesty International.</p>

<p>In September, AFP reported that Saudi Arabia had carried out its highest number of executions in more than three decades, surpassing its previous highs of 196 in 2022 and 192 in 1995.</p>

<p>Executions have continued at a rapid clip since then and totalled 274 for the year as of Sunday, according to AFP's tally.</p>

<p><strong>'Execution crisis'</strong></p>

<p>Foreigners executed this year have included 21 from Pakistan, 20 from Yemen, 14 from Syria, 10 from Nigeria, nine from Egypt, eight from Jordan and seven from Ethiopia.</p>

<p>There were also three each from Sudan, India and Afghanistan, and one each from Sri Lanka, Eritrea and the Philippines.</p>

<p>Saudi Arabia in 2022 ended a three-year moratorium on the execution of drug offenders, and executions for drug-related crimes have boosted this year's numbers.</p>

<p>There have been 92 such executions so far this year, 69 of them of foreigners, according to the AFP tally.</p>

<p>Diplomats and activists say that foreign defendants usually face a higher barrier to fair trials, including the right to access court documents.</p>

<p>Foreigners "are the most vulnerable group", said Hajji of the ESOHR.</p>

<p>Not only are they often "victims of major drug dealers" but also "subjected to a series of violations from the moment of their arrest until their execution," he said.</p>

<p>Saudi Arabia is notorious for beheading those convicted of capital crimes, although official statements tend not to mention the method of execution.</p>

<p>The high number of executions undercuts statements by Saudi Arabia's de facto ruler, Crown Prince Mohammed bin Salman, who told The Atlantic in 2022 that the kingdom had eliminated the death penalty with the exception of murder cases or when an individual posed a threat to many lives.</p>

<p>Jeed Basyouni, who heads Middle East anti-death penalty advocacy for the NGO Reprieve, said persistent drug arrests were "perpetuating the cycle of violence".</p>

<p>The overall number of executions was on track to exceed 300 for the year, she noted.</p>

<p>"This is an unprecedented execution crisis in Saudi Arabia," said Basyouni.</p>

<p>"Families of foreign nationals on death row are understandably terrified that their loved one will be next."<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ag44m6e_saudi-generic-unsplash_625x300_17_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[This is almost triple the figures for 2023 and 2022 (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-modi-receives-nigerias-gcon-award-2nd-foreign-dignitary-after-queen-elizabeth-7040499]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[PM Modi 2nd Foreign Guest After Queen Elizabeth To Get Nigeria's GCON Award]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-modi-receives-nigerias-gcon-award-2nd-foreign-dignitary-after-queen-elizabeth-7040499]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 17 Nov 2024 17:25:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[This prestigious award is Nigeria's second-highest national honour, and it marks a milestone in the bilateral relations between the two nations.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a significant move to strengthen diplomatic ties between Nigeria and India, President Bola Tinubu has conferred the Grand Commander of the Order of the Niger (GCON) upon Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi.</p>

<p>This prestigious award is Nigeria's second-highest national honour, and it marks a milestone in the bilateral relations between the two nations.</p>

<p>The award was announced during a bilateral meeting held at the Aso Rock Presidential Villa in Abuja, where Mr. Modi was warmly received by President Tinubu. The Indian leader arrived in Abuja on Saturday evening and was welcomed with the Indian Anthem, followed by a Guard of Honour and a 21-gun salute.</p>

<p>President Tinubu emphasised that the honour is "to signify our appreciation of India as Nigeria's partner."&nbsp;</p>

<p>This gesture underscores the strong strategic partnership between the two countries, which was established in 2007 during Dr. Manmohan Singh's state visit. Mr. Modi's visit is the first by an Indian prime minister since Dr. Manmohan Singh's state visit in 2007.</p>

<p>President Tinubu and Prime Minister Modi will engage in bilateral discussions to further enhance collaboration in critical sectors. The two leaders will exchange signed MOUs to strengthen cooperation in key areas. The visit will feature delegation-level talks, marking a significant step forward in Nigeria-India relations.</p>

<p>This honour is the 17th international award conferred upon Prime Minister Modi, solidifying his reputation as a key player in global diplomacy. The Grand Commander of the Order of the Niger (GCON) has previously been awarded to Queen Elizabeth II in 1969, making Mr. Modi the second foreign dignitary to receive this prestigious honour.</p>

<p>As Nigeria and India continue to foster their strategic partnership, this visit is expected to yield significant outcomes in areas such as economic development, energy, and defence. With over 200 Indian companies investing more than USD 27 billion in critical sectors in Nigeria, the bilateral relationship is poised for further growth and cooperation.</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/d36aoeto_modi-in-nigeria-pti_625x300_17_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mr. Modi is the second foreign dignitary to receive this prestigious honour.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-asian-woman-24-found-murdered-in-car-boot-in-east-london-7040439]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[South Asian Woman, 24, Found Murdered In Car Boot In London]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-asian-woman-24-found-murdered-in-car-boot-in-east-london-7040439]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 17 Nov 2024 17:12:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 24-year-old woman believed to be of South Asian origin has been found murdered in a car boot in east London after a missing person inquiry was launched for her in the East Midlands region of England.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 24-year-old woman believed to be of South Asian origin has been found murdered in a car boot in east London after a missing person inquiry was launched for her in the East Midlands region of England.</p>

<p>Northamptonshire Police named the victim as Harshita Brella on Saturday night as the force launched a murder inquiry and appealed for information in the case.</p>

<p>Police said it had received a call on Wednesday regarding concerns for Harshita's welfare and officers were deployed to her home address at Skegness Walk in Corby, Northamptonshire.</p>

<p>After getting no answer, the police launched a missing person investigation and fast-track enquiries were made which led to the discovery of the victim's body inside the boot of a vehicle on Brisbane Road in the Ilford area of east London in the early hours of Thursday.</p>

<p>A post-mortem was conducted at Leicester Royal Infirmary on Friday which established the murder victim as Harshita Brella, whose name indicates a South Asian heritage, but there is no further confirmation of her family background at this stage of the inquiry.</p>

<p>"First of all, I want to express my heartfelt condolences to everyone who loved Harshita Brella," said Detective Chief Inspector Johnny Campbell, Senior Investigating Officer from the East Midlands Special Operations Major Crime Unit (EMSOU).</p>

<p>"She was a young woman in her early 20s with her whole life ahead of her and it is absolutely tragic that her life has been cut short in this way. Detectives from EMSOU and Northamptonshire Police are working around the clock to establish the circumstances behind her death, including the exact location and timeframe in which it took place," he said.</p>

<p>Investigators believe Harshita was killed in a "targeted incident" as they appealed to anyone who may have information about the incident to come forward.</p>

<p>"Although we believe Harshita was attacked by someone known to her, we are keeping an open mind, and would appeal to anyone who knew her to contact us with any relevant information they may have," Campbell said.</p>

<p>If you saw anything suspicious in the past week or have any information, no matter how small, please contact us. We would always rather receive well-meaning information that turns out to be nothing as opposed to not receiving it all," he said.</p>

<p>The police said officers were satisfied there is no wider risk to the public as a result of this incident, however, extra patrols will be taking place in Corby in the coming days for reassurance purposes.</p>

<p>As is mandatory, Northamptonshire Police has also made a referral to the Independent Office for Police Conduct (IOPC) due to previous contact between the police force and the victim.</p>

<p>"Shortly after midnight on the morning of Thursday, November 14, the Met was contacted by officers from Northamptonshire Police raising concerns for the welfare of a woman who was believed to be in a car in the east London area," a Metropolitan Police spokesperson said.</p>

<p>"The car was located parked in Brisbane Road, Ilford, and the body of a 24-year-old woman was found inside the vehicle," the spokesperson said.</p>

<p>The police investigators are now working to establish the connection between Harshita going missing from her home in Corby, around 145km north of London, and being found dead in a car in the UK capital days later.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-12/ima4e49o_uk-police_625x300_14_December_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The body was found inside the boot of a vehicle on Brisbane Road of east London.(Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/red-skull-masks-swastikas-racial-slurs-neo-nazi-group-marches-in-ohio-7040054]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Red Skull Masks, Swastikas, Racial Slurs: Neo-Nazi Group Marches In Ohio]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/red-skull-masks-swastikas-racial-slurs-neo-nazi-group-marches-in-ohio-7040054]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 17 Nov 2024 16:00:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A group of masked people dressed in black and carrying black flags with red swastikas marched through the Short North neighbourhood of Columbus in Ohio on Saturday afternoon, drawing swift condemnation from state and city officials.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A group of masked people dressed in black and carrying black flags with red swastikas marched through the Short North neighbourhood of Columbus in Ohio on Saturday afternoon, drawing swift condemnation from state and city officials. As they paraded, they shouted racial slurs, and their masks featured a red skull design.</p>

<p>Ohio Governor Mike DeWine condemned the demonstration and decried the display of hate on social media. "We will not tolerate hate in Ohio," Mr DeWine said. "Neo-Nazis -- their faces hidden behind red masks -- roamed streets in Columbus today, carrying Nazi flags and spewing vile and racist speech against people of colour and Jews. There were reports that they were also espousing white power sentiments." He added, "There is no place in this State for hate, bigotry, antisemitism, or violence, and we must denounce it wherever we see it."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="zxx"><a href="https://t.co/pqA4h5L9K7">pic.twitter.com/pqA4h5L9K7</a></p>
â€” Governor Mike DeWine (@GovMikeDeWine) <a href="https://twitter.com/GovMikeDeWine/status/1857957427783561450?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 17, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Videos and pictures began circulating on social media showing about a dozen masked individuals walking through the streets.</p>

<p>A user wrote, "Neo-Nazis marched through the streets of Columbus, Ohio today, clamoring for "white power." Masked men dressed in black waved black flags with red swastikas, ranting at all people of colour and shouting antisemitic slurs. You can bet these were emboldened Trump voters."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Neo-Nazis marched through the streets of Columbus, Ohio today, clamoring for â€œwhite power.â€<br />
<br />
Masked men dressed in black waved black flags with red swastikas, ranting at all people of color and shouting antisemitic slurs.<br />
<br />
You can bet these were emboldened Trump voters. <a href="https://t.co/oENUckX7zT">pic.twitter.com/oENUckX7zT</a></p>
â€” Stephanie Kennedy (@WordswithSteph) <a href="https://twitter.com/WordswithSteph/status/1857955520759398808?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 17, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">âš ï¸ EXPLICIT: Viewers shared video with us of a group of neo-nazis marching through downtown Columbus, yelling racial slurs. Tonight residents and community leaders are denouncing the hate. Video credit to Dwight Holland. <a href="https://twitter.com/10TV?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@10TV</a> <a href="https://t.co/g13LH8CWj4">pic.twitter.com/g13LH8CWj4</a></p>
â€” Carla Rogner (@CarlaRogner) <a href="https://twitter.com/CarlaRogner/status/1857962808027083259?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 17, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Someone wrote on X, â€œFeds had a Neo-Nazi parade in Columbus, OH today pretending to be MAGA .â€</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Feds had a Neo-Nazi parade in Columbus, OH today pretending to be MAGA<br />
<br />
Link below in comments.???? <a href="https://t.co/ntx7nURqFl">pic.twitter.com/ntx7nURqFl</a></p>
â€” Ashtronaut Girl (@AshtronautGirl) <a href="https://twitter.com/AshtronautGirl/status/1857921756813734371?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 16, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The City of Columbus also addressed the incident, emphasising the community's values of tolerance and safety. "We will not allow any of our neighbours to be intimidated, threatened, or harmed because of who they are, how they worship, or whom they love," the city said in a statement reported by <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://abcnews.go.com/US/masked-group-marches-ohio-neighborhood-swastikas-flags/story?id=115937210">ABC News</a>. It also called the march a "cowardly display" and assured residents that authorities are working to ensure the city's security.</p>

<p>City Attorney Zach Klein addressed the group directly, urging them to leave the city permanently. "Take your flags and the masks you hide behind and go home and never come back," Mr Klein said in a statement on X. "Your hate isn't welcome in our city."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">To those involved in the neo-Nazi march in the Short North today, take your flags and the masks you hide behind and go home and never come back.<br />
<br />
Your hate isn't welcome in our city. <a href="https://t.co/m9JpOrwxZQ">pic.twitter.com/m9JpOrwxZQ</a></p>
â€” Columbus City Attorney Zach Klein (@CityAttyKlein) <a href="https://twitter.com/CityAttyKlein/status/1857878822437191920?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 16, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>This demonstration comes just a week after a similar display outside a production of <em>The Diary of Anne Frank</em> in Howell, Michigan, where masked protesters waved Nazi flags. In that instance, no arrests were made, though the individuals were asked to leave.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/a63eumtg_neo-nazi-rally-us_625x300_17_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Videos and pictures of the incident are circulating on social media]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-and-xi-unite-on-nuclear-safety-humans-over-ai-7039906]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden And Xi Unite On Nuclear Safety: Humans Over AI]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-and-xi-unite-on-nuclear-safety-humans-over-ai-7039906]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 17 Nov 2024 15:36:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden and Chinese President Xi Jinping made a landmark agreement on Saturday, emphasising the importance of human decision-making over artificial intelligence when it comes to nuclear weapons.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden and Chinese President Xi Jinping made a landmark agreement on Saturday, emphasising the importance of human decision-making over artificial intelligence when it comes to nuclear weapons.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The two leaders affirmed the need to maintain human control over the decision to use nuclear weapons," said a statement from the White House. "The two leaders also stressed the need to consider carefully the potential risks and develop AI technology in the military field in a prudent and responsible manner."</p>

<p>This breakthrough marks a significant step forward in discussions between the two nations on nuclear arms and artificial intelligence, areas where progress has been challenging.</p>

<p>The US has been pushing China to engage in nuclear arms talks for months, but negotiations stalled after briefly resuming in November, with the US expressing frustration regarding China's responsiveness.</p>

<p>The US Defense Department estimates that China currently possesses around 500 operational nuclear warheads, with projections suggesting this number will exceed 1,000 by 2030.&nbsp;</p>

<p>This rapid buildup has raised concerns, particularly given China's modernised nuclear program, which includes advanced ballistic missile submarines, hypersonic glide vehicles, and regular nuclear-armed sea patrols.</p>

<p>China's nuclear arsenal is dwarfed by those of Russia (1,710 operational warheads) and the US (1,770 operational warheads), but its advancements have sparked worries about a potential arms race. Despite this, China maintains a policy of no first use and advocates for minimal nuclear deterrence.</p>

<p>The Biden administration updated its classified nuclear guidance earlier this year, citing concerns about nuclear arsenals in China, North Korea, and Russia. While this agreement is a positive step, it remains unclear whether it will lead to further talks or concrete actions.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/dddn3te_biden-jinping-reuters_625x300_17_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[This marks a significant step forward in discussions between the two nations on nuclear arms and AI]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/xi-tells-biden-about-chinas-4-red-lines-that-us-must-not-cross-7039771]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Xi Tells Biden About China's 4 "Red Lines" That US Must Not Cross]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/xi-tells-biden-about-chinas-4-red-lines-that-us-must-not-cross-7039771]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 17 Nov 2024 15:10:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Chinese President Xi Jinping warned the United States on Saturday not to cross a "red line" in support for Taiwan, but told his counterpart Joe Biden that Beijing was willing to work with the incoming administration of Donald Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Chinese President Xi Jinping warned the United States on Saturday not to cross a "red line" in support for Taiwan, but told his counterpart Joe Biden that Beijing was willing to work with the incoming administration of Donald Trump.</p>

<p>Biden and Xi met on the sidelines of the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) summit in Peru, two months before Trump takes office and amid concerns of new trade wars and diplomatic upheaval.</p>

<p>China claims Taiwan as its own territory and has refused to rule out using force to seize it, while the United States is the self-ruled island's main security backer even though it does not recognise Taipei diplomatically.</p>

<p>Xi told Biden that the "Taiwan issue, democracy and human rights, pathways and systems, and development interests are China's four red lines that must not be challenged", according to Chinese state broadcaster CCTV.</p>

<p>"These are the most important guardrails and safety net for China-US relations," CCTV reported Xi as saying.</p>

<p>"The separatist actions of 'Taiwan independence' are incompatible with peace and stability in the Taiwan Strait," he added.</p>

<p>Taiwan's foreign ministry said Sunday that "China's ongoing military provocations near Taiwan are the root cause of destroying regional peace and stability and the major threat to global economic prosperity".</p>

<p>Xi also told Biden that Washington "should not intervene in bilateral disputes... and not condone or support provocative impulses" in the South China Sea, according to CCTV.</p>

<p>Beijing has this year pressed its sweeping claims in the contested waterway with greater assertiveness, despite increased frictions with regional neighbours and a longstanding international ruling that its claims have no legal basis.</p>

<p>Xi also said China's position on the war in Ukraine was "open and aboveboard", and that Beijing would not allow tensions on the Korean peninsula to "descend into conflict or chaos", CCTV reported.</p>

<p>He announced during a separate meeting that China would host the next APEC summit in 2026.</p>

<p>State news agency Xinhua said those talks would aim to "unite Asia-Pacific countries to champion open economic and trade cooperation while rejecting protectionist and confrontational trade tactics".</p>

<h2><strong>'Smooth transition'</strong></h2>

<p>But Xi said China would "strive for a smooth transition" in relations with the United States and is ready to work with the incoming Trump government.</p>

<p>"China is ready to work with the new US administration to maintain communication, expand cooperation and manage differences, so as to strive for a smooth transition of the China-US relationship," Xi told Biden through a translator.</p>

<p>In his first White House term, Trump engaged in a bruising trade war with China, imposing tariffs on billions of dollars in Chinese products and drawing retaliation from Beijing.</p>

<p>He embraced a similar stance on the campaign trail this year.</p>

<p>Both sides should "keep exploring the right way for the two major countries to get along well with each other," Xi said.</p>

<p>Xi warned Saturday that bilateral ties could "encounter twists and turns or even regress" if one side regarded the other as an opponent or enemy, according to the official Xinhua news agency.</p>

<p>"Major country competition should not be the underlying logic of the times," Xi added, urging against a "small yard, high fences" approach. He added that "a stable China-US relationship is critical" to both parties and the world, noting that Beijing continues to aim for healthy ties.</p>

<p>But he stressed that Beijing's position of "firmly safeguarding its sovereignty, security and development interests has not changed," according to Xinhua.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ovd5tjcg_biden-xi-afp_625x300_17_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Biden and Xi met on the sidelines of the APEC summit in Peru.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>