<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Fri, 16 Aug 2024 08:35:05 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-is-the-dinosaur-killing-asteroids-origin-scientists-have-an-answer-6347594]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What Is The Dinosaur-Killing Asteroid's Origin? Scientists Have An Answer]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-is-the-dinosaur-killing-asteroids-origin-scientists-have-an-answer-6347594]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 16 Aug 2024 07:50:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An intense debate surrounding the cosmic rock that killed the dinosaurs has stirred scientists for decades, but a new study has revealed some important -- and far-out -- data about the impactor's origin story.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An intense debate surrounding the cosmic rock that killed the dinosaurs has stirred scientists for decades, but a new study has revealed some important -- and far-out -- data about the impactor's origin story.</p>

<p>Researchers, whose findings were published Thursday in the journal Science, used an innovative technique to demonstrate that the apocalyptic culprit which slammed into the Earth's surface 66 million years ago, causing the most recent mass extinction, had formed beyond Jupiter's orbit.</p>

<p>They also refute the idea that it was a comet.</p>

<p>The new insights into the apparent asteroid that cratered into Chicxulub, in what is present-day Mexico's Yucatan Peninsula, could improve the understanding of celestial objects that have struck our planet.</p>

<p>"Now we can, with all this knowledge... say that this asteroid initially formed beyond Jupiter," Mario Fischer-Godde, lead author of the study and a geochemist at the University of Cologne, told AFP.</p>

<p>The conclusions are particularly notable, given how rarely this type of asteroid collides with Earth.</p>

<p>Such information may well prove useful in assessing future threats, or determining how water arrived on this planet, Fischer-Godde said.</p>

<h3><strong>Samples&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>The new findings are based on an analysis of sediment samples formed at the period between the Cretaceous and Paleogene eras, the time of the asteroid's cataclysmic impact.</p>

<p>Researchers measured the isotopes of the element ruthenium, which is not uncommon on asteroids but extremely rare on Earth. So by inspecting the deposits in multiple geological layers that mark the debris from the impact at Chicxulub, they could be sure that the ruthenium studied came "100 per cent from this asteroid."</p>

<p>"Our lab in Cologne is one of the rare labs that can do these measurements," and it was the first time such study techniques were used on impact debris layers, Fischer-Godde said.</p>

<p>Ruthenium isotopes can be used to distinguish between the two main groups of asteroids: C-type, or carbonaceous, asteroids that formed in the outer solar system, and S-type silicate asteroids from the inner solar system, nearer the sun.</p>

<p>The study affirms that the asteroid that triggered a mega-earthquake, precipitated a global winter and wiped out the dinosaurs and most other life, was a C-type asteroid that formed beyond Jupiter.</p>

<p>Studies from two decades ago had already made such an assumption but with far less certainty.</p>

<p>The conclusions are striking, because most meteorites -- pieces of asteroids that fall to Earth -- are S-types, Fischer-Godde pointed out.</p>

<p>Does that mean the Chicxulub impactor formed beyond Jupiter and made a beeline for our planet? Not necessarily.</p>

<p>"We cannot be really sure where the asteroid was kind of hiding just before it impacted on Earth," Fischer-Godde said, adding that after its formation, it may have made a stopover in the asteroid belt, located between Mars and Jupiter and where most meteorites originate.</p>

<h3><strong>Not a comet&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>The study also dismisses the idea that the destructive impactor was a comet, an amalgam of icy rock from the very edge of the solar system. Such a hypothesis was put forward in a much-publicized study in 2021, based on statistical simulations.</p>

<p>Sample analyses now show that the celestial object was far different in composition from a subset of meteorites which are believed to have been comets in the past. It is therefore "unlikely" the impactor in question was a comet, Fischer-Godde said.</p>

<p>As to the wider usefulness of his findings, the geochemist offered two suggestions.&nbsp;</p>

<p>He believes that more accurately defining the nature of asteroids that have struck Earth since its beginnings some 4.5 billion years ago could help solve the enigma of the origin of our planet's water.</p>

<p>Scientists believe water may have been brought to Earth by asteroids, likely of the C-type like the one that struck 66 million years ago, even though they are less frequent.</p>

<p>Studying past asteroids also allows humanity to prepare for the future, Fischer-Godde said.</p>

<p>"If we find that earlier mass extinction events could also be related to C-type asteroid impacts, then... if there's ever going to be a C-type asteroid on an Earth-crossing orbit, we have to be very careful," he said, "because it might be the last one we witness."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-09/knur2obo_dinosaurs_625x300_11_September_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The study says that an asteroid led to a global winter, wiping out the dinosaurs (representational).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-donald-trump-says-i-appreciate-nikki-haleys-advice-but-will-do-it-my-way-6347467]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Appreciate Nikki Haley's Advice But Will Do It My Way": Donald Trump]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-donald-trump-says-i-appreciate-nikki-haleys-advice-but-will-do-it-my-way-6347467]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 16 Aug 2024 07:18:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Republican presidential candidate and former president Donald Trump said he appreciates the support he has received from Indian American and former South Carolina governor Nikki Haley but hasn't taken her advice related to campaigning.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Republican presidential candidate and former president Donald Trump said he appreciates the support he has received from Indian American and former South Carolina governor Nikki Haley but hasn't taken her advice related to campaigning.</p>

<p>"I fought Nikki (Haley) very hard. I beat her in her own state by legendary numbers. I get along with her fine. I appreciate that she endorsed me," Trump said to reporters at his golf club in Bedminster, New Jersey, on Thursday.</p>

<p>Trump was responding to questions about a recent interview of Haley in which she said that the Republican presidential nominee should quit whining about his Democratic opponent Vice President Kamala Harris and instead focus on policy issues.</p>

<p>"You can't win on those things. American people are smart. Treat them like they're smart. It's not about her. It's about the American people. Talk to them and let them know you need their vote," Haley told Fox News in an interview.</p>

<p>"I think I'm doing a very calm campaign. I mean, we're here. There's no shouting. Now you'll say he ranted and raved, …. I'm a very calm person. Believe it or not. If I wasn't, I probably wouldn't be around anymore. I appreciate her advice but I have to do it my way," Trump said.</p>

<p>He said that he ran against Haley in his own ways and "won in South Carolina by numbers that nobody's ever seen before".</p>

<p>"I think she's (Haley) a good woman. I'd love to have her support. She gave me support," Trump added.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2017-09/nikki-haley-donald-trump-afp_650x400_41506056552.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump said he is doing a very calm campaign.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-us-elections-2024-donald-trump-criticises-gaza-ceasefire-call-wants-israel-to-win-fast-6347476]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump Criticises Gaza Ceasefire Call, Wants Israel To "Win Fast"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-us-elections-2024-donald-trump-criticises-gaza-ceasefire-call-wants-israel-to-win-fast-6347476]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 16 Aug 2024 07:18:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Republican US presidential candidate Donald Trump said on Thursday he told Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu during their last meeting in July to quickly end Israel's war in Gaza, but the former president also criticized ceasefire demands.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Republican US presidential candidate Donald Trump said on Thursday he told Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu during their last meeting in July to quickly end Israel's war in Gaza, but the former president also criticized ceasefire demands.</p>

<p>"He knows what he's doing, I did encourage him to get this over with," Trump told reporters at a press conference on Thursday. "It has to get over with fast. ... Get your victory and get it over with. It has to stop, the killing has to stop."</p>

<p>Trump was referring to his meeting with Netanyahu at his Mar-a-Lago residence in late July, when Netanyahu visited the United States. He also met President Joe Biden and Vice President and Democratic presidential candidate Kamala Harris during his trip.</p>

<p>There has been an increased risk of a broader war in the Middle East after the recent killings of Palestinian Islamist group Hamas' leader Ismail Haniyeh in Iran and Hezbollah military commander Fuad Shukr in Beirut. Both drew threats of retaliation against Israel.</p>

<p>In an event later on Thursday about tackling antisemitism, Trump criticized Biden and Harris' months-long calls for a ceasefire in Gaza.</p>

<p>"From the start, Harris has worked to tie Israel's hand behind its back, demanding an immediate ceasefire, always demanding ceasefire," Trump said, adding it "would only give Hamas time to regroup and launch a new October 7 style attack."</p>

<p>Trump added: "I will give Israel the support that it needs to win but I do want them to win fast."</p>

<p>In the same event, Trump also labelled pro-Palestinian supporters calling for an end to US support for Israel's war as "pro-Hamas thugs" and "jihad sympathizers." He threatened to arrest and deport them from the US if he became president.</p>

<p>Netanyahu's office and Trump both separately denied on Thursday an Axios report that said they had spoken the previous day about the Gaza ceasefire and hostage release talks.</p>

<p>Biden laid out a three-phase ceasefire proposal in an address on May 31. Washington and regional mediators have since tried arranging the Gaza ceasefire-for-hostages deal but have run into repeated obstacles.</p>

<p>The Axios report cited two US sources. One source said the reported call was intended to encourage Netanyahu to take the deal, but stressed he did not know if this is indeed what the former president told Netanyahu.</p>

<p>Egypt, the United States and Qatar have scheduled a new round of Gaza ceasefire negotiations this week.</p>

<p>Washington, Israel's most important ally, has said that a ceasefire in Gaza will reduce the rising threat of a wider war.</p>

<p>The latest bloodshed in the decades-old Israeli-Palestinian conflict was triggered on Oct. 7 when Hamas attacked Israel, killing 1,200 and taking about 250 hostages, according to Israeli tallies.</p>

<p>Israel's subsequent assault on the Hamas-governed enclave has since killed over 40,000 Palestinians, according to the local health ministry, while also displacing nearly the entire population of 2.3 million, causing a hunger crisis and leading to genocide allegations at the World Court that Israel denies.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/da04e9s4_donald-trump_625x300_13_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump said that he wants Israel to win fast and he will give them the support they need (file).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-girl-12-dies-after-parents-used-smoothies-vitamins-to-treat-injuries-6347472]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Girl, 12, Dies After Parents Use Smoothies, Vitamins To Treat Injuries]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-girl-12-dies-after-parents-used-smoothies-vitamins-to-treat-injuries-6347472]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 16 Aug 2024 07:15:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 12-year-old girl died in US' Texas after she mysteriously suffered from "life-threatening" injuries which her parents tried to treat with smoothies and vitamins, officials said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 12-year-old girl died in US' Texas after she mysteriously suffered from "life-threatening" injuries which her parents tried to treat with smoothies and vitamins, officials said.</p>

<p>Miranda Sipps died at a hospital on Monday after her parents called emergency services for help when she was unable to breathe, four days after she sustained said injuries. In a bizarre twist, after they made the call, her mother left the house with the girl in a car as she didn't want policemen inside the house.</p>

<p>While fleeing the scene, their car was stopped by police near a highway and Miranda was found unconscious but alive inside the vehicle. She was rushed to the hospital but declared dead soon after.</p>

<p>Investigation revealed that the mother, Denise Balbaneda (36) and stepfather Gerald Gonzalez (40), did not seek medical help for the girl during the four days while she was "mentally and physically incapacitated and non-responsive".</p>

<p>For four days, the couple kept their daughter at home and allegedly fed her smoothies and vitamins even though she wasn't responsive. They might have tried to giver her oxygen in an attempt to revive her, officials alleged.</p>

<p>"Basically they thought they could nurse her back to health and we do not think they wanted the attention that this would draw if the little girl was injured," Atascosa County Sheriff David Soward told local media.</p>

<p>The parents told authorities that over the four days their daughter could only "flutter her eyes and move her hands a little bit".</p>

<p>While it is not known how she sustained the severe injuries, an autopsy is being conducted to find out the nature of her injuries.</p>

<p>Her mother and stepfather have been arrested and charged with injury to a child causing serious bodily injury.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/o0jqid3_us-girl-death_625x300_16_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Her mother, Denise Balbaneda and stepfather Gerald Gonzalez, did not seek medical help for the girl]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-donald-trump-says-i-dont-have-a-lot-of-respect-for-kamala-harris-6347399]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["I Don't Have A Lot Of Respect" For Kamala Harris: Donald Trump]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-donald-trump-says-i-dont-have-a-lot-of-respect-for-kamala-harris-6347399]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 16 Aug 2024 07:15:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Republican presidential candidate former president Donald Trump said he is "very angry" at Vice President Kamala Harris and is entitled to personal attack on his Democratic opponent.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Republican presidential candidate former president Donald Trump said he is "very angry" at Vice President Kamala Harris and is entitled to personal attack on his Democratic opponent.</p>

<p>"I don't have a lot of respect for her. I don't have a lot of respect for her intelligence. I think she'll be a terrible president. I think it's very important that we win. And whether the personal attacks are good or bad … she certainly attacks me personally," Trump said to reporters at his golf club in Bedminster, New Jersey.</p>

<p>Trump was responding to questions from his party members urging him not to make personal attacks on Harris, who is the first woman of colour running for presidency.</p>

<p>"As far as the personal attacks (against Harris), I'm very angry at her because of what she's done to the country. I'm very angry at her that she weaponised the justice system against me and other people. (I am) very angry at her. I think I'm entitled to personal attacks," he said.</p>

<p>"She (Harris) actually called me weird. He's weird, it was just a sound bite, and she called J D (Vance, his running mate) and I weird. He's not weird. He was a great student at Yale, he went to Ohio State, graduated in two years at the top of his class and all of these different things. We have this guy that's running failed, really a very failed state who had a terrible career. I mean, you have him saying they're weird. No, he's a weird guy," Trump said.</p>

<p>He said Harris is "weird in her policy", adding that “people don't know who she is yet".</p>

<p>"She is weird in her policy. Who wouldn't want to have strongholds, who doesn't want to have lower taxes? You know, all my life I've watched as politicians campaigned and I've always been on for the most part, on the other side. This is the only campaign I've ever heard. When they're saying we're going to increase your taxes and then people say they're going to vote for," Trump said.</p>

<p>Early this week, several of his party colleagues and aides, including former Trump White House aide Peter Navarro and former Republican candidate Vivek Ramaswamy, urged him to focus on policy instead of attacking Harris.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/knofc75_donald-trump-kamala-harris_625x300_31_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump said he is "very angry" at Vice President Kamala Harris.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/matthew-perry-jasveen-sangha-who-is-jasveen-sangha-ketamine-queen-charged-for-matthew-perrys-death-6347441]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Who Is Jasveen Sangha, "Ketamine Queen" Charged With Matthew Perry's Death]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/matthew-perry-jasveen-sangha-who-is-jasveen-sangha-ketamine-queen-charged-for-matthew-perrys-death-6347441]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 16 Aug 2024 07:09:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Among the five people who have been charged in actor Matthew Perry's death due to a drug overdose last year is a woman called Jasveen Sangha, popularly known as "the Ketamine Queen".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Among the five people who have been charged in <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/took-advantage-of-his-addiction-5-charged-over-matthew-perrys-death-6345973">actor Matthew Perry</a>'s death due to a drug overdose last year is a woman called Jasveen Sangha, popularly known as "the Ketamine Queen". According to investigators, Ms Sangha provided the lethal dose of ketamine that led to Mr Perry's death.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Ms Sangha, a 41-year-old dual British and American citizen, has been under the radar of federal authorities for her involvement in the distribution of dangerous narcotics. Dubbed the "Ketamine Queen of Los Angeles," Ms Sangha allegedly ran a drug operation out of her North Hollywood home, where officials claim she stored, packaged, and distributed various narcotics. According to a federal indictment, her residence was described as a "drug-selling emporium" filled with methamphetamine, cocaine, and prescription drugs like Xanax.</p>

<p>Ms Sangha's operation, which dates back to at least June 2019, came under scrutiny after she was busted in March for selling methamphetamine in an unrelated case. During the raid on her home, federal agents seized 79 bottles of liquid ketamine and nearly 2,000 meth pills, highlighting the scale of her illicit activities.</p>

<p>Mr Perry died on October 28 last year. The 'Friends' actor, who had long battled addiction, was found in his home, with his death attributed to a ketamine overdose. According to investigators, Mr Perry had obtained the fatal batch of ketamine through a broker, Eric Fleming, who in turn sourced the drug from Ms Sangha.</p>

<p>According to court documents, Ms Sangha provided Mr Fleming with 50 vials of ketamine in two separate deals in the weeks leading up to Mr Perry's death. The indictment alleges that Mr Perry first sampled the drug on October 13, and Mr Fleming subsequently delivered two large batches to Mr Perry's home on October 14 and October 24. Ms Sangha even included "ketamine lollipops" as a bonus due to the size of Mr Perry's order.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/k180k688_matthew-perry-jasveen-sangha-_625x300_16_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Actor Matthew Perry died on October 28 last year.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-palestine-west-bank-conflict-white-house-slams-violence-against-west-bank-palestinian-settlers-by-israel-6347403]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[White House Slams Violence Against West Bank Palestinian Settlers By Israel]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-palestine-west-bank-conflict-white-house-slams-violence-against-west-bank-palestinian-settlers-by-israel-6347403]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 16 Aug 2024 06:58:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The White House on Thursday condemned what it called "unacceptable" attacks on Palestinians by Jewish settlers, after one person was killed and another wounded in a village in the occupied West Bank.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The White House on Thursday condemned what it called "unacceptable" attacks on Palestinians by Jewish settlers, after one person was killed and another wounded in a village in the occupied West Bank.</p>

<p>"Attacks by violent settlers against Palestinian civilians in the West Bank are unacceptable and must stop," a National Security Council spokesperson said in a statement.</p>

<p>"Israeli authorities must take measures to protect all communities from harm, this includes intervening to stop such violence, and holding all perpetrators of such violence to account."</p>

<p>The Palestinian health ministry said a 23-year-old man was killed and another suffered critical gunshot wounds to the chest in the attack on the village of Jit, west of Nablus.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said "dozens of Israeli civilians, some of them masked," had entered Jit and "set fire to vehicles and structures in the area, hurled rocks and Molotov cocktails."</p>

<p>Israeli President Isaac Herzog condemned the incident.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2017-12/west-bank-conflict-afp_650x400_71512650307.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Palestinian health ministry said a 23-year-old man was killed in the attack (file).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-approves-sale-of-600-patriot-missiles-to-germany-6347396]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Approves Sale Of 600 Patriot Missiles To Germany]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-approves-sale-of-600-patriot-missiles-to-germany-6347396]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 16 Aug 2024 06:50:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United States on Thursday announced its approval of a $5 billion sale of up to 600 Patriot missiles and related equipment to Germany, which has donated several of the advanced air defense systems to Ukraine.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United States on Thursday announced its approval of a $5 billion sale of up to 600 Patriot missiles and related equipment to Germany, which has donated several of the advanced air defense systems to Ukraine.</p>

<p>The proposed sale of the PAC-3 MSE missiles "will support the foreign policy and national security of the United States by improving the security of a NATO ally that is an important force for political and economic stability in Europe," the Defense Security Cooperation Agency (DSCA) said in a statement.</p>

<p>It "will improve Germany's capability to meet current and future threats and increase the defensive capabilities of its military. It will support Germany's goal of improving national and territorial defense as well as interoperability with US and NATO forces," the statement added.</p>

<p>The State Department approved the possible sale of the missiles to Germany, and the DSCA on Thursday provided the required notification to Congress, which still needs to sign off on the transaction.</p>

<p>Germany has donated several Patriot systems to Ukraine, which has faced repeated Russian missile barrages and drone attacks targeting its infrastructure, leaving it in desperate need of additional air defenses.</p>

<p>After the outbreak of the Ukraine war in 2022, Berlin dropped a traditionally pacifist stance and has become Kyiv's second-biggest supplier of military aid, after Washington.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-12/5vbutas4_us-patriot-missiles-reuters_625x300_23_December_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US on Thursday announced its approval of a $5 billion sale of patriot missiles and other equipments.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ceasefire-must-involve-complete-israeli-withdrawal-from-gaza-hamas-6347342]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ceasefire Must Involve "Complete" Israeli Withdrawal From Gaza: Hamas]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ceasefire-must-involve-complete-israeli-withdrawal-from-gaza-hamas-6347342]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 16 Aug 2024 06:39:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Palestinian group Hamas on Thursday said any Gaza ceasefire deal must involve the total withdrawal of Israeli forces from the embattled territory.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Palestinian group Hamas on Thursday said any Gaza ceasefire deal must involve the total withdrawal of Israeli forces from the embattled territory.</p>

<p>"Any agreement must achieve a comprehensive ceasefire, a complete (Israeli) withdrawal from Gaza, (and) the return of the displaced," Hamas official Hossam Badran said in a statement after truce talks resumed in Doha on Thursday.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/c94ffj98_israel-army-in-gaza-afp_625x300_14_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[More than 40,000 people have been killed in Gaza since war began between Israeli forces and Hamas.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/6-3-magnitude-earthquake-hits-taiwan-weather-agency-6347168]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[6.3 Magnitude Earthquake Hits Taiwan: Weather Agency]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/6-3-magnitude-earthquake-hits-taiwan-weather-agency-6347168]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 16 Aug 2024 05:33:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 6.3 magnitude earthquake struck 34 km (21.13 miles) off Taiwan's eastern city of Hualien on Friday, the island's weather administration said, with no immediate reports of damage.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;A 6.3 magnitude earthquake struck 34 km (21.13 miles) off Taiwan's eastern city of Hualien on Friday, the island's weather administration said, with no immediate reports of damage.</p>

<p>The quake shook buildings in the capital, Taipei. The quake had a depth of 9.7 km, the weather administration said.</p>

<p>Taiwan lies near the junction of two tectonic plates and is prone to earthquakes.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2017-09/earthquake-generic_650x400_71505899871.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Taiwan lies near the junction of two tectonic plates and is prone to earthquakes.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukraine-russia-both-claim-advances-in-kursk-region-6346537]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ukraine, Russia Both Claim Advances In Kursk Region]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukraine-russia-both-claim-advances-in-kursk-region-6346537]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 16 Aug 2024 01:46:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ukraine on Thursday claimed fresh advances in its offensive into Russia, saying it had seized over 1,100 square kilometres in the biggest attack by a foreign army on Russian soil since World War II.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ukraine on Thursday claimed fresh advances in its offensive into Russia, saying it had seized over &nbsp;1,100 square kilometres in the biggest attack by a foreign army on Russian soil since World War II.</p>

<p>Russia said it had recaptured a first village from Ukrainian forces in the Kursk border region and announced it was sending "additional forces" to the neighbouring Belgorod region.</p>

<p>Ukraine said it now controlled dozens of settlements and Sudzha, a town eight kilometres (five miles) from the border.</p>

<p>"We have taken control of 1,150 square kilometres of territory and 82 settlements," said top military commander Oleksandr Syrsky.</p>

<p>Ukrainian troops launched the offensive on August 6, breaking months of setbacks for the army that has been battling a Russian invasion for more than two years.</p>

<p>The top general also told President Volodymyr Zelensky the army had set up an administrative office "to maintain law and order and meet the priority needs of the population in the controlled territories".</p>

<p>Zelensky announced "the completion of the liberation of the town of Sudzha from the Russian military".</p>

<p><br />
<strong>- 120,000 Russians displaced -</strong><br />
At an Orthodox church in the centre of Sumy, the regional hub across the border from Kursk, dozens of mourners gathered Thursday to pay their final respects to six Ukrainian soldiers killed in the offensive.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Tearful family members received a steady stream of friends and relatives wearing black and clutching wreaths as the priest intoned a funeral mass and incense hung in the air.</p>

<p>"It is hard to say goodbye to them, because we want them to live forever, to live among us as honoured sons of their homeland," the priest told mourners.</p>

<p>"Our task is to pray for our heroic fighters and their families."&nbsp;</p>

<p>Pallbearers lifted the coffins one by one for burial as a choir sang hymns. Air raid sirens echoed over Sumy as the service ended.</p>

<p>In Kursk, AFP reporters saw around 500 evacuees from border areas queueing for food and clothes being distributed by the Russian Red Cross.</p>

<p><br />
<strong>- 'Completed destruction' -</strong><br />
The assault took Russian troops by surprise and triggered mass evacuations. Russia says more than 120,000 people have left or been evacuated.</p>

<p>The fighting has killed at least 12 civilians and wounded 121 others according to Russian authorities, who have not released a toll since Monday.</p>

<p>Moscow scrambled reinforcements and announced the recapture of a first village in the Kursk region on Thursday.</p>

<p>Russia's defence ministry said the army had "completed destruction of the enemy and restored control of the settlement of Krupets".</p>

<p>The Russian army also announced measures to prevent attacks on neighbouring regions, particularly Belgorod.</p>

<p>Russia has prepared "concrete actions" to defend Belgorod from Ukrainian attacks, Defence Minister Andrei Belousov said at a meeting with officials including Belgorod governor Vyacheslav Gladkov.</p>

<p>They include "the allocation of additional forces".</p>

<p>Kursk and Belgorod have seen small incursions since President Vladimir Putin launched Russia's invasion of Ukraine in February 2022, but nothing on this scale.</p>

<p><br />
<strong>- Intensity of attacks -</strong><br />
Ukrainian officials have argued the offensive was an act of "self-defence" and experts suggest it could be aimed at alleviating pressure from the eastern front.</p>

<p>Ukrainian troops are still struggling in the eastern Donbas region, a key Russian target.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Most Russian attacks are taking place" in the Donbas, Zelensky said, adding: "We are paying maximum defensive attention."</p>

<p>Local authorities in three Ukrainian regions reported at least five civilian deaths in Russian strikes, including Donetsk in the east, Kharkiv in the northeast and Kherson in the south.<br />
\<br />
Russia said its forces had captured Ivanivka in Donetsk, a frontline village just 15 kilometres from the Kyiv-held transport hub of Pokrovsk in east Ukraine.</p>

<p>Pokrovsk lies on the intersection of a key road that supplies Ukrainian troops and towns across the eastern front and has long been a Russian target.<br />
In a briefing, Russia's defence ministry said its army had "liberated the &nbsp;village of Ivanovka", using the Russian name for the village.</p>

<p>Russian forces have been inching towards Pokrovsk for months, taking a string of villages on the way to the city outskirts.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/gs061fko_kursk_625x300_14_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Ukraine on Thursday claimed fresh advances in its offensive into Russia.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gaza-ceasefire-talks-underway-in-qatar-as-deaths-top-40-000-6346420]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Gaza Ceasefire Talks Underway In Qatar As Deaths Top 40,000]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gaza-ceasefire-talks-underway-in-qatar-as-deaths-top-40-000-6346420]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 16 Aug 2024 01:09:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United States hailed a "promising start" to Gaza ceasefire talks Thursday, as pressure mounted for a deal to halt the spread of a war that the Hamas-run territory's health ministry said has killed 40,005.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United States hailed a "promising start" to Gaza ceasefire talks Thursday, as pressure mounted for a deal to halt the spread of a war that the Hamas-run territory's health ministry said has killed 40,005.</p>

<p>The conflict sparked by Hamas's unprecedented October 7 attack on Israel has devastated Gaza, displaced nearly all of its population at least once and triggered a towering humanitarian crisis.</p>

<p>Talks involving CIA director William Burns opened in the Qatari capital Doha, US National Security Council spokesman John Kirby said.</p>

<p>"Today is a promising start," Kirby told reporters in Washington, adding: "There remains a lot of work to do."</p>

<p>The talks were expected to continue on Friday, he said.</p>

<p>Hamas official Osama Hamdan said the movement did not take part in Thursday's meeting but stood ready to join the indirect negotiations if they produced new commitments from Israel.</p>

<p>The Palestinian group has demanded the implementation of a truce plan laid out in late May by US President Joe Biden.</p>

<p>"If the mediators succeed in forcing the (Israeli) occupation to agree, we would, but so far there's nothing new," Hamdan told AFP.</p>

<p>He said Hamas would not take part in protracted negotiations that "give (Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin) Netanyahu more time to kill the Palestinian people".</p>

<p>So far, there has been only one truce in November, when Gaza militants released 105 hostages seized in the October 7 attack, the Israelis among them in exchange for 240 Palestinian prisoners held in Israeli jails.</p>

<p>The latest diplomatic push comes as the health ministry in Gaza said the death toll in the besieged Palestinian territory had surpassed 40,000 -- which UN chief Antonio Guterres said was "yet another reason" why a ceasefire was needed now.</p>

<p>"Given the... disturbing number of people who remain unaccounted for, who may be trapped or dead under the rubble, this number may, if anything, be an undercount," his spokesman Farhan Haq said.</p>

<p>"This is yet another reason why we need to have a ceasefire now, as well as the release of all hostages and unimpeded humanitarian assistance."</p>

<p>The Gaza health ministry, which does not provide a breakdown of civilian and militant casualties, said the tally included 40 deaths in the previous 24 hours.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said it had killed "more than 17,000" Palestinian militants in Gaza since the war began.</p>

<p><strong>- 'Time is now' -</strong><br />
British foreign minister David Lammy and his French counterpart Stephane Sejourne are to discuss the truce talks with Israel's top diplomat Israel Katz on Friday.</p>

<p>In Beirut on Wednesday, visiting US envoy Amos Hochstein said a deal in Gaza "would also help enable a diplomatic resolution here in Lebanon and that would prevent an outbreak of a wider war".</p>

<p>"We have to take advantage of this window for diplomatic action and diplomatic solutions. That time is now," he added.</p>

<p>Hamas's October 7 attack on southern Israel triggered the war and resulted in the deaths of 1,198 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally of Israeli official figures.</p>

<p>Militants also seized 251 people, 111 of whom are still held in Gaza, including 39 the military says are dead.</p>

<p>Mediation efforts have repeatedly stalled since the week-long truce in November.</p>

<p>Hamas officials, some analysts and critics in Israel have said Netanyahu has sought to prolong the war for political gain.</p>

<p>Israeli media this week quoted Defence Minister Yoav Gallant as privately telling a parliamentary committee that a hostage release deal "is stalling... in part because of Israel".</p>

<p>Netanyahu's office accused Gallant of adopting an "anti-Israel narrative" and said Hamas leader Yahya Sinwar is "the only obstacle to a hostage deal".</p>

<p>- Bloodied children -<br />
The latest mediation push follows the July 31 killing of Sinwar's predecessor, Hamas political leader and truce negotiator Ismail Haniyeh. His killing during a visit to Tehran sent fears of a wider conflagration soaring.</p>

<p>Iran and its regional allies blamed Israel and vowed retaliation. Israel has not claimed responsibility for the attack.</p>

<p>Western leaders have urged Tehran to avoid hitting Israel over Haniyeh's killing, which came hours after an Israeli strike in Beirut killed Hezbollah's military commander.</p>

<p>Fallout from the conflict has drawn in Iran-aligned groups from Lebanon, Yemen, Iraq and Syria.</p>

<p>More than 370 Hezbollah members have been killed in 10 months of near daily cross-border fire with Israeli forces, according to an AFP tally, more than the Iran-backed movement lost in the 2006 war with Israel.</p>

<p>On the Israeli side, 22 soldiers and 26 civilians have been killed, including in the annexed Golan Heights, according to military figures.</p>

<p>In Gaza, where the war has destroyed much of the territory's housing and other infrastructure, relatively few deaths were reported on Thursday.</p>

<p>In the deadliest bombardment, emergency services said air strikes killed five people in Gaza City.</p>

<p>Israel's military said troops had killed about 20 militants in Rafah, southern Gaza.</p>

<p>On Wednesday, dead and wounded including bloodied children arrived at Nasser Hospital in the southern city of Khan Yunis after an Israeli strike.</p>

<p>"I was not pro-Hamas but now I support them and I want to fight," one grieving man shouted.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/4dmff0tg_israel-hamas-war_625x300_31_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[More than 40,000 people have been killed in Gaza since war began between Israel and Hamas.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-to-hold-press-conference-his-campaign-adds-senior-advisers-6346337]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump To Hold Press Conference, His Campaign Adds Senior Advisers]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-to-hold-press-conference-his-campaign-adds-senior-advisers-6346337]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 16 Aug 2024 00:36:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump will hold a press conference at his New Jersey golf club on Thursday, his latest effort to steal the spotlight back from Democratic rival Kamala Harris, who has dominated headlines since her late entry into the race.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Republican U.S. presidential candidate Donald Trump will hold a press conference at his New Jersey golf club on Thursday, his latest effort to steal the spotlight back from Democratic rival Kamala Harris, who has dominated headlines since her late entry into the race.</p>

<p>Trump's event is aimed at drawing a contrast with Vice President Harris, who has rarely taken questions from reporters since replacing President Joe Biden at the top of the Democratic ticket in late July. Harris has said she plans to do her first formal press interview by the end of the month.</p>

<p>Trump held a similar press event at his Florida resort last week, where he spoke for more than an hour, bashing Harris over immigration and the economy and falsely claiming that his campaign crowds have been much larger than hers.</p>

<p>The Harris campaign sent out a mock "media advisory" for Trump's press conference on Thursday with the headline, "Donald Trump to Ramble Incoherently and Spread Dangerous Lies in Public, but at Different Home," a reference to his Bedminster estate.</p>

<p>Hours earlier, the Trump campaign announced five hires, including Corey Lewandowski, who served as Trump's first campaign manager during his successful 2016 campaign. Lewandowski voiced his excitement on joining the campaign, posting on X: "Let Trump, Be Trump!"</p>

<p>It was not immediately clear what those additions would mean for the campaign's day-to-day operations and hierarchy. One campaign official, who requested anonymity to discuss internal personnel matters, said the campaign needed more "soldiers" in the race's closing months and that the hires were not indicative of any broader shakeup.</p>

<p>"Corey Lewandowski, Taylor Budowich, Alex Pfeiffer, Alex Bruesewitz, and Tim Murtaugh are all veterans of prior Trump campaigns and their unmatched experience will help President Trump prosecute the case against Kamala Harris and Tim Walz, the most radical ticket in American history," Trump co-campaign managers Chris LaCivita and Susie Wiles said in a statement.</p>

<p>Budowich was most recently the executive director of MAGA Inc, the main outside super PAC supporting Trump's bid, while Pfeiffer served as the communications director there. It is common for staff to move between campaigns and their affiliated super PACs, as it can allow each organization to have greater visibility into the other operations. Legally, campaigns and super PACs have limits on how much they can coordinate.</p>

<p>Bruesewitz is a pro-Trump political consultant known for his social media savvy, and Murtaugh was communications director of Trump's unsuccessful 2020 bid.</p>

<p>Lewandowski was forced out of Trump's 2016 bid in the months before the election, though Trump later said he regretted it. Lewandowski was later forced out of a pro-Trump super PAC in 2021 after a donor's wife accused him of unwanted sexual advances.</p>

<p>Trump intends to use Thursday's press conference to criticize Harris over inflation and the economy, a campaign official said.</p>

<p>His campaign event in North Carolina on Wednesday also was billed as being focused on the economy, but Trump veered a number of times into other topics and personal attacks on Harris.</p>

<p>Harris is scheduled to deliver a speech on economic policy on Friday in North Carolina.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/6tjcj0g_donald-trump-afp_625x300_13_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump held a similar press event at his Florida resort last week.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/more-monkey-pox-cases-likely-to-hit-europe-soon-says-who-6346134]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[More Monkey Pox Cases Likely To Hit Europe Soon, Says WHO]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/more-monkey-pox-cases-likely-to-hit-europe-soon-says-who-6346134]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 15 Aug 2024 23:33:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The World Health Organization said more imported Clade 1 mpox cases were likely to be confirmed in Europe soon, after Sweden on Thursday announced the first such case outside Africa.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The World Health Organization said more imported Clade 1 mpox cases were likely to be confirmed in Europe soon, after Sweden on Thursday announced the first such case outside Africa.</p>

<p>"The confirmation of mpox Clade 1 in Sweden is a clear reflection of the interconnectedness of our world... there are likely to be further imported cases of Clade 1 in the European region over the coming days and weeks," the WHO's European regional office said in a statement.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-07/19v8uptk_monkeypox-screening_625x300_26_July_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sweden on Thursday announced the first such case outside Africa. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-to-build-new-jewish-settlement-between-jerusalem-west-bank-report-6346095]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel To Build New Jewish Settlement Between Jerusalem, West Bank: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-to-build-new-jewish-settlement-between-jerusalem-west-bank-report-6346095]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 15 Aug 2024 23:23:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel is to build the first West Bank settlement since 2017, announced the Israeli Civil Administration, the country's governing body that operates in the West Bank, local media reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel is to build the first West Bank settlement since 2017, announced the Israeli Civil Administration, the country's governing body that operates in the West Bank, local media reported.</p>

<p>Nahal Heletz, the new settlement, will cover approximately 148 acres (about 600,000 square metres) southwest of Jerusalem, near the Palestinian city of Bethlehem, reports Xinhua news agency, quoting the Times of Israel.</p>

<p>The construction is likely years away since obtaining the zoning plans and construction permits would take time, the report further read.</p>

<p>Peace Now, an organisation opposing the settlements, warned that Nahal Heletz "will be an enclave in a Palestinian zone and will bring about friction and security challenges."</p>

<p>It said Nahal Heletz is designed to disrupt Palestinian territorial continuity and argued that it contributes to Israel's "de facto annexation" of the West Bank.</p>

<p>It also pointed out that the settlement will be built on land that belongs to Battir, a Palestinian village known for its ancient agricultural terraces recognised as a UNESCO World Heritage site.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-03/68s23gu8_west-bank-_625x300_22_March_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The construction is likely years away: Report (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/took-advantage-of-his-addiction-5-charged-over-matthew-perrys-death-6345973]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Took Advantage Of His Addiction": 5 Charged Over Matthew Perry's Death]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/took-advantage-of-his-addiction-5-charged-over-matthew-perrys-death-6345973]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 15 Aug 2024 22:54:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US prosecutors said Thursday they have charged five people, including two doctors, over the death of "Friends" star Matthew Perry, who died at his Los Angeles home last year after years of struggling with addiction.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US prosecutors said Thursday they have charged five people, including two doctors, over the death of "Friends" star Matthew Perry, who died at his Los Angeles home last year after years of struggling with addiction.</p>

<p>"These defendants took advantage of Mr Perry's addiction issues to enrich themselves. They knew what they were doing was wrong. They knew what they were doing was risking great danger to Mr Perry, but they did it anyway," said US Attorney Martin Estrada.</p>

<p>The five include two doctors and the actor's assistant.</p>

<p>"In the end, these defendants were more interested in profiting off Mr Perry than caring for his well-being."</p>

<p>One of the doctors, Salvador Plasencia, faces up to 120 years in federal prison, Estrada said.</p>

<p>Matthew&nbsp;Perry, who played the character Chandler Bing on the hit TV sitcom from 1994-2004, was found unresponsive in his swimming pool in October last year at the age of 54, sparking a global outpouring of grief from fans and colleagues.</p>

<p>An autopsy found the cause of his death was "the acute effects of ketamine," a controlled drug which the recovering addict was understood to be taking as part of supervised therapy.</p>

<p>While only small amounts were found in his stomach, a high level was detected in his bloodstream.</p>

<p>Just how the actor -- who had reportedly not had a supervised infusion session for several days -- obtained the drug became the subject of a legal investigation, with Los Angeles police confirming in May that they were probing the death.</p>

<p>Doctors and veterinarians often employ ketamine as an anesthetic, and researchers have explored its use as a treatment for depression. Underground users take it illicitly for its hallucinogenic effects.</p>

<p>"Friends," which followed the lives of six New Yorkers navigating adulthood, dating and careers, drew a massive global following and made megastars of previously unknown actors who became a fixture in the lives of millions of viewers.</p>

<p>One of the biggest draws was Matthew&nbsp;Perry's Chandler character, a sarcastic 20-something-year-old who resisted growing up.</p>

<p>Matthew&nbsp;Perry's comic talent brought him fabulous wealth, but hid a darkness that left him struggling with addiction to painkillers and alcohol.</p>

<p>In 2018 he suffered a burst colon, related to drug usage, and underwent multiple surgeries.</p>

<p>In his memoir "Friends, Lovers and the Big Terrible Thing," published in 2022, Matthew&nbsp;Perry described going through detox dozens of times. He dedicated the book to "all of the sufferers out there," and wrote in the prologue: "I should be dead."</p>

<p>"I have mostly been sober since 2001," he wrote, "save for about sixty or seventy little mishaps over the years."</p>

<p>His sudden death last year drew shocked reactions from Hollywood A-listers, his costars, and "Friends" fans worldwide.</p>

<p>"Oh boy this one has cut deep," said Jennifer Aniston, who played Rachel on the show.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-11/fpgn1dq_matthew-perry-instagram_625x300_27_November_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The five include two doctors and the actor's assistant. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kim-dotcom-to-be-extradited-from-new-zealand-after-12-year-fight-with-us-6345743]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kim Dotcom To Be Extradited From New Zealand After 12-Year Fight With US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kim-dotcom-to-be-extradited-from-new-zealand-after-12-year-fight-with-us-6345743]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 15 Aug 2024 22:09:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kim Dotcom, who is facing criminal charges relating to the defunct file-sharing website Megaupload, will be extradited to the United States from New Zealand, the New Zealand justice minister said on Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kim Dotcom, who is facing criminal charges relating to the defunct file-sharing website Megaupload, will be extradited to the United States from New Zealand, the New Zealand justice minister said on Thursday.</p>

<p>German-born Dotcom, who has New Zealand residency, has been fighting extradition to the United States since 2012 following a FBI-ordered raid on his Auckland mansion.</p>

<p>Justice Minister Paul Goldsmith signed an extradition order for Dotcom, a spokesperson for the Minister of Justice said</p>

<p>"I considered all of the information carefully, and have decided that Mr Dotcom should be surrendered to the U.S. to face trial," Goldsmith said in a statement.</p>

<p>"As is common practice, I have allowed Mr Dotcom a short period of time to consider and take advice on my decision. I will not, therefore, be commenting further at this stage."</p>

<p>In a post on social media website X on Tuesday, Dotcom said "the obedient US colony in the South Pacific just decided to extradite me for what users uploaded to Megaupload", in what appears to be a reference to the extradition order.</p>

<p>Reuters could not immediately contact Dotcom for a response.</p>

<p>U.S. authorities say Dotcom and three other Megaupload executives cost film studios and record companies more than $500 million by encouraging paying users to store and share copyrighted material, which generated more than $175 million in revenue for the website.</p>

<p>The company's chief marketing officer Finn Batato and chief technical officer and co-founder Mathias Ortmann, both from Germany, along with a third executive Dutch national Bram van der Kolk were arrested with Dotcom in 2012.</p>

<p>Ortmann and van der Kolk entered plea deals that saw them sentenced in 2023 to jail terms in New Zealand but allowed them to avoid extradition. Batato died in 2022 in New Zealand.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/s8lfgcgo_kim-dotcom_625x300_15_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["Mr Dotcom should be surrendered to the U.S. to face trial," Mr Goldsmith said. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sweden-confirms-1st-case-of-more-grave-type-of-monkey-pox-virus-6345621]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Sweden Confirms 1st Case Of "More Grave" Type Of Monkey Pox Virus]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sweden-confirms-1st-case-of-more-grave-type-of-monkey-pox-virus-6345621]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 15 Aug 2024 21:47:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Sweden said on Thursday it had confirmed a first case of mpox, a viral infection that spreads through close contact.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sweden said on Thursday it had confirmed a first case of mpox, a viral infection that spreads through close contact.</p>

<p>Earlier on Thursday, the World Health Organization declared mpox a global public health emergency for the second time in two years, following an outbreak in Democratic Republic of Congo that has spread to other countries.</p>

<p>"We have now also during the afternoon had confirmation that we have one case in Sweden of the more grave type of mpox, the one called Clade I," Health and Social Affairs Minister Jakob Forssmed told a news conference.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-07/19v8uptk_monkeypox-screening_625x300_26_July_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Earlier on Thursday, WHO declared mpox a global public health emergency (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/1-arrested-in-connection-to-friends-actor-matthew-perrys-death-report-6345227]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[1 Arrested In Connection To "Friends" Actor Matthew Perry's Death: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/1-arrested-in-connection-to-friends-actor-matthew-perrys-death-report-6345227]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 15 Aug 2024 20:31:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[At least one person has been arrested in connection with the ketamine overdose death last year of "Friends" actor Matthew Perry, US media reported Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p>

<p>At least one person has been arrested in connection with the ketamine overdose death last year of "Friends" actor Matthew Perry, US media reported Thursday.</p>

<p>NBC, citing law enforcement officials, said one arrest had been made, while TMZ said there had been "multiple" arrests including one doctor, as investigators probed how Perry obtained the drug.</p>

<p>Perry, who played Chandler Bing on the hit TV sitcom from 1994-2004, was found unresponsive in his pool in October last year at the age of 54, sparking a global outpouring of grief from fans and colleagues.</p>

<p>An autopsy found the cause of his death was "the acute effects of ketamine," a controlled drug which the recovering addict was understood to be taking as part of supervised therapy.</p>

<p>While only small amounts were found in his stomach, a high level was detected in his bloodstream.</p>

<p>Just how the actor -- who had reportedly not had a supervised infusion session for several days -- obtained the drug became the subject of a legal investigation, with Los Angeles police confirming in May that they were probing the death.</p>

<p>Celebrity news site TMZ, citing law enforcement sources, reported that "at least one doctor has been arrested, along with several dealers who helped arrange and deliver ketamine to Perry."</p>

<p>Doctors and veterinarians often employ ketamine as an anesthetic, and researchers have explored its use as a treatment for depression. Underground users take it illicitly for its hallucinogenic effects.</p>

<p>"Friends," which followed the lives of six New Yorkers navigating adulthood, dating and careers, drew a massive global following and made megastars of previously unknown actors who became a fixture in the lives of millions of viewers.</p>

<p>But Perry's comic talent, which brought him fabulous wealth, hid a darkness that left him struggling with addictions to painkillers and alcohol.</p>

<p>His sudden death last year drew shocked reactions from Hollywood A-listers, his costars, and "Friends" fans worldwide.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/92mrh7ag_matthew-perry_625x300_04_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Some sources claim "multiple" arrests have been made. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/monkeypox-virus-killed-548-people-in-this-nation-since-start-of-2024-6344938]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Monkeypox Virus Killed 548 People In This Nation Since Start Of 2024]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/monkeypox-virus-killed-548-people-in-this-nation-since-start-of-2024-6344938]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 15 Aug 2024 19:35:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An mpox outbreak in the Democratic Republic of Congo has killed 548 people since the start of the year, with all provinces affected by the virus, the health minister said on Thursday in a statement.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An mpox outbreak in the Democratic Republic of Congo has killed 548 people since the start of the year, with all provinces affected by the virus, the health minister said on Thursday in a statement.</p>

<p>The World Health Organization (WHO) on Wednesday declared the mpox surge in Africa a global public health emergency, worried by the rise in cases in DRC and the spread to nearby countries.</p>

<p>"According to the latest epidemiological report, our country has recorded 15,664 potential cases and 548 deaths since the beginning of the year," Health Minister Samuel-Roger Kamba said in a separate video message seen by AFP on Thursday.</p>

<p>The DRC is made up of 26 provinces and has a population of around 100 million.</p>

<p>The most affected provinces are South Kivu, North Kivu, Tshopo, Equateur, North Ubangi, Tshuapa, Mongala and Sankuru, Kamba said.</p>

<p>The UN health agency's decision came the day after the African Union's health watchdog declared its own public health emergency over the growing outbreak.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/62h05c3g_mpox_625x300_14_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The DRC is made up of 26 provinces and has a population of around 100 million. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>