<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Thu, 24 Oct 2024 01:21:56 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-explainer-understanding-the-lac-and-the-stand-off-with-china-6858970]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Video Explainer: Understanding The LAC And The Stand-Off With China]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-explainer-understanding-the-lac-and-the-stand-off-with-china-6858970]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:57:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[PM Narendra Modi and Chinese President Xi Jinping held their first "formal bilateral meeting" since the military stand-off between India and China began in 2020. Here is an explainer with video, a map, and satellite images to help understand the LAC.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi and Chinese President Xi Jinping held a bilateral meeting in Russia's Kazan today, on the sidelines of the BRICS Summit that both leaders attended. This is the first "formal bilateral meeting" between the PM Modi and President Xi since the military stand-off between both countries began in 2020.</p>

<p>Ties between India and China took a severe hit and came to an abrupt halt after the military clash in Galwan Valley. It took four years of diplomatic and military-level talks between both sides to finally come to an agreement to reinstate the status quo to what it was before the stand-off in 2020.</p>

<p>Both countries welcomed the move and in less than 72 after the disengagement agreement, the two leaders met in Russia today.</p>

<p>To understand what exactly had happened back in 2020, what the friction points were, and the kind of build up China had in place since then - which has now been dismantled, we need maps and satellite images.</p>

<h2><strong>UNDERSTANDING THE MAP</strong></h2>

<p>This is the map of Ladakh with the Line of Actual Control or LAC marked in red. The area between the LAC and the original border in black is the Aksai Chin region of Ladakh occupied by China since the 1962 war. While Galwan Valley was where the military clash happened in May, 2020, there were several other friction points, namely - Depsang, Galwan, Gogra Hot Springs, Pangong Tso, and Demchok.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/taha99mo_ladakh-map-showing-lac_625x300_24_October_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Shortly after the uprising in China in 1959, and the occupation of Tibet that year, China started making claims in areas that fall in Ladakh, an "integral and inalienable" part of India. During the Sino-India war of 1962, Chinese troops had crossed the original border but had to withdraw later. It however never withdrew from Aksai Chin.</p>

<p>The dotted red line in the map above represents the approximate patrol points established by India and are the farthest points till where Indian soldiers patrol. All the areas labelled along the LAC are points where Chinese troops blocked Indian soldiers from reaching the last patrol point that would walk up to till 2020. This led to the military stand-off between India and China.</p>

<p>After the Galwan Clash in May, 2020, both sides brought in reinforcements - tens of thousands of troops and military hardware from tanks and artillery guns to fighter jets and drones. At this stage both sides started engaging in talks - both at diplomatic and military levels.</p>

<p>The disengagement talks began and both sides created disengagement zones, also known as buffer zones in the areas of Galwan - where the clash happened, Gogra Hot Springs, and Pangong.</p>

<h3><strong>What is a buffer zone?</strong></h3>

<ul>
	<li><em>Soldiers from both sides, as a result of a grievance, agreed to go back a certain number of kilometers, and the areas that fell in between, which included points that were disputed would be where troops from neither side would go. Structures that were built in these locations during the stand-off by either side were also removed as the disengagement talks progressed over the months and years.</em></li>
</ul>

<h3><strong>SATELLITE IMAGES</strong></h3>

<h3><big>Here are a set of satellite images show the way the situation developed since 2020:</big></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/3sp7delo_pangong-lake-north-side_625x300_24_October_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>This image shows the north side of the Pangong Lake where in June, 2020, Chinese soldiers came to an area that India claims and put markings of the flag of China and wrote beneath it in Mandarin that "This area belongs to China". This was a time when the Chinese had come right in along the Pangong Lake.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/247it08c_pangong-lake-area-satellite-image_625x300_24_October_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>This second image is also from the north bank of the Pangong Lake and a place where the Chinese had a major built-up area.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/92m16mds_pangong-lake-south-side_625x300_24_October_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>This third image shows the south bank of the Pangong Lake where the Chinese troops had brought in their boats (left side of the image) and the right side shows how these were eventually removed by Beijing as the disengagement process moved forward at a slow but steady pace.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/2r36srj8_galwan-valley-chinese-buildup_625x300_24_October_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>This fourth image is from where it all began - The Galwan Valley - where the clash took place in which soldiers on either side were killed in action. China set up and built multiple structures along the banks of the river and in the area where the river meanders. In this photo, the LAC is approximately 400 meters south of where the river is seen bending to the right. These were areas where Indian soldiers would patrol in the past, but in 2020, the Chinese soldiers attempted to stop them from doing that.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/1v6q1alc_gogra-hot-springs-area_625x300_24_October_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>In this fifth satellite image, we take a look at the Gogra Hot Springs area - an area which had seen conflict in 1962 as well. The screen is divided in two - the left showing the Chinese build-up in 2021, which they later dismantled in 2022 and vacated the area, as seen on the right.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/47k1su88_gogra-ht-spring-area-china-base-relocation_625x300_24_October_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>The sixth satellite image shows the relocated Chinese base. This was set up by China 3 kilometers south of the spot they vacated in the image shown above this one.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/8mpks1pg_gogra-hot-springs-buffer-zone_625x300_24_October_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>This seventh image gives a clearer picture of where the Chinese had built a structure and where they relocated to as the disengagement talks continued. This was part of the buffer zone that was created in this particular area.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/fhgg44c8_depsang-area-yjunction_625x300_24_October_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>The eighth image shows the area in Depsang - an area of real concern. In a place called the Y-junction in Depsang, Chinese troops have set up a base and have been preventing Indian soldiers to patrol up to a point where they used to before 2020. As the photo shows, Indian soldiers have been prevented from moving east (right). If after the latest agreement of shifting the status quo to pre-2020 times, then Indian soldiers would now be able to patrol right up to the farthest point where they used to.</p>

<p><strong>WHAT PM MODI TOLD XI JINPING IN THEIR FIRST OFFICIAL MEET AFTER 2020</strong></p>

<p><em>"Excellency, I am happy to meet you, and like you mentioned, this is a formal meeting between us after five years. It is my belief that the importance of India-China relations is not just for the citizens of our two countries, but also very significant for peace, stability, and progress for the entire world.</em></p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/h1u97bss_narendra-modi-xi-jinping-bilateral-meeting-kazan-russia_625x300_23_October_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn," title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p><em>Excellency, We welcome the consensus reached on the issues that have arisen in the last 4 years along the border. It should be our priority to ensure there is peace and stability along our border. Mutual trust, mutual respect, and mutual sensitivity should be the basis our bilateral relations. Today, we have got an opportunity to speak about all these issues and I trust that we will hold these talks with an open mind and that our talks will be constructive going forward. Thank you."</em><br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/4smtf6m4_india-china-lac-line-of-actual-control-lac-ians_625x300_29_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[It took 4 years of diplomatic and military talks between both sides to come to an agreement]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uks-birmingham-airport-evacuated-flights-suspended-over-suspicious-vehicle-6858819]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK's Birmingham Airport Evacuated Over "Suspicious Vehicle"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uks-birmingham-airport-evacuated-flights-suspended-over-suspicious-vehicle-6858819]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:16:00 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A major international airport serving the UK's second-largest city was evacuated and all flights were suspended for several hours on Wednesday because of a security alert.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A major international airport serving the UK's second-largest city was evacuated and all flights were suspended for several hours on Wednesday because of a security alert.</p>

<p>West Midlands Police in central England ordered the partial closure of Birmingham Airport after receiving reports of a suspicious vehicle.</p>

<p>Airport authorities advised passengers not to travel while those already awaiting flights were forced to leave terminals on foot with their luggage.</p>

<p>"Whilst we apologise for any inconvenience and disruption, the safety and security of everyone at the airport was our number one priority," a statement read.</p>

<p>West Midlands Police said the evacuation was a "precautionary measure" while the vehicle was searched and assessed.</p>

<p>"Following a search by the Explosive Ordnance Disposal (EDO) team the vehicle was deemed to be safe. The vehicle is no longer being treated as suspicious," it added.</p>

<p>Birmingham Airport is the seventh busiest UK airport by passenger numbers and is used as an operating base for easyJet, Ryanair, TUI Airways and Jet2.com.</p>

<p>Its busiest routes are to and from Dublin, Dubai, Amsterdam, Palma de Mallorca and Tenerife-South.</p>

<p>"Operations will slowly be returning to normal," an airport spokesperson said. "All passengers are advised to check latest flight information from their airline."<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/ekv4lj68_birmingham-airport_625x300_24_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Birmingham Airport is the seventh busiest UK airport by passenger numbers]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/american-man-declared-brain-dead-awakens-just-before-organ-removal-6858631]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[American Man Declared Brain Dead Awakens Just Before Organ Removal]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/american-man-declared-brain-dead-awakens-just-before-organ-removal-6858631]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Oct 2024 23:35:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Concerns about organ donation procedures arose after a Kentucky man appeared to wake up moments before his organs were to be removed.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Concerns over hospital and organ donation procedures were raised after a man from Kentucky woke up right before his organs were to be removed.</p>

<p>According to a report by the US public broadcasting organisation <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.npr.org/sections/shots-health-news/2024/10/16/nx-s1-5113976/organ-transplantion-mistake-brain-dead-surgery-still-alive"><em>National Public Radio (NPR),</em></a> Natasha Miller, an employee of Kentucky Hospital, was getting ready to do her job preserving donated organs for transplantation when the nurses wheeled the donor, Anthony Thomas "TJ" Hoover II, into the operating room.</p>

<p>Natasha recognised right away that something wasn't quite right. The donor appeared to her to be very much alive, even though he had been certified brain dead.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"He was moving around-kind of thrashing. Like, moving, thrashing around on the bed," Miller told <em>NPR</em> in an interview. "And then when we went over there, you could see he had tears coming down. He was crying visibly."</p>

<p>The donor's condition alarmed everyone in the operating room at Baptist Health Hospital in Richmond, Kentucky, including the two doctors, who refused to participate in the organ retrieval, she says.</p>

<p>"The procuring surgeon was like, 'I'm out of it. I don't want to have anything to do with it,'" Miller says. "It was very chaotic. Everyone was just very upset."</p>

<p>Miller says she overheard the case coordinator at the hospital for her employer, Kentucky Organ Donor Affiliates (KODA), call her supervisor for advice.</p>

<p>"So the coordinator calls the supervisor at the time. And she was saying that he was telling her that she needed to 'find another doctor to do'it'-that, 'We were going to do this case. She needs to find someone else,'" Miller says. "And she's like, 'There is no one else.' She's crying-the coordinator-because she's getting yelled at."</p>

<p>The case of Anthony Thomas "TJ" Hoover II is under investigation by state and federal government officials. In a letter to the US House of Representatives, whistleblower Nyckoletta Martin <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://energycommerce.house.gov/events/oversight-and-investigations-subcommittee-hearing-a-year-removed-oversight-of-securing-the-u-s-organ-procurement-and-transplantation-network-act-implementation">detailed her observations</a> while working for Kentucky Organ Donor Affiliates at the time of the incident.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/jpbtmgdg_operation-theater_625x300_23_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The donor was moving and visibly crying, causing chaos in the operating room.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/brics-is-for-the-fairies-until-china-india-get-serious-says-mr-brics-6858595]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["BRICS Is For The Fairies Until China, India Get Serious," Says Mr 'BRICS']]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/brics-is-for-the-fairies-until-china-india-get-serious-says-mr-brics-6858595]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Oct 2024 23:28:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The idea of the BRICS group ever challenging the US dollar is for the fairies as long as China and India remain so divided and refuse to cooperate on trade, the former Goldman Sachs economist who came up with the BRIC acronym told Reuters.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The idea of the BRICS group ever challenging the US dollar is for the fairies as long as China and India remain so divided and refuse to cooperate on trade, the former Goldman Sachs economist who came up with the BRIC acronym told Reuters.</p>

<p>Russian President Vladimir Putin is using the summit of BRICS leaders to show that Western attempts to isolate Russia over the Ukraine war have failed and that Russia is building ties with the rising powers of Asia.</p>

<p>Then-Goldman Sachs chief economist Jim O'Neill introduced the term BRIC in 2001 in a research paper that underlined the massive growth potential of Brazil, Russia, India and China - and the need to reform global governance to include them.</p>

<p>"The idea that the BRICS can be some genuine global economic club, it's obviously a bit out there with the fairies in the same way that the G7 can be, and it's very disturbing that they see themselves as some kind of alternative global thing, because it's obviously not feasible," O'Neill told Reuters.</p>

<p>"It seems to me basically to be a symbolic annual gathering where important emerging countries, particularly noisy ones like Russia, but also China, can basically get together and highlight how good it is to be part of something that doesn't involve the US and that global governance isn't good enough."</p>

<p>O'Neill, who admitted he would "have Mr BRICS stamped on my forehead forever", said the BRICS as a group had achieved very little over the past 15 years.</p>

<p>He added that it was not possible to solve truly global issues without the United States and Europe - just as it was not possible for the West to solve truly global issues without China, India and, to a lesser extent, Russia and Brazil.</p>

<p>The BRICS group grew out of meetings between Russia, India and China which then began to meet more formally, eventually adding Brazil, then South Africa, Egypt, Ethiopia, Iran and the United Arab Emirates. Saudi Arabia has yet to formally join.</p>

<p>The group now accounts for 45 per cent of the world's population and 35 per cent of its economy, based on purchasing power parity, though China accounts for more than half of its economic might.</p>

<p>Putin opened the summit on Wednesday by saying that more than 30 states had expressed interest in joining the group but that it was important to strike a balance in any expansion.</p>

<p>Bringing in more members into BRICS would make achieving anything even harder, O'Neill said.</p>

<p><strong>Dollar challenge?</strong></p>

<p>Russia is seeking to convince BRICS countries to build an alternative platform for international payments that would be immune to Western sanctions.</p>

<p>O'Neill, 67, said people had been talking about alternatives to the dollar since he started out in finance but that none of the countries with the potential to challenge the dollar had done anything to seriously do so.</p>

<p>Any BRICS currency, he said, would be heavily dependent on China while Russia and Brazil would not be significant parts of it, he said.</p>

<p>"If they wanted to be really serious about economic matters, why don't they genuinely pursue less tariff based trade between each other?" O'Neill said.</p>

<p>"I will take the BRICS group seriously when I see signs that the two countries that really matter - China and India - are actually really trying to agree on things, rather than effectively trying to confront each other all the time."</p>

<p>India has tried to curb Chinese investments in the country since a decades old border dispute erupted into a clash between border guards in 2020. The two countries pledged to enhance cooperation on Wednesday in their first formal talks in five years.</p>

<p>Chinese President Xi Jinping told Putin the international situation was gripped by chaos but that Beijing's strategic partnership with Moscow was a force for stability amid the most significant changes seen in a century.</p>

<p>O'Neill said the G20 had failed to become a sinew of truly global governance because the United States and China had both turned inwards since the middle of the last decade. BRICS, he said, lacked clear objectives and should take on major issues for humanity - such as finding vaccines or drugs against infectious diseases, or fighting climate change.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/f9ot9bng_india-china-russia_625x300_23_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Then-Goldman Sachs chief economist Jim O'Neill introduced the term BRIC in 2001]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-dead-over-suspected-carbon-monoxide-poisoning-at-elderly-care-home-in-uk-6858594]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[3 Dead Over Suspected Carbon Monoxide Poisoning At Elderly Care Home In UK]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-dead-over-suspected-carbon-monoxide-poisoning-at-elderly-care-home-in-uk-6858594]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Oct 2024 23:27:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Three people were found dead and four others were taken to hospital after a suspected carbon monoxide poisoning at a care home for the elderly in southwest England, police said on Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Three people were found dead and four others were taken to hospital after a suspected carbon monoxide poisoning at a care home for the elderly in southwest England, police said on Wednesday.</p>

<p>Other residents at the Gainsborough Care Home in Swanage were evacuated from the premises to a nearby church hall as an investigation was launched.</p>

<p>Chief Superintendent Heather Dixey, of Dorset Police, said carbon monoxide poisoning was the investigation's "primary line of inquiry".</p>

<p>A spokesperson for gas network company SGN confirmed that engineers were called to the care home on Wednesday morning, the BBC reported.</p>

<p>The care home has 48 rooms and houses some residents with dementia.</p>

<p>"The families of those who have died have been informed and the coroner has been notified," the force said in a statement.</p>

<p>"At this time there is nothing to indicate any risk to the wider public."</p>

<p>South Western Ambulance Service said separately that it was called to the home at 0420 GMT and sent a hazardous area response team, 10 ambulances each with two crew, and "a significant number of additional resources".</p>

<p>"Two patients were conveyed by ambulance to Poole Hospital," it added.</p>

<p>The care home is run by Agincare, one of the UK's largest independent care providers.</p>

<p>At its last inspection October 2021 by the Care Quality Commission regulator, its standard of care was classed overall as "good".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-11/99c52h6_hospital-generic_625x300_17_November_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The care home has 48 rooms and houses some residents with dementia. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-strikes-lebanons-unesco-world-heritage-site-city-tyre-6858541]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Strikes Lebanon's UNESCO World Heritage Site City 'Tyre']]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-strikes-lebanons-unesco-world-heritage-site-city-tyre-6858541]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Oct 2024 23:18:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli strikes on Wednesday pounded Lebanon's Tyre, an ancient coastal city which boasts a UNESCO World Heritage site, leaving swathes of its centre in ruins.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli strikes on Wednesday pounded Lebanon's Tyre, an ancient coastal city which boasts a UNESCO World Heritage site, leaving swathes of its centre in ruins.</p>

<p>The raids, among the worst since the start of the Israel-Hezbollah war last month, hit the "heart of Tyre", said Rana, a resident who asked to only use her first name over security concerns.</p>

<p>"The whole city shook," said Rana, after fleeing to the seafront following an Israeli military warning for people to evacuate much of Tyre's centre in the morning.</p>

<p>Thick black plumes of smoke were seen rising from several neighbourhoods, with parts of the evacuation area just 500 metres (yards) from the city's ancient ruins.</p>

<p>The strikes caused "massive destruction and serious damage to homes, infrastructure, buildings, shops and cars," said the official National News Agency.</p>

<p>AFP footage showed entire neighbourhoods buried under rubble.</p>

<p>The Israeli army struck "command and control complexes of various Hezbollah units", according to a post from the military's Arabic-language spokesman, Avichay Adraee, on social media platform X.</p>

<p>Adraee described Tyre as an "important" Hezbollah stronghold, although Amal, an ally of the Iran-backed group, was believed to hold more sway there.</p>

<p>Bilal Kashmar of Tyre's disaster management unit said seven building were completely levelled and more than 400 apartments in their vicinity damaged in the strikes.</p>

<p>Four streets were completely blocked by debris, he told AFP, adding that at least two people were left wounded after most residents fled.</p>

<p><strong>Fresh exodus</strong></p>

<p>Before Hezbollah and Israel started trading fire over the border last year, at least 50,000 people lived in Tyre, a vibrant city home to both Christians and Muslims.</p>

<p>The city was emptied of most of its population when Israel's heavy bombardment began last month.</p>

<p>Only 14,500 remained there on Tuesday, Kashamr said.</p>

<p>But the city saw a fresh exodus on Wednesday as people began to escape immediately after the Israeli army issued an evacuation warning for four neighbourhoods at 8:00 am (0500 GMT).</p>

<p>Emergency teams drove around the city, urging people to evacuate over megaphones, a video journalist collaborating with AFP said.</p>

<p>An AFP photographer in the city of Sidon, further north, saw dozens of cars on the coastal highway filled with families carrying mattresses, suitcases and clothes.</p>

<p>"Some families, who had not left the city of Tyre before, began leaving their homes to stay clear of areas that the Israeli enemy threatened to target," NNA said.</p>

<p>Civil defence teams helped transport elderly people and people with limited mobility "to safe areas", the NNA added.</p>

<p><strong>Antique city</strong></p>

<p>The Risala Scouts, rescuers affiliated with Hezbollah ally Amal, deployed ambulances to targeted areas to transport wounded civilians to nearby hospitals.</p>

<p>"We are working on providing alternative housing with municipalities," said Rabih Issa, an official with the organisation.</p>

<p>Tyre is one of the oldest continuously inhabited cities in the world. It is home to important archaeological sites, mainly from Roman times.</p>

<p>Kashmar of Tyre's disaster management unit said there has yet to be a damage assessment for heritage sites.</p>

<p>However, "damage is possible," he said, explaining that one strike hit less than 50 metres away from one of the city's ruins.</p>

<p>UNESCO said it was "closely following the impact of the ongoing conflict on the World Heritage site of Tyre" using remote sensing tools and satellite imagery.</p>

<p>On September 23, Israel launched an intensive air campaign in Lebanon, after almost a year of cross-border exchanges with Hezbollah over the Gaza war.</p>

<p>Since then, at least 1,552 people have been killed in Israeli strikes on Lebanon, according to an AFP tally of health ministry figures, although the real number is likely to be higher due to data gaps.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/lpd4e3j8_lebanon_625x300_23_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[At least 50,000 people lived in Tyre before Hezbollah and Israel started trading fire]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/war-with-israel-likely-to-wipe-9-off-lebanons-gdp-un-6858432]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[War With Israel Likely To Wipe 9% Off Lebanon's GDP: UN]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/war-with-israel-likely-to-wipe-9-off-lebanons-gdp-un-6858432]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Oct 2024 22:52:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The war between Israel and armed group Hezbollah is expected to wipe 9% off Lebanon's national wealth as measured by GDP, the United Nations said on Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The war between Israel and armed group Hezbollah is expected to wipe 9% off Lebanon's national wealth as measured by GDP, the United Nations said on Wednesday, with the scale of hostilities and the economic fallout set to surpass the last war in 2006.</p>

<p>The UN Development Programme's rapid appraisal of the conflict's impact on Lebanon's gross domestic product was released a day ahead of a summit hosted by France to help drum up international support for Lebanon.</p>

<p>UNDP said it expected the conflict to last until the end of 2024, leading to a 30% jump in the government's financing needs in a country in dire straits even before violence began.</p>

<p>"GDP is projected to decline by 9.2% compared to a no-war scenario, indicating a significant decline in economic activity as a direct consequence of the conflict (around 2 billion dollars)," the report said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>UNDP said that even if the war ended in 2024, the consequences would persist for years, with GDP likely to contract by 2.28% in 2025 and 2.43% in 2026.</p>

<p>Lebanon was already suffering a four-year-old economic downturn and a political crisis when Hezbollah began firing rockets at Israel last year in support of its Palestinian ally Hamas.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In late September, Israel dramatically ramped up its bombing across Lebanon, with strikes now regularly hitting Beirut's southern suburbs, major cities in southern Lebanon and parts of the eastern Bekaa Valley, including the border with Syria.</p>

<p>Hezbollah and Israel last fought in 2006, when a month-long conflict left much of Lebanon's south and the capital's southern suburbs in ruins and required international help to rebuild.</p>

<p>UNDP said the damage to physical infrastructure, housing and productive capacities like factories would likely be close to that estimated for the 2006 war, which was between $2.5 billion and $3.6 billion. But it warned of larger overall damage to Lebanon.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The scale of the military engagement, the geopolitical context, the humanitarian impact and the economic fallout in 2024 are expected to be much greater than in 2006," it said.</p>

<p>UNDP's report said the closure of border crossings critical for trade would bring a 21% drop in trade activities, and that it expected job losses in the tourism, agriculture and construction sectors.&nbsp;</p>

<p>It said Lebanon had already sustained "massive environmental losses" over the last year, including due to unexploded ordnance and contamination from possibly hazardous material, particularly the use of white phosphorus across southern Lebanon.</p>

<p>Government revenue is expected to fall by 9% and total investment by more than 6% through both 2025 and 2026.</p>

<p>As a result, increased international assistance will be essential for sustainable recovery in Lebanon, UNDP said - not only to address the spike in humanitarian needs but to stem the long-term social and economic consequences of the conflict.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Lebanon's minister in charge of its crisis response told Reuters that the country needed $250 million a month to help more than 1.2 million people displaced by Israeli strikes.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/lpd4e3j8_lebanon_625x300_23_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[UNDP said the damages would likely be close to that estimated for the 2006 war. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iranian-hackers-looking-at-us-election-websites-ahead-of-polls-microsoft-6858373]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iranian Hackers Looking At US Election Websites Ahead Of Polls: Microsoft]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iranian-hackers-looking-at-us-election-websites-ahead-of-polls-microsoft-6858373]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Oct 2024 22:44:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An Iranian hacking group is actively scouting US election-related websites and American media outlets as election day nears, according to a Microsoft blog published on Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An Iranian hacking group is actively scouting US election-related websites and American media outlets as election day nears, according to a Microsoft blog published on Wednesday. Researchers say the activity suggests "preparations for more direct influence operations."</p>

<p>The hackers - dubbed Cotton Sandstorm by Microsoft and linked to Iran's Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps - performed reconnaissance and limited probing of multiple "election-related websites" in several unnamed swing states, the report notes. In May, they also scanned an unidentified US news outlet to understand its vulnerabilities.</p>

<p>"Cotton Sandstorm will increase its activity as the election nears given the group's operational tempo and history of election interference," researchers wrote. The development is particularly concerning because of the group's past efforts.</p>

<p>A spokesperson for Iran's mission to the United Nations said that "such allegations are fundamentally unfounded, and wholly inadmissible."</p>

<p>"Iran neither has any motive nor intent to interfere in the US election," they added.</p>

<p>In 2020, Cotton Sandstorm launched a different cyber-enabled influence operation shortly before the last presidential election. Posing as the right-wing "Proud Boys," the hackers sent thousands of emails to Florida residents, threatening them to "vote for Trump or else!".</p>

<p>The group also released a video on social media, purporting to come from hacktivists, where they showed them probing an election system. While that operation never affected individual voting systems, the goal was to cause chaos, confusion and doubt, senior U.S. officials said at the time.</p>

<p>Following the 2020 election, Cotton Sandstorm also ran a separate operation that encouraged violence against US election officials who had denied claims of widespread voter fraud, Microsoft said.</p>

<p>The Office of the Director of National Intelligence, which is coordinating the federal effort to defend the election from foreign influence, did not immediately respond to a request for comment.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/rphbec7o_hacker-generic_625x300_23_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The hackers are dubbed Cotton Sandstorm by Microsoft (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-bans-student-wing-of-ex-pm-sheikh-hasinas-party-under-anti-terror-law-6858324]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh Bans Student Wing Of Ex PM's Party Under Anti-Terror Law]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-bans-student-wing-of-ex-pm-sheikh-hasinas-party-under-anti-terror-law-6858324]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Oct 2024 22:34:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Bangladesh banned the student wing of ousted premier Sheikh Hasina's party on Thursday, citing its involvement in violent attacks on demonstrations that toppled the autocratic leader.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bangladesh banned the student wing of ousted premier Sheikh Hasina's party on Thursday, citing its involvement in violent attacks on demonstrations that toppled the autocratic leader.</p>

<p>Sheikh Hasina fled the country in August as thousands marched on her official residence, ending a 15-year tenure that saw widespread human rights abuses.</p>

<p>The student wing of her Awami League party was accused of propping up her iron-fisted rule, which saw the mass detention and extrajudicial killings of her political opponents.</p>

<p>A government notice accused the party's youth wing, known as the Chhatra League, of involvement in "murders, persecution, torture... and many other activities that threaten public security".</p>

<p>The statement added that the student group had been outlawed under anti-terrorism laws.</p>

<p>Initially peaceful protests that began in July against Sheikh Hasina's government turned violent when Chhatra League activists attacked student demonstrators on university campuses.</p>

<p>The attempt by pro-government cadres to quell the protests instead fanned public anger, culminating in Sheikh Hasina's overthrow weeks later.</p>

<p>More than 700 people were killed in the resulting unrest, according to official estimates -- most in clashes between police and anti-Hasina protesters.</p>

<p>A Bangladeshi court this month issued an arrest warrant for the exiled leader, who fled to neighbouring India on the day of her overthrow.</p>

<p>Dozens of Sheikh Hasina's allies were taken into custody after her regime collapsed, accused of culpability in the police crackdown.</p>

<p>Former cabinet ministers and other senior members of the Awami League have been arrested, and her government's appointees were purged from courts and the central bank.</p>

<p>Sheikh Hasina, however, has not been seen in public since fleeing the country by helicopter.</p>

<p>The 77-year-old's last official whereabouts are a military airbase near Delhi.</p>

<p>Her presence in India -- her government's biggest benefactor -- has infuriated the interim administration in Bangladesh that replaced her.</p>

<p>Dhaka has revoked her diplomatic passport, and the countries have a bilateral extradition treaty which would facilitate her return to face criminal trial.</p>

<p>A clause in the treaty, however, says extradition might be refused if the offence is of a "political character".</p>

<p>Sheikh Hasina was replaced by Nobel Peace Prize winner Muhammad Yunus, who was sworn in to helm an interim administration days after her departure.</p>

<p>The 84-year-old microfinance pioneer's temporary administration is facing what he has called the "extremely tough" challenge of restoring democratic institutions.</p>

<p>Yunus has said he inherited a "completely broken down" system of public administration and justice that needs a comprehensive overhaul to prevent a future return to autocracy.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/81hfi6o_sheikh-hasina_625x300_07_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Dozens of Sheikh Hasina's allies were taken into custody after her regime collapsed. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-confirms-nasrallahs-likely-successor-killed-in-israeli-strike-6858250]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hezbollah Confirms Nasrallah's Likely Successor Killed In Israeli Strike]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-confirms-nasrallahs-likely-successor-killed-in-israeli-strike-6858250]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Oct 2024 22:23:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hezbollah confirmed Wednesday that Israel killed Hashem Safieddine, the apparent successor of its slain leader Hassan Nasrallah, in a strike, without saying when or where it happened.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hezbollah confirmed Wednesday that Israel killed Hashem Safieddine, the apparent successor of its ex leader Hassan Nasrallah, in a strike, without saying when or where it happened.</p>

<p>The announcement came a day after Israel said he was killed along with other Hezbollah leaders in an air strike in Beirut's southern suburbs three weeks ago.</p>

<p>"We mourn... the head of the Executive Council of Hezbollah, his eminence the scholar Sayyed Hashem Safieddine," the Iran-backed group said in a statement, adding he was killed by "a criminal and aggressive Zionist raid" alongside other Hezbollah fighters.</p>

<p>The deeply religious Safieddine, a cleric with family ties to Nasrallah, had been widely viewed as the most likely candidate for the party's top job after the assassination of Nasrallah on September 27 in a huge Israeli air strike on Beirut's southern suburbs.</p>

<p>Safieddine, a member of the group's governing Shura Council, had strong ties to Iran after undergoing religious studies in the Islamic republic's holy city of Qom.</p>

<p>The United States and Saudi Arabia had put him on their respective lists of designated "terrorists" in 2017.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/rj463n3_hashem-safieddine_625x300_05_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hashem Safieddine had been widely viewed as the most likely candidate for the party's top job. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/norways-crown-princess-on-sick-leave-due-to-rare-lung-condition-6858199]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Norway's Crown Princess On "Sick Leave" Due To Rare Lung Condition]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/norways-crown-princess-on-sick-leave-due-to-rare-lung-condition-6858199]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Oct 2024 22:15:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Norway's Crown Princess Mette-Marit has been placed on sick leave for at least a week due to a rare lung condition from which she suffers, the palace said Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Norway's Crown Princess Mette-Marit has been placed on sick leave for at least a week due to a rare lung condition from which she suffers, the palace said Wednesday.</p>

<p>The 51-year-old wife of Crown Prince Haakon announced in October 2018 that she had been diagnosed with a rare form of pulmonary fibrosis, an incurable disease that causes scarring of the lungs and shortness of breath.</p>

<p>"Due to side effects from the medication that the Crown Princess has to take for her chronic lung disease, she has been placed on sick leave, initially for one week," the palace said on its website.</p>

<p>The condition has at times affected her royal duties, requiring her to lighten her load or cancel engagements.</p>

<p>"She will never be cured, but the illness is not deteriorating very rapidly, which is what the doctors are aiming for," Haakon said in an official autobiography published last year.</p>

<p>"She has many good days. But the uncertainty is always there. Do we have to cancel? We never know. Illness is also a part of life, as is addressing challenges together," he added.</p>

<p>Mette-Marit has been in the Norwegian headlines recently after her 27-year-old son -- from a relationship prior to her marriage to the crown prince -- was accused by several ex-girlfriends of assault, most recently in August when he admitted being under the influence of alcohol and cocaine.</p>

<p>She has repeatedly told media that she is unable to comment on the case "out of respect for all parties".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/a8erl7v8_norway-crown-princess_625x300_23_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The condition has at times affected the princess' royal duties. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/justin-trudeau-meets-legislators-unhappy-with-his-leadership-they-want-him-to-go-6858169]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trudeau Meets Legislators Unhappy With His Leadership, They Want Him To Go]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/justin-trudeau-meets-legislators-unhappy-with-his-leadership-they-want-him-to-go-6858169]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Oct 2024 22:11:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau on Wednesday met legislators from his ruling Liberals, some of whom blame him for the party's poor showing in the polls and want him to quit after nine years in power.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau on Wednesday met legislators from his ruling Liberals, some of whom blame him for the party's poor showing in the polls and want him to quit after nine years in power.</p>

<p>While Trudeau is in no immediate danger, since he cannot be pushed out, the public display of unhappiness is among the most serious political challenges he has faced. Major parties usually meet on Wednesdays, but the circumstances this time are unusual.</p>

<p>Trudeau insists he will lead the Liberals into the next election, which must be held by the end of October 2025, even though surveys of public opinion suggest that with him at the helm, the party will lose badly to the official opposition Conservatives.</p>

<p>A Nanos Research poll released on Oct. 15 put the Conservatives on 39% public support, with the Liberals well behind on 23% and the rival left-leaning New Democrats on 21%. Such a result on election day would give the Conservatives a comfortable majority.</p>

<p>The Canadian Broadcasting Corp said 24 of the party's 153 legislators had signed a letter calling on Trudeau to go.</p>

<p>Ken McDonald, a Liberal parliamentarian from Atlantic Canada who is not standing in the next election, said ahead of the meeting that some of those who signed the letter "are worried because of the polling that is going constantly down."</p>

<p>Wayne Long, another legislator from the same region, said if the party had a new leader it could beat the Conservatives, who blame Trudeau for rising prices and a housing crisis.</p>

<p>There is no mechanism to oust Trudeau. Unlike Australia, where leaders are elected by legislators, Canadian party chiefs are chosen by members at a special convention.</p>

<p>Unhappiness with Trudeau bubbled up after the party lost two of its safest parliamentary seats in special elections in June and September.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/32dkuepo_justin-trudeau-reuters_625x300_17_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Canadian Broadcasting Corp said 24 of 153 legislators signed a letter calling on Justin Trudeau to go]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chinese-controlled-bot-army-tries-to-influence-us-voters-microsoft-report-6858117]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Chinese-Controlled Bot Army Tries To Influence US Voters: Microsoft Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chinese-controlled-bot-army-tries-to-influence-us-voters-microsoft-report-6858117]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Oct 2024 22:07:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An army of Chinese-controlled social media bots is attempting to influence voters in Alabama, Texas and Tennessee, while denigrating Florida Senator Marco Rubio, according to new research published on Wednesday by Microsoft.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An army of Chinese-controlled social media bots is attempting to influence voters in Alabama, Texas and Tennessee, while denigrating Florida Senator Marco Rubio, according to new research published on Wednesday by Microsoft.</p>

<p>The operation represents a coordinated interference effort against down ballot races, experts say, in which the fake accounts are denigrating Representative Barry Moore of Alabama, Texas representative Michael McCaul, Tennessee Senator Marsha Blackburn and Rubio, all Republicans.</p>

<p>The troll network has "parroted antisemitic messages, amplified accusations of corruption and promoted opposition candidates," according to Microsoft.</p>

<p>The group responsible is known as Taizi Flood, which has been previously associated with China's Ministry of Public Security, researchers say. The lawmakers were each targeted because they had denounced Chinese government policies historically, the report notes.</p>

<p>China's embassy in Washington did not immediately respond to a request for comment.</p>

<p>Among other things, the bots criticized Moore's support for Israel and used antisemitic language. Another collective of related accounts claimed Rubio was part of a financial corruption scheme.</p>

<p>The bots amplified support for Blackburn's election rival while spreading claims she took money from pharmaceutical companies. With McCaul, they pushed narratives that he engaged in insider trading.</p>

<p>Moore, McCaul and Blackburn are all running for reelection next month. Rubio, who serves as vice chair of the Senate intelligence committee, is not up for reelection until 2028.</p>

<p>The Microsoft researchers found the influence effort did not result "in high levels of engagement." The report did not provide any metrics for how many Americans viewed the relevant social media posts.</p>

<p>A spokesperson for Moore, Madison Green, said his office was aware of the campaign.</p>

<p>"We know that the CCP is antisemitic, so it isn't surprising that they are targeting me and other politicians who support Israel to try sow division in advance of the most important election in our lifetime," said Moore.</p>

<p>"China has made it clear they will use every weapon in their arsenal, including offensive cyber capabilities, to try and destroy democracy across the world," he added.</p>

<p>Spokespeople for the other three lawmakers did not immediately respond to a request for comment.</p>

<p>The Office of the Director of National Intelligence, which is coordinating the federal effort to defend the election from foreign influence, did not immediately respond to a request for comment.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/ockvg5ro_us-voters-reuters_625x300_23_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[China's embassy in Washington did not immediately respond to a request for comment. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-a-first-scientists-discover-dinosaur-fossils-in-hong-kong-6858111]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[In A First, Scientists Discover Dinosaur Fossils In Hong Kong]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-a-first-scientists-discover-dinosaur-fossils-in-hong-kong-6858111]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Oct 2024 22:03:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Scientists have discovered dinosaur fossils in Hong Kong for the first time, the city's government announcement on Wednesday, adding that the species remains unknown.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Scientists have discovered dinosaur fossils in Hong Kong for the first time, the city's government announcement on Wednesday, adding that the species remains unknown.</p>

<p>Experts from Hong Kong and mainland China identified the fossils as belonging to a large, aged dinosaur from the Cretaceous period, around 145 million to 66 million years ago, the Development Bureau said in a statement.</p>

<p>The first humans are believed to have appeared on Earth around six million years ago.</p>

<p>Further analysis will be conducted to confirm the species of the dinosaur, the statement said.</p>

<p>The fossils will be put on public display from Friday, it added.</p>

<p>They were discovered on Hong Kong's remote, northeastern Port Island, where suspected vertebrate fossils were first spotted in sedimentary rock in March.</p>

<p>The small, uninhabited outlying islet -- part of Hong Kong's 150-square-kilometre (58-square-mile) UNESCO Global Geopark -- has been closed from Wednesday for further excavations.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/i8qvouf8_hong-kong-unsplash_625x300_23_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The fossils will be put on public display from Friday in Hong Kong. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/female-athletes-lost-nearly-900-medals-to-transgender-competitors-un-report-6857482]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Female Athletes Lost Nearly 900 Medals To Transgender Rivals: UN Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/female-athletes-lost-nearly-900-medals-to-transgender-competitors-un-report-6857482]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Oct 2024 20:38:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Over 600 female athletes across 29 sports have lost medals, sparking ongoing debates on gender inclusivity in sports.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The 2024 Paris Olympics' gender parity milestone was tainted by gender-related disputes, with a recent United Nations report voicing concerns about issues related to women's sports competition.</p>

<p>According to the report, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://documents.un.org/doc/undoc/gen/n24/249/94/pdf/n2424994.pdf"><em>"Violence Against Women and Girls in Sports,"</em> </a>transgender athletes have won around 900 medals in different women's sports at several events, replacing female athletes.&nbsp;</p>

<p>It also brought attention to the fact that more than 600 female athletes had lost against individuals born male in a variety of competitions, escalating the argument about competition fairness.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://sports.ndtv.com/swimming/transgender-us-swimmer-wins-ivy-league-500-yard-womens-freestyle-2775787"><strong>Also Read | Transgender US Swimmer Wins Ivy League 500-Yard Women's Freestyle</strong></a></p>

<p>These findings spotlight significant gaps in the IOC's policies, which continue to affect athletes globally, raising questions about the future of gender inclusivity in sports.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://sports.ndtv.com/olympics-2024/olympics-why-is-algerian-boxer-imane-khelif-embroiled-in-gender-row-being-called-biological-male-explained-6246580"><strong>Also Read | Why Algerian Boxer Imane Khelif, Embroiled In Gender Row, Is Being Called 'Biological Male' - Explained</strong></a></p>

<p>"Policies implemented by International Federations, national governing bodies, along with national legislation of some countries, allow males who identify as women to compete in female sports categories," the report said.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/who-is-roma-michael-pakistani-models-bikini-ramp-walk-sparks-controversy-6857263"><strong>Also Read | Who Is Roma Michael? Pakistani Model's Bikini Ramp Walk Sparks Controversy</strong></a></p>

<p>"In other cases, this practice is not explicitly prohibited and is thus tolerated in practice. The replacement of the female sports category with a mixed sex category has resulted in an increasing number of female athletes losing opportunities including medals when competing against males."</p>

<p>"According to information received, by 30 March 2024, over 600 female athletes in more than 400 competitions have lost more than 890 medals in 29 different sports," the report said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-02/8qpqa3v8_lia-thomas-afp_625x300_18_February_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Transgender athletes have won nearly 900 medals in women's sports.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/updates-terror-attack-in-turkeys-ankara-hostages-taken-say-reports-6857255]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Highlights: Terror Attack In Turkey's Ankara, Hostages Taken, Say Reports]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/updates-terror-attack-in-turkeys-ankara-hostages-taken-say-reports-6857255]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Oct 2024 20:07:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Several people died and got injured in an explosion outside Turkish Aerospace Industries (TAI) near Turkey capital Ankara today.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Several people died and got injured in an explosion outside Turkish Aerospace Industries (TAI) near Turkey capital Ankara today. Turkey's interior minister called it a "terrorist attack". Gunshots were reportedly heard from the spot and visuals show smoke at the site of explosion. According to the local media, there is an ongoing "hostage situation".&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>Here are the highlights of the big story:</strong></h2>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/g3mbmfo8_turkey-terror-attack_625x300_23_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[According to the local media, there is an ongoing "hostage situation".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-modi-xi-jinping-bilateral-summit-brics-summit-russia-india-china-patrolling-agreement-pm-modi-xi-welcome-complete-disengagement-between-soldiers-al-6857182]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[PM Modi, Xi Welcome "Complete Disengagement" Between Soldiers Along LAC]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-modi-xi-jinping-bilateral-summit-brics-summit-russia-india-china-patrolling-agreement-pm-modi-xi-welcome-complete-disengagement-between-soldiers-al-6857182]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Oct 2024 20:00:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India and China on Wednesday welcomed the patrolling agreement announced this week that calls for "complete (military) disengagement" along the Line of Actual Control in the Himalayas.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/topic/pm-modi" target="_blank">Prime Minister Narendra Modi</a> and China's <a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/topic/xi-jinping" target="_blank">Xi Jinping</a>&nbsp;have&nbsp;welcomed the patrolling agreement announced this week that calls for "complete (military) disengagement" along the Line of Actual Control in the Himalayas, as well as "resolution of issues that arose in 2020 in the India-China border areas".</p>

<p>The phrase "complete disengagement" indicates the two militaries will withdraw to pre-May 2020 positions, i.e., before skirmishes, including violent clashes in Ladakh's Galwan, in which 20 Indian soldiers were killed, triggered by the May 5 face-off in the Pangong Lake region.</p>

<p>The withdrawal to pre-May 2020 positions was also flagged by Foreign Minister S Jaishankar, who told the NDTV the patrolling agreement "creates a basis for peace and tranquillity along the border, which (was) there before 2020". He said the agreement was due to "patient and persevering diplomacy".</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/we-will-be-able-to-go-back-to-2020-patrolling-s-jaishankar-on-lac-border-row-6839082" target="_blank">"Back To 2020...": S Jaishankar To NDTV On India, China Pact</a></p>

<p>Meanwhile, in another significant step forward, Special Representatives of both sides - India's National Security Advisor Ajit Doval and China's Foreign Minister, Wang Yi - could meet soon "to explore a fair, reasonable, and mutually acceptable solution to the boundary question".</p>

<p>Mr Doval and Mr Yi have not met - as Special Representatives - since 2019.</p>

<p>These points were announced in a statement after PM Modi and President Jinping held a first bilateral meet since the May 2020 clashes; they met on the sidelines of the BRICS Summit in Russia's Kazan.</p>

<p>In the meeting the Prime Minister emphasised to his Chinese counterpart "the importance of properly handling differences and disputes" and not allowing these to disturb relations.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-modi-chinas-xi-jinping-bilateral-starts-in-russia-first-since-2020-6856030#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">"Peace On Border Should Be Priority," PM Tells Xi Jinping In Russia</a></p>

<p>The two leaders also recognised that "stable, predictable, and amicable bilateral relations... between the two largest nations on Earth... will have a positive impact on regional and global peace and prosperity" and also contribute to a multi-polar Asian and global community.</p>

<p>India and China, therefore, underlined the need to progress bilateral relations, enhance strategic communication, and explore cooperation to address developmental challenges.</p>

<p>In statements before the bilateral, Mr Modi told the Chinese leader, "It should be our priority to ensure there is peace and stability along our border", and stressed the need for "mutual trust, mutual respect".</p>

<p>Mr Jinping pointed to India and China's ancient historical connections and present-day statuses as major developing countries and members of the Global South, and said, "It best serves the fundamental interest of our countries and peoples to keep to the trend of history..."</p>

<p>Today's meet between PM Modi and President Jinping took place less than 72 hours after the patrolling agreement - which followed sustained dialogue at military and diplomatic levels -was announced.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/india-china-agree-on-patrolling-agreement-along-lac-leads-to-disengagement-6838489" target="_blank">India To Resume Patrolling In Ladakh After Big Breakthrough With China</a></p>

<p>The agreement was seen as a big step to de-escalation in a region in which both sides have amassed tens of thousands of troops and armaments over the past four years.</p>

<p><em>NDTV is now available on WhatsApp channels. <a href="https://www.whatsapp.com/channel/0029Va4lixw7z4kcvZI9JM12">Click on the link</a> to get all the latest updates from NDTV on your chat. </em></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/f7rh9k5g_pm-modi-xi-jinping-bilateral-meeting-kazan-russia_625x300_23_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/turkey-terror-attack-many-dead-and-injured-in-huge-explosion-near-ankara-6857092]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[2 Terrorists And 4 Civilians Killed, 14 Injured In Turkey Terror Attack]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/turkey-terror-attack-many-dead-and-injured-in-huge-explosion-near-ankara-6857092]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Oct 2024 19:45:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Four people were killed and 14 others wounded in an attack on the headquarters of a top Turkish defence firm near Ankara, Turkish officials said Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Four people were killed and 14 others wounded in an attack on the headquarters of a top Turkish defence firm near Ankara, Turkish officials said Wednesday.</p>

<p>President Recep Tayyip Erdogan, who was holding talks in Russia with Vladimir Putin at the time, confirmed the toll, and condemned what he said was a "heinous terrorist attack" at state-run Turkish Aerospace Industries (TAI).</p>

<p>Interior Minister Ali Yerlikaya said three of the injured were in critical condition and that two attackers "a woman and a man, have been neutralised".</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="tr">YEN BLG-1<br />
<br />
Trk Havaclk ve Uzay Sanayii A. (TUSA) Ankara Kahramankazan tesislerine ynelik terr saldrsnda 2 terrist etkisiz hale getirilmitir.<br />
<br />
Saldrda maalesef 3 ehidimiz, 14 yaralmz var.<br />
<br />
ehitlerimize Allah'tan rahmet; yarallarmza acil ifalar diliyorum....</p>
 Ali Yerlikaya (@AliYerlikaya) <a href="https://twitter.com/AliYerlikaya/status/1849101152098410932?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 23, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>He said work was under way to determine their identities but did not say whether there were any other attackers still at large.</p>

<p>Local media broadcast footage showing clouds of smoke and a large fire raging at the site in Kahramankazan, a small town some 40 kilometres (25 miles) north of Ankara.</p>

<p>The incident happened as Erdogan was meeting Vladimir Putin at a summit in Kazan, with the Russian leader expressing his condolences over the attack.</p>

<p>Media outlets which had been showing live footage from the scene were forced to halt their broadcasts after Turkey's media watchdog ordered a blackout of images from the site.</p>

<p>Haberturk TV said there was an ongoing "hostage situation" without giving further details, while the private NTV television spoke of gunshots after the blast, which took place around 4:00 pm (1300 GMT).</p>

<p>There was no immediate claim for the attack but the justice minister said an investigation had been opened.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="tr">Ankara'nn Kahramankazan ilesinde bulunan Trk Havaclk ve Uzay Sanayii tesislerine dzenlenen terr saldrsn iddetle knyor ve lanetliyorum.<br />
<br />
Hain terr saldrsyla ilgili Ankara Cumhuriyet Basavcl tarafndan adli soruturma balatlm olup, 1 Basavcvekili ve 8</p>
 Ylmaz TUN (@yilmaztunc) <a href="https://twitter.com/yilmaztunc/status/1849086919193272824?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 23, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>NTV spoke of a suicide attack, saying "a group of terrorists" had burst into TAI's headquarters and one of them blew themself up.</p>

<p>Images shown by Haberturk suggested one attacker was a woman, while Sabah newspaper published a CCTV image from cameras at the building's entrance of a black-clad young man with a moustache carrying a rucksack and what appeared to be an assault rifle.</p>

<p>The attack drew condemnation from Transport Minister Abdulkadir Uraloglu as well as opposition leader Ozgur Ozel, who heads the CHP.</p>

<p>"I condemn the terrorist attack against TAI facilities in Kahramankazan... I condemn terrorism, no matter who or where it comes from," Ozel wrote on X.</p>

<p>According to TAI's website, the state-run company, which is also a major arms producer, employs 15,500 people and has a vast production site covering an area of five million square metres.</p>

<p><strong>Erdogan in Russia</strong></p>

<p>The blast occurred as Erdogan was with Putin in the Russian city of Kazan for the BRICS summit of major emerging market nations, including Brazil, Russia, India, China and South Africa.</p>

<p>"I would like to express my condolences in connection with the terror attack," Putin told him at the start of their meeting.</p>

<p>NATO chief Mark Rutte also offered the alliance's backing to member state Turkey in a call with Erdogan following the attack.</p>

<p>"I just spoke with (President) Erdogan about the terror attack in Ankara. My message was clear: NATO stands with Turkiye," Rutte wrote on X, using the country's official Turkish name.</p>

<p>The Turkish city of Istanbul is currently hosting a major trade fair for the defence and aerospace industries at the moment, visited this week by Ukraine's top diplomat.</p>

<p>Turkey's defence sector, which is known for its Bayraktar drones, accounts for some 80 percent of the nation's export revenues.</p>

<p>Contracts worth $10.2 billion were signed last year, according to Haluk Gorgun, head of Turkey's state Defence Industry Agency (SSB).</p>

<p>In the first eight months of this year, defence export revenues reached $3.7 billion, up nearly 10 percent from same period a year earlier, Gorgun said.</p>

<p>The last attack in Turkey took place in January when a man was shot dead by two gunmen who opened fire inside a Catholic church in Istanbul.</p>

<p>That attack was claimed by Islamic State (IS) group jihadists.</p>

<p>In October 2023, two policemen were injured in an attack in the government district in Ankara.</p>

<p>Police shot dead one assailant while the other died in an apparent suicide blast outside the interior ministry.</p>

<p>That attack was claimed by the PKK (Kurdistan Workers' Party) which has waged an insurgency against the Turkish state since 1984 in a conflict that has claimed tens of thousands of lives.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/4cikek6g_turkey-terror-attack-_625x300_23_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[There was no immediate claim for the attack]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/un-aid-worker-killed-in-strike-on-vehicle-in-gaza-6856997]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UN Aid Worker Killed In Strike On Vehicle In Gaza]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/un-aid-worker-killed-in-strike-on-vehicle-in-gaza-6856997]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Oct 2024 19:32:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An UNRWA employee was killed in a strike on a vehicle in Gaza Wednesday, the UN agency for Palestinian refugees said, the latest aid worker death in the war-torn territory.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An UNRWA employee was killed in a strike on a vehicle in Gaza Wednesday, the UN agency for Palestinian refugees said, the latest aid worker death in the war-torn territory.</p>

<p>"I can confirm that an UNRWA car was hit. One UNRWA colleague was killed," UNRWA spokeswoman Juliette Touma told AFP.</p>

<p>An AFP photographer said the strike in the southern Gaza city of Khan Yunis early on Wednesday killed two people in all.</p>

<p>At least 223 UNRWA staff have been killed and two-thirds of the agency's facilities in Gaza damaged or destroyed since the war erupted early last year, its head, Philippe Lazzarini, said last month.</p>

<p>Many Gazans displaced by the fighting have sought shelter in UNRWA facilities including schools. Israel has conducted strikes on several of these schools-turned-shelter, accusing Hamas of using them as command centers -- a charge denied by the Palestinian operator group.</p>

<p>Wednesday's strike came as Israel moves to curb UNRWA's activities, with the foreign affairs and defence committee of Israel's parliament approving two bills earlier this month essentially aimed at ending the agency's activity and privileges in Israel.</p>

<p>One bill seeks to prevent UNRWA from operating any institution or providing any services or activity in Israel. The second bill says that UNRWA workers will not enjoy the immunity or special rights enjoyed by other UN workers in Israel.</p>

<p>UNRWA and the wider humanitarian response to Israel's military operations in Gaza have been a bone of contention in the conflict, with Israeli authorities accused of restricting aid flows.</p>

<p>The war in Gaza began with Hamas's October 7, 2023 attack on Israel, which resulted in the deaths of 1,206 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally of Israeli official figures.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory offensive has killed more than 42,792 people in Gaza, also mostly civilians, according to figures from the Hamas-run territory's health ministry which the UN considers reliable.</p>

<p>The agency saw funding cuts earlier this year after Israel accused a dozen of its 13,000 Gaza employees of involvement in the October 7 attack by Hamas.</p>

<p>An internal probe published in August found that nine employees "may have been involved in the armed attacks of 7 October".</p>

<p>UNRWA was created in 1949 to support Palestinian refugees in the Middle East.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/09fg66ig_gaza_625x300_22_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Wednesday's strike came as Israel moves to curb UNRWA's activities (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/india-in-very-good-position-to-listen-to-both-russia-ukraine-german-envoy-6856947]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India In Very Good Position To Listen To Both Russia, Ukraine: German Envoy]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/india-in-very-good-position-to-listen-to-both-russia-ukraine-german-envoy-6856947]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Oct 2024 19:26:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[German Ambassador Philipp Ackermann has noted that Germany has always said India is in a "very good position" to basically listen to both sides when it comes to the Russia-Ukraine conflict.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>German Ambassador Philipp Ackermann has noted that Germany has always said India is in a "very good position" to basically listen to both sides when it comes to the Russia-Ukraine conflict. Though he does not know what New Delhi is intending to do, but Berlin would "welcome any engagement", he added.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/german-envoy-on-lok-sabha-elections-we-are-observing-with-admiration-worlds-biggest-elections-5451559">Ambassador Ackermann</a> interacted with media at his residence here, ahead of German Chancellor Olaf Scholz's visit to India.</p>

<p>On October 25, Prime Minister Narendra Modi and <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-germany-decide-to-expand-ties-in-renewable-energy-mobility-sectors-6617255">Chancellor Scholz</a> will co-chair the seventh Intergovernmental Consultations (IGC).</p>

<p>The IGC is a whole-of-government framework under which ministers from both sides hold discussions in their respective areas of responsibility and report on the outcome of their deliberations to the prime minister and the chancellor.</p>

<p>In response to a query on India's potential role towards seeking a resolution of the over two-year-long conflict, Ackermann said, "We all know that Prime Minister (Modi) is coming back from Kazan... BRICS Summit. He has been talking to a lot of leaders, including the Russian president, and without being privy to know the agenda of the bilateral talks... I am sure it will be on the agenda, and chancellor will be very curious what the PM has to say after this meeting".</p>

<p>"We have always said that India is in a very good position to basically listen to both sides, and to have both sides in mind. We have seen the PM going to Kyiv, we have seen a renewed interest in the conflict... I think, I don't know what India is intending to do, but we would welcome any engagement," he said.</p>

<p>Later an interaction with PTI Videos after his briefing, the German envoy said he was convinced that Modi and Scholz "will discuss geopolitics".</p>

<p>"I am very convinced, although I don't know the agenda of the bilateral meeting, but I am very convinced that they will discuss geopolitics. It will always be good to listen to India's perspective on things. We have a Euro-centric perspective on things, India can add to this view a lot. I know that the chancellor and the PM have a very good communication on these questions, and I am sure these will be tackled during the.. .(meeting)," he said, when asked if the ongoing conflicts in Ukraine and West Asia will figure in their talks.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Modi is currently visiting Russia for the 16th BRICS summit being held in Kazan. On Tuesday, he held bilateral talks with Russian President Vladimir Putin hours after arriving in the central Russian city to attend the summit.</p>

<p>India supports dialogue and diplomacy and not war, Prime Minister Modi said at the BRICS Summit on Wednesday, in an unambiguous message calling for resolution of the Russia-Ukraine conflict through peaceful negotiations.</p>

<p>In his address, Modi flagged concerns over pressing challenges such as wars, economic uncertainty, climate change and terrorism and said the BRICS can play a positive role in taking the world on the right path.</p>

<p>PM Modi had visited Russia in July, marking his first visit since the Russian invasion of Ukraine.</p>

<p>In August he undertook a visit to Ukraine at the invitation of Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskyy.</p>

<p>In a joint statement issued by the MEA on this visit, the Indian side had reiterated its principled position and focus on peaceful resolution through dialogue and diplomacy, as part of which, India attended the Summit on Peace in Ukraine, held in Burgenstock, Switzerland, in June this year.</p>

<p>The Ukrainian side had welcomed such participation by India and highlighted the importance of high-level Indian participation in the next Peace Summit.</p>

<p>In September, PM Modi had met Zelenskyy on the sidelines of UNGA in New York.</p>

<p>The leaders had exchanged views on bilateral ties and also discussed the situation in Ukraine.</p>

<p>The prime minister had reiterated India's willingness to play a constructive role in the quest for a peaceful resolution of the conflict through dialogue and diplomacy.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-05/94do25ig_modi-olaf-_625x300_20_May_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[PM Modi and Chancellor Scholz will co-chair the 7th Intergovernmental Consultations on Oct 25. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>