<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Thu, 26 Sep 2024 12:09:51 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/high-profile-exit-from-openai-mira-murati-quits-as-cto-ceo-sam-altman-reacts-6652614]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Why Mira Murati Quit As Chief Technology Officer Of OpenAI]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/high-profile-exit-from-openai-mira-murati-quits-as-cto-ceo-sam-altman-reacts-6652614]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 26 Sep 2024 11:57:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Mira Murati quit as the Chief Technology Officer of OpenAI on Wednesday. She's the latest to join a growing list of high-profile exits from the company. Ms Murati's decision comes after 6 years with the artificial intelligence pioneer behind ChatGPT.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Mira Murati quit as the Chief Technology Officer of OpenAI on Wednesday. She's the latest to join a growing list of high-profile exits from the company. Ms Murati's decision comes after six years with the artificial intelligence pioneer behind ChatGPT.</p>

<p>In a post on X, Ms Murati described her time at OpenAI as “an extraordinary privilege” and her decision to leave as “difficult.” “There's never an ideal time to walk away from a place one cherishes, but the moment feels right. I want to create the time and space to do my exploration,” she said.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">I shared the following note with the OpenAI team today. <a href="https://t.co/nsZ4khI06P">pic.twitter.com/nsZ4khI06P</a></p>
— Mira Murati (@miramurati) <a href="https://twitter.com/miramurati/status/1839025700009030027?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 25, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>OpenAI CEO Sam Altman responded with a touching tribute to X, thanking her for her contributions and conveying his support.&nbsp;“It's hard to overstate how much Mira has meant to OpenAI, our mission, and to us all personally,” the CEO wrote. “I feel tremendous gratitude towards her for what she has helped us build and accomplish.”&nbsp;</p>

<p>He said he was "excited for what she'll do next."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">I replied with this. Mira, thank you for everything.<br />
<br />
It's hard to overstate how much Mira has meant to OpenAI, our mission, and to us all personally.<br />
<br />
I feel tremendous gratitude towards her for what she has helped us build and accomplish, but I most of all feel personal…</p>
— Sam Altman (@sama) <a href="https://twitter.com/sama/status/1839028518996324755?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 25, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Mira Murati, 35, played a major role in developing ChatGPT and overseeing releases of image generator Dall-E and AI code generator Codex. Her exit comes after her brief tenure as interim CEO following Mr Altman's ousting last November.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Sam Altman announced Mark Chen as senior VP of research and Josh Achiam as head of mission alignment to ensure a smooth transition.</p>

<p>Mira Murati's departure follows those of co-founders Greg Brockman (on extended leave) and John Schulman (joined rival Anthropic), as well as a product team leader and former Meta employee. Earlier this year, co-founder Ilya Sutskever exited OpenAI after a boardroom dispute. Ms Murati's exit now leaves only two of its 11 founders remaining.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The shakeup comes as OpenAI releases its new Strawberry AI model, designed to improve "thinking" in generative AI chatbots. The company aims to address "hallucinations" - persuasive but incorrect content - and provide more accurate responses.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-11/vmieto2g_mira-murati_625x300_18_November_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mira Murati described her time at OpenAI as "an extraordinary privilege". (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iwao-hakamada-japan-awaits-verdict-on-worlds-longest-serving-death-row-inmate-6652339]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Japan's Longest-serving Death Row Inmate Now A Free Man]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iwao-hakamada-japan-awaits-verdict-on-worlds-longest-serving-death-row-inmate-6652339]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 26 Sep 2024 10:59:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Japanese court on Thursday acquitted Iwao Hakamada, the world's longest-serving death row prisoner, closing a nearly six decades-long chapter.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Japanese court on Thursday acquitted Iwao Hakamada, the world's longest-serving death row prisoner, closing a nearly six decades-long chapter. After spending nearly half a century in solitary confinement, Hakamada was finally declared innocent of the 1968 murders that led to his conviction.</p>

<p>At 88, the former professional boxer was not present in the courtroom due to fragile health, but his 91-year-old sister, Hideko Hakamada, stood in his place, bowing deeply to the judge as the verdict was read. “The court finds the defendant innocent,” declared Judge Koshi Kunii at the Shizuoka District Court, as per AFP.</p>

<p>In 1968, Iwao Hakamada was convicted for the brutal murders of his boss, his boss's wife, and their two teenage children. The family was found stabbed to death in their home, which was subsequently set on fire. Hakamada, who worked at a soybean processing plant owned by the victim, confessed to the crime after 20 days of police interrogation, only to later retract his confession, saying it was forced through violence and intimidation.</p>

<p>Human rights activists have long decried Japan's so-called "hostage justice" system, where suspects are subjected to long periods of detention and aggressive questioning, often leading to forced confessions.</p>

<p>For nearly half a century, Iwao Hakamada lived in solitary confinement, waiting for the hangman's noose. Japan, unlike many industrialised nations, still retains the death penalty. Executions are carried out by hanging, and inmates are notified only hours before their execution.</p>

<p>Hakamada's lengthy detention took a significant toll on his mental health. According to his lawyers, he often appears disoriented, living in what they describe as a "world of fantasy."&nbsp;</p>

<p>His sister, Hideko Hakamada, who has campaigned tirelessly for his release, said her brother struggled to recognise reality. "We have not even discussed the trial with Iwao because of his inability to recognize reality," Ms Hideko, now 91, told AFP. "Sometimes he smiles happily, but that's when he's in his delusion."</p>

<p>Despite his mental state, Hakamada's brief taste of freedom over the past decade has provided some solace. According to Ms Hideko, small acts, such as taking care of two cats he adopted in February, have helped him reconnect with life outside prison walls. He also enjoys daily drives with his supporters, during which he indulges in his favourite pastries and juice.</p>

<p>Supporters of Hakamada gathered outside the court on Thursday with many holding banners and flags demanding his acquittal.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"For so long, we have fought a battle that has felt endless," Hideko Hakamada said during a press conference earlier this year. "But this time, I believe it will be settled."&nbsp;</p>

<p>Iwao Hakamada's legal team, led by Hideyo Ogawa, is hopeful that the court will deliver a not-guilty verdict, bringing an end to this decades-long ordeal. "We told prosecutors that the onus is on them to put an end to this 58-year-old case," Mr Ogawa told reporters. However, prosecutors remain adamant that the initial conviction was just and that Hakamada should face the death penalty.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/creglmio_iwao-hakamada_625x300_22_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Iwao Hakamada worked at a soybean processing plant owned by the victim.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/worlds-first-ai-powered-vertical-berry-farm-opens-in-us-produces-4-million-pounds-annually-6652404]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[World First Indoor Vertical Farm In US Produces 4 Million Pounds Berries]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/worlds-first-ai-powered-vertical-berry-farm-opens-in-us-produces-4-million-pounds-annually-6652404]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 26 Sep 2024 10:54:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Plenty Richmond Farm is engineered to produce over four million pounds (1.8 million kg) of strawberries annually.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An innovative new agricultural project has started in Richmond, Virginia, United States, representing an impressive step forward in sustainable food production. The Plenty Richmond Farm is the world's first indoor, vertically farmed berries facility at a scale where they are harvested and preserved.</p>

<p>This new technique, backed by a worldwide team of scientists, which promises to make it possible to produce ample food supplies without badly impacting the environment. The farm-based approach uses towering structures in controlled conditions to grow strawberries, dramatically less land compared with traditional agriculture.</p>

<p>The strawberries, developed in collaboration with the multinational corporation Driscoll's, are anticipated to hit grocery store shelves in early 2025. This invention marks a significant expansion of vertical farming capabilities, which have previously been centred on leafy greens such as lettuce.</p>

<p>"With agriculture serving as the Commonwealth's largest private sector industry, Plenty choosing Virginia for the world's first farm to grow indoor, vertically farmed berries at scale reinforces Virginia's leading role in the controlled environment agriculture industry," <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/plenty-opens-worlds-first-farm-to-grow-indoor-vertically-farmed-berries-at-scale-302255372.html">said Governor Glenn Youngkin.</a> "Plenty's farm will boost local agriculture production and drive economic development, all while diversifying against risks and protecting the environment. We look forward to supporting their innovative approaches to revolutionizing the industry, and know that Plenty's success will be Virginia's success."&nbsp;</p>

<p>By managing temperature, light, and humidity, the farm can improve plant growth and pollination, resulting in more consistent and high-quality product. This fresh approach is projected to reduce waste while increasing overall efficiency in the agriculture industry.</p>

<p>"This farm is a model for the positive impact climate-agnostic agriculture can have, and proof that vertical farming can deliver the crop diversity, scaled and local production needed to future-proof the global food system," <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/plenty-opens-worlds-first-farm-to-grow-indoor-vertically-farmed-berries-at-scale-302255372.html">said Arama Kukutai</a>, Plenty CEO. "The Plenty Richmond Farm is the culmination of 200 research trials over the past six years to perfect growing strawberries with consistent peak-season flavor indoors year-round. Driscoll's sets an incredibly high bar for the quality of its berries and we're excited to join forces to consistently deliver an ultra-premium Driscoll's strawberry year-round."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/avuq0lso_berry_625x300_26_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[This innovative farm aims to address global food demands.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mira-murati-chatgpt-a-new-exit-in-openais-growing-list-of-high-level-departures-6652199]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[A New Exit In OpenAI's Growing List Of High-Level Departures]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mira-murati-chatgpt-a-new-exit-in-openais-growing-list-of-high-level-departures-6652199]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 26 Sep 2024 10:19:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[OpenAI chief technology officer Mira Murati on Wednesday said she is leaving the company behind ChatGPT.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>OpenAI chief technology officer Mira Murati on Wednesday said she is leaving the company behind ChatGPT, adding to a growing list of high-level departures. Murati called her more than six years at the San Francisco-based company "an extraordinary privilege" and described her decision to leave as difficult in a post on X, formerly Twitter.</p>

<p>"There's never an ideal time to walk away from a place one cherishes, but the moment feels right," Murati said in the post.</p>

<p>"I want to create the time and space to do my own exploration."</p>

<p>OpenAI chief Sam Altman replied to Murati's post with his thanks for what Murati has helped the company build, and promised details on a transition plan soon.</p>

<p>Murati is the latest influential member of the OpenAI team to step away from their position.</p>

<p>Co-founder Greg Brockman is on an extended leave of absence and fellow OpenAI founder John Schulman left for AI sector rival Anthropic, according to a report in The Information.</p>

<p>A product team leader who OpenAI had lured over from Meta also left, the report said.</p>

<p>OpenAI co-founder Ilya Sutskever exited OpenAI early this year in the wake of a boardroom battle that saw Altman temporarily ousted from the company.</p>

<p>OpenAI earlier this month released a new series of artificial intelligence models designed to spend more time thinking -- in hopes that generative AI chatbots provide more accurate and beneficial responses.</p>

<p>The new model, nicknamed Strawberry, is designed to tackle complex tasks and solve more challenging problems in science, coding and mathematics -- something that earlier models have been criticized for failing to provide consistently.</p>

<p>Unlike their predecessors, these models have been trained to refine their thinking processes, try different methods and recognize mistakes before they deploy a final answer.</p>

<p>OpenAI's push to improve "thinking" in its model is a response to the persistent problem of "hallucinations" in AI chatbots.</p>

<p>This refers to their tendency to generate persuasive but incorrect content that has somewhat cooled the excitement over ChatGPT-style AI features among business customers.</p>

<p>The new release came as OpenAI was raising funds that could see it valued around $150 billion, which would make it one of the world's most valuable private companies, according to US media.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-11/jfsu8bjo_mira-murati_625x300_18_November_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Murati is the latest influential member of the OpenAI team to step away]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/meghan-markles-ex-staff-call-her-a-demon-boss-with-psycho-moments-6652193]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Meghan Markle's Ex-Staff Call Her A "Demon Boss" With "Psycho Moments"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/meghan-markles-ex-staff-call-her-a-demon-boss-with-psycho-moments-6652193]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 26 Sep 2024 10:16:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former staffers alleged that the 42-year-old royal mistreated employees and often made them feel "like s**t."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Following accusations labelling her as "just terrible," "a dictator," and "absolutely relentless," Meghan Markle is now facing fresh claims regarding her conduct as a boss. In a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.thedailybeast.com/former-employees-of-demon-meghan-markle-share-their-truth-on-her-psycho-moments" rel="nofollow, noindex"><em>Daily Beast </em></a>report, a former staff member described the Duchess of Sussex as a "demon" prone to "psycho moments." Former staffers alleged that the 42-year-old royal mistreated employees and often made them feel "like s**t."</p>

<p>One ex-staffer, who claimed to have worked for Meghan and Prince Harry during their time at the palace, was particularly critical.</p>

<p>"There were definitely bad, even psycho moments," the source told the Daily Beast. "I saw people being berated in person and over the phone, made to feel like s-t."</p>

<p>The source admitted it was a stressful period and gave the royal the benefit of the doubt, referencing her admission of suicidal thoughts.</p>

<p>Another source, who reportedly worked with Meghan leading up to her 2018 wedding, labelled her a "narcissist."</p>

<p>"I always thought she was a classic narcissist, and getting her staff to praise her in magazines only confirmed it," the insider said, adding, "She's lovely when things go her way but a demon when they don't."</p>

<p>A different insider alleged a florist was "screamed at" for over half an hour for posting a minor detail about a bouquet online.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"They vowed never to work with her again, despite the prestige," the insider noted, claiming staff were often treated "like tradesmen who could be treated like s-t."</p>

<p>While The Daily Beast's report paints Markle in a negative light, Us Weekly released a more favourable account, featuring positive remarks from Ben Browning, who worked on Meghan and Harry's 2022 Netflix documentary, and former chief of staff Catherine St-Laurent, both describing their time with the couple as meaningful and supportive.</p>

<p>However, the Hollywood Reporter presented a contrasting narrative, with sources accusing Markle of belittling her staff and acting as a "dictator in high heels." One source claimed to have witnessed her reduce "grown men to tears."</p>

<p>Throughout the years, Markle and Prince Harry have faced a high turnover of staff. In 2018, Buckingham Palace investigated claims of Meghan's bullying behavior, but the findings were never made public, with Markle dismissing the allegations as part of a "calculated smear campaign."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-07/fv3rifoc_meghan-markle_625x300_01_July_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The source admitted it was a stressful period]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hindu-college-expresses-pride-in-its-alumna-harini-amarasuriya-becoming-sri-lankas-pm-6652128]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hindu College Expresses Pride In Its Alumna Harini Amarasuriya Becoming Sri Lanka's PM]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hindu-college-expresses-pride-in-its-alumna-harini-amarasuriya-becoming-sri-lankas-pm-6652128]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 26 Sep 2024 10:12:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Hindu College in Delhi has expressed its "immense pride" in its alumna, Harini Amarasuriya, becoming the 16th Prime Minister of Sri Lanka.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Hindu College in Delhi has expressed its "immense pride" in its alumna, Harini Amarasuriya, becoming the 16th Prime Minister of Sri Lanka.</p>

<p>"Hindu College proudly celebrates the remarkable achievement of its alumna, Dr. Harini Amarasuriya, who has made history by becoming the 16th Prime Minister of the Democratic Socialist Republic of Sri Lanka and the third woman to hold this prestigious office. Dr. Harini's journey from the classrooms of Hindu College to the highest office in her country is a moment of immense pride for her alma mater," the college said in a statement.</p>

<p>Amarasuriya of the National People's Power (NPP) party is an academic, rights activist, and university lecturer and is known for her work in education and social justice. Her appointment marks a significant milestone in Sri Lankan politics.</p>

<p>Reflecting on this extraordinary milestone, Hindu College's principal, Prof. Anju Srivastava, shared, "Dr. Harini Amarasuriya was a student of the Sociology Department during her academic years at Hindu College from 1991 to 1994. We are incredibly proud of her success and her rise to such a significant leadership role. We are sure that her time at Hindu College played a part in shaping her path to becoming a transformative leader."</p>

<p>Hindu College has long fostered leadership skills through its unique student-led parliamentary system, where students elect a prime minister and leader of the opposition each year.</p>

<p>"This system broadens students' horizons and helps cultivate the leaders of tomorrow. Dr. Harini Amarasuriya is a shining example of how this experience can inspire and empower students to make a lasting impact on society and their nation," Srivastava said .</p>

<p>"We are confident that Dr. Harini Amarasuriya's leadership, vision, and unwavering commitment to public service will serve as a beacon of hope for Sri Lanka, guiding the nation towards greater progress and prosperity," she added.</p>

<p>Amarasuriya becomes Sri Lanka's third woman Prime Minister after Sirimavo Bandaranaike and Chandrika Bandaranaike Kumaratunga. The new Sri Lankan PM is the first academic-turned-politician to assume office. Harini Amarasuriya entered Parliament through the NPP national list in 2020.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/sbpg753o_harini-amarasuriya-reuters_625x300_26_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Harini Amarasuriya entered Parliament through the NPP national list in 2020.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/celebrities-like-julianne-moore-james-mcavoy-and-tom-brady-duped-by-goodbye-meta-ai-scam-6651958]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA['Goodbye Meta AI' Scam Dupes Thousands, Including Hollywood Stars]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/celebrities-like-julianne-moore-james-mcavoy-and-tom-brady-duped-by-goodbye-meta-ai-scam-6651958]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 26 Sep 2024 09:30:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Julianne Moore, Sarah Paulson, and James McAvoy are among the celebrities who have shared the post so far, which first gained traction earlier this month.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In early September, a viral message spread throughout social networking sites like Threads, Facebook, and Instagram, claiming to prevent Meta from freely accessing users' personal information. The tweet, which was apparently shared by over 600,000 people, including several well-known celebrities, began with the phrase, "Goodbye Meta AI."</p>

<p>According to<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cj4d5jjqg2qo"><em> the BBC</em></a>, film stars Julianne Moore, James McAvoy, and Ashley Tisdale, as well as former NFL player Tom Brady, are among those who re-shared the fake "Goodbye Meta AI" message on Instagram stories.</p>

<p>The message reads, "Goodbye Meta AI. Please note an attorney has advised us to put this on; failure to do so may result in legal consequences. As Meta is now a public entity, all members must post a similar statement."</p>

<p>"If you do not post at least once, it will be assumed you are okay with them using your information and photos. I do not give Meta or anyone else permission to use any of my personal data, profile information, or photos."</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/a2hfnlhg_julianne-moore_625x300_26_September_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: Instagram/Julianne Moore</span></p>
</div>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cj4d5jjqg2qo"><em>the BBC</em></a>, many of these messages have now been labelled "false information" by Lead Stories, one of Meta's third-party fact-checking sites.</p>

<p>The post appears to have been created in opposition to Meta's announcement in June that it will use public posts to train its AI model, but the company has confirmed to the BBC that posting the message has no impact on any user's privacy settings.</p>

<p>"Does posting a statement ensure that users of Meta services will not have their data used in Meta's artificial intelligence training? No, that's not true: Posting the viral statement, or any other statement, doesn't mean that Meta will not use that data for AI training, but users in Europe can object via a form in their account settings," Lead Stories, aka Facebook's fact-checking partner since 2019, said on its <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://leadstories.com/hoax-alert/2024/09/fact-check-legal-statement-does-not-protect-user-data-from-metas-generative-ai-its-made-up.html">official website.</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/mtpaveuo_instagramjames-mcavoy_625x300_26_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Posting an exemption from AI training wont prevent Meta from using your personal data.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jhumpa-lahiri-declines-award-over-new-york-noguchi-museums-keffiyeh-ban-6651940]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Author Jhumpa Lahiri Declines Award Over New York Museum's Keffiyeh Ban]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jhumpa-lahiri-declines-award-over-new-york-noguchi-museums-keffiyeh-ban-6651940]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 26 Sep 2024 09:26:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Pulitzer Prize winning author Jhumpa Lahiri declined to accept an award from New York City's Noguchi Museum after it fired three employees for wearing keffiyeh head scarves, an emblem of Palestinian solidarity, following an updated dress code.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pulitzer Prize winning author Jhumpa Lahiri declined to accept an award from New York City's Noguchi Museum after it fired three employees for wearing keffiyeh head scarves, an emblem of Palestinian solidarity, following an updated dress code.</p>

<p>"Jhumpa Lahiri has chosen to withdraw her acceptance of the 2024 Isamu Noguchi Award in response to our updated dress code policy," the museum said in a statement on Wednesday.</p>

<p>"We respect her perspective and understand that this policy may or may not align with everyone's views." Lahiri received the Pulitzer Prize in 2000 for her book "Interpreter of Maladies."</p>

<p>Across the world, protesters demanding an end to Israel's war in Gaza have worn the black-and-white keffiyeh head scarf, a symbol of Palestinian self-determination.</p>

<p>Anti-apartheid South African leader Nelson Mandela was also seen wearing the scarf on many occasions.</p>

<p>Israel's supporters, on the other hand, say it signals backing extremism.</p>

<p>In November, three students of Palestinian descent in Vermont were shot in an attack. Two were wearing the keffiyeh.</p>

<p>Israel's ongoing assault on Gaza has killed tens of thousands and displaced nearly everyone there. It followed a deadly attack by Palestinian Hamas militants on Israel on Oct. 7.</p>

<p>Last month, the art museum - founded by Japanese American sculptor Isamu Noguchi - announced a policy prohibiting employees from wearing anything that expressed "political messages, slogans or symbols." Three employees were sacked.</p>

<p>Other people in the United States have also lost their jobs due to their stance on the Israel-Gaza war.</p>

<p>A New York City hospital fired a Palestinian American nurse in May after she called Israel's actions in Gaza a "genocide" during an acceptance speech for an award. Israel denies genocide charges brought by South Africa at the World Court.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/aq30m0ro_jhumpa-lahiri_625x300_26_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[File photo]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/swiss-police-make-arrests-after-suicide-capsule-is-used-for-first-time-6651845]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[4 Arrested After 'Suicide Pod' Is Used For First Time In Switzerland]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/swiss-police-make-arrests-after-suicide-capsule-is-used-for-first-time-6651845]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 26 Sep 2024 09:05:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Swiss police have arrested several people after a controversial futuristic-looking capsule designed to allow its occupant to commit suicide was used for the first time, authorities said on Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Swiss police have arrested several people after a controversial futuristic-looking capsule designed to allow its occupant to commit suicide was used for the first time, authorities said on Tuesday.</p>

<p>Police in the northern canton of Schaffhausen bordering Germany said the so-called "Sarco" capsule <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-woman-64-dies-in-controversial-suicide-capsule-in-switzerland-6641812">had been deployed</a> in a wood in the municipality of Merishausen on Monday.</p>

<p>Prosecutors in Schaffhausen have opened criminal proceedings against several people for "inducing and aiding and abetting suicide", a police statement said, adding several people were detained, without giving details about them or the deceased.</p>

<p>A spokesperson for the group behind the capsule, The Last Resort, said the deceased was a 64-year-old American woman who had been suffering from a severely compromised immune system.</p>

<p>Florian Willet, co-president of The Last Resort, was among the four detainees, along with a Dutch journalist and two Swiss people, the spokesperson said. Willet was the only other person present when the woman ended her life, the spokesperson said.</p>

<p>In a statement issued by The Last Resort, Willet had described the death as "peaceful, fast and dignified."</p>

<p>The Last Resort spokesperson said the woman had passed psychiatric evaluations prior to ending her life.</p>

<p>A spokesperson for prosecutors in Schaffhausen declined to give details or confirm there were four detainees.</p>

<p>Cast along sleek, aerodynamic lines, the "Sarco" causes death when its occupant releases nitrogen gas inside, lowering the amount of oxygen to lethal levels. It is the brainchild of Philip Nitschke, an Australian physician famous for his work on assisted suicide since the 1990s.</p>

<p>Switzerland has been a magnet for advocates of assisted suicide due to laws that make it legal there, and The Last Resort says its legal advice was that it could be deployed.</p>

<p>The capsule has generated considerable media attention and discussion among authorities on whether they would allow it.</p>

<p>Elisabeth Baume-Schneider, the Swiss minister responsible for health, said on Monday that the capsule does not meet the requirements of product safety law, and that its use of nitrogen is not legally compliant.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p><p><div class='table-div suicide'><table class='table'><thead><tr><th colspan='2'>Helplines</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>Vandrevala Foundation for Mental Health</td><td><a href='tel:+919999666555'>9999666555</a> or <a href='mailto:help@vandrevalafoundation.com'>help@vandrevalafoundation.com</a> </td></tr><tr><td>TISS iCall</td><td><a href='tel:+912225521111'>022-25521111</a> (Monday-Saturday: 8 am to 10 pm)</td></tr> <tr><td colspan='2'>(If you need support or know someone who does, please reach out to your nearest mental health specialist.)</td></tr></tbody></table></div></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ps1g567o_sarco-suicide-capsule-afp-_625x300_18_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The portable human-sized pod has raised a host of legal and ethical questions in Switzerland (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/watch-nasa-astronaut-tracy-dyson-returns-to-earth-after-78-million-mile-journey-in-space-6651844]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[NASA Astronaut Returns To Earth After 78 Million Miles Journey In Space]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/watch-nasa-astronaut-tracy-dyson-returns-to-earth-after-78-million-mile-journey-in-space-6651844]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 26 Sep 2024 09:02:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Tracy Dyson spent 184 days in space, completing 2,944 orbits around Earth.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>NASA astronaut Tracy Dyson safely returned to Earth in Kazakhstan on Monday, September 23, after travelling 78 million miles in space aboard a Soyuz capsule. Alongside her were Russian cosmonauts Oleg Kononenko and Nikolai Chub, who also landed after spending 374 days on the International Space Station (ISS), marking the longest continuous stay at the station.</p>

<p>Dyson spent 184 days in space, completing 2,944 orbits around Earth. There are still eight astronauts aboard the ISS, including Americans Butch Wilmore and Suni Williams, whose return to Earth has been delayed.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">After 184 days in space, 2,944 orbits of the Earth, 78 million miles traveled, and a safe landing, astronaut Tracy Dyson's mission concludes. <a href="https://t.co/csgJcgSTSZ">pic.twitter.com/csgJcgSTSZ</a></p>
— NASA (@NASA) <a href="https://twitter.com/NASA/status/1838187655114145822?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 23, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p><em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.nasa.gov/news-release/nasa-astronaut-tracy-c-dyson-crewmates-return-from-space-station/" rel="nofollow, noindex">NASA </a></em>reported that the trio departed the ISS aboard the Soyuz MS-25 spacecraft at 4:36 a.m. EDT on Monday, September 23, and made a safe, parachute-assisted landing at 7:59 a.m. (4:59 p.m. Kazakhstan time) southeast of Dzhezkazgan, Kazakhstan.</p>

<p>During her time aboard the ISS, Dyson participated in various scientific and technological activities. Notably, she operated a 3D bioprinter to print cardiac tissue samples, which could pave the way for advancements in creating replacement organs and tissues for transplants. She also worked on crystallizing model proteins to test hardware for potential pharmaceutical applications and oversaw a program where student-designed software controlled the station's free-flying robots, inspiring future innovators.</p>

<p>Dyson had launched on March 23 and arrived at the station two days later with Roscosmos cosmonaut Oleg Novitskiy and spaceflight participant Marina Vasilevskaya from Belarus. Novitskiy and Vasilevskaya stayed on the station for 12 days before returning to Earth on April 6 with NASA astronaut Loral O'Hara.</p>

<p>In total, Dyson's third spaceflight lasted 184 days, during which she orbited the Earth 2,944 times and travelled 78 million miles as part of the Expedition 70/71 mission. She also conducted one spacewalk, lasting 31 minutes, bringing her total spacewalk time to 23 hours and 20 minutes across four spacewalks.</p>

<p>Kononenko and Chub, who launched with O'Hara on the Soyuz MS-24 spacecraft last September, spent 374 days in space, travelling 158.6 million miles over 5,984 orbits. Kononenko, on his fifth spaceflight, has now spent a record 1,111 days in orbit, while Chub completed his first spaceflight.</p>

<p>After post-landing medical checks, the crew will return to Karaganda, Kazakhstan, before Dyson boards a NASA plane bound for the Johnson Space Center in Houston.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/87hv9id8_tracy-dyson_625x300_26_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Dyson participated in various scientific and technological activities]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-secret-service-agent-probed-over-sexual-misconduct-involving-kamala-harris-staffer-6651057]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Secret Service Agent Probed Over "Sexual Misconduct" Involving Harris Staffer]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-secret-service-agent-probed-over-sexual-misconduct-involving-kamala-harris-staffer-6651057]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 26 Sep 2024 08:47:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Secret Service is investigating one of its agents after an incident involving someone in Democratic Vice President Kamala Harris' office, her office said in a statement on Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Secret Service is investigating one of its agents after an incident involving someone in Democratic Vice President Kamala Harris' office, her office said in a statement on Wednesday.</p>

<p>A US Secret Service (USSS) spokesperson said separately that the employee was placed on administrative leave pending the outcome of the investigation into "a misconduct allegation involving an employee," without providing further details.</p>

<p>Harris' office has "zero tolerance for sexual misconduct," its statement said. Senior officials "were alerted by the USSS about an incident involving an agent and informed that USSS initiated an investigation," it read.</p>

<p>Neither the Secret Service agent nor the person in Harris' office were named in the statement by Harris' office. The office said it would not provide further information.</p>

<p>A Secret Service agent allegedly forced himself onto a Harris staffer in a hotel room in Wisconsin this week, Real Clear Politics reported, as the group scouted future campaign stops.</p>

<p>Harris faces Republican former President Donald Trump in what polls show to be a tight race for the Nov. 5 U.S. elections.</p>

<p>The Secret Service, which protects U.S. political leaders and their families, has been under scrutiny in recent weeks over the security of Trump, who survived an assassination attempt on July 13 during a rally in Pennsylvania.</p>

<p>The agency's former boss resigned in the aftermath and a probe found lack of diligence ahead of that shooting.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/hk2u230o_us-secret-service-agent-reuters_625x300_26_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A Secret Service agent allegedly forced himself onto a Harris staffer in a hotel room.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/baps-shri-swaminarayan-mandir-in-sacramento-temple-defaced-with-anti-hindu-grafitti-in-us-second-time-in-2-weeks-6651673]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Temple Defaced With Anti-Hindu Graffiti In US, Second Time In 8 Days]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/baps-shri-swaminarayan-mandir-in-sacramento-temple-defaced-with-anti-hindu-grafitti-in-us-second-time-in-2-weeks-6651673]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 26 Sep 2024 08:21:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The BAPS Shri Swaminarayan Mandir in California was on Wednesday desecrated with expletive-laden anti-Hindu messages, in the second such incident in the US in as many weeks.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The BAPS Shri Swaminarayan Mandir in California was on Wednesday desecrated with expletive-laden anti-Hindu messages, in the second such incident in the US in as many weeks. The BAPS Public Affairs said their temple in Sacramento was desecrated with a "Hindus go back!" message.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"We stand united against hate with prayers for peace," they said in a post on X.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Less than 10 days after the desecration of the <a href="https://twitter.com/BAPS?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@BAPS</a> Mandir in New York, our Mandir in the Sacramento, CA area was desecrated last night with anti-Hindu hate: “Hindus go back!” We stand united against hate with prayers for peace.</p>
— BAPS Public Affairs (@BAPS_PubAffairs) <a href="https://twitter.com/BAPS_PubAffairs/status/1838994965336031580?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 25, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The Sacramento Police said that they were investigating a "vandalism being classified as a hate crime" at the BAPS Hindu Temple in Mather.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Those who defaced the temple also cut water lines at the property, the police said.</p>

<p>"Detectives and CSI (Crime Scene Investigation) are on scene," they posted on X.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en"><a href="https://twitter.com/sacsheriff?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@sacsheriff</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/RanchoCordovaPD?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@RanchoCordovaPD</a> are investigating a vandalism being classified as a hate crime at the BAPS Hindu Temple in Mather. Detectives and CSI are on scene. <a href="https://t.co/0mAyfhu9JA">pic.twitter.com/0mAyfhu9JA</a></p>
— Sacramento Sheriff (@sacsheriff) <a href="https://twitter.com/sacsheriff/status/1839056639686750681?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 25, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Following the incident, Hindu community leaders gathered at the temple in Sacramento for a prayer ceremony calling for "peace and unity".</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Community leaders gathered for a heartfelt prayer ceremony at the <a href="https://twitter.com/BAPS?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@BAPS</a> Mandir in Sacramento, CA, following the desecration of the mandir. Inspired by Mahant Swami Maharaj, we remain dedicated to promoting harmony and standing against intolerance. Together we will defeat hate. <a href="https://t.co/LVBUAkCBnh">pic.twitter.com/LVBUAkCBnh</a></p>
— BAPS Public Affairs (@BAPS_PubAffairs) <a href="https://twitter.com/BAPS_PubAffairs/status/1839116146693308894?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 26, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Earlier on September 16, the road and the signage outside the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/heinous-act-indian-consulate-condemns-vandalism-of-baps-swaminarayan-temple-in-new-york-6580680" target="_blank">BAPS Swaminarayan Temple in Melville</a>, New York, were sprayed with expletives. Melville is located in Suffolk County and is about 28 km from the Nassau Veterans Memorial Coliseum, where Prime Minister Narendra Modi addressed a mega Indian community event on Sunday.</p>

<p>The Consulate General of India in New York had condemned the vandalism in Melville, labelling it "unacceptable" and a "heinous act".</p>

<h3><strong>"No Place For Religious Bigotry And Hatred"</strong></h3>

<p>Indian-American Congressman Ami Bera, who represents Sacramento County, reacted to the vandalism at the Hindu temple and said there is "no place for religious bigotry and hatred" in Sacramento.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"I strongly condemn this apparent act of vandalism in our community. All of us must stand against intolerance and ensure that everyone in our community, regardless of faith, feels safe and respected," he posted on X.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">There is no place for religious bigotry and hatred in <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/SacramentoCounty?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#SacramentoCounty</a>. I strongly condemn this apparent act of vandalism in our community.<br />
<br />
All of us must stand against intolerance and ensure that everyone in our community, regardless of faith, feels safe and respected. <a href="https://t.co/TRX3Q7XJ6t">https://t.co/TRX3Q7XJ6t</a></p>
— Ami Bera, M.D. (@RepBera) <a href="https://twitter.com/RepBera/status/1839018645953065148?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 25, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Ro Khanna, another Indian-American Congressman, said "this type of hate against Hindu Americans and vandalism is appalling and morally wrong".&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The Department of Justice must investigate these hate crimes, and those responsible should be held fully accountable under the law," Mr Khanna said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/24hvtodg_hindu-temple_625x300_26_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The BAPS Shri Swaminarayan Mandir in Sacramento]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/el-cosmico-pics-worlds-first-3d-printed-hotel-takes-shape-in-texas-6651507]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Pics: World's First 3D-Printed Hotel Takes Shape In Texas]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/el-cosmico-pics-worlds-first-3d-printed-hotel-takes-shape-in-texas-6651507]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 26 Sep 2024 07:38:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[El Cosmico, an existing hotel and campground on the outskirts of the city of Marfa, is building 43 new hotel units and 18 residential homes over 40 acres - all with a 3D printer.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It looks like any other 3D printer - except it's the size of a crane and is, layer by layer, building a hotel in the Texan desert. El Cosmico, an existing hotel and campground on the outskirts of the city of Marfa, is expanding. It is building 43 new hotel units and 18 residential homes over 40 acres (16 hectares) - all with a 3D printer.</p>

<p>It is the world's first 3D-printed hotel, says El Cosmico owner Liz Lambert and the partners behind the project - Austin, Texas-based 3D printing company ICON and architects Bjarke Ingels Group.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/gtui9hf8_worlds-first-3dprinted-hotel_625x300_26_September_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: REUTERS</span></p>
</div>

<p>Lambert said the technology allows for unprecedented creativity.</p>

<p>"Most hotels are contained within four walls and a lot of times you are building the same unit over and over and over again," Lambert said. "I've never been able to build with such little constraint and such fluidity ... just the curves, and the domes, and the parabolas. It's a crazy way to build."</p>

<p>The units can include architectural features that would normally be too expensive to replicate on a large scale with traditional construction, according to Lambert.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/8gvp2u4g_worlds-first-3dprinted-hotel_625x300_26_September_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: REUTERS</span></p>
</div>

<p>The single-story, 12-foot (3.7-meter) high walls of the first two units under construction are a three-bedroom residential space and a single-room hotel unit.</p>

<p>The curvy, beige-colored walls are being piped out by ICON's Vulcan, a 46.5-foot (14.2 m) wide 3D printer standing 15.5 feet (4.7 m) and weighing 4.75 tons.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/vep2n58_worlds-first-3dprinted-hotel_625x300_26_September_24.jpeg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: REUTERS</span></p>
</div>

<p>A print technician monitors Vulcan as its robotic arm and nozzle glide through the work site on a gantry.</p>

<p>The "ink" of this 3D printer is a special cement-based material called Lavacrete, a proprietary mixture designed for strength, affordable scale, and printability. ICON CEO and founder Jason Ballard said workers adjust and blend the ingredients based on weather conditions.</p>

<p>"The magic happens in the admixtures that allow us to continue printing," Ballard said, adding that humidity, temperature, and irradiance affect the material's behavior and even the final color.</p>

<p>ICON is also working on a 3D-printed neighborhood of homes near Austin.</p>

<p>In the long term, 3D-printed construction could displace some skilled laboring jobs, said Milad Bazli, a science and technology lecturer at Charles Darwin University in Australia.</p>

<p>"I think from the social point of view and the effect on the economy in terms of the local jobs, especially in remote areas, that will be one of the challenges that we need to consider when we're going to the 3D printing method," Bazli said.</p>

<p>The expansion of El Cosmico is set to be completed by 2026. The hotel units will range between $200 and $450 per night.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/usioa7fo_worlds-first-3dprinted-hotel_625x300_26_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The curvy, beige-colored walls are being piped out by 3D printing company ICON]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/eric-adams-new-york-mayor-indicted-following-corruption-probe-6651470]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[New York Mayor Eric Adams Indicted Following Corruption Probe]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/eric-adams-new-york-mayor-indicted-following-corruption-probe-6651470]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 26 Sep 2024 07:23:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[New York City Mayor Eric Adams has been indicted after a federal corruption investigation, but the indictment is sealed and it is unclear what charges he will face, the New York Times reported on Wednesday, citing people with knowledge of the matter.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>New York City Mayor Eric Adams has been indicted after a federal corruption investigation, but the indictment is sealed and it is unclear what charges he will face, the New York Times reported on Wednesday, citing people with knowledge of the matter. It was not immediately clear whether Adams would be arrested or voluntarily surrender. The charges are likely to be unsealed on Thursday, when Adams may appear in court.</p>

<p>The charges come after the FBI last November searched Adams' electronic devices, and in the wake of a slew of resignations by top city officials in recent weeks as multiple federal corruption investigations entangle his administration.</p>

<p>A spokesman for the U.S. Attorney's office in Manhattan, which brought the charges, declined to comment. Adams' lawyers did not immediately respond to a request for comment.</p>

<p>One of his lawyers has said that the mayor, a Democrat, was cooperating with an investigation but did not say what it was about.</p>

<p>The case is likely to complicate any Adams bid for re-election in 2025. Other Democratic politicians, including New York City comptroller Brad Lander, plan to challenge Adams - once a key ally of Democratic President Joe Biden - for the party's nomination.</p>

<p>The Times, citing a search warrant, reported in early November 2023 that federal authorities were investigating the possible acceptance by Adams' 2021 campaign of illegal donations, including by the Turkish government.</p>

<p>The probe, conducted by the U.S. Attorney's office in Manhattan, focused on whether Adams' 2021 mayoral campaign conspired with a Brooklyn construction company to funnel foreign money into the campaign through a straw-donor scheme, the Times said.</p>

<p>Authorities have also sought information about Adams' interactions with Israel, China, Qatar, South Korea and Uzbekistan, according to the Times.</p>

<p>Adams, a former police officer, has repeatedly denied wrongdoing and said he is cooperating with the probe. His lawyers said in a statement on Aug. 15 that they had conducted their own investigation into the matters prosecutors were probing and had not found evidence of illegal conduct by Adams.</p>

<p>"To the contrary, we have identified extensive evidence undermining the reported theories of federal prosecution as to the Mayor, which we have voluntarily shared with the U.S. Attorney," said the lawyers, Brendan McGuire and Boyd Johnson.</p>

<p>The largest U.S. city has been in a state of political upheaval for the past month. Police Commissioner Edward Caban resigned on Sept. 12, a week after FBI agents seized his phone. Days later, Adams' chief legal adviser resigned, saying she could "no longer effectively serve" in the position.</p>

<p>On Wednesday, the city's public schools chancellor David Banks said he would retire at the end of the year, weeks after the Times reported his phones were seized by federal agents.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/cnrmira8_eric-adams_625x300_26_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[It was not immediately clear whether Adams would be arrested or voluntarily surrender]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hints-at-lebanon-hezbollah-ground-invasion-as-joe-biden-warns-of-all-out-war-in-middle-east-6651437]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Hints At Lebanon Ground Invasion As Joe Biden Warns Of "All Out War"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hints-at-lebanon-hezbollah-ground-invasion-as-joe-biden-warns-of-all-out-war-in-middle-east-6651437]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 26 Sep 2024 07:15:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel has told its soldiers to prepare for a possible ground operation against Iran-backed Hezbollah in Lebanon as US President Joe Biden warned against "all-out war" in the Middle East.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="CetSht_cn">
<ol class="CetSht_ol">
	<li class="CetSht_li">Israel's army chief, Lieutenant General Herzi Halevi, told a tank brigade that <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-army-chief-puts-troops-on-alert-for-possible-entry-into-lebanon-6648757#pfrom=home-ndtv_topstories" target="_blank">they are "attacking" Lebanon</a> to prepare the ground for the possibility of their entry into Lebanon, according to a statement on Wednesday,&nbsp;</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">The Israeli military said it hit more than 2,000 Hezbollah targets in Lebanon over the past three days.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu vowed that Israel's military operations against Hezbollah would not stop until northern residents displaced by cross-border clashes could safely return to their homes.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Israel's warnings came after <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-iran-backed-hezbollah-is-attacking-israel-despite-death-of-its-top-commanders-pager-attacks-in-lebanon-6645836" target="_blank">Hezbollah</a> said it had targeted Israel's Mossad spy agency headquarters on Tel Aviv's outskirts -- the first time it has fired a ballistic missile in almost a year of cross-border clashes sparked by the Gaza war.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Israel's close ally, the United States, said it did not think Israeli troops' ground operation in Lebanon is "imminent". "It doesn't look like something is imminent," Deputy Pentagon Press Secretary Sabrina Singh told reporters. US President <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-warns-all-out-war-possible-in-middle-east-6649493" target="_blank">Joe Biden</a>, however, warned of the possibility of "all-out war" in the Middle East. "An all-out war is possible," he told a news channel.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">The US, France, Germany, Saudi Arabia, Qatar, the United Arab Emirates, and some other partner nations called for an immediate 21-day ceasefire across the Israel-Lebanon border, according to a joint statement of the countries released late on Wednesday.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">UN Secretary-General Antonio Guterres urged an immediate ceasefire in Lebanon and warned, "Hell is breaking loose."</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Iran, Hezbollah's main backer, condemned Israel's raids and said the Middle East was facing a "full-scale catastrophe". It also warned that Tehran would back Lebanon by "all means" if Israel escalated its offensive.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li"><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/avoid-travel-to-lebanon-indian-embassy-urges-citizens-amid-violence-6650494" target="_blank">India issued an advisory</a> "strongly" urging Indians against travelling to Lebanon till further notice. The Indian Embassy in Beirut also advised the Indian nationals residing in Lebanon to leave the country and further advised the people to exercise "extreme caution".</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li"><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-israel-war-soon-32-killed-as-walkie-talkies-pagers-explode-across-lebanon-6598300" target="_blank">Israel and Hezbollah members have been fighting</a> across the Lebanese border after the war in Gaza erupted when Hamas, a Hezbollah ally also backed by Iran, attacked Israeli towns on October 7 last year.</li>
</ol>

<p></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/1qih95vg_israel-hezbollah_625x300_26_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel said it hit more than 2,000 Hezbollah targets in Lebanon over the past three days]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nuclear-bomb-can-deflect-life-threatening-asteroid-say-scientists-6651367]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[N-Bomb Can Deflect Life-Threatening Asteroid Hurtling Towards Earth In Future]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nuclear-bomb-can-deflect-life-threatening-asteroid-say-scientists-6651367]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 26 Sep 2024 06:56:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Humanity could use a nuclear bomb to deflect a massive, life-threatening asteroid hurtling towards Earth in the future, according to scientists who tested the theory in the laboratory by blasting X-rays at a marble-sized "mock asteroid".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Humanity could use a nuclear bomb to deflect a massive, life-threatening asteroid hurtling towards Earth in the future, according to scientists who tested the theory in the laboratory by blasting X-rays at a marble-sized "mock asteroid".</p>

<p>The biggest real-life test of our planetary defences was carried out in 2022, when NASA's fridge-sized DART spacecraft smashed into a 160-metre (525-feet) wide asteroid, successfully knocking it well off course.</p>

<p>But for bigger asteroids, merely crashing spaceships into them will probably not do the trick.</p>

<p>When the roughly 10-kilometre wide Chicxulub asteroid struck the Yucatan peninsula around 66 million years ago, it is believed to have plunged Earth into darkness, sent kilometres-high tsunamis rippling around the globe and killed three quarters of all life -- including wiping out the dinosaurs.</p>

<p>We humans are hoping to avoid a similar fate.</p>

<p>There is no current threat looming, but scientists have been working on how to stave off any big asteroids that could come our way in the future.</p>

<p>A leading theory has been to be blow them up with a nuclear bomb -- a last-ditch plan famously depicted in the 1998 sci-fi action movie "Armageddon".</p>

<p>In the movie, Bruce Willis and a plucky team of drillers save Earth from an asteroid 1,000 kilometres wide -- roughly the size of Texas.</p>

<p>For a proof-of-concept study published in the journal Nature Physics this week, a team of US scientists worked on a much smaller scale, taking aim at a mock asteroid just 12 millimetres (half an inch) wide.</p>

<p>To test whether the theory would work, they used what was billed as the world's largest X-ray machine at Sandia National Laboratories in Albuquerque, New Mexico.</p>

<p>The machine is capable of generating "the brightest flash of X-rays in the world using 80 trillion watts of electricity", Sandia's Nathan Moore, the lead study author, told AFP.</p>

<p>Much of the energy created by a nuclear explosion is in the form of X-rays. Since there is no air in space, there would be no shockwave or fireball.</p>

<p>But the X-rays still pack a powerful punch.</p>

<p><strong>- Turned into a 'rocket engine' -</strong></p>

<p>For the lab experiment, the X-rays easily vaporised the surface of the mock asteroid.</p>

<p>The vaporising material then propelled the mock asteroid in the opposite direction, so that it effectively "turned into a rocket engine," Moore said.</p>

<p>It reached speeds of 250 kilometres an hour, "about as fast as a high-speed train," he added.</p>

<p>The test marked the first time that predictions about how X-rays would affect an asteroid had been confirmed, Moore said.</p>

<p>"It really proves this concept could work."</p>

<p>The scientists used modelling to scale up their experiment, estimating that X-rays from a nuclear blast could deflect an asteroid up to four kilometres wide -- if given enough advanced notice.</p>

<p>The biggest asteroids are the easiest to detect ahead of time, so "this approach could be quite viable" even for asteroids the size of the dinosaur-killing Chicxulub, Moore said.</p>

<p>The experiment was based on using a one-megaton nuclear weapon. The largest ever detonated was the 50-megaton Soviet Tsar Bomba.</p>

<p>If there was to be a planet-saving mission in the future, the nuclear bomb would need to be placed within a few kilometres of the asteroid -- and millions of kilometres away from Earth, Moore said.</p>

<p>- Asteroids come in many flavours -</p>

<p>Testing out the theory using a real nuke would be dangerous, hugely expensive -- and banned by international treaties.</p>

<p>But there is still plenty to be discovered before such a high-risk test.</p>

<p>The largest uncertainty right now is that asteroids can "come in many flavours", Moore said.</p>

<p>"We have to be prepared for every scenario."</p>

<p>For example, the asteroid hit by DART, Dimorphos, turned out to be a loosely held-together pile of rubble.</p>

<p>The European Space Agency's Hera mission is scheduled to launch next month on a mission to find out more about its composition -- and the finer details about how DART sent it packing.</p>

<p>Mary Burkey, a staff scientist at California's Lawrence Livermore National Laboratory that was not involved in the new study, has run computer simulations about using nukes on asteroids.</p>

<p>She praised the study, saying that "being able to match my calculations to real-life data increases the credibility of my results."</p>

<p>Her simulations have also demonstrated that such a mission "would be a very effective means to defend planet Earth", Burkey told AFP.</p>

<p>"However, in order for it to work, there must be enough time after a mission for the extra push of velocity to move the asteroid's trajectory off Earth."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/2an1kn9_asteroid_625x300_19_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[According to scientists, there is no current threat that an asteroid could hit the Earth in near future.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-vows-to-destroy-iran-amid-death-threats-6651149]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Will "Blow Your Country To Smithereens": Trump To Iran Amid Death Threats]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-vows-to-destroy-iran-amid-death-threats-6651149]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 26 Sep 2024 05:44:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump said Wednesday Iran should be blown "to smithereens" if the Islamic Republic is involved in the harming of a US White House candidate or ex-president.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump said Wednesday Iran should be blown "to smithereens" if the Islamic Republic is involved in the harming of a US White House candidate or ex-president.</p>

<p>The provocative remarks come after US intelligence warned of threats from Tehran against the Republican's life after two apparent assassination bids in recent months.</p>

<p>"As you know, there have been two assassination attempts on my life that we know of, and they may or may not involve -- but possibly do -- Iran," Trump said at a campaign event in North Carolina.</p>

<p>"If I were the president, I would inform the threatening country, in this case Iran, that if you do anything to harm this person, we are going to blow your largest cities and the country itself to smithereens," he added.</p>

<p>Trump went on to say he and the United States have been "threatened very directly by Iran" and that a firm message needed to reach Tehran that there would be the most severe consequences should it be involved in plots to kill or hurt a US president or presidential candidate.</p>

<p>"The best way to do it is through the office of the president, that (if) you do any attacks on former presidents or candidates for president, your country gets blown to smithereens, as we say."</p>

<p>Trump also said it was "strange" that Iranian President Masoud Pezeshkian was in New York this week and accorded substantial protection as he attends the United Nations General Assembly even as news of the threats emerged.</p>

<p>"We have large security forces guarding him, and yet they're threatening our former president and the leading candidate to become the next president of the United States," Trump said, referring to himself.</p>

<p>The United States is obligated to extend security to foreign heads of state at the General Assembly under its treaty with the United Nations and its own laws.</p>

<p><strong>- 'Credible intelligence' -</strong></p>

<p>Trump's remarks come as world leaders scramble to try to avert hostilities between Iran-backed Hezbollah and Israel escalating into a wider regional war.</p>

<p>Iran has rejected accusations it is trying to kill Trump this summer, shortly after a gunman opened fire at a rally in Pennsylvania on July 13, killing one person and wounding the presidential candidate.</p>

<p>Days later, Trump posted on social media that if Iran did kill him, "I hope that America obliterates Iran, wipes it off the face of the Earth."</p>

<p>In a highly critical report on the security arrangements around Trump at the Pennsylvania rally, a US Senate committee noted that the deployment of elite US Secret Service countersnipers was made "in response to 'credible intelligence' of a threat."</p>

<p>On Wednesday, the 78-year-old Trump suggested the would-be assassin in Pennsylvania had used "potentially foreign-based apps," and that the alleged gunman in the second attempt in Florida had multiple mobile phones that Trump said US authorities have been unable to open.</p>

<p>"They must get Apple to open these foreign apps (and) open the six phones from the second lunatic," Trump said. "Because we have a lot at stake."</p>

<p>On Wednesday, US Attorney General Merrick Garland called the attempted assassination bids "abhorrent."</p>

<p>"Our nation has now experienced two assassination attempts against the former President in just the last three months. That is abhorrent," he said.</p>

<p>"The Justice Department will not tolerate violence that strikes at the heart of our democracy. And we will find and hold accountable those who perpetrate it. This must stop."</p>

<p>In August, the United States announced that it had foiled a plan by a Pakistani linked to Tehran to assassinate a US official in revenge for the death of Iranian general Qassem Soleimani, killed in 2020 in a US strike in Iraq ordered by then-president Trump.</p>

<p>US intelligence services have also warned of attempted cyberattacks on the presidential campaigns of Trump and rival Kamala Harris by actors it says are backed by Iran.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/11vtqnj8_donald-trump_625x300_25_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Trump's remarks come as world leaders scramble to try to avert hostilities between Hezbollah and Israel.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/imf-approves-7-billion-loan-to-support-pakistans-economy-6651027]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[IMF Approves $7 Billion Loan To Support Pakistan's Economy]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/imf-approves-7-billion-loan-to-support-pakistans-economy-6651027]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 26 Sep 2024 05:05:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The board of the International Monetary Fund on Wednesday agreed to loan Pakistan $7 billion to bolster its faltering economy, approving a relief package that Islamabad has pledged would be the last from the Washington-based lender.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The board of the International Monetary Fund on Wednesday agreed to loan Pakistan $7 billion to bolster its faltering economy, approving a relief package that Islamabad has pledged would be the last from the Washington-based lender.</p>

<p>The three-year loan program "will require sound policies and reforms" to support Pakistan's ongoing efforts to strengthen its economy "and create conditions for a stronger, more inclusive, and resilient growth," the IMF said in a statement.</p>

<p>The South Asian nation in July agreed to the deal -- its 24th IMF payout since 1958 -- in exchange for unpopular reforms, including widening its chronically low tax base.</p>

<p>Pakistan last year came to the brink of default as the economy shriveled amid political chaos following catastrophic 2022 monsoon floods and decades of mismanagement, as well as a global economic downturn.</p>

<p>It was saved by last-minute loans from friendly countries as well as an IMF rescue package, but its finances remain in dire straits, with high inflation and staggering public debts.</p>

<p>"This program should be considered the last program," Prime Minister Shehbaz Sharif said in July when the loan deal was agreed.</p>

<p>Islamabad wrangled for months with IMF officials to unlock the new loan.</p>

<p>It came on the condition of far-reaching reforms including hiking household bills to remedy a permanently crisis-stricken energy sector and uplifting pitiful tax takings.</p>

<p>In a nation of over 240 million people where most jobs are in the informal sector, only 5.2 million filed income tax returns in 2022.</p>

<p>The IMF said Pakistan "has taken key steps to restoring economic stability with consistent reforms." But "despite this progress, Pakistan's vulnerabilities and structural challenges remain formidable," it warned.</p>

<p>"A difficult business environment, weak governance, and an outsized role of the state hinder investment, which remains very low compared to peers," it added.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-06/1v07o9a_imf_625x300_30_June_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The IMF stated that 3-year loan program will require sound policies and reforms to support Pak's economy.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-announces-375-million-aid-package-for-ukraine-6650848]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Announces $375 Million Aid Package For Ukraine]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-announces-375-million-aid-package-for-ukraine-6650848]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 26 Sep 2024 04:05:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US Secretary of State Antony Blinken announced $375 million in military aid for Ukraine on Wednesday, in a package that includes munitions for HIMARS precision rocket launchers, cluster munitions and light tactical vehicles.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US Secretary of State Antony Blinken announced $375 million in military aid for Ukraine on Wednesday, in a package that includes munitions for HIMARS precision rocket launchers, cluster munitions and light tactical vehicles.</p>

<p>"The United States is committed to Ukraine's defense against Russia's brutal aggression," Blinken said in a statement, adding that Washington would "deploy this new assistance as quickly as possible."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-01/ds79oupo_antony-blinken-afp_625x300_08_January_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US Secretary of State Antony Blinken announced $375 million in military aid for Ukraine on Wednesday.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/social-media-platform-x-to-request-service-restoration-in-brazil-amid-row-6650788]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Social Media Platform X To Request Service Restoration In Brazil Amid Row]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/social-media-platform-x-to-request-service-restoration-in-brazil-amid-row-6650788]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 26 Sep 2024 03:48:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Elon Musk's social media platform X will file documents requested by Brazil's Supreme Court and ask by this Monday that service be restored in the country, according to two people familiar with the situation.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;Elon Musk's social media platform X will file documents requested by Brazil's Supreme Court and ask by this Monday that service be restored in the country, according to two people familiar with the situation.</p>

<p>Access to the platform formerly known as Twitter has been blocked in Brazil since the end of August, following an order by Supreme Court Justice Alexandre de Moraes. The judge and the U.S. tech firm have been at loggerheads over his investigation of "digital militias" he has accused of spreading hate messages in Brazil.</p>

<p>The dispute led X to close its offices in the country and let go of employees including its legal agent, breaching a local law.</p>

<p>The platform may again be available to Brazilians as early as next week after X provides documents requested by the court proving it now has a legal representative in the country, said the sources familiar with X's plans.</p>

<p>X and the Brazilian Supreme Court did not immediately respond to requests for comment.</p>

<p>Last week, X lawyers said the company had appointed a legal representative in Brazil, as ordered by the Supreme Court, but it did not initially provide documents to prove the appointee was formally able to respond for the company. Once the new set of documents have been sent, the firm expects the issue to be resolved, according to the sources.</p>

<p>The sources said X has also started to comply with the court's other demands - blocking profiles of people allegedly spreading fake news and paying a 18 million reais ($3 million) fine via accounts of Musk's Starlink.</p>

<p>The social media firm is keen to smooth over the relationship with Moraes and operate like any other tech company in the country, said one of the sources.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/mafbd1e4_x-twitter_625x300_30_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[X and the Brazilian Supreme Court did not immediately respond to requests for comment.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>