<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Nov 2024 20:53:34 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/international-court-to-begin-hearings-that-may-shape-global-climate-litigation-7135670]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[World Court To Begin Hearings That May Shape Global Climate Litigation]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/international-court-to-begin-hearings-that-may-shape-global-climate-litigation-7135670]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Nov 2024 20:40:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United Nations' top court next week begins hearings on the legal obligation of countries to fight climate change and the consequences for states of contributing to global warming, the outcome of which could influence litigation worldwide.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United Nations' top court next week begins hearings on the legal obligation of countries to fight climate change and the consequences for states of contributing to global warming, the outcome of which could influence litigation worldwide.</p>

<p>While the advisory opinions of the International Court of Justice's (ICJ) are non-binding, they are legally and politically significant. Experts say the ICJ's eventual opinion on climate change will likely be cited in climate change-driven lawsuits in courts from Europe to Latin America and beyond.</p>

<p>The hearings begin a week after developing nations denounced as woefully inadequate an agreement reached at the COP29 summit for countries to provide $300 billion in annual climate finance by 2035 to help poorer nations cope with climate change.</p>

<p>Ralph Regenvanu, Vanuatu's special envoy for climate change and the environment, said it was imperative fossil fuels be phased out and more money provided to poorer nations bearing the brunt of climate change, such as his Pacific island nation.</p>

<p>"We're not seeing that in the outcome of the COPs," Regenvanu told Reuters.</p>

<p>"We are hoping (the ICJ) can provide a new avenue to break through the inertia we experience when trying to talk about climate justice," he added.</p>

<p>Fiji's Attorney General Graham Leung called the hearings an historic opportunity for small island developing states in their quest for climate change justice.</p>

<h2><strong>CLIMATE LITIGATION</strong></h2>

<p>Climate litigation is on the rise.</p>

<p>Earlier this year, Europe's top human rights court ruled that the Swiss government had violated the rights of its citizens by failing to do enough to combat climate change. But it also rejected two other cases, pointing to the complexities of the growing wave of climate litigation.</p>

<p>Vanuatu, one of the small developing nations that pushed for an ICJ advisory opinion, says it disproportionately suffers the effects of climate change as a result of increasingly intense storms and rising sea levels.</p>

<p>Vanuatu will be the first of 98 countries and twelve international organisations to present arguments to the ICJ, also known as the World Court. It is the United Nations' highest court for resolving international disputes between states and can be tasked by the U.N. General Assembly to give advisory opinions.</p>

<p>In 2023, the assembly asked it for a formal opinion on questions including the legal obligations of states to protect the climate system and whether large states that contribute to greenhouse gas emissions may be liable for damages, in particular to small island nations.</p>

<p>"As COP29 failed to provide a clear direction for climate justice and ambition, any developments from the ICJ will now only become more weighty," said Lea Main-Klingst, a lawyer with ClientEarth.</p>

<p>Aside from small island states and numerous Western and developing countries, the court will also hear from the world's top two emitters of greenhouse gases, the United States and China. Oil producer group OPEC will also give its views.</p>

<p>The hearings will start at 10 a.m. (0900 GMT) local time on Monday and run until Dec. 13. The court's opinion will be delivered in 2025.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/g5jtre8g_international-court-of-justice-icj-the-hague-reuters_625x300_29_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A view of the International Court of Justice (ICJ) in The Hague, Netherlands.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/dozens-feared-dead-in-nigeria-boat-accident-7135527]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Dozens Feared Dead As Boat Capsizes In Nigeria]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/dozens-feared-dead-in-nigeria-boat-accident-7135527]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Nov 2024 20:21:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Dozens of people were feared dead after a boat capsized on the Niger River in central Nigeria, a waterways agency spokesperson said on Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dozens of people were feared dead after a boat capsized on the Niger River in central Nigeria, a waterways agency spokesperson said on Friday.</p>

<p>National Inland Waterways Authority (NIWA) spokesperson Makama Suleiman said the boat was carrying mostly traders from Missa community in the central Kogi state heading to a weekly market in the neighbouring Niger state.</p>

<p>Suleiman said that rescue operations were currently underway, but the exact number of fatalities was unknown.</p>

<p>None of the passengers were wearing life jackets, which significantly increased the risk of fatalities, he said.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2016-10/capsized-boat-ferry_650x400_71476688000.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[None of the passengers were wearing life jackets. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/notre-dame-reconstruction-teams-did-what-was-thought-impossible-emmanuel-macron-7135389]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Notre Dame Reconstruction Teams Did What Was Thought Impossible"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/notre-dame-reconstruction-teams-did-what-was-thought-impossible-emmanuel-macron-7135389]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Nov 2024 20:01:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[French President Emmanuel Macron on Friday inspected the gleaming restored interior of Notre Dame cathedral, saying workers had done the "impossible" by healing a "national wound" caused by a 2019 fire that ravaged the mediaeval landmark.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>French President Emmanuel Macron on Friday inspected the gleaming restored interior of Notre Dame cathedral, saying workers had done the "impossible" by healing a "national wound" caused by a 2019 fire that ravaged the mediaeval landmark.</p>

<p>Eight days ahead of the December 7 reopening of the cathedral, Macron conducted an inspection, broadcast live on television, which provided the first official insight into how the 850-year-old edifice now looks inside.</p>

<p>"You have achieved what was thought impossible," Macron told workers and officials who packed Notre Dame after the French president toured the cathedral.</p>

<p>"The blaze at Notre Dame was a national wound, and you have been its remedy through will, through work, through commitment," he said, adding the cathedral's re-opening will be a "shock of hope."</p>

<p>"This is an immense source of pride for the entire nation," Macron said, expressing hope that the spirit of "fraternity" would endure.</p>

<p>Notre Dame will welcome visitors and worshippers again over the December 7-8 weekend, after a sometimes challenging restoration to return the imposing Paris cathedral to its former glory after it was badly damaged by fire on April 19, 2019.</p>

<p>World leaders are expected to attend but the guest list has yet to be revealed.</p>

<p>The French president is hoping the re-opening of Notre Dame will be a major feather in his cap amid the current political deadlock following early parliamentary elections this summer.</p>

<p>"We were told many times at the beginning that it wouldn't be possible, that it was crazy, that it was arbitrary, that we were going to do it wrong," Macron said.</p>

<p>"But in the end," he added, "you did it."</p>

<p>Macron toured the key areas of the cathedral, including the nave, choir and chapel, and spoke to experts.</p>

<p>"Sublime," said a visibly pleased Macron, who was accompanied by Paris' archbishop Laurent Ulrich, the culture minister, the mayor of Paris and other officials.</p>

<p>"It is much more welcoming," he added, praising Notre Dame's pale-coloured stones and saying everyone involved in the reconstruction should "be proud".</p>

<p><strong>'Insane challenge'</strong></p>

<p>After the devastating fire Macron set the ambitious goal to rebuild Notre Dame within five years and make it "even more beautiful" than before, a target that the French authorities say has been met.</p>

<p>The "building site of the century" was a "challenge that many considered insane", Macron has said.</p>

<p>Some 250 companies and hundreds of experts were brought it for restoration work costing hundreds of millions of euros.</p>

<p>All 2,000 people who contributed to the effort had been invited to Friday's event.</p>

<p>The restoration cost a total of nearly 700 million euros (more than $750 million at today's rate).</p>

<p>It was financed from the 846 million euros in donations that poured in from 150 countries in an unprecedented surge of solidarity.</p>

<p>The 19th-century gothic spire has now been resurrected with an exact copy of the original, the stained windows have regained their colour, the walls shining after fire stains cleaned and a restored organ ready to thunder out again.</p>

<p>Unseen to visitors is a new mechanism to protect against any future fires, a discreet system of pipes ready to release millions of water droplets in case of a new disaster.</p>

<p>Notre Dame, which welcomed 12 million visitors in 2017, expects to receive an even higher figure of 14 to 15 million after the reopening, according to the church authorities.</p>

<p>French ministers have also floated the idea of charging tourists an entrance fee to the site but the Paris diocese has said free admission was an important principle to maintain.</p>

<p><strong>Reopening ceremony</strong></p>

<p>Macron had hoped to speak inside Notre Dame to mark the reopening but after negotiations with the diocese, he was now set to speak in the forecourt only.</p>

<p>France is by its constitution a secular country with a strict division between church and state.</p>

<p>The next day, Sunday December 8, will see the first mass and consecration of the new altar.</p>

<p>Macron said in December 2023 he had invited Pope Francis to the reopening of the cathedral but the head of the Catholic church announced in September, to the surprise of some observers, that he would not be coming.</p>

<p>Instead, the pontiff is making a landmark visit during the subsequent weekend to the French island of Corsica.</p>

<p>The French Catholic church has in recent years been rocked by a succession of sexual abuse allegations against clerics, including most recently the monk known as Abbe Pierre who became a household name for providing aid to the destitute.</p>

<p>Over five years on, the investigation into what caused the fire is ongoing, with initial findings backing an accidental cause such as a short circuit, a welder's torch or a cigarette.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/f19ipnn_notre-dame_625x300_29_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[French President Emmanuel Macron.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pics-pariss-iconic-notre-dame-cathedral-gutted-by-fire-restores-gothic-grandeur-7135327]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Pics: Gothic Grandeur Of Notre-Dame Cathedral, Gutted By Fire, Restored]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pics-pariss-iconic-notre-dame-cathedral-gutted-by-fire-restores-gothic-grandeur-7135327]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Nov 2024 19:54:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[French President Emmanuel Macron praised on Friday the more than 1,000 craftspeople who helped rebuild Paris' Notre-Dame Cathedral in what he called "the project of the century", five-and-a-half years after fire gutted the Gothic masterpiece.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>French President Emmanuel Macron praised on Friday the more than 1,000 craftspeople who helped rebuild Paris' Notre-Dame Cathedral in what he called "the project of the century", five-and-a-half years after fire gutted the Gothic masterpiece.</p>

<p>The 12th-century cathedral, one of the French capital's most beloved and visited monuments, will reopen its doors next week to tourists and to the Catholic faithful.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/5l7ge758_notre-dame-cathedral-paris-reuters_625x300_29_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>"Never before have we seen such a construction site. You all had your share in the project of the century," Macron told a gathering that included carpenters, stonemasons, art restorers, firefighters and donors.</p>

<p>"The burning of Notre-Dame was a national wound and you were its remedy, (restoring it) through determination, hard work and commitment."</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/bk36akpk_notre-dame-cathedral-paris-reuters_625x300_29_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>The workers, who include members of the elite 'Compagnons du Devoir', a centuries-old guild of artisans considered France's finest, burst into joyful applause when Macron concluded his address with a final 'thank you'.</p>

<p>The reconstruction work restored the cathedral's spire, its rib vaulting, flying buttresses, stained-glass windows and carved stone gargoyles to their past glory, with the white stone and gold decorations shining brighter than ever.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/4f05rlkc_notre-dame-cathedral-paris-reuters_625x300_29_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>It is a far cry from the evening of April 15, 2019, when TV viewers in France and worldwide watched with horror as the cathedral's roof and spire burst into flames and collapsed in a raging fire that also threatened the main bell towers, which narrowly avoided destruction.</p>

<p>On his visit to the site, Macron seemed deeply impressed as light poured into the nave through the renewed windows.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/bbtrkchc_notre-dame-cathedral-paris-afp_625x300_29_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>"This is overwhelming," he said as he toured the cathedral with his wife Brigitte, Paris mayor Anne Hidalgo and other senior officials.</p>

<h2><strong>'EXCEPTIONAL'</strong></h2>

<p>"It was an exceptional renovation project," stone-carver Samir Abbas, 38, told Reuters, relieved at having finished on schedule.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/1lghnd7k_notre-dame-cathedral-paris-afp_625x300_29_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>An opening ceremony - to which celebrities and heads of state have been invited - is planned for the evening of Dec. 7, followed by days of special Masses to celebrate the reopening and to thank those who helped save and rebuild the cathedral.</p>

<p>So much money poured in for the renovation from all over the world - more than 840 million euros ($882 million), according to Macron's office - that there are still funds left over for further investment in the building.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/6104jts_notre-dame-cathedral-paris-afp_625x300_29_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>The Catholic Church now expects the cathedral to welcome some 15 million visitors annually.</p>

<p>"We are very eager to welcome the whole world under the roof of our cathedral," Paris' Archbishop Laurent Ulrich said in a message on the cathedral website, expressing the Church's gratitude to all those who helped save it.</p>

<p>"On the night of April 15, hundreds of thousands of people committed themselves to what then seemed an impossible bet: to restore the cathedral and give it back its splendour within the unprecedented deadline of five years."</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/j6dchac8_notre-dame-cathedral-paris-afp_625x300_29_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>The guest-list for the reopening ceremony has not yet been published, but one source familiar with the planning said U.S. President Joe Biden's wife Jill would come, while President-elect Donald Trump had not yet confirmed his attendance.</p>

<p>Parisians expressed excitement and relief at the prospect of the cathedral reopening.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/436kgaac_notre-dame-cathedral-paris-afp_625x300_29_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>"I'm so happy," said 50-year-old architect Sebastien Truchot, who lives nearby. "Whether you believe in God or not, Notre-Dame is a universal symbol, and it's amazing to have it back and to rediscover it."</p>

<p>Albert Abid, a bookseller whose stall stands on the quay, was shocked to see it burn five years ago. "It's a relief. Finally, Notre Dame is restored," he said.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/30m1m4q_notre-dame-cathedral-paris-reuters_625x300_29_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A view of the facade of Notre-Dame de Paris cathedral in Paris, France ahead of its grand re-opening]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/asteroid-ryugu-sample-was-rapidly-colonised-by-earth-bacteria-study-7135273]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Asteroid Ryugu Sample Was 'Rapidly Colonised' By Earth Bacteria: Study]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/asteroid-ryugu-sample-was-rapidly-colonised-by-earth-bacteria-study-7135273]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Nov 2024 19:50:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The sample from the asteroid Ryugu was overrun with Earth-based life forms after they were brought to the planet, scientists have concluded in a study.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The sample from the asteroid Ryugu was overrun with Earth-based life forms after they were brought to the planet, scientists have concluded in a study. The research, published in the journal Meteoritics &amp; Planetary Science, explains how successful terrestrial microorganisms are at colonisation, even for extraterrestrial materials.</p>

<p>These samples have been collected by the Hayabusa2 spacecraft of the&nbsp;Japan&nbsp;Aerospace Exploration Agency (JAXA). It was launched in December 2014 and successfully rendezvoused with Ryugu in June 2018.</p>

<p>Later, it spent a year examining the asteroid having a diameter of roughly 3,000 feet (900 meters), before scooping out a sample, which returned to The Earth on December 6, 2020. Haybusa2 continued with its study of more asteroids.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The sample was split and sent to different teams of scientists, including the one that conducted the latest research. Team leader Matthew Genge, who is from Imperial College London told Space.com that they have discovered microorganisms in the sample returned from the asteroid.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"They appeared on the rock and spread with time before finally dying off," Genge said.</p>

<p>The "change in the number of microorganisms" further confirmed these were living microbes. "However, it also suggested they only recently colonised the specimen just before our analyses and were terrestrial in origin," Genge added.</p>

<p>The team observed filamentous microorganisms as the discovery took the form of filaments and rods of organic matter, Space.com reported.</p>

<p>However, the researcher noted the type of microorganisms was still unknown.</p>

<p>"Without studying their DNA, it is impossible to identify their exact type... However, they were most likely bacteria such as Bacillus since these are very common filamentous microorganisms, particularly in soil and rocks," Genge noted.</p>

<p>The team has ruled out the possibility of these microorganisms being already there on Ryugu when the samples were gathered.</p>

<p>"Before we prepared the sample, we performed nano-X-ray computed tomography, and no microbes were seen," Genge said, adding the change in population suggests they only appeared after the sample was exposed to the atmosphere upon its return to the Earth.</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/kmdghmag_asteroid-rygusu_625x300_29_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/turducken-and-how-nfl-legend-john-madden-made-it-popular-on-thanksgiving-7135171]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[As Thanksgiving Dish Turducken Trends, It's Link To NFL Legend John Madden]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/turducken-and-how-nfl-legend-john-madden-made-it-popular-on-thanksgiving-7135171]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Nov 2024 19:32:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[This celebrated dish was brought to prominence by NFL legend John Madden, football coach and commentator, in 1996 during a game between the New Orleans Saints and St. Louis Rams at the Louisiana Superdome.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Picture this: A matryoshka doll of bird meat - a turducken.<br />
<br />
A thanksgiving dish consisting of a boneless turkey, a boneless duck and a boneless chicken cooked together between layers of dressing.</p>

<p>This celebrated dish was brought to prominence by NFL legend John Madden, football coach and commentator, in 1996 during a game between the New Orleans Saints and St. Louis Rams at the Louisiana Superdome. He made it a focal point of his holiday game day shows, incidentally bringing Gourmet Butcher Block to national stature.</p>

<p>In an interview with the New York Times, Madden said, "The first one I ever had I was doing a game in New Orleans. The PR guy for the Saints brought me one. And he brought it to the booth. It smelled and looked so good. I didn't have any plates or silverware or anything, and I just started eating it with my hands."</p>

<p>Even his final public words on the dish were: "You can't beat a good turducken."</p>

<p>But apart from Louisiana, Europe also has a lengthy history of stuffing one bird in another. The French have Quail à la Talleyrand, which is essentially a quail in a chicken in a turkey! And the English have their gooducken with goose, duck and chicken.</p>

<p>Gordon Ramsey, British celebrity chef and restaurateur, recently went to meet Glenn Mistich of Gourmet Butcher Block, to make the infamous dish for a special episode of Thanksgiving on Fox NFL and was left blown away by it. He said, "Oh my goodness, it is like magic. Now I know why John went crazy for this."</p>

<p>Tom Brady, an NFL player and broadcaster also ate turducken on live TV this Thursday. Brady and his partner Kevin Burkhardt split up the turkey legs to keep Madden's Thanksgiving tradition alive.</p>

<p>"That's good!" Brady said after a bite, although viewers are not convinced he liked it. Some made jokes about him spitting it out after the camera panned away from him. But Brady even joked about abandoning the broadcast to continue eating.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Brady 100% spit this out as soon as the camera cut away <a href="https://t.co/vIvAgDIlHE">https://t.co/vIvAgDIlHE</a></p>
— Zach Regelin (@ZRegelin) <a href="https://twitter.com/ZRegelin/status/1862297676219654301?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 29, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>After almost 30 years of turducken's debut on NFL Thanksgiving broadcasts, the legacy continues.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/clq4g9f8_turducken-twitter_625x300_29_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Turducken was brought to prominence by NFL legend John Madden]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/swiss-socialite-jocelyn-wildenstein-claims-shes-never-had-plastic-surgery-report-7135056]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Jocelyn Wildenstein Claims She's "Never" Had Plastic Surgery: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/swiss-socialite-jocelyn-wildenstein-claims-shes-never-had-plastic-surgery-report-7135056]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Nov 2024 19:17:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Jocelyn Wildenstein, the 84-year-old Swiss socialite known as "Catwoman" due to her extensive plastic surgeries, has denied getting any work done on her face.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Jocelyn Wildenstein, the 84-year-old Swiss socialite known as "Catwoman" due to her extensive plastic surgeries, has denied getting any work done on her face. In an interview with <em>The Sun</em>, Ms Wildenstein claimed that she has "never" had plastic surgery because she is scared of the results. Her statement comes despite her former husband Alec Wildenstein once saying that they both got their respective first plastic surgeries together about a year after they got married.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"I haven't had plastic surgery. I am scared of what can happen, and I don't like to have something heavy. Sometimes it is a bit heavy and terrible," Ms Wildenstein told the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.thesun.co.uk/fabulous/31968684/catwoman-jocelyne-wildenstein-plastic-surgery-botox/" rel="noindex,nofollow">outlet</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The 84-year-old claims to have eschewed even Botox after a bad experience with the cosmetic treatment. "I don't like the Botox. Everyone has a different reaction to it," she explained, adding, "I have had Botox only twice. I don't know if I am allergic, but when I had it, it did not go well with me. It was not a good result. My face swelled up. If [other women] want to do it too strong, it doesn't work well."</p>

<p>Ms Wildenstein also insisted that she has never used any fillers. "I never did any fillers. I have some friends who had fillers and were not happy," she said.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/sophie-rain-this-adult-star-earns-rs-360-crore-annually-surpassing-nba-superstars-earnings-7133564">This Adult Star Earns Rs 360 Crore Annually, Surpassing NBA Superstar's Earnings</a></strong></p>

<p>Jocelyn Wildenstein became a tabloid fixture in the 1990s during her divorce from her billionaire art dealer husband Alec Wildenstein. Several reports suggest that she began her facial transmogrification because of her late ex-husband, who wanted her to look like a lynx.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://people.com/where-is-jocelyn-wildenstein-now-8645335" rel="noindex,nofollow">People </a>magazine, Mr Wildenstein once also claimed that he and Jocelyn both got some of their respective first plastic surgeries together about a year after they got married.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Notably, Ms Wildenstein's face has earned her the nickname "Catwoman". However, she has repeatedly said that some of her facial features are partially natural. "The lynx has perfect eyes. If I show you pictures of my grandmother, what you see is these eyes - cat eyes - and high cheekbones," she once said.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/93nvperg_jocelyn-wildenstein_625x300_29_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Ms Wildenstein also insisted that she has never used any fillers.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-germanys-patriot-air-defence-systems-will-protect-ukraine-via-poland-7134908]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How Germany's Patriot Air Defence Systems Will Protect Ukraine Via Poland]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-germanys-patriot-air-defence-systems-will-protect-ukraine-via-poland-7134908]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Nov 2024 18:57:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Germany has offered to re-deploy Patriot air defence systems to NATO ally Poland at the start of the new year, the German defence ministry said on Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Germany has offered to re-deploy Patriot air defence systems to NATO ally Poland at the start of the new year, the German defence ministry said on Thursday.</p>

<p>The units could be deployed for up to six months, the ministry said in a statement.</p>

<p>"With this we will protect a logistical hub in Poland which is of central importance for the delivery of materials to Ukraine," German Defence Minister Boris Pistorius said.</p>

<p>His Polish counterpart Wladyslaw Kosiniak-Kamysz said in a post on social media platform X that Warsaw welcomed the decision.</p>

<p>Germany previously deployed 300 troops along with three Patriot units to Poland from January to November 2022.</p>

<p>They were based in the town of Zamosc, about 50 km (31 miles) from the Ukrainian border, to protect the southern town and its crucial railway link to Ukraine.</p>

<p>The deployment was triggered by a stray Ukrainian missile that struck the Polish village of Przewodow in November 2022, in an incident that raised fears of the war in Ukraine spilling over the border.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/50d45sl_german-patriot-air-defence-system-reuters_625x300_29_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Germany has offered to re-deploy Patriot air defence systems to NATO ally Poland.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-reiterates-support-for-syria-as-jihadists-attack-7134837]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iran Reiterates Support For Syria As Jihadists Attack]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-reiterates-support-for-syria-as-jihadists-attack-7134837]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Nov 2024 18:47:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iran on Friday reiterated its strong support for ally Syria, where jihadists are waging a major offensive in the northwest of the country.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Iran on Friday reiterated its strong support for ally Syria, where jihadists are waging a major offensive in the northwest of the country.</p>

<p>Iranian Foreign Minister Abbas Araghchi "stressed Iran's continued support for the government, nation and army of Syria in their fight against terrorism," during a phone call with his Syrian counterpart Bassam al-Sabbagh, according to a statement.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/8db1u4jo_iran-syria_625x300_29_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Fighters enter the Rashidin district on the outskirts of Aleppo on their motorbikes on Friday.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-behind-staggeringly-reckless-sabotage-in-europe-uk-spy-chief-7134653]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russia Behind 'Staggeringly Reckless' Sabotage In Europe: UK Spy Chief]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-behind-staggeringly-reckless-sabotage-in-europe-uk-spy-chief-7134653]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Nov 2024 18:24:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[British security services have uncovered a "staggeringly reckless campaign" of Russian sabotage in Europe, that comes as Russia also resorts to nuclear sabre-rattling to deter countries from backing Ukraine, its foreign spy chief said on Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>British security services have uncovered a "staggeringly reckless campaign" of Russian sabotage in Europe, that comes as Russia also resorts to nuclear sabre-rattling to deter countries from backing Ukraine, its foreign spy chief said on Friday.</p>

<p>Richard Moore, the head of Britain's Secret Intelligence Service known as MI6, said in a speech in Paris on Friday that were&nbsp; Putin to succeed in reducing Ukraine to a vassal state, he would not stop there.</p>

<p>"Our security - British, French, European and transatlantic- will be jeopardised."</p>

<p>"We have recently uncovered a staggeringly reckless campaign of Russian sabotage in Europe, even as Putin and his acolytes resort to nuclear sabre-rattling to sow fear about the consequences of aiding Ukraine".</p>

<p>He said the cost of supporting Ukraine was well known, but added: "The cost of not doing so would be infinitely higher. If Putin succeeds China would weigh the implications, North Korea would be emboldened and Iran would become still more dangerous."</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/dhh0nq6k_vladimir-putin-reuters_625x300_29_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Russia President Vladimir Putin.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-korea-scrambles-jets-as-chinese-russian-warplanes-approach-7134563]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[South Korea Scrambles Jets As Chinese, Russian Warplanes Approach]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-korea-scrambles-jets-as-chinese-russian-warplanes-approach-7134563]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Nov 2024 18:14:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[South Korea's military said Friday it scrambled fighter jets as five Chinese and six Russian military planes flew through its air defence zone, an area wider than the country's airspace.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>South Korea's military said Friday it scrambled fighter jets as five Chinese and six Russian military planes flew through its air defence zone, an area wider than the country's airspace.</p>

<p>Five Chinese and six Russian military aircraft entered and exited the Korea Air Defence Identification Zone in the East Sea and South Sea from 9:35 am (0035 GMT) to 1:53 pm, Seoul's Joint Chiefs of Staff said in a statement.</p>

<p>But the planes crossed into the KADIZ "without violating South Korean airspace", the JCS said, adding that the military "identified the aircraft before they entered KADIZ and deployed Air Force fighter jets to take tactical measures in preparation for any contingencies".</p>

<p>An air defence identification zone is a broader area than a country's airspace in which it tries to control aircraft for security reasons, but the concept is not defined in any international treaty.</p>

<p>China's defence ministry called the flights "their ninth joint strategic patrol", which occurred above the Sea of Japan, also known as the East Sea in South Korea.</p>

<p>It added in a post on its official social media account that the flights were held Friday "according to the annual cooperation plan between the Chinese and Russian militaries".</p>

<p>South Korean military officials told local media that Chinese military aircraft flew towards the small Dokdo islands off South Korea's eastern coast, after passing between the Korean peninsula and Japan near the contested submerged rock of Ieodo.</p>

<p>Russian planes also flew south towards the Dokdo islets, known as Takeshima in Japanese.</p>

<p>Officials said the Chinese and Russian aircraft flew together over the sea south of Dokdo before departing.</p>

<p>Since 2019, China and Russia have regularly flown military aircraft into South Korea's air defence zone without prior notice, citing joint exercises.</p>

<p>Similar incidents occurred in June and December last year, and in May and November 2022, with Beijing and Moscow describing the flights as "joint strategic air patrols".</p>

<p>South Korea's defence ministry on Friday "expressed regret" to China and Russia over their military aircraft entering the South's air defence zone and "flying for an extended period without prior notice", according to a statement.</p>

<p>The ministry requested that "appropriate measures be taken to prevent a recurrence", adding that such actions could "unnecessarily heighten tensions in the region".</p>

<p>China and Russia have expanded military and defence ties since Moscow ordered troops into Ukraine nearly three years ago.</p>

<p>Both are also traditional allies of North Korea, Seoul's arch-foe.</p>

<p>South Korea and the United States have accused nuclear-armed North Korea of sending thousands of soldiers to Russia to fight in Ukraine and this month Pyongyang ratified a landmark defence pact with Moscow.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-12/rpse1pk8_south-korea-military_625x300_28_December_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Officials said the Chinese and Russian aircraft flew over the sea south of Dokdo. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/chinese-man-suffering-from-chronic-sneezing-finds-20-year-old-dice-lodged-in-nose-7134509]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Chinese Man Shocked After Discovering 20-Year-Old Dice Lodged In Nose]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/chinese-man-suffering-from-chronic-sneezing-finds-20-year-old-dice-lodged-in-nose-7134509]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Nov 2024 18:09:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 23-year-old man in China who had been experiencing persistent sneezing and a runny nose was shocked to discover a dice lodged in his nose for more than 20 years.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 23-year-old man in China who had been experiencing persistent sneezing and a runny nose was shocked to discover a dice lodged in his nose for more than 20 years. According to the <em>South China Morning Post</em>, the man, known simply as Xiaoma, had been suffering from chronic sneezing, nasal congestion and a constant runny nose for nearly a month. Initially, he tried treating himself with traditional Chinese medicine. However, after unsuccessful attempts, he visited a hospital where he was diagnosed with allergic rhinitis and identified a foreign object in his nasal passage.&nbsp;</p>

<p>At the hospital, the doctors performed a nasal endoscopy and revealed a dice lodged in the 23-year-old's nasal cavity, the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3287513/china-diamond-bachelor-cons-3-women-uses-ill-gotten-funds-lavish-gifts-real-lover?module=perpetual_scroll_1_RM&amp;pgtype=article" rel="noindex,nofollow">outlet </a>reported. The doctors discovered the "foreign object" covered with secretions. Upon extraction, it turned out to be a 2-centimetre dice.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"During the nasal endoscopy, we discovered a foreign object - a white lump coated with secretions. Upon extraction, it turned out to be a two-cm dice, partially corroded from being lodged in his nasal cavity for an extended period. It was located in the lower nasal passage, causing damage to the nasal mucosa," Dr Yang Rong, an otolaryngologist at the hospital, explained.</p>

<p>Doctors said that the situation was particularly dangerous because the dice had adhered to the surrounding tissues over the years. Any improper handling during the procedure could have caused it to fall into his airway, potentially leading to suffocation. Fortunately, the object was successfully removed through surgery.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/feature/young-gorilla-dies-at-canada-zoo-after-accidentally-being-crushed-by-hydraulic-door-7127177">Young Gorilla Dies At Canada Zoo After Accidentally Being Crushed By Hydraulic Door</a></strong></p>

<p>It remains unclear if the 23-year-old has experienced any long-term health consequences or side effects from living with the dice for more than 20 years.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Mr Xiaoma recalled that the dice may have accidentally entered his nose when he was around three or four years old.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, on social media, the incident has sparked a flurry of reactions. "He's only 23 years old, and the dice has been lodged in his nose for 20 years? How big was his nostril at three years old? Honestly, it's impressive he managed to live with that for 20 years," wrote one user.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"This is really horrifying. It's been corroded. Just looking at the picture makes me uncomfortable," commented another.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"This is a wake-up call for parents. Foreign objects in the nose are no joke; any abnormal symptoms should be addressed immediately at a hospital!" said a third user.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/fobckr28_dice-generic_625x300_29_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[On social media, the incident has sparked a flurry of reactions. (Representative pic)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/british-lawmakers-debate-contentious-assisted-dying-law-7134446]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[British MPs Debate On Legalising Assisted Dying]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/british-lawmakers-debate-contentious-assisted-dying-law-7134446]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Nov 2024 18:00:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[UK lawmakers debated whether to advance emotive legislation to legalise assisted dying for terminally ill people in England and Wales ahead of an expected vote on Friday, as competing protesters made their voices heard outside parliament.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>UK lawmakers debated whether to advance emotive legislation to legalise assisted dying for terminally ill people in England and Wales ahead of an expected vote on Friday, as competing protesters made their voices heard outside parliament.</p>

<p>The House of Commons last debated, and defeated, a euthanasia bill in 2015, but public support for giving terminally ill people the choice to end their lives has since shifted in favour, polls show.</p>

<p>A change in the law would see Britain emulate several other countries in Europe and elsewhere who allow some form of assisted dying.</p>

<p>Labour MP Kim Leadbeater, who is behind the Terminally Ill Adults (End of Life) Bill, opened the debate by arguing that changing the law would give terminally ill people "choice, autonomy and dignity at the end of their lives".</p>

<p>Advocates also argue that it would make some deaths less painful.</p>

<p>But other MPs expressed concern that people might feel coerced into opting for euthanasia, while some said they were worried it would discriminate against people with disabilities.</p>

<p>Opponents also worry that the healthcare system is not ready for such a landmark change and that it could cause a decline in investment for palliative care.</p>

<p>"True dignity consists in being cared for to the end," Conservative MP Danny Kruger told a close-to-full chamber, urging colleagues to reject a "state suicide service".</p>

<p>Outside, dozens of opponents gathered holding signs with "Kill the Bill, not the ill" and "care not killing", urging MPs to vote against the proposed legislation.</p>

<p>A nearby gathering in favour of the legislation saw people dressed in pink holding placards with slogans like "my life, my death, my choice".</p>

<p>Assisted suicide currently carries a maximum prison sentence of 14 years in England, Wales and Northern Ireland.</p>

<p><strong>'Shortening death'</strong></p>

<p>In Scotland, which has a separate legal system and devolved powers to set its own health policy, it is not a specific criminal offence. But it can leave a person open to other charges, including murder.</p>

<p>Leadbeater's bill would allow assisted suicide in England and Wales for adults with an incurable illness who have a life expectancy of fewer than six months and are able to take the substance that causes their death themselves.</p>

<p>Any patient's wish to die would have to be signed off by a judge and two doctors.</p>

<p>The measures are stricter than assisted dying laws in other European countries and also proposed legislation being contemplated in France.</p>

<p>Consideration is being given to a similar bill in Scotland.</p>

<p>Leadbeater's initiative is a so-called private members' bill and is not part of the government's agenda.</p>

<p>The debate was due to end at 2:00 pm (1400 GMT), with a vote on progressing the bill to its next parliamentary stage expected shortly afterwards.</p>

<p>MPs will have a free vote, meaning the outcome is very difficult to predict.</p>

<p>If the legislation is advanced then it would kickstart parliamentary scrutiny that could take months or years.</p>

<p>The bill follows Prime Minister Keir Starmer's vow, before winning power in July, to allow parliament to revisit the issue.</p>

<p>The UK leader, who voted in favour of permitting assisted suicide in 2015 but with "robust" safeguards, has not revealed his current view.</p>

<p>His ministerial team had been instructed to remain neutral but several expressed views, both in support and against.</p>

<p>Two polls last week indicated that a majority of Britons back changing the law.</p>

<p>Faith leaders are among the stringent opponents, with nearly 30 signing a joint letter last weekend arguing they are "deeply concerned" by the plans.</p>

<p>Ex-premiers Liz Truss, Boris Johnson, Theresa May and Gordon Brown have all said they oppose the legislation.</p>

<p>But former prime minister David Cameron, who resisted the 2015 law change, revealed he had changed his mind on the issue.</p>

<p>"As campaigners have convincingly argued, this proposal is not about ending life. It is about shortening death," he wrote in The Times newspaper on Thursday.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/psmi2aqg_assisted-dying-law_625x300_29_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Campaigners supporting the assisted suicide bill hold placards at a demonstration in central London.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/vladimir-putins-secret-daughter-hiding-in-paris-since-ukraine-war-report-7134081]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Putin's 'Secret' Daughter Hiding In Paris Since Ukraine War: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/vladimir-putins-secret-daughter-hiding-in-paris-since-ukraine-war-report-7134081]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Nov 2024 17:16:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Rozova had social media accounts, on which she posted photos of herself, posing and dancing. However, she deleted her accounts in 2022, shortly after Putin announced the invasion of Ukraine.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russian President Vladimir Putin alleged 'illegitimate' daughter lives in Paris, and works as a DJ but she does not go by "Vladimirovna" a name Vladimir's daughters would take in patronymic form.<br />
Instead, the 21-year-old goes by Luiza Rozova or Elizaveta Olegovna Rudnova. The latter is interesting because "Olegovna" means daughter of Oleg and, according to a Ukrainian TV channel - TSN, that tracked her down using leaked air manifests, Oleg Rudnov was Putin's close ally and confidant who used to arrange luxury real estate deals, who passed away in 2015.</p>

<p>Her mother, Svetlana Krivonogikh, with whom Putin allegedly had a love affair was a cleaner once but is now a multi-millionaire. According to UK-based daily, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.telegraph.co.uk/world-news/2024/11/28/putin-youngest-daughter-paris-pseudonym-luiza-rozova/" rel="noindex,nofollow">The Telegraph</a>, she is now worth £83 million and owns multiple houses in Monte Carlo, a yacht and is a board member of Bank Rossiya - a bank used by the elites to move money around. Apart from this, she also has a stake in the Igora Ski Resort near Finland and is the director of National Media Group, which is used to regulate key propaganda channels by the Kremlin.</p>

<p>Leaked Pandora Papers brought out in the open how Krivonogikh gradually became rich after 2000 when Putin became Russia's president.</p>

<p>Proekt, an independent investigative news organisation, mentions that Krivonogikh and Putin developed a friendship when he was St Petersburg's mayor, while also being married to Lyudmila Shkrebneva, with whom he has two legitimate daughters.</p>

<p>Rozova had social media accounts, on which she posted photos of herself, posing and dancing. However, she deleted her accounts in 2022, shortly after Putin announced the invasion of Ukraine, when she was trolled in the comments with people posting Ukraine flag emojis and accusing her of hiding in a bunker.</p>

<p>So, according to Luiza Rozova's birth certificate, she does not have a father's name but her patronymic name has been mentioned as Vladimirovna but Rozova denied any connection by saying, "Listen, judging by his young photos, probably, yes, it looks similar. But, as it turned out, there are a lot of people who look like Vladimir Vladimirovich", using the formal address in Russian.</p>

<p>Andrey Zakharov, now a BBC journalist, had then broken the story for Proekt. "Have I caused you a bad trauma by my investigation?" he asked Rozova on Clubhouse, a social audio app, to which she replied, "Oh no, not at all. My life was so stagnant, I am very grateful for the chance to be in the limelight, that people heard about my account."<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/c8k7k6p8_vladimir-putin-reuters_625x300_29_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Russian President Vladimir Putin alleged 'illegitimate' daughter lives in Paris]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/spain-introduces-4-day-paid-climate-leave-for-workers-after-deadly-floods-7133971]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Spain Introduces 4-Day Paid Climate Leave For Workers After Deadly Floods]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/spain-introduces-4-day-paid-climate-leave-for-workers-after-deadly-floods-7133971]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Nov 2024 17:05:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A month after floods killed at least 224 people, Spain has introduced "paid climate leave" for up to four days in a bid to allow workers to stay home during weather emergencies.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A month after floods killed at least 224 people, Spain has introduced "paid climate leave" for up to four days in a bid to allow workers to stay home during weather emergencies. According to <em>The Guardian</em>, the policy comes after several companies faced criticism for ordering employees to keep working during the floods, despite a red alert issued by the National Weather Agency. The firms argued that they were not adequately informed by the authorities and blamed delayed telephone alerts for their failure to act during the European country's deadliest floods in decades.</p>

<p>Spain's labour minister Yolanda Diaz said that the new measure aims to "regulate in accordance with the climate emergency" so that "no worker must run risks". If emergency authorities raise the alarm about a risk, "the worker must refrain from going to work", said Ms Diaz, per the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2024/nov/29/spain-paid-climate-leave-floods">outlet</a>. Separately, the government stated that employees can resort to a reduced working day beyond the four-day period, a mechanism that already exists for emergencies.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"In the face of climate denialism from the right, the Spanish government is committed to green policies," the labour minister added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Economy Minister Carlos Cuerpo highlighted the growing financial impact of extreme weather, warning that related costs could double by 2050. He also announced 2.3 billion euros in new aid for flood victims.</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/massive-411-mile-snowstorm-to-hit-uk-this-week-warnings-issued-7126846">Massive 411-Mile Snowstorm To Hit UK This Week, Warnings Issued</a></strong></p>

<p>In October, Valencia was hit the hardest by the floods, with at least 216 fatalities reported in the region. Conservative regional president Carlos Mazon admitted mistakes, however, he resisted calls to resign, describing the floods as an "apocalyptic" event that overwhelmed systems.</p>

<p>Notably, just two weeks after the devastating floods, torrential rains returned to Spain, forcing 3,000 residents in Malaga to evacuate their homes.</p>

<p>Climate experts have linked the intensifying rainfall to human-driven climate breakdown. According to <em>The Guardian</em>, they explained that this is because warmer air can hold more water vapour, making extreme rainfall events more frequent and severe, particularly in Europe, most of Asia, central and eastern North America and parts of South America, Africa and Australia. However, the extent of flooding is also influenced by factors such as flood defences and land use, experts said.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/a2vupdpg_spain-flood_625x300_02_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The government announced 2.3 billion euros in new aid for flood victims.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/why-indias-solar-mission-aditya-l1-is-important-for-the-world-7133738]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Why India's Solar Mission Aditya-L1 Is Important For The World]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/why-indias-solar-mission-aditya-l1-is-important-for-the-world-7133738]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Nov 2024 16:39:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[NASA and space agencies of other countries have also been watching the Sun for decades. But the coronagraph on Aditya-L1 has a slight advantage over other missions' equipment.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Aditya-L1, India's own solar observation mission, has achieved a milestone in solar research. On July 16, it captured the exact onset of a Coronal Mass Ejection (CME) by using the Visible Emission Line Coronagraph (VELC). After studying the output for months, scientists have now said that this "significant result" will help them keep power grids and communication satellites out of harm's way. Aditya-L1, developed by Indian Space Research Organisation (ISRO), was launched in September 2023 to study the solar atmosphere and has been orbiting the Sun at about 1.5 million km from Earth in a halo orbit (around the Lagrange point 1 or L1).</p>

<p>Studying CMEs is one of the most important scientific objectives of Aditya-L1.</p>

<p>"Made up of charged particles, a CME could weigh up to a trillion kilograms and can attain a speed of up to 3,000 kilometres per second while travelling. It can head out in any direction, including towards the Earth," Prof R Ramesh of the Indian Institute of Astrophysics that designed Velc <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c0qdy5dg7v7o" rel="noindex,nofollow">told the <em>BBC</em></a>.</p>

<p>"Now imagine this huge fireball hurtling towards Earth. At its top speed, it would take just about 15 hours to cover the 150 million km Earth-Sun distance," he further said.</p>

<h3><strong>How can Aditya-L1 mission protect our infrastructure?</strong></h3>

<p>The CMEs can lead to serious impact since the charged particles can make all satellites and electronic equipment malfunction. These particles can also knock down power grids and affect the weather.</p>

<p>Scientists say if they are able to see a solar storm in real time and track its trajectory, they can switch off power grids and satellites to protect them.</p>

<p>NASA and space agencies of other countries have also been watching the Sun for decades. But the coronagraph on Aditya-L1 has a slight advantage over other missions' equipment.</p>

<p>"With Velc, we can precisely estimate the time a coronal mass ejection begins and in which direction it's headed," said Professor Ramesh.</p>

<h3><strong>About Aditya-L1 mission</strong></h3>

<p>Named after the Hindi word for Sun, this mission follows ISRO's achievement of being the first country to successfully land on the Moon's south pole, surpassing Russia's failed Luna-25 with the Chandrayaan-3 mission. Chandrayaan-3 landed on the unexplored south pole of the Moon in August last year.</p>

<p>Scientists involved in the project aim to gain insights into the impact of solar radiation on the increasing number of satellites in orbit, with a particular focus on phenomena affecting ventures like Elon Musk's Starlink communications network.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/jt7dv20o_solar-flare_625x300_08_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Aditya-L1 mission was launched in September 2023.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/sophie-rain-this-adult-star-earns-rs-360-crore-annually-surpassing-nba-superstars-earnings-7133564]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Sophie Rain: OnlyFans Model Reveals She Earns Rs 360 Crore A Year]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/sophie-rain-this-adult-star-earns-rs-360-crore-annually-surpassing-nba-superstars-earnings-7133564]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Nov 2024 16:18:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Sophie Rain, a prominent model and influencer, revealed her remarkable $43.4 million earnings from OnlyFans, surpassing NBA star Jayson Tatums $35 million salary.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prominent social media influencer and model Sophie Rain recently surprised her fans and followers by disclosing her enormous income over the last one year. She posted a screenshot of her OnlyFans earnings, which came to an incredible $43.4 million, on X (previously Twitter). In the post, she expressed her gratitude, captioning the image, “Thankful for one year on here.” In addition to sending a shockwave to the world of digital content creation, the screenshot started a comparison of her earnings with those of other well-known celebrities.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">thankful for one year on here ?? <a href="https://t.co/Rq8KU5ju7n">pic.twitter.com/Rq8KU5ju7n</a></p>
— Sophie Rain (@sophieraiin) <a href="https://twitter.com/sophieraiin/status/1862198946300338556?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 28, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.essentiallysports.com/nba-active-basketball-news-three-hundred-fifteen-million-nba-star-jayson-tatum-s-current-salary-disparity-to-onlyfans-sophie-rain-leaves-fans-in-disbelief/"><em>EssentiallySports,</em></a> Sophie Rain's earnings reportedly surpass Jayson Tatum's annual salary, a jaw-dropping stat that has many fans talking. While Tatum continues to shine on the court for the Boston Celtics, Rain proves that success can come from unexpected streams in this modern-day internet age.</p>

<p>In comparison to Sophie Rain's $43 million this year, Jayson Tatum made $35 million. Rain's pay check is almost 23% more than what the C's forward gets paid for his MVP-calibre performances day in and day out.</p>

<p>And it's not just Tatum; according to <em>Basketball Forever,</em> in 2023, OnlyFans creators earned a staggering $6.6 billion, surpassing the combined salaries of every NBA star for the 2023-2024 season. The players' combined payroll was $4.9 billion.</p>

<p>The post by Rain immediately went viral, with close to 17 million views. The social media user went on and talked about this huge sum of earnings.</p>

<p>"OnlyFans pays better than Real Madrid," commented a user.</p>

<p>"I would need like two lifetimes to spend this," wrote another user.</p>

<p>"Think about how much we could accomplish if OnlyFans income was taxed like regular earnings," commented a third user.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/qvnt5q0g_sophie-rain_625x300_29_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The post about her earnings, shared on X, sparked widespread discussion.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/viral-video-shows-pakistan-forces-pushing-praying-protester-off-containers-7133479]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Viral Video Shows Pakistan Forces Pushing Praying Protester Off Containers]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/viral-video-shows-pakistan-forces-pushing-praying-protester-off-containers-7133479]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Nov 2024 16:09:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A video showing Pakistan's security forces pushing a man off a stack of shipping containers during a demonstration has surfaced online.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A video showing Pakistan's security forces pushing a man off a stack of shipping containers during a demonstration has surfaced online. According to <em>The BBC</em>, the incident occurred on Tuesday as thousands of former Prime Minister Imran Khan supporters converged in Islamabad to demand his release from prison. Top aides of Mr Khan said that the incident was one of several examples of police brutality at the demonstrations and has since called off the protests. The man had been praying on top of a container when armed officers approached him and "brutally pushed him off from a height equivalent to three storeys", Pakistan Tehreek-e-Insaf (PTI) said, per the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cm2md1jvrnvo" rel="noindex,nofollow">outlet</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The clip showed a man seemingly praying on top of a 25-foot-tall tower of shipping containers erected to block protesters from reaching their destination. Security forces are then seen following him to the top, surrounding him and then pushing him off the edge.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Take a look below:&nbsp;</strong></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Pakistani police throw man from three-story-high stack of shipping containers while he is praying <a href="https://t.co/vjaVXza4Vb">pic.twitter.com/vjaVXza4Vb</a></p>
— Bad Cops ? (@CopsGoneWrong) <a href="https://twitter.com/CopsGoneWrong/status/1861591638381867484?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 27, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.independent.co.uk/asia/south-asia/pakistan-army-man-pushed-container-imran-khan-protest-b2655153.html" rel="noindex,nofollow"><em>The Independent</em></a>, the condition of the man remains unknown. A PTI official said that the party was still investigating what happened to him.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Pakistan was marred by protests in the past few days. At least six people - four security forces and two civilians - died in the clashes during the protests. On Wednesday, police in Islamabad also said that 600 protesters had been arrested following Tuesday's operation, bringing the total since the protest sit-in began to over 1,000.</p>

<p>On Sunday, Imran Khan's party launched a march toward Islamabad, demanding the release of the jailed leader. Protesters said that they would not leave the capital until Mr Khan, who is in prison on several criminal charges including fraud, was freed. However, as they made their way to Democracy Square on Tuesday, they were pushed back by police firing tear gas.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-embassy-in-pakistan-issues-security-alert-for-peshawar-7125955">US Embassy In Pakistan Issues Security Alert For Peshawar</a></strong></p>

<p>On Wednesday, PTI said that the protests had been "temporarily suspended" due to the "government's brutality". It said Pakistan government forces had "launched a violent assault" on peaceful protesters "firing live rounds with the intent to kill as many people as possible". The party also claimed, without providing evidence, that several of their party workers were killed during the crackdown and appealed for an investigation.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Law enforcement defended its actions, arguing that the protests had devolved into "terrorism" after security personnel were targeted and public property was damaged.</p>

<p>Notably, Imran Khan was arrested in 2023 over allegations that he and his wife Bushra Bibi accepted land as a bribe through a trust. Mr Khan also faces anti-terrorism charges tied to clashes that followed his arrest. Other allegations include unlawfully disclosing state secrets in 2022, for which he was acquitted, and an unlawful marriage in 2018, also resulting in acquittal.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/7qlml2dg_pakistan-protester_625x300_29_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The incident took place on Tuesday.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/concerns-over-extremist-rhetoric-india-on-bangladesh-violence-7133305]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Concerns Over Extremist Rhetoric": India On Bangladesh Violence]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/concerns-over-extremist-rhetoric-india-on-bangladesh-violence-7133305]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Nov 2024 15:46:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India has conveyed its "serious concern" to Bangladesh over the "increasing incidents of violence" against the minority Hindu community in the neighbouring country. New Delhi has also shared its worry with Dhaka over the "surge in extremist rhetoric"]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India has conveyed its "serious concern" to Bangladesh over the "increasing incidents of violence" against the minority Hindu community in the neighbouring country. New Delhi has also shared its worry with Dhaka over the "surge in extremist rhetoric".</p>

<p>The Ministry of External Affairs, in its weekly press briefing, told reporters that India has been in touch with the interim government in Bangladesh on a routine and consistent basis regarding the rising cases of communal incidents targeting the Hindu minority.</p>

<p>"India has consistently and strongly raised with the Bangladesh government the threats and targeted attacks on Hindus and other minorities. Our position on the matter is clear - the interim government must live up to its responsibility of protecting all minorities," the foreign ministry said.</p>

<p>"We are concerned at the surge of extremist rhetoric, increasing incidents of violence and provocation. These developments cannot be dismissed only as media exaggeration," it added.</p>

<p>On the Bangladesh government calling renowned international religious group ISKCON a "fundamental organisation", the Ministry of External Affairs responded by saying, "ISKCON is a globally well-regarded organisation with a strong record of social service. We once again call upon Bangladesh to take all steps for the protection of minorities."</p>

<p>The reference to ISKCON as a "religious fundamentalist" organisation was part of the Bangladesh Attorney General's response to a question about the origin of the group in Bangladesh.</p>

<p>Regarding a popular Hindu priest - Chinmoy Krishna Das - being arrested in Bangladesh, the foreign ministry said "As far as cases against individuals are concerned, we have noted that legal processes are underway.&nbsp; We expect that these processes will deal with the case in a just, fair and transparent manner, ensuring full respect for the legal rights of all concerned."</p>

<p>Chandan Kumar Dhar Prokash alias Chinmoy Krishna Das Brahmachari is a spokesperson of the Sanatan Jagaran Mancha. He was the former head of ISKCON-operated religious site named Pundarik Dham in Chittagong.</p>

<p>On Thursday, Bangladesh's ousted prime minister Sheikh Hasina spoke out about the arrest of a Hindu priest in her country. She said "A top leader of Sanatan religious community has been unjustly arrested, he must be released immediately. A temple has been burnt in Chittagong. Previously, mosques, shrines, churches, monasteries and homes of the Ahmadiyya community were attacked, vandalized and looted and set on fire. Religious freedom and security of life and property of people of all communities should be ensured."</p>

<p>Since Sheikh Hasina was forced to step down as prime minister, the new military-backed interim administration, led by Nobel laureate Mohammed Yunus, has faced criticism for failing to control violence against minorities. This includes instances of vandalism and desecration at temples, damage of Hindu businesses and properties, and homes of Hindus being attacked.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/q2lv04lk_bangladesh-violence-targeting-hindus-ians_625x300_29_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hindu minority in Bangladesh have been protesting incidents of violence and rhetoric against them]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/meet-honey-and-mouni-nepals-first-transgender-candidates-running-for-local-office-7133214]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[All About Nepal's First Transgender Candidates Running For Local Office]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/meet-honey-and-mouni-nepals-first-transgender-candidates-running-for-local-office-7133214]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Nov 2024 15:36:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Two transgender candidates -- Honey Maharjan and Mouni Maharjan -- are contesting the by-elections to local bodies in Nepal. The voting in 32 districts across the Himalayan nation is scheduled for Sunday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Two transgender candidates -- Honey Maharjan and Mouni Maharjan -- are contesting the by-elections to local bodies in Nepal. The voting in 32 districts across the Himalayan nation is scheduled for Sunday.</p>

<p>Although there were 44 vacant positions, the by-polls are being conducted only for 41 local-level positions. Among the positions up for grabs are two chairs of rural municipalities, four vice-chairpersons, one municipal chief, one deputy chief and 32 ward chairpersons, news agency PTI reported.</p>

<p>Earlier, the two chiefs of district coordination committees and one ward chairperson were elected unopposed. A total of 376 candidates, including independents, are in the fray for by-election.</p>

<p><strong>Who are the transgender candidates?</strong></p>

<p>With hope for political representation among the sexual and gender minorities in Nepal, Honey Maharjan and Mouni Maharjan have filed their nomination for different positions in the by-elections.</p>

<p>Honey, 44, is running for the post of mayor of Kirtipur, located on the outskirts of Nepal's capital city Kathmandu, AFP reported.</p>

<p>Currently working as a tour guide, Honey was brought up in a poor family. Struggling to make ends meet, she earlier used to wash dishes at a restaurant and even worked at a garment factory.</p>

<p>Mouni Maharjan, on the other hand, is eying a victory from the ward chair position in the same municipality. Mouni, 29, and Honey are representing Nepal's People's Socialist Party.</p>

<p><strong>LGBTQ rights in Nepal</strong></p>

<p>While Nepal has progressive laws on LGBTQ rights, nobody from the community has ever held public office since 2008, when a gay person emerged as a lawmaker in the Parliament of Nepal after getting nominated under the proportional representation system.</p>

<p>Honey hopes that her candidature will "inspire others in the queer community to participate openly in future elections".</p>

<p>Even after progressive laws, people from the community face discrimination in various sectors such as employment, healthcare and education in Nepal.</p>

<p>"Until now, not one of our community members exercised the right to run for mayoral elections in Nepal," said Honey. Recalling her "nightmare" past, she added that she faced a lot of discrimination and abuse and hoped to bring change.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Mouni said her priorities included not just improvement in infrastructure and sanitation but also fighting the stigma against LGBTQ people.</p>

<p>Mouni will work to add a "curriculum in school courses regarding the community", she said. This will allow the new generation to "easily accept our presence" and treat them better.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/11ob0rtg_honey-maharjan-_625x300_29_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Honey Maharjan, one of the transgender candidates running for local office in Nepal]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>