<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 15:29:54 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/why-the-vance-walz-debate-boils-down-to-contrasting-versions-of-masculinity-6683266]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Why The Vance-Walz Debate Boils Down To Contrasting Versions Of Masculinity]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/why-the-vance-walz-debate-boils-down-to-contrasting-versions-of-masculinity-6683266]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 15:20:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump's running mate JD Vance and Kamala Harris's vice-presidential pick Tim Walz -- set to debate each other Tuesday -- embody different versions of masculinity in an election that is dividing American men and women like never before.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump's running mate JD Vance and Kamala Harris's vice-presidential pick Tim Walz -- set to debate each other Tuesday -- embody different versions of masculinity in an election that is dividing American men and women like never before.</p>

<p>Vance, on the Republican ticket, has a conservative definition of family.</p>

<p>The Ohio senator has been criticized for denouncing "childless cat ladies" who have no "direct interest" in the welfare of the country, he alleged, because they have no children.</p>

<p>As a former soldier from a lower-class family, Vance sees himself as the spokesman for the downtrodden Americans with whom he grew up.</p>

<p>Stringently opposed to abortion, Vance also criticizes progressive ideas of family which, in his view, encourage "people to shift spouses like they change their underwear."</p>

<p>On the other side, Democrat Tim Walz strives to project a different image of the good family man -- one who does not hesitate to show a more vulnerable side of himself, like when discussing the fertility problems he faced with his wife Gwen.</p>

<p>"I can remember praying each night for a phone call," he recounted at the Democratic National Convention.</p>

<p>"The pit in your stomach when the phone would ring, and the absolute agony when we heard the treatments hadn't worked."</p>

<p>The Minnesota governor, a former teacher, also frequently retells the story of how he helped create the first LGBTQ student club at the high school where he taught, long before gay rights were widely socially accepted.</p>

<h3><strong>'Toxic masculinity' alternatives&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Walz, who also coached high school football and served 24 years in the National Guard, still plays into a classic male archetype, whether he is discussing his favourite hardware store on TikTok or boasting about his hunting skills.</p>

<p>In reference to Vance, for instance, Walz said: "I guarantee you he can't shoot pheasants like I can."</p>

<p>"The Harris campaign is offering alternatives to the 'toxic masculinity' that has captured the Republican party," said Karrin Vasby Anderson, a communications studies professor at Colorado State University.</p>

<p>And Walz isn't alone, she added.</p>

<p>Harris's husband, Doug Emhoff, enthusiastically supports his wife and has no problem making himself the butt of the joke, including when he describes the awkward voicemail he left her after their first date.</p>

<p>The posturing is a far cry from Donald Trump's "macho man" stance -- one that he references by playing the Village People hit of the same name to open his rallies.</p>

<p>Anderson argues that societal gains by women and people of colour have "required white men to make adjustments to how they speak, what jokes they tell, how they comport themselves in romantic relationships, how they conduct themselves at work."</p>

<p>"Some men don't like having to change," she added.</p>

<h3><strong>Gender divide&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>According to recent polls, a growing number of young men are throwing their support behind Trump, whose rhetoric centres on strength, authority and even violence.</p>

<p>The Republican is capitalizing on this well of support by increasing the number of events he holds with influencers involved in cryptocurrency, video games and combat sports, many of whom have followings in the tens of millions.</p>

<p>In the extremely close race for the White House, Trump hopes to motivate an electorate that historically has not had a strong turnout at the polls.</p>

<p>Harris, on the other hand, often says that "the true measure of strength is based on who you lift up, not who you beat down."</p>

<p>The Democrat, who fiercely defends abortion rights, is banking on mobilizing women, who vote in greater numbers than men in the United States.</p>

<p>The 2020 election saw 82.2 million women go to the polls, compared with 72.5 million men, according to the Center for American Women and Politics.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/4hjdk9n8_tim-walz-jd-vance-split_625x300_29_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[JD Vance slams progressive ideas of family while Tim Walz projects a different image of a good family man]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/frenchman-on-mass-rape-trial-absent-from-court-for-being-unwell-6683064]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Frenchman On Mass Rape Trial Absent From Court For Being "Unwell"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/frenchman-on-mass-rape-trial-absent-from-court-for-being-unwell-6683064]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 14:54:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Dominique Pelicot, 71, has been on trial since September 2 over raping and recruiting strangers to rape his heavily sedated wife Gisele for nearly a decade.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The main defendant in a mass rape trial that has sparked horror and protests in France was absent on Monday because he is "unwell" and must undergo medical treatment, the presiding judge said.</p>

<p>Dominique Pelicot, 71, has been on trial since September 2 over raping and recruiting strangers to rape his heavily sedated wife Gisele for nearly a decade.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The trial had already been briefly suspended in mid-September due to the absence of Dominique Pelicot, who was suffering from intestinal problems.</p>

<p>"He's unwell. He has to have medical treatment this afternoon," Judge Roger Arata said at the start of the hearing on Monday in the southeastern city of Avignon. "We'll see tomorrow," he added.</p>

<p>Dominique Pelicot had already been excused from the hearing on Friday to undergo a medical examination.&nbsp;</p>

<p>His lawyer Beatrice Zavarro had told AFP on Sunday that the examination "went well."</p>

<p>Pelicot has admitted to the charges against him.</p>

<p>He is being tried along with 50 other men aged between 26 and 74, many of whom have denied the rape charge. Most risk up to 20 years in jail if convicted of aggravated rape.</p>

<p>Seven more defendants will be called to testify on Thursday.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Among them is 46-year-old Jerome V., a former grocery store employee, who sexually assaulted Gisele Pelicot six times in 2020 at the couple's home in the town of Mazan in southeastern France.</p>

<p>Gisele Pelicot, Dominique's ex-wife who only discovered the abuse in 2020 after being told of it by police, has requested that the trial be open to the public to raise awareness about the use of drugs to commit sexual abuse.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/5m5tlorg_gisele-pelicot-french-mass-rape-survivor-afp_625x300_14_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Gisele Pelicot, Dominique's ex-wife discovered the abuse only in 2020. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-to-expect-from-natos-new-chief-mark-rutte-6682988]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What To Expect From NATO's New Chief Mark Rutte?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-to-expect-from-natos-new-chief-mark-rutte-6682988]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 14:45:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Incoming NATO chief Mark Rutte brings new leadership this week to one of the world's most powerful-sounding roles -- helming the nuclear-armed Atlantic alliance.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Incoming NATO chief Mark Rutte brings new leadership this week to one of the world's most powerful-sounding roles -- helming the nuclear-armed Atlantic alliance.</p>

<p>But even if the former Dutch prime minister wanted to shake things up after taking over from Jens Stoltenberg, he probably couldn't.</p>

<p>The reality of the NATO job means Rutte will be heading a risk-averse civilian bureaucracy, with hard power ultimately residing with member countries and above all the United States.</p>

<p>And in many ways NATO's 32 nations -- by swapping one mild-mannered, middle-aged, northern European male ex-premier for another -- have opted for more of the same, to steer the alliance in troubled times.</p>

<p>"In such a difficult geopolitical situation, keeping continuation and the same foreign policy and security line is very important," a senior NATO diplomat told AFP, talking on condition of anonymity to discuss internal deliberations.</p>

<p>During his more than 10 years at the helm, Stoltenberg won plaudits for his calm stewardship of the sometimes fractious alliance.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Norwegian helped keep then-US president Donald Trump on board, threw his weight behind Ukraine while making sure NATO didn't get dragged into a war with Russia and kicked off an overhaul of the alliance's defences to face Moscow.</p>

<p>"Allies were looking for somebody who has many of the same qualities as Stoltenberg and will continue in the same direction: prime minister, well-connected, long experience, good address book, has handled Trump," said Jamie Shea, a former senior NATO official now with the Chatham House think tank.</p>

<p>Rutte, a favourite of key powers the US, Britain, France and Germany, ticked all those boxes.</p>

<p>A veteran who led complex coalitions in the Netherlands for 13 years, he has ample experience that can be put to use keeping countries with disparate -- and often competing -- interests on the same page.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"He is a consensus builder with an unflinching commitment to the transatlantic alliance," a senior US official said.</p>

<p>The Dutchman has been a stalwart backer of Kyiv and wasn't afraid to talk frankly to Trump, who could make a comeback after elections in November.&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>Consensus straitjacket?</strong></h3>

<p>Similarities aside, diplomats say the straight-talking Rutte should bring a breath of fresh air to the alliance after Stoltenberg's long tenure.</p>

<p>But Rutte would likely struggle to get through major changes.</p>

<p>While the job of running the alliance sounds like a potent role, the secretary general actually only heads the civilian bureaucracy of some 1,500 staff.</p>

<p>Military power rests with the member countries -- mainly in the hands of an American general as Supreme Allied Commander in Europe.</p>

<p>The NATO head often serves more as a spokesperson-in-chief for the organisation, with Stoltenberg known for carefully parsing the position he could stake out.</p>

<p>All decisions at NATO need to be agreed by each member and the person at the top is constrained by how far allies -- and particularly Washington -- are willing to go.</p>

<p>The direction for the next year was set at the last summit in Washington in July.</p>

<p>"NATO is a consensus organisation. Everything, absolutely everything, from the most mundane to the most strategic, is decided by consensus," said Ian Lesser of the German Marshall Fund think tank.</p>

<p>"So the scope for individual secretary generals to reshape what NATO does and how it does it is obviously very limited."&nbsp;</p>

<p>That said, Rutte does have some levers at his disposal to try to drive through priorities.</p>

<p>"The secretary-general can be instrumental in bringing issues to the agenda for discussion," Lesser said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"That's actually a big role."</p>

<p>Stoltenberg used his pulpit to press allies on supporting Ukraine, paying more attention to the impact of climate change or strengthening ties with partners in Asia-Pacific.</p>

<p>Diplomats say one area where Rutte could push is trying to improve coordination between the European Union and NATO -- long hamstrung by alliance member Turkey's standoff with Cyprus.&nbsp;</p>

<p>But Rutte's main chance to shape the office will likely come if the political situation gets stormier -- with Trump's return to office or a major change in Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Then he'll need all his diplomatic guile -- and lengthy contact list -- to keep the ears and commitment of NATO's diverse leaders.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The skill and personality of a secretary general can make a difference, especially under conditions when the alliance is being tested," Lesser said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/u2qnhp2g_mark-rutte-reuters-_625x300_30_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mark Rutte, a favourite of key powers the US, Britain, France and Germany, ticked all those boxes.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/business-news/global-investment-firm-fidelity-reduces-value-of-elon-musks-x-by-79-per-cent-platform-likely-worth-9-4-billion-6681613]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Investment Firm Fidelity Reduces Value Of Elon Musk's X By 79%]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/business-news/global-investment-firm-fidelity-reduces-value-of-elon-musks-x-by-79-per-cent-platform-likely-worth-9-4-billion-6681613]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 14:05:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Global investment firm Fidelity has reduce the value of its holding in Elon Musk-run X (formerly Twitter) by a massive 78.7 per cent, which implies that the X social media platform is likely valued at just $9.4 billion.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Global investment firm Fidelity has reduce the value of its holding in Elon Musk-run X (formerly Twitter) by a massive 78.7 per cent, which implies that the X social media platform is likely valued at just $9.4 billion.</p>

<p>The tech billionaire had bought the social media company for $44 billion in October 2022 after an intense drama.</p>

<p>As per new estimate from asset manager Fidelity, X is now valued at less than a quarter of its $44 billion purchase price (at August end), reports TechCrunch, citing its filings.</p>

<p>The fund now values its stake in X at approximately $4.18 million. In July, Fidelity valued its shares in X at about $5.5 million.</p>

<p>X, Fidelity or Musk did not immediately comment on the report based on regulatory disclosures.</p>

<p>In May, Musk-run artificial intelligence (AI) company xAI raised $6 billion to accelerate the research and development of future technologies. In a post, the X owner said the pre-money valuation was $18 billion.</p>

<p>xAI, which has unveiled an AI chatbot called 'Grok', raised funds from key investors, including Fidelity Management and Research.</p>

<p>In January this year, the global investment firm Fidelity marked down its investment in Musk-run X Holdings (the parent company of X) by a whopping 71.5 per cent from the original value.</p>

<p>Fidelity took a stake in X Corp for $300 million in October 2022 when Musk acquired the platform, formerly called Twitter, for $44 billion.</p>

<p>In 2023, Fidelity had cut the valuation by 65 per cent, and now, it has further cut X's valuation in a new disclosure.</p>

<p>Musk had reportedly told bankers, after taking $13 billion in loan to fund his Twitter acquisition, that they will not lose any money on the deal. The debt is split between $6.5 billion of term loans, as well as $6 billion of senior and junior bonds and a $500 million revolver. Lenders were unlikely to get even 60 cents on the dollar for the bonds and loans.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-07/83n5a6vo_x-logo-_625x300_29_July_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The fund now values its stake in X at approximately $4.18 million.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-ukraine-conflict-all-goals-set-for-ukraine-will-be-achieved-says-russian-president-putin-6682481]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["All Goals" Set For Ukraine Will Be Achieved, Says Russian President Putin]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-ukraine-conflict-all-goals-set-for-ukraine-will-be-achieved-says-russian-president-putin-6682481]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 13:32:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russian President Vladimir Putin on Monday vowed that Moscow would accomplish all goals it has set for itself in Ukraine, in its third year of conflict.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russian President Vladimir Putin on Monday vowed that Moscow would accomplish all goals it has set for itself in Ukraine, in its third year of conflict.</p>

<p>"The truth is on our side. All goals set will be achieved," Putin said in a video message released to mark the second anniversary of what Russia calls "Reunification Day" when Moscow annexed four Ukrainian regions.</p>

<p>After it sent troops into Ukraine in February 2022, Russia annexed the regions of Lugansk, Donetsk, Zaporizhzhia and Kherson. It does not fully control all territory in these regions.</p>

<p>In his address, Putin repeated his justification for sending troops into Ukraine as protecting Russian speakers against a "neo-Nazi dictatorship" that aimed to "cut them off forever from Russia, their historic homeland".</p>

<p>He also slammed "Western elites" who "turned Ukraine into their colony, a military base aimed at Russia" and who fanned "hate, radical nationalism... hostility to everything Russian".</p>

<p>"Today we are fighting for a secure, prosperous future for our children and grandchildren", he said.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/14dvuelo_vladimir-putin-afp-putin-in-office-afp_625x300_27_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[In his address, Vladimir Putin repeated his justification for sending troops into Ukraine. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-confirms-death-of-its-leader-in-lebanon-in-israeli-airstrike-6682312]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hamas Confirms Death Of Its Leader In Lebanon In Israeli Airstrike]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-confirms-death-of-its-leader-in-lebanon-in-israeli-airstrike-6682312]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 13:06:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Palestinian militant group Hamas said its leader in Lebanon was killed Monday in a strike on the country's south, as official media reported a strike on a Palestinian refugee camp.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Palestinian militant group Hamas said its leader in Lebanon was killed Monday in a strike on the country's south, as official media reported a strike on a Palestinian refugee camp.</p>

<p>"Fatah Sharif Abu al-Amine, the leader of Hamas... in Lebanon and member of the movement's leadership abroad" was killed in an air strike on his "home in the Al-Bass camp in south Lebanon", a Hamas statement said.</p>

<p>It said he was killed with his wife, son and daughter in a "terrorist and criminal assassination".</p>

<p>The official National News Agency reported an air strike on Al-Bass near the city of Tyre, saying it was the "first time" the camp had been targeted.</p>

<p>The statement came hours after the Popular Front for the Liberation of Palestine (PFLP), a secular left-wing group, said three of its members were killed in a strike in Beirut's Kola district early Monday.</p>

<p>Israel has repeatedly targeted Hamas officials in Lebanon since the Gaza war erupted almost a year ago.</p>

<p>A strike in January, which a US defence official said was carried out by Israel, killed Hamas deputy leader Saleh al-Aruri and six other militants in Hezbollah's south Beirut stronghold.</p>

<p>In August, an Israeli strike on a vehicle in the south Lebanon city of Sidon killed Hamas commander Samer al-Hajj.</p>

<p>Lebanon's official Palestinian refugee camps were created for Palestinians who were driven out or fled during the 1948 war at the time of Israel's creation.</p>

<p>By longstanding convention, the Lebanese army stays out of the camps and leaves the Palestinian factions to handle security.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/s5vcg3b8_israeli-airstrike-afp-_625x300_30_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel has repeatedly targeted Hamas officials in Lebanon since the Gaza war.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iranian-hardliners-urge-closure-of-hormuz-and-nuclear-armament-after-hezbollah-chief-hassan-nasrallah-s-killing-6682276]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Only Available Card Is Atom Bomb": Iran's Hardliners Amid Mideast Tensions]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iranian-hardliners-urge-closure-of-hormuz-and-nuclear-armament-after-hezbollah-chief-hassan-nasrallah-s-killing-6682276]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 13:03:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iran's ultra-hardliners are demanding the closure of the Strait of Hormuz and the development of a nuclear bomb in response to the recent killing of Hezbollah chief Hassan Nasrallah.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The hardliners in Iran are calling for drastic measures in response to Israel's recent killing of Hezbollah chief Hassan Nasrallah. Dominated by supporters of ultra-hardliner figures such as former nuclear negotiator Saeed Jalili, there's been a growing chorus on social media for Iran to adopt a more aggressive stance, including blocking the vital Strait of Hormuz and pursuing nuclear weapon development.<br />
<br />
In recent posts, ultra-hardliners have voiced frustration with President Masoud Pezeshkian's government, accusing it of being too passive in the face of Israel's military operations in Gaza and Lebanon. However, according to the report, these criticisms largely omit the fact that any decision regarding military action against Israel lies with Supreme Leader Ali Khamenei, who holds ultimate authority as the head of Iran's Armed Forces.<br />
<br />
Following Nasrallah's death, Khamenei, through a number of posts on X (formerly Twitter), urged “all Muslims to stand with the people of Lebanon and the honorable Hezbollah” but refrained from any direct call for retaliation, falling short of the revenge many hardliners had anticipated.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Sayyid Hassan Nasrallah was martyred while busy making plans for defending the defenseless people of Beirut's Dahiya neighborhood - the same way for tens of years he had planned, strategized, and fought for the oppressed people of Palestine &amp; their occupied cities &amp; villages.</p>
— Khamenei.ir (@khamenei_ir) <a href="https://twitter.com/khamenei_ir/status/1840058558047563901?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 28, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">The Islamic world has lost a noble figure, the Resistance Front has lost an eminent standard-bearer, and Lebanon's Hezbollah has lost an unparalleled leader. However, the blessings from Sayyid Hassan Nasrallah's decades of planning and jihad will never be lost.</p>
— Khamenei.ir (@khamenei_ir) <a href="https://twitter.com/khamenei_ir/status/1840061688013283336?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 28, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">It is an obligation for all Muslims to stand with the people of Lebanon and the honorable Hezbollah, offering their resources and assistance as Hezbollah confronts the usurping, cruel, malicious Zionist regime.</p>
— Khamenei.ir (@khamenei_ir) <a href="https://twitter.com/khamenei_ir/status/1839986619870314501?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 28, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>In the absence of such a directive, Jalili's followers have begun advocating for radical actions, according to Iran International.<br />
<br />
Comparisons to Yemen's control of the Bab al-Mandab Strait, another critical oil shipping route, have been drawn by these factions, with some questioning why Iran hasn't similarly closed the Hormuz to Western vessels.<br />
<br />
One social media post, when translated to English, read, “Why can Yemen block the main passageway of oil [in the Bab al-Mandab Strait], but we are not doing the same in the Strait of Hormuz?”</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="rtl" lang="fa">‌<br />
چرا یمن شاهرگ عبور نفت رو میبنده ما شاه رگ عبور نفت در تنگه هرمز رو نمیبندیم ؟!<br />
‌</p>
— | عـَلامـَــتـْــ | (@Aqamehrdad) <a href="https://twitter.com/Aqamehrdad/status/1839951929016762810?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 28, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The escalating rhetoric from Iran's ultra-hardline camp suggests that blocking the Strait, which handles a significant percentage of the world's oil shipments, would serve as a warning to Israel and its Western allies, said the Iran International report, adding, this action could, however, also trigger a military confrontation with the US and other naval powers in the region.<br />
<br />
Alongside these demands, a growing number of voices within Iran's hardline factions are advocating for the development of a nuclear weapon. Sohrab Salehi, a university professor, wrote on X, “Iran burned its cards in the past. Now the only available card is Atom Bomb. This is the only way to bring the West to negotiations.”</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="rtl" lang="fa">خوشمان بیاید یا نه، ایران باید دکترین نظامی خود را به سمت ساخت بمب اتم هدایت کند. ایران کارت های خود را در گذشته، سوزانده. اکنون تنها کارت قابل دسترس، بمب اتم است. این تنها راهی است که غرب را به سمت مذاکره می کشاند.</p>
— dr sohrab salehi (@drsohrabsalehi) <a href="https://twitter.com/drsohrabsalehi/status/1839719932264886366?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 27, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Not everyone, though, agrees with these suggestions. Many argue that closing the Strait of Hormuz would not only escalate tensions but could also backfire on Iran economically and diplomatically. Additionally, despite some calls for nuclear weapon development, there remains the issue of Khamenei's reported religious edict against weapons of mass destruction, including nuclear arms.<br />
<br />
These tensions are playing out against the backdrop of a broader reassessment within Iran's political circles regarding the fallout from Israel's recent military actions. Abdolreza Davari, a former ally of ex-President Mahmoud Ahmadinejad, has been one of the more prominent voices calling for a more pragmatic approach. Davari, who supported President Pezeshkian in the last election, tweeted that the operation that killed Nasrallah was an “irreparable blow to the body of the resistance front.”</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="rtl" lang="fa">شهادت مجاهد کبیر سیدحسن نصرالله، ضربه ای مهلک و جبران ناپذیر بر پیکره جبهه مقاومت و نشانه برتری یافتن صهیونیستهای وحشی در منطقه است.<br />
فارغ از رجزخوانیهای معمول، این ضربه مرگ بار را علت یابی کنیم و متناسب با اقتضائات و دگرگونیهای منطقه در عصر پسا نصرالله، منافع ایران را دنبال کنیم. <a href="https://t.co/hlvLyhieJ9">https://t.co/hlvLyhieJ9</a></p>
— عبدالرضا داوری ???????? (@DavariAbdolreza) <a href="https://twitter.com/DavariAbdolreza/status/1840038993347436738?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 28, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Davari also suggested that Iran focus more on protecting its own national interests, taking into account the evolving geopolitical landscape in the post-Nasrallah era.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/edmrg2ao_israelhezbollah-conflict_625x300_30_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Middle East is on boil as Israel increased attacks on Hezbollah in Lebanon]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/marburg-virus-outbreak-in-rwanda-what-is-it-symptoms-cure-6681999]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: What Is Marburg Virus That Has Killed 6 In This African Country]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/marburg-virus-outbreak-in-rwanda-what-is-it-symptoms-cure-6681999]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 12:44:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[At least six people have died in Rwanda's first-ever outbreak of the deadly Marburg virus. Sabin Nsanzimana, the country's health minister, confirmed that most of the victims were healthcare workers in a hospital intensive care unit.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At least six people have died in Rwanda's first-ever outbreak of the deadly Marburg virus. Sabin Nsanzimana, the country's health minister, <a href="https://africa.cgtn.com/six-dead-as-rwanda-battles-marburg-virus-outbreak/ ">confirmed</a> that most of the victims were healthcare workers in a hospital intensive care unit.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Twenty-six cases have been confirmed since Friday. Authorities are tracking around 300 people who may have been exposed to the virus, mostly in the capital city, Kigali. To curb its spread, the government is implementing measures such as contact tracing, quarantining affected individuals and launching public health awareness campaigns.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
<strong>What is the Marburg Virus?</strong></p>

<p>The Marburg virus is a highly infectious disease similar to Ebola. According to the World Health Organisation, the disease has a high fatality rate, ranging from 24 per cent to 88 per cent, depending on the outbreak and the healthcare response.</p>

<p>The virus was first identified in 1967. This outbreak, linked to African green monkeys imported from Uganda, occurred simultaneously in Marburg and Frankfurt in Germany and Belgrade in Serbia, leading to 31 infections and seven deaths at the time.<br />
<br />
<strong>How the virus spreads</strong></p>

<p>The primary carrier of the Marburg virus is the Egyptian rousette fruit bat, which can transmit the virus to humans. African green monkeys and pigs can also carry the virus.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The virus spreads between humans through contact with:</p>

<ul>
	<li>Bodily fluids (blood, saliva, vomit, etc)</li>
	<li>Contaminated bedding or surfaces</li>
	<li>Infected semen, which can remain infectious months after recovery</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Symptoms</strong><br />
<br />
Symptoms can start suddenly and include:</p>

<ul>
	<li>High fever</li>
	<li>Severe headaches</li>
	<li>Muscle pains</li>
</ul>

<p>After about three days, patients report severe symptoms such as:</p>

<ul>
	<li>Watery diarrhoea</li>
	<li>Stomach pain</li>
	<li>Vomiting</li>
	<li>Bleeding from various parts of the body</li>
</ul>

<p>According to the WHO, “The appearance of patients at this phase has been described as showing 'ghost-like' drawn features, deep-set eyes, expressionless faces and extreme lethargy.”<br />
<br />
Extreme blood loss and shock can result in death within eight to nine days after symptoms appear.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
<strong>Current control measures</strong><br />
<br />
Health authorities recommend:</p>

<ul>
	<li>Avoiding physical contact with the infected people</li>
	<li>Washing hands regularly with soap and water or using sanitiser</li>
	<li>Avoiding consumption of bushmeat or contact with pigs in outbreak areas</li>
</ul>

<p>The WHO is providing support to Rwanda in managing the outbreak. There are currently no specific treatments or vaccines, although supportive care, including fluid replacement and blood transfusions, may help manage symptoms. Researchers are developing various blood products, drug therapies, and immune treatments.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-06/h2ihbnsg_virus-generic_625x300_04_June_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The primary carrier of the Marburg virus is the Egyptian rousette fruit bat.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/over-13-000-immigrants-convicted-of-homicide-roaming-free-in-us-report-6681727]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Over 13,000 Immigrants Convicted Of Homicide Roaming Free In US: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/over-13-000-immigrants-convicted-of-homicide-roaming-free-in-us-report-6681727]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 12:40:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[More than 13,000 immigrants, convicted of homicide either in the United States or abroad, are currently living freely in America, according to the country's Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE).]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>More than 13,000 immigrants, convicted of homicide either in the United States or abroad, are currently living freely in America, according to the country's Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE). These individuals are not in ICE detention but part of the agency's “non-detained” docket, meaning they are known to ICE but are not currently prioritised for detention or cannot be located.</p>

<p>The revelation was made in response to a request from Republican Congressman Tony Gonzales of Texas in March, with the statistics collected as of July 21. Acting ICE Director P.J. Lechleitner provided the information as part of his response.</p>

<p>Sharing the information on X (formerly Twitter), Gonzales wrote, “As of July 21, 2024, there were 662,566 noncitizens with criminal histories on ICE's national docket—13,099 criminally convicted MURDERS! Americans deserve to be SAFE in our communities.”</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">As of July 21, 2024, there were 662,566 noncitizens with criminal histories on ICE's national docket—13,099 criminally convicted MURDERS!<br />
<br />
Americans deserve to be SAFE in our own communities. <a href="https://t.co/fIoCAduJ9M">pic.twitter.com/fIoCAduJ9M</a></p>
— Rep. Tony Gonzales (@RepTonyGonzales) <a href="https://twitter.com/RepTonyGonzales/status/1839699359010533680?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 27, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The timeline of when the first of the 13,000 individuals entered the US remains unclear. Two law enforcement officials with knowledge of the data explained that many of the immigrants, including those convicted of serious crimes, entered the country under previous administrations, including that of former President Donald Trump. These individuals are now awaiting immigration hearings but remain at large in the country, reported <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/investigations/13000-immigrants-convicted-homicide-living-freely-us-ice-data-rcna173125">NBC News</a>.</p>

<p>On Friday, during a campaign event in Michigan, the Republican nominee used the figures to criticise the Joe Biden administration's immigration policies, specifically calling out Vice President Kamala Harris. “These are hard, tough, vicious criminals that are free to roam in our country,” Trump said, adding, “I can finally look at them and say ‘I told you so,' to the fake news.”</p>

<p>While the White House has yet to respond to the numbers, one official noted the administration was caught off-guard by the timing of the disclosure. The figures shed light on the complex and often fragmented immigration enforcement system, where federal, state, and local authorities sometimes fail to coordinate effectively.</p>

<p>The NBC News report said that according to law enforcement sources, some of these individuals may have crossed the border and been released because the US Border Patrol lacked information on their criminal histories at the time. In many cases, the US is only notified of an immigrant's criminal conviction after they enter the country. Furthermore, migrants who have completed their prison sentences may be released by local or state authorities without ICE being informed, particularly in sanctuary cities, making it more difficult for the agency to locate and detain them.</p>

<p>The law enforcement officials told NBC News that ICE prioritises arresting migrants convicted of serious crimes, such as homicide but they also highlighted that the agency's limited resources pose challenges in tracking down and arresting all those on the list. ICE currently has over 7.5 million immigrants on its “non-detained” docket, meaning they have pending immigration cases but are not in custody.</p>

<p>Lechleitner told NBC News that despite these challenges, there has been an increase in cooperation from local jurisdictions, with some re-evaluating their sanctuary city policies amid rising concerns over migrant crime.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-08/1b5k69b8_us-border-agent_625x300_04_August_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[White House has yet to respond to the numbers.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/saudi-arabia-voices-great-concern-for-lebanon-amid-israeli-strikes-6682004]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Saudi Arabia Voices "Great Concern" For Lebanon Amid Israeli Strikes]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/saudi-arabia-voices-great-concern-for-lebanon-amid-israeli-strikes-6682004]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 12:25:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Saudi Arabia expressed its "great concern" at the conflict in Lebanon on Monday, calling for the country's "sovereignty and territorial integrity" to be respected.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Saudi Arabia expressed its "great concern" at the conflict in Lebanon on Monday, calling for the country's "sovereignty and territorial integrity" to be respected.</p>

<p>A foreign ministry statement said: "the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia is following with great concern the developments taking place in the Republic of Lebanon."</p>

<p>As the country's health ministry said more than a hundred people had been killed in Israel's strikes on targets across the country on Sunday, Riyadh stressed the need to respect Lebanon's sovereignty.</p>

<p>"The Kingdom calls on the international community to assume its responsibilities towards protecting regional peace and security to spare the region and its people the dangers and tragedies of wars," it added.</p>

<p>Israel has carried out several days of deadly strikes on targets in Lebanon, killing the leader of the Iran-backed Hezbollah group Hassan Nasrallah on Friday and other senior figures in the movement.</p>

<p>There have been growing calls internationally for restraint from Israel as it prepares for a possible ground offensive against Hezbollah in Lebanon, amid fears of all-out war in the Middle East.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/5dqbqth8_lebanon-afp-_625x300_30_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel has carried out several days of deadly strikes on targets in Lebanon (File).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-ukraine-war-over-650-000-russian-soldiers-killed-8-869-tanks-destroyed-in-ukraine-war-6681661]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ukraine Claims Over 650,000 Russian Soldiers Killed Since War Began In 2022]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-ukraine-war-over-650-000-russian-soldiers-killed-8-869-tanks-destroyed-in-ukraine-war-6681661]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 12:24:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russia has lost 651,810 troops since the onset of its full-scale invasion of Ukraine on February 24, 2022, the General Staff of Ukraine's Armed Forces said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russia has lost 651,810 troops since the onset of its full-scale invasion of Ukraine on February 24, 2022, the General Staff of Ukraine's Armed Forces said. This figure, released on September 29, includes 1,170 Russian casualties recorded in just one day.</p>

<p>In addition to troop casualties, <a href="https://www.facebook.com/GeneralStaff.ua/posts/pfbid0r4aNSzquVq6yvzhBtrd9NJtQeifM6kKgeGXzCcgxKUGEtxqbRqLFXadSAVAZGGq8l">the report</a> said Russia lost 8,869 tanks, 17,476 armoured fighting vehicles, and 25,495 vehicles and fuel tanks.</p>

<p>Other significant losses include 18,795 artillery systems, 1,204 multiple launch rocket systems, 962 air defence systems, 369 aeroplanes, 328 helicopters, 16,186 drones, 28 ships and boats and one submarine.</p>

<p>On the same day, at least 16 people were reported wounded due to a series of Russian strikes on Zaporizhzhia in southern Ukraine. The regional capital experienced multiple “massive aerial strikes” early in the morning, destroying a multi-storey building and several houses. Among the wounded were two children aged eight and 17, <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2024/sep/30/ukraine-war-briefing-zaporizhzhia-attacks-injured-russia ">The Guardian</a> reported.</p>

<p>In the neighbouring Donetsk region, three killings and additional injuries were reported following Russian attacks on Pokrovsk, a city in the throes of the ongoing assault. Ukrainian emergency services said they were working to rescue those trapped under rubble.</p>

<p>Regional officials noted the extensive damage caused by the strikes, with Governor Ivan Fedorov confirming that one of the train stations in Zaporizhzhya was also hit.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Andriy Yermak, head of Ukraine President Volodymyr Zelenskyy's office, condemned the attacks, accusing Russia of attempting to “terrorise” the civilian population. He reiterated calls for increased military support from Western allies, including advanced weaponry to intercept Russian missile strikes.</p>

<p>Denmark has pledged $194 million to support Ukraine's military, while Norway is considering border security measures.</p>

<p>Earlier, former US President <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-meets-ukraines-zelenskiy-vows-to-end-ukraine-war-quickly-6664967">Donald Trump met Ukrainian President</a> Volodymyr Zelensky at Trump Tower, stressing the need to end the war in Ukraine. Zelensky invited Trump to visit Ukraine, while the Republican presidential nominee claimed he could quickly resolve the conflict if re-elected.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-06/7e31dnr8_russia-tanks-ukraine-reuters_625x300_15_June_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Russia lost 8,869 tanks, 17,476 armoured fighting vehicles, and 25,495 vehicles and fuel tanks.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jeremy-allen-drunk-us-man-kills-friend-after-talks-over-quitting-alcohol-turns-violent-6681353]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Drunk US Man Kills Friend After Talks Over Quitting Alcohol Turn Violent]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jeremy-allen-drunk-us-man-kills-friend-after-talks-over-quitting-alcohol-turns-violent-6681353]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 10:34:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[After the attack, Allen texted a local handyman for cleanup assistance. However, the handyman discovered the bloodied body and instead contacted Southampton Town Police.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Long Island man is facing murder charges after allegedly killing his friend during an altercation in the Hamptons early Saturday morning. Jeremy Allen, 43, was arrested after police discovered the body of Christopher Hahn, 43, hidden under a tarp on Allen's back patio.<br />
<br />
According to authorities, the two drunken men were discussing their plans for a 12-step recovery programme when their conversation turned heated. Prosecutors said Allen beat Hahn for approximately six hours before ultimately stabbing him in the head and neck with a large knife.<br />
<br />
Suffolk County prosecutor Elena Tomaro described the attack as “brutal and heinous to watch”. Allen's lawyer reported that the two men were “pounding down drinks” before the violent altercation. Allen has a history of drunk driving offences dating back to 2007, raising concerns about his conduct.<br />
<br />
After the attack, Allen texted a local handyman for cleanup assistance. However, the handyman discovered the bloodied body and instead contacted Southampton Town Police. Southampton Town Police responded to the scene shortly before 10 am, where Christopher Hahn was pronounced dead.<br />
<br />
Jeremy Allen was taken into custody about an hour later and was arraigned on Sunday, where he was ordered to be held without bail. He also has a pending rape case in Southampton and is currently on probation for a 2022 drunken driving conviction in Ulster County.<br />
<br />
This incident follows another case in Ohio where a 40-year-old man was charged with murder after <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-man-stabs-mother-to-death-after-being-denied-overnight-stay-at-family-home-6318691">fatally stabbing his mother</a> during a heated argument. The incident occurred in Green Township when Kenneth Mortimer's mother refused his request to stay overnight at their family home.<br />
<br />
The confrontation escalated, leading Mortimer to get a knife from the kitchen and attack both his parents. Despite his mother's attempts to flee and call for help, she succumbed to her injuries, while Mortimer's father remained in serious condition at a hospital. The man fled the scene but was later apprehended by police.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/1neck6oo_us-police-generic_625x300_30_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Jeremy Allen beat Christopher Hahn for six hours before stabbing him (Representative)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bts-suga-fined-11-500-for-drunk-driving-on-e-scooter-6681290]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[BTS' Suga Fined $11,500 For Drunk Driving On E-Scooter]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bts-suga-fined-11-500-for-drunk-driving-on-e-scooter-6681290]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 10:22:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Suga rode the scooter and tripped when parking at night. He made an apology for the incident calling it "careless and wrong behaviour".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>K-pop star Suga, a member of the boy band supergroup BTS, has been fined 15 million won ($11,500) by a court for drunk driving while on an electric scooter. A judge at the Seoul Western District Court issued the fine in a summary judgment made last week after his case was referred to the prosecution, a court official said on Monday.</p>

<p>In August, the songwriter and rapper made an apology for the incident calling it "careless and wrong behaviour" with police also revoking his licence for riding the e-scooter while drunk.</p>

<p>Suga rode the scooter and tripped when parking at night, according to his label Big Hit Music, which is part of K-pop firm HYBE. The label also said he failed a breath test to measure his blood alcohol level conducted by police.</p>

<p>Since announcing a break from group projects in June 2022, BTS members pursued solo activities before starting military service.</p>

<p>The 31-year-old Suga has been engaged in social service work in order to meet his military duty commitment.</p>

<p>The drunk driving incident is the latest example of K-pop performers sometimes falling short of their squeaky-clean image.</p>

<p>The case prompted some BTS fans upset by his action to send flower wreaths near HYBE headquarters, with messages on boards asking him to leave the band.</p>

<p>Those notified of summary judgments can apply for a regular trial within seven days to challenge the decision.</p>

<p>Suga's label did not immediately respond to a request for comment.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/u7kaq89g_suga_625x300_30_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Police had revoked Suga's licence for riding the e-scooter while drunk (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-police-officer-sacked-for-spanking-12-year-old-girl-on-numerous-occasions-6681263]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK Police Officer Sacked For 'Spanking' 12-Year-Old Girl]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-police-officer-sacked-for-spanking-12-year-old-girl-on-numerous-occasions-6681263]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 10:20:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The child was known to Benson, and the incidents, which occurred while he was off duty, were found to have a sexual element, the force added.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Metropolitan Police officer has been sacked after a misconduct panel concluded he assaulted a 12-year-old girl by "spanking her bare bottom on multiple occasions." The panel found that Ross Benson had been accused of hitting the child between April and August 2018, according to the Met Police.</p>

<p>The child was known to Benson, and the incidents, which occurred while he was off duty, were found to have a sexual element, the force added.</p>

<p>Following the disciplinary hearing, Benson was dismissed without notice and placed on the College of Policing's barred list, the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cd6qgw97w92o" rel="nofollow, noindex"><em>BBC </em></a>reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Benson had served in the North West Basic Command Unit in London.</p>

<p>In November 2020, Bedfordshire Police arrested Benson on suspicion of sexual assault, but by September 2021, he was informed that no further action would be taken. Bedfordshire Police then referred the case to the Met's Directorate of Professional Standards, which launched a misconduct investigation. The investigation concluded on Friday, finding that Benson had committed gross misconduct by breaching the professional standards expected of police officers.</p>

<p>Detective Superintendent Will Lexton-Jones told the media outlet: "My thoughts are with the victim, who showed great courage in coming forward. PC Benson's appalling behaviour has resulted in his immediate dismissal, a decision I fully support. I hope this outcome sends a clear message that we are committed to removing those who fail to uphold the high standards expected of our officers."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/rn66qmio_metropolitan-police_625x300_30_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Benson had served in the North West Basic Command Unit in London.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/austrias-far-right-unsure-about-forming-government-despite-historic-victory-6681224]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Austria's Far-Right Unsure About Forming Government Despite Historic Victory]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/austrias-far-right-unsure-about-forming-government-despite-historic-victory-6681224]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 10:10:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[As jubilant Austrian far-right supporters celebrated their party's historic win in Sunday's national elections with beers, they knew forming a government would not be easy.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As jubilant Austrian far-right supporters celebrated their party's historic win in Sunday's national elections with beers, they knew forming a government would not be easy.</p>

<p>"It's a real success... (but) I predict that no matter who forms the government, we will certainly not have one before Christmas," Erik Berglund, a 35-year-old waiter, told AFP.</p>

<p>Led by sharp-tongued Herbert Kickl since 2021, the far-right Freedom Party (FPOe) had been tipped to narrowly beat the ruling conservatives but Sunday's results -- with the party getting around 29 per cent -- were even slightly better than expected.</p>

<p>Like other party supporters around him in traditional Austrian dress, Berglund credited Kickl as the "most competent leader".</p>

<p>But he said it would now be up to the other parties to decide if the FPOe head can become chancellor.</p>

<p>"It will certainly be a very, very exciting time," he added as electric blue light -- the FPOe colour -- illuminated the restaurant in downtown Vienna where the party was celebrating.</p>

<h3><strong>'Mountain climber'</strong></h3>

<p>Chancellor Karl Nehammer, whose conservatives came second in the elections, has already said he would not form a coalition government with Kickl. Other party leaders have also rejected him.</p>

<p>"I am a mountain climber, but the bag that I have been given is not light," the sporty Kickl told his cheering supporters.</p>

<p>As supporters watched the vote night unfold on private television rather than public broadcaster ORF, which the FPOe has accused of being biased, they booed whenever other parties' representatives appeared onscreen.</p>

<p>Hilmar Kabas, an FPOe member since the 1960s, said other parties' "weakness" was the main reason that propelled the far right to victory.</p>

<p>But supporters wearing "Team Kickl" parkas also rattle off other reasons, such as asylum seeker applications deemed too many, a slumping economy and the high cost of living that has seen far-right parties across Europe gain ground.</p>

<p>But if no one is willing to form a coalition under Kickl, it's better to stay in the opposition, Kabas said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"It is not the other parties that decide for us," he added.</p>

<h3><strong>'Beacon in our night'&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>A loden-clothed activist from the far-right Alternative for Germany (AfD) party was also among the crowd, having come specially from Bavaria state in neighbouring Germany to celebrate with his "friends".</p>

<p>"Germany is looking toward Vienna tonight," he said, declining to give his name.</p>

<p>With him, he brought a gift for Kickl: a small blue lighthouse engraved with his name because "he is a beacon in our night".</p>

<p>Outgoing lawmaker Petra Steger said President Alexander Van der Bellen must now give the mandate to Kickl to form a government "respecting the voters".</p>

<p>"That's how it works in a democracy," she said.</p>

<p>Having expressed reservations about Kickl a few months ago, Van der Bellen promised after the results were announced he would make sure a government is formed that respects the "foundations of our liberal democracy".</p>

<p>Not far from the FPOe celebration, in front of parliament, a few hundred people gathered to say "no to Kickl", leader of a party formed by former Nazis.</p>

<p>"Nazis out", they chanted.</p>

<p>"Unfortunately, it was to be expected that the FPOe would be in the lead, but it is quite sad (to have this result), because somehow we have learned nothing from history," Juliana Hofmann, a 19-year-old student, told AFP.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/7pamq2v8_herbert-kickl_625x300_30_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The far-right Freedom Party in Austria is led by the sharp-tongued Herbert Kickl since 2021.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hurricane-helene-rips-through-florida-town-people-left-to-start-from-scratch-6681187]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["We've Been Wiped Off Map": Hurricane Helene Leaves Florida Town In Ruins]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hurricane-helene-rips-through-florida-town-people-left-to-start-from-scratch-6681187]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 10:03:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A small town in Florida has been devastated by Hurricane Helene, leaving homes and businesses destroyed.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The tiny town of Steinhatchee on Florida's Gulf Coast has been left in ruins after Hurricane Helene unleashed winds of up to 140 mph (around 225 km) and a 10-foot storm surge earlier this week. Most of the town's 500 residents were evacuated before the storm, only to return to a scene of devastation.</p>

<p>“It's heartbreaking. We've been wiped off the map. There's nothing left. I have some insurance but now I have to rebuild,” Donna Landon told The New York Post. Ms Landon's mobile home on the outskirts of Steinhatchee was destroyed.</p>

<p>Few structures remain in the town, about 90 miles (around 145 km) southeast of Tallahassee, the state capital. Buildings that survived were badly damaged, making recovery an uphill battle for the close-knit community. “I don't think there's anyone who hasn't been touched by this. But this is a community where everyone looks out for each other,” Ms Landon added.<br />
<br />
On Friday, electrical crews from neighbouring states arrived in Steinhatchee, working to repair the town's power grid. However, the restoration of electricity is expected to take considerable time. “It's going to take weeks to fix it. We're going to have to start from scratch,” said Russ Rhodes, part of a team working to replace a downed power line.<br />
<br />
One of the town's most loved establishments, Roy's Restaurant, located along the Steinhatchee River, was obliterated by the hurricane. The restaurant reopened nine months ago after suffering extensive damage from Hurricane Idalia. “Our employees are safe. The restaurant didn't fare as well. But that's all right. We're thinking of our community, our employees, and everyone who is affected out there. We love them,” the manager shared in a <a href="https://www.facebook.com/roys.steinhatchee/videos/1043112834274720/">Facebook Live message</a>.<br />
<br />
Despite the overwhelming loss, Roy's owner, Linda Wicker, has vowed to rebuild the 55-year-old restaurant. “I think we need to do that,” Wicker told the Palm Beach Post. While insurance will cover some of the damage, Wicker noted, “It's never enough,” as she reflected on the future of her business and its 30 employees.<br />
<br />
Steinhatchee is just one of many coastal communities in Florida dealing with the severe impact of Hurricane Helene, a Category 4 storm that has claimed at least 45 lives as of September 28.<br />
<br />
In the nearby town of Perry, around 7,000 residents are assessing the destruction, reported The New York Post. Roads are blocked by fallen trees, electrical poles have snapped in half, and many buildings have lost their roofs. The town is currently without electricity or running water, further complicating recovery efforts.<br />
<br />
“I've been in Florida all my life. My entire life, and it's never been this bad. But I'm still alive and everyone I love is still alive, so I'm grateful to God for sparing us,” The New York Post quoted 80-year-old Perry resident Nancy Belleville as saying.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/lf0bcrd8_hurricane-helene-afp-_625x300_30_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Buildings that survived were badly damaged due to the storm.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-urges-violent-police-crackdown-calls-kamala-harris-mentally-impaired-6681078]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Urges "Violent" Police Crackdown, Calls Harris "Mentally Impaired"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-urges-violent-police-crackdown-calls-kamala-harris-mentally-impaired-6681078]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 09:44:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump on Sunday used a speech in key swing state Pennsylvania to urge a "violent" police crackdown on crime in the United States, while his White House rival Kamala Harris emphasized the need for immigration reform at a rally in Nevada.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump on Sunday used a speech in key swing state Pennsylvania to urge a "violent" police crackdown on crime in the United States, while his White House rival Kamala Harris emphasized the need for immigration reform at a rally in Nevada.</p>

<p>Pennsylvania is considered the most important of the seven toss-up states that will likely decide the November 5 presidential election, but Nevada is also one of the key battlegrounds.</p>

<p>The Republican former president and current candidate, who held a similar rally in swing state Wisconsin on Saturday, reprised his dark, racially charged message about an America crumbling under "invasion" by violent migrants and other criminals.</p>

<p>Recounting isolated -- but widely publicized -- incidents of thieves staging brazen daylight robberies of shops in major cities, Trump got a loud cheer when he said police should become "extraordinarily rough."</p>

<p>Criminals, he said, "have to be taught" and this could be done "if you had one really violent day."</p>

<p>"One rough hour -- and I mean real rough -- the word would get out and it would end immediately," Trump said.</p>

<p>"The police aren't allowed to do their job" because "the liberal left won't let them."</p>

<p>Harris, the vice president and Democratic candidate, addressed the "serious problems" of border security at a rally in Las Vegas later in the day, where she reeled off her usual stump speech, emphasizing the economy, health care and the need for immigration reform.</p>

<p>"As president, I will double the resources for the Department of Justice to go after the transnational cartels," Harris said.</p>

<p>"We know Donald Trump won't solve them. When he was president, he did nothing to fix our immigration system," she added, calling for comprehensive reform but without offering details.</p>

<p>As on Saturday in Wisconsin, Trump spent much of his speech painting a picture of a failing United States, inundated by what he said was the "massive number of savage criminal aliens that Kamala Harris has allowed to invade."</p>

<p>He claimed "terrorists are pouring into our country" and cited "a big prison in the Congo, in Africa," as the source of "a lot of people" last week.</p>

<h3><strong>Insults</strong></h3>

<p>Anti-immigrant sentiment has been at the core of Trump's appeal in economically depressed, majority-white parts of the country ever since his 2016 presidential victory, but the rhetoric is turning ever more extreme as election day nears.</p>

<p>Following record numbers of illegal border crossings earlier in President Joe Biden's administration, a tightening of rules -- to the consternation of immigrant rights and civil liberties groups -- led to a plunge in numbers this year.</p>

<p>Crime, including murder, is also in steep decline nationwide, the FBI says.</p>

<p>Trump has long prided himself on his ability to coin insulting nicknames or slurs for his opponents and on Sunday, he repeated one that he aired on Saturday, calling Harris -- a former top California prosecutor and US senator -- "mentally impaired."</p>

<p>"Crooked Joe Biden became mentally impaired. Sad. But lying Kamala Harris, honestly, I believe she was born that way," Trump said to loud laughter from the crowd.</p>

<p>Harris did not address Trump's comments during her rally in Vegas, instead focusing on her usual bread-and-butter issues -- protecting access to abortion services and putting more money in the pockets of everyday Americans.</p>

<p>"When Congress passes a bill to restore reproductive freedom, as president of the United States, I will proudly sign it into law," she told supporters.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/gfbm3a8_donald-trump-reuters_625x300_27_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Anti-immigrant sentiment has been at the core of Donald Trump's appeal (file).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israels-bombing-campaign-in-lebanon-an-analysis-through-satellite-data-6681030]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel's Bombing Campaign In Lebanon - An Analysis Through Satellite Data]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israels-bombing-campaign-in-lebanon-an-analysis-through-satellite-data-6681030]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 09:34:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hezbollah, a Lebanon-based Shia militant group has lost its chief in Israeli air strikes in the capital Beirut. The Israel Defence Forces have moved the conflict north and have vowed to uproot Hezbollah's political and military arsenal.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hezbollah, a Lebanon-based Shia militant group has lost its chief in Israeli air strikes in the capital Beirut. The Israel Defence Forces have moved the conflict north and have vowed to uproot Hezbollah's political and military arsenal. In the last few weeks intense cross-border shelling and rocket attacks have been witnessed with no sign of a descalation.</p>

<p>Since the pager and walkie-talkie explosions across Lebanon which killed over 30 and injured thousands, the war between Hezbollah and Israel has intensified, with the former calling it a "massacre". Since Israel invaded Gaza last year to destroy Hamas, Hezbollah has been targeting northern Israel which led to a mass displacement of over 70,000 people due to frequent rocket attacks.</p>

<h3><strong>'Settling Scores'</strong></h3>

<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said they have "settled the score" after killing Hezbollah General Secretary Hassan Nasrallah in an air strike. This came after a week-long aerial bombing campaign carried out by IDF across Lebanon. The heat signature detected by NASA's Visible Infrared Imaging Radiometer Suite (VIIRS) instrument explains the extent of attacks.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="NASA Active Fire Map for the last seven days" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/ibfpm4q_nasa-active-fire-data_625x300_30_September_24.jpg?im=FitAndFill,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="NASA Active Fire Map for the last seven days" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><em>NASA's Active Fire Map for the last seven days</em></p>
</div>

<p>Pink indicates the urban settlement and the red dots show the region's active fire data for the last seven days. This is more likely a result of Israeli air strikes and artillery bombing. The data processed by VIIRS shows how Israeli raids were focused more on southern Lebanon, where it believed most of the Hezbollah cadre was stationed.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="NASAs Active Fire Data for the last three days" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/c7ooic18_nasa-active-fire-data_625x300_30_September_24.jpg?im=FitAndFill,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="NASAs Active Fire Data for the last three days" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><em>NASA's Active Fire Data for the last three days</em></p>
</div>

<p>The bombing campaign over the weekend also included the capital Beirut, where Hassan Nasrallah was killed along with Ali Karaki, the southern front commander of Lebanon and 19 other Hezbollah members. On its east bordering Syria, the campaign was primarily aimed at blocking the supply of weapons from Syria - A state which has an ongoing conflict with Israel and is backed by Iran.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The border between Syria and Lebanon acts as the supply line for weapons and reportedly some manufacturing units are located in southern Lebanon, as claimed by IDF in a post on X after it carried out strikes east of Beqqa valley, south and north Lebanon.&nbsp;</p>

<p>When NASA's active fire data can be backed by the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://understandingwar.org/backgrounder/iran-update-september-29-2024" rel="no follow, no index">Institute for the Study of War</a> (ISW) analysis which geolocates the Israeli bombing campaign, suggesting that the heat signatures detected by VIIRS were indeed from the bombing campaign.&nbsp;</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="This is not exhaustive list of strikes. Israel has been conducted strikes daily on Lebanon." id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/6f7o1pmg_lebanon-explosions_625x300_30_September_24.jpeg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="This is not exhaustive list of strikes. Israel has been conducted strikes daily on Lebanon." /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><em>This is not an exhaustive list of strikes. Israel has been conducting strikes daily in Lebanon.</em></p>
</div>

<p>"We settled the score with the one responsible for the murder of countless Israelis and many citizens of other countries, including hundreds of Americans and dozens of French," Netanyahu said after it was confirmed that Nasrallah was dead. Meanwhile, Israeli military spokesman, Daniel Hagari, said "the world would be a safer place with him (Hasrallah)."&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to the IDF, it has eliminated most of the Hezbollah top cadre.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="The list has been compiled after claims made by IDF and data analysed by ISW" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/nii5v3eg_hezbollah-chain-of-command-list_625x300_30_September_24.jpg?im=FitAndFill,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="The list has been compiled after claims made by IDF and data analysed by ISW" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><em>The list has been compiled after claims made by IDF and data analysed by ISW</em></p>
</div>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hezbollah-war-hassan-nasrallah-as-hezbollah-recovers-nasrallahs-body-israeli-strikes-kill-105-in-lebanon-6680467">Over 1,000 people died in Lebanon</a> in the bombardment which began after the pager and walkie-talkie explosions across the country intended to disrupt the communication network of Hezbollah. Most of the deaths came last Monday, the deadliest day in Lebanon's history since the 1975-90 civil war.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Israel says that it warned the civilian population to evacuate the region before the bombing but almost every attack was directed toward urban settlements. IDF claims that Hezbollah is hiding weapons in populated areas, which act as a shield against attacks.</p>

<p>"For the last 20 years, Hezbollah built its terror network within population centres in Lebanon - primarily throughout southern Lebanon, an area that they turned almost entirely into a launch pad to attack Israel."</p>

<h3><strong>Iran Is Furious</strong></h3>

<p>Hezbollah is part of Iran's "Axis of Resistance" - a group of nations, and proxies - that came into existence after the Iranian revolution in 1979. This includes Syria, Houthi rebels in Yemen, Hamas, the Islamic Resistance in Iraq, Hezbollah and other Palestinian groups.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.dni.gov/nctc/groups/hizballah.html">Hezbollah has participated in the Lebanese Government </a>since 1992. In 2005, a UN Security Council resolution called for disarming militias in Lebanon, but Hezbollah has actively tried to justify the retention of arms by calling itself the defender against Israeli aggression. Since the war between Israel and Hezbollah in 2006, where the latter kidnapped two Israeli soldiers, it has sought to use the conflict to justify its move.</p>

<p>After the death of Nasrallah, Iran has lost an ally in the region that could wage war against Israel. The Hezbollah cadre remains but precision strikes came as a blow, especially after several reports suggest an Iranian spy colluded with Israel and gave coordinates for strikes against Nasrallah.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Iran also vowed to avenge the killing of Revolutionary Guards General Abbas Nilforoushan, who died alongside the Hezbollah leader.</p>

<p>Nasrallah's death came around two months after Palestinian group Hamas's political chief Ismail Haniyeh was killed in late July in Tehran where he had attended President Masoud Pezeshkian's inauguration.</p>

<p>Israel is fighting on two fronts - Gaza and Lebanon - while it has largely succeeded in destabilizing Hamas's chain of command, the cost of the war was borne by over 40,000 people who have died in a campaign that is in its eleventh month. A similar situation is unfolding in Lebanon.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Houthi rebels fired a rocket to express solidarity over Nasrallah's death. Late at night, Israel carried out air strikes in Yemen, killing four and injuring 33.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Iran - reeling from the economic impact of international sanctions - has managed to keep afloat its operations through proxies outside its territory but is treading with caution to avoid any major US response.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Tehran-based international relations professor <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/irans-serious-dilemma-after-hezbollah-chief-hassan-nasrallahs-killing-6678151">Mehdi Zakerian</a> said the Iran-aligned resistance front "was not only unable to contain Israel, it also suffered serious blows". "If the government wants to get involved in reconstructing Lebanon or re-equipping Hezbollah, it will aggravate Iran's economic crisis," he added.</p>

<p>Ali Vaez of the International Crisis Group says, &nbsp;Iran "has every interest in trying to preserve whatever remains of Hezbollah. Hezbollah is Iran's shield. I don't think Iranians would give up on almost 40 years of investment in this project overnight because a dozen people were eliminated."&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/nu1riq3o_hezbollahiran_625x300_25_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The bombing campaign over the weekend also included the capital Beirut.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/from-1982-to-2024-roots-of-israel-hezbollah-wars-explained-6680983]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[From 1982 to 2024: Roots Of Israel-Hezbollah Wars Explained]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/from-1982-to-2024-roots-of-israel-hezbollah-wars-explained-6680983]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 09:27:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel and Lebanon's Shiite Muslim movement Hezbollah, whose leader Hassan Nasrallah was killed in an Israeli air strike on a Beirut suburb, have been sworn enemies for decades.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel and Lebanon's Shiite Muslim movement Hezbollah, whose leader Hassan Nasrallah was killed in an Israeli air strike on a Beirut suburb, have been sworn enemies for decades.</p>

<p>Here is a history of their long conflict:</p>

<p><strong>1982: Israel invades Lebanon; the birth of Hezbollah</strong><br />
Hezbollah -- the "Party of God" -- was born in the wake of Israel's 1982 invasion of Lebanon in the country's eastern Bekaa area, and overseen by Iran's Revolutionary Guards Corps.</p>

<p>In 1985 Hezbollah emerged from the shadows, establishing its armed wing the Islamic Resistance in Lebanon as the spearhead in the fight against Israel.</p>

<p>It carries out suicide car bombings and human wave attacks in the south against Israeli forces and their ally the South Lebanon Army (SLA), a mostly Christian militia.</p>

<p><strong>1992: Nasrallah becomes the group's leader</strong><br />
In February 1992 an Israeli helicopter gunship attack kills Hezbollah secretary-general Sheikh Abbas al-Musawi.</p>

<p>Aged just 32, Hassan Nasrallah is elected his successor. His baptism of fire comes a year later when Hezbollah, the only group that refused to give up its weapons after Lebanon's 15-year civil war ended in 1990, battles a large-scale Israeli incursion dubbed "Operation Accountability".&nbsp;</p>

<p>The stature of the man considered at his death to be the most powerful in Lebanon begins to build.</p>

<p>It is enhanced even further in 1996.</p>

<p><strong>1996: 'Operation Grapes of Wrath'</strong><br />
On April 11, 1996, Israel launched "Operation Grapes of Wrath", raids aimed at breaking Hezbollah's military potential and halting the firing of rockets into northern Israel.</p>

<p>Over 17 days, Israeli forces launched 600 raids and fired 23,000 shells, killing 175 people in Lebanon, mostly civilians. More than 300,000 refugees flee their homes.</p>

<p>International calls for a ceasefire mount after artillery bombards a United Nations camp where fleeing civilians had sought shelter. More than 100 people are killed.</p>

<p>On April 26 an agreement is signed ending the Israeli operation.</p>

<p><strong>2000: Israel withdraws from Lebanon&nbsp;</strong><br />
Israel's army withdrew in May 2000 after its years-long occupation. The pull-out from its so-called "security" zone is intended to end a situation that had cost it 1,000 men.</p>

<p>Nasrallah will be seen as the architect of this climbdown, after a war of attrition by Hezbollah forces a change of heart among the Israeli population.</p>

<p>This pressure also led to the Israeli government accepting in 1998 a UN Security Council resolution demanding its immediate withdrawal from south Lebanon.</p>

<p><strong>2006: Israel-Hezbollah war</strong><br />
In 2006 Hezbollah seized two Israeli soldiers on the Israel-Lebanon border. Hezbollah says it wants to exchange the pair for prisoners held inside Israel, but the outcome is war.</p>

<p>The conflict lasts through July and August and causes 1,200 deaths in Lebanon, mostly civilians, and 160 in Israel, mostly military.</p>

<p>Israel is unable to vanquish Hezbollah, which paints the conflict as a victory.</p>

<p><strong>2023-2024: a new front opens up&nbsp;</strong><br />
When war began between Israel and Hamas after Palestinian militants in the Gaza Strip attacked southern Israel on October 7, Iran-backed Hezbollah forces in south Lebanon fired into Israel in support of Hamas.</p>

<p>After nearly a year of cross-border exchanges of fire, Israel on September 23 severely escalated deadly air strikes targeting Hezbollah in Lebanon.</p>

<p>Israel says it is acting to end attacks on it from south Lebanon.</p>

<p>Israel's military says it has killed most of Hezbollah's senior leadership. The Hezbollah chief is killed in an air strike on the group's southern Beirut bastion.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/rlioj0e_israel-hezbollah-getty_625x300_30_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel says it is acting to end attacks on it from south Lebanon.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/worlds-oldest-cheese-found-on-3600-year-old-chinese-mummies-6680893]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[World's Oldest Cheese Found On 3600-Year-Old Chinese Mummies]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/worlds-oldest-cheese-found-on-3600-year-old-chinese-mummies-6680893]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 09:02:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Bronze Age coffin was found during the excavation of the Xiaohe Cemetery in 2003.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When the 3,600-year-old coffin of a young woman was unearthed in northwestern China two decades ago, archaeologists uncovered a puzzling substance draped around her neck like jewellery. Remarkably, it turned out to be cheese; researchers now believe it's the oldest known cheese ever discovered, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.livescience.com/archaeology/mysterious-white-substance-smeared-on-3600-year-old-mummies-is-worlds-oldest-cheese" rel="nofollow, noindex"><em>Live Science </em></a>reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"While regular cheese is soft, this one has dried out, becoming dense, hard, and powdery," said Fu Qiaomei, a paleogeneticist at the Chinese Academy of Sciences in Beijing, and co-author of a study published Tuesday in <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(24)00899-7" rel="nofollow, noindex"><em>Cell</em></a>. In an interview with <em>NBC News</em>, Fu explained that DNA analysis of the cheese sheds light on the lives of the Xiaohe people- who lived in what is now Xinjiang- but also on the mammals they raised and the evolution of animal husbandry in East Asia.</p>

<p>The Bronze Age coffin was found during the excavation of the Xiaohe Cemetery in 2003. Thanks to the arid climate of the Tarim Basin desert, the woman's coffin was exceptionally well-preserved, as were her boots, hat, and the cheese that had adorned her body, Fu noted.</p>

<p>In ancient burial practices, significant items were often placed alongside the deceased. The discovery of kefir cheese near the woman suggests that cheese played a crucial role in their daily lives.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Cheese production has been recorded in history for millennia, with murals in ancient Egyptian tombs dating back to 2000 BC, and European cheese-making evidence going back 7,000 years. However, the Tarim Basin cheese samples are the oldest physical examples found to date.</p>

<p>Fu and her team collected samples from three tombs and analyzed the DNA, tracing the evolution of bacteria involved in cheese-making over thousands of years. The cheese was identified as kefir cheese, made from fermenting milk with kefir grains. Evidence of both goat and cow milk was found in the samples.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The study also highlights how the Xiaohe people, despite being genetically lactose intolerant, consumed dairy before the advent of pasteurization and refrigeration. Cheese production, which reduces lactose levels, allowed them to include dairy in their diet.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/ik5fd6n8_the-study-also-highlights-how-the-xiaohe-people_625x300_30_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The study also highlights how the Xiaohe people]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>