<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 17:15:27 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/as-iran-gets-new-president-masoud-pezeshkian-will-it-change-its-stance-on-nuclear-standoff-6067652]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[As Iran Gets New President, Will It Change Its Stance On Nuclear Standoff?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/as-iran-gets-new-president-masoud-pezeshkian-will-it-change-its-stance-on-nuclear-standoff-6067652]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 16:45:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The election of relative moderate Masoud Pezeshkian as Iran's president has lifted the hopes of Iranians yearning for social freedoms and better relations with the West, but few expect big policy changes.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The election of relative moderate Masoud Pezeshkian as Iran's president has lifted the hopes of Iranians yearning for social freedoms and better relations with the West, but few expect big policy changes.</p>

<p>Iran's ruling clerics' political fortunes' rely on tackling economic hardship, so Pezeshkian may have a comparatively strong hand to revive the economy, but his scope to permit social freedoms will be limited, insiders and analysts said.</p>

<p>Under Iran's dual system of clerical and republican rule, the president cannot usher in any major policy shift on Iran's nuclear programme or foreign policy, since Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei calls all the shots on top state matters.</p>

<p>However, the president can influence the tone of policy and he will be closely involved in selecting the successor to Khamenei, now 85.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Hardliners, entrenched in institutions Khamenei controls such as the judiciary, armed forces and the media, have in the past blocked either the new opening to the West or domestic liberalisation.</p>

<p>Khamenei has set out guidelines he would like to see in the new government by counselling Pezeshkian to continue the policies of hardline President Ebrahim Raisi, who was killed in a helicopter crash in May.</p>

<p>"Pezeshkian self-identifies as a 'principlist' - someone committed to the ideological principles of the revolution - and has been clear about his devotion to the Revolutionary Guards and Khamenei," said Karim Sadjadpour, an associate at the Carnegie Endowment in Washington.</p>

<h3><strong>Will Iran Change Its Stance On The Nuclear Standoff?</strong></h3>

<p>Pezeshkian, a 69-year-old former heart surgeon, won Iran's run-off presidential vote last week and is yet to be sworn in.</p>

<p>He has pledged to promote a pragmatic foreign policy and ease tensions with the six major powers that have been involved in now-stalled nuclear talks to revive a 2015 nuclear pact.</p>

<p>Undoubtedly, analysts said, Pezeshkian's victory was a setback for hawks such as his rival, hardliner Saeed Jalili, who opposed any opening to the West and revival of the nuclear pact.</p>

<p>Jalili's supporters have criticised a hardline watchdog body for allowing Pezeshkian to run, with insiders suggesting that this decision was made by Khamenei to secure a high turnout amid consistently low participation in elections since 2020.</p>

<p>Pezeshkian hopes that revived talks with the West would lead to a lifting of tough U.S. sanctions, given growing popular discontent over economic hardships.</p>

<p>However, White House spokesperson John Kirby said on Monday the United States was not ready to resume nuclear talks with Iran under the new president.</p>

<p>For Pezeshkian the stakes are high. The president could become politically vulnerable if he fails to revive the pact, which then-U.S. President Donald Trump ditched in 2018 and reimposed harsh sanctions on Iran.</p>

<p>"He has a difficult path ahead ... Pezeshkian's inability to revive the pact will weaken the president and also lead to a backlash against the pro-reform camp who backed him," said a senior reformist former official.</p>

<p>A restoration of ties with the United States, which Iran's rulers have called the "Great Satan" since taking power in a 1979 revolution, remains out of the question.</p>

<h3><strong>Will The Economy See A Boom?</strong></h3>

<p>As the economy remains the Achilles heel for Khamenei, breaking free of the crippling U.S. sanctions, which have cost Iran billions of dollars in income from oil, will remain the top economic goal for Pezeshkian.</p>

<p>Spiralling prices and constricted spending power have left millions of Iranians struggling against a combination of sanctions and mismanagement.</p>

<p>Khamenei knows the economic struggle is a persistent challenge for the ruling clerics, who fear a revival of protests that have erupted since 2017 among lower- and middle-income people angry at enduring hardship.</p>

<p>"Failure to improve the economy will lead to street protests, particularly now that people have high hopes because of Pezeshkian's campaign promises," said an insider who is close to Khamenei.</p>

<p>Iran's economic outlook looks ever more uncertain, analysts say, with the possible return of Trump as U.S. president considered likely to lead to tougher enforcement of oil sanctions.</p>

<h3><strong>Will Strict Social Restrictions Change?</strong></h3>

<p>Pezeshkian enjoys an insider status and close relationship with the theocratic Khamenei, and may be able to build bridges between factions to yield moderation, but this would not enable him to bring about the fundamental changes that many pro-reform Iranians demand.</p>

<p>Pezeshkian, analysts said, is highly likely to end up in a similar position to his predecessors - reformist President Mohammad Khatami and pragmatist Hassan Rouhani - who whetted Iranians' appetite for change but ultimately were blocked by hardliners in the dominant elite of clerics and the powerful Revolutionary Guards.</p>

<p>"Pezeshkian is neither a reformist nor a moderate ... As a foot soldier of Khamanei, Pezeshkian will be subjected to his wishes which clearly has been to rule by violence and repression," said Hadi Ghaemi, executive director of New York-based advocacy group the Centre for Human Rights in Iran (CHRI).</p>

<p>As a lawmaker in 2022, Pezeshkian criticised the establishment over the death in custody of young Iranian woman Mahsa Amini, which triggered months of unrest in Iran.</p>

<h3><strong>Will Iran Change Its Regional Policy?</strong></h3>

<p>Unlikely. The top authority in regional policy is not the president, but the Guards, who answer only to Khamenei.</p>

<p>Pezeshkian is taking office at a time of escalating Middle East tensions over the Israel-Hamas war in Gaza and Hezbollah in Lebanon.</p>

<p>Signalling no change in Iran's regional policies, Pezeshkian reaffirmed on Monday Iran's anti-Israel stance and its support for resistance movements across the region</p>

<p>"Supporting the resistance of the people in the region against the illegitimate Zionist regime (Israel) is rooted in the fundamental policies of the Islamic Republic," Pezeshkian said in a message to the Hezbollah leader Hassan Nasrallah.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/aslhaiv8_masoud-pezeshkian_625x300_09_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Masoud Pezeshkian, 69-year-old, is former heart surgeon]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/brain-eating-amoeba-kills-israeli-man-25-after-he-went-swimming-on-beach-6067544]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Brain-Eating Amoeba Kills Israeli Man, 25, After He Went Swimming On Beach]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/brain-eating-amoeba-kills-israeli-man-25-after-he-went-swimming-on-beach-6067544]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 16:31:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Israeli man is thought to have potentially come into contact with the amoeba while swimming at Gai Beach on the shores of the Kinneret in northern Israel.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 25-year-old man has died after being infected with 'brain-eating amoeba', likely during a swim at a popular beach in Israel. According to <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.timesofisrael.com/man-dies-after-contracting-brain-eating-amoeba-in-israels-2nd-ever-recorded-case/">Times Of Israel,</a></em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.timesofisrael.com/man-dies-after-contracting-brain-eating-amoeba-in-israels-2nd-ever-recorded-case/">&nbsp;</a>the&nbsp;Israeli man, who officials have not publicly named, is thought to have potentially come into contact with the amoeba while swimming at Gai Beach on the shores of the Kinneret in northern Israel.</p>

<p>The man, without underlying health conditions, was initially admitted to Sharon Hospital last Tuesday after presenting with symptoms including fever, headaches, and vomiting. After his condition worsened, he was transferred to Beilinson Hospital in Petah Tikvah. Despite the best treatments, he died on Sunday.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The hospital said, ''Medical teams used everything at their disposal, including drug treatments and surgical interventions to save the patient's life, but his condition continued to deteriorate.''</p>

<p>Notably, this is the second-ever case recorded in Israel. A&nbsp; healthy 36-year-old man from northern Israel died of severe brain inflammation after contracting the amoeba in August 2022.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In India, the&nbsp;rare brain infection has claimed three lives. Last week, a&nbsp;14-year-old boy in Kerala died from the infection he contracted while swimming in contaminated water.&nbsp;The first instance was the death of a five-year-old girl from Malappuram on May 21 and the second was a 13-year-old girl from Kannur who died on June 25.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><b>What is Naegleria&nbsp;fowleri, the brain-eating amoeba?</b></h2>

<p>The&nbsp;<em>Naegleria fowleri</em>&nbsp;amoeba, commonly described as brain-eating amoeba because it destroys brain tissue, is typically found in bodies of warm freshwater such as lakes, rivers, or hot springs, and more rarely in poorly maintained under-chlorinated swimming pools.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Swimming or diving in water containing this amoeba can enter their bodies through the nose. Once in the nasal passages, Naegleria&nbsp;fowleri&nbsp;can travel to the brain, resulting in inflammation of the brain tissue and&nbsp;causing a severe infection called primary amebic meningoencephalitis (PAM), as per the&nbsp;<a href="http://%20https//my.clevelandclinic.org/health/diseases/24485-brain-eating-amoeba">Cleveland Clinic</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Symptoms can include headaches, fever, nausea, and vomiting, and the illness "usually leads to coma and death after 5 days," according to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.&nbsp;Other symptoms can include a stiff neck, confusion, lack of attention to people and surroundings, loss of balance, and hallucinations.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The mortality rate from encephalitis caused by the amoeba is extremely high, and while infection is extremely rare, it is often fatal. The US Centres for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) states that most people with PAM die within 1 to 18 days after symptoms start to appear.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Scientists have not found any effective treatments for PAM yet. Currently, doctors have been managing the disease with a combination of drugs.&nbsp;Only some 400 cases have ever been diagnosed worldwide.</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-09/p66hm678_braineating-amoeba-generic_625x300_29_September_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Naegleria fowleri amoeba is typically found in lakes, rivers, or hot springs]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-how-this-year-of-elections-is-going-to-reshape-global-politics-6067513]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: How This Year Of Elections Is Going To Reshape Global Politics]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-how-this-year-of-elections-is-going-to-reshape-global-politics-6067513]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 16:30:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Elections are taking place this year in countries home to almost half of the world's population, from Taiwan's general election in January to the U.S. presidential race in November.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Elections are taking place this year in countries home to almost half of the world's population, from Taiwan's general election in January to the U.S. presidential race in November.</p>

<p>The votes come amid growing economic and geopolitical strife, with the Ukraine war, conflicts in the Middle East and rising trade tensions between the United States and China, the world's two largest economies.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In some countries, there are concerns about the resilience of democracy itself as political discourse has polarized or been warped by disinformation. Many of this year's elections will not be free and fair - or their results will be disputed.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Half-way through the biggest year for elections in history, here are some common themes that have emerged in Reuters' reporting from around the world:</p>

<h3><strong>Cost Of Living</strong></h3>

<p>From the price of green onions in Indonesia to higher fuel bills across Europe, rises in the price of food, energy and other basics have hit the living standards of households across the world. Incumbent governments and leaders are paying for it.</p>

<p>Polling showed that cost of living concerns were a powerful factor in a fall in support for Prime Minister Narendra Modi's party in India, losses suffered by mainstream parties in June's European Parliament elections and the poll rout of Britain's ruling Conservatives.</p>

<p>In Africa, discontent over living standards and unemployment contributed to the ANC's loss of its majority in South Africa's election. Worsening poverty is likely to help shape the outcome of Ghana's December vote to succeed President Nana Akufo-Addo.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Polling ahead of the U.S. election suggests voters are similarly unimpressed with President Joe Biden's efforts to improve their livelihoods, with many Americans feeling their living standards are falling despite strong headline economic data. One outlier: In Mexico, the ruling MORENA party emerged the winner after offering ample subsidies to low-income voters.</p>

<p>While economic policymakers say there are signs that inflation is returning to normal, they warn it has not yet been fully tamed and many economies remain fragile.</p>

<p>"A number of pressure points could throw the global economy off track," Agustin Carstens, head of the central bank umbrella group the Bank of International Settlements (BIS), warned in June.</p>

<h3><strong>Green Transition</strong></h3>

<p>With the cost of living uppermost in many voters' minds, climate change action has often been crowded out of election campaigns - even as global temperatures break new records and death tolls from extreme heat climb.</p>

<p>While surveys show Europeans still support ambitious action on global warming, the debate there has focused on the perceived cost to livelihoods, with farming and other lobbies stepping up calls for an easing of net-zero policies.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In the EU elections, ecologist Greens shed most of the gains made five years earlier. In Britain, Labour dropped a 28-billion-pound green investment pledge ahead of the July 4 general election, saying the country could not afford it, while their Conservative rivals described themselves as "on the side of drivers", attacking low-traffic and low-emission schemes.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The biggest challenge to the green transition may come from the United States, with Donald Trump campaigning on policies supporting continued fossil fuel use. It remains to be seen how much of Biden's Inflation Reduction Act (IRA) green subsidies stay in place in the event of a Trump victory.</p>

<h3><strong>Swing To The (Far) Right?</strong></h3>

<p>The cost of living crisis has led to rising support for far-right movement in Western countries with a mix of anti-immigration and nationalist policies, often unfunded economic spending plans and populist rhetoric attacking global elites.</p>

<p>Back in March, Portugal's Chega party quadrupled its seats in parliament to become the country's third-largest party. Three months later, its far-right, eurosceptic peers across Europe made gains in elections to the European Parliament.</p>

<p>In France, Marine Le Pen's National Rally failed in elections on Sunday to achieve the majority they were coveting but became the largest single party in a hung parliament that now risks plunging Europe's second-largest economy into policy paralyis.</p>

<p>In Britain, the anti-immigrant, nationalist Reform Party won over four million votes, contributing to the collapse in support for the ruling Conservatives even if Britain's first-past-the-post electoral system meant it only won a handful of seats.</p>

<p>Austria's Sept. 29 election will be closely watched, with polls showing the far-right Freedom Party (FPO) leading rivals after it ranked first in European Parliament elections.</p>

<p>In the United States, Trump has made immigration one of his top domestic campaign issues, declaring he would carry out mass deportations, end birthright citizenship, and expand a travel ban on people from certain countries.</p>

<p>Mohit Kumar, chief economist for investment house Jefferies, noted that immigration as an election theme was hottest in precisely the large Western economies whose ageing populations were creating labour shortages.</p>

<p>"Economically we need immigration but the political dynamics are shifting away from immigration," he said.</p>

<h3><strong>Debt And Election Largesse</strong></h3>

<p>With economic hardship so prevalent, many politicians are offering to spend big and cut taxes in a bid to win power - at the risk of adding to global debt already at record levels after huge post-pandemic stimulus packages in rich-world economies.</p>

<p>Credit rating firm S&amp;P Global has warned the United States, France and other Group of Seven (G7) governments were unlikely to halt rises in their debt "at the present stage in their electoral cycles".&nbsp;</p>

<p>The BIS annual report in June said an election year like this brought an "especially high" risk of fiscal expansion that could complicate efforts to bring inflation down to target.</p>

<p>Budget watchdogs in Britain and France - two countries struggling to balance their budgets - noted that many spending pledges were either unfunded or unrealistically costed.</p>

<p>Trump has pledged to keep in place a broad 2017 tax cut that he signed while in office, and his economic team has discussed a further round of cuts beyond those enacted in his first term.</p>

<p>Biden, meanwhile, proposes raising levies on businesses and rich individuals, while vowing not to increase taxes for households earning less than $400,000 a year and to assist low- and middle-income Americans with childcare costs. U.S. federal government currently has more than $34 trillion in debt.</p>

<p>Such levels of debt are seen making the global economy more vulnerable to financial shocks and the International Monetary Fund has urged governments to reduce their borrowing.</p>

<p>"Unfortunately, fiscal plans so far are insufficient and could be derailed further given the record number of elections this year," its chief economist Pierre-Olivier Gourinchas said in a recent blog.</p>

<h3><strong>Defence And Security</strong></h3>

<p>As geopolitical tensions rise, defence and security matters have been prominent in a number of election campaigns so far this year - particularly in countries near the hotspots.</p>

<p>In February, Finland elected as president Alexander Stubb, who campaigned on the previously non-aligned country fully participating in NATO and allowing the transit of nuclear arms through it. Incumbents in Lithuania won an election dominated by concerns over Russia and calls for higher defence spending.</p>

<p>Taiwan's presidential and parliamentary elections on Jan. 13 focused around arguments on how best to deal with China, which views the island as its own territory. The ruling DPP party secured the presidency for a third term as its candidate vowed to safeguard Taiwan from intimidation while emphasising the need for dialogue with Beijing.</p>

<p>In the United States, Democratic voters' anger over Israel's military action in Gaza - and over Biden's continued support of Israel - has emerged as a major vulnerability for him. American views on the conflict have broken down along party lines with Republicans largely supporting Israel.</p>

<p>While Biden voices unwavering support for NATO, Trump has said that if he is returned to the White House, America would fundamentally rethink NATO's purpose. He has also asserted without evidence that if elected he would end the conflict in Ukraine before even taking office. On that, Biden has retorted that Trump has "no idea what he's talking about".</p>

<h3><strong>Democracy At Stake?</strong></h3>

<p>Pro-democracy watchdogs estimate that nearly three-quarters of the world's population live in autocracies. Observers and human rights groups have signalled concerns about the fairness of elections this year in Bangladesh, Azerbaijan, Belarus, Cambodia, Iran and Russia. Votes in Algeria and Uzbekistan face similar questions.</p>

<p>Modi's electoral setback has been hailed by some commentators as proof of the resilience of its democracy. There was relief at the peaceful handover of power in Senegal in March after moves by the incumbent to delay the vote triggered protests.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Democracy's biggest test this year may, however, be in Washington.</p>

<p>Trump refuses to commit to accepting the election results or to rule out possible violence around the Nov. 5 contest. He is already laying the groundwork to contest a potential defeat.</p>

<p>"We should be quite worried," Steven Levitsky, political scientist and professor of government at Harvard University, told a Brookings think tank event in June.</p>

<p>"A democracy cannot survive if one party in a two-party system is not committed to playing by the democratic rules of the game."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/g7qpj5u_election-generic_625x300_09_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Defence, security matters have been prominent in a number of election campaigns (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-modi-russia-visit-pm-hugs-putin-ukraine-president-volodymyr-zelenskyy-a-huge-disappointment-ukraine-president-reacts-to-pm-modi-putin-hug-6067174]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Huge Disappointment...": Ukraine President Reacts To PM Modi's Russia Visit]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-modi-russia-visit-pm-hugs-putin-ukraine-president-volodymyr-zelenskyy-a-huge-disappointment-ukraine-president-reacts-to-pm-modi-putin-hug-6067174]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 15:45:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ukraine President Volodymyr Zelenskyy has reacted sharply to Prime Minister Narendra Modi's brief visit to Russia and his interaction with Russian President Vladimir Putin.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ukraine President <a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/topic/volodymyr-zelenskyy" target="_blank">Volodymyr Zelenskyy</a> has reacted sharply to Prime Minister <a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/topic/pm-modi" target="_blank">Narendra Modi</a>'s brief visit to Russia and his interaction with Russian President <a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/topic/vladimir-putin" target="_blank">Vladimir Putin</a>.</p>

<p>In a post on X (formerly Twitter) Mr Zelenskyy referred to Russia's attack Monday - in which at least 37 people, including three children, were killed after a missile strike on a children's hospital in Kyiv.</p>

<p>The strike also damaged nearly 100 buildings, including schools and maternity hospitals.</p>

<p>His tweet included photographs of the bombed hospital and babies in ambulances.</p>

<p>Mr Zelenskky's post came after Prime Minister Modi met President Putin in Moscow and shared an embrace. Visuals from their meeting showed the two leaders drinking tea on a terrace at Mr Putin's home in Novo-Ogaryovo outside Moscow, and Mr Modi being driven around in a golf cart.</p>

<p>One photo in particular - of <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/topic/pm-modi-hugs-putin" target="_blank">Mr Modi and Mr Putin hugging</a> - has been widely shared online.</p>

<p><strong>READ |</strong>&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/pm-modi-hugs-putin-on-russia-visit-tea-meet-on-terrace-golf-cart-ride-6064443" target="_blank">PM Hugs Putin On Russia Visit, Tea Meet At Home, Golf Cart Ride</a></p>

<p>And the Ukraine President was particularly critical of that image, posting, "It is a huge disappointment and a devastating blow to peace efforts to see the leader of the world's largest democracy hug the world's most bloody criminal in Moscow on such a day..."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">In Ukraine today, 37 people were killed, three of whom were children, and 170 were injured, including 13 children, as a result of Russia's brutal missile strike.<br />
<br />
A Russian missile struck the largest children's hospital in Ukraine, targeting young cancer patients. Many were… <a href="https://t.co/V1k7PEz2rJ">pic.twitter.com/V1k7PEz2rJ</a></p>
— Volodymyr Zelenskyy / Володимир Зеленський (@ZelenskyyUa) <a href="https://twitter.com/ZelenskyyUa/status/1810437647581716707?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 8, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>PM Modi flew into Moscow on a two-day visit that treads a fine line between maintaining a longstanding relationship and courting closer ties with the West amid the war in Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>

<p>This is the Prime Minister's first visit since he was voted back to power last month.</p>

<p>It is also his first to Russia since the war in Ukraine began.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/pm-modis-advice-to-vladimir-putin-no-solution-can-be-found-on-the-battleground-6064774" target="_blank">At Modi-Putin Dinner, India's Direct Appeal To End Ukraine War</a></p>

<p>Sources have told NDTV that Mr Modi, during his meeting with Mr Putin, stressed no solution - to the violence - could be found on the battlefield. "India has always called for respecting the United Nations Charter, including territorial integrity and sovereignty. There is no solution on the battlefield. Dialogue and diplomacy is the way forward," Mr Modi is believed to have said.</p>

<p>Mr Modi has also spoken to Mr Zelenskyy on numerous occasions, including meeting him in Italy last month <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-narendra-modi-ukraine-president-volodymyr-zelensky-meet-on-sidelines-of-g7-summit-in-italy-5889246" target="_blank">on the sidelines of the G7 summit</a>. The two were photographed sharing a hug. Their first face-to-face meeting since the war started was in May last year, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/pm-modi-meets-ukraine-president-zelensky-for-the-first-time-since-russias-invasion-4051293" target="_blank">at the G7 summit hosted by Japan</a>.</p>

<p>In a phone call with President Zelenskyy in October 2022, PM Modi said there can be "no military solution" and that India is ready to contribute to any peace efforts</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/pm-modi-to-speak-with-ukraine-president-volodymyr-zelensky-today-government-sources-2807514" target="_blank">PM Speaks To Ukraine President, Call With Putin Later Today</a></p>

<p>Ever since the war began India has maintained it can only be resolved through dialogue and diplomacy, and the Prime Minister has said "India is ready to contribute to any peace efforts".</p>

<p><em>NDTV is now available on WhatsApp channels. <a href="https://www.whatsapp.com/channel/0029Va4lixw7z4kcvZI9JM12">Click on the link</a> to get all the latest updates from NDTV on your chat. </em></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-02/3n4vdap8_ukraine-president-volodymyr-zelenskyy-afp_625x300_25_February_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Ukraine President Volodymyr Zelenskyy (File).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/watch-major-bridge-in-new-york-stuck-open-due-to-extreme-heat-6067151]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Watch: Major Bridge In New York Stuck Open After Getting Too Hot]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/watch-major-bridge-in-new-york-stuck-open-due-to-extreme-heat-6067151]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 15:40:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[As a result, traffic was halted on the one-lane structure, leaving multiple vehicles without any option to cross into Manhattan.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A New York City bridge&nbsp;that connects Manhattan to the Bronx&nbsp;became stuck open on Monday afternoon after hot summer weather caused it to overheat. Notably, the Third Avenue Bridge, built in 1898, crosses the Harlem River and serves as the link between the two boroughs. On Monday, temperatures hit 35°C, reportedly resulting in the metal machinery to overheat and swell.</p>

<p>&nbsp;According to <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.foxnews.com/us/major-new-york-city-bridge-gets-unexpectedly-stuck-summer-temps-authorities-investigate">Fox News</a></em>,&nbsp;the metal on the 126-year-old bridge expanded due to extreme heat at about 3 p.m. and caused it to become stuck open.&nbsp;"[There was a] report of bridge stuck halfway open. Marine units standing by as well as land units,'' officials said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Crews on boats spent hours spraying water onto the bridge to cool the metal so they could realign it with the road deck. Aerial footage showed FDNY boats spraying water onto the span and bottom of the open bridge to cool it.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Watch the video here:</strong></p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Third Avenue Bridge Closed in All Directions Due to Overheating Equipment, Causing it to Become Stuck in the Open Position <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/NewYork?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#NewYork</a> <a href="https://t.co/GLT89m7j7I">pic.twitter.com/GLT89m7j7I</a></p>
— William John (@Johnwilliam_123) <a href="https://twitter.com/Johnwilliam_123/status/1810615086484275333?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 9, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>As a result, traffic was halted on the one-lane structure, leaving multiple vehicles without any option to cross into Manhattan. The bridge reopened for vehicles in both directions around 6:40 p.m.&nbsp;Fortunately, no injuries were reported as a result of the incident.</p>

<p data-v-be063cea=""></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Update: The Third Avenue Bridge is now open for vehicles in both directions. <a href="https://t.co/QFLaIaPPKM">https://t.co/QFLaIaPPKM</a></p>
— NYPD NEWS (@NYPDnews) <a href="https://twitter.com/NYPDnews/status/1810444053189664915?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 8, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>This is New York's second heatwave this summer. As per <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://metro.co.uk/2024/07/09/new-york-city-bridge-stuck-open-due-weather-heat-advisory-effect-21189915/">Metro</a></em>, a&nbsp;heat advisory is currently in effect for Bronx, Brooklyn, Manhattan, Northern Queens, Staten Island, and Southern Queens Counties until 8 pm on Wednesday.</p>

<p></p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/e2qrp93_third-avenue-bridge_625x300_09_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The incident caused major traffic delays during one of the hottest days of the year in New York]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukraines-children-hospital-was-probably-directly-hit-by-russian-missile-un-6067064]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kyiv Children Hospital Was Probably Directly Hit By Russian Missile: UN]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukraines-children-hospital-was-probably-directly-hit-by-russian-missile-un-6067064]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 15:29:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United Nations on Tuesday said there was a "high likelihood" that the children's hospital in Kyiv suffered "a direct hit" from a Russian missile.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United Nations on Tuesday said there was a "high likelihood" that the children's hospital in Kyiv suffered "a direct hit" from a Russian missile.</p>

<p>Danielle Bell, head of the UN Human Rights Monitoring Mission in Ukraine, called Monday's strike "one of the most egregious attacks that we've seen since the onset of the full-scale invasion" in February 2022.</p>

<p>She was speaking after Russia attacked cities across Ukraine on Monday with a missile barrage that killed more than three dozen people and ripped open the Okhmatdyt children's hospital in Kyiv, sparking international outcry.</p>

<p>Dozens of volunteers including hospital staff and rescue workers dug through debris from the hospital in a desperate search for survivors after the rare day-time bombardment, AFP journalists on the scene saw.</p>

<p>Russia has denied that it was responsible for the hospital strike, claiming the extensive missile damage in Kyiv was caused by Ukrainian air defence systems.</p>

<p>But Bell told reporters in Geneva that video footage "shows the weapon directly impacting the hospital".</p>

<p>The Okhmatdyt paediatric hospital is a children's specialist facility where families from across the country bring their children for treatment of serious medical conditions, such as cancer and kidney disease, she said, speaking via video-link from Kyiv.</p>

<p>"Analysis of the video footage and assessment made at the incident site indicates a high likelihood that the children's hospital suffered a direct hit, rather than receiving damages due to an intercepted weapons system.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"This must be investigated," said Bell, who said her team and military experts had observed the damage at the hospital and spoken to staff, patients' parents and local residents.</p>

<p>She said that at the time of the attack, 670 child patients and more than a thousand medical staff were present.</p>

<p>Bell said Russia had likely fired from an aircraft a Kh-101 air-to-surface cruise missile armed with several hundred kilogrammes of explosives.</p>

<p>"The factors suggesting that it was a direct hit are based on video footage which shows the technical specification of the type of weapon that was used; it shows the weapon directly impacting the hospital, rather than being intercepted in the air," said Bell.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/r1gln45o_ukraine-children-hospital_625x300_09_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Russia has denied that it was responsible for the hospital strike]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ripcartoonnetwork-become-the-top-trend-is-the-channel-shutting-down-rumour-video-6067053]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: Why RIPCartoonNetwork Has Become The Top Trend]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ripcartoonnetwork-become-the-top-trend-is-the-channel-shutting-down-rumour-video-6067053]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 15:28:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A rumour that Cartoon Network is shutting down sent shockwaves across the Internet. So much so that the hashtag RIPCartoonNetwork became the top trend.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A rumour that Cartoon Network is shutting down sent shockwaves across the Internet. So much so that the hashtag RIPCartoonNetwork became the top trend.</p>

<p>The rumour started with a video posted on X (formerly Twitter) by the account "Animation Workers Ignited", which claimed that the channel was "dead". However, it has since been clarified that the channel is not actually shutting down.</p>

<h3><strong>Why is RIPCartoonNetwork trending?</strong></h3>

<p>The video was intended to bring attention to the struggles faced by the animation industry, which has been heavily impacted by the pandemic. Many workers have been left unemployed for over a year and the industry as a whole is struggling to recover.</p>

<p>The video sparked a widespread reaction, with fans expressing their support for the animation industry and its workers. The hashtag RIPCartoonNetwork was used to show solidarity and raise awareness about the issues faced by the industry.</p>

<p>The video talked about the harsh realities faced by animation workers in the wake of the Covid-19 pandemic. Despite the industry's ability to operate remotely and continue production uninterrupted, studios have been accused of cancelling projects, outsourcing jobs and laying off artists en masse.</p>

<p>The video claimed that big studios are driven by greed, cutting finances by reducing spending and staff, while CEOs and executives continue to reap benefits for themselves. The animation industry is "under attack," the video declared, urging fans to take a stand and show support for the affected artists.</p>

<p>The video called on fans to share their favourite Cartoon Network shows that were cancelled too soon, using the hashtag RIPCartoonNetwork.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Cartoon Network is dead?!?!<br />
<br />
Spread the word about what's at stake for animation!!! Post about your favorite Cartoon Network shows using <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/RIPCartoonNetwork?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#RIPCartoonNetwork</a><br />
<br />
Active members of TAG can help by filling out your survey! Today (7/8) is the last day! <a href="https://t.co/dHNMvA1q0A">pic.twitter.com/dHNMvA1q0A</a></p>
— Animation Workers Ignited (@AWorkersIgnited) <a href="https://twitter.com/AWorkersIgnited/status/1810440310838968397?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 8, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<h3><strong>Is Cartoon Network shutting down?</strong></h3>

<p>Cartoon Network is not shutting down, despite rumours. The channel is adapting to changes in the media landscape and has new programming in development, including spin-offs of popular shows.</p>

<p>New programmes are also in the works, including The Amazing World of Gumball: The Series premiering this year, and spin-offs of Adventure Time, Regular Show, and Foster's Home of Imaginary Friends in development.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-10/d9mn8pdo_cartoon-network-_625x300_14_October_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Cartoon Network is not shutting down, despite rumours]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explainer-why-democrats-are-urging-joe-biden-to-step-out-of-us-presidential-race-6066866]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explainer: Why Democrats Are Urging Biden To Step Out Of Presidential Race]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explainer-why-democrats-are-urging-joe-biden-to-step-out-of-us-presidential-race-6066866]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 14:56:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Citing concerns about his health and ability to take on Donald Trump, prominent House Democrats have doubted Joe Biden's fitness for office and his chances of winning in 2024.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Fifty-six years ago, a US President appeared on television and announced, to the nation's shock, that he'd not seek re-election. His name was Lyndon B. Johnson, the most recent US President to not run for his second elected term. The reasons were many and varied.</p>

<p>In November 1963, Johnson, the then US Vice-President, ascended to the top job following the assassination of then-President John F. Kennedy. A year later, he registered a landslide victory for Democrats in Presidential polls.</p>

<p>However, that changed after he presided over the deeply unpopular Vietnam War. Even though he was elected as the Democratic nominee in 1968, his health, plunging approval ratings and the way he handled the war -- all went against him. Johnson decided it was time for him to make way for someone else.</p>

<p>Fast-forward to 2024, another US President's reelection bid is in jeopardy. This time, it's Joe Biden faced with growing calls from within the party to drop out of the presidential race. Citing concerns about his health and ability to take on Donald Trump, prominent House Democrats have doubted Biden's fitness for office and his chances of winning in 2024.</p>

<p>Despite the mounting pressure, Biden remains defiant, insisting he will stay in the race. But will his determination be enough to overcome the rising dissent against his candidacy?</p>

<p>On Sunday, a group of <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/2024-election/four-democrats-congress-call-biden-step-2024-race-rcna160625">Democratic lawmakers</a>, including Reps Adam Smith, Jerry Nadler, Mark Takano and Joe Morelle, gathered to discuss their party's future. According to sources, they all agreed that President Biden should withdraw from the presidential race. This was also echoed publicly by Rep Adam Smith in a Monday interview with CNN, where he openly called for Biden to drop out.</p>

<p>Rep Angie Craig urged President Biden to <a href="http://https://www.forbes.com/sites/brianbushard/2024/07/05/biden-calls-debate-just-a-bad-episode-i-was-sick-in-abc-interview/ ">withdraw from the presidential race</a> following his interview with ABC News' George Stephanopoulos. Craig cited Biden's disappointing debate performance and his inability to deliver a strong response in the aftermath.</p>

<p>Reps Mike Quigley and Seth Moulton have joined the growing chorus of Democrats calling for President Biden to withdraw from the presidential race. In an interview with <a href="http://https://www.msnbc.com/all-in/watch/dem-rep-mike-quigley-calls-on-biden-to-step-aside-let-someone-else-do-this-214313029546 ">MSNBC</a>'s Chris Hayes, Quigley said that stepping down is the only way for Biden to secure his legacy and prevent a disastrous outcome.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Seth Moulton said he didn't have confidence in Biden's ability to defeat Donald Trump in November, urging him to "step aside and let new leaders rise" in an interview with Boston's <a href="http://https://www.wbur.org/news/2024/07/04/moulton-says-biden-drop-out-election ">WBUR</a>.</p>

<p>Reps Lloyd Doggett and Raul Grijalva were among the first sitting Democrats to urge President Biden to withdraw from the race. Doggett said he was disappointed that Biden failed to defend his accomplishments and expose Trump's lies during the debate, while Grijalva said it was Biden's "responsibility" to step down. Former Secretary of Housing and Urban Development Julian Castro also joined the calls for Biden to withdraw, suggesting Vice President Kamala Harris as a suitable replacement on the Democratic ticket.</p>

<p>President Biden's performance in the first debate was widely criticised, with many saying he appeared weak and disoriented. He struggled to speak clearly, fumbled, gave confusing answers and often looked lost. Even Trump's critics agreed that Biden's performance was disappointing.</p>

<p>In a speech in Raleigh, North Carolina, the day after the debate, Biden addressed the crowd saying he was not as spry as he used to be. "I don't walk as easy as I used to, I don't speak as smoothly as I used to, I don't debate as well as I used to,” he said. "I know what I do know, I know how to tell the truth!"</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/jdufu96_biden3_625x300_06_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/dog-turns-on-stove-in-us-house-apple-homepad-alerts-owners-of-fire-6066726]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Dog Turns On Stove In US House, Apple HomePad Alerts Owners Of Fire]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/dog-turns-on-stove-in-us-house-apple-homepad-alerts-owners-of-fire-6066726]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 14:38:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A pet dog's curiosity almost turned deadly for a family in the US after the family pet accidentally switched on the stove at night while its owners were asleep. The family was saved from disaster after their Apple HomePad sent them an alert.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A pet dog's curiosity almost turned deadly for a family in the US after the family pet accidentally switched on the stove at night while its owners were asleep. The family was saved from disaster after their Apple HomePad, a home assistant device, sent an alert notifying them of "high heat". The episode was caught on camera placed in the kitchen.</p>

<p>The incident occurred in US's Colorado last month at around 4:40 am. A CCTV video showed the dog pawing at the kitchen counter during which it turned on the stove.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The camera showed the dog on its hind legs and switching on the stove. Within moments, a few boxes kept on top of the stove caught fire, quickly setting fire to the kitchen. Another video showed the kitchen engulfed in flames and filled with smoke setting off the fire alarm.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">On Wednesday, June 26th at 4:43 a.m. CSFD was dispatched to a possible structure fire at a home on the 1600 block of Rushmore Dr. Homeowners reported to our call takers that they had experienced a fire on the stove in their home that had been extinguished by one of the… <a href="https://t.co/lohlgUvC2q">pic.twitter.com/lohlgUvC2q</a></p>
— CSFD PIO (@CSFDPIO) <a href="https://twitter.com/CSFDPIO/status/1808255474187526290?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 2, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p></p>

<p>At this moment, the Apple HomePad sent an alert to the owners who were awakened by the "high heat" notification. One of them put off the fire before the fire department arrived.&nbsp;</p>

<p>When the fire department officials arrived they saw the video recorded in the kitchen and shared it on social media. The video has over 13,000 views on X.</p>

<p>The owner was taken to a local hospital to get treated for smoke inhalation. No other injuries were reported.</p>

<p>“This is a good reminder to always have working smoke alarms inside and outside every sleeping area and on every floor of the home, ensure all combustibles are away from your stovetop/oven, and know two ways out of every room in your home in the event of a fire,” the fire department said in a post on X.</p>

<p>X users have slammed the owners for neglect after the incident arguing that flammable boxes should not have been put on top of the stove. Other warned that a similar incident involving a child could also have taken place.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/5rdb2ego_colorado-fire-dog_625x300_09_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The incident occurred in US's Colorado last month at around 4:40 am.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/haw-par-villa-park-singapores-hell-theme-park-dead-serious-about-afterlife-6066649]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Singapore's Hell Theme Park Dead Serious About Afterlife]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/haw-par-villa-park-singapores-hell-theme-park-dead-serious-about-afterlife-6066649]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 14:24:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Gory grottos with demons impaling sinners on stakes and people drowning in a pool of blood are not part of your average theme park experience.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Gory grottos with demons impaling sinners on stakes and people drowning in a pool of blood are not part of your average theme park experience.</p>

<p>But at Hell's Museum in Singapore, the main attraction at the Haw Par Villa park, visitors are welcomed to a kitschy, air-conditioned hell on Earth.</p>

<p>Inside the sprawling park complex with over 1,000 statues and dioramas showcasing Asian culture, faiths and philosophy, Hell's Museum exhibits various religious views on the afterlife.</p>

<p>Visitors are encouraged to learn about the 10 Courts of Hell through intense depictions of punishments for earthly sins.</p>

<p>At court number two, for instance, corruption gets you frozen in ice while rapists at court seven are thrown in boiling oil.</p>

<p>The 10 Courts of Hell are "the result of the mixing of four different religions and philosophies: Buddhism, Taoism, Hinduism, Confucianism", said Eisen Teo, the chief curator of Hell's Museum in the multicultural city-state.</p>

<p>"The sculptures and dioramas are a visual dissection of many classics, stories and moral values that many Singaporeans have and are familiar with," Teo said.</p>

<p>Visitor Gin Goldberg told AFP she wasn't so surprised to learn that many religions had differing opinions on the afterlife.</p>

<p>"One person's heaven would be another person's hell," the American said.</p>

<p><strong>Party in hell</strong></p>

<p>The odd park stands apart from gleaming Singapore's mainstream tourist attractions such as the luxury shops of Marina Bay Sands or the towering "supertrees" of Gardens by the Bay.</p>

<p>Haw Par Villa was built in 1937 by entrepreneur Aw Boon Haw, known for co-developing Asia's much-loved Tiger Balm pain relief rub.</p>

<p>While fondly remembered by older generations, the park has had trouble attracting the Gen Z crowd and younger millenials, according to Journeys, the firm that manages the park.</p>

<p>To broaden appeal, it has held several rave parties and other private events -- but not too near to religious exhibits.</p>

<p>"After they came here (for the parties) they fell in love with the quirky, eccentric park, with these cool sculptures. Fell in love with them and they keep doing repeat visits," said Savita Kashyap, Journeys' executive director.</p>

<p>While Haw Par Villa isn't just about the afterlife, and raves -- it also displays scenes from Chinese folklore such as "Romance of the Three Kingdoms" -- its hellish attraction remains the top draw.</p>

<p>But not for all.</p>

<p>One Filipina visitor told AFP while leaving that she won't be returning anytime soon.</p>

<p>"It's very scary," she said.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/fa0gpj5_haw-par-villa-singapore-afp_625x300_09_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Visitors are encouraged to learn about the 10 Courts of Hell through intense depictions of punishments.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/most-cancer-patients-die-of-cachexia-not-cancer-read-details-6063036]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Most Cancer Patients Die Of "Cachexia", Not Cancer: Read Details]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/most-cancer-patients-die-of-cachexia-not-cancer-read-details-6063036]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 13:48:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[When tumours in cancer patients elevate levels of an immune system molecule called Interleukin-6 (IL-6), it can cause severe brain dysfunction, which leads to a lethal wasting disease called 'cachexia' in about 50 to 80% cancer patients, a study said]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When tumours in cancer patients elevate levels of an immune system molecule called Interleukin-6 (IL-6), it can cause severe brain dysfunction, which leads to a lethal wasting disease called 'cachexia' in about 50 to 80 per cent of cancer patients, a new study said.</p>

<p>As per US-based Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory's (CSHL) Professor Bo Li, "It's a very severe syndrome".</p>

<p>"Most people with cancer die of 'cachexia' instead of cancer. And once the patient enters this stage, there's no way to go back because essentially there's no treatment," he said in a study published in the journal Nature Communications.</p>

<p>Li and other researchers in the team found that blocking 'IL-6' from binding to neurons in a part of the brain called the area postrema (AP) prevents cachexia in mice.</p>

<p>As a result, the mice live longer with healthier brain function.</p>

<p>"Future drugs targeting these neurons could help make cancer cachexia a treatable disease," the researchers suggested.</p>

<p>In healthy patients, 'IL-6' plays a vital role in natural immune response. The molecules circulate throughout the body. When they encounter a possible threat, they alert the brain to coordinate a response.</p>

<p>According to the researchers, cancer disrupts this process as too much IL-6 gets produced, and it begins binding to AP neurons in the brain.</p>

<p>"That leads to several consequences. One is animals and humans alike will stop eating. Another is to engage this response that leads to the wasting syndrome," Li said.</p>

<p>The team took a two-pronged approach to keeping elevated IL-6 out of the brain in mice. Their first strategy neutralised IL-6 with custom antibodies. The second used CRISPR to reduce the levels of IL-6 receptors in AP neurons. Both tactics produced the same results -- the mice started eating again, stopped losing weight, and lived longer, the study noted.</p>

<p>"The brain is so powerful in regulating the peripheral system. Simply changing a small number of neurons in the brain has a profound effect on whole-body physiology. I knew there was an interaction between tumours and brain function, but not to this extent," said Li.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-05/6tvmdl64_hospital-generic_625x300_20_May_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[What's 'cancer cachexia' syndrome, a disease behind most patients' death? (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/samsung-says-no-disruption-to-production-despite-workers-strike-6066401]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["No Disruption" To Production Despite Workers Strike: Samsung]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/samsung-says-no-disruption-to-production-despite-workers-strike-6066401]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 13:44:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[South Korean tech giant Samsung said Tuesday that production was not being disrupted despite a three-day general strike by thousands of workers.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>South Korean tech giant Samsung said Tuesday that production was not being disrupted despite a three-day general strike by thousands of workers.</p>

<p>More than 5,000 members of the National Samsung Electronic Union stopped working Monday, the organisation said, as part of a long-running battle over pay and benefits.</p>

<p>The union has more than 30,000 members -- more than a fifth of the company's total workforce.</p>

<p>"There has been no disruption to production," local media quoted Samsung as saying.</p>

<p>Park Seol, a senior member of the union, told AFP Tuesday that production was being affected.</p>

<p>"But more importantly, the company should understand that we aren't trying just to affect their production line, we want them to hear our voice and understand how desperate we are," he said.</p>

<p>The union has been locked in negotiations with management since January, but the two sides have failed to narrow differences on benefits and a 5.1 percent pay raise offer from the firm was rejected.</p>

<p>In a regulatory filing last week, Samsung Electronics said that its April-June operating profits were expected to rise to 10.4 trillion won ($7.54 billion), up 1,452.2 percent from 670 billion won a year earlier.</p>

<p>Sales, meanwhile, are expected to rise 23.3 percent to 74 trillion won, Samsung said.</p>

<p>Samsung Electronics is the world's largest memory chip maker and accounts for a significant chunk of the global output of high-end chips.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2018-11/e5sr0itg_samsung-generic_625x300_14_November_18.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The union has more than 30,000 members -- more than a fifth of the company's total workforce.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-cyclones-and-hurricanes-will-change-as-the-earth-warms-due-to-climate-change-6065176]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Climate Change: How Cyclones And Hurricanes Will Change As The Earth Warms]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-cyclones-and-hurricanes-will-change-as-the-earth-warms-due-to-climate-change-6065176]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 13:31:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[When Hurricane Beryl hit the Grenadine Islands on July 1, its 150-mph winds and awesome storm surge made it the earliest category 5 storm (the most destructive grade on the Saffir-Simpson hurricane wind scale) the tropical Atlantic has seen.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When Hurricane Beryl hit the Grenadine Islands on July 1, its 150-mph winds and awesome storm surge made it the earliest category 5 storm (the most destructive grade on the Saffir-Simpson hurricane wind scale) the tropical Atlantic has seen.</p>

<p>An active hurricane season in 2024 was forecast well in advance. However, the speed at which Beryl intensified, jumping from tropical-storm strength with winds averaging 70mph to major-hurricane status with 130mph winds in just 24 hours, astounded scientists.</p>

<p>“Beryl is a storm more typical of <a href="https://theconversation.com/hurricane-beryls-rapid-intensification-and-category-5-winds-are-alarming-heres-why-more-tropical-storms-are-exploding-in-strength-233780">the heart of hurricane season</a> than of June, and its rapid intensification and strength have likely been driven by unusually warm waters,” says Brian Tang, an associate professor of atmospheric science at the University at Albany, State University of New York.</p>

<p>As the world heats faster due to record fossil fuel emissions, research suggests that there are more unpleasant surprises to come.</p>

<p>In a narrow band of the mid-Atlantic Ocean where most hurricanes form, <a href="https://theconversation.com/the-worlds-fourth-mass-coral-bleaching-is-underway-but-well-connected-reefs-may-have-a-better-chance-to-recover-230755">sea surface temperatures are anomalously high</a>. In fact, the ocean's heat content – a measure of how much energy is contained in the surface water that hurricanes draw strength from – was close to its average for September on July 1.</p>

<p>Water accumulates heat slowly, so it is alarming to see ocean heat near its usual peak at the start of summer. If the tropical Atlantic is already producing such storms, what might the rest of the hurricane season hold?</p>

<h2>A bumper season</h2>

<p>“If the National Hurricane Center's early forecast, released May 23, is right, the North Atlantic could see 17 to 25 named storms, eight to 13 hurricanes, and four to seven major hurricanes by the end of November,” says Jhordanne Jones, a postdoctoral research fellow who studies how climate change affects the scientific effort to predict hurricanes at Purdue University.</p>

<p>“That's the <a href="https://theconversation.com/hurricane-forecast-points-to-a-dangerous-2024-atlantic-season-with-la-nina-and-a-persistently-warm-ocean-teaming-up-to-power-fierce-storms-228351">highest number of named storms</a> in any preseason forecast.”</p>

<p>Seawater hotter than 26°C (79°F) is the lifeblood of hurricanes. Warm, moist air is another prerequisite. But that's not all these monsters need to reach the limits of their savagery: consistent winds in the upper and lower atmosphere are also necessary to keep cyclonic storms spinning.</p>

<p>A shift from El Niño to La Niña – two opposite phases in a long-term temperature pattern in the Pacific – is expected later this summer. This could tamp down trade winds that might otherwise tear a hurricane's vortex apart. Jones says:</p>

<p>“La Niña may indicate an early start to the season as well as a longer season, as La Niña – along with a warm Atlantic – maintains a hurricane-friendly environment earlier and longer within the year.”</p>

<p>You might expect global heating to bring more hurricanes. But that's not what research has found so far, according to Ben Clarke (University of Oxford) and Friederike Otto (Imperial College London), two scientists who try to attribute the role of climate change in extreme weather events.</p>

<p>“Warm, moist air and high ocean temperatures are in ample supply in a rapidly warming world. Yet there is no evidence that hurricanes are happening more often, nor do scientists expect this to change with further climate change,” they say.</p>

<p>Instead, hurricanes that do occur are <a href="https://theconversation.com/hurricane-ian-how-climate-change-is-making-north-atlantic-tropical-storms-worse-191547">more likely to be major storms</a> like Beryl. Conditions for breeding hurricanes will be found further north and south of the equator too, since the ocean is heating rapidly everywhere. And Atlantic hurricanes may form outside of the season (June 1 to November 30) that people have come to expect them in.</p>

<p>“There is also evidence that they are moving more slowly, and are increasingly likely to completely stall near the coast, leading to more flooding as more rain is dumped over one place. This was one reason why Hurricane Harvey, which struck Texas and Louisiana in 2017, was so destructive,” Clarke and Otto say.</p>

<p>The trio of deadly hurricanes (Harvey, Irma and Maria) that hammered the Atlantic in quick succession that summer gave people little respite. These “storm clusters”, as climate adaptation researcher Anitha Karthik (Edinburgh Napier University) calls them, are <a href="https://theconversation.com/big-storm-clusters-are-on-the-increase-what-this-means-for-hurricane-hotspots-112584">a growing weather trend</a> that is making hurricane-prone areas increasingly inhospitable.</p>

<h2>Climate colonialism</h2>

<p>“When Hurricane Maria struck the eastern Caribbean island of Dominica in 2017, it caused the kind of devastation which is unthinkable to larger countries,” says Emily Wilkinson, an expert in climate resilience at the University of the West Indies.</p>

<p>“The category 5 hurricane damaged 98% of building roofs and caused US$1.2 billion (£950 million) in damage. Dominica effectively lost 226% of its GDP overnight.”</p>

<p>Vowing to become <a href="https://theconversation.com/how-a-small-caribbean-island-is-trying-to-become-hurricane-proof-217999">the first climate-resilient nation</a>, Dominica set about rebuilding homes, bridges and other infrastructure. Conserving the forests and reefs that buffer rain, wind and waves was a priority, Wilkinson says. But in trying to build a sustainable future from the wreckage of Maria, Dominica had to contend with its past as a European colony – a fate shared by many small-island states in the Caribbean and elsewhere.</p>

<p>“Across most Caribbean islands, hazard exposure is about the same, but research shows that poverty and social inequality <a href="https://theconversation.com/in-the-caribbean-colonialism-and-inequality-mean-hurricanes-hit-harder-84106">drastically magnify the severity of disasters</a>,” say Levi Gahman and Gabrielle Thongs, lecturers in geography, also at the University of the West Indies.</p>

<p>Dominica had a plantation economy imposed on it by the British that squandered the island's productive potential and funnelled its wealth overseas, Wilkinson says.</p>

<p>“Yet Dominica also has the Caribbean's largest remaining indigenous community, and the Kalinago people have farming practices that combine crop diversification with planting methods that help stabilise slopes,” she adds.</p>

<p>Climate-vulnerable states can draw from advantages such as these to navigate an uncertain future. But the experiences of Caribbean islands show how a supposedly historical process like colonialism still claims lives in the present.</p>

<p>Mounting storms will add greater urgency to demands for “climate reparations” to the formerly colonised world from rich countries that have contributed most to the climate problem.<!-- Below is The Conversation's page counter tag. Please DO NOT REMOVE. --><img alt="The Conversation" height="1" referrerpolicy="no-referrer-when-downgrade" src="https://counter.theconversation.com/content/233726/count.gif?distributor=republish-lightbox-basic" style="border: none !important; box-shadow: none !important; margin: 0 !important; max-height: 1px !important; max-width: 1px !important; min-height: 1px !important; min-width: 1px !important; opacity: 0 !important; outline: none !important; padding: 0 !important" width="1" /><!-- End of code. If you don't see any code above, please get new code from the Advanced tab after you click the republish button. The page counter does not collect any personal data. More info: https://theconversation.com/republishing-guidelines --></p>

<p><em><span>(<strong>Author:</strong> <a href="https://theconversation.com/uk/team#jack-marley">Jack Marley</a>, Environment + Energy Editor, <a href="http://www.theconversation.com/">The Conversation</a>)</span></em></p>

<p><em>This article is republished from <a href="https://theconversation.com">The Conversation</a> under a Creative Commons license. Read the <a href="https://theconversation.com/how-hurricanes-will-change-as-the-earth-warms-233726">original article</a>.</em><br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2017-05/cyclone-generic_650x400_71496034253.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Climate change leading to global warming will bring many more hurricanes. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/meet-the-democrats-who-may-take-joe-bidens-place-in-presidential-race-6066254]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Meet The Democrats Who May Take Joe Biden's Place In Presidential Race]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/meet-the-democrats-who-may-take-joe-bidens-place-in-presidential-race-6066254]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 13:27:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Not that there weren't enough questions already about an 81-year-old seeking re-election to the highest US office, but the first Presidential debate compelled Democrats to ask, "Does Joe Biden have what it takes to defeat Donald Trump again?"]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Not that there weren't enough questions already about an 81-year-old seeking re-election to the highest US office, but the first Presidential debate compelled Democrats to ask, "Does Joe Biden have what it takes to defeat Donald Trump again?"</p>

<p>The first Biden-Trump debate has only heightened concerns about the sitting US President's ability to grasp matters of national and international importance. While Biden stuttered and fumbled, Trump used every opportunity to underline why his Democratic counterpart wasn't up to the mark.</p>

<p>Although Biden has reaffirmed his commitment to staying in the race, Democrats are growing anxious about their chances. As Trump closes the gap, party leaders are starting to consider alternatives to Biden, should he decide to withdraw.</p>

<p><strong>Here are some possible candidates:</strong></p>

<p><strong>VP Kamala Harris</strong></p>

<p>Vice-President Kamala Harris is a clear choice to replace President Joe Biden on the Democratic ticket. As Biden's deputy, she has become the face of the administration's campaign to protect reproductive rights. Harris has proven to be a loyal ally to the president, and a fierce defender, admitting he had a "slow start" in the debate but arguing he provided more substantive answers than Trump. She has reiterated her support for Biden, stating "Joe Biden is our nominee. We beat Trump once and we're going to beat him again, period."</p>

<p><strong>Michigan Governor Gretchen Whitmer</strong></p>

<p>Michigan Governor Gretchen Whitmer is a rising star in the Democratic Party, with many speculating that she will make a bid for the presidency in 2028. A two-term governor, Whitmer has been a vocal supporter of President Biden and has expressed her own political ambitions, telling the New York Times that she hopes to see a Generation X president in 2028.</p>

<p><strong>California Governor Gavin Newsom</strong></p>

<p>California Governor Gavin Newsom is a vocal supporter of the Biden administration and is often mentioned as a potential candidate for the presidency in 2028. Some Democratic members believe he could even be a stand-in for Biden in the current election.</p>

<p>Newsom has been increasingly engaging with conservative media and debated Florida Governor Ron DeSantis last year. He was a prominent surrogate for Biden at the June debate in Atlanta, but dodged questions about whether he would consider replacing Biden on the ticket. For now, he is publicly supporting the president and headlined a Biden campaign event in Michigan on July 4.</p>

<p><strong>Transportation Secretary Pete Buttigieg</strong></p>

<p>Transportation Secretary Pete Buttigieg ran for President earlier in 2020. He is widely regarded as one of the Biden administration's most effective communicators. During his tenure as transportation secretary, Buttigieg has demonstrated his crisis management skills, and navigated several high-profile incidents, including the East Palestine train derailment in Ohio, the Baltimore Bridge collapse and Southwest Airlines' scheduling crisis in 2022.</p>

<p><strong>Pennsylvania Governor Josh Shapiro</strong></p>

<p>Josh Shapiro has maintained high public approval ratings since his 2022 election in Pennsylvania, a swing state. A former attorney general, Shapiro made headlines during his tenure as governor by swiftly rebuilding a collapsed Philadelphia bridge. This has led to speculations about his potential 2028 presidential bid, with the bridge repair serving as a strong infrastructure talking point.<br />
<br />
<strong>Illinois Governor JB Pritzker</strong><br />
<br />
JB Pritzker, the Governor of Illinois, has time-and-again vocally opposed former President Trump and actively supported President Biden. Following a recent debate, Pritzker labelled Trump a "liar" and talked about his 34 criminal convictions, saying he was a “felon who cares only about himself". Pritzker has consistently delivered on key agenda items for progressive Democrats, like on issues like abortion rights and gun control.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
<strong>Some others who could potentially be Biden's replacement are:</strong><br />
<br />
Kentucky Governor Andy Beshear, a two-term governor in a conservative state, has been getting more national attention since his re-election last year. Maryland Governor Wes Moore recently handled a crisis when a bridge collapsed in Baltimore, showing his leadership skills.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
Senators Amy Klobuchar and Cory Booker have run for presidential posts before and are well-known among Democrats.<br />
<br />
Georgia Senator Raphael Warnock is also a potential candidate. He won a close Senate race in a swing state, showing he can win tough elections.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
A recent poll found that Michelle Obama is the only person who could beat Trump in November, but she has said she doesn't want to run for president.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/h13tfc7_joe-biden_625x300_28_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Joe Biden has reaffirmed his commitment to staying in the race.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/six-ninja-turtle-gang-members-arrested-in-malaysia-tortoises-seized-6066263]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[6 "Ninja Turtle Gang" Members Arrested In Malaysia, Tortoises Seized]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/six-ninja-turtle-gang-members-arrested-in-malaysia-tortoises-seized-6066263]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 13:26:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Malaysian authorities have arrested six members of an international crime ring known as the "Ninja Turtle Gang" and seized about 200 smuggled tortoises and turtles, a wildlife official said Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Malaysian authorities have arrested six members of an international crime ring known as the "Ninja Turtle Gang" and seized about 200 smuggled tortoises and turtles, a wildlife official said Tuesday.</p>

<p>Abdul Kadir Abu Hashim, director-general of Malaysia's wildlife and national parks department, said four Cambodians and two Malaysians were arrested during a July 2 raid on a house in Kuala Lumpur by police and wildlife officials.</p>

<p>He told AFP some 200 turtles and tortoises worth an estimated 246,394 ringgit ($52,300) were rescued during the raid, the second seizure in Malaysia in less than a week.</p>

<p>Many people across Asia believe that turtles and tortoises bring good luck and prosperity.</p>

<p>Abdul Kadir said the six arrested belong to the Ninja Turtle Gang, an international crime ring involved in smuggling the reptiles.</p>

<p>Police and wildlife officials rescued 400 tortoises during an initial raid on June 29 that were meant for sale in Southeast Asia and were worth $805,084 on the black market.</p>

<p>Animals rescued in the latest raid included the critically endangered Chinese striped-necked turtle, which is also known as the golden thread turtle, Abdul Kadir said.</p>

<p>Other species included the endangered black pond turtle, snapping turtle, sulcata tortoise, leopard tortoise and the red-footed tortoise found throughout South America and the Caribbean islands of Trinidad and Barbados.</p>

<p>"Initial investigations revealed that the reptiles were smuggled from abroad to meet the lucrative pet market," Abdul Kadir said.</p>

<p>Also discovered were three snakes, four softshell turtles, a skink and five frogs.</p>

<p>The rescued animals were being kept in a Malaysian wildlife department quarantine centre.</p>

<p>The reptiles are illegally brought into Malaysia by road or in suitcases by smugglers aboard commercial flights, Abdul Kadir said last week.</p>

<p>Traffic, a wildlife NGO, has said that Southeast Asian countries "function as source, consumer and as entrepots for wildlife originating from within the region as well as the rest of the world".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-08/3ob2f3a_customs-seizes-60-live-star-tortoises_625x300_30_August_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[About 200 smuggled tortoises and turtles were seized.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/river-seine-to-have-flying-taxi-landing-pad-at-paris-olympics-6066050]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[River Seine To Have Flying Taxi Landing Pad At Paris Olympics]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/river-seine-to-have-flying-taxi-landing-pad-at-paris-olympics-6066050]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 12:51:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[France's government on Tuesday gave the go-ahead for construction of a floating landing pad on the River Seine for flying taxis set to be shown off during the Paris Olympics.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>France's government on Tuesday gave the go-ahead for construction of a floating landing pad on the River Seine for flying taxis set to be shown off during the Paris Olympics.</p>

<p>An official decree said that the pad "can be used until December 31, 2024" after months of suspense over whether the taxis would take to the air during the July 26 - August 11 Games.</p>

<p>The landing site will float on the Seine near the Austerlitz railway station in southeastern Paris.</p>

<p>Flights will be limited to two per hour, between 8:00 am to 5:00 pm, and no more than 900 over the whole trial period "given the experimental nature" of the vehicles, the decree read.</p>

<p>Private firms involved in the flying taxi project include Paris airport operator ADP and Germany-based Volocopter.</p>

<p>Its "Volocity" two-seaters are fitted with 18 electric-powered rotors on a circular frame above the fuselage.</p>

<p>They hope to use the global draw of the Olympics to show that the technology can efficiently link "vertiport" take-off and landing sites.</p>

<p>While four vertiports -- airports for vertical take-off and landing vehicles -- have already been set up in the Paris suburbs, including one at Charles de Gaulle airport, the Austerlitz site will be the first within the city proper.</p>

<p>Backers tout flying taxis as a low-carbon form of aviation and hope future larger versions could be used as ambulances or in other roles.</p>

<p>But many city officials in Paris have derided the plans as harmful to the environment.</p>

<p>France's national environment authority found that an impact assessment for the landing pad was "incomplete" on issues including noise pollution, energy consumption and greenhouse emissions.</p>

<p>Neither have the taxis been certified by the European Union's Aviation Safety Agency (EASA) -- meaning operators can only offer free demonstration flights during the Games.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-10/7nld1ve8_rome-airport-readies-for-flying-taxis-by-2024_625x300_29_October_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The landing site will float on the Seine near the Austerlitz railway station in southeastern Paris.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/world-acknowledging-indias-resurgence-pm-modi-to-indians-in-russia-6065682]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Till Last Ball...": PM's T20 Win Mention In Address To Indians In Russia]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/world-acknowledging-indias-resurgence-pm-modi-to-indians-in-russia-6065682]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 11:57:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India is transforming at a record pace and the world is taking note, Prime Minister Narendra Modi said today at an event organised by the Indian community in Russia's Moscow.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India is transforming at a record pace and the world is taking note, Prime Minister Narendra Modi said today at an event organised by the Indian community in Russia's Moscow.&nbsp;The country, he said, is infused with a confidence and is making things happen. "Over 140 crore Indians are making this resurgence of India possible -- they dream big, they take a pledge and then make it happen," he said.</p>

<p>In this context, the Prime Minister also referred to India's victory in the Men's T20 cricket world cup that ended the 13-year ICC trophy drought for the Men in Blue.</p>

<p>"Before 2014, we were into the pit of despair. Today, the country is full of confidence. Two patients suffering from the same ailment are in the same hospital, similarly capable doctors are attending to them. But if one patient is hopeful and the other is in despair, you will see the hopeful one will recover soon. India's asset now is its confidence," the Prime Minister said.</p>

<p>"You must have celebrated India's T20 World Cup victory here. The real story of that win is the journey towards it. Today's young India does not accept defeat till the last ball and the last moment. And victory kisses the feet of those who do not accept defeat," he said.</p>

<p>Showcasing his government's achievements, the Prime Minister said, "When India hosts the G20 Summit at the scale at which it did, the world takes notice. When India electrifies 40,000 km of rail lines, then the world notices India's power to grow. When India launches a solar mission and successfully and takes an L1 orbit, when India lands on the moon, when India builds the world's highest rail bridge, when India build's the world's tallest statue, the world sees a growing India. And India can do all this because of the potential and capability of 140 crore Indians, of its talented diaspora in every country of the world."</p>

<p>The Prime Minister said India and Russia are working together to boost global prosperity. "You all are taking India-Russia ties to new heights. With your hard work and honesty, you have contributed to the Russian society. I have been a fan of the unique relationship between India and Russia," he said, referring to Russia as India's "all-weather ally" and "trustworthy friend".</p>

<p>This relationship, he said, is based on mutual trust and respect. "Our ties have been tested multiple times, and our friendship has always emerged strong. I thank my friend, President Putin for his leadership. For over two decades, he has worked to make this partnership stronger. This is my 6th visit to Russia in the past 10 years and we have met each other 17 times during this time. These meetings have strengthened trust and respect. When our students were stuck amid (Ukraine) conflict, President Putin helped us take them home," he said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Prime Minister said it is his honour that his first diaspora event after being elected for the third time is happening in Moscow. "I have taken a pledge that I will work thrice as hard and thrice as fast as I have in the first two terms. I can assure you that in this third term, you will see that India will challenge every challenge that comes its way. And it is in my DNA that I give chunauti (challenge) to every chunauti," he said.</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/pt58jmag_pm-in-russia_625x300_09_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[PM Narendra Modi addressed the Indian community in Moscow today]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bobs-burgers-actor-jay-johnston-pleads-guilty-to-charges-over-january-6-us-riots-6065658]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA['Bob's Burgers' Actor Pleads Guilty To Charges Over January 6 US Riots]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bobs-burgers-actor-jay-johnston-pleads-guilty-to-charges-over-january-6-us-riots-6065658]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 11:52:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The 54-year-old faces up to five years in prison for the felony count of civil disorder.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bob's Burgers' actor Jay Johnston has pleaded guilty to charges of being involved in the January 2021 US Capitol riot, <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/articles/cw0yqv84x4ko ">BBC</a> has reported.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
The 54-year-old faces up to five years in prison for the felony count of civil disorder. A sentencing date has not been set yet. According to court documents, Johnston participated in a violent mob that attacked police officers. A video showed him taking a shield from an officer and using it to push back officers defending the Capitol.<br />
<br />
He was arrested and charged with multiple felonies, including obstruction of officers during civil disorder, unlawful entry on restricted buildings or grounds and impeding passage through Capitol grounds. He was released on a $25,000 bail bond in June 2023 following his initial court appearance in California.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
Court documents revealed that Johnston was near the tunnel entrance, gestured to other rioters to follow him, and later acknowledged his involvement in the Capitol riot in a text message. The message stated, "It wasn't an attack, but it kind of turned into that." Another message described the scene as "a mess."<br />
<br />
The FBI identified Johnston as a suspect after three acquaintances recognised him in photos published on social media. One of these associates provided investigators with the incriminating text message. Airline records also showed that Johnston booked a round-trip flight from Los Angeles to Washington DC, flying on January 4, 2021, and returning on January 7.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
On January 6, 2021, a mob of then-US President Donald Trump supporters attacked the US Capitol Building, seeking to overturn the 2020 election results. Thousands gathered in Washington, DC, fueled by Trump's false claims of election fraud.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
Rioters breached the Capitol, vandalising offices, assaulting police and reporters, and attempting to harm lawmakers. Pipe bombs and Molotov cocktails were found nearby. Five people, including a police officer, died and 174 officers were injured. The attack was a failed attempt to disrupt the electoral vote count and keep Trump in power.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
Nearly 1,000 people have been found guilty or pleaded guilty to federal crimes related to the riots, reported AP. Over half of these people have received prison sentences, ranging from seven days to 18 years.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/elvk5b4o_jay-johnston_625x300_09_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/porn-star-jesse-jane-died-of-drug-overdose-reveals-autopsy-6065422]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Porn Star Jesse Jane Died Of Drug Overdose, Reveals Autopsy]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/porn-star-jesse-jane-died-of-drug-overdose-reveals-autopsy-6065422]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 11:23:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Adult film star Jesse Jane died from an accidental overdose of fentanyl and cocaine toxicity in January 2024, herautopsy report has confirmed. Her body was found in a decomposed state, it stated.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Adult film star Jesse Jane died from an accidental overdose of fentanyl and cocaine toxicity in January 2024, her&nbsp;<a href="http://https://www.oklahoman.com/story/news/2024/07/08/jesse-jane-cause-of-death-revealed-porn-star-oklahoma-overdose-fentanyl/74323582007/ \">autopsy report</a> has confirmed. Her body was found in a decomposed state, it stated.</p>

<p>The 43-year-old actor, whose real name was Cindy Taylor or Cynthia Ann Howell, was found unresponsive in her boyfriend's home in Oklahoma on January 24, 2024. Her boyfriend, Brett Hasenmuller, 33, was also found dead at the scene.</p>

<p>The Oklahoma Medical Examiner's Office performed the autopsy, revealing acute fentanyl and cocaine intoxication as the cause of death. The report, released on Sunday, noted that Ms Jane's body was in a state of advanced decomposition, indicating she had been dead for some time before her body was found.</p>

<p>According to TMZ, the bodies were discovered after the boyfriend's boss requested a welfare check, leading cops to visit the residence. They were found dead, and their cause of death was suspected to be an overdose at the time.</p>

<p>Jesse Jane was a prominent figure in the adult entertainment industry, appearing in over 100 adult films and earning many awards and nominations. She began her porn career in 2002, signing an exclusive contract with Digital Playground Studio, where she remained until 2014. She later signed with Jules Jordan Video and announced her retirement from the industry in 2017.</p>

<p>Jane also appeared in mainstream TV shows and films, including <em>Baywatch: Hawaiian Wedding, Pirates II: Stagnetti's Revenge, Starsky and Hutch, Family Business, Entourage,</em> <em>Night Calls </em>and <em>The Bad Girls Club</em>. She also featured in the CNBC documentary <em>Porn: Business of Pleasure.</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-01/ocheejp_pornstar-jesse-jane-dies_625x300_26_January_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Jesse Jane's boyfriend, Brett Hasenmuller, was also found dead at the scene. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/american-mountaineer-william-stampfl-found-mummified-in-peru-22-years-after-vanishing-6065379]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[American Mountaineer Found Mummified In Peru 22 Years After Vanishing]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/american-mountaineer-william-stampfl-found-mummified-in-peru-22-years-after-vanishing-6065379]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 11:07:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The preserved body of an American mountaineer -- who disappeared 22 years ago while scaling a snowy peak in Peru -- has been found after being exposed by climate change-induced ice melt, police said Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The preserved body of an American mountaineer -- who disappeared 22 years ago while scaling a snowy peak in Peru -- has been found after being exposed by climate change-induced ice melt, police said Monday.</p>

<p>William Stampfl was reported missing in June 2002, aged 59, when an avalanche buried his climbing party on the mountain Huascaran, which stands more than 6,700 meters (22,000 feet) high. Search and rescue efforts were fruitless.</p>

<p>Peruvian police said his remains were finally exposed by ice melt on the Cordillera Blanca range of the Andes.</p>

<p>Stampfl's body, as well as his clothes, harness and boots had been well-preserved by the cold, according to images distributed by police.</p>

<p>His passport was found among his possessions, allowing police to identify the body.</p>

<p>The mountains of northeastern Peru, home to snowy peaks such as Huascaran and Cashan, are a favorite with mountaineers from around the world.</p>

<p>In May, the body of an Israeli hiker was found there nearly a month after he disappeared.</p>

<p>And last month, an experienced Italian mountaineer was found dead after he fell while trying to scale another Andean peak.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/dn40nrjg_william-stampfl-american-mountaineer-afp_625x300_09_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Peruvian police said his remains were finally exposed by ice melt on the Cordillera Blanca range.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>