<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Sun, 20 Oct 2024 14:19:49 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/israel-has-little-reason-to-end-its-war-on-gaza-even-with-yahya-sinwar-dead-6831240]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: Israel Has Little Reason To End Its War On Gaza - Even With Yahya Sinwar Dead]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/israel-has-little-reason-to-end-its-war-on-gaza-even-with-yahya-sinwar-dead-6831240]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 20 Oct 2024 13:57:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[With US elections just weeks away, Israeli PM Netanyahu understands that he would likely get a free pass, whether Trump becomes President or Kamala Harris.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/q461lp8_gaza_625x300_20_October_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>The death of Hamas chief Yahya Sinwar on Thursday, October 17, by the Israeli Defense Forces (IDF), is a watershed moment in the Israel-Hamas war that has raged on since October 7 last year.&nbsp;</p>

<p>A senior member of Hamas, Sinwar had taken over its leadership following the assassination of Hamas chief Ismail Haniyeh earlier this year in Tehran. Committed to Israel's destruction, he was the mastermind of the brutal Hamas attacks in October last year, which claimed the lives of over 1,200 Israelis, with more than 200 people taken hostage by the Hamas. Since then, Israeli reprisals have killed almost 42,000 Palestinians in the Gaza Strip, according to the Gaza Health Ministry. Meanwhile, Iran's proxy and ally on Israel's northern borders, the Hezbollah, began launching rocket attacks on Israel. In retaliation, since October 1 this year, Israel has been involved in full-scale military operations in Southern Lebanon and Beirut in a bid to create a buffer zone free of the Hezbollah's presence between Israel and Lebanon.</p>

<p>Following Sinwar's death, US President Joe Biden and European leaders have renewed calls for a ceasefire in the Gaza Strip. Biden said Sinwar's death was "an opportunity to seek a path to peace" in Gaza.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>The Two Aspects To Sinwar's Death</strong></h2>

<p>However, a ceasefire has proved elusive since Israel's operations in Gaza. All that has been made possible is a few “humanitarian pauses" to let aid reach the besieged people in Gaza. Israel has resisted all calls for a ceasefire, alleging that any such step would be exploited by the Hamas to regroup and remobilise. Shortly after Sinwar's death, Danny Danon, Israel's ambassador to the United Nations wrote on X: "Yesterday at the UN Security Council, many asked why we are still in Gaza a year after the October 7th atrocities. Today they got the answer. No terrorist is immune to the long arm of the IDF. We will not stop until we bring home all of our hostages and eliminate the Hamas monsters.”</p>

<p>There are two aspects to Sinwar's death. On the one hand, defence experts have pointed out that the pictures of the last moments leading to Sinwar's death show him sitting alone in a room above ground. The scene points to significant damage inflicted by the IDF on the numerous underground tunnels that the Hamas used. With the death of numerous high-profile leaders of both the Hamas and the Hezbollah, the organisations are in disarray. The former, especially, has been heavily dismantled. This factor alone may push its other members to surrender and release the 100-odd Israeli hostages still being held captive in the Strip.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Discussions between the US, Israel, the European Union, and Arab states have also revolved around a plan whereby post-war Gaza would see joint-Arab force.</p>

<h2><strong>The Question Of Hostages</strong></h2>

<p>Israel has turned Gaza into rubble. Even with 42,000 dead in the strip, even after a year of war, it has not been able to achieve one of its major objectives —the release of all hostages. While about 120-odd hostages have been freed—thanks to major back-channel efforts by Qatar, Egypt, and the US—a number of them died in captivity, while about 100-odd hostages are still with the Hamas.</p>

<p>On the other hand, the fact remains that high-profile assassinations like Sinwar's are not something new for the Hamas. Israel has a long history of carrying out such operations, and, if anything, the Hamas has only emerged militarily stronger, inflicting increasingly more brutal attacks on Israelis. The October 7 attacks were a culmination of this history,&nbsp;when Hamas launched multi-pronged strikes on Israel from land, sea, and air, carefully dodging all surveillance and air defence systems.&nbsp;&nbsp;launched multi-pronged strikes on Israel from land, sea, and air, carefully dodging all surveillance and air defence systems.&nbsp;, carefully dodging all surveillance and air defence systems. Many, including those inside Israel, have pointed out that the unprecedented destruction wrought by Israel in Gaza may just be what incentivises others to join the ranks of Hamas and continue its work.</p>

<p>Of course, Hamas has kept up the bravado up too. Sinwar's long-time deputy, Khalil al-Hayya, has said that Sinwar's death “will only increase the strength and resolve of Hamas and our resistance”. What is also interesting is that Fatah, the Hamas's arch-rival and which together with the rest of the Palestinian Liberation Organisation had promised to eschew any violence against Israel, has also officially released a statement mourning the death of "martyr Yahya Sinwar ". Hence, while the world would want nothing more for the hostages to be released and a ceasefire reached, whether it will actually happen remains anyone's guess.</p>

<h2><strong>Netanyahu's Quandary</strong></h2>

<p>Tellingly, Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu has also not committed to any ceasefire. "The war ... is not over yet. And it is difficult, and it exacts heavy prices from us,” Netanyahu said in a video statement after Sinwar's death. He also had a message for the Hamas: “Whoever lays down his weapon and returns our hostages—we will allow him to go on living.”&nbsp;</p>

<p>Indeed, Netanyahu would hope for this to happen. His war on Gaza has not exactly provided him the domestic support he had hoped for, with many in his own country opposing it. As long as the hostages from October 7 remain captive in Gaza, it would be seen as a failure. Besides, with hundreds of IDF soldiers dead and the economy taking an unprecedented hit, the war has taken a great toll on the Israeli people themselves. The conflict has significantly escalated with Israel's air and ground operations in Lebanon, which have killed more than 1,000 people and displaced many Lebanese civilians. After the death of Hezbollah chief Hassan Nasrallah, Iran launched a barrage of missiles directly at Israel, the second time it has done so this year. Israel has vowed to avenge this. And in another symbolic escalation, none other than Netanyahu's house was targeted in a Hezbollah drone strike.</p>

<h2><strong>Harris Or Trump, US Support May Continue</strong></h2>

<p>There is little incentive for Netanyahu's government to agree to a ceasefire now, when the IDF's successes in Lebanon and the deaths of those like Nasrallah and Sinwar are being hailed by the Israeli people as achievements after a year of opposition, which even saw calls for the government to resign.</p>

<p>More importantly, with US elections just weeks away, Netanyahu understands that he would likely get a free pass. No matter what US Vice President and Democrat Presidential candidate Kamala Harris's domestic compulsions may be, overall, there is unlikely to be any major opposition to Israel's wars. And in case Donald Trump and the Republicans form the next government, they are only expected to take a harsher stance against Iran. Marwan al-Muasher, Jordan's former foreign minister and now Vice-President for Studies at the U.S.-based Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, sums it up: "There is no reason for Netanyahu to stop his wars before the American elections."</p>

<p>Increasingly, it seems both Israel and Hamas, led by some unknown-to-us, apocalyptic vision, are fighting to the finish.</p>

<p><em>(Aditi Bhaduri is a journalist and political analyst. She has translated the works of Nicholas Roerich from Russian to English)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/b7mgppk8_israel_625x300_20_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/barack-obama-us-election-donald-trump-do-not-boo-go-barack-obama-to-trump-supporters-at-us-election-rally-6831233]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Do Not Boo, Go": Barack Obama To Trump Supporters At US Election Rally]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/barack-obama-us-election-donald-trump-do-not-boo-go-barack-obama-to-trump-supporters-at-us-election-rally-6831233]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 20 Oct 2024 13:56:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Addressing a public rally to build support for Democrat Presidential candidate Kamala Harris and her running mate Tim Walz, former US President Barack Obama today blasted Donald Trump, saying that the Republican candidate cares only about his ego]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Addressing a public rally to build support for Democrat Presidential candidate Kamala Harris and her running mate Tim Walz, former US President Barack Obama today blasted Donald Trump, saying that the Republican candidate cares only about "his ego, money and status".</p>

<p>"We are ready for President Kamala Harris. That's what we want and the good news is Kamala Harris is ready for the job. This is a leader who has spent her entire life fighting for people who need a champion. Somebody raised in the middle class, worked at McDonald's while she was in college just to pay her expenses, somebody who believes in the values that built this country. And she is as prepared for the job as any nominee for president has ever been," he said at the rally in Nevada, praising the 60-year-old leader who has earlier served as US vice president.</p>

<p>Praising the Democratic vice-president nominee, Obama said, "And in the White House, she (Harris) will have an outstanding partner in Governor Tim Walz of Minnesota. I love that guy. Tim's a veteran. He is a teacher, he is a football coach, he is a hunter. Been a great governor, working with Democrats and Republicans to get stuff done. And I just found out he can take vintage trucks apart and put them back together again. You think Donald Trump can do that?"</p>

<p>The former President then slipped in a reference to Jeeves -- the timeless valet character created by English author PG Wodehouse. "Do you think Donald Trump has ever changed a tyre in his life? If he gets a flat tyre, he calls Jeeves (and says) 'Jeeves, change that tyre'. The point is if you elect Kamala and Tim, they won't be focused on their problems. They are gonna be focused on your problems," he said.&nbsp;At one point, a section of the crowd started booing at his remarks on Trump. "Do not boo, go," Obama responded.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">.<a href="https://twitter.com/KamalaHarris?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@KamalaHarris</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/Tim_Walz?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Tim_Walz</a> are the leaders we need right now.<br />
<br />
Let's help them get elected: <a href="https://t.co/P9hoDajB1P">https://t.co/P9hoDajB1P</a> <a href="https://t.co/eXnJZPNbbp">pic.twitter.com/eXnJZPNbbp</a></p>
— Barack Obama (@BarackObama) <a href="https://twitter.com/BarackObama/status/1847857485631078629?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 20, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>The former President said the US had been grappling with price rise following the Covid pandemic.&nbsp;"We know this election is going to be tight and it's going to be tight because a lot of Americans are still struggling. As a country, we have been through a lot over these last few years. We had a pandemic that wreaked havoc on businesses and communities and then the disruptions from the pandemic caused price hikes and that put a strain on family budgets... So I get why people are looking to shake things up. It's understandable. What I cannot understand is why anybody would think that Donald Trump will shake things up in a way that is good for people because there is absolutely no evidence that this man thinks about anybody but himself," he said.</p>

<p>"I have said it before and I am gonna say it again, Donald Trump is a 78-year-old billionaire who has not stopped whining about his problem since he rode down that golden escalator nine years ago. He is constantly complaining, and when he is not complaining, he is trying to sell you stuff," he said.</p>

<p>"He is trying to sell you a Trump Bible. He's got his name right next to Matthew and Luke. And I will give you one guess where those bibles are made -- in China. This is Mr Tough Guy on China except when he can make a few bucks... And the reason he is doing it is because all he cares about is his ego, money and his status. He is not thinking about you. He sees power as nothing more than a means to meet his ends. He wants the middle class to pay the price for another huge tax cut, to help mostly him and his country club buddies," he added.</p>

<p>Obama said Trump wants the US to be hopelessly divided between "us and them". "Between 'real Americans' who obviously support him and anybody who doesn't because having people divided and angry and resentful and full of grievance boosts his chances of being elected," he said.</p>

<p>"You would be worried if your grandfather started acting like this. You would call up your brother, cousins and ask, 'have you seen grandpa lately? what do we do?' But this is coming from somebody who wants unchecked power, wants the most powerful office on Earth. We don't need to see what an older, loonier Donald Trump looks like with no guardrails. America is ready to turn the page. We are ready for a better story," Obama said.</p>

<p>The age reference is significant against the backdrop of the Democrats choosing Harris as their candidate after incumbent President Joe Biden, who was under age scrutiny, opted out of the race. The change has tilted the balance in favour of the Democrats.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">When it comes to the economy, Donald Trump plans to give another massive tax cut to billionaires and big corporations.<br />
<br />
We need leaders like <a href="https://twitter.com/KamalaHarris?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@KamalaHarris</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/Tim_Walz?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Tim_Walz</a> who will work to lower costs for Americans and hold corporations accountable. <a href="https://t.co/d89Um8w5lh">https://t.co/d89Um8w5lh</a> <a href="https://t.co/hTCD9vBYeo">pic.twitter.com/hTCD9vBYeo</a></p>
— Barack Obama (@BarackObama) <a href="https://twitter.com/BarackObama/status/1847846978853470646?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 20, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>Obama said Trump plans to give a massive tax cut to billionaires and big corporations. "I remember the economy when he first came into office, the first two years were pretty good. Yeah, it was good because it was my economy," he said to loud cheers.</p>

<p>"Some of you remember what it was like in Nevada when I came into office. The worst financial crisis in history, the housing market collapsed here in Nevada. I spent eight years cleaning up that mess that the Republicans had left me. And then I handed over to Donald Trump, 75 straight months of job growth and all he did with it was give a tax cut to people who didn't need it, drove up the deficit in the process and now he wants to do it all over again."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/dol48qm_obama-afp_625x300_20_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Former US President Barack Obama was addressing a rally in Nevada]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rare-us-constitution-copy-from-1787-fetches-over-11-million-at-auction-6830918]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Rare US Constitution Copy From 1787 Fetches Over $11 Million At Auction]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rare-us-constitution-copy-from-1787-fetches-over-11-million-at-auction-6830918]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 20 Oct 2024 12:56:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A rare copy of the United States Constitution, printed after the 1787 Constitutional Convention, has sold for more than $11 million during a live auction in Asheville, North Carolina, on Thursday evening.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A rare copy of the United States Constitution, printed after the 1787 Constitutional Convention, has sold for more than $11 million during a live auction in Asheville, North Carolina, on Thursday evening.</p>

<p>The auction, conducted by Brunk Auctions, ended with a final bid of $9 million, excluding a 23 per cent buyer's premium and undisclosed taxes. The identity of the buyer remains confidential as of now. The bidding of this rare copy commenced at $1.1 million and escalated fast, reaching the final bid within a period of a brief seven minutes. NBC Los Angeles reported that there were 62 bids in total.</p>

<p>The Constitutional Convention, which took place in Philadelphia from May to September 1787, was a pivotal moment in American history. Initially assembled to amend the Articles of Confederation, the need for a new framework of government due to the loopholes in the existing system was quickly pointed out. This resulted in a new constitution, which established a federal government with checks and balances among its branches. This document thus remains foundational to American democracy, making it all the more historically significant at an auction such as this one.</p>

<p>Nancy Zander, the director of external affairs for Brunk Auctions, described the sale as a "spectacular price" to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/19/us/us-constitution-copy-sold.html?smid=whatsapp-nytimes">The New York Times</a>. "It's really important that important things get strong prices," she said in an interview on Friday.</p>

<p>This copy of the Constitution was discovered two years ago in a filing cabinet at Hayes Farm in Edenton, North Carolina. The farm was owned by Samuel Johnston, the governor of North Carolina from 1787 to 1789. It is one of approximately 100 copies printed back then, with only eight or nine known remaining today.</p>

<p>In addition to the Constitution, other notable items sold at the auction included a painting of George Washington crossing the Delaware River, which fetched over $307,000, and a copy of the Articles of Confederation that sold for more than $1.2 million.</p>

<p>Seth Kaller, a historical document expert involved in the auction, said that while there were hopes for a sale price comparable to a previous record-setting sale in 2021-when another early Constitution copy sold for over $43 million- this outcome was anticipated due to differing market conditions this time. Kaller was also representing one of the bidders in this auction.</p>

<p>The auction was initially set up for September 28 but was postponed due to Hurricane Helene's impact on the neighbouring area. "It was not as celebratory as it would have been had we not had the terrible catastrophe around us," said Ms. Zander "But we were all together, appreciating the moment." &nbsp;Despite limited public attendance due to the storm, bidders allegedly also participated via phone calls.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/jufj2hf_rare-copy-us-constitution-_625x300_20_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[This copy of the Constitution was found 2 years ago in a filing cabinet at Hayes Farm North Carolina.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-turns-60-as-age-plays-key-role-in-2024-us-presidential-election-6830910]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris Turns 60 As Age Plays Key Role In US Election]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-turns-60-as-age-plays-key-role-in-2024-us-presidential-election-6830910]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 20 Oct 2024 12:53:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Age has been a crucial factor in a campaign that Joe Biden quit over fears about his capacity, and where Kamala Harris has steadily taken aim at Donald Trump's mental fitness for office.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kamala Harris turns 60 on Sunday in the final stretch of a knife-edge election battle with 78-year-old Donald Trump, who is now the oldest presidential candidate in US history. Age has been a crucial factor in a campaign that President Joe Biden quit over fears about his capacity, and where Harris has steadily taken aim at Trump's mental fitness for office.</p>

<p>With just over two weeks before Election Day, the Democratic vice president and the Republican billionaire are in a fierce race that polls suggest is effectively tied.</p>

<p>The two candidates will on Sunday again be in Pennsylvania, the battleground that is considered a must-win among the seven key states expected to decide the November 5 election.</p>

<p>Biden passed the torch to Harris after a disastrous debate against Trump raised concerns in the Democratic Party about his mental sharpness.</p>

<p>But Trump's age has not appeared to be a deal-breaker for voters, as polls show a close battle.</p>

<p>"Now he's ducking debates and canceling interviews because of exhaustion," Harris told a rally Saturday in Atlanta, mocking his rambling, off-script speeches.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">While Donald Trump is canceling interviews and ducking debates from “exhaustion,” the American people are exhausted by his same old, tired playbook.<br />
<br />
He is unfit to be President of the United States. <a href="https://t.co/SxFfuCcGvt">pic.twitter.com/SxFfuCcGvt</a></p>
— Kamala Harris (@KamalaHarris) <a href="https://twitter.com/KamalaHarris/status/1847812550727016954?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 20, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>"He's called it the weave. But we here, we will call it nonsense," she added.</p>

<h3><strong>'Across the finish line'</strong></h3>

<p>Harris had also sought to goad Trump with a report on October 12 that described her "excellent health", but the ex-president's campaign noted he too is "in perfect and excellent health to be Commander-in-Chief".</p>

<p>The Republican running for a second go in the White House countered Harris's accusations with a marathon speech in Pennsylvania on Saturday, a day after saying she "doesn't have the energy of a rabbit."</p>

<p>Both candidates are spending their final campaign days in pivotal battleground states, but so are their surrogates.</p>

<p>Tesla and SpaceX boss Elon Musk has personally hit the campaign trail in Pennsylvania, holding a series of events in the must-win state.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Speaking in the southeastern city of Harrisburg, he announced he would start to randomly distribute cash awards -- $1 million each day until the November 5 vote -- to a registered voter in the state who signed his organization's petition.</p>

<p>Harris deployed surrogates in the form of pop stars Lizzo and Usher to make her case to voters.</p>

<p>Lizzo drew cheers when telling a Detroit rally that America was more than ready for its first woman president, dropping a reference to her own hit song: "It's about damn time!"</p>

<p>One of Atlanta's major stars, Usher, told voters there that "I'm counting on you" to get Harris's "campaign across the finish line" in Georgia.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/lllq04ug_kamala-harris_625x300_20_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Biden passed the torch to Harris after a disastrous debate against Trump]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/forever-chemicals-found-in-bottled-and-tap-water-from-around-the-world-study-6830358]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA['Forever Chemicals' Found In Bottled And Tap Water Across UK and China]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/forever-chemicals-found-in-bottled-and-tap-water-from-around-the-world-study-6830358]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 20 Oct 2024 11:06:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA['Forever Chemicals', known as perfluoroalkyl substances are long-lasting chemicals that break down extremely slowly over time.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A new study has revealed that toxic 'Forever Chemicals', known as perfluoroalkyl substances (PFAS), have been found in drinking water samples worldwide. The study conducted by researchers from the University of Birmingham and Hainan University found 10 'target' PFAS chemicals in tap and bottled water available for consumption in major cities across the UK and China, <em>I<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.independent.co.uk/news/science/forever-chemicals-drinking-tap-water-b2631492.html">ndependent</a></em> reported.&nbsp;These chemicals are notorious for not breaking down in nature and persisting in the environment. In their findings published in&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://pubs.acs.org/toc/aewcaa/0/0"><em>ACS ES&amp;T Water</em></a>, the researchers found that perfluorooctanoic acid (PFOA) and perfluorooctane sulfonate (PFOS) were detected in over 99 per cent of their samples of bottled water.</p>

<p>Further testing revealed varying levels of PFAS in bottled water from different countries, with purified water containing lower concentrations than natural mineral water. Fortunately, most concentrations were below regulatory agencies' health advisory levels. However, tap water samples told a different story. Chinese tap water had higher concentrations of PFAS compared to UK tap water, with samples from Shenzhen exceeding the US Environmental Protection Agency's maximum contaminant level of 4 ng/L.</p>

<p>For the study, researchers collected 153 samples from various sources. For bottled water, they purchased 112 samples from local shops and online supermarkets in the UK and China. The bottled water samples included 89 still and 23 sparkling waters, packaged in both plastic and glass bottles. Additionally, 41 tap water samples were collected from homes in Birmingham, Worcester, Coventry, and Derby, supplied by South Staffordshire Water and Severn Trent Water, while 14 tap water samples came from homes in Shenzhen, China.&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>What are PFAS?</strong></h3>

<p>PFAS are long-lasting chemicals that break down extremely slowly over time. They're commonly used in products like non-stick cookware, water-repellent clothing, stain-resistant fabrics, cosmetics, and items that resist grease, water, and oil. While some PFAS have been banned in certain countries, others remain widely used.</p>

<p>These chemicals are already known to enter the body in different ways, for example being breathed in, ingested via food or drinking water, or absorbed through the skin. They are known to cause adverse health effects such as a lowered immune response to vaccination, impaired liver function, decreased birth weight, and increased risk of some cancers.</p>

<h3><strong>How to reduce PFAs?</strong></h3>

<p>Fortunately, simple methods can reduce PFAS levels in drinking water. Boiling water or using a carbon filter can remove up to 90% of these toxic chemicals.</p>

<p>''Our findings highlight the widespread presence of PFAS in drinking water and the effectiveness of simple treatment methods to reduce their levels. Either using a simple water filtration jug or boiling the water removes a substantial proportion of these substances,'' Professor Stuart Harrad from the University of Birmingham said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Co-author Professor Yi Zheng, from Southern University of Science and Technology, said, ''Increased awareness about the presence of PFAS in both tap and bottled water can lead to more informed choices by consumers, encouraging the use of water purification methods.''</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/7oas1r3_water-bottle_625x300_01_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[For the study, researchers collected 153 samples from various sources.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-to-award-1-million-each-day-to-a-signer-of-his-petition-6830305]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk To Award $1 Million Each Day To A Signer Of His Petition]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-to-award-1-million-each-day-to-a-signer-of-his-petition-6830305]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 20 Oct 2024 10:52:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Elon Musk awarded a $1 million check to an attendee of his event in Pennsylvania aimed at rallying supporters behind Republican Donald Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Billionaire Elon Musk promised on Saturday to give away $1 million each day until November's election to someone who signs his online petition supporting the U.S. Constitution. And he wasted no time, awarding a $1 million check to an attendee of his event in Pennsylvania aimed at rallying supporters behind Republican Donald Trump. The winner was a man named John Dreher, according to event staff.</p>

<p>"By the way, John had no idea. So anyway, you're welcome," the Tesla founder said as he handed Dreher the check.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Link to the petition:<a href="https://t.co/Wb3hUCxGvl">https://t.co/Wb3hUCxGvl</a></p>
— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1847860746627023143?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 20, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The money is the latest example of Musk using his extraordinary wealth to influence the tightly-contested presidential race between Trump and his Democratic rival Kamala Harris.</p>

<p>Musk started America PAC, a political action organization he founded in support of Trump's presidential campaign. The group is helping mobilize and register voters in battleground states, but there are signs it is having trouble meeting its goals.</p>

<p>The Harrisburg event is the third in as many days in Pennsylvania, where Musk is painting November's election in stark terms and encouraging supporters to vote early and get others to do the same.</p>

<p>He said on Saturday that if Harris wins, it will be "the last election," suggesting the US will no longer exist.</p>

<p>He also said the two assassination attempts against Trump prove he is ruffling feathers and upending the status quo in ways Harris won't. He said that's why no one is trying to kill Harris.</p>

<p>"Assassinating a puppet is worthless," Musk said, reiterating an argument he has made in a social media post.</p>

<p>The petition Musk is asking people to sign reads: "The First and Second Amendments guarantee freedom of speech and the right to bear arms. By signing below, I am pledging my support for the First and Second Amendments."</p>

<p>Attendees of Saturday's event had to sign the petition, which allows America PAC to garner contact details for more potential voters that it can work to get to the polls for Trump.</p>

<p>Musk, ranked by Forbes as the world's richest person, so far has supplied at least $75 million to America PAC, according to federal disclosures, making the group a crucial part of Trump's bid to regain the White House.</p>

<p>The entrepreneur behind carmaker Tesla and rocket and satellite venture SpaceX has increasingly supported Republican causes and this year became an outspoken Trump supporter.</p>

<p>Trump in turn has said if elected he would appoint Musk to head a government efficiency commission.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/i53kvgkg_elon-musk_625x300_20_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Musk so far has supplied at least $75 million to America PAC]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-woman-fired-after-coming-back-from-maternity-leave-pregnant-again-awarded-compensation-6830250]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Boss Fires Woman After She Comes Back From Maternity Leave Pregnant Again]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-woman-fired-after-coming-back-from-maternity-leave-pregnant-again-awarded-compensation-6830250]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 20 Oct 2024 10:43:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Nikita Twitchen, a former admin assistant at First Grade Projects, launched an unfair dismissal claim, alleging her pregnancy was the reason for her termination.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A woman in the UK who was fired from her job when she came back from maternity leave pregnant again, has been awarded 28,000 pounds by an employment tribunal.&nbsp;Nikita Twitchen, a former admin assistant at First Grade Projects in Pontypridd launched an unfair dismissal claim, alleging her pregnancy was the reason for her termination, <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://metro.co.uk/2024/10/19/mum-sacked-coming-back-maternity-leave-pregnant-21826305/#:~:text=A%20mum%20who%20lost%20her,Grade%20Projects%20in%20April%202022.">Metro</a></em> reported.&nbsp;During her back-to-work meeting with Managing Director Jeremy Morgan in early 2022, Ms Twitchen revealed she was expecting another child, which she claims caught her boss off guard.</p>

<p>Initially, the meeting seemed positive, with Mr Morgan expressing enthusiasm for her return. However, Ms Twitchen testified that the tone shifted dramatically upon disclosing her pregnancy, leading her to believe her job loss was directly linked to her pregnancy.</p>

<p>The woman said that when her maternity leave ended in March 2022, her company didn't reach out to discuss her return. She then emailed her boss on April 4 about holiday entitlement, but he didn't respond, which was unusual. Ms Twitchen followed up on April 11 and 18. Later that day, Mr Morgan called her to say she was being made redundant due to financial struggles&nbsp;and delays in some payments to the business.</p>

<p>He later claimed new software was being installed which meant her role ''would no longer exist.''</p>

<p>However, the tribunal ruled in Ms Twitchen's favour, finding First Grade Projects liable for unfair dismissal and awarding her 28,000 pounds in compensation.&nbsp;Judge Robin Harvard pointed out a significant inconsistency in Jeremy Morgan's reasoning for making her redundant. During their February meeting, Mr Morgan had claimed the business was doing well and made no mention of financial difficulties. He also didn't mention the new software that supposedly made Ms Twitchen's role obsolete, even during their April phone call.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The judge criticised First Grade's failure to ''produce any evidence of the alleged financial difficulties or the new software'' during the court case. He also pointed out that at no stage did Ms Twitchen receive a written statement setting out the reasons for her dismissal.&nbsp;Judge Havard ruled that Ms Twitchen was dismissed because she was pregnant.</p>

<p>He said that her dismissal was "unfair, discriminatory, and caused significant emotional distress." He emphasised that being fired while pregnant and losing financial stability had a profound impact on her, particularly given her family responsibilities.</p>

<p>First Grade Projects told <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.walesonline.co.uk/news/wales-news/boss-laid-member-staff-because-30174272" rel="nofollow, noindex">WalesOnline</a></em> in a statement: "We are extremely disappointed with the outcome of the tribunal. We are actively reviewing all relevant information and considering all available options. At this point in time we are unable to provide any further comment."</p>

<p></p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/atkj5em8_pregnant-woman_625x300_12_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The tribunal ruled in Ms Twitchen's favour, finding First Grade Projects liable for unfair dismissal]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/yazidi-woman-freed-by-idf-from-gaza-reveals-isis-forced-them-to-eat-babies-6829920]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Had Weird Taste": Woman Freed From ISIS Reveals They Made Them Eat Babies]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/yazidi-woman-freed-by-idf-from-gaza-reveals-isis-forced-them-to-eat-babies-6829920]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 20 Oct 2024 09:43:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Fawzia Sido recounted how, at the age of nine, she was captured along with her brothers and starved for three days. She was rescued by Israel from Gaza earlier this month.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Two weeks after her rescue by the Israeli Defense Forces (IDF) from Gaza, Yazidi survivor Fawzia Amin Sido has recounted the harrowing atrocities she endured during her time in captivity under ISIS. Ms Sido recounted how, at the age of nine, she was captured along with her brothers and forced to march from Sinjar to Tal Afar. The group was starved for three days before being fed rice and meat, which they later discovered was the flesh of Yazidi babies.</p>

<p>“They made rice and gave us meat to eat with it. The meat had a weird taste, and some of us had stomach aches afterwards,” Ms Sido recalled, as per the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.jpost.com/middle-east/article-825066" rel="nofollow,noindex">Jerusalem Post</a>.</p>

<p>“When we were done, they told us that this was the meat of Yazidi babies. They showed us pictures of beheaded babies and said, ‘these are the kids that you ate now.'”</p>

<p>“One woman suffered heart failure and died shortly after,” Ms Sido said, adding that one mother even recognised her own child because of the baby's hands. “They forced us. But it's very hard to know that it happened. But it was not in our hands,” she said.</p>

<p>Fawzia Sido was one of many Yazidi women enslaved by ISIS in 2014 during the group's reign of terror. The Yazidis, a religious minority in northern Iraq, were subjected to unimaginable horrors.</p>

<p>Ms Sido's revelation follows previous accusations that ISIS fed human meat to their captives. Yazidi parliamentarian Vian Dakhil first brought this practice to light in 2017, but Ms Sido's firsthand account is one of the clearest confirmations of this depravity.</p>

<p>Fawzia Sido's ordeal did not end with the forced consumption of human flesh. She was held captive for nine months in an underground prison alongside 200 other Yazidi women and children. Some of the children died due to contaminated water. Ms Sido was also sold to multiple jihadi fighters, including Abu Amar al-Makdisi, with whom she had two children.</p>

<p>After years of captivity, she was rescued by the IDF in a joint operation with the US Embassy and returned to her family in Iraq. However, her children remain in Gaza with her captor's family, where they are being raised as Arab Muslims.</p>

<p>She said, “Until I got back to Iraq, I was all the time a ‘sabaya,' also in Gaza,” using the Arabic term for a young woman held captive and exploited sexually.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/67oisrd8_fawzia-amin-sido_625x300_20_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[She was rescued by the IDF in a joint operation with the US Embassy]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-ukraine-war-russian-troops-gathered-for-training-then-a-ukrainian-drone-helped-attack-them-6829950]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[A Ukraine Drone Hovered Over Russian Troops. Then A Rocket Rained Fire]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-ukraine-war-russian-troops-gathered-for-training-then-a-ukrainian-drone-helped-attack-them-6829950]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 20 Oct 2024 09:40:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A drone this week helped Ukrainian troops attack a military training facility of Russian troops in Zaporizhzhia Oblast in Russian-occupied southern Ukraine.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A drone this week helped Ukrainian troops attack a military training facility of Russian troops in Zaporizhzhia Oblast in Russian-occupied southern Ukraine.</p>

<p>As the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-ukraines-dragon-drone-rains-molten-metal-on-russian-positions-6510999" target="_blank">Ukrainian drone spotted the Russian troops</a>, a 660-pound rocket, reportedly packed with hundreds of grenade-sized submunitions, attacked them.</p>

<p>At the time of the attack on October 15, there were about 24 soldiers in the area, Ukraine's Southern Defense Forces said in a statement on Facebook without specifying the number of casualties.</p>

<p>They also tagged a video that showed the drone footage of an initial explosion at the facility followed by a number of additional blasts in the area.</p>

<p><iframe allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="true" frameborder="0" height="314" scrolling="no" src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/video.php?height=314&amp;href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2F61558717479769%2Fvideos%2F1724450694982369%2F&amp;show_text=false&amp;width=560&amp;t=0" style="border:none;overflow:hidden" width="560"></iframe></p>

<p>According to reports, there have been about seven attacks on Russian trainees all along the 700-mile front line since February.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">GMLRS cluster munitions cover a pile of Russian infantry at another training ground in the South.<br />
<br />
The adjustments were carried out by operators of the 128th Separate Mechanized Brigade and the Black Forest Brigade using Shark reconnaissance UAVs. <a href="https://t.co/YYZvGegr5u">pic.twitter.com/YYZvGegr5u</a></p>
— WarTranslated (Dmitri) (@wartranslated) <a href="https://twitter.com/wartranslated/status/1846526541943001265?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 16, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Ukraine claims it has <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukraine-says-downed-69-drones-2-missiles-in-overnight-russian-attack-6668506" target="_blank">killed about 6.7 lakh Russian troops</a> since the war began in 2022. The Ukrainian Defence Forces said on Saturday that they have destroyed 144 Russian artillery brigades, equivalent to $ 8 billion, this year.</p>

<p>Earlier today, regional officials said that Ukraine launched a series of drones targeting Moscow and western Russia.</p>

<p>Russia's air-defence units destroyed at least one drone flying towards Moscow, the mayor of the Russian capital, Sergei Sobyanin said.</p>

<p>According to preliminary information, there was no damage or casualties where debris fell in the Ramensky district of the Moscow region.</p>

<p>Drone debris sparked several short-lived fires in the Lipetsk region in southwestern Russia, the region's governor said. No injuries were reported, he added.</p>

<p>Governors of the Bryansk and Oryol regions, also in western parts of Russia, reported that air defence units destroyed several drones there.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-ukraine-swap-190-pows-ministry-6823089" target="_blank">Ukraine</a> has often said in the past that its air attacks target infrastructure key to Russia's war efforts and are a response to Moscow's continued air attacks.</p>

<p>Russian officials, on the other hand, often do not disclose the full extent of damage inflicted by the drone attacks, especially on military, transport or energy infrastructure.</p>

<p><strong><em>(With agency inputs)</em></strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/c6ssfklg_ukraine-drone-attack_625x300_20_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[There were about 24 Russian soldiers in the area]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/diwali-at-times-square-indians-mark-festival-of-lights-ahead-of-us-polls-6829827]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Diwali At Times Square: Indians Mark Festival Of Lights Ahead Of US Polls]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/diwali-at-times-square-indians-mark-festival-of-lights-ahead-of-us-polls-6829827]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 20 Oct 2024 09:19:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Celebrations sparkled up the Times Square in New York City yesterday as the Indian community and several US citizens gathered to observe the Hindu festival of lights.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Celebrations sparkled up the Times Square in New York City yesterday as the Indian community and several US citizens gathered to observe the Hindu festival of lights.</p>

<p>The event featured performances from various cultural groups. Among the notable attendees were Mayor Eric Adams, New York State Assemblywoman Jennifer Rajkumar, Senator Chuck Schumer and Consul General of India in New York, Binaya Pradhan. Ms Rajkumar has been a key advocate for recognizing Diwali as a school holiday in the USA throughout.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Mayor Adams took to social media platform X (formerly, Twitter) to address the event.</p>

<p>"Proud to be with our Hindu brothers and sisters today for the annual Diwali at Times Square celebration as we push away the darkness and welcome in light all across our city," he wrote.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">What better place to celebrate the festival of lights than in the Crossroads of the World?<br />
<br />
Proud to be with our Hindu brothers and sisters today for the annual Diwali at Times Square celebration as we push away the darkness and welcome in light all across our city. <a href="https://t.co/VauEgY14IO">pic.twitter.com/VauEgY14IO</a></p>
— Mayor Eric Adams (@NYCMayor) <a href="https://twitter.com/NYCMayor/status/1847790041319264642?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 20, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The official Twitter account of the Consulate General of India, New York also shared pictures of the glamourous celebrations on social media.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Diwali @ TimesSquare : Indian American Community &amp; American Friends join together at Times Square to celebrate Diwali.<a href="https://twitter.com/narendramodi?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@narendramodi</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/PMOIndia?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@PMOIndia</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/MEAIndia?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@MEAIndia</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/IndianEmbassyUS?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@IndianEmbassyUS</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/IndianDiplomacy?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@IndianDiplomacy</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/diaspora_india?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@diaspora_india</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/binaysrikant76?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@binaysrikant76</a> <a href="https://t.co/kylTXrtbni">pic.twitter.com/kylTXrtbni</a></p>
— India in New York (@IndiainNewYork) <a href="https://twitter.com/IndiainNewYork/status/1847799184637747233?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 20, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Neeta Bhasin, founder of Diwali at Times Square, also played an instrumental role during the celebration. The festivities culminated in a ceremonial lighting of diyas (lamps), symbolizing hope and renewal.</p>

<p>Diwali has been celebrated in the heart of New York City since 2013. As attendees gathered to witness this moment, they were reminded of the festival's core values and its ability to unite diverse communities.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">CG <a href="https://twitter.com/binaysrikant76?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@binaysrikant76</a> joined friends from Indian-American Community &amp; American friends to celebrate Diwali; Spl thanks to Senate Majority Leader Senator <a href="https://twitter.com/SenSchumer?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@SenSchumer</a> , Mayor Eric Adams <a href="https://twitter.com/NYCMayor?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@NYCMayor</a> , Assemblywoman <a href="https://twitter.com/JeniferRajkumar?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@JeniferRajkumar</a> for joining &amp; to main organiser of the event Ms. Neeta… <a href="https://t.co/Ul7gsLoiYb">pic.twitter.com/Ul7gsLoiYb</a></p>
— India in New York (@IndiainNewYork) <a href="https://twitter.com/IndiainNewYork/status/1847799893357973844?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 20, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Diwali has also been officially recognized as a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/diwali-to-become-school-holiday-in-new-york-4155467">school holiday</a> in New York City last year.&nbsp;About 4.4 million Indian origin people reside in the US with persons of Indian origin constituting the third largest Asian ethnic group in the US, according to ANI.&nbsp;New York, San Francisco and Chicago metropolitan areas are places in the USA which have the highest population of the Indian community in the country.</p>

<p>Another event to commemorate Diwali was organised by the Indian Consulate in Pennsylvania.&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Deputy Consul General <a href="https://twitter.com/VarunJeph?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@varunjeph</a> joined the Diwali celebrations by Khalsa Asian American Association in Upper Darby, Pennsylvania along with members of the Indian diaspora and Asian American community.<br />
<br />
Thank you <a href="https://twitter.com/UpperDarbyPA?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@UpperDarbyPA</a> Mayor Ed Brown and PA State Senator Tim Kearny… <a href="https://t.co/6LzwVJ3FR1">pic.twitter.com/6LzwVJ3FR1</a></p>
— India in New York (@IndiainNewYork) <a href="https://twitter.com/IndiainNewYork/status/1847812073574539311?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 20, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Deputy Consul General Varun Jeph joined the Diwali celebrations by the Khalsa Asian American Association along with members of the Indian and Asian American community.</p>

<p>While the festive spirit, through such events and recognitions, continues to exhibit an attempt at endeavours towards fostering a spirit of unity and equality, the Asian American Pacific Islander (AAPI)'s recent report showed another side of South Asian experiences. As reported by <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/online-hate-against-south-asian-americans-rises-steadily-report-says-2024-10-09/">Reuters</a>, the AAPI <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://stopaapihate.org/2024/10/09/south-asian-report-oct24-press-release/">study</a> shows that South Asian people in the US have been facing alarmingly high levels of hate ahead of the 2024 elections, which transcends not just to the common people but also to heavyweights such as Kamala Harris, and Usha Vance. Such celebrations of South Asian festivities thus do their bit in bringing together the diverse communities in a dazzling show of vibrant unity across the globe.</p>

<p>Last year, Prime Minister Narendra Modi sent a video message to 'the attendees, emphasizing the festival's role in promoting unity and goodwill. He stated that Diwali serves as a reminder of the victory of good over evil and the importance of knowledge over ignorance. He has also highlighted the importance of the Indian community in the US and referred to them as a 'living bridge' connecting the two places. Diwali falls on November 1st this year.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/7rcvaago_diwali-nyc-usa-_625x300_20_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Diwali has been celebrated in the heart of New York City since 2013.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/35-pay-raise-7-000-signing-bonus-boeings-deal-with-protesting-workers-6829618]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[35% Pay Raise, $7,000 Signing Bonus: Boeing's Deal With Protesting Workers]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/35-pay-raise-7-000-signing-bonus-boeings-deal-with-protesting-workers-6829618]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 20 Oct 2024 08:22:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Boeing workers began a strike on September 13 in a dispute over pay and other compensation issues.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Boeing and its striking Seattle-area workers have reached a tentative deal to end a more than month-long stoppage, the union said Saturday. Boeing confirmed a tentative deal was reached and said it includes a 35 percent pay raise over four years and a one-time signing bonus of $7,000. Union members will vote Wednesday on the proposal.</p>

<p>The strike began September 13 in a dispute over pay and other compensation issues, the International Association of Machinists and Aerospace Workers said on social media platform X in a message to its members.</p>

<p>"It warrants presenting to the members and is worthy of your consideration," IAM Union District 751 said.</p>

<p>The strike by some 33,000 unionized workers, mainly in Washington state, halted work at two Seattle-area assembly plants and production of its 737 MAX planes.</p>

<p>The workers were seeking hefty wage hikes and other gains, complaining of more than a decade of near-flat wages amid inflation.</p>

<p>Wage increases had been a stumbling block. Boeing first offered a 25 percent raise, and then 30 percent, while the union wanted 40 percent.</p>

<p>Workers had also been pressing for the restoration of a traditional employer-paid pension plan, which Boeing withdrew in 2014, but they did not get it.</p>

<p>Such retirement plans had been a staple of the American workplace for decades but they are now rare, as the onus for preparing for old age has shifted from employer to employee.</p>

<p>Instead, among the sweeteners Boeing is now offering are enhanced contributions to largely worker-funded retirement schemes called 401(k) plans.</p>

<p>The strike has cost an estimated $7.6 billion in direct losses -- including at least $4.35 billion for Boeing and almost $2 billion for its suppliers -- the Anderson Economic Group consultancy said Friday.</p>

<p>Boeing said in a one-sentence statement, "We look forward to our employees voting on the negotiated proposal."</p>

<p>The work stoppage added to the company's litany of problems.</p>

<p>Boeing sank into further turmoil in January when a window panel blew out mid-flight on an Alaska Airlines plane, necessitating an emergency landing on a 737 MAX, the aircraft involved in two fatal crashes in 2018 and 2019.</p>

<p>That led to the Federal Aviation Administration tightening oversight of Boeing's production processes, capping the company's output.&nbsp;</p>

<p>This week Boeing unveiled measures meant to replenish its cash flow, including an intention to raise up to $25 billion, as it navigated recurrent production problems and the strike.</p>

<p>Last week, Boeing said it planned to cut 10 percent of its workforce as it projected a large third-quarter loss in the wake of the labor action.</p>

<p>The cuts of 17,000 positions globally will include executives, managers and employees, according to Chief Executive Kelly Ortberg, who added that the company must "reset our workforce levels to align with our financial reality."</p>

<p>In other fallout from the strike, Boeing has said it is pushing back first delivery of its 777X plane to 2026 from 2025.</p>

<p>The much-delayed jet was originally supposed to enter service in January 2020.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/176cls7o_boeing_625x300_20_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Union members will vote Wednesday on the proposal.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-man-bites-off-teen-girls-face-in-front-of-horrified-bus-passengers-6829576]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK Man Bites Off Teen Girl's Face In Front Of Horrified Bus Passengers]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-man-bites-off-teen-girls-face-in-front-of-horrified-bus-passengers-6829576]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 20 Oct 2024 08:11:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 19-year-old girl suffered a horrific attack on a bus when a stranger bit off part of her face, leaving her requiring 50 stitches.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A teenager in the UK suffered a horrific attack on a bus when an inebriated stranger allegedly assaulted her. According to <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://metro.co.uk/2024/10/18/girl-19-face-bitten-off-stranger-bus-front-passengers-21825416/">Metro, </a></em>the incident occurred last year when Darren Taylor, 53, began making inappropriate comments about Ella Dowling and her friends. An argument between them followed, but as the bus pulled up at the Promenade and the teen tried to get off, Taylor lunged at her.&nbsp;He grabbed the 19-year-old's face and repeatedly bit her nose and mouth. The violent assault lasted approximately five minutes, leaving Ms Dowling severely injured.</p>

<p>With the help of her friends, she managed to escape and bystanders held Taylor until the police arrived. He was arrested for causing grievous bodily harm with intent after leaving the teen student severely injured. Her&nbsp;left nostril to the lower part of her top lip was detached, except for a thin layer of skin. Her lip on the right side was also split open and she had visible bite marks over her nose and mouth.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The young woman was quickly taken to Cheltenham General Hospital before moving to Gloucestershire Royal Hospital for emergency surgery. She required 50 stitches for her injuries.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In March 2024, Taylor pleaded guilty to GBH with intent at Gloucester Crown Court. On July 18, he received a sentence of six years and nine months in prison, accompanied by a lifelong restraining order.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">A man has been jailed after he bit a woman's face and caused significant injuries to her.<br />
<br />
Darren Taylor attacked the 19-year-old victim on a bus in <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Cheltenham?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Cheltenham</a> in November last year (2023).<br />
<br />
More on the case here: <a href="https://t.co/0WYEbnqmXt">https://t.co/0WYEbnqmXt</a> <a href="https://t.co/2PHcZU1Kbp">pic.twitter.com/2PHcZU1Kbp</a></p>
— Gloucestershire Constabulary (@Glos_Police) <a href="https://twitter.com/Glos_Police/status/1821901770844487798?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 9, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>Ella, a social work student at Portsmouth University from Cheltenham, Gloucestershire, said, ''The pain I felt when he sank his teeth into my face is something which will stay with me forever. He was like a dog with a toy – moving his head side to side. I put my hands around the back of his head because I knew if I didn't he would rip my lip and nose off completely. When I saw my face for the first time after the attack, I didn't recognise my own reflection, and I couldn't look in the mirror for months after that.''</p>

<p>Ms Dowling revealed that the traumatic experience left her with lasting effects. She hasn't taken the bus since the incident due to her post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD). Whenever she leaves her house, she requires constant reassurance, needing to be on the phone with her mother or a friend due to an intense fear of being attacked again.</p>

<p>She added, ''People say my scar is healing well but for me, it's more than a scar, it's a disfigurement and a permanent reminder of what's happened to me. I smile and speak differently which is something I'm going to have to learn to live with for the rest of my life.''</p>

<p>Detective Constable Sophie McGough commented, ''The injuries Taylor caused were some of the worst I have ever seen. His actions that evening were dreadful, and I am relieved that he will now serve time behind bars.''</p>

<p></p>

<p></p>

<p></p>

<p></p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/b84jciog_darren-taylor_625x300_20_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Darren Taylor has been sentenced to almost seven years in prison after the attack]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-backs-paper-ballots-for-us-polls-claims-voting-machines-rig-elections-6829458]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Musk Backs Paper Ballots For US Polls, Claims Voting Machines Rig Elections]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-backs-paper-ballots-for-us-polls-claims-voting-machines-rig-elections-6829458]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 20 Oct 2024 07:36:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Elon Musk, the owner of X, while speaking at a town hall in the swing state of Pennsylvania, claimed that voting machines rig elections, ABC News reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Elon Musk, the owner of X, while speaking at a town hall in the swing state of Pennsylvania, claimed that voting machines rig elections, ABC News reported.</p>

<p>Musk is on a speaking tour around Pennsylvania, ABC News reported.</p>

<p>In his speech, Musk linked voting machines by Dominion to Republicans' losses in Philadelphia and Arizona, saying, "There's always a sort of question of like, say, the Dominion voting machines. It is weird that you know, I think they're used in Philadelphia and Maricopa County, but not in a lot of other places," ABC News reported. "Doesn't that seem like a heck of a coincidence?" Musk said while calling for states around the country to "only do paper ballots, hand-counted."</p>

<p>Elon Musk emerged as a staunch supporter of Presidential Republican candidate Donald Trump and donated USD 75 million to his Political Action Committee to put Trump back in the White House. The donation made Musk one of the largest spenders of the 2024 cycle, as per ABC News.</p>

<p>"I'm a technologist, I know a lot about computers," Musk told the crowd during the event on Thursday (local time). "And I'm like, the last thing I would do is trust a computer program, because it's just too easy to hack."</p>

<p>Musk mentioned a voting machine company Dominion, which last year sued Fox News for defamation over the network's claims that it engaged in a vote-rigging conspiracy, then agreed to a landmark USD 787 million settlement with the network, as per ABC reported.</p>

<p>A statement given by Dominion's spokesperson following Musk's comments said, "Fact: Dominion does not serve Philadelphia County. Fact: Dominion's voting systems are already based on voter verified paper ballots. Fact: Hand counts and audits of such paper ballots have repeatedly proven that Dominion machines produce accurate results. These are not matters of opinion. They are verifiable facts," ABC News quoted.</p>

<p>ABC News reported that even before Musk's comments, Dominion issued a statement, encouraging voters to rely on verified sources of information with regards to elections.</p>

<p>"We are closely monitoring claims around the 2024 election. We strongly encourage people to rely upon verified, credible sources of election information -- sources who can fully explain the many layers of physical, operational, and technical safeguards that exist to protect the integrity of our elections, including voting with paper ballots that can be audited and recounted," ABC News quoted Dominion's statement.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/jhsp7d2_elon-musk_625x300_21_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Elon Musk is on a speaking tour around Pennsylvania. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-releases-footage-showing-yahya-sinwar-hours-ahead-of-hamas-oct-7-attack-6829387]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hamas' Yahya Sinwar Seen Inside Tunnel Hours Before October 7 Attack]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-releases-footage-showing-yahya-sinwar-hours-ahead-of-hamas-oct-7-attack-6829387]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 20 Oct 2024 07:18:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel released footage showing Hamas leader Yahya Sinwar moving his belongings to a tunnel in Gaza hours before the October 7 attack last year that triggered the ongoing war.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel on Saturday released footage showing Hamas leader Yahya Sinwar moving his belongings to a tunnel in Gaza hours before the October 7 attack last year that triggered the ongoing war.</p>

<p>The footage was released following <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-drops-leaflets-over-gaza-showing-yahya-sinwars-body-and-message-to-hamas-6828030">Sinwar's death</a> in the southern Gaza city of Rafah, in a firefight that ended with the Hamas leader cornered and alone in a destroyed building.</p>

<p>The footage shows <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-yahya-sinwar-the-hamas-leader-killed-by-israel-6819037">Sinwar</a> and his wife and children moving belongings, including a television, water, pillows and mattresses, into the tunnel that Israeli army spokesman Rear Admiral Daniel Hagari said was located under the family home in Khan Younis.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">?DECLASSIFIED FOOTAGE:<br />
<br />
Sinwar hours before the October 7 massacre: taking down his TV into his tunnel, hiding underneath his civilians, and preparing to watch his terrorists murder, kindap and rape. <a href="https://t.co/wTAF9xAPLU">pic.twitter.com/wTAF9xAPLU</a></p>
— LTC Nadav Shoshani (@LTC_Shoshani) <a href="https://twitter.com/LTC_Shoshani/status/1847704609156190441?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 19, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>During a press briefing, Hagari showed photos of the underground compound, which had toilets, showers and a kitchen. Food, cash and documents were also found there.</p>

<p>Hamas, meanwhile, said Sinwar died heroically engaging in battle, calling Hagar's remarks "blatant lies".</p>

<p>Drone footage from earlier this week showed Sinwar critically wounded in his last moments, throwing an object at the drone. Autopsy found that Sinwar was killed by a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bullet-in-head-finger-cut-off-chilling-details-of-yahya-sinwars-autopsy-6822817">gunshot to the head</a>, and also found one of his fingers was cut off.</p>

<p>During a year of the Israel-Hamas conflict, the Israel Defence Forces had often closed in on Sinwar, but the latter managed to escape.&nbsp;Israel had identified Sinwar's final hiding after the military found "his DNA sample on a tissue with which he blew his nose," said Hagari.</p>

<p>While the October 7 attack in Israel killed around 1,200 people and resulted in <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/yahya-sinwars-death-clouds-path-to-freeing-israeli-hostages-6824913">235 people being taken hostage</a>, the Israel operation in Gaza over a year has resulted in over 40,000 deaths.</p>

<p>The death of Sinwar, who had just months ago replaced&nbsp;slain predecessor Ismail Haniyeh, raises questions on who will lead the Hamas amid a war that has also drawn in Lebanon. Israeli attacks on Lebanon killed at least 2,350 people over the last year, according to the Lebanese health ministry, with more than 1.2 million people displaced. Hezbollah attacks have killed 50 Israeli soldiers and civilians, according to Israel.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/06f5tq6s_yahya-sinwar_625x300_20_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel said the underground compound had toilets, showers and a kitchen]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-iran-us-leaked-us-intelligence-reports-reveal-israels-plan-of-attack-on-iran-6829355]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Classified US Intelligence Leaked, Documents Show Israel's Plans For Iran]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-iran-us-leaked-us-intelligence-reports-reveal-israels-plan-of-attack-on-iran-6829355]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 20 Oct 2024 07:04:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Two highly classified US intelligence documents have leaked, allegedly exposing Israel's military preparations for a potential strike on Iran, the New York Times reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Two highly classified US intelligence documents have leaked, allegedly exposing <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hits-beirut-gaza-after-assassination-attempt-on-benjamin-netanyahu-by-iran-backed-hezbollah-6829326#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll_Imagetopscroll">Israel</a>'s military preparations for a potential strike on Iran, the New York Times <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/19/us/politics/us-intelligence-israel-iran.html" rel="noindex,nofollow" target="_blank">reported</a>. The documents, originating from the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency (NGA) - "responsible for analysing images and information collected by American spy satellites" - offer insights into Israeli military exercises and operational readiness.</p>

<p>The two documents, dated October 15 and 16, were circulated on Telegram by accounts largely associated with pro-Iran sentiments. They provide detailed analyses of satellite images showing Israel's military exercises, which appear to be in preparation for a retaliatory strike on Iran. The potential strike comes in the wake of escalating tensions following an Iranian missile barrage on October 1, itself a retaliation for an earlier Israeli attack.</p>

<p><strong>READ </strong>| <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/netanyahu-says-attempt-by-irans-proxy-hezbollah-to-assassinate-me-and-my-wife-was-a-grave-mistake-6827757">"Grave Mistake": Netanyahu On Hezbollah's "Assassination" Attempt</a></p>

<p>One of the documents is titled "Israel: Air Force Continues Preparations for Strike on Iran" and outlines recent Israeli exercises that seem to rehearse a potential military operation against Iran. These preparations reportedly include air-to-air refuelling operations, search-and-rescue missions, and the repositioning of missile systems in anticipation of potential Iranian strikes. The second document reveals Israeli efforts to move munitions and other military assets to strategic locations.</p>

<p>Although the documents describe Israeli military movements and exercises, they do not provide satellite images themselves. The US intelligence gathered from these images suggests that Israel is gearing up for a strike, but it is unclear whether these documents reveal the full scope of Israel's plans for Iran.</p>

<p><strong>US Response&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p>The leaks have reportedly prompted immediate concern within the US government. US officials are divided over the severity of the leak, with some downplaying its impact given that the documents do not reveal new American capabilities. Others, however, are alarmed by the exposure of Israel's sensitive military plans, particularly at a time of heightened tensions in the Middle East.&nbsp;</p>

<p>President Joe Biden, when asked during a recent trip to Germany whether he was aware of Israel's planned strike on Iran and its targets, responded with a brief "Yes and yes," but declined to elaborate.&nbsp;</p>

<p>While the exact source of the leak remains unknown, early indications suggest that the documents may have been taken by a lower-level US government employee. A joint investigation by the Pentagon, U.S. intelligence agencies, and the FBI is underway to determine how the information was leaked and whether more documents could follow.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/2pt0puu_israel-army-reuters_625x300_31_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[One of the documents is titled "Israel: Air Force Continues Preparations for Strike on Iran".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hits-beirut-gaza-after-assassination-attempt-on-benjamin-netanyahu-by-iran-backed-hezbollah-6829326]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Hits Beirut, Gaza After "Assassination" Attempt On Netanyahu]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hits-beirut-gaza-after-assassination-attempt-on-benjamin-netanyahu-by-iran-backed-hezbollah-6829326]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 20 Oct 2024 06:58:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel on Saturday said it hit Iran-backed group Hezbollah's arms facilities in Beirut and "Hamas terror target" in Gaza after a drone was launched towards Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's residence.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="CetSht_cn">
<ol class="CetSht_ol">
	<li class="CetSht_li"><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/netanyahu-says-attempt-by-irans-proxy-hezbollah-to-assassinate-me-and-my-wife-was-a-grave-mistake-6827757#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">Benjamin Netanyahu's office</a> said a drone was launched towards his residence in the central town of Caesarea, which is about 20 kilometres south of the Haifa city area, which Hezbollah has regularly targeted.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">The Israeli PM and his wife were not home at the time of the attack and there were no injuries.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">"The attempt by Iran's proxy Hezbollah to assassinate me and my wife today was a grave mistake," Netanyahu said in a statement.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Hours after the drone attack, Israel said it struck <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-and-iran-backed-foes-hamas-and-hezbollah-vow-more-war-after-yahya-sinwars-death-6822057" target="_blank">Hezbollah</a> arms facilities in southern Beirut after the Lebanese armed group fired rockets into northern Israel.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">The Israeli military said the strikes targeted "a number of Hezbollah weapons storage facilities and a Hezbollah intelligence headquarters command centre".</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Israel and Hezbollah have been fighting across the Lebanese border since the war in Gaza erupted after <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-searching-for-yahya-sinwars-replacement-outside-gaza-report-6821136" target="_blank">Hamas</a> attacked Israeli towns on October 7 last year.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Later on Saturday, Israeli strikes killed at least 73 people in the northern Gaza town of Beit Lahiya.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Gaza's civil defence agency on Saturday said that a sweeping Israeli military operation had killed more than 400 people in two weeks in the territory's north.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">The death of Hamas leader <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-drops-leaflets-over-gaza-showing-yahya-sinwars-body-and-message-to-hamas-6828030" target="_blank">Yahya Sinwar</a> on Wednesday has further escalated tensions in the Middle East.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Israeli planes on Saturday dropped leaflets over southern Gaza with a picture of Sinwar and the message: "Hamas will no longer rule Gaza".</li>
</ol>
</div>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/kttnpti_israel-hezbollah_625x300_20_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israeli military said the strikes targeted "a number of Hezbollah weapons storage facilities"]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/lost-ghost-story-by-dracula-author-bram-stoker-discovered-in-dublin-6828104]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Lost Ghost Story By 'Dracula' Author Bram Stoker Discovered In Dublin]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/lost-ghost-story-by-dracula-author-bram-stoker-discovered-in-dublin-6828104]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 19 Oct 2024 23:52:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A short story by Bram Stoker, the legendary author of "Dracula", has been unearthed by a lifelong enthusiast in Dublin who stumbled upon the work while browsing in a library archive.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A short story by Bram Stoker, the legendary author of "Dracula", has been unearthed by a lifelong enthusiast in Dublin who stumbled upon the work while browsing in a library archive.</p>

<p>Titled "Gibbet Hill", the story was uncovered by Brian Cleary in a Christmas supplement of the Dublin edition of the Daily Mail newspaper from 1890 and had remained undocumented for more than 130 years.</p>

<p>The rare find, which has never been referenced in any Stoker bibliography or biography, is now being brought to the public for the first time at an exhibition in the Irish capital.</p>

<p>"Dracula", the Gothic, mysterious and supernatural vampire novel from 1897 may have been set in Transylvania and England but its author, Stoker, was a Dubliner.</p>

<p>"I read 'Dracula' as a child and it stuck with me, I read everything from and about Stoker that I could get my hands on," said Cleary, 44, a writer and amateur historian who lives in the Marino neighbourhood of Dublin where the author grew up.</p>

<p>Thanks to "Dracula", Stoker "had a massive impact on popular culture, but is under-appreciated", Cleary told AFP in the Casino at Marino, an opulent 18th-century building near the writer's birthplace that is hosting the exhibition.</p>

<p><strong>'Flabbergasted'</strong></p>

<p>Cleary's journey of discovery began in 2021 when a sudden onset of deafness changed his life.</p>

<p>While on leave to retrain his hearing after having cochlear implant surgery, Cleary visited the National Library of Ireland to indulge his interest in historical literature and the works of Stoker.</p>

<p>There, in October 2023, he chanced upon the hidden literary gem, the "Gibbet Hill" story which he had never heard of before.</p>

<p>"I sat in the library flabbergasted, that I was looking at potentially a lost ghost story from Stoker, especially one from around the time he was writing 'Dracula', with elements of 'Dracula' in it," said Cleary.</p>

<p>"I sat looking at the screen wondering, am I the only living person who had read it? Followed by, what on earth do I do with it?"</p>

<p>Cleary did extensive literary searches to verify the find and consulted Stoker expert and biographer Paul Murray who confirmed the story was unknown, lost and buried in the archives for more than 130 years.</p>

<p>"'Gibbet Hill' is very significant in terms of Stoker's development as a writer, 1890 was when he was a young writer and made his first notes for 'Dracula'," Murray told AFP.</p>

<p>"It's a classic Stoker story, the struggle between good and evil, evil which crops up in exotic and unexplained ways, and is a way station on his route to publishing 'Dracula'."</p>

<p><strong>Illustrations</strong></p>

<p>The macabre tale tells of a sailor murdered by three criminals whose bodies were strung up on a gibbet or hanging gallows on a hill as a ghostly warning to passing travellers.</p>

<p>To celebrate the discovery, "Gibbet Hill" has been captured in a book that features cover art and illustrations inspired by the story by respected Irish artist Paul McKinley.</p>

<p>"It's quite surreal now to be standing next to a picture inspired by three of the characters in the story," said Cleary.</p>

<p>"When Brian sent me the 'Gibbet Hill' there was so much I could work with," said McKinley.</p>

<p>His eery, sometimes sinister illustrations include a "juicy, wet, oily painting" of worms inspired by a young character in the story who has a bunch of earthworms in his hands.</p>

<p>"Making new images for an old story that has been buried for so long" was a "fascinating challenge" said the artist.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/4v3g6gv8_bram-stoker_625x300_19_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["Gibbet Hill" has never been referenced in any Bram Stoker bibliography or biography (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/power-outage-in-cuba-as-electrical-grid-collapses-for-2nd-time-within-hours-6828068]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Power Outage In Cuba As Electrical Grid Collapses For 2nd Time Within Hours]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/power-outage-in-cuba-as-electrical-grid-collapses-for-2nd-time-within-hours-6828068]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 19 Oct 2024 23:46:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Cuba's electrical grid collapsed again early on Saturday morning, state-run media reported, plunging the entire country into blackout for a second time just hours after authorities announced they had begun reestablishing service.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Cuba's electrical grid collapsed again early on Saturday morning, state-run media reported, plunging the entire country into blackout for a second time just hours after authorities announced they had begun reestablishing service.</p>

<p>CubaDebate, one of the islands state-run media outlets, said Cub's grid operator, UNE, had reported at 6:15AM the "total disconnection of the national electro-energetic system."</p>

<p>"The Electric Union is working on its reestablishment," the brief message said.</p>

<p>Cub's electrical grid first collapsed around midday on Friday after one of the island's largest power plants failed, suddenly leaving more than 10 million without power.</p>

<p>Even before the grid's collapse, an electricity shortfall on Friday had forced Cub's communist-run government to send non-essential state workers home and cancel school classes for children as it sought to conserve fuel for generation.</p>

<p>But lights began to flicker on in scattered pockets across the island early in the evening on Friday, offering some hope that power would be restored.</p>

<p>The grid operator has not yet provided any details on what caused the grid to collapse again on Saturday, or how long it will take to reestablish service.</p>

<p>Cub's government has blamed weeks of worsening blackouts - often 10 to 20 hours a day across much of the island - on deteriorating infrastructure, fuel shortages and rising demand.</p>

<p>Strong winds that began with Hurricane Milton last week had also complicated the island's ability to deliver scarce fuel from boats offshore to feed its power plants, officials have said.</p>

<p>Fuel deliveries to the island have dropped off significantly this year, as Venezuela, Russia and Mexico, once key suppliers, have reduced their exports to Cuba.</p>

<p>Key ally Venezuela slashed by half its deliveries of subsidized fuel to Cuba this year, forcing the island to search elsewhere for far more pricey oil on the spot market.</p>

<p>Cuba's government also blames the U.S. trade embargo, as well as sanctions under then-President Donald Trump, for ongoing difficulties in acquiring fuel and spare parts to operate and maintain its oil-fired plants.</p>

<p>The United States on Friday denied any role in the grid collapse in Cuba.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/8jkj67do_cuba-power-outage_625x300_19_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The United States on Friday denied any role in the grid collapse in Cuba.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-drops-leaflets-over-gaza-showing-yahya-sinwars-body-and-message-to-hamas-6828030]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Drops Leaflets Over Gaza Showing Yahya Sinwar's Body]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-drops-leaflets-over-gaza-showing-yahya-sinwars-body-and-message-to-hamas-6828030]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 19 Oct 2024 23:39:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli planes dropped leaflets over southern Gaza on Saturday showing a picture of the dead Hamas chief Yahya Sinwar with the message that "Hamas will no longer rule Gaza", echoing language used by Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli planes dropped leaflets over southern Gaza on Saturday showing a picture of the dead Hamas chief Yahya Sinwar with the message that "Hamas will no longer rule Gaza", echoing language used by Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu.</p>

<p>The move came as Israeli military strikes killed at least 35 people across the Gaza Strip and its forces tightened a siege around hospitals in Jabalia in the north of the enclave, Palestinian health officials said.</p>

<p>"Whoever drops the weapon and hands over the hostages will be allowed to leave and live in peace," the leaflet, written in Arabic, read, according to residents of the southern city of Khan Younis and images circulating online.</p>

<p>The leaflet's wording was from a statement by Netanyahu on Thursday after Sinwar was killed by Israeli soldiers operating in Rafah, in the south near the Egyptian border, on Wednesday.</p>

<p>The October 7 attack Sinwar planned on Israeli communities a year ago killed around 1,200 people, with another 253 dragged back to Gaza as hostages, according to Israeli tallies.</p>

<p>Israel's subsequent war has devastated Gaza, killing more than 42,500 Palestinians, with another 10,000 uncounted dead thought to lie under the rubble, Gaza health authorities say.</p>

<p>In the central Gaza Strip camp of Al-Maghzai, an Israeli strike on a house killed 11 people, while another strike at the nearby camp of Nuseirat killed four others.</p>

<p>Five other people were killed in two separate strikes in the south Gaza cities of Khan Younis and Rafah, medics said, while seven Palestinians were killed in the Shati camp in the northern Gaza Strip.</p>

<p>Later on Saturday, an Israeli strike killed three Palestinians in Nuseirat in central Gaza, medics said.</p>

<p>Late on Friday, medics said 33 people, mostly women and children, were killed and 85 others were wounded in Israeli strikes that destroyed at least three houses in Jabalia.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said it was unaware of that incident.</p>

<p>It said forces were continuing operations against Hamas across the enclave, killing several gunmen in Rafah and Jabalia and dismantling military infrastructure. Palestinian medics said five people were killed in Jabalia on Saturday.</p>

<p><strong>EVACUATION ORDERS</strong></p>

<p>Residents and medics said Israeli forces had tightened their siege on Jabalia, the largest of the enclave's eight historic camps, which it encircled by also sending tanks to nearby towns of Beit Hanoun and Beit Lahiya and issuing evacuation orders to residents.</p>

<p>Israeli officials said evacuation orders were aimed at separating Hamas fighters from civilians and denied that there was any systematic plan to clear civilians out of Jabalia or other northern areas.</p>

<p>In Jabalia, residents said Israeli army forces besieged several shelters housing displaced families before they stormed them and detained dozens of men. Footage circulated on social media, which Reuters could not immediately verify, showed dozens of Palestinian men sitting on the ground next to a tank, while others were led by a soldier to a gathering site.</p>

<p>Residents and medical officials said Israeli forces were bombing houses and besieging hospitals, preventing medical and food supplies from entering to force them to leave the camp.</p>

<p>Health officials said they refused orders by the Israeli army to evacuate the hospital or leave the patients, many in a critical condition, unattended.</p>

<p>"The Israeli occupation is intensifying its targeting of the health system in the northern Gaza Strip, by besieging and directly targeting the Indonesian Hospital, Kamal Adwan Hospital, and Al-Awda Hospital during the past hours and its insistence on putting them out of service," the Gaza health ministry said.</p>

<p>It said two patients in intensive care at the Indonesian Hospital died "as a result of the hospital's siege and the power outage and medical supplies".</p>

<p>Israel's military said the troops operating in the area had been "briefed on the importance of mitigating harm to civilians and medical infrastructure".</p>

<p>"It is emphasized that the hospital continues to operate without disruption and in full capacity, and there was no intentional fire directed at it," it said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/ho12kj4g_gaza-reuters_625x300_19_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The message on leaflets read "Hamas will no longer rule Gaza" (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-consulate-in-myanmar-hit-with-explosive-device-report-6828015]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[China Consulate In Myanmar Hit With Explosive Device: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-consulate-in-myanmar-hit-with-explosive-device-report-6828015]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 19 Oct 2024 23:34:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[China's consulate in Myanmar's city of Mandalay was attacked with an explosive device, local media said Saturday, adding that no deaths or injuries were reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>China's consulate in Myanmar's city of Mandalay was attacked with an explosive device, local media said Saturday, adding that no deaths or injuries were reported.</p>

<p>The blast occurred at the consulate office in central Mandalay, south of the sprawling Royal Palace, around 7 pm Friday (1230 GMT Friday), local media said.</p>

<p>China is a major ally and arms supplier to Myanmar's junta, but it also maintains ties with ethnic groups fighting the military in Myanmar's northern Shan state, according to analysts.</p>

<p>Myanmar has been in turmoil since the military deposed the government of Aung San Suu Kyi and seized power in 2021.</p>

<p>A statement from the junta on Saturday night blamed "terrorists" for the incident, which it said it was investigating in cooperation with consulate officials.</p>

<p>It said security had found "a blast" had occurred and that it was "raising the necessary security measures".</p>

<p>"About two feet of clay tiles of the roof of the two-storey building were damaged," the statement said.</p>

<p>A Myanmar official in Mandalay confirmed to AFP there had been "an incident at the Chinese consulate office compound in Mandalay late evening yesterday".</p>

<p>"There was no one injured," the official said, without specifying the nature of the incident.</p>

<p>The Irrawaddy outlet reported a grenade had been thrown at the compound, which is usually guarded by members of Myanmar's security forces.</p>

<p>The Voice of Myanmar newspaper reported the consulate had been hit by an unidentified "explosion" without giving details.</p>

<p>China's embassy in Yangon did not respond to AFP's queries.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-06/78bgh10o_china-flag_625x300_12_June_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[China is a major ally and arms supplier to Myanmar's junta (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>