<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Sat, 21 Sep 2024 05:43:58 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/un-security-council-meets-in-emergency-session-over-lebanon-6614012]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UN Security Council Meets In Emergency Session Over Lebanon]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/un-security-council-meets-in-emergency-session-over-lebanon-6614012]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 21 Sep 2024 05:41:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The UN Security Council has met in an emergency session on Lebanon, following an uptick in cross-border fire between Hezbollah and Israeli forces, and deadly wireless device explosions targeting members of the militant group.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The UN Security Council has met in an emergency session on Lebanon, following an uptick in cross-border fire between Hezbollah and Israeli forces, and deadly wireless device explosions targeting members of the militant group.</p>

<p>Rosemary DiCarlo, UN under-secretary-general for political and peacebuilding affairs, said on Friday that alarming developments in Lebanon and the region have come after nearly one year of hostilities on an almost daily basis across the Blue Line, a buffer zone separating Israel and Lebanon, Xinhua news agency reported.</p>

<p>"These exchanges have been a repeated breach of the cessation of hostilities and in violation of (Security Council) resolution 1701," she said.</p>

<p>Abdallah Bou Habib, Lebanon's foreign minister, said "Israel, through this terrorist aggression, has violated the basic principles of international humanitarian law ... and indiscriminately targeted civilians."</p>

<p>Denouncing Israel as "a rogue state," he called on the council to condemn the recent attacks, implement resolution 1701 and stand on the right side of history.</p>

<p>"Isn't this terrorism when you target a whole population while they tend to their daily life and not fighting on the front?" he asked.</p>

<p>Speaking on behalf of the Arab Group, Syria's permanent representative to the United Nations Koussay Aldahhak said the devastating recent attacks were deployed without any regard to international law or to humanity.</p>

<p>He said the Arab Group demands the Security Council condemn this cyberterrorism and Israel's aggressions against the Palestinian people in Gaza and attacks on other countries, including Syria.</p>

<p>In his national capacity, Aldahhak said Syria condemns the aggression and ongoing terrorism against the Lebanese people.</p>

<p>Speaking in his national capacity, Samuel Zbogar of Slovenia, which holds the Security Council presidency for September, said "We are stepping in a dangerous new territory and as new technology is being used and developed, we underline the need to respect the existing legal obligations."</p>

<p>He called on the Security Council to act before the situation in the region spirals beyond control, emphasizing that diplomacy must be the only path forward.</p>

<p>Danny Danon, Israel's permanent representative to the United Nations, said his country did not seek the war, stating that on October 8, when Israeli citizens in the south were being "slaughtered" by Hamas, Hezbollah "unleased hundreds of rockets" in the north against civilians.</p>

<p>He said that since then, more than 8,000 rockets have "rained down" on Israel, killing 46 people and injuring a further 294. Danon added that Israel's objective is to "restore security to our northern borders" and "bring our people home."</p>

<p>"We are very concerned at the heightened escalation across the Blue Line, including the deadly strike we saw on Beirut today," Stephane Dujarric, spokesman for UN Secretary-General Antonio Guterres, said at a daily briefing.</p>

<p>He urged all parties to de-escalate immediately, exercise "maximum restraint" and "immediately return to the cessation of hostilities and to fully implement Security Council resolution 1701."</p>

<p>Warning that the region is "on the brink of a catastrophe," he said all efforts should focus on finding a diplomatic solution.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-12/d2l8jjd_un-security-council_625x300_09_December_23.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The UN Security Council has met in an emergency session on Lebanon following attacks against Hezbollah.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-confirms-senior-commander-ibrahim-akil-killed-in-israeli-airstrike-6613957]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hezbollah Confirms Senior Commander Killed In Israeli Airstrike]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-confirms-senior-commander-ibrahim-akil-killed-in-israeli-airstrike-6613957]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 21 Sep 2024 05:26:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Lebanon's Hezbollah on Friday night mourned the acting commander of its Elite Radwan Force, Ibrahim Akil, who was killed earlier in the day by an Israeli airstrike on Beirut's southern suburbs.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lebanon's Hezbollah on Friday night mourned the acting commander of its Elite Radwan Force, Ibrahim Akil, who was killed earlier in the day by an Israeli airstrike on Beirut's southern suburbs.</p>

<p>"Today, the great jihadist leader Ibrahim Akil joined the procession of his brothers, the great martyr leaders, after a blessed life full of jihad, work, wounds, sacrifices, risks, challenges, achievements, and victories," read a statement released late Friday by Hezbollah.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the local MTV channel reported that the body of Akil was found along with seven other members of Hezbollah's Elite Radwan Force.</p>

<p>The channel reported earlier that the whole command committee of the Elite Radwan Force was meeting in the building that was targeted by the Israeli airstrike.</p>

<p>Civil defence teams are still searching for bodies under the rubble, Xinhua news agency reported.</p>

<p>According to the Health Ministry, the Israeli airstrike has killed 14 people and injured 66 others.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/e02n2u88_israellebanon-conflict-afp_625x300_07_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[According to the Health Ministry, the Israeli airstrike has killed 14 people and injured 66 others.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-secret-service-director-admits-complacency-at-july-donald-trump-rally-6613844]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Secret Service Director Admits "Complacency" At July Trump Rally]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-secret-service-director-admits-complacency-at-july-donald-trump-rally-6613844]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 21 Sep 2024 04:49:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The US Secret Service on Friday detailed a litany of failures uncovered by its review of the attempted assassination of former president Donald Trump at a rally in July.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The US Secret Service on Friday detailed a litany of failures uncovered by its review of the attempted assassination of former president Donald Trump at a rally in July.</p>

<p>Shooter Thomas Matthew Crooks was able to open fire from a nearby rooftop at the outdoor event held by Republican election candidate Trump, who narrowly escaped death and suffered a wound to his right ear.</p>

<p>The review "identified deficiencies in the advanced planning and its implementation," Acting Director Ronald Rowe Jr. said at a press briefing.</p>

<p>"While some members of the advance team were very diligent, there was complacency on the part of others that led to a breach of security protocols."</p>

<p><strong>- Alerts 'not relayed' -</strong></p>

<p>Among the failures identified by Rowe were poor communication with local law enforcement, an "over-reliance" on mobile devices "resulting in information being siloed" and line of sight issues, which "were acknowledged but not properly mitigated."</p>

<p>"At approximately 18:10 local time, by a phone call, the Secret Service security room calls the countersniper response agent reporting an individual on the roof of the AGR building," Rowe recounted.</p>

<p>"That vital piece of information was not relayed over the Secret Service radio network."</p>

<p>Two attendees of the rally in Butler, Pennsylvania were injured from gunfire and a third, 50-year-old firefighter Corey Comperatore, died as a result.</p>

<p>Crooks was shot dead on the roof by Secret Service personnel.</p>

<p>Secret Service director Kimberly Cheatle resigned in the aftermath of the dramatic incident, and several Secret Service agents have been put on leave.</p>

<p>Rowe said the Secret Service needed additional funding, personnel and equipment to complete a "paradigm shift...from a state of reaction to a state of readiness."</p>

<p>The Congressional task force investigating the attempted assassination of Trump issued a statement Friday encouraging Rowe to "follow through" on holding employees accountable and to cooperate with its independent investigation.</p>

<p>"Complacency has no place in the Secret Service," the task force said.</p>

<p>The US House of Representatives unanimously passed a bill Friday to boost Secret Service protection for presidential candidates to the same level as sitting presidents and vice presidents.</p>

<p>The bill now awaits a vote in the Senate and a signature by President Joe Biden before it becomes law.</p>

<p>Rowe said that Trump is now being given the same levels of protection as the president.</p>

<p>The increased demand for security came into sharp focus again after a second apparent assassination attempt on Trump's life at his golf course in West Palm Beach, Florida last weekend.</p>

<p>"What occurred on Sunday demonstrates that the threat environment in which the Secret Service operates is tremendous," Rowe said.</p>

<p>The gunman in Florida did not have a line of sight on the former president and failed to fire a shot before he was discovered and arrested, officials say.</p>

<p>Trump has sought political advantage by blaming -- without evidence -- Biden and Democratic election rival Kamala Harris for fueling motivation behind the plots, citing their "rhetoric" about him endangering democracy.</p>

<p>Both Biden and Harris have repeatedly denounced the assassination bids and any political violence, with Biden calling for Congress to provide more resources for the Secret Service.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/bokt02qg_donald-trump-shooting_625x300_14_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Shooter was able to open fire from a nearby rooftop at the outdoor event held by Trump in July.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/quad-may-announce-expansion-of-maritime-pact-to-indian-ocean-white-house-6613641]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Quad May Announce Expansion Of Maritime Pact To Indian Ocean: White House]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/quad-may-announce-expansion-of-maritime-pact-to-indian-ocean-white-house-6613641]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 21 Sep 2024 03:31:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The QUAD summit has plans to expand the Indo-Pacific Partnership for Maritime Domain Awareness initiative from South East Asia to the Indian Ocean Region, the White House said Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The QUAD summit has plans to expand the Indo-Pacific Partnership for Maritime Domain Awareness initiative from South East Asia to the Indian Ocean Region, the White House said Friday.</p>

<p>The QUAD leadership summit begins Saturday in Wilmington, Delaware, with participation of the four member states -- India, US, Japan, and Australia.</p>

<p>The maritime initiative which seeks to keep a check on illegal activities on seas was first launched at the QUAD Leaders Summit in Tokyo two years ago.</p>

<p>A formal announcement about the expansion will be made in Wilmington on Saturday, a senior administration official told reporters on condition of anonymity Besides the expansion, the partnership will now include "new sophisticated technologies to improve the maritime domain picture", as well as new training programmes, the official said.</p>

<p>Another senior administration official said the expansion of the IPMDA to the Indian Ocean "provides opportunities, not just for Australia to coordinate with us in the Pacific, but also with India to coordinate more with a lot of our partners in the Indian Ocean region." "We are also going to be launching as part of our new quad development, increased work together on logistics cooperation. The advent of the QUAD was responding to humanitarian disasters.</p>

<p>"All of our countries have a lot of capacity when it comes to logistics, in the air, at the sea, to respond to these kinds of disasters. We are really pleased that we're going to be piloting this next year with some new work that will allow us to work more closely in this space," the official said.</p>

<p>Responding to a question, the official expressed confidence in the QUAD countries' long term future as like-minded democracies.</p>

<p>"We are, of course, four leading democracies and political change is baked into the cake," the person said.</p>

<p>US President Joe Biden will host Prime Minister Narendra Modi, Prime Minister Anthony Albanese of Australia and Prime Minister Kishida Fumio of Japan for the fourth in-person Quad Leaders' Summit on Saturday, September 21.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-05/d3gh6meg_quad-summit-hiroshima_625x300_20_May_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden will host Quad summit today in Delaware, the White House said.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-slams-donald-trump-over-abortion-as-us-starts-voting-6613499]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Hypocrite": Kamala Harris Slams Trump Over Abortion As US Starts Voting]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-slams-donald-trump-over-abortion-as-us-starts-voting-6613499]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 21 Sep 2024 02:45:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kamala Harris on Friday attacked Republican rival Donald Trump and his party as "hypocrites" over abortion, as the first voters cast their ballots for November's knife-edge US election.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kamala Harris on Friday attacked Republican rival Donald Trump and his party as "hypocrites" over abortion, as the first voters cast their ballots for November's knife-edge US election.</p>

<p>The Democrat unleashed one of the most forceful speeches of her campaign so far as she blamed Trump for an abortion ban in the battleground state of Georgia that she said had caused the deaths of two women.</p>

<p>"And these hypocrites want to start talking about how this is in the best interest of women and children," the vice president told a rally in Atlanta, Georgia to cheers from a mainly female audience.</p>

<p>"Well, where have you been? Where have you been when it comes to taking care of the women and children of America, where have you been? How dare they."</p>

<p>Since replacing President Joe Biden at the top of the Democratic ticket two months ago, Harris has repeatedly focused on what she calls "Trump abortion bans."</p>

<p>Trump has frequently bragged on the campaign trail that his three Supreme Court picks paved the way for the 2022 overturning of the national right to abortion.</p>

<p>At least 20 states have since brought in full or partial restrictions, with Georgia banning most abortions after six weeks of pregnancy.</p>

<p>Harris led the crowd in chanting the name of Amber Nicole Thurman, a 28-year-old mother-of-one from Georgia who developed a rare complication from abortion pills and died during emergency surgery in 2022.</p>

<p>An official state committee blamed the fatal outcome on a "preventable" lag in performing a critical procedure.</p>

<p>"We will make sure Amber is not just remembered as a statistic," said Harris, who met Thurman's family during a campaign event hosted by chat show star Oprah Winfrey on Thursday.</p>

<p><strong>- 'Excited' -</strong></p>

<p>Harris's abortion speech came as three US states -- Virginia, Minnesota and South Dakota -- began early voting 46 days before election day in what is an agonizingly close race.</p>

<p>Former president Trump has previously cast doubt on early voting and mail voting to back his false claims that he won the 2020 election against Biden.</p>

<p>Most US states permit in-person voting or mail-in voting to allow people to deal with scheduling conflicts or an inability to cast their ballots on election day itself on November 5.</p>

<p>Dozens of people waited at a polling station in the center of Arlington, Virginia, just outside the capital Washington.</p>

<p>A number had "Harris-Walz" shirts, while there were also some "Trump-Vance" signs in front of the building.</p>

<p>"I'm excited," said Michelle Kilkenny, 55, adding that voting early, "especially on day one, helps the campaign and raises the enthusiasm level."</p>

<p>Ann Spiker, 71, told AFP she usually cast her ballot by mail "but I'm going to vote today because it's so exciting."</p>

<p>The Democratic supporter added: "I can't believe we can pick Donald Trump, when I think about it I become very worried. That's why we're out and doing what we can."</p>

<p>Trump, 78, faces criminal charges for allegedly trying to overturn the 2020 result, after which his supporters assaulted the US Capitol on January 6, 2021.</p>

<p>- 'Abhorrent' -</p>

<p>Every vote will count in the race, whose result Trump has once again refused to say he will accept.</p>

<p>Harris, 59, has erased Trump's lead since sensationally replacing President Biden as Democratic candidate in July, but remains neck-and-neck with the Republican.</p>

<p>The result is expected to hinge on just seven crucial swing states, including Georgia.</p>

<p>Trump however sought to lay the blame for any potential loss at the door of Jewish American voters, sparking outrage on Friday.</p>

<p>"If I don't win this election... in my opinion the Jewish people would have a lot to do with a loss," Trump told an anti-Semitism event on Thursday, repeating his grievance that Jewish voters have historically leaned towards the Democrats.</p>

<p>The White House slammed his comments.</p>

<p>"It is abhorrent to traffic in dangerous tropes or engage in scapegoating at any time -- let alone now, when all leaders have an obligation to fight back against the tragic worldwide rise in anti-Semitism," White House spokesperson Andrew Bates said in a statement.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/pq4qlj0o_kamala-harris-reuters_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kamala Harris on Friday attacked Republican rival Trump and his party as "hypocrites" over abortion.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/un-condemns-lebanon-device-blasts-as-violation-of-international-law-6613285]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UN Condemns Lebanon Device Blasts As Violation Of International Law]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/un-condemns-lebanon-device-blasts-as-violation-of-international-law-6613285]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 21 Sep 2024 01:40:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United Nations on Friday denounced the detonation of hand-held devices used by Hezbollah operatives in Lebanon, saying the attack violated international law and could constitute a war crime.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United Nations on Friday denounced the detonation of hand-held communication devices used by Hezbollah operatives in Lebanon this week, saying the attack violated international law and could constitute a war crime.</p>

<p>"International humanitarian law prohibits the use of booby-trap devices in the form of apparently harmless portable objects," the UN's High Commissioner for Human Rights, Volker Turk, told the Security Council, adding that it "is a war crime to commit violence intended to spread terror among civilians."</p>

<p>The blasts that killed at least 37 people and wounded nearly 3,000 over two days targeted communication devices used by the Iran-backed Hezbollah group.</p>

<p>Pagers and walkie-talkies exploded as their users were shopping in supermarkets, walking on streets and attending funerals, plunging the country into panic.</p>

<p>Hezbollah blamed Israel for the blasts.</p>

<p>"I am appalled by the breadth and impact of the attacks," said Turk.</p>

<p>"These attacks represent a new development in warfare, where communication tools become weapons," he added.</p>

<p>"This cannot be the new normal."</p>

<p>Israel has not commented on the operation but has said it will widen the scope of its war in Gaza to include the Lebanon front.</p>

<p>Speaking to reporters on Friday, Israel's ambassador to the UN refused to comment on the device blasts.</p>

<p>"But I can tell you that we will do everything we can to target those terrorists," Danny Danon said.</p>

<p>He spoke after Israel announced it had killed the commander of Hezbollah's elite unit in a strike on Beirut on Friday.</p>

<p>"We have no intention to enter a war with Hezbollah in Lebanon, but we cannot continue the way it is," Danon said, noting that Israel prefers a diplomatic solution and wants to "prevent" further escalation.</p>

<p>Iran-backed Hezbollah is an ally of Palestinian militant group Hamas, which has been fighting a war in Gaza since its October 7 attack on Israel.</p>

<p>For nearly a year, the focus of Israel's firepower has been on Gaza but its troops have also been engaged in near-daily clashes with Hezbollah militants along its northern border.</p>

<p>Hundreds have been killed in Lebanon, most of them fighters, and dozens in Israel, including soldiers.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/3egae548_lebanon-hospital_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The UN said that the attack violated international law and could constitute a war crime.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ndtv-exclusive-what-sri-lankan-president-ranil-wickremesinghe-seeking-re-election-said-about-india-5-key-quotes-6613217]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What Lankan President, Seeking Re-Election, Said About India: 5 Key Quotes]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ndtv-exclusive-what-sri-lankan-president-ranil-wickremesinghe-seeking-re-election-said-about-india-5-key-quotes-6613217]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 21 Sep 2024 01:15:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A day before Sri Lanka votes for the next President, Ranil Wickremesinghe, who currently occupies the post spoke to NDTV. During the interview, he spoke about his country's special bond with India and how he aims to strengthen ties, if re-elected.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<ol>
	<li>"India and Sri Lanka have to have a close economic relationship. The vision statement that Prime Minister Modi and I had issued mentions this," Mr Wickremesinghe, who is seeking another term as President, told NDTV.</li>
	<li>Speaking further about areas of shared investment and development, Mr Wickremesinghe said, "India has a huge demand of renewable energy, as do we. That is an area we seek to strengthen ties. When the Singapore-India pipeline (via Andaman and Nicobar Islands) is complete, we too can look for opportunity in it."</li>
	<li>Other significant area that he said Sri Lanka aims partner with India for is to enhance port infrastructure and to get more tourists from India. "We want to encourage more investments from India and more tourists from India. We are working together with India on infrastructure projects like the Trincomalee Harbour," he said.</li>
	<li>Speaking about the social and cultural ties shared by the two countries, President Ranil Wickremesinghe said, "that has been happening for thousands of years". He also said that the two nations share very strong people-to-people ties and that it is the people's mutual regard and appreciation that is the bedrock of India-Sri Lanka relations. "There will always be some groups who may make anti-India remarks, what needs to be done is to minimise it. As far as the India-Sri Lanka friendship is concerned, it is decided by the people and they have already decided it. So, let's further strengthen (the bond)."</li>
	<li>India's economy has "taken off", the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ahead-of-sri-lankan-elections-president-ranil-wickremesinghe-tells-ndtv-about-chinas-growing-presence-6604052" target="_blank">Sri Lankan President told NDTV</a>, adding that Sri Lanka would also like to benefit from it, after all India is "just 20 miles away" and the two nations have shared deep cultural and historical ties. Mr Wickremesinghe further said that "Sri Lanka will deal with China as well to fulfill its national objectives, but at the same time, we will always keep India's interests in mind."</li>
</ol>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-09/rcgunci_sri-lanka-ranil-reuters-_625x300_16_September_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sri Lanka Polls: Sri Lankan President Ranil Wickremesinghe, 75, is seeking to be re-elected.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/killed-hezbollah-commander-was-wanted-for-deadly-1983-us-embassy-marine-blasts-6613152]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Killed Hezbollah Commander Was Wanted For Deadly 1983 US Embassy Blast]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/killed-hezbollah-commander-was-wanted-for-deadly-1983-us-embassy-marine-blasts-6613152]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 21 Sep 2024 00:58:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ibrahim Aqil, the Hezbollah operations commander killed in an Israeli strike on Friday, had a $7 million bounty on his head for two 1983 Beirut truck bombings that killed more than 300 people at the American embassy and a U.S. Marines barracks.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ibrahim Aqil, the Hezbollah operations commander killed in an Israeli strike on Friday, had a $7 million bounty on his head for two 1983 Beirut truck bombings that killed more than 300 people at the American embassy and a U.S. Marines barracks.</p>

<p>Two security sources in Lebanon confirmed the veteran fighter was killed in an airstrike on Beirut's southern suburbs during a meeting of the elite Radwan unit of the Iranian-backed Lebanese militant group.</p>

<p>Aqil, who has also used the aliases Tahsin and Abdelqader, was the second member of Hezbollah's top military body, the Jihad Council, to be killed in two months after an Israeli strike in the same area targeted Fuad Shukr in July.</p>

<p>Israel escalated its attacks on the group this week after months of border fighting triggered by the conflict in Gaza that began on Oct. 7 with a deadly raid and hostage-taking in Israel by Hezbollah's Palestinian ally Hamas.</p>

<p>Like Shukr, Aqil is a veteran of Hezbollah, which was founded by Iran's Revolutionary Guards in the early 1980s to battle Israeli forces that had invaded and occupied Lebanon.</p>

<p>Born in a village in Lebanon's Beqaa valley sometime around 1960, Aqil had joined the other big Lebanese Shi'ite political movement, Amal, before switching to Hezbollah as a founding member, according to a security source.</p>

<p>The United States accuses him of a role in the Beirut truck bombings at the American embassy in April 1983, which killed 63 people, and a U.S. Marine barracks six months later that killed 241 people.</p>

<p>It further accused him of directing the abduction of American and German hostages in Lebanon and listed him as a Specially Designated Global Terrorist in 2019, putting the $7 million bounty on his head.</p>

<p>Referring to the bombing of the U.S. Marine barracks and other attacks on Western interests in Lebanon in the 1980s, Hezbollah leader Sayyed Hassan Nasrallah said in a 2022 interview with an Arabic broadcaster that they were carried out by small groups not linked to Hezbollah.</p>

<p>Aqil's cohort of founding Hezbollah operatives helped turn the group from a shadowy militia into Lebanon's most powerful military and political organisation, pushing Israel from its occupation of the south in 2000 and fighting it again in 2006.</p>

<p>When Shukr was killed in July, it was seen as the heaviest blow to its command structure since the 2008 assassination of Imad Mughniyeh, remembered by Hezbollah as a legendary commander but by Israel and the United States as a terrorist.</p>

<p>Aqil, whose bounty was set by the United States at an even higher value than that of Shukr's, may prove a similar blow.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/933oja6g_israel-hamas-war-afp_625x300_11_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Hezbollah operations commander Ibrahim Aqil was killed in an Israeli strike on Friday.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-hack-of-hezbollah-devices-exposes-dark-corners-of-asia-supply-chains-6612932]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How Hack Of Hezbollah Devices Exposes Dark Corners Of Asia Supply Chains]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-hack-of-hezbollah-devices-exposes-dark-corners-of-asia-supply-chains-6612932]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Sep 2024 23:55:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The lethal hack of Hezbollah's Asian-branded pagers and walkie-talkies has sparked an intense search for the devices' path, revealing a murky market for older technologies where buyers may have few assurances about what they are getting.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The lethal hack of Hezbollah's Asian-branded pagers and walkie-talkies has sparked an intense search for the devices' path, revealing a murky market for older technologies where buyers may have few assurances about what they are getting.</p>

<p>While supply chains and distribution channels for higher-margin and newer products are tightly managed, that's not the case for older electronics from Asia where counterfeiting, surplus inventories and complex contract manufacturing deals can sometimes make it impossible to identify the source of a product, analysts and consultants say.</p>

<p>The response from the companies at the centre of the booby-trapped gadgets that killed 37 people and wounded about 3,000 in Lebanon this week has underlined difficulties in discerning how and when they were weaponised.</p>

<p>Taiwan-based Gold Apollo put the blame on a Europe-based licensee of its pager, sparking investigations in Hungary, Bulgaria, Norway and Romania into the origins of the deadly device. Japan's Icom said it could not tell if the walkie-talkies bearing its name were real, in a market awash with fake products.</p>

<p>"If the supply chain was compromised to put explosives inside ... it's incredible engineering to do that. But the actual supply chain compromise is not that hard. Probably the easiest part was the supply chain compromise," said David Fincher, a China-based technologist and consultant.</p>

<p>He said counterfeit products are prevalent, especially in big manufacturing centres like China where fake components can be easily produced, adding that it isn't a big leap to go from fake components to supply chain compromise.</p>

<p>"As the technologist I am, I can tell you getting a little explosive in a radio is not that hard."</p>

<p>Hezbollah acquired the devices around five months ago, according to a security source, who added that the armed group thought it was buying the pagers from Gold Apollo.</p>

<p>The hand-held radios, which the source said were purchased around the same time as the pagers, had labels bearing the name of Osaka-based Icom and the phrase "Made in Japan", images of one exploded device showed.</p>

<p>Both companies have ruled out the possibility that any of the deadly components were made in factories in either of their home locations.</p>

<p>Taiwan's Economy Minister Kuo Jyh-huei has also said the components used in the pagers that detonated in Lebanon were not made in Taiwan.</p>

<p>A preliminary investigation by Lebanese authorities into the devices found that the explosives were implanted before they arrived in the country, according to a letter to the U.N. Security Council by Lebanon's mission to the United Nations.</p>

<p><strong>FAKE GOODS</strong></p>

<p>But, for now, that's about all anyone is certain of. It's not clear how or when the pagers and walkie-talkies were weaponised so they could be remotely detonated.</p>

<p>Joe Simone, partner with Chinese intellectual property firm East IP, said part of the problem is that smaller brands tend to invest less in policing counterfeits, due in large part to costs that could impact their profitability.</p>

<p>"Authorities are happy to deal with low-tech counterfeits but the IP owners need to monitor, investigate and file complaints and that doesn't always happen as much as it might for high-tech and bigger technology brands," he said.</p>

<p>For Icom, one problem is that it stopped making the IC-V82 model in question a decade ago, around the time it started introducing holographic stickers as a protection against counterfeit products, the company said.</p>

<p>The company has long warned about imitation products, especially of its older models.</p>

<p>In fact, more than 7% of firms in Japan reported business losses from counterfeit products in 2020, according to the latest available report by the Japan Patent Office, with around a third of cases linked to China.</p>

<p>Icom has urged that customers only use its official distributor network to ensure they are buying genuine products.</p>

<p>But in China, there are dozens of shops selling Icom-branded walkie-talkies on e-commerce platforms such as Alibaba.com, Taobao, JD.com and Pinduoduo, including in some cases the IC-V82 model, according to Reuters checks.</p>

<p>Among three China-based vendors of Icom products on Alibaba.com, none of which were listed as official suppliers on Icom's website, Guangzhou Minxing Communications Equipment Co and Chengdu Bingxin Technology Co Ltd both said they sell authentic products, while Quanzhou Yitian Trading Co acknowledged selling "Chinese made imitations" in addition to original products.</p>

<p>Icom has said it makes all its products in its factories in Japan. It did not immediately reply to a request for comment on Icom-branded products sold in Chinese online sites.</p>

<p>The discontinued IC-V82 model is also sold in Vietnam on e-commerce platform Shopee, a Reuters check showed, indicating wide availability of such products.</p>

<p>For Gold Apollo, which licensed its brand to Budapest-based BAC, the supply chain devolved into a mysterious production trail that authorities in various countries are now trying to piece together.</p>

<p>"The widespread availability of cheap, second-hand manufacturing equipment meant counterfeiters were increasingly able to go beyond single components and even make full-fledged products," said Diganta Das from the University of Maryland's Center for Advanced Lifecycle Engineering, who studies counterfeit electronics.</p>

<p>"I wouldn't call it counterfeiting anymore, it's like illegal manufacturing," Das said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/ol7bsm98_walkie-talkie-explosion_625x300_20_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hezbollah acquired the devices around five months ago, according to a security source (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-national-tortured-to-death-in-ukraine-by-russian-soldiers-moscow-says-6612920]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US National Tortured To Death In Ukraine By Russian soldiers, Moscow Says]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-national-tortured-to-death-in-ukraine-by-russian-soldiers-moscow-says-6612920]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Sep 2024 23:51:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russell Bentley, a US national who went missing in Russian-controlled eastern Ukraine early this year, is believed to have been tortured to death by Russian soldiers who are now set to go on trial, Russia's top investigative body said on Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russell Bentley, a US national who went missing in Russian-controlled eastern Ukraine early this year, is believed to have been tortured to death by Russian soldiers who are now set to go on trial, Russia's top investigative body said on Friday.</p>

<p>Bentley died in the Russian-controlled city of Donetsk in April, Margarita Simonyan, head of Russia's state media outlet RT, wrote at the time, saying he had been "fighting there for our guys" and working with Russia's Sputnik news service.</p>

<p>Bentley, born in 1960, was a self-declared supporter of Russian-backed forces in Ukraine. The Russian state news agency RIA reported that he had joined pro-Russian fighters in eastern Ukraine in 2014, later working with Sputnik and obtaining Russian citizenship.</p>

<p>The Investigative Committee said in a statement that it had completed its probe and accused three Russian servicemen of torturing Bentley to death in Donetsk on April 8.</p>

<p>It said two of the soldiers had then put his body in a car and blown it up. A fourth soldier had been ordered the following day to move Bentley's remains to another location in an attempt to conceal the crime.</p>

<p>The Committee's statement said the accused soldiers, whom it named, were familiarising themselves with the allegations before the indictment was sent for approval.</p>

<p>It said they would variously be tried on charges ranging from exceeding their authority, using physical violence and torture, and causing death by negligence, to attempted concealment of a serious crime. It did not say whether or not they had denied the accusations.</p>

<p>Russian media outlets have suggested that the soldiers may have mistaken Bentley - the subject of a 2022 interview with Rolling Stone magazine titled "The Bizarre Story of How a Hardcore Texas Leftist Became a Frontline Putin propagandist" - for a US spy.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/50a9boq_donetsk-ukraine_625x300_20_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Russell Bentley died in the Russian-controlled city of Donetsk in April]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-secret-service-admits-lack-of-diligence-ahead-of-trump-rally-shooting-6612861]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Secret Service Admits Lack Of Diligence Ahead Of Trump Rally Shooting]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-secret-service-admits-lack-of-diligence-ahead-of-trump-rally-shooting-6612861]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Sep 2024 23:41:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A US Secret Service probe found communication gaps and a lack of diligence ahead of the July attempted assassination of Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump at a Butler, Pennsylvania rally.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A US Secret Service probe found communication gaps and a lack of diligence ahead of the July attempted assassination of Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump at a Butler, Pennsylvania rally.</p>

<p>"There was complacency on the part of" some agents "that led to a breach of security protocols," Acting Secret Service Director Ronald Rowe told reporters on Friday, adding that agency employees will be held accountable.</p>

<p>The assassination attempt against Trump at the July 13 rally led to widespread criticism of the Secret Service and the resignation of its former director. Critics raised concerns about how the suspect was able to access a nearby rooftop with a direct line of sight to where the former president was speaking.</p>

<p>Trump's ear was wounded, a rally attendee was killed and two others were wounded in the shooting. The Secret Service has since said it was "ashamed" of the security lapse.</p>

<p>Authorities are also probing a separate apparent assassination attempt against Trump in Florida on Sunday. In that case, the Secret Service caught the suspect and no shots were fired at Trump.</p>

<p>Rowe said that Trump was getting the same level of protection as President Joe Biden and Democratic presidential candidate Vice President Kamala Harris, his rival in the Nov. 5 election.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/68fqh6to_trump-assassination-attempt-reuters_625x300_15_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The assassination attempt against Trump was carried out during a rally on July 13 (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sri-lanka-elections-as-sri-lanka-votes-ndtv-asks-presidential-candidate-sajith-premadasa-9-key-questions-6612596]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[As Sri Lanka Votes, NDTV Asks Presidential Candidate 9 Key Questions]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sri-lanka-elections-as-sri-lanka-votes-ndtv-asks-presidential-candidate-sajith-premadasa-9-key-questions-6612596]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Sep 2024 22:55:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Sri Lanka will vote to elect the next President on Saturday. While current President Ranil Wickremesinghe is seeking another term in office, he is being challenged by the key Opposition leader Sajith Premadasa.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sri Lanka, which is slowly recovering from its worst-ever economic crisis, will vote to elect the next President on Saturday. While current President Ranil Wickremesinghe is seeking another term in office, he is being challenged by the key Opposition leader Sajith Premadasa.</p>

<p>Mr Premadasa, 57, is the son of former President Ranasinghe Premadasa. He leads the Samagi Jana Balawegaya party or SJB, that separated from Ranil Wickremesinghe's party - United National Party or UNP in 2020.</p>

<p>Mr Premadasa's centrist, more left-leaning party has called for major changes to the $2.9 billion bailout programme with the International Monetary Fund (IMF) and has outlined plans of his own to adjust some targets, such as changing taxes to reduce the cost of living. He plans a very different approach to that of Mr Wickremesinghe.</p>

<p>Mr Premadasa favours a mix of interventionist and free-market economic policies, and has promised subsidies and has been accused of promising freebies too at his election rallies. But he says he has a different vision for Sri Lanka and has a plan for how he will achieve them.</p>

<p>Speaking exclusively to NDTV, Mr Premadasa spoke about how his vision is different from the current regime, how he plans to revive the economy differently from how the current President is doing, how he views the India-Sri Lanka relationship and how he plans to tackle China.</p>

<h2><strong>Here are the key highlights of his interview to NDTV:</strong></h2>

<p><strong>Q) What according to you makes these elections so significant and crucial?</strong><br />
<strong>A)</strong> Sri Lanka is facing multiple crises. In the economic sphere, the social sphere, the political sphere - and we don't have a legitimate government in the sense that the present administration is an extension of the administration that was primarily responsible for making Sri Lanka bankrupt. It is the very same parliamentary majority that led to the bankruptcy. So the Sri Lankan people are eagerly waiting to express their opinions and provide their mandate for change. Change that will make the country prosperous.</p>

<p><strong>Q) It is acknowledged widely that the incumbent President, Ranil Wickremesinghe, is credited for bringing stability to the economy, but you are saying he is part of the problem and not the solution - that is a serious charge. Can you please elaborate?</strong><br />
<strong>A)</strong> If one takes out their laurels and gets on to the streets and talks to the poor, the downtrodden, the self-employed, the labour force, the entrepreneurs, the rural and urban estate sectors; if you look at the major sections of society, other than those who are super rich, people who have been impacted detrimentally, and if I may provide you with some statistics... stats which were ascertained by the government statistical department has Illustrated that more than 260,000 micro, small and medium sized enterprises have closed. Millions have become unemployed, millions more have become poor, and the government does not have a strategy to deal with it.</p>

<p>The micro, small, and medium sized enterprises contribute to 50% of GDP, employs over 4 million, so people are suffering from the policies of a government that has basically suffocated the people. So, if you achieving stability at great human cost... at a cost where people are suffering,&nbsp; then I don't think that's the right way to do it.</p>

<p><strong>Q) So, in comparison, what is your action plan?</strong><br />
<strong>A)</strong> Where we defer, is that we will grow ourselves out of the problem. We have to go on a massive economic growth trajectory. Huge amounts of FDI coming into Sri Lanka, restructuring of society to ensure that entrepreneurs thrive. That the hold of the bureaucracy, which has basically suffocated entrepreneurship, must be ended. Ensure that businesses flourish... ensure that the micro, small, and medium sized industry are given adequate support. What you have right now is not inclusivity, it's exclusive.</p>

<p><strong>Q) So, how do you plan to ensure all this? How do you go about solving the funding problem? And furthermore, ensure that the economy grows and not shrinks because of the fund crunch?</strong><br />
<strong>A)</strong> You're quite correct in stating that the economy is fragile. That fragility does not give an excuse to be corrupt... to loot the public treasury. Shold we be elected, what we propose to do is to ensure that we follow good governance practices... ensure that the major indices that have a contributing factor with regard to foreign direct investment, good governance indices, ease of doing business... We should have a responsible government, a transparent government, and a&nbsp; government that is accountable - All three are lacking at the moment.</p>

<p><strong>Q) One of the criticisms your party has faced largely, is that you are promising large subsidies and freebies to people at a time when the economy is facing a fund crunch. Where will the funds come from? Would that not jeopardise the economy further?</strong><br />
<strong>A)</strong> We will eradicate the crony-capitalist structure that is existing at present. We will ensure that growth is the major phenomenon in our economic program. This government doesn't understand growth. They are contracting growth. To show everybody that the economy is stable, you're making everything smaller - That is not the way to go. We have to grow ourselves out of the problem. So, stability with malnutrition, stability with huge unemployment, stability with growth contraction, stability while losing livelihoods, stability while having lower standards of living... I'm sorry, I don't agree with that. The difference between the government and us is that we don't just focus on macroeconomics, we also look at the microeconomics. So, we are taking an overarching integrated approach, whereas this government is only keen on showing to the whole world and to a particular class in our country that everything is stable and fine.</p>

<p><strong>Q) India has strategic interests in the region. India had and still has very close ties with Sri Lanka. How do you view the India-Sri Lanka relationship from here on?</strong><br />
<strong>A)</strong> When you talk of recovery, I must say in these very difficult and dire times, India has been one of the countries that has been very generous, and very supportive... and I would like to extend a very big thank you to the Indian government, PM Modi's government, and also to the people of India... and to the various states that have come forward to help our country. So, a big thank you. Having said that, I don't think Sri Lanka is on the correct path to recovery. So, we will ensure that we have a very balanced policy. Where India comes in, is that our External Affairs policy will be to promote our national interest. We will do what is right for our country, and it is in the interest of our country to have cordial relation with India and the rest of the powers in the world.</p>

<p>We do what recognise that we have a special relationship, a kinship, a camaraderie between our two countries and we have a history of positive progressive and good relationship. We have to build upon that and I think we will ensure that mutual interests that matter to both of us are accomplished.</p>

<p><strong>Q) China is a significant player in the region and the last couple of years has seen a rise in Chinese Investments and&nbsp; rise in Chinese naval presence in the region. How do you view the China equation for Sri Lanka?</strong><br />
<strong>A)</strong> As I mentioned to you, in our external relations, we have a special relationship with India. But we also have to work with all of the other nation states. I'm the only politician (from Sri Lanka) who has proposed that India must be included in the United Nations Security Council. Having said that, we as a country will work with all other countries, all other democracies, all other nation states to ensure that Sri Lanka's national interests are achieved. We will in no way work towards downgrading the security and geopolitical interests of others.</p>

<p><strong>Q) What is your reasoning of wanting India as a veto power in the UN Security Council?</strong><br />
<strong>A)</strong> Well, that is a major reflection of global geopolitical reality and I must say it's not just China... all the five permanent members of the UN Security Council have veto power. Sri Lanka as a whole has been very balanced. We want to make sure that we protect our interests and also ensure that interests of other nation states are also not compromised and neutralised. So we are very sensitive to ensure that we don't interfere in the affairs of other nations.</p>

<p><strong>Q) What would be your number one expectation or demand from India, keeping in mind your vision for Sri Lanka and the region?</strong><br />
<strong>A)</strong> First and foremost, I must say I don't demand. I always use uh the power to persuade. I will use all available skills at my disposal to persuade India to invest more in Sri Lanka, to support Sri Lanka to come out of this problem, to help the people of Sri Lanka... ensure that social and economic stability are protected. So, I would use my power to persuade your great country, India, to protect Sri Lankan people's human rights, not just political and civil rights, but their economic rights, their social rights, their right to life, right to alleviate poverty, right to alleviate unemployment... and that's the arena in which we hope to cooperate with India.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/mc9u4elo_sri-lanka-leader-sajith-premadasa_625x300_20_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sri Lanka Elections: Opposition leader Sajith Premadasa speaks exclusively to NDTV about his vision]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/truly-sorry-french-mayor-for-no-one-died-remark-on-mass-rape-case-6611968]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Truly Sorry": French Mayor For "No One Died" Remark On Mass Rape Case]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/truly-sorry-french-mayor-for-no-one-died-remark-on-mass-rape-case-6611968]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Sep 2024 21:19:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The mayor of the French town where a man for over a decade brought strangers to rape his wife apologised on Friday for remarks that were criticised for playing down the ordeal of the victim.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The mayor of the French town where a man for over a decade brought strangers to rape his wife apologised on Friday for remarks that were criticised for playing down the ordeal of the victim.</p>

<p>Louis Bonnet, 74, mayor of Mazan in southern France, told broadcaster BBC in an interview that "after all, no one died" about the mass rape for which dozens of men are on trial.</p>

<p>They are accused of raping Gisele Pelicot at the invitation of her then-husband Dominique Pelicot who drugged her first.</p>

<p>"It could have been far more serious," Bonnet told the BBC. "There were no kids involved. No women were killed."</p>

<p>Bonnet's remark caused a storm of indignation on social media in France and beyond.</p>

<p>"People say I minimised the serious nature of the abject crimes of which the defendants are accused," Bonnet said in a statement posted on Facebook.</p>

<p>"I understand that people are shocked by these remarks and I am truly sorry."</p>

<p>The mayor said his apologies were addressed "notably to women who were hurt by the clumsy words that were pronounced under the pressure felt in front of the microphone of a foreign media".</p>

<p>Mazan and its 6,000 residents had been under "constant media pressure" since the start of the mass rape trial this month, he said.</p>

<p>Dominique Pelicot has admitted to drugging Gisele Pelicot into unconsciousness and inviting strangers to rape her.</p>

<p>She has become a feminist icon since demanding a public trial.</p>

<p>The trial has horrified France, partly because 71-year-old Dominique Pelicot's co-defendants include apparently ordinary men such as a fireman, a nurse and a journalist, many of them with families.</p>

<p>Forty-nine co-defendants are accused of raping or attempting to rape Gisele Pelicot, and one is accused of imitating Dominique Pelicot to sexually assault his own wife.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/5m5tlorg_gisele-pelicot-french-mass-rape-survivor-afp_625x300_14_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Forty-nine co-defendants are accused of raping or attempting to rape Gisele Pelicot (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/lebanon-pager-blasts-walkie-talkie-blasts-a-modern-trojan-horse-how-hezbollah-faced-2-days-of-mayhem-in-lebanon-6611177]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[A Modern 'Trojan Horse': How Hezbollah Faced 2 Days Of Mayhem In Lebanon]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/lebanon-pager-blasts-walkie-talkie-blasts-a-modern-trojan-horse-how-hezbollah-faced-2-days-of-mayhem-in-lebanon-6611177]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Sep 2024 19:26:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[It's around 3:30 in the afternoon on September 17. People in Lebanon are going about their daily business, doing the shopping, having a haircut, conducting meetings.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It's around 3:30 in the afternoon on September 17. People in Lebanon are going about their daily business, doing the shopping, having a haircut, conducting meetings.</p>

<p>Hundreds of pagers across the country, and even outside its borders, then simultaneously bleep with a message and explode, wounding and killing their owners and also bystanders.</p>

<p>The communications devices were used by members of the Iran-backed Lebanese Shiite group Hezbollah, which swiftly blamed Israel for the operation, as did several international media organisations.</p>

<p>Israel, according to its convention for operations outside its borders, neither confirmed nor denied the charge.</p>

<p>But observers say that the simultaneous explosions bear all the hallmarks of an operation by Israel, which appears to have infiltrated the supply chain of the pager production and inserted tiny but potent explosives inside.</p>

<p>Israel may have even set up a shell company to supply the devices to Hezbollah in a years-long project that would seem fantastical even in an espionage thriller, according to analysts.</p>

<p>But that was not the end. A day later, on September 18, around the same time in the afternoon, another low-fi gadget, the walkie-talkies used by Hezbollah cadres, exploded, even amid the funerals for those killed in the pager attacks.</p>

<p>The subsequent day, Hezbollah chief Hassan Nasrallah, who himself had told group members to use low-fi devices so as not to be targeted by Israel through the positioning of their smartphones, made his first public comments, admitting an "unprecedented blow" but also vowing "tough retribution and just punishment" for Israel.</p>

<p>Even though there is next to no doubt Israel was behind the operation, questions abounded. Why now? Is this the start of the widely-feared Israeli offensive into southern Lebanon? Or has Israel simply activated the explosives now simply because it feared the whole operation risked being compromised?</p>

<h2><strong>'IN THE MIDST OF THEIR ORDINARY LIVES'</strong></h2>

<p>The explosions were felt Hezbollah's strongholds throughout Lebanon: the southern Beirut suburbs, the south of the country and the Bekaa Valley in the east, as well as in Syria.</p>

<p>At least 37 people were killed in the two attacks and thousands injured.</p>

<p>The wounded included Iran's ambassador to Lebanon. But those killed also included a 10-year-old girl and another child. As the hospitals filled up the most common wounds were mutilated hands and eyes.</p>

<p>"Hezbollah suffered a very serious blow on a tactical level, a very impressive and comprehensive one that affects the operational side, the cognitive side," said Yoram Schweitzer, a former intelligence officer now at the The Institute for National Security Studies at Tel Aviv University.</p>

<p>Peter Harling, founder of the Synaps Lab think tank added: "The targets may have been Hezbollah members, but many were caught in the midst of their ordinary lives, and in the heart of their communities."</p>

<p>"This is also a breach that is extraordinarily hard to explain."</p>

<p>UN rights chief Volker Turk warned that the simultaneous targeting of thousands of individuals "whether civilians or members of armed groups" without knowledge as to who was around them at the time "violates international human rights law".</p>

<p>International humanitarian law prohibits the use of "booby traps" precisely to avoid putting civilians at grave risk and "produce the devastating scenes that continue to unfold across Lebanon", said Lama Fakih, Middle East and North Africa Director at Human Rights Watch.</p>

<h3><strong>'ISRAELI FRONT'</strong></h3>

<p>Espionage professionals have meanwhile expressed their admiration for how the operation was put together.</p>

<p>"It's not a technological feat," said a person working for a European intelligence service, asking not to be named. But "it's the result of human intelligence and heavy logistics."</p>

<p>The small devices, bearing the name of the firm Gold Apollo in Taiwan, were intercepted by Israeli services before their arrival in Lebanon, according to multiple security sources who spoke to AFP, asking not to be named.</p>

<p>But the Taiwanese company denied having manufactured them and pointed to its Hungarian partner BAC.</p>

<p>Founded in 2022, the company is registered in Budapest. Its CEO, Cristiana Barsony-Arcidiacono, appears there as the only employee.</p>

<p>The devices in question have never been on Hungarian soil, according to the Hungarian authorities.</p>

<p>The New York Times, citing three intelligence sources, said BAC was "part of an Israeli front" with at least two other shell companies were created as well to mask the real identities of the people creating the pagers who were Israeli intelligence officers.</p>

<p>It described the pagers as a "modern day Trojan Horse" after the wooden horse said to have been used by the Greeks to enter the city of Troy in the Trojan War.</p>

<h3><strong>'IMPRESSIVE OPERATION'</strong></h3>

<p>The attack comes nearly a year after Hezbollah ally Hamas carried out its October 7 attack on Israel, sparking the war in Gaza.</p>

<p>The focus of Israel's firepower has since been on the Palestinian territory, but Hezbollah fighters and Israeli troops have exchanged fire almost daily across the border region since October, forcing thousands on both sides to flee their homes.</p>

<p>Israel's Defence Minister Yoav Gallant said the focus of the war was shifting towards Lebanon, while the government said securing the northern front was a key objective, in order to allow Israelis evacuated from the area to return home.</p>

<p>Schweitzer said that despite the spectacular nature of the device operation it did not represent the end of Israel's work to degrade Hezbollah.</p>

<p>"I don't think this impressive operation that has its tactical gains... is getting into the strategic layers yet.</p>

<p>"It does not change the equation, it is not a decisive victory. But it sends another signal to Hezbollah, Iran and others," he said.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/5g8d25mc_lebanon-pager-blasts-reuters_625x300_20_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Pager and walkie-talkie blasts targetting Hezbollah militants caused mayhem across Lebanon.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/sunita-williams-celebrates-59th-birthday-her-second-in-space-6611006]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Sunita Williams Celebrates Birthday In Space. Not Her 1st Time]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/sunita-williams-celebrates-59th-birthday-her-second-in-space-6611006]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Sep 2024 19:03:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Indian-Origin astronaut Sunita Williams has celebrated her 59th birthday -- the second in space.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p>

<p>Indian-Origin astronaut Sunita Williams has celebrated her 59th birthday -- the second in space.</p>

<p>SunitaWilliams is currently stranded at the International Space Station (ISS) after Boeing's faulty Starliner spacecraft was declared unfit for human travel by NASA. While Starliner is back on Earth unharmed, SunitaWilliams is expected to return on SpaceX's capsule in February next year.</p>

<p>SunitaWilliams marked her 59th birthday aboard the ISS on September 19. She dedicated her day to vital maintenance tasks and scientific research on the orbiting lab.</p>

<p>Along with fellow astronaut Don Pettit, she worked on maintaining life support systems on the ISS.</p>

<p>The astronaut duo then replaced filters in the station's waste and hygiene compartment -- called the space bathroom.</p>

<p>The 59-year-old created history by becoming the first woman to fly on the maiden mission of the Starliner. The Starliner flight is SunitaWilliams's third to space -- the first being in 2006 and the second in 2012.</p>

<p>According to NASA, "Sunita has spent a cumulative total of 322 days in space", and she is the second woman astronaut with the highest number of spacewalks.</p>

<p>On her birthday, Sunita Williams received a rendition of legendary singer Mohd Rafi's birthday song 'Bar bar din ye aaye' from Indian music company Saregama.</p>

<p>In a post on Instagram, Saregama shared: "Come on India let's sing #HappyBirthdaySunita along with India's biggest icons and send our collective wishes to Astronaut Sunita Williams up in space. Use #HappyBirthdaySunita to post your videos and Tag @saregama_official".</p>

<p>In the video shared along with the post, film director Karan Johar, and iconic singers Sonu Nigam, Shaan, Hariharan, and Neeti Mohan sang the song to wish her birthday.</p>

<p>The post also called for people to make videos wishing Sunita Williams and share them with #HappyBirthdaySunita.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Sunita Williams is expected to cast her votes in the 2024 US presidential elections, scheduled for November 5, from space.</p>

<p>Originally slated for an eight-day mission, Sunita William's stay in space has now stretched to eight months.</p>

<p>Commenting on being stuck in space, the Indian-origin astronaut in a recent video press conference said, "That's how things go in this business."</p>

<p>She added that the transition to station life was "not that hard" since both astronauts had prior experience on the ISS.</p>

<p>Reflecting on her extended mission, Sunita Williams shared, "This is my happy place. I love being up here in space."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/00gim5tg_sunita-williams-butch-wilmore_625x300_14_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sunita William's stay in space has now stretched to eight months. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-army-says-conducted-targeted-strike-in-beirut-6610855]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Top Hezbollah Commander Killed As Israeli Strike Rattles Beirut]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-army-says-conducted-targeted-strike-in-beirut-6610855]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Sep 2024 18:42:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel announced it had killed the commander of Hezbollah's elite unit in a strike Friday that Lebanese officials said left 12 dead and dozens wounded in the movement's Beirut stronghold.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel announced it had killed the commander of Hezbollah's elite unit in a strike Friday that Lebanese officials said left 12 dead and dozens wounded in the movement's Beirut stronghold.</p>

<p>Ibrahim Aqil, who was also wanted by the United States for involvement in the 1983 bombing of the US embassy in Beirut, headed the Iran-backed militant group's elite Radwan unit.</p>

<p>AFP journalists at the scene said the blast had left a massive crater and destroyed the lower floors of a high-rise building in the Lebanese capital's southern suburbs, a Hezbollah stronghold.</p>

<p>The killing of Aqil was the second of a senior Hezbollah commander since the start of the war in Gaza, following another Israeli strike in Beirut that killed Fuad Shukr in July.</p>

<p>It also came after two waves of explosions, on Tuesday and Wednesday, of communication devices used by Hezbollah members, which Hezbollah blamed on Israel, that killed dozens and left Hezbollah reeling while dramatically shifting the focus of the Israel-Hamas war northwards.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said Friday it conducted a "targeted strike" to kill Aqil and which also killed around 10 other senior Radwan commanders.</p>

<p>Lebanon's health ministry said the attack killed 12 people and wounded 66 more.</p>

<p>Earlier, a source close to Hezbollah, requesting anonymity to discuss sensitive matters, said the strike had killed Aqil.</p>

<p>"The Israeli air strike killed Radwan Force commander Ibrahim Aqil, its armed force's second-in-command after Fuad Shukr," the source close to Hezbollah said.</p>

<p>Hezbollah has not officially confirmed his death, but it said after the strike that it targeted with rockets an Israeli intelligence base it blamed for unspecified "assassinations".</p>

<p>The United States had offered a $7 million reward for information on Aqil, describing him as a "principal member" of the organisation that claimed the 1983 embassy bombing, which killed 63 people.</p>

<p><strong>Communication device explosions</strong></p>

<p>Israeli troops and Hezbollah fighters have battled each other along the Israel-Lebanon border since Hamas sparked the war in Gaza with its October 7 attack.</p>

<p>The focus of Israel's firepower for nearly a year has been on Gaza, but with Hamas much weakened, the focus of the war has shifted dramatically to Israel's northern border.</p>

<p>Months of near-daily border clashes have killed hundreds in Lebanon, most of them fighters, and dozens in Israel, and forced thousands on both sides to flee their homes.</p>

<p>On Tuesday and Wednesday, Hezbollah was hit by an unprecedented attack that it has blamed on Israel, though Israel has yet to comment.</p>

<p>The attack saw thousands of Hezbollah operatives' communication devices explode across two days, killing 37 people and wounding thousands more.</p>

<p>Hezbollah chief Hassan Nasrallah vowed on Thursday that Israel would face retribution for the blasts.</p>

<p>Earlier Friday, Israel said Hezbollah had fired dozens of rockets from Lebanon following air strikes which destroyed dozens of the militant group's launchers.</p>

<p>Speaking to troops on Wednesday, Israeli Defence Minister Yoav Gallant said: "Hezbollah will pay an increasing price" as Israel tries to "ensure the safe return" of its citizens to border areas.</p>

<p>"We are at the start of a new phase in the war," he said.</p>

<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu meanwhile delayed his scheduled departure to the United States, where he is due to address the UN General Assembly, by a day, with an official citing the situation on the northern front.</p>

<p>Earlier Friday, Hezbollah said it targeted at least six Israeli military bases with salvos of rockets after overnight bombardment that people in south Lebanon described as among the fiercest so far.</p>

<p><strong>'Fear of wider war'</strong></p>

<p>Residents of Marjayoun, a Lebanese town close to the border, said the overnight bombardment was among the heaviest since the border clashes began last October.</p>

<p>"We were very scared, especially for my grandchildren," said Nuha Abdo, 62. "We were moving them from one room to another."</p>

<p>Clothing store owner Elie Rmeih, 45, counted more than 50 strikes.</p>

<p>"It was a terrifying scene and unlike anything we have experienced since the escalation began.</p>

<p>"We live in fear of a wider war, you don't know where to go."</p>

<p><strong>Calls for restraint</strong></p>

<p>International mediators have been scrambling to stop the Gaza war from turning into an all-out regional conflict.</p>

<p>US Secretary of State Antony Blinken, who has tried to salvage efforts for a Gaza ceasefire and hostage release deal, called for restraint on all sides.</p>

<p>"We don't want to see any escalatory actions by any party" that would endanger the goal of a Gaza ceasefire, he said.</p>

<p>Hamas's October 7 attacks that sparked the Gaza war resulted in the deaths of 1,205 people, mostly civilians, on the Israeli side, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli official figures that include hostages killed in captivity.</p>

<p>Out of 251 hostages seized by militants, 97 are still held in Gaza, including 33 the Israeli military says are dead.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory military offensive has killed at least 41,272 people in Gaza, most of them civilians, according to figures provided by the Hamas-run territory's health ministry. The United Nations has acknowledged the figures as reliable.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/46stftj_israel-strikes-beirut_625x300_20_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hezbollah has not officially confirmed Ibrahim Aqil's death]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uns-summit-of-the-future-has-arrived-heres-all-you-need-to-know-6610401]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UN's Summit Of The Future Has Arrived. Here's All You Need To Know]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uns-summit-of-the-future-has-arrived-heres-all-you-need-to-know-6610401]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Sep 2024 17:48:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[With just six years left to meet the deadline for the United Nations' Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs), the world is not on track to meet those targets.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With just six years left to meet the deadline for the United Nations' Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs), the world is not on track to meet those targets.</p>

<p>The COVID-19 pandemic, escalating conflicts and growing climate chaos have severely hindered progress.</p>

<p>To get back on track, the world needs massive investment in sustainable development, as well as accelerated action in several critical areas, including climate change, peace and security, and inequalities among and between countries, as the recent <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://dashboards.sdgindex.org/" rel="No follow, no index" target="_blank">Sustainable Development Report 2024</a> found.</p>

<p>To address these acute challenges, UN Secretary-General Antonio Guterres has called for a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.un.org/en/summit-of-the-future" rel="No follow, no index" target="_blank">Summit of the Future</a> at the United Nations in New York on September 22-23.</p>

<p>With the theme "Multilateral solutions for a better tomorrow", the summit will bring together UN member states and agencies, academic institutions, non-governmental organisations, civil society organisations, the private sector and young people.</p>

<p>Humanity is facing a set of unprecedented challenges that can only be solved through global cooperation, also known as multilateralism. During the summit, attendees will collectively forge a new global consensus on what our future should look like - and what we can do today to secure it.</p>

<p>The summit will focus on five core areas: sustainable development and financing; international peace and security; fostering digital cooperation and the control of new technologies, such as artificial intelligence; the empowerment of young people and future generations; and reform of the UN architecture.</p>

<p>Within sustainable development, the core challenge is securing global financing. After all, achieving the Sustainable Development Goals will require sizeable public investment.</p>

<p>With low-income and lower-middle-income countries, in particular, lacking the access to financing they need to achieve those goals, the global system will need to work out a way to provide access to long-term, low-cost financing to these countries.</p>

<p>To achieve global peace, one of the core challenges today is great-power competition, including between the US, Russia and China. The world will need to move toward a UN-led system in which this great-power competition is governed and restrained by the UN Charter rather than by militarism and power politics.</p>

<p>To support this goal, countries must be truly committed to global cooperation - and a new index on UN-based multilateralism could play a part in monitoring just how committed to that goal UN member states are.</p>

<p>For digital cooperation and new technologies, the main challenge is to ensure that they are transparently and responsibly governed.</p>

<p>For youth and future generations, high-quality education plays an essential role in their empowerment and progress. The world will need to work toward a new global financial arrangement to ensure that every child, even in the poorest countries, is given the opportunity for a decent education.</p>

<p>All of these objectives cannot be achieved without reform of the UN system, ensuring that more power is given to UN institutions and ensuring that they are more representative. To make the UN as representative as possible, boosting diverse representation, including women's representation, at leadership levels is essential.</p>

<p>Furthermore, approaching decarbonisation and other sustainability efforts with a gender lens and boosting women's representation in this area is critical for making progress on all of the above challenges.</p>

<p>Published to coincide with the UN's Summit of the Future, this special report, a collaboration between 360info and the UN Sustainable Development Solutions Network (SDSN), tables solutions to some of the world's most pressing issues.</p>

<p><em>(<strong>Authors:</strong> Alyson Marks, the UN Sustainable Development Solutions Network (SDSN), and 360info editorial team)</em></p>

<p><em><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> Originally published under <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/" rel="No follow, no index" target="_top">Creative Commons</a> by <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://360info.org/" rel="No follow, no index" target="_blank">360info</a></em><br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/grpvqmo_summit-of-the-future-illustration-image-360info_625x300_20_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Summit of the Future is being held in the United States next week. (Illustration Image)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-handed-out-pagers-hours-before-blasts-even-after-checks-6610247]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hezbollah Handed Out Pagers Hours Before Blasts - Even After Checks]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-handed-out-pagers-hours-before-blasts-even-after-checks-6610247]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Sep 2024 17:28:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hezbollah was handing its members new Gold Apollo branded pagers hours before thousands blew up this week, two security sources said, indicating they were confident the devices were safe despite an ongoing sweep of electronic kit to identify threats.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lebanon's Hezbollah was still handing its members new Gold Apollo branded pagers hours before thousands blew up this week, two security sources said, indicating the group was confident the devices were safe despite an ongoing sweep of electronic kit to identify threats.</p>

<p>One member of the Iranian-backed militia received a new pager on Monday that exploded the next day while it was still in its box, said one of the sources.</p>

<p>A pager given to a senior member just days earlier injured a subordinate when it detonated, the second source said.</p>

<p>In an apparently coordinated attack the Gold Apollo branded devices detonated on Tuesday across Hezbollah's strongholds of south Lebanon, Beirut's suburbs and the eastern Bekaa valley.</p>

<p>On Wednesday, hundreds of Hezbollah walkie-talkies exploded. The consecutive attacks killed 37 people, including at least two children, and injured more than 3,000 people.</p>

<p>The batteries of the walkie-talkies were laced with a highly explosive compound known as PETN, another Lebanese source familiar with the device's components told Reuters on Friday. Up to three grams of explosives hidden in the pagers had gone undetected for months by Hezbollah, Reuters reported earlier this week.</p>

<p>One of the security sources said it was very hard to detect the explosives "with any device or scanner." The source did not specify what type of scanners Hezbollah had run the pagers through.</p>

<p>Hezbollah examined the pagers after they were delivered to Lebanon, starting in 2022, including by travelling through airports with them to ensure they would not trigger alarms, two additional sources told Reuters. In total, Reuters spoke to six sources familiar with the details of the exploding devices for this story.</p>

<p>The sources did not specify the name of the airports where they conducted the tests.</p>

<p>Lebanon, Hezbollah and Western security sources say Israel was behind the attacks. Israel, which has since stepped up airstrikes on Lebanon, has neither denied or confirmed involvement.</p>

<p>Rather than a specific suspicion of the pagers, the checks had been part of a routine "sweep" of its equipment, including communications devices, to find any indications that they were laced with explosives or surveillance mechanisms, one of the security sources said.</p>

<p>The attacks, and the distribution of the devices despite the routine sweep and checks for breaches, have struck at Hezbollah's reputation as the most formidable of Iran's allied 'Axis of Resistance' umbrella of anti-Israel irregular forces across the Middle East.</p>

<p>In a televised speech on Thursday, Hezbollah Secretary-General Hassan Nasrallah said the attacks were "unprecedented in the history" of the group.</p>

<p>Hezbollah's media office and Israel's armed forces did not immediately respond to requests for comment for this story.</p>

<p>Taiwan-based Gold Apollo has said it did not manufacture the devices used in the attack, saying they were made by a company in Europe licensed to use the firm's brand. Reuters has not been able to establish where they were made or at what point they were tampered with.&nbsp;</p>

<p>A batch of 5,000 of the pagers were brought into Lebanon earlier this year. Reuters previously reported that Hezbollah turned to pagers in an attempt to evade Israeli surveillance of its mobile phones, following the killing of senior commanders in targeted airstrikes over the past year.</p>

<p>Hezbollah's conflict with Israel dates back decades but has flared up in the past year in parallel with the Gaza war, heightening worries of a full-blown regional war.</p>

<p><strong>TOO LITTLE, TOO LATE</strong></p>

<p>After the pagers detonated on Tuesday, Hezbollah suspected more of its devices may have been compromised, two of the security sources, as well as an intelligence source, told Reuters.</p>

<p>In response, it intensified the sweep of its communications systems, carrying out careful examinations of all devices. It also began investigating the supply chains through which the pagers were brought in, the two security sources said.</p>

<p>But the review had not been concluded by Wednesday afternoon, when the hand-held radios exploded.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Hezbollah believes that Israel opted to detonate the group's hand-held radios because it feared Hezbollah would soon find that the walkie-talkies were also rigged with explosives, one of the sources told Reuters.</p>

<p>The walkie-talkie explosions left 25 people dead and at least 650 injured, according to Lebanon's health ministry - a much higher fatality rate than the previous day's pager blasts, which killed 12 and wounded nearly 3,000.&nbsp;</p>

<p>That is because they carried a higher payload of explosives than the beepers, one of the security sources and the intelligence source said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The group's probe into precisely where, when and how the devices were laced with explosives is ongoing, three of the sources said. Nasrallah later said the same in the speech on Thursday.</p>

<p>One of the security sources said Hezbollah had foiled previous Israeli operations targeting devices imported from abroad by the group - from its private landline telephones to ventilation units in the group's offices.&nbsp;</p>

<p>That includes suspected breaches in the past year.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"There are several electronic issues that we were able to discover - but not the pagers," the source said. "They tricked us, hats off to the enemy."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/944ak7j_pagers_625x300_19_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A security source said it was very hard to detect the explosives "with any device or scanner." (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/4-key-obstacles-to-india-joining-un-security-council-with-veto-power-6610212]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[4 Key Obstacles To India Joining UN Security Council With Veto Power]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/4-key-obstacles-to-india-joining-un-security-council-with-veto-power-6610212]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Sep 2024 17:21:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Indian politicians have argued for decades that the nation deserves to be a member of the United Nations Security Council (UNSC).]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Indian politicians have argued for decades that the nation deserves to be a member of the United Nations Security Council (UNSC).</p>

<p>An aspirational superpower, India believes that it has been unfairly denied a seat at the high table.</p>

<p>Several visiting foreign political dignitaries and international coalitions that have pushed for UNSC reforms have also voiced support for India's candidacy for permanent membership of the Security Council.</p>

<p>However, despite persistent lobbying by India, experts are not hopeful of change in the near future.</p>

<p>There are four key challenges India must overcome before it secures veto power in the United Nations.</p>

<h2><strong>CHINA'S OPPOSITION</strong></h2>

<p>Among the five permanent security council members all except China - the US, the UK, France, and Russia - have categorically supported India's candidature in the past.</p>

<p>As a close competitor of India in regional and international politics, China - the only Asian country with a security council seat - is unwilling to endorse New Delhi's position.</p>

<p>This adds to its power and international prestige and China is unlikely to want to share this space with India. What's more, particularly amid an ongoing border dispute with India, China will resist any attempt by any of the four members to change the composition of the UNSC.</p>

<p>China is also uncomfortable with Japan, a close US ally that, like India, is a strong contender for a permanent seat.</p>

<p>China has unofficially dropped hints that it may back India, provided New Delhi doesn't endorse Japan's bid. China knows that New Delhi will not break the unity of the G-4 (comprising Brazil, Germany, India, and Japan, are four countries which support each other's bids for permanent seats on the security council) and thus, considers it is a safe bet to pit India against Japan.</p>

<h3><strong>DISAGREEMENT ON MEMBERSHIP WITHOUT VETO POWER</strong></h3>

<p>Some parties have raised the prospect of India gaining UNSC membership without veto power.</p>

<p>Groups including Uniting for Consensus (UfC) - a powerful coalition led by Italy, with other members including Canada, Mexico, Spain, Pakistan, South Korea and Turkey - have advocated reinforcing the working of the General Assembly and increasing the number of non-permanent members.</p>

<p>Its argument is that the addition of non-permanent members will make the UN more accountable and representative by accommodating relevant regional voices in the decision-making process. In doing so, the group argues, this solution would mean there are more than a few select chief custodians of the international system.</p>

<p>But there are questions about what happens if India gets a high seat without veto power. Could this be considered a piecemeal approach towards achieving the larger objective?</p>

<p>Despite some parties saying they prefer this kind of arrangement, New Delhi is not comfortable with this proposition. India's position is that all new permanent members to the security council must possess a veto. Thus, it is unlikely this outcome will unfold.</p>

<h3><strong>WESTERN CONCERNS THAT INDIA MAY NOT ALIGN WITH US PRIORITIES</strong></h3>

<p>The US has, in principle, endorsed India gaining a permanent seat on the security council. But not everyone believes US policymakers will actually support such a reform in practice.</p>

<p>Indeed, in the past, P-5 countries have displayed "a habit of being non-commital" when it comes to actual decision-making on veto powers. As former US Under Secretary of State for Political Affairs Nicholas Burns said in 2008: "We want to preserve the veto, and we do not want to extend a veto to new permanent members."</p>

<p>Prominent US-based South Asian expert Ashley Tellis recently penned a piece in <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.foreignaffairs.com/india/americas-bad-bet-india-modi" rel="No follow, no index" target="_blank">Foreign Affairs magazine</a> arguing that the US cannot be sure of India's support on significant strategic matters. Ashley later defended this position in an interview, saying "the current war in Ukraine is a good example... India defines its interest in ways that are not always identical to our own".</p>

<p>It is true that India has not always voted with the West in the UN and has maintained an independent position on several critical subjects (e.g., India abstaining on the Russian invasion of Ukraine). Due to this, many think India is a fence-sitter and see it as an unreliable partner.</p>

<p>The West, particularly after the Russian-Ukraine war, is more watchful of new geopolitical reality. The understanding that Russia may fail to secure any support in the world for its war has changed.</p>

<p>Despite developing closer strategic ties with the West, India remained uncommitted on supporting sanctions on Russia. While China's response was anticipated, for the West, foot dragging by New Delhi in criticising Russia was no less than a shock.</p>

<p>In these changed circumstances, it is difficult to imagine that the West, particularly the US, will go ahead with a reformed security council where India has veto power.</p>

<h3><strong>THE REGIONAL CONUNDRUM</strong></h3>

<p>India also faces formidable challenges to its leadership emanating from its own region. India influences the region, but not in absolute terms. Indeed, as instability in the region has increased, so too have New Delhi's troubles.</p>

<p>South Asia has become a battleground of India-China competition.</p>

<p>And while the India-Pakistan rivalry captures most attention, there are major India-related issues that agitate people in Nepal, Bangladesh, Sri Lanka, Maldives and even in Bhutan.</p>

<p>With its recent change of government, Bangladeshis no longer on the same page. Queries over India's regional leadership raises questions over its claims to be a global power.</p>

<h3><strong>NEXT STEP FOR INDIA</strong></h3>

<p>There are convincing arguments that the UN is in desperate need of reform, particularly the Security Council. Expanding the Security Council's membership to include developing countries like India would benefit the UN and the international community.</p>

<p>However, New Delhi must make more concerted efforts to address criticisms to further legitimise its demand for permanent membership.</p>

<p>India's geographical, political, and social influence in South Asia cannot be ignored. Recent criticism around its increasing political intolerance - which is directly linked to the state of democracy in India - must be addressed and resolved.</p>

<p>India's failure to improve its ranking in the Human Development Index, the issue of economic inequality, and its lack of world-class infrastructure all contribute to the nation's global image.</p>

<p>Therefore, there are structural and more prominent geopolitical factors that overshadow India's chances to acquire security council permanent membership.</p>

<p>Additionally, India needs better engagement with the region and much more internal work to strengthen its claim further.</p>

<p><em>(<strong>Author:</strong> Dhananjay Tripathi is Associate Professor in the Department of International Relations at South Asian University, New Delhi)</em></p>

<p><em><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> Originally published under <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/" rel="No follow, no index" target="_blank">Creative Commons</a> by <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://360info.org/" rel="No follow, no index" target="_blank">360info</a></em><br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-08/gg6u123_india-at-un-security-council-un-security-council-un-security-council-president_625x300_01_August_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[There are 4 key challenges India must overcome before it secures veto power in UN Security Council]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ex-google-employee-in-canada-highlights-undervaluation-of-indian-work-experience-6609982]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Google Ex-Employee Shares Struggle For Indians To Find Job In Canada]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ex-google-employee-in-canada-highlights-undervaluation-of-indian-work-experience-6609982]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Sep 2024 16:52:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Is work experience from India not enough to fetch you a decent salary abroad? A video of an Indian man, who works as a process inventory associate in Canada, highlights the struggle to land a job.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Is work experience from India not enough to fetch you a decent salary abroad? A video of an Indian man, who works as a process inventory associate in Canada, highlights the struggle to land a job even though he previously worked with Google India for three years.</p>

<p>"They (Canadians) are preferably looking for <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-canadas-2-year-cap-on-foreign-students-and-who-will-be-impacted-4969561">Canadian candidates</a> only and not looking for Indian candidates," he said. In a conversation with digital creator Piyush Monga, the man expressed dissatisfaction with his current salary of CAD 17,500 (around Rs 10.78 lakh), deeming it inadequate for a comfortable living.</p>

<p>When asked about his satisfaction with the salary, he candidly responded, "Obviously no one is happy. You hardly make any survival with that sort of money."</p>

<p>The former Google employee voiced his disappointment regarding the undervaluation of his experience, saying that he has worked on-site with the company in India for over three years as a digital marketing expert. However, since moving to Canada, he feels compelled to "cut down his experience" as employers think that "if you have experience from India, it's not going to count."&nbsp;</p>

<p>Addressing the significance of local experience, he said, "It definitely doesn't make any sense because you have spent a lot of years over there and have done a lot of things. Some companies say I'm overqualified for the job."</p>

<p>&nbsp;"Is Indian experience irrelevant? Bro has worked with Google but, recruiters don't care," read the caption posted with the video on Instagram.</p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/reel/C_vJh0YRiNH/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/C_vJh0YRiNH/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/C_vJh0YRiNH/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/C_vJh0YRiNH/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by Piyush Monga (@salaryscale)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p>The video highlights the ongoing challenges faced by Indian professionals in Canada.</p>

<p>People reacted in the comments of the video with their own edperiences. One of them wrote, "Here I was sad my Wipro experience doesn't count in Canada."&nbsp;</p>

<p>"When fresher goes they want experience. When experienced guy goes they want less experience. What do they want," a person wrote questioning the confusion over job opportunities.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Another user, however, did not agree with the man's claims and added, "I do not think that's true. If one has developed Google ad skills, a recruiter will prefer those. Not having Canadian experience might impact his level and pay but you can get a job or at least an internship in a year.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the Justin Trudeau-led government in Canada recently announced a <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-students-in-canada-face-deportation-after-policy-change-6429289#:~:text=Canada%20is%20also%20reducing%20the,getting%20deported%20from%20the%20country">policy change</a> affecting foreign students. The Canadian government has tightened work permits and increased financial requirements, among other adjustments.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The changes have led to protests from Indian students in Canada.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/vcjo7f5o_job-generic-_625x300_20_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The video highlights the ongoing challenges faced by Indian professionals in Canada. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>