<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Wed, 28 Aug 2024 08:45:55 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hunters-conservationists-design-safer-traps-to-protect-formosan-bears-6433792]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hunters, Conservationists Design Safer Traps To Protect Formosan Bears]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hunters-conservationists-design-safer-traps-to-protect-formosan-bears-6433792]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 28 Aug 2024 08:43:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[As the cage holding an endangered Formosan black bear swung open conservationists blasted gunshots and air horns to ensure the frightened young bear disappeared quickly into the mountains of central Taiwan, hopefully far from human contact.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As the cage holding an endangered Formosan black bear swung open conservationists blasted gunshots and air horns to ensure the frightened young bear disappeared quickly into the mountains of central Taiwan, hopefully far from human contact.</p>

<p>Ziman, a one-and-a-half-year-old bear, had finally recovered from the amputation of a paw caused by a hunter's steel noose and now had a second chance in life.</p>

<p>"Please take care of him and help him find his parents safely," Pihao Payen, the leader of a nearby ethnic Atayal community, said in a prayer as Ziman disappeared from sight.</p>

<p>Wearing a traditional tribal tunic and headgear decorated with animal horns, the 74-year-old chief and an experienced hunter also prayed for his ancestors' help to keep Ziman away from traps.</p>

<p>Taiwanese hunters and conservationists are teaming up to protect the Formosan black bear, with only a few hundred estimated still in the wild, by designing new traps which will not amputate limbs if they are accidentally caught in a snare.</p>

<p>While bears are not a target for Indigenous Taiwanese hunters, people in Pihao Payen's village accidentally caught bears twice in recent years when laying traps for prey such as deer and boars, a traditional practice in Indigenous culture.</p>

<p>Since 2014, 18 bears have been captured in traps, with six found dead, according to the non-governmental organisation, the Taiwan Black Bear Conservation Association.</p>

<p>While most of the bears were released, some suffered major injuries caused by old-fashioned hunting tools such as metal snares, which can break bones or sever paws or toes as the bear struggles to break free.</p>

<p>"Steel snares bounce off from the ground and tighten up their limbs when triggered by animals," said Liu Li-wen, an animal caretaker who oversaw Ziman's recovery in a government-run bear shelter in the mountains of Taichung.</p>

<p>"The snares turned tighter and tighter as the animal struggled. When blood circulation stopped, his entire paw turned necrotic," she said, showing pictures of Ziman's swollen left paw. Vets had to cut most of the paw off to save the cub's life after two months of treatment.</p>

<p>"That's why we are seeing many bears with broken paws or toes in the wild. It's likely that they were entangled by traps, broke free by themselves and survived," she said.</p>

<h3><strong>NEW SNARES</strong></h3>

<p>The Formosan black bear is one of seven subspecies of Asiatic black bear which is considered vulnerable to extinction by the International Union for Conservation of Nature.</p>

<p>Indigenous to sub-tropical Taiwan with an iconic V-shaped white mark on the chest, the Formosan black bear is seen as a symbol of Taiwanese identity that champions its diverse culture and freedom. Democratic Taiwan was previously better known internationally as Formosa.</p>

<p>To reduce death or injuries of wildlife, the Forestry and Nature Conservation Agency is now urging hunters and farmers to adopt a new type of animal snare designed to only trap smaller prey and which does not tighten to the point of amputation.</p>

<p>More than 5,600 such traps have been given to hunters and farmers for free across mountainous Taiwan which is 60% covered by forest, while monetary rewards are given to those who report cases of bears caught by traps.</p>

<p>"Because of its small size, and because the bear's palm is very wide, you see that it (the bear paw) will not fall in completely when stepped on like this," explained Pan Wen-ming, an ethnic Amis hunter and guava farmer in central Taiwan, as he demonstrated how to set up the new trap to Reuters reporters.</p>

<p>"It tries to minimise (bear injuries) while letting the elders and hunters of our tribe still hunt for prey," he said.</p>

<p>Chen Yen-long, chief of the Wushikeng Research Centre bear shelter in Taichung, said some hunters killed snared bears for fear of being prosecuted for trapping a protected animal.</p>

<p>Sadly, Ziman, the cub with the amputated paw, was found dead in the central mountains only weeks after his release, with authorities unable to determine the cause of death.</p>

<p>"This is not the end of the story. We will not stop what we are doing," said Lai Chiao Ling, one of Ziman's caretakers. "At least there are still bears in the wild for us to save."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/kh3gqt58_formosan-black-bear-reuters-_625x300_28_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Formosan black bear is one of seven subspecies of Asiatic black bear, vulnerable to extinction.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/no-modis-ukraine-visit-wasnt-about-ditching-russia-6433766]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: No, Modi's Ukraine Visit Wasn't About 'Ditching' Russia]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/no-modis-ukraine-visit-wasnt-about-ditching-russia-6433766]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 28 Aug 2024 08:40:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India is not in a position to either alienate the West or Russia, as it needs both to protect and advance its larger national interest.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/kkihncj_pm-modi-and-zelensky_625x300_23_August_24.jpeg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi's visit to Poland and Ukraine is being construed by pro-West lobbies in India as a new thrust of Indian foreign policy towards Central and East Europe, to re-balance and de-hyphenate its engagement with Russia and Central Europe, and more particularly, its ties with Russia and Ukraine.</p>

<p>The view of this lobby is that India, in defence of its Russia sensitivities, did not engage Ukraine and the erstwhile Warsaw Pact countries so far. Modi's visit to Ukraine is therefore seen in these pro-Western circles as a long overdue correction of India's approach to the Russian invasion of Ukraine.</p>

<p>India, it is argued, has all along stayed silent on Russia's unacceptable actions even when they challenged the core principles of India's worldview - the sanctity of national sovereignty and territorial integrity. The political costs of this silence on Russian aggressions have been mounting and ergo the change in India's approach that we see.</p>

<h2><strong>A Shallow Analysis</strong></h2>

<p>This kind of analysis of India's foreign policy is ill-informed, shallow and ideological. Take the Czech Republic as an example of India's supposed lack of engagement with Central and East Europe. Look at the reality: India's former President, Ram Nath Kovind, made a visit there in 2018; the Czech PM visited India in 2019, when the Czech Republic was a partner country at the Vibrant Gujarat Summit; its Defence Minister came in February 2019, its Foreign Minister in January 2020; former CDS General Rawat visited the Czech Republic in November 2021; India's External Affairs Minister (EAM) went there in June 2022; the Czech Foreign Minister came to India in February 2023; the Czech Prime Minister came to India in January 2024 when the India-Czechia Strategic Partnership On Innovation was adopted. The Czech Foreign Minister visited India again in February 2024. Similarly, Prime Minister Orban of Hungary visited India in 2013, the Hungarian Foreign Minister has visited India three times - in 2020, 2022 and 2024 - while India's EAM visited Hungary in 2019. High-level visits have been exchanged with Slovakia too, as well as Poland.</p>

<p>The Russia-Ukraine conflict has posed serious problems for not only India but the international community as a whole. The US, Europe and the G7 are pitted against Russia. China, which has intensive ties with the West, is supporting Russia, bearing in mind that Beijing is now seen by the US as its biggest adversary. It therefore sees the value of Russia as a partner. India has deepening ties with the West but also has close historical ties with Russia. India is not in a position to either alienate the West or Russia, as it needs both to protect and advance its larger national interest.</p>

<h2><strong>The Russia-Ukraine Issue Is Multilayered</strong></h2>

<p>If Russia has committed aggression against Ukraine, the list of aggressions that the US and its partners in NATO have committed against other countries is incomparably longer. If this has not deterred India from forging close ties with the US and NATO countries, why would it be wrong to preserve our ties with Russia? Should we have double standards too?</p>

<p>More pertinently, an objective analysis of the Ukraine conflict would show that the responsibility for it does not lie on one side only. It is not a simple case of violation of the sovereignty and territorial integrity of one country. Much larger and complex issues of historical legacies, geopolitics, national security, balance of power, ethnic rights, external interference, regime change, etc., are involved.</p>

<p>India cannot take a simplistic view of the conflict. More so as those who want to promote the interests of the West should recall that on issues of our own sovereignty and territorial integrity, the record of the West has been adverse to our interests, and is not supportive even now.</p>

<h2><strong>Multilateralism Has Collapsed</strong></h2>

<p>Modi's visit to Ukraine should not be seen as India de-hyphenating its engagement with Russia and Ukraine. India, as well as the global south in general, has been impacted by the Russia-Ukraine conflict in many ways. Europe, too, has been hit by this conflict, which is also against our interest at a time when we seek to deepen our ties with Europe, especially on the trade and technology front, not to mention the larger issues of energy security, climate change, critical technologies, etc., which require constructive cooperation with Europe.</p>

<p>The complete breakdown of a dialogue between the US and Russia is against our interests too. The liberal use of sanctions as a political and economic tool disrupts our ties with Russia as well as with others, like Iran. Multilateralism has virtually collapsed. This prevents much-needed international cooperation to address problems that are global in nature. Viewing Modi's visit to Ukraine only in the context of balancing our ties with Russia is missing the larger point.</p>

<p>All the more so as Russia had been taken into confidence about the visit and no doubt felt assured that India would do nothing to harm its interests. Russia has never counselled us not to engage Ukraine, or, for that matter, forge closer relations with the US, including defence ties, an area of prime interest for Moscow in ties with India. The US, on the contrary, openly asks us to dilute ties with Russia, especially in the defence area.</p>

<h2><strong>A Range Of Reasons</strong></h2>

<p>The reasons for Modi visiting Ukraine are diverse. They flow from a developing willingness to play whatever role is feasible in resolving the conflict peacefully. Modi has been saying in many fora that India is willing to be helpful. India's rising stature under Modi's leadership, the success of India's G-20 presidency, the Indian discourse that we seek friendship with all, that we are in a position to talk to countries that may be adversaries of each other, the belief promoted by our Western interlocutors that Modi, after his homily to Putin that "today is not an era of war", could talk peace to the Russian persuasively, may explain why Modi may have felt it was time to carry his message of dialogue and diplomacy to Kyiv.</p>

<p>Beyond this, Modi may have wanted to defuse rising criticism in the US and Ukraine after his visit to Moscow where he embraced Putin in his signature greeting style that Putin too has adopted, by making a balancing visit to Kyiv. During the visit, he consciously embraced Zelenskyy on three occasions, put his arm around his shoulders and held his hand in a gesture of personal empathy and fellow-feeling. The Ukrainian side, keeping in mind that while in Moscow Modi had expressed great anguish to Putin at the killing of children in war, organised a visit to the exhibition in Kyiv on children killed in the ongoing conflict to expose Modi to Russian brutalities. The Ukrainian side had also wanted Modi to visit the hospital allegedly bombed by Russia, but the Indian side would have resisted being drawn into too many anti-Russia elements in the programme.</p>

<h2><strong>India's Position Is Clear</strong></h2>

<p>On substance, India yielded nothing during the visit on the fundamentals of its position on the conflict. India did not endorse Zelenskyy's 10-point peace plan that the Ukrainian president lobbied for. EAM Jaishankar declared in his press briefing that there were multiple ways of approaching the issue of peace talks. India's position is clearly reflected in the joint statement, to the effect that all stakeholders should be engaged to develop innovative solutions that should have broad acceptability. Jaishankar made it a point to draw attention to this para in the joint statement in his press briefing.</p>

<p>It is noteworthy that in the joint statement with Poland and Ukraine, the paragraphs on the Ukraine issue make no mention of Russia by name, just as in the case of the G-20 Delhi Declaration. But there, neither Ukraine nor Poland were present. This was a notable success of Indian diplomacy.<br />
India preserved its equities with Russia while engaging Zelenskyy in Ukraine.</p>

<p>Perhaps the failure to draw India to his side and drive some wedge between India and Russia would explain Zelenskyy's remarks to the Indian press in Kyiv that conveyed his differences with India on substance and altogether lacked diplomatic propriety.</p>

<p><em>(Kanwal Sibal was Foreign Secretary and Ambassador to Turkey, Egypt, France and Russia, and Deputy Chief Of Mission in Washington.)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/kkihncj_pm-modi-and-zelensky_625x300_23_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/telegram-ceos-fate-hangs-in-balance-amid-judicial-proceedings-after-arrest-6433650]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Telegram CEO's Fate Hangs In Balance Amid Judicial Proceedings After Arrest]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/telegram-ceos-fate-hangs-in-balance-amid-judicial-proceedings-after-arrest-6433650]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 28 Aug 2024 08:08:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Pavel Durov, the founder and chief of Telegram, is set to learn Wednesday whether he will face charges and even be remanded in custody after his weekend arrest by French authorities over alleged violations at the messaging app.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pavel Durov, the founder and chief of Telegram, is set to learn Wednesday whether he will face charges and even be remanded in custody after his weekend arrest by French authorities over alleged violations at the messaging app.</p>

<p>Durov, 39, was arrested at Le Bourget airport outside Paris late Saturday, and while the judicial authorities have repeatedly extended his initial period of detention, it can last a maximum of 96 hours.</p>

<p>As part of a probe that was confidentially opened on July 8, Durov is being investigated on suspicion of 12 offences related to failing to curb extremist content on Telegram, sources close to the investigation have said.</p>

<p>The tech mogul founded Telegram as he was in the process of quitting his native Russia a decade ago. Its growth has been exponential, with the app now boasting over 900 million users.</p>

<p>An enigmatic figure who rarely speaks in public, Durov is a citizen of Russia, France and the United Arab Emirates, where Telegram is based.</p>

<p>Forbes magazine estimates his current fortune at $15.5 billion, though he proudly promotes the virtues of an ascetic life that includes ice baths and not drinking alcohol or coffee.</p>

<p>Numerous questions have been raised about the timing and circumstances of Durov's detention, in particular why he flew into Paris apparently knowing a warrant had been issued against him.</p>

<h3><strong>'In no way political'&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>In a post on X to address what he called "false information" concerning the case, French President Emmanuel Macron said Durov's arrest "took place as part of an ongoing judicial investigation".&nbsp;</p>

<p>"It is in no way a political decision. It is up to the judges to rule on the matter," he wrote in a highly unusual comment on a legal case.</p>

<p>In Moscow, Kremlin spokesman Dmitry Peskov said the charges were very serious and thus needed "no less serious evidence".</p>

<p>"Otherwise this would be a direct attempt to restrict freedom of communication, and, I might even say, directly intimidate the head of a large company," he said.</p>

<p>The UAE meanwhile said it was "closely following the case" and had requested consular access for its citizen.</p>

<p>Among those voicing support for Durov is fellow tech tycoon and chief executive of X, Elon Musk, who has posted comments under the hashtag #FreePavel.</p>

<p><strong>'Nothing to hide'&nbsp;</strong><br />
When the initial 96-hour questioning period ends, the investigating magistrate can either free Durov or press charges and remand him in custody.</p>

<p>He could also be freed under judicial control which could include restrictions on his movements.</p>

<p>Durov, who has been based in Dubai in recent years, arrived in Paris from the Azerbaijani capital Baku and was planning to have dinner in the French capital, a source close to the case said.</p>

<p>He was accompanied by a bodyguard and a personal assistant who always travel with him, added the source, asking not to be named.</p>

<p>Russian President Vladimir Putin was in Baku on a state visit to Azerbaijan on August 18 and 19, though Peskov has denied that the two met.</p>

<p>France's OFMIN, an office tasked with preventing violence against minors, issued an arrest warrant for Durov in a preliminary investigation into alleged offences including fraud, drug trafficking, cyberbullying, organised crime and promotion of terrorism.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Telegram said in response that "Durov has nothing to hide and travels frequently in Europe".</p>

<p>"Telegram abides by EU laws, including the Digital Services Act -- its moderation is within industry standards," it added.</p>

<p>"It is absurd to claim that a platform or its owner is responsible for the abuse of that platform."</p>

<p>Telegram has positioned itself as a "neutral" alternative to US-owned platforms, which have been criticised for their commercial exploitation of users' personal data.&nbsp;</p>

<p>It has also played a key role since Russia's invasion of Ukraine, used actively by politicians and commentators on both sides of the war.</p>

<p>But critics accuse it of often hosting illegal content ranging from extreme sexual imagery to disinformation and narcotics services.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/2j54hml8_pavel-durov_625x300_25_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[An enigmatic figure who rarely speaks in public, Pavel Durov is a citizen of Russia, France and UAE(file)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-2024-donald-trump-faces-revised-charges-in-election-subversion-calls-it-witch-hunt-6433543]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Faces Revised Charges In Election Subversion, Calls It "Witch Hunt"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-2024-donald-trump-faces-revised-charges-in-election-subversion-calls-it-witch-hunt-6433543]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 28 Aug 2024 07:34:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prosecutors on Tuesday filed a revised indictment of Donald Trump, pressing ahead with bombshell charges that he tried to overturn the 2020 US election after losing to Joe Biden.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prosecutors on Tuesday filed a revised indictment of Donald Trump, pressing ahead with bombshell charges that he tried to overturn the 2020 US election after losing to Joe Biden.</p>

<p>The superseding indictment retains the same four charges against Trump as in an earlier version but takes into account a recent Supreme Court ruling that a former president has broad immunity from criminal prosecution.</p>

<p>The new indictment of the 78-year-old Republican White House candidate is 36 pages long, down from 45 pages previously, and removes material affected by the immunity ruling from the conservative-dominated top court.</p>

<p>It retains the same core, stating that Trump lost in 2020 but "was determined to remain in power" and attempted to subvert the results.</p>

<p>The Supreme Court ruled in July that an ex-president has broad immunity from prosecution for official acts conducted while in office, but can be pursued for unofficial acts.</p>

<p>This threw into doubt the historic prosecution of the ex-president.</p>

<p>Trump referred to the new indictment as an "act of desperation" that was part of a "witch hunt" against him.</p>

<p>"The illegally appointed 'Special Counsel' Deranged Jack Smith, has brought a ridiculous new Indictment against me, which has all the problems of the old Indictment, and should be dismissed IMMEDIATELY," he posted on his Truth Social platform.</p>

<p>The new indictment comes three days before Special Counsel Jack Smith, who brought the charges against Trump, and lawyers for the former president had been set to file a schedule for pre-trial proceedings.</p>

<p>Judge Tanya Chutkan, who is presiding over the case, had also scheduled a status hearing for September 5 in Washington and it was not immediately clear if that would go ahead now, following the filing of the superseding indictment.</p>

<p>Trump's lawyers have been seeking to delay a trial until after November's election between Trump and Vice President Kamala Harris, the Democratic presidential candidate.</p>

<p>Trump is accused of conspiracy to defraud the United States and conspiracy to obstruct an official proceeding -- the January 6, 2021 joint session of Congress that was attacked by Trump supporters.</p>

<p>Trump is also accused of seeking to disenfranchise US voters with his campaign of false claims that he won the 2020 election.</p>

<p>He was originally scheduled to go on trial on March 4, but that was put on hold while his lawyers pushed his claim of presidential immunity all the way up to the Supreme Court.</p>

<h3><strong>'Private capacity'&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>It will be up to Chutkan, an appointee of former Democratic president Barack Obama, to decide which of Trump's actions regarding the 2020 election were official acts and which were unofficial acts subject to potential prosecution.</p>

<p>That and other pre-trial issues are expected to take months, making it unlikely the case will go to trial before the November 5 presidential vote.</p>

<p>The new indictment drops references to Jeffrey Clark, a former senior Justice Department official who was one of six co-conspirators listed in the original indictment allegedly enlisted by Trump to press his false claims of election fraud.</p>

<p>The Supreme Court, in its immunity ruling, said a president's communications with members of the Justice Department should be considered official acts.</p>

<p>The remaining co-conspirators, who include Trump's former personal lawyer Rudy Giuliani, "were acting in a private capacity," the indictment said, "to assist him in his criminal efforts to overturn the legitimate results of the 2020 presidential election and retain power."</p>

<p>Regarding the ruling on Trump's immunity, Supreme Court Judge Ketanji Brown Jackson said that she was "concerned" about the July verdict, according to an interview released by CBS News on Tuesday.</p>

<p>"I was concerned about a system that appeared to provide immunity for one individual under one set of circumstances when we have a criminal justice system that had ordinarily treated everyone the same," she said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Jackson was among three justices who dissented from the court's ruling.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Trump was convicted in New York in May of 34 counts of falsifying business records to cover up hush money payments made to porn star Stormy Daniels.</p>

<p>Sentencing has been scheduled for September 18, but Trump's lawyers have asked for his conviction to be tossed, citing the Supreme Court immunity ruling, and sentencing to be delayed.</p>

<p>Trump also faces charges in Georgia related to efforts to overturn the 2020 election.</p>

<p>Trump was also charged in Florida with mishandling top-secret documents after leaving the White House.</p>

<p>The judge presiding over the documents case, Aileen Cannon, a Trump appointee, dismissed the charges on the grounds that Smith, the special counsel, was unlawfully appointed.</p>

<p>Smith has appealed Cannon's ruling.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/vjnq2ub_donald-trump_625x300_18_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump also faces charges in Georgia related to efforts to overturn the 2020 election (file).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/all-about-the-rub-al-khali-desert-where-a-telangana-man-died-6427681]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[All About The Rub al-Khali Desert Where A Telangana Man Died]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/all-about-the-rub-al-khali-desert-where-a-telangana-man-died-6427681]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 28 Aug 2024 07:26:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[27-year-old Indian was among two telecommunications professionals who recently died in the harsh Rub' al Khali desert in Saudi Arabia.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>27-year-old Indian was among two telecommunications professionals who recently <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/indians-abroad/telangana-man-colleague-die-in-saudi-arabia-desert-after-losing-gps-signal-6412473">died in the harsh Rub' al Khali desert</a> in Saudi Arabia. Mohammad Shehzad Khan, from Telangana, and his Sudanese colleague were on a mission to repair a cellular tower when they got stranded there following a series of unfortunate events.</p>

<p>Their GPS signal failed, their mobile phones had no battery, and their vehicle ran out of fuel, leaving them exposed to the scorching desert conditions. The incident occurred between August 19 and August 21, and despite efforts to survive, the duo succumbed to dehydration. Their bodies are being repatriated to their respective countries.</p>

<p><strong>Rub' al-Khali Desert</strong></p>

<p>The Rub' al-Khali desert, also known as the Empty Quarter, is the world's most dangerous desert, spanning 650 square km across Saudi Arabia, Oman, Yemen, and the UAE. It is a vast expanse of nothingness, with extreme heat, navigation difficulties, and scarce food and water.</p>

<p>The desert is known for its isolated dunes, horned vipers, burrowing snakes, and boas. The notorious sabkhas, or salt flats, pose a massive challenge for drivers, and the absence of internet and help at hand makes it even more daunting. The Rub' al-Khali desert is unforgiving, with temperatures soaring to extreme highs and lows. The lack of landmarks, combined with the harsh weather conditions, makes it a treacherous terrain for travellers.</p>

<p><strong><em>'Arabian Sands' </em>by Wilfred Thesiger</strong></p>

<p>Despite the risks, adventurers and travellers continue to be drawn to the desert. Wilfred Thesiger, a British explorer, crossed the desert in the 1940s, and his book,<em> Arabian Sands</em>, chronicles his journey.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"To return to the Empty Quarter would be to answer a challenge, and to remain there for long would be to test myself to the limit. Much of it was unexplored. It was one of the very few places left where I could satisfy an urge to go where others had not been... The Empty Quarter offered me the chances to win distinction as a traveller," read an excerpt from the book by Wilfred Thesiger. "For this was the real desert where differences of race and colour, of wealth and social standing, are almost meaningless; where coverings of pretence are stripped away and basic truths emerge."</p>

<p>Mr Thesiger's approach to exploration was distinct, as he embraced physical challenges and chose to travel in a way that was unconventional for his time. He walked barefoot in the desert, preferred camels to cars, and spent extended periods with the Bedouin people, despite his privileged upbringing.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"I pondered on this desert hospitality and compared it with our own. I remembered other encampments where I had slept, small tents on which I had happened in the Syrian desert and where I had spent the night. Gaunt men in rags and hungry-looking children had greeted me, and bade me welcome with the sonorous phrases of the desert," he wrote in <em>Arabian Sands</em>. "In the desert, I had found a freedom unattainable in civilization; a life unhampered by possessions, since everything that was not a necessity was an encumbrance."</p>

<p>Before his journey, only two people had successfully crossed the Empty Quarter: Bertram Thomas in 1931 and Harry St John Philby in 1932.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>'Sabkhas' or salt flats</strong></p>

<p>The Empty Quarter is characterised by its sabkhas, or salt flats, which form when landlocked seas evaporate, leaving behind salt deposits. These salt flats, situated between dunes, pose a significant challenge for drivers due to their soft and expansive nature. Razia Ali, a geophysicist and maths teacher who travelled through the Empty Quarter in February 2023, described her experience with sabkhas as "daunting" and noted the risk of cars becoming stuck in the soft sand.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Ms Ali also highlighted the challenges faced by modern-day travellers. In a post on&nbsp;<a href="https://medium.com/@RaaziaAli/rub-al-khali-where-man-and-nature-are-forced-to-ponder-767cf216b6f9 ">Medium</a>, she described the lack of internet as "like cutting the umbilical cord and leaving you without food and oxygen." She pointed out how deeply modern society was tied to social media and digital communication, saying, "People of this century are slaves of social media. We can't go to sleep without surfing through social media, we can't get out of bed without browsing through WhatsApp, Instagram, TikTok, Snapchat, YouTube and other apps."</p>

<p>The Rub' al-Khali remains an unforgiving environment, with extreme heat, navigation difficulties, isolation, and scarce resources. Despite technological advancements, travellers in the region remain vulnerable to the harsh conditions, where a single GPS malfunction can have severe consequences, even death.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/bdg0vkio_rub-al-khali_625x300_28_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/first-january-6-rioter-to-breach-us-capitol-jailed-for-more-than-4-years-6433249]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[First January 6 Rioter To Breach US Capitol Jailed For More Than 4 Years]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/first-january-6-rioter-to-breach-us-capitol-jailed-for-more-than-4-years-6433249]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 28 Aug 2024 05:57:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Kentucky man who was the first rioter to enter the US Capitol during the January 6, 2021, attack on Congress by Donald Trump supporters was sentenced to 53 months in prison on Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Kentucky man who was the first rioter to enter the US Capitol during the January 6, 2021, attack on Congress by Donald Trump supporters was sentenced to 53 months in prison on Tuesday.</p>

<p>Michael Sparks, 46, a factory supervisor, was convicted in March of civil disorder and disorderly and disruptive conduct in a restricted building.</p>

<p>Prosecutors had sought a sentence of 57 months while Sparks's defense attorneys asked that he be given 12 months of home detention.</p>

<p>District Judge Timothy Kelly sentenced Sparks to 53 months in prison and a $2,000 fine.</p>

<p>In their sentencing memorandum, prosecutors said Sparks was "the very first rioter to enter the United States Capitol building" and "helped light the fire that day."</p>

<p>Sparks jumped through a broken window, they said, "ignoring the warnings of the rioters behind him and the pepper spray (from US Capitol police) that hit him squarely in the face."</p>

<p>Capitol police sergeant Victor Nichols, testifying at Sparks's trial in Washington, said he "acted like a green light for everybody behind him, and everyone followed right behind him."</p>

<p>Nearly 1,500 people have been charged for their roles in the storming of Congress by supporters of former Republican president Trump.</p>

<p>David Dempsey, 37, of Santa Ana, California, described by prosecutors as one of the "most violent" members of the mob, was sentenced to 20 years in prison this month.</p>

<p>The sentence was the second longest handed down so far.</p>

<p>Enrique Tarrio, the former leader of the far-right Proud Boys group, was convicted of seditious conspiracy and sentenced to 22 years in prison.</p>

<p>The assault on the Capitol left at least five people dead and 140 police officers injured.</p>

<p>It followed a fiery speech by Trump to supporters near the White House in which he repeated his false claims that he won the 2020 election.</p>

<p>Trump faces four federal felony charges in Washington related to efforts to overturn the election results, but the case is unlikely to reach trial before the November presidential vote, in which he is once again the Republican candidate.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-12/vm0ddmko_us-capitol-riot_625x300_23_December_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Nearly 1,500 people have been charged for their roles in the storming of Congress in January 2021.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-kamala-harris-agree-to-mute-mics-for-september-10-us-presidential-debate-6433078]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump, Kamala Harris Agree To Mute Mics For September 10 Debate]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-kamala-harris-agree-to-mute-mics-for-september-10-us-presidential-debate-6433078]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 28 Aug 2024 04:56:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump said on Tuesday an agreement has been reached to have closed microphones at the Sept. 10 U.S. presidential debate with Democratic rival Kamala Harris.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump said on Tuesday an agreement has been reached to have closed microphones at the Sept. 10 U.S. presidential debate with Democratic rival Kamala Harris.</p>

<p>The Harris campaign did not immediately return a request for confirmation about the ABC-hosted debate.</p>

<p>The candidates campaigns clashed on Monday over the previously agreed-upon debate, with the vice president's team seeking a return to open microphones while Trump threatened to pull out entirely after suggesting the network was biased.</p>

<p>In a social media post on Tuesday, Trump said the rules for next month's debate will be the same as they were for the June CNN debate he had with President Joe Biden, whose poor performance led him to drop out of the 2024 race.</p>

<p>"The Debate will be 'stand up,' and Candidates cannot bring notes, or 'cheat sheets.' We have also been given assurance by ABC that this will be a 'fair and equitable' Debate, and that neither side will be given the questions in advance," Trump wrote.</p>

<p>The CNN debate did not have a live audience. Trump's post did not mention that.</p>

<p>Harris' campaign had said it wanted the broadcaster to keep the candidates' microphones on throughout the event, not muted when their opponent was speaking as in the last presidential debate. So-called "hot mics" can help or hurt political candidates, catching offhand comments that sometimes were not meant for the public.</p>

<p>While Trump's team said it had already agreed to have closed microphones, Trump later told reporters that he preferred to have his microphone kept on.</p>

<p>Trump's campaign has floated an additional debate on Sept. 4 on Fox News network but the Harris team rejected that.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ugf3uu1g_trump-harris-_625x300_22_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Trump said on Tuesday an agreement has been reached to have closed microphones at the Sept. 10.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-koreas-kim-jong-un-attends-test-firing-of-rocket-launcher-6433045]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[North Korea's Kim Jong Un Attends Test-Firing Of Rocket Launcher]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-koreas-kim-jong-un-attends-test-firing-of-rocket-launcher-6433045]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 28 Aug 2024 04:41:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[North Korean leader Kim Jong Un attended the test of an upgraded 240 mm rocket launcher system, state media said on Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>North Korean leader Kim Jong Un attended the test of an upgraded 240 mm rocket launcher system, state media said on Wednesday.</p>

<p>The system "proved its superiority in mobility and strike concentration" during the inspection testing, state news agency KCNA said.</p>

<p>Earlier this week, Kim Jong Un oversaw tests of new "suicide drones," watching them take off and destroy test targets including a mock tank, and urged researchers to develop artificial intelligence for the unmanned vehicles.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/mnt7e4vo_kim-jong-un-_625x300_14_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Earlier this week, Kim Jong Un oversaw tests of new "suicide drones".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukraine-claims-seizure-of-100-settlements-in-russia-6433013]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ukraine Claims Seizure Of 100 Settlements In Russia]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukraine-claims-seizure-of-100-settlements-in-russia-6433013]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 28 Aug 2024 04:34:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ukrainian troops have seized 100 settlements in Russia since they broke into bordering Russia's Kursk region on August 6, Oleksandr Syrsky, Commander-in-Chief of the Ukrainian Armed Forces, said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ukrainian troops have seized 100 settlements in Russia since they broke into bordering Russia's Kursk region on August 6, Oleksandr Syrsky, Commander-in-Chief of the Ukrainian Armed Forces, said.</p>

<p>"We continue to advance forward, inflicting significant losses on the Russian troops in manpower and equipment," Syrsky was cited as saying by the Interfax-Ukraine news agency on Tuesday.</p>

<p>According to Syrsky, Russia has redeployed about 30,000 troops from other areas to the Kursk region and is now trying to form "a defensive ring" around the Ukrainian forces, Xinhua news agency reported.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Russia's Defence Ministry said in a statement on Tuesday that its Akhmat special forces had carried out a reconnaissance operation, securing a commanding height in the Sudzha district in the Kursk region, previously held by Ukraine.</p>

<p>The height was located 400-500 metres away from Ukrainian forward positions.</p>

<p>The Russian troops can now monitor Ukrainian military movements, TASS reported citing a source at the scene.</p>

<p>Syrsky said that Ukraine launched an operation in Kursk with the aim of creating a buffer zone to prevent shelling in Ukraine's adjacent Sumy region, adding that his troops continue to advance and have captured 594 Russian servicemen.</p>

<p>According to Syrskyi, Russia is trying to oppose Ukraine by withdrawing troops from other fronts.</p>

<p>He said that Russia is not withdrawing forces from the Pokrovsk front in Ukraine's eastern Donetsk region, where he said the situation remained "difficult".</p>

<p>The Kursk region has been the site of an offensive since the night of August 5-6, when Ukrainian forces entered the region near the town of Sudzha, about 10 km (6.2 miles) from the border.</p>

<p>Russian President Vladimir Putin accused Kyiv of carrying out a "large-scale provocation" and "indiscriminate shooting," defining the incursion as a "terrorist attack".</p>

<p>Days later, Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky admitted it was an "operation" by Ukraine's troops, specifying that the goal is to create a "buffer zone" against Russian attacks.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-09/cj3eokm4_russia-ukraine-war_625x300_13_September_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[According to Ukraine, Russia is trying to oppose Ukraine by withdrawing troops from other fronts.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-agrees-to-debate-with-kamala-harris-outlines-specific-rules-6432983]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Agrees To Debate With Kamala Harris, Outlines Specific Rules]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-agrees-to-debate-with-kamala-harris-outlines-specific-rules-6432983]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 28 Aug 2024 04:21:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ahead of the presidential elections in the United States, former US President and Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump accepted the debate with Vice President Kamala Harris, outlining specific conditions and rules for the face-off.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ahead of the presidential elections in the United States, former US President and Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump accepted the debate with Vice President Kamala Harris, outlining specific conditions and rules for the face-off.</p>

<p>Sharing a post on the social media platform Truth, Trump said, "I have reached an agreement with the Radical Left Democrats for a debate with Comrade Kamala Harris. It will be broadcast live on ABC FAKE NEWS, by far the nastiest and most unfair newscaster in the business, on Tuesday, September 10th, in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania."</p>

<p>This comes after Trump suggested over the weekend he might cancel the debate amid a feud between the campaigns over the rules.</p>

<p>Trump said on Truth Social he and Harris had reached an agreement to follow the same set of rules he and President Joe Biden did during the June 27 CNN debate, including no live audience and muted microphones when the candidates aren't speaking.</p>

<p>"The rules will be the same as the last CNN debate, which seemed to work out well for everyone except, perhaps, Crooked Joe Biden. The debate will be "stand up," and candidates cannot bring notes, or "cheat sheets." We have also been given assurance by ABC that this will be a "fair and equitable" debate and that neither side will be given the questions in advance (No Donna Brazile!)."</p>

<p>The Republican presidential candidate further stated that a third debate has not been agreed upon by the Radical Left. The post said, "Harris would not agree to the FoxNews debate on September 4th, but that date will be held open in case she changes her mind or, Flip Flops, as she has done on every single one of her long-held and cherished policy beliefs. A possible third debate, which would go to NBC FAKE NEWS, has not been agreed to by the Radical Left. GOD BLESS AMERICA!"</p>

<p>Notably, Biden's halting and disjointed performance in his June debate with Trump at CNN ultimately led him to drop out of the presidential race.</p>

<p>Harris entered the fray for the presidential ticket after US President Joe Biden announced in July that he was withdrawing from the election bid.</p>

<p>If elected president, the 59-year-old Harris would become the first woman in history to become the US president. The vice president is only the second woman ever nominated for the presidency by a major political party.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/knofc75_donald-trump-kamala-harris_625x300_31_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump accepted the debate with Vice President Kamala Harris.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-says-droplets-a-minor-route-of-mpox-spread-what-we-know-so-far-6432134]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[WHO Says Droplets A Minor Route Of Mpox Spread. What We Know So Far]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-says-droplets-a-minor-route-of-mpox-spread-what-we-know-so-far-6432134]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 28 Aug 2024 00:04:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The World Health Organization (WHO) said today that droplets were a "minor" route of transmission for mpox compared to physical contact, saying that more research is required to understand how the virus spreads.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The World Health Organization (WHO) said today that droplets were a "minor" route of transmission for mpox compared to physical contact, adding that more research is required to understand how the virus spreads.</p>

<p>The UN health agency declared mpox a public health emergency of international concern on August 14 amid a surge of cases across the Democratic Republic of Congo (DRC) and its neighbouring countries.</p>

<p>Mainly, two distinct clades of the virus, Ia and Ib, are causing significant concern in the DRC. A third variant, Clade II, originated in Nigeria and has been responsible for the global outbreak that began in 2022.</p>

<h3><strong>What is Mpox?</strong></h3>

<p>The mpox virus is an orthopoxvirus that causes mpox (monkeypox), a disease with symptoms similar to smallpox, although less severe, according to the WHO website.&nbsp;</p>

<p>What are the symptoms of Mpox?</p>

<ol>
	<li>Fever</li>
	<li>Extensive characteristic rash&nbsp;</li>
	<li>Swollen lymph nodes</li>
	<li>Headache</li>
	<li>Back pain and muscle ache</li>
	<li>Lack of energy</li>
</ol>

<p>The incubation period of mpox can range from 5 to 21 days. The febrile stage of illness (when fever persists) usually lasts 1 to 3 days, according to WHO. This is followed by the skin eruption stage, which can last for 2 to 4 weeks.</p>

<h3><strong>How does Mpox spread?</strong></h3>

<p>WHO has said that mpox spreads between people mainly through close physical contact with someone who has the virus. "Close contact includes skin-to-skin (such as touching or sex) and mouth-to-mouth, or mouth-to-skin contact (such as kissing)," it said.</p>

<p>However, WHO spokeswoman Margaret Harris said today that if a person with the virus had lesions, "if you're talking closely to someone, breathing on them, physically close, face-to-face, there is a possibility" of viral spread, "but this is a minor source".</p>

<p>"When you're talking to somebody, you're spitting out droplets," but "it's not a very major form of transmission -- and it's not a... through-the-air, long-distance sort of transmission," she added.</p>

<p>The WHO recommends the use of facemasks for those with mpox, their close contacts and health workers treating them.</p>

<h3><strong>Does mpox have a vaccine?</strong></h3>

<p>Yes, there are vaccines recommended by WHO for use against mpox. However, only people who are at risk should get the vaccine. WHO has not recommended mass vaccination against mpox.</p>

<h3><strong>How has India prepared for a possible mpox outbreak?</strong></h3>

<p>India currently has no active mpox cases. The government had ordered the authorities in airports, ports and borders with Bangladesh and Pakistan to remain alert about incoming international passengers who show mpox symptoms.</p>

<p>The All India Institute for Medical Sciences (AIIMS) had issued protocols for handling suspected mpox cases in India. Various government hospitals were directed to set up isolation rooms for suspected and confirmed cases of mpox.</p>

<p>The institute has recommended setting up a screening process in the triage area wherein, upon arrival, patients with fever, rash, or a history of contact with confirmed mpox cases should be flagged for immediate assessment.</p>

<p>According to an assessment, the risk of a large outbreak with sustained transmission is low, officials had said.<br />
&nbsp;</p>

<p>(With inputs from AFP)</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/j3oo1mhg_mpox-reuters_625x300_20_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mpox has symptoms similar to smallpox, although less severe, according to WHO. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trumps-edge-over-kamala-harris-on-economy-crime-is-eroding-report-6431887]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump's Edge Over Kamala Harris On Economy, Crime Is Eroding: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trumps-edge-over-kamala-harris-on-economy-crime-is-eroding-report-6431887]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 27 Aug 2024 23:11:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump's advantage over Kamala Harris on the economy and crime is eroding among U.S. voters, a sign the Democratic vice president's campaign is gathering momentum ahead of the Nov. 5 presidential election, according to a new Reuters/Ipsos poll.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump's advantage over Kamala Harris on the economy and crime is eroding among U.S. voters, a sign the Democratic vice president's campaign is gathering momentum ahead of the Nov. 5 presidential election, according to a new Reuters/Ipsos poll.</p>

<p>The three-day poll, conducted Aug. 23-25, showed Republican former President Trump's approach to the economy and employment was preferred by 43% of registered voters compared to 40% who preferred Harris's approach. The 3 percentage point difference was too small to be significant given the poll's 4 percentage point margin of error. A prior Reuters/Ipsos poll in late July showed Trump with an 11-point advantage on the economy.</p>

<p>On crime and corruption, Harris and Trump were tied with 40% support for each, showing more movement toward Harris, who trailed Trump by 5 points in the July poll.</p>

<p>Recent national polls have shown Harris building a small lead over Trump since she entered the race on July 21 following President Joe Biden's decision to fold his campaign. The Reuters/Ipsos poll from late July showed Harris up by 1 point, 43% to 42%.</p>

<p>It remains to be seen how the race will be affected by independent candidate Robert F. Kennedy Jr's decision on Friday to suspend his campaign. Kennedy, who had attracted the support of about 8% of voters in a July poll, subsequently endorsed Trump.</p>

<p>Trump's campaign speeches frequently criticize the Biden administration's management of the economy as households continue to feel the sting of several years of high inflation. Harris has pledged to get prices under control through efforts like cracking down on "price gouging" by grocers.</p>

<p>The new poll showed the economy was the biggest issue for 26% of registered voters, compared to 22% who picked political extremism and threats to democracy and 13% who picked immigration.</p>

<p>Voters picked Harris over Trump on the issue of extremism by 42% to 36%. Trump had an advantage on immigration policy, picked by 45% of voters compared to Harris' 37%.</p>

<p>Neither of the two candidates is broadly liked, with 59% of voters saying they have an unfavorable view of Trump and 52% saying the same of Harris. Harris was viewed favorably by 47% of voters, compared to 39% for Trump.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The poll gathered responses online from 1,028 adults nationwide, including 902 registered voters.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/06lu95io_kamala-harris-donald-trump-afp_625x300_03_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[On crime and corruption, Harris and Trump were tied with 40% support for each.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukraine-wants-next-peace-summit-to-be-held-in-global-south-6431851]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ukraine Wants Next Peace Summit To Be Held In Global South]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukraine-wants-next-peace-summit-to-be-held-in-global-south-6431851]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 27 Aug 2024 23:08:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Ukrainian presidency on Tuesday said it wanted the next peace summit aimed at ending the conflict in Ukraine to be held in a country of the Global South.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Ukrainian presidency on Tuesday said it wanted the next peace summit aimed at ending the conflict in Ukraine to be held in a country of the Global South.</p>

<p>Leaders and top officials from more than 90 states gathered in Switzerland in June for a first summit organised by Ukraine, held without Russia or China.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"We would like for the second summit to be held in one of the countries of the Global South," Andriy Yermak said at a forum in Kyiv.</p>

<p>The Global South refers to several countries and blocs outside Europe and North America, whose foreign policy interests are not fully aligned with either Kyiv or Moscow.</p>

<p>Russia had been excluded from the first summit but Ukraine said it hoped Moscow could be involved in a second round of talks.</p>

<p>"If Russian representatives want to attend the second summit, they will attend," Ukraine's President Volodymyr Zelensky said Tuesday.</p>

<p>Any diplomatic breakthrough however looks elusive as the Kremlin said it "will not talk" to Ukraine since its counter-assault in Russia's Kursk region.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Even before the incursion, the Kremlin insisted any peace deal would need to force Kyiv to surrender territory that Moscow claims as its own -- an unacceptable condition for Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Kyiv's announcement comes a few days after Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi visited Kyiv, where he advocated for peace.</p>

<p>Mr Modi "made it absolutely clear that India will never support any plan, any proposal that includes any compromise with the territorial integrity of Ukraine," Mr Yermak said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>However neither side showed any signs of breakthrough in Kyiv -- and India firmly believes Moscow should be involved in diplomatic efforts.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Mr Modi spoke to Russian President Vladimir Putin and "emphasised his interest to contribute to a possible political and diplomatic settlement of the situation around Ukraine," the Kremlin said Tuesday.</p>

<p>Besides Modi, Zelensky has met with several leaders of countries in the Global South including South African President Cyril Ramaphosa.</p>

<p>He is yet to meet with Chinese leader Xi Jinping, who has become Moscow's key political and economic partner since it invaded Ukraine in February 2022.</p>

<p>"The only thing that remains is for our president to meet with the leader of China. But I am confident that this will happen," Mr Yermak said.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-05/bca7ka1s_ukraine-president-volodymyr-zelensky_625x300_21_May_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The first peace summit was organised by Ukraine in Switzerland in June. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-captures-fatal-crash-motorcyclist-dies-in-collision-on-british-highway-6431797]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Motorcyclist Dies In Collision On British Highway]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-captures-fatal-crash-motorcyclist-dies-in-collision-on-british-highway-6431797]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 27 Aug 2024 22:57:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Despite efforts by an off-duty doctor and ambulance staff, the man was pronounced dead at the scene.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A motorcycle rider was tragically killed in a collision with a car on the British highway A4112 near Kinnersley, Herefordshire, on Sunday. The fatal crash occurred around Monday, leaving one person dead. The video of the tragic accident has gone viral on social media.</p>

<p>The viral video shows a motorcyclist travelling at dangerously high speed crashing into a car that was making a slow right turn. Despite the motorcyclist's attempt to brake sharply upon realising the imminent collision, he lost control, causing the bike to flip. The impact triggered a devastating fire that engulfed both the rider and the motorcycle.</p>

<p>According to a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://wmas.nhs.uk/2024/08/27/motorcyclist-dies-in-hereford-collision/">release by the National Health Service of the UK</a>, West Midlands Ambulance Service received calls from police and fire colleagues reporting a road traffic collision involving a motorcycle and a car on the A4112 in Kinnersley, Hereford, at 11.05am yesterday (26th August 2024). Two ambulances and a paramedic officer responded to the scene.</p>

<p>A West Midlands Ambulance Service spokeswoman said: "On arrival, ambulance staff found a motorcyclist, a man, who was in a critical condition being cared for by an off-duty doctor. Sadly, nothing could be done to save the man, and he was confirmed dead on scene. No one else was injured in the collision."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/4q1ir6ro_video-captures-fatal-crash_625x300_27_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The video captures the moment of the collision between the car and motorcycle.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/australia-restricts-foreign-student-intake-for-2025-indians-impacted-6431742]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Australia Restricts Foreign Student Intake For 2025, Indians Impacted]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/australia-restricts-foreign-student-intake-for-2025-indians-impacted-6431742]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 27 Aug 2024 22:45:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Australia has announced that it will be limiting its international student intake to 2.7 lakh in 2025 in a bid to tackle record levels of migration that has led to skyrocketing house rental prices.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Australia has announced that it will be limiting its international student intake to 2.7 lakh in 2025 in a bid to tackle record levels of migration that has led to skyrocketing house rental prices.</p>

<p>The limit includes higher education courses as well as vocational education and training courses, Australia's Education Minister Jason Clare said today.</p>

<p>The move is set to impact Indian students hoping to go abroad for higher education, especially those from Punjab which accounts for a large number of such students.</p>

<p>"In June 2022, Australia capped the foreign student intake at 5.10 lakh. This number was reduced to 3.75 lakh in 2023. Now they have reduced the annual planning levels further. These levels are accorded to individual universities for all international students and not just for Indian students. The universities will distribute the quotas country wise then state wise," &nbsp;Sunil Jaggi, a member of Migration Agents Registration Authority of Australia, said.</p>

<p>"The students who were preparing to take admission for the February intake will get affected by this announcement. Students from Punjab will be worst affected," he further said.</p>

<p>"This will affect my career. My family is taking loans for my education as the cost of studying in Australia is quite high," a student from Haryana, who wishes to study nursing in Australia, said.</p>

<p>"The Indian government must put forward students' point of view to the Australian government," another student said.</p>

<p>Notably, the Australian Education Minister on a visit to India last year had signed an agreement to expand in-country access to Australian higher education institutions for Indian students.</p>

<p>According to India's Ministry of External Affairs, around 1.22 lakh students from the country study in Australia. India's Quad partner is the fourth most popular destination for Indian students studying abroad, after Canada, the US and the UK.</p>

<p>Australia also increased its non-refundable visa fee for foreign students from AUD 710 to AUD 1,600, another measure that seemingly aims to reduce migration levels.</p>

<p>Canada has also announced new restrictions on its temporary foreign workers' programme. Starting September 26, businesses will only be allowed to fill up to 10 per cent of their workforce with low-wage foreign workers, down from the previous 20 per cent. The decision to limit the number of low-wage foreign workers comes in response to rising unemployment rates in Canada. The overall unemployment rate has climbed to 6.4 per cent, with the rate for younger workers reaching 14.2 per cent.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/fbqec90g_australia-students-generic-bloomberg-_625x300_27_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Australia has raised its visa fee for foreign students from AUD 710 to AUD 1,600. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-woman-handcuffed-son-allowed-him-to-bemauled-by-pitbull-as-punishment-police-6431352]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Woman Handcuffed Son, Allowed Him To Be Mauled By Pitbull: Police]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-woman-handcuffed-son-allowed-him-to-bemauled-by-pitbull-as-punishment-police-6431352]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 27 Aug 2024 21:49:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The incident occurred on August 17, 2024, in Savannah, Ohio. Police found the child in serious condition and quickly transported him to the hospital.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An Ohio woman and her boyfriend have been arrested following a shocking incident in which her 6-year-old son was handcuffed as a form of "corporal punishment" before being attacked by a pit bull, according to police. Angelina Williams, 27, of Cleveland, and her boyfriend, Taylor Marvin-Brown, now face charges of endangering children and obstructing justice.</p>

<p>In a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ashlandcountysheriff.org/news-releases/2024/8/20/savannah"><em>release,</em></a> the Ashland County Police said, "On Saturday, August 17, 2024, at 5:06 pm the cops received a 911 call for a squad to be sent to 23 Chapel Street, Savannah, Ohio. Dispatchers were told that a Pitbull had bitten a 6-year-old child on the neck and ear. When the squad members and deputies arrived, the child was in serious condition, and Life Flight was called. Deputies identified the mother as Angelina Williams of Cleveland, Ohio, who was living with a family member of Robert Michalski, who was the owner of the house and dog. Robert had left the house with Pitbull prior to deputies arriving."</p>

<p>Detectives and deputies learnt through an investigation that the 6-year-old child had been restrained with handcuffs on his hands and feet when the Pitbull attacked him.</p>

<p>A search warrant was executed at the house where deputies recovered evidence to support the investigation. Also, they found Robert and the Pitbull hiding in a cubbyhole upstairs at the residence. The Pitbull was taken into custody to be housed as a vicious dog.</p>

<p>Angelina Williams and Robert Michalski were taken into custody and taken to jail. Angelina's boyfriend, Taylor Desiree Marvin-Brown, was at the house and assisted with the restraining of the 6-year-old child. She was taken into custody along with Williams and Michalski.</p>

<p>The investigation will continue, and the case will be forwarded to the Ashland County Prosecutor's Office.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/vq9a3nh8_pitbull-attacked-boy_625x300_27_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The dog's owner, are now facing charges of child endangerment.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/regret-not-speaking-out-meta-ceo-mark-zuckerberg-on-us-pressure-to-censor-covid-19-posts-6431267]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Regret Not Speaking Out: Mark Zuckerberg On US Pressure Over Covid Posts]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/regret-not-speaking-out-meta-ceo-mark-zuckerberg-on-us-pressure-to-censor-covid-19-posts-6431267]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 27 Aug 2024 21:33:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Meta CEO Mark Zuckerberg believes US government pressure on his social media platforms to take down certain Covid-19 content in 2021 was "wrong", according to a letter submitted to a US congressional committee.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Meta CEO Mark Zuckerberg believes US government pressure on his social media platforms to take down certain Covid-19 content in 2021 was "wrong," and said he would resist similar attempts in the future, according to a letter submitted to a US congressional committee.</p>

<p>In the letter, addressed to House Judiciary Committee Chairman Jim Jordan and released by Republicans on the committee, Mr Zuckerberg addressed a number of controversies centered on content moderation on his platforms.</p>

<p>He also asserted that he did not plan on repeating funding efforts for US election infrastructure ahead of the country's presidential poll this year, donations that had drawn sharp criticism from Republicans.</p>

<p>Mr Zuckerberg's submission to the committee on Monday comes just over two months out from a tightly contested US presidential election race, with the spotlight on widespread online misinformation about the candidates.</p>

<p>Regarding the pandemic, the Facebook founder said President Joe Biden's administration had in 2021 "repeatedly pressured our teams for months to censor certain COVID-19 content, including humor and satire."</p>

<p>"I believe the government pressure was wrong, and I regret that we were not more outspoken about it," Mr Zuckerberg wrote.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"I feel strongly that we should not compromise our content standards due to pressure from any administration in either direction -- and we're ready to push back if something like this happens again."</p>

<p>Republicans took the letter as a victory, with the Republicans' House Judiciary Committee account on social media platform X, formerly Twitter, labeling it a "big win for free speech."</p>

<p>The White House defended its actions during the pandemic, which killed more than a million people in the United States amid bitter political battles over vaccines and attempts to limit the spread of the virus.</p>

<p>"When confronted with a deadly pandemic, this administration encouraged responsible actions to protect public health and safety," a White House spokesman said Tuesday.</p>

<p>"We believe tech companies and other private actors should take into account the effects their actions have."</p>

<p>Zuckerberg said he would not be repeating his Covid-era push to fund non-profits working to support US electoral infrastructure due to such donations being seen by Republicans as being partisan.</p>

<p>"My goal is to be neutral and not play a role one way or another -- or to even appear to be playing a role," he wrote.</p>

<p>The letter also touched on controversy regarding Facebook's handling of a story regarding US President Joe Biden's son Hunter that was published by the New York Post in 2020.</p>

<p>Zuckerberg said the story, which purported to expose corrupt dealings by the Biden family, was "temporarily demoted" while Facebook fact-checkers probed the possibility of it being "a potential Russian disinformation operation."</p>

<p>The Meta CEO said the story was ultimately found not to be part of such an operation and that the platform has changed its policy such that posts in the United States are no longer demoted while fact checkers investigate them.</p>

<p>Republicans in Congress have been targeting social media and tech companies in recent months, alleging that they are suppressing or censoring conservative views.</p>

<p>Donald Trump, who is seeking a return to power in November after losing his reelection fight to Biden in 2020, claimed that Zuckerberg's statement offered support for his conspiracy theory that the election was stolen.</p>

<p>"This is what everyone's been waiting for -- THE 2020 PRESIDENTIAL ELECTION WAS RIGGED!" Trump wrote on his Truth Social platform.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/0hc64vf_mark-zuckerberg_625x300_26_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["My goal is to be neutral and not play a role one way or another," Mark Zuckerberg said. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/2-5-billion-public-funds-stolen-in-iraqs-heist-of-the-century-6431208]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[$2.5 Billion Public Funds Stolen In Iraq's "Heist Of The Century"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/2-5-billion-public-funds-stolen-in-iraqs-heist-of-the-century-6431208]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 27 Aug 2024 21:27:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An Iraqi criminal court on Tuesday issued arrest warrants for a businessman and a former government official wanted over their alleged involvement in stealing $2.5 billion of public funds.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An Iraqi criminal court on Tuesday issued arrest warrants for a businessman and a former government official wanted over their alleged involvement in stealing $2.5 billion of public funds.</p>

<p>The scandal dubbed the "heist of the century", sparked widespread anger in Iraq, which is ravaged by rampant corruption, unemployment and decaying infrastructure after decades of conflict.</p>

<p>The criminal court issued the warrants for businessman Nour Zuhair and Haitham al-Juburi, a former adviser to then prime minister Mustafa al-Kadhemi, state news agency INA reported.</p>

<p>The two suspects are among several facing a trial which opened in mid-August, but are on the run and failed to appear in court.</p>

<p>According to the tax authorities, the defendants allegedly expropriated the $2.5 billion between September 2021 and August 2022 through 247 cheques cashed by five companies.</p>

<p>The money was subsequently withdrawn -- in cash -- from the firms' accounts.</p>

<p>The owners of those accounts -- most of whom are also on the run -- have also been subject to arrest warrants.</p>

<p>Around 30 suspects are facing trial, INA reported, including six already behind bars or awaiting extradition to Iraq, the national anti-fraud agency has said.</p>

<p>In October 2022, Zuhair was arrested at Baghdad airport as he was trying to leave the country.</p>

<p>A month later he was released on bail after giving back more than $125 million and pledging to return the rest in instalments.</p>

<p>Juburi also returned $2.6 million of the allegedly embezzled funds before disappearing, a judicial source told AFP.</p>

<p>The current whereabouts of both men is unknown.</p>

<p>However, wealthy businessman Zuhair was back in the news over the few days after he reportedly had a car crash in Lebanon, following an interview he gave to an Iraqi news channel.</p>

<p>"The Nour Zuhair affair is a scandal... that concerns the entire political system," Iraqi journalist and commentator Hamed al-Sayyed told AFP.</p>

<p>He blamed the authorities for releasing him on bail two years ago, allowing him "to flee".</p>

<p>"His release from jail, at a time when he was being investigated, shows that the political system, at the highest echelons, is complicit," Sayyed added.</p>

<p>Corruption is endemic in Iraqi state institutions, with the top echelons of power often evading accountability.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/b3mfkeso_cyber-crime-generic-istock_625x300_08_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The two suspects are among several facing a trial. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/pm-narendra-modi-to-visit-singapore-soon-a-look-at-the-likely-agenda-6430835]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[PM Modi To Visit Singapore Soon. A Look At The Likely Agenda]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/pm-narendra-modi-to-visit-singapore-soon-a-look-at-the-likely-agenda-6430835]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 27 Aug 2024 20:33:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Narendra Modi is likely to visit Singapore soon to further strengthen bilateral ties between the two nations. The specific dates for the prime minister's official visit are not known yet, but it will happen shortly, a top official said]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi is likely to visit Singapore soon to further strengthen bilateral ties between the two nations. The specific dates for the prime minister's official visit are not known yet, but it will happen shortly, a top official said.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Modi's visit to Singapore was mentioned by Singaporean Foreign Minister Vivian Balakrishnan after senior ministers of India and Singapore concluded a high-level meeting to further their strategic ties.</p>

<p>A four-member Indian delegation comprising Finance Minister Nirmala Sitharaman, External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar, Commerce Minister Piyush Goyal, and Railway &amp; IT Minister Ashwini Vaishnaw participated in the second India-Singapore Ministerial Roundtable (ISMR) in Singapore.</p>

<p>Calling the meeting "productive", Mr Balakrishnan said, "We will, very shortly, be announcing an official visit by Prime Minister Modi to Singapore. I cannot give you the specific date, but it will occur shortly".</p>

<p>During the multi-ministerial meeting, the two countries discussed ways to boost bilateral cooperation in the digital arena, skill development, sustainability, healthcare, connectivity and manufacturing.</p>

<p>Mr Balakrishnan further said that advanced manufacturing and semiconductors, as well as aviation and maritime connectivity are the new areas that Singapore and India have added to their bilateral talks.</p>

<p>"A country with more than 1.4 billion people is now embarking on a major upgrade of its aviation sector. This is a once in a two, three-decade opportunity, and it's good that we are, in a sense, in the front seat and have a chance (to collaborate)," he said.</p>

<p>At the meeting, Singapore was represented by Deputy Prime Minister and Trade and Industry Minister Gan Kim Yong, Home Affairs and Law Minister K. Shanmugam, Digital Development and Information Minister Josephine Teo, Manpower Minister Tan See Leng and Transport Minister Chee Hong Tat.</p>

<p>"During the meeting, the ministers reaffirmed the close and long-standing relationship between the two nations, underpinned by strong economic and people-to-people ties," Singapore's Ministry of Foreign Affairs and Ministry of Trade and Industry said in a joint release.</p>

<p>Besides a link-up between Singapore's PayNow and India's Unified Payments Interface (UPI) in February 2023, which lets financial institutions from both sides transfer funds in real time, the two countries have also facilitated investments in renewable energy, such as green ammonia.</p>

<p>"I am confident that the discussions we had today and those in the future will pave the way to foster greater collaboration between Singapore and India," Singapore's Deputy Prime Minister said.</p>

<p>An official announcement by the Ministry of External Affairs regarding Prime Minister Narendra Modi's visit is awaited.</p>

<p><em><strong>(Inputs from PTI)</strong></em><br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-06/2dr9i44k_narendra-modi-wave-narendra-modi-india-flag-ndtv-file-photo_625x300_15_June_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[PM Modi is likely to visit Singapore soon to further strengthen bilateral ties between the two nations.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-says-west-playing-with-fire-warns-us-of-risks-of-world-war-iii-6430340]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russia Says West Playing With Fire, Warns US Of Risks Of World War III]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-says-west-playing-with-fire-warns-us-of-risks-of-world-war-iii-6430340]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 27 Aug 2024 19:29:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russia said the West was playing with fire by considering allowing Ukraine to strike deep into Russia with Western missiles and cautioned the United States on Tuesday that World War Three would not be confined to Europe.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russia said the West was playing with fire by considering allowing Ukraine to strike deep into Russia with Western missiles and cautioned the United States on Tuesday that World War Three would not be confined to Europe.</p>

<p>Ukraine attacked Russia's western Kursk region on Aug. 6 and has carved out a slice of territory in the biggest foreign attack on Russia since World War Two. President Vladimir Putin said there would be a worthy response from Russia to the attack.</p>

<p>Sergei Lavrov, who has served as Putin's foreign minister for more than 20 years, said that the West was seeking to escalate the Ukraine war and was "asking for trouble" by considering Ukrainian requests to loosen curbs on using foreign-supplied weapons.</p>

<p>Since invading Ukraine in 2022, Putin has repeatedly warned of the risk of a much broader war involving the world's biggest nuclear powers, though he has said Russia does not want a conflict with the U.S.-led NATO alliance.</p>

<p>"We are now confirming once again that playing with fire - and they are like small children playing with matches - is a very dangerous thing for grown-up uncles and aunts who are entrusted with nuclear weapons in one or another Western country," Lavrov told reporters in Moscow.</p>

<p>"Americans unequivocally associate conversations about the Third World War as something that, God forbid, if it happens, will affect Europe exclusively," Lavrov said.</p>

<p>Lavrov added that Russia was "clarifying" its nuclear doctrine.</p>

<p>Russia's 2020 nuclear doctrine sets out when its president would consider using a nuclear weapon: broadly as a response to an attack using nuclear or other weapons of mass destruction or conventional weapons "when the very existence of the state is put under threat".</p>

<p><strong>RUSSIA'S RESPONSE</strong></p>

<p>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskiy said earlier this month that the assault on Russia's Kursk region showed that Kremlin threats of retaliation were a bluff.</p>

<p>Zelenskiy said Ukraine, because of the restrictions imposed by allies, could not use the weapons at its disposal to hit some Russian military targets. He urged allies to be bolder in their decisions about how to help Kyiv in the war.</p>

<p>Russia has said that Western weaponry, including British tanks and U.S. rocket systems, have been used by Ukraine in Kursk. Kyiv has confirmed using U.S. HIMARS missiles to take out bridges in Kursk.</p>

<p>Washington says it was not informed about Ukraine's plans ahead of the surprise incursion into Kursk. The United States has also said it did not take any part in the operation.</p>

<p>Putin's foreign intelligence chief, Sergei Naryshkin, said on Tuesday that Moscow did not believe Western assertions that it had nothing to do with the Kursk attack. Russian Deputy Foreign Minister Sergei Ryabkov said the involvement of the United States was "an obvious fact".</p>

<p>The New York Times reported that the United States and Britain provided Ukraine with satellite imagery and other information about the Kursk region in the days after the Ukrainian attack.</p>

<p>The Times said that the intelligence was aimed at helping Ukraine keep better track of Russian reinforcements.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/p59m2dh8_putin-afp_625x300_13_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[President Vladimir Putin said there would be a worthy response from Russia to the attack.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>