<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Fri, 11 Oct 2024 18:21:25 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/why-india-shouldnt-let-russia-and-china-control-brics-agenda-6767416]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: India Can Do A Lot With BRICS - If It Doesn't Let China Run The Show]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/why-india-shouldnt-let-russia-and-china-control-brics-agenda-6767416]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 11 Oct 2024 17:28:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[China and Russia are pushing BRICS to become a decidedly anti-West bloc. The recent inclusion of anti-West Iran, at their behest, is a case in point.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/r4gkka2_brics_625x300_11_October_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Among all BRICS leaders, it's perhaps Russian President Vladimir Putin who is waiting for this year's summit, scheduled to be held on October 22-24 in Kazan, most eagerly.</p>

<p>Last year, he skipped the summit in South Africa for fear of being arrested. In March 2023, the International Criminal Court (ICC) issued an arrest warrant for Putin over alleged war crimes committed during Russia's full-scale invasion of Ukraine. South Africa, as a signatory to the Rome Statute, would have been obligated to arrest him had he entered the country. And so, Putin had to make do with virtual participation.</p>

<p>But this year's BRICS summit will be a significant moment for him as he will not only host the event on his own turf but he will also be keen to show to the Western world that despite their sanctions on Russia and attempts to diplomatically isolate him, he is still playing host to some of the world's most influential leaders, such as Prime Minister Narendra Modi and Chinese President Xi Jinping. As a host, Putin's effort will be to highlight Russia's successful outreach to non-Western countries.</p>

<p>It is true that despite Western sanctions, Russia remains a pivotal member of this dynamic group, which represents 24% of the global nominal GDP and 41% of the world's population. Despite attempts to isolate Russia following its invasion of Ukraine, Putin may also claim that Moscow remains a key player in reshaping the world order, drawing strength from its BRICS alliances. These ties illustrate how countries outside the G7 are increasingly seeking alternatives to Western-dominated institutions like the International Monetary Fund (IMF) and the World Bank</p>

<h2><b>BRICS Is Here To Stay</b></h2>

<p>BRICS, the economic and political alliance comprising Brazil, Russia, India, China and South Africa, has gained a lot of prominence since its inception 15 years ago. Political analysts, economists and academics in the West had long predicted its demise. For instance, Eurasia Group, a political risk consultancy, questioned BRICS' relevance in 2013, saying, "BRICS is a term that has lost its relevance... It's a grouping that doesn't have a lot of coherence, and it's not clear what they are trying to achieve together."</p>

<p>But it has not just endured but is expanding, defying initial Western scepticism. Its latest members are Iran, Saudi Arabia, Egypt, Ethiopia and the United Arab Emirates. The bloc has attracted interest from nearly 40 other countries, including NATO member Turkey, which has now formally applied for its membership. Indonesia has been invited to join too, but it seems to be reluctant to become a part of the group, which, it views as anti-West.</p>

<h2><strong>India Should Carve Out Its Own Playing Field</strong></h2>

<p>Many years after the Indian National Congress was founded in 1885, it remained a petitioner to the British Raj. The assertion of its right to self-determination was weak until Mahatma Gandhi arrived on the national landscape.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Today, India should not be seen to be petitioning for a permanent seat on the United Nations Security Council (UNSC). The UN and UNSC, formed after the Second World War, are relics of the 20th century. The global landscape has dramatically changed since then, with emerging economies like India yearning to play a far more significant role in global affairs.</p>

<p>As the world's most populous country, the fifth-largest economy and a robust democracy to boot, Indians believe they should have a permanent voice in the decision-making processes that affect global peace and security. But the US, often in collaboration with its Western allies, has considerable sway within the UN system, which allows it to exert influence over its priorities and decision-making. The US is so powerful that it has managed to restrict BRICS's progress too. For example, many Chinese banks have ceased transactions with Russia to avoid US penalties, and BRICS's New Development Bank (NDB) has frozen its projects in Russia due to US sanctions.</p>

<p>The Indian government is not necessarily in favour of dismantling the existing US-led world order. It argues that the system has to be more inclusive; it wants what it believes are its rights in the existing system. It urges reforms in global financial institutions, such as the International Monetary Fund (IMF) and the World Bank, which further highlights its desire for a more equitable distribution of power in the global system.</p>

<h2><strong>West 'Protecting' The Existing Order</strong></h2>

<p>The US, France and the UK, all three permanent members of the UNSC, have often openly supported India's stance on the reform of international bodies. But it's unclear how genuine their intentions are. With the war raging in Ukraine, West Asia engulfed in violence and China's rise as their global challenger, the US and its Western allies appear to have become more assertive to protect their dominance of the world order.</p>

<p>For India, the time for petitioning or expecting favours from the West without a quid pro quo is over. India should use BRICS as a platform for amplifying its voice in global governance. It should value BRICS as a platform to advocate for a multipolar world. This is not to suggest that New Delhi should allow BRICS to become an overtly anti-West group. But it should use the platform to its advantage. Prime Minister Narendra Modi has often talked about India's ambition to be a leading voice of the Global South. Global bodies, such as BRICS and G20, provide a means to achieve such goals.</p>

<h2><strong>Why Does China Have The Upper Hand</strong></h2>

<p>India has benefited economically from the group, particularly through discounted Russian energy imports amid Western sanctions. Being a founding member of BRICS, India should realise that global fora such as BRICS and the G20 are credible products of a new, multipolar international order. If you do not get your rightful place in the existing order, you help create a new one, a more just order, without disengaging yourself with the existing one. India's increasing engagement in BRICS and the G20 demonstrates its willingness to work within the existing global order while advocating for change</p>

<p>India should go a step further and be an agent of change. It should not allow China to control the BRICS agenda. But sadly, even though India is a founding member, it does not wield as much direct influence as China, mostly due to the latter's economic and geopolitical clout. Russia, despite sanctions, remains a key BRICS player, especially because it sees the group as a way to counterbalance Western influence. But India's importance within the group is undisputed in some areas. For example, it brings credibility to the bloc because of its democratic credentials. It is an established global player in the IT sector and a huge market for investment. &nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>What The West Thinks Of BRICS</strong></h2>

<p>Many in the West now appear to take BRICS quite seriously as a counterbalance to the Western hegemony. But they suspect that the inherent division within the group could hamper its progress into a true alternative to the West-dominated world order. China and Russia are pushing BRICS to become a decidedly anti-West bloc. The recent inclusion of anti-West Iran, at their behest, is a case in point. Indeed, experts in the West believe that the alliance seeks alternative centres of power, frustrated with Western domination.</p>

<p>Under President Xi Jinping, China has been trying to create an alternative global financial and technological system to circumvent the US dollar dominance. Projects such as the Belt and Road Initiative (BRI), the creation of the New Development Bank (NDB) and efforts to internationalise the Yuan align with Chinese goals of establishing an alternative multipolar world order.&nbsp;</p>

<p>On the other hand, India, South Africa and Brazil do not fully share China's ambitions. They favour reforming the existing global system rather than dismantling it. They aim for a multipolar world where they can balance relations between the US and China, without fully aligning with either.</p>

<p>The question of whether BRICS can maintain its cohesion amid internal divisions looms large over the Kazan summit. I will be keenly observing how the summit navigates its members' competing national interests. But what one can say with confidence is that the group's relevance as a counterweight to Western power is indisputable.</p>

<p><em>(Syed Zubair Ahmed is a London-based senior Indian journalist with three decades of experience with the Western media)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/v6ngbbqo_bircs_625x300_11_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/people/noel-tata-takes-over-from-ratan-tata-know-the-tata-family-ancestry-and-history-6767399]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Noel Tata Takes Over From Ratan Tata. Know The Tata Ancestry And History]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/people/noel-tata-takes-over-from-ratan-tata-know-the-tata-family-ancestry-and-history-6767399]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 11 Oct 2024 17:24:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Founded in 1868, Tatas have become one of largest and most diverse global conglomerates. It is a name heard in almost every home in India and tens of millions overseas.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Tatas, a brand that has for more than 150 years instilled a feeling of trust and reassurance, has always seen a line of succession where the people at the helm have set the very highest standards and ethics in the world of business. Their personalities cannot be separated from what the brand has evolved into.</p>

<p>Founded in 1868, Tatas have become one of largest and most diverse global conglomerates. It is a name heard in almost every home in India and tens of millions overseas.</p>

<p>Ratan Tata, the kind and graceful gentleman-industrialist and philanthropist, who is credited with taking brand Tata to over 100 countries under his leadership, died at a hospital in Mumbai earlier this week. His stewardship of the Tata behemoth has left a void that few can fill, or not - only time will tell.</p>

<p>Ratan Tata is being succeeded by his half-brother Noel Tata. Ratan Tata's parents Naval Tata and Soonoo Commissariat got divorced when Ratan and his younger brother Jimmy were very young. Years later their father married Simone Dunoyer, and the two had a son Noel.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Ratan Tata and his half-brother Noel Tata with their father Naval Tata. Noel Tata is 20 years younger than Ratan Tata. (Photo: facebook/WelcometoJamshedpur)" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/tduanp48_ratan-tata-and-noel-tata-with-father-naval-tata-facebook_625x300_11_October_24.jpg" title="Ratan Tata and his half-brother Noel Tata with their father Naval Tata. Noel Tata is 20 years younger than Ratan Tata. (Photo: facebook/WelcometoJamshedpur)" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">Ratan Tata and his half-brother Noel Tata with their father Naval Tata. Noel Tata is 20 years younger than Ratan Tata. (Photo: facebook/WelcometoJamshedpur)</p>
</div>

<h2><strong>THE TATA FAMILY ANCESTRY</strong></h2>

<p>Ancestors of the Tata family migrated to India from Persia, now Iran, in the 8th century AD. They were part of a large group of Parsis (people from Persia), a Zoroastrian ethnic community, who fled persecution during the Islamic Conquest of Persia.</p>

<p>According to the Tata Central Archives, the Tatas settled in Navsari in Gujarat and lived there for 25 generations before business took them to Bombay - then the Bombay Presidency under the British Raj. At the time Bombay Province included the western two-thirds of Maharashtra, northwestern Karnataka, all of Gujarat, all of Sindh (now in Pakistan), and Aden (in present-day Yemen).</p>

<p>The journey of the Tata family's business began with Jamsetji Nusserwanji Tata, who stated a trading company in Bombay in 1868, which has today become the Tata Group. The Tatas have always believed in the concept of country and society - building and uplifting the people and the community over personal gains - and right from the very beginning, Jamsetji and his two sons - Sir Dorabji Tata and Sir Ratan Tata - left most of their estate and shares in the company to charitable trusts.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="The Tata family moved from Persia to India in the 8th Century and settled in Gujarat. Jamsetji Tata founded the business in 1868." id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/8j6niovs_ratan-tata-and-noel-tata-with-their-father-naval-tata_625x300_11_October_24.jpg" title="The Tata family moved from Persia to India in the 8th Century and settled in Gujarat. Jamsetji Tata founded the business in 1868." /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">The Tata family moved from Persia to India in the 8th Century and settled in Gujarat. Jamsetji Tata founded the business in 1868.</p>
</div>

<p>Today, there are 14 different trusts run by the Tatas which work in different sectors, each independent of the other in the nature and field of work they do. All of these however, come under an umbrella organisation called Tata Trust. <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ratan-tatas-journey-from-mumbai-boy-to-the-global-icon-a-timeline-of-his-life-6756202" target="_blank">Ratan Tata was the Chairman of the Tata Trusts</a> and Chairman Emeritus of the Tata Group. After his demise, his half-brother Noel Tata has become the Chairman of Tata Trusts while Natarajan Chandrasekaran is Chairman of the Tata Group, whose largest stakeholder is the Tata Trust.</p>

<h3><strong>NOEL TATA - NEW CHAIRMAN - TATA TRUSTS</strong></h3>

<p>Born in December 1957, Noel Tata is twenty years younger than his half-brother Ratan Tata. He is the son of Naval Tata and Simone Dunoyer, a French-Swiss Catholic and businesswoman from Switzerland.</p>

<p>Noel Tata holds a degree from Sussex University (UK) and has completed the International Executive Programme (IEP) at INSEAD.. He is an Indian-Irish businessman and has been appointed as the Chairman of the Tata Trust. He is married to Aloo Mistry, who is Cyrus Mistry's sister and Shapoorji Pallonji Mistry's granddaughter. They have three children - Neville, Maya, and Leah - all of whom are actively involved in the Tata conglomerate. Leah Tata is the Vice President at the Indian Hotels Company. While Maya Tata is associated with Tata Capital, Neville Tata is part of Trent and leadership team at Star Bazaar.</p>

<p>Noel Tata's most prominent role before this new appointment was as Managing Director of Tata International Ltd, the group's trading and distribution arm. Under his leadership from 2010 to 2021, the company grew from a turnover of $500 million to over $3 billion. As Managing Director of Trent Ltd, Tata's retail arm, he expanded its operations from a single store in 1998 to over 700 stores across various formats.</p>

<p>Till his appointment as Chairman - Tata Trusts, Noel Tata has been chairman of Trent, Tata International Limited, Voltas and Tata Investment Corporation. He is also vice chairman of Tata Steel and Titan Company Limited. He also serves as a trustee on the board of Sir Ratan Tata Trust and Sir Dorabji Tata Trust, which together comprise over 50 per cent of the ownership of Tata Sons.</p>

<p>Noel Tata has now become the sixth chairman of Sir Ratan Tata Trust and 11th chairman of Sir Dorabji Tata Trust.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/8u13mh4o_ratan-tata-noel-tata-ndtv_625x300_11_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Noel Tata takes over as Chairman of Tata Trusts from Ratan Tata. They were half-brothers.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nuclear-weapons-dont-bring-peace-warns-nobel-winning-atomic-bomb-survivor-6766606]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Nuclear Weapons Don't Bring Peace, Warns Nobel-Winning Atomic Bomb Survivor]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nuclear-weapons-dont-bring-peace-warns-nobel-winning-atomic-bomb-survivor-6766606]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 11 Oct 2024 15:37:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Nuclear weapons never bring peace, said the co-chair of Nihon Hidankyo, a group of atomic bomb survivors from Hiroshima and Nagasaki that won the Nobel Peace Prize on Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Nuclear weapons never bring peace, said the co-chair of Nihon Hidankyo, a group of atomic bomb survivors from Hiroshima and Nagasaki that won the Nobel Peace Prize on Friday.</p>

<p>The Norwegian Nobel Committee in Oslo awarded the group the Nobel prize on Friday "for its efforts to achieve a world free of nuclear weapons and for demonstrating through witness testimony that nuclear weapons must never be used again".</p>

<p>Toshiyuki Mimaki, co-chair of Nihon Hidankyo, broke down in tears at a press conference after the award was announced, saying "never did I dream this could happen".</p>

<p>"It has been said that because of nuclear weapons, the world maintains peace. But nuclear weapons can be used by terrorists," Mimaki told reporters.</p>

<p>"For example, if Russia uses them against Ukraine, Israel against Gaza, it won't end there. Politicians should know these things."</p>

<p>He added that members of the group -- which was founded in 1956 -- were the "average age of 85".</p>

<p>"I hope that the second-generation (of atomic bomb survivors) and the general public participate in peace activities, for peace without nuclear weapons," he said.</p>

<p>Mimaki also said the situation for children in Gaza is similar to what Japan faced at the end of World War II.</p>

<p>"In Gaza, bleeding children are being held (by their parents). It's like in Japan 80 years ago," he said.</p>

<p>"(Children in Japan/Hiroshima Nagasaki) lost their fathers in the war and mothers in the atomic bomb. They became orphans."</p>

<p>The 20th century brought Japan's brutal rampage across Asia and World War II, which ended in 1945 after the United States dropped atomic bombs on Hiroshima and Nagasaki.</p>

<p>The first nuclear bomb hit Hiroshima on August 6, 1945, and killed 140,000 people.</p>

<p>Three days later, the United States dropped an atomic bomb on Nagasaki, killing 74,000 people including many who survived the explosion but died later from radiation exposure.</p>

<p>Japan announced its surrender in World War II on August 15, 1945.</p>

<p>The mayor of Hiroshima, Kazumi Matsui, denounced nuclear weapons as an "absolute evil".</p>

<p>"Hibakusha (survivors) are fast ageing and there are fewer and fewer people able to testify to the meaninglessness of possessing atomic bombs and their absolute evil," he told reporters Friday.</p>

<p>"People in coming generations must know that what happened is not just a tragedy for Hiroshima and Nagasaki, but one that concerns all humanity that must not be repeated."</p>

<p>Prime Minister Shigeru Ishiba also hailed the awarding of the prize to Nihon Hidankyo.</p>

<p>"The fact that the Nobel Peace Prize was awarded to this organisation, which has spent many years working toward the abolition of nuclear weapons, is extremely meaningful," Ishiba told reporters.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/vcmjt3uo_nuclear-bomb-generic_625x300_11_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Nuclear weapons can be used by terrorists, Toshiyuki Mimaki said. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/belgian-military-evacuates-100-europeans-from-lebanon-6766498]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Belgian Military Evacuates 100 Europeans From Lebanon]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/belgian-military-evacuates-100-europeans-from-lebanon-6766498]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 11 Oct 2024 15:23:00 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[More than 100 Europeans were evacuated from Lebanon on a Belgian military plane on Thursday evening, most of them from Belgium, the Netherlands and France, the government in Brussels said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>More than 100 Europeans were evacuated from Lebanon on a Belgian military plane on Thursday evening, most of them from Belgium, the Netherlands and France, the government in Brussels said.</p>

<p>The aircraft, which landed at Melsbroek military base near the Belgian capital was carrying "58 Belgians and dependents, 41 Dutch citizens, 11 from France and one from Luxembourg, a foreign ministry spokesman told AFP on Friday.</p>

<p>Over the past week nearly 150 of the 1,800 or so Belgians living in Lebanon have benefited from assistance to return to Belgium, he said.</p>

<p>A first group left last week on two flights arranged by the Netherlands.</p>

<p>It included two Belgian journalists who were attacked and injured in Beirut while covering an Israeli bombardment of the city on the night of October 2 to 3.</p>

<p>"All the Belgians who wanted to leave have been able to do so. We are continuing to assess the situation," the spokesman said.</p>

<p>Israeli ground forces invaded Lebanon on September 30, saying they were aiming to stop cross-border fire from Hezbollah in support of Palestinian militant group Hamas, which attacked Israel on October 7, sparking a devastating ongoing war in Gaza.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/buucrch8_belgian-military-evacuates-100-europeans-from-lebanon_625x300_11_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A first group left last week on two flights arranged by the Netherlands.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/research-reveals-headspin-hole-a-hidden-risk-of-breakdancing-6766496]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Research Reveals "Headspin Hole": A Hidden Risk Of Breakdancing]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/research-reveals-headspin-hole-a-hidden-risk-of-breakdancing-6766496]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 11 Oct 2024 15:21:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A case report in the BMJ details the first known case of the “breakdance bulge” – a benign tumour on the scalp, caused by the repeated friction and pressure exerted during headspins.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Months after breakdance made its Olympic debut in Paris this year, researchers in Denmark have shed light on a lesser-known risk associated with one of the sport's most iconic moves: the headspin. Danish researchers recently published a case report in the <a href="https://casereports.bmj.com/content/17/9/e261854 ">BMJ</a>&nbsp;detailing the first known case of what they call “breakdance bulge” – a benign tumour on the scalp, caused by the repeated friction and pressure exerted during headspins. The patient, a man in his early 30s, was a breakdancer for nearly 20 years and developed a tumour more than an inch thick on the top of his head.</p>

<p>Though not life-threatening, the bump caused discomfort and made the patient self-conscious. He reported feeling uneasy in public without wearing a hat. He later underwent surgery to remove the growth. “It's great to be able to go out in public without a cap or hat,” he told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/10/10/health/headspin-hole-breakdancers/index.html">CNN</a>. “Many people tell me they don't notice the bump anymore and that my head looks completely normal.”</p>

<p>The continuous strain on the patient's scalp led to inflammation, bleeding and ultimately the formation of thickened skin and scar tissue.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to Dr Christian Baastrup Sondergaard, a neurosurgery specialist at Rigshospitalet in Copenhagen, “the condition results from repeated friction between the head and the floor, combined with the weight-bearing nature of headspins, accumulated over years of breakdancing.”</p>

<p>Known as “headspin hole” within the breaking community, the injury typically starts with hair loss but can progress into a noticeable bump.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Despite this being an acknowledged issue in the community, especially among long-time practitioners, the medical literature on headspin-related injuries remains scarce. Breakers online, including users of Reddit's boy forum, have shared their own experiences with bald spots and offered tips like wearing padded beanies or using gel pads under hats to reduce friction while performing.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/k5uursc8_breakdance_625x300_11_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["Breakdance bulge" is a benign tumour on the scalp, caused by repeated headspins (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/isro-and-nasa-discover-stunning-eruptions-from-a-black-hole-s-stellar-wreckage-6766303]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[ISRO, NASA Discover Stunning Eruptions From Black Hole's Stellar Wreckage]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/isro-and-nasa-discover-stunning-eruptions-from-a-black-hole-s-stellar-wreckage-6766303]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 11 Oct 2024 14:53:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Astronomers have observed a spectacular cosmic event where a massive black hole is disrupting two celestial objects, one of which was a star.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Astronomers have observed a spectacular cosmic event where a massive black hole is disrupting two celestial objects, one of which was a star. The discovery, made with NASA's observatories, including Chandra, NICER and Hubble, alongside India's AstroSat, provides insights into the behaviour of stellar debris around supermassive black holes.</p>

<p><strong>History</strong></p>

<p>Back in 2019, astronomers observed a star venturing too close to a supermassive black hole. The star was shredded by the intense gravitational forces, known as a tidal disruption event (TDE). The remnants of the star formed an accretion disk - a swirling graveyard of stellar material around the black hole. For several years, this disk remained relatively stable, but recently, astronomers noted something extraordinary. The disk expanded and began interacting with a second object, either a star or possibly a smaller black hole previously orbiting at a safe distance.</p>

<p>Now, this second object is colliding with the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.isro.gov.in/Indias_AstroSat_and_NASAs_Space_Observatories_Capture_Dramatic_Eruptions.html">stellar debris</a> disk every 48 hours, creating dramatic eruptions of X-rays each time it passes through. "Imagine a diver repeatedly entering a pool and causing a splash each time," said Matt Nicholl of Queen's University Belfast. "The star here is like the diver, while the disk acts as the pool, creating a cosmic 'splash' of gas and X-rays."</p>

<p>Astronomers have long documented TDEs, where a single star is destroyed by a black hole in one intense burst of energy. More recently, however, a puzzling phenomenon known as quasi-periodic eruptions (QPEs) has also been observed. These are bright X-ray flashes from the centres of galaxies that appear in regular intervals but were poorly understood - until now.</p>

<p>"There had been feverish speculation that these phenomena were connected, and now we've discovered the proof that they are," said Dheeraj Pasham from the Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT). It's like solving two cosmic mysteries at once," said Mr Pasham.</p>

<p>The event, now named AT2019qiz, was first identified in 2019 by the Zwicky Transient Facility at the Palomar Observatory. As the accretion disk expanded and began interacting with the second object, NASA's Chandra Observatory captured three separate sets of X-ray data over several hours, providing clear evidence of repeated eruptions.</p>

<p>NICER, another NASA instrument aboard the International Space Station, continued monitoring AT2019qiz and confirmed the X-ray eruptions occurred every 48 hours. Complementary observations from NASA's Swift observatory and India's AstroSat telescope further reinforced these findings. AstroSat's unique capability to observe both X-rays and ultraviolet (UV) light provided critical data that helped astronomers confirm the size of the accretion disk and the repetitive nature of these eruptions.</p>

<p>Gulab Dewangan, a co-author from the Inter-University Center for Astronomy &amp; Astrophysics (IUCAA) in Pune, talked about AstroSat's role. "India's AstroSat mission provides unique UV/X-ray capability for studying such events," he said, as per an ISRO report. "AstroSat's Soft X-ray Telescope and the Ultraviolet Imaging Telescope (UVIT) both detected the source AT2019qiz, but the eruptions were only seen in X-rays. Future sensitive simultaneous X-ray and UV observations of similar eruptions will enable a deeper investigation into their nature."</p>

<p>"This is a huge breakthrough in our understanding of the origin of these regular eruptions," said Andrew Mummery of Oxford University. "We now realise we need to wait a few years for the eruptions to 'turn on' after a star has been torn apart because it takes some time for the disk to spread out far enough to encounter another star."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/g2glk33o_isro-massive-black-hole_625x300_11_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Artist's impression of an orbiting star crashing through the accretion disk around a black hole.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nobel-peace-prize-2024-goes-to-japanese-organisation-nihon-hidankyo-6766192]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Nobel Peace Prize 2024 Goes To Japanese Organisation Nihon Hidankyo]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nobel-peace-prize-2024-goes-to-japanese-organisation-nihon-hidankyo-6766192]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 11 Oct 2024 14:36:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Nihon Hidankyo is a grassroots movement of atomic bomb survivors from Hiroshima and Nagasaki which strives to "achieve a world free of nuclear weapons".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Japanese organisation Nihon Hidankyo has been conferred with the Nobel Peace Prize 2024 for its efforts to achieve a world free of nuclear weapons.</p>

<p>The organisation is a grassroots movement of atomic bomb survivors from Hiroshima and Nagasaki, also known as Hibakusha, which strives to "achieve a world free of nuclear weapons and for demonstrating through witness testimony that nuclear weapons must never be used again".</p>

<p>While announcing this year's <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-how-is-the-nobel-peace-prize-decided-6764236">Peace Prize</a>, the Norwegian Nobel Committee honoured the&nbsp;atomic bomb survivors from Hiroshima and Nagasaki for cultivating hope for peace through&nbsp;"their costly experience". "They help us to describe the indescribable, to think the unthinkable, and to somehow grasp the incomprehensible pain and suffering caused by nuclear weapons," the committee stated on X.</p>

<p>The committee also highlighted that no nuclear weapon has been used in war in nearly 80 years. Acknowledging&nbsp;Nihon Hidankyo's efforts towards the establishment of a nuclear taboo, the Nobel Committee also aid that the same is under pressure.</p>

<p>By&nbsp;drawing on personal stories, creating educational campaigns based on their own experience, and issuing urgent warnings against the spread and use of nuclear weapons, the organisation has helped consolidate opposition to nuclear weapons, said a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.nobelprize.org/press-release-peace-2024/">Nobel Committee press release</a>.</p>

<p>"The nuclear powers are modernising and upgrading their arsenals, new countries appear to be preparing to acquire nuclear weapons, and threats are being made to use nuclear weapons in ongoing warfare. At this moment in human history, it is worth reminding ourselves what nuclear weapons are: the most destructive weapons the world has ever seen," a press release stated.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the 2024 <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nobel-prize-in-chemistry-goes-to-scientists-david-baker-demis-hassabis-john-jumper-6751373">Nobel Prize in Chemistry</a> went to scientists David Baker, Demis Hassabis and John Jumper, while the&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/2024-nobel-prize-in-medicine-goes-to-us-scientists-victor-ambros-and-gary-ruvkun-6735227">Nobel Prize in Physiology or Medicine</a> went to&nbsp;Victor Ambros and Gary Ruvkun for the discovery of microRNA and its role in gene regulation.</p>

<p>South Korean writer Han Kang, was awarded 2024 the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nobel-prize-in-literature-goes-to-south-korean-author-han-kang-6759706">Nobel Prize in Literature,</a> "for her intense poetic prose that confronts historical traumas and exposes the fragility of human life."</p>

<p>American John Hopfield and British-Canadian Geoffrey Hinton won the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-the-nobel-prize-for-physics-co-winner-fears-6744406">Nobel Prize in Physics</a> for pioneering work in the development of artificial intelligence. Shortly after the award's announcement,&nbsp;Hinton raised concerns about the technology he has created.</p>

<p>The prize comes with a gold medal, a diploma and a prize sum of $1 million (913,000 euro).</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/iaooaoeg_nobel-prize-replica-in-norway-afp_625x300_10_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Nobel Committee honoured atomic bomb survivors for cultivating hope for peace through their experience]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/tiktok-cuts-hundreds-of-jobs-in-shift-towards-ai-content-moderation-6766176]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[TikTok Cuts Hundreds Of Jobs In Shift Towards AI Content Moderation]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/tiktok-cuts-hundreds-of-jobs-in-shift-towards-ai-content-moderation-6766176]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 11 Oct 2024 14:33:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[TikTok confirmed the layoffs and said that several hundred employees were expected to be impacted globally as part of a wider plan to improve its moderation operations.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Social media platform TikTok is laying off hundreds of employees from its global workforce, including a large number of staff in Malaysia, the company said on Friday, as it shifts focus towards a greater use of AI in content moderation.</p>

<p>Two sources familiar with the matter earlier told Reuters that more than 700 jobs were slashed in Malaysia. TikTok, owned by China's ByteDance, later clarified that less than 500 employees in the country were affected.</p>

<p>The employees, most of whom were involved in the firm's content moderation operations, were informed of their dismissal by email late Wednesday, the sources said, requesting anonymity as they were not authorized to speak to media.</p>

<p>In response to Reuters' queries, TikTok confirmed the layoffs and said that several hundred employees were expected to be impacted globally as part of a wider plan to improve its moderation operations.</p>

<p>TikTok employs a mix of automated detection and human moderators to review content posted on the site.</p>

<p>ByteDance has over 110,000 employees in more than 200 cities globally, according to the company website.</p>

<p>The technology firm is also planning more retrenchments next month as it looks to consolidate some of its regional operations, one of the sources said.</p>

<p>"We're making these changes as part of our ongoing efforts to further strengthen our global operating model for content moderation," a TikTok spokesperson said in a statement.</p>

<p>The company expects to invest $2 billion globally in trust and safety this year and will continue to improve efficiency, with 80% of guidelines-violating content now removed by automated technologies, the spokesperson said.</p>

<p>The layoffs were first reported by business portal The Malaysian Reserve on Thursday.</p>

<p>The job cuts occur as global technology firms face greater regulatory pressure in Malaysia, where the government has asked social media operators to apply for an operating licence by January as part of an effort to combat cyber offences.</p>

<p>Malaysia reported a sharp increase in harmful social media content earlier this year and urged firms, including TikTok, to step up monitoring on their platforms.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/8i3cjd98_tik-tok_625x300_11_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/voice-of-japans-beloved-robot-cat-doraemon-dies-at-90-6765892]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Voice Of Japan's Beloved Robot Cat 'Doraemon' Dies At 90]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/voice-of-japans-beloved-robot-cat-doraemon-dies-at-90-6765892]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 11 Oct 2024 13:58:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Nobuyo Oyama, a Japenese actor who was the voice of Doraemon, died on September 29 due to old age, her talent agency told news agency AFP.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Japanese actor who was the voice of "Doraemon", a cartoon cat robot beloved by children in Japan and other countries has died, her agency said Friday. Nobuyo Oyama was 90.</p>

<p>For a quarter of a century until 2005, Oyama lent her endearingly hoarse voice to the titular blue feline from the 22nd century with his "magic pocket" and its supply of fantastical gadgets, including a door that lets you travel anywhere.</p>

<p>She "passed away on September 29 due to old age", her talent agency told AFP. Her funeral was attended by close relatives, it said.</p>

<p>"Doraemon" is still on air as one of the longest-running Japanese anime series, popular across Asia and farther afield.</p>

<p>While Oyama's successor has played the role for nearly two decades, her voice remains the definitive sound of the robot for many who grew up hearing it.</p>

<p>In "Doraemon", the cuddly robot cat with its huge smile travels back in time to help a lazy schoolboy called Nobita overcome the trials of everyday life.</p>

<p>Created by the artist Fujiko F. Fujio, the character first appeared in manga strips in 1969, making the transition to the small and big screen over the following decades.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/sanatt2g_nobuyo-oyama-doraemon_625x300_11_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-courageous-to-step-out-of-us-elections-2024-kamala-harris-6765719]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Joe Biden "Courageous" To Step Out Of US Elections 2024: Kamala Harris]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-courageous-to-step-out-of-us-elections-2024-kamala-harris-6765719]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 11 Oct 2024 13:24:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US Vice President Kamala Harris said that Joe Biden's decision to drop out of the 2024 election race this summer was "one of the most courageous" any president has made.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US Vice President Kamala Harris said on Thursday that Joe Biden's decision to drop out of the 2024 election race this summer was "one of the most courageous" any president has made.</p>

<p>"President Biden made a decision that I think history will show was probably one of the most courageous that a president could make, which is he decided to put country above his personal interest," Harris said during the Las Vegas event sponsored by Univision, a Spanish-language television network, according to press pool reporters. Her remarks were dubbed into Spanish on television.</p>

<p>"I believe that the stakes right now are extraordinarily high, and potentially, some might say, historians have said unprecedented."</p>

<p>The Democratic presidential nominee made the remarks when pressed by a voter who said he was leaning towards Trump and expressed concern about how Biden exited the race. The voter said he wanted clarity on why Harris became the nominee without going through a competitive primary.</p>

<p>Biden ended his re-election bid on July 21, after facing weeks of pressure from prominent Democratic elected officials and donors concerned about his age and fitness. Biden immediately endorsed Harris, who locked down the support of enough Democratic delegates to secure the party's nomination.</p>

<p>Harris said in an interview on ABC News' "The View" on Tuesday that there is "not a thing" she would have done differently from Biden as president. The remark was seized upon by Donald Trump's campaign, which wants voters to see the Republican ex-president as the 2024 candidate of change.</p>

<p>Harris said Biden, who is not making regular campaign appearances on her behalf, has been a key partner and supporter and that his decision to leave the race marked a sharp contrast with Trump, who never conceded his 2020 election loss.</p>

<p>"We are literally having a choice as the American people about choosing a path either that is about rule of law, democracy or something that is about admiring dictators," she said, according to the pool reporters.</p>

<p>The Trump campaign did not immediately respond to a request for comment.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/mqfp33jg_trump-harris-biden-split_625x300_11_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/international-day-of-girl-child-2024-one-in-eight-girls-experiences-sexual-assault-before-turning-18-says-unicef-6765714]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[One In Eight Girls Suffers Sexual Assault Before Turning 18, Says UNICEF]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/international-day-of-girl-child-2024-one-in-eight-girls-experiences-sexual-assault-before-turning-18-says-unicef-6765714]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 11 Oct 2024 13:21:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[International Day Of Girl Child 2024: The report highlights that when "non-contact" forms of abuse - such as online harassment or verbal assault - are factored in, the number rises to 650 million, or 1 in 5.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A new UNICEF report reveals that over 370 million women and girls - or 1 in 8 globally - have experienced sexual violence, including rape and assault, before the age of 18. The figures were released ahead of the International Day of the Girl Child on October 11, marking the first-ever comprehensive global and regional data on childhood sexual violence.</p>

<p>The<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.unicef.org/press-releases/over-370-million-girls-and-women-globally-subjected-rape-or-sexual-assault-children"> report highlights </a>that when "non-contact" forms of abuse - such as online harassment or verbal assault - are factored in, the number rises to 650 million, or 1 in 5. The staggering statistics underscore the critical need for urgent and comprehensive strategies to prevent and address the widespread violation of children's rights.</p>

<p>"Sexual violence against children is a stain on our moral conscience," stated UNICEF Executive Director Catherine Russell. "It inflicts deep and lasting trauma, often by someone the child knows and trusts, in places where they should feel safe."</p>

<p>The pervasive nature of childhood sexual violence spans across cultural, geographical, and economic divides. The report highlights Sub-Saharan Africa as the region with the highest number of victims, accounting for 79 million affected women and girls. Other affected regions include Eastern and South-Eastern Asia (75 million), Central and Southern Asia (73 million), Europe and Northern America (68 million), and Latin America and the Caribbean (45 million).</p>

<p>In regions marred by conflict and political instability, the situation is even more dire. Girls in fragile settings, such as refugee camps or areas under UN peacekeeping missions, face a higher risk, with sexual violence affecting more than 1 in 4 girls. "We are witnessing horrific sexual violence in conflict zones, where rape and gender-based violence are often used as weapons of war," Russell added.</p>

<p>The report points to a disturbing trend: most sexual violence against children occurs during adolescence, with a significant spike between ages 14 and 17. Victims are more likely to experience repeated abuse, emphasizing the need for targeted interventions to break the cycle of trauma.</p>

<p>The long-term impacts of sexual violence can be devastating. Survivors often struggle with mental health issues, such as anxiety and depression, and are at increased risk of sexually transmitted infections, substance abuse, and difficulty forming healthy relationships. The trauma is further compounded when survivors delay disclosing their abuse, or never report it at all.</p>

<p>While girls and women make up the majority of victims, the report also notes that boys are similarly affected. Between 240 and 310 million boys and men have experienced sexual violence during childhood, with the number rising to 530 million when non-contact forms of abuse are included.</p>

<p>As the Global Ministerial Conference on Violence Against Children approaches next month, UNICEF calls for urgent international action. Key recommendations include changing harmful social norms, equipping children with information to report abuse, ensuring victims have access to support services, and strengthening legal frameworks to protect children.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/qc1obs6_unicef-report-on-girl-child-sexual-violence_625x300_11_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[International Day Of Girl 2024: Sub-Saharan Africa reports the highest number of sexual violence victims.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-hasnt-decided-to-build-a-nuclear-weapon-believes-us-6765492]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iran Hasn't Decided To Build A Nuclear Weapon, Believes US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-hasnt-decided-to-build-a-nuclear-weapon-believes-us-6765492]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 11 Oct 2024 12:49:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US still believes that Iran has not decided to build a nuclear weapon despite Tehran's recent strategic setbacks, including Israel's killing of Hezbollah leaders and two largely unsuccessful attempts to attack Israel, two US officials told Reuters.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United States still believes that Iran has not decided to build a nuclear weapon despite Tehran's recent strategic setbacks, including Israel's killing of Hezbollah leaders and two largely unsuccessful attempts to attack Israel, two US officials told Reuters.</p>

<p>The comments from a senior Biden administration official and a spokesperson for the Office of the Director of National Intelligence (ODNI) added to public remarks earlier this week by CIA Director William Burns, who said the United States had not seen any evidence Iran's leader had reversed his 2003 decision to suspend the weaponization program.</p>

<p>"We assess that the Supreme Leader has not made a decision to resume the nuclear weapons program that Iran suspended in 2003," said the ODNI spokesperson, referring to Iran's leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei.</p>

<p>The intelligence assessment could help explain US opposition to any Israeli strike on Iran's nuclear program in retaliation for a ballistic missile attack that Tehran carried out last week.</p>

<p>President Joe Biden said after that attack he would not support an Israeli strike on Iranian nuclear sites, but did not explain why he had reached that conclusion. His remarks drew fierce criticism from Republicans, including former President Donald Trump.</p>

<p>US officials have long acknowledged that an attempt to destroy Iran's nuclear weapons program might only delay the country's efforts to develop a nuclear bomb and could even strengthen Tehran's resolve to do so.</p>

<p>"We're all watching this space very carefully," the Biden administration official said.</p>

<p>Iran's mission to the United Nations in New York did not immediately respond to a request for comment but Tehran has repeatedly denied ever having had a nuclear weapons program.</p>

<p><strong>Key Iran ally weakened</strong></p>

<p>In the past weeks, Israel's military has inflicted heavy losses on Hezbollah, the most powerful member of the Iran-backed network known as the Axis of Resistance. The group's setbacks have included the killing of its leader Hassan Nasrallah in an Israeli airstrike last month.</p>

<p>The weakening of a key Iranian ally has prompted some experts to speculate that Tehran may restart its efforts to acquire a nuclear bomb to protect itself.</p>

<p>Beth Sanner, a former US deputy director of national intelligence, said the risk of Khamenei reversing his 2003 religious dictum against nuclear weapons is "higher now than it has been" and that if Israel were to strike nuclear facilities Tehran would likely move ahead with building a nuclear weapon.</p>

<p>That would still take time, however.</p>

<p>"They can't get a weapon in a day. It will take months and months and months," said Sanner, now a fellow with the German Marshall Fund.</p>

<p>Iran is now enriching uranium to up to 60% fissile purity, close to the 90% of weapons grade, at two sites, and in theory it has enough material enriched to that level, if enriched further, for almost four bombs, according to a yardstick of the International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA), the UN watchdog.</p>

<p>The expansion in Iran's enrichment program has reduced the so-called breakout time it would need to produce enough weapons-grade uranium for a nuclear bomb to "a week or a little more," according to Burns, from more than a year under a 2015 accord that Trump pulled out of when president.Actually making a bomb with that material would take longer. How long is less clear and the subject of debate.</p>

<p><strong>Possible Israeli attack</strong></p>

<p>Israel has not yet disclosed what it will target in retaliation for Iran's attack last week with more than 180 ballistic missiles, which largely failed thanks to interceptions by Israeli air defenses as well as by the US military.</p>

<p>The United States has been privately urging Israel to calibrate its response to avoid triggering a broader war in the Middle East, officials say, with Biden publicly voicing his opposition to a nuclear attack and concerns about a strike on Iran's energy infrastructure.</p>

<p>Israel, however, views Iran's nuclear program as an existential threat.</p>

<p>The conflicts in the Middle East between Israel and Iran and Iran-backed groups in Lebanon, Gaza and Yemen have become campaign issues ahead of the Nov. 5 presidential election, with Trump and his Democratic rival, Vice President Kamala Harris, positioning themselves as pro-Israel.</p>

<p>Speaking at a campaign event last week, Trump mocked Biden for opposing an attack on Iran's nuclear sites, saying: "That's the thing you wanna hit, right?"</p>

<p>Avi Melamed, a former Israeli intelligence officer and government official, said Iran still had space to compensate for setbacks dealt to its proxies and missile force without having to resort to developing a nuclear warhead.</p>

<p>"The Iranians have to recalculate what's next. I don't think at this point they will rush to either develop or boost the (nuclear) program toward military capacity," he said.</p>

<p>"They will look around to find what maneuvering space they can move around in."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/8s66n2ug_iran_625x300_11_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/boat-carrying-turkish-evacuees-from-lebanon-lands-in-turkey-6765377]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Boat Carrying Turkish Evacuees From Lebanon Lands In Turkey]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/boat-carrying-turkish-evacuees-from-lebanon-lands-in-turkey-6765377]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 11 Oct 2024 12:24:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The first of two naval ships evacuating Turkish citizens and their families from war-torn Lebanon landed at a port in southern Turkey late on Thursday, an AFP correspondent at the scene said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The first of two naval ships evacuating Turkish citizens and their families from war-torn Lebanon landed at a port in southern Turkey late on Thursday, an AFP correspondent at the scene said.</p>

<p>The TCG Bayraktar, which set sail from Beirut around 8:00 am (0500 GMT), pulled into the port of Mersin around 9:00 pm carrying the first batch of 966 people.</p>

<p>As it pulled into the port, a large group of journalists were waiting on the quayside.</p>

<p>A second boat carrying a similar number of passengers was set to dock around midnight, officials said.</p>

<p>Turkish officials said around 2,000 people had signed up to leave Lebanon on navy ships in the first such evacuation by sea.</p>

<p>Turkey, which is estimated to have 14,000 citizens registered with its consulate in Lebanon, announced the move on Tuesday because of the deteriorating security situation in the country.</p>

<p>Speaking to AFP in Beirut ahead of the boats' departure on Wednesday, Turkish ambassador in Lebanon Ali Baris Ulusoy told AFP the evacuation was a first and came after "a growing number of requests from our Turkish nationals living in Lebanon to be evacuated".</p>

<p>He said they were allowing close relatives "who are not necessarily Turkish nationals, like spouses, children or parents" to travel too.</p>

<p>Israel and Lebanese militant group Hezbollah have exchanged near-daily fire on the country's southern border since the start of the Gaza war a year ago.</p>

<p>But Israel has intensified its strikes against Hezbollah since September 23, killing more than 1,200 people in Lebanon and displacing more than a million from their homes.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/st6dq6r_boat-carrying-turkish-evacuees-from-lebanon_625x300_11_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Around 2,000 people had signed up to leave Lebanon on navy ships in the first such evacuation by sea.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-modi-meets-antony-blinken-on-sidelines-of-asean-summit-6764846]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[PM Modi Meets Antony Blinken On Sidelines Of ASEAN Summit]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-modi-meets-antony-blinken-on-sidelines-of-asean-summit-6764846]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 11 Oct 2024 12:19:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Narendra Modi on Friday met with US Secretary of State Antony Blinken on the sidelines of the ASEAN-India Summit in Laos.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi on Friday met with US Secretary of State Antony Blinken on the sidelines of the ASEAN-India Summit in Laos.</p>

<p>During the meeting, PM Modi extended his condolences on the loss of lives due to Hurricane Milton in the US and also discussed strengthening bilateral ties and cooperation in regional matters.</p>

<p>The meeting highlighted the strong diplomatic relationship between India and the US, reaffirming their commitment to working together on global and regional challenges.</p>

<p>Earlier on Thursday, PM Modi held bilateral meetings with his counterparts from Japan and New Zealand on the sidelines of the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/pm-modi-calls-for-peace-in-eurasia-west-asia-this-is-not-the-era-of-war-6764956">ASEAN-India Summit</a> in Laos.</p>

<p>PM Modi congratulated the newly-appointed Japanese Prime Minister Shigeru Ishiba on his new responsibility and wished him success in leading Japan to greater heights. He also underscored that India will continue to accord the highest priority to its ties with Japan, a trusted friend and strategic partner.</p>

<p>The Prime Minister also met New Zealand PM Christopher Luxon which was the first meeting between the two leaders. PM Modi welcomed New Zealand's decision to join the International Solar Alliance and also extended an invitation to Luxon to visit India on mutually convenient dates, which he accepted.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi on Thursday during the ASEAN summit, said that the 21st century is the "Asian century" of India and the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) countries.</p>

<p>"I believe that the 21st century is the Asian century of India and ASEAN countries. Today, when there is a situation of conflict and tension in many parts of the world, the friendship, coordination, dialogue and cooperation between India and ASEAN remains very important," he remarked.</p>

<p>During the Summit, Prime Minister Modi announced a 10-point plan to strengthen connectivity and resilience based on Laos' theme as the 2024 ASEAN Chair and in celebration of 10 years of the 'Act East' policy.</p>

<p>The 10-point plan to strengthen the ASEAN-India Comprehensive Partnership includes enhancing physical, digital, cultural and spiritual connectivity towards achieving cyber, disaster, supply chain, health and climate resilience.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/krvbb7dg_pm-modiantony-blinken-twitter-ani_625x300_11_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[PM Modi and US Secretary of State Antony Blinken met on the sidelines of the East Asia Summit.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/pm-modi-calls-for-peace-in-eurasia-west-asia-this-is-not-the-era-of-war-6764956]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Approach Should Be Of Development, Not Expansion": PM At East Asia Summit]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/pm-modi-calls-for-peace-in-eurasia-west-asia-this-is-not-the-era-of-war-6764956]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 11 Oct 2024 11:59:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Noting that conflicts in different parts of the world are having the most negative impact on the countries of the Global South, Prime Minister Narendra Modi on Friday called for the restoration of peace and stability in Eurasia and West Asia.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Noting that conflicts in different parts of the world are having the most negative impact on the countries of the Global South, Prime Minister Narendra Modi on Friday called for the restoration of peace and stability in Eurasia and West Asia.</p>

<p>Addressing the 19th East Asia Summit, PM Modi also asserted that solutions to problems cannot come from the battlefield.</p>

<p>He also said a free, open, inclusive, prosperous and rule-based Indo-Pacific is important for the peace and progress of the entire region.</p>

<p>Peace, security and stability of the South China Sea is in the interest of the entire Indo-Pacific region, he said.</p>

<p>“We believe that maritime activities should be conducted under the UN Convention on the Law of the Seas (UNCLOS). It is necessary to ensure freedom of navigation and air space. A strong and effective Code of Conduct should be created. And it should not curb the foreign policy of regional countries,” PM Modi said.</p>

<p>“Our approach should be one of developmentalism and not expansionism,” he said.</p>

<p>Noting that the conflicts going on in different parts of the world are having the most negative impact on the countries of the Global South, PM Modi said everyone wants whether it is Eurasia or West Asia, peace and stability should be restored as soon as possible.</p>

<p>“I come from the land of Buddha, and I have repeatedly said that this is not the era of war. Solutions to problems cannot come from the battlefield,” he said.</p>

<p>“It is necessary to respect sovereignty, territorial integrity and international laws. Keeping a humanitarian approach, dialogue and diplomacy will have to be given priority,” the prime minister asserted.</p>

<p>Fulfilling the responsibility of ‘Vishwabandhu', India will continue to contribute in every possible way in this direction, he added.</p>

<p>His remarks came amidst conflicts between Ukraine and Russia in Eurasia and the Israel-Hamas war in West Asia.</p>

<p>“Terrorism is also a serious challenge to global peace and security. To face it, forces believing in humanity will have to work together,” PM Modi said.</p>

<p>At the start of his address, he also expressed his deepest condolences to the people affected by “Typhoon Yagi”, a destructive tropical cyclone which impacted Southeast Asia and South China in September this year.</p>

<p>“In this difficult time, we have provided humanitarian assistance through Operation Sadbhav,” PM Modi said.</p>

<p>PM Modi also said India has always supported ASEAN Unity and Centrality and pointed out that ASEAN is also at the centre of India's Indo-Pacific vision and Quad cooperation.</p>

<p>“There are deep similarities between India's ‘Indo-Pacific Oceans' Initiative' and ‘ASEAN Outlook on Indo-Pacific',” he said.</p>

<p>“We support the ASEAN approach to the situation in Myanmar. We also support the Five-point Consensus. At the same time, we believe that it is important to maintain humanitarian assistance,” PM Modi said.</p>

<p>He called for appropriate steps for the restoration of democracy there.</p>

<p>“We believe that, for this, Myanmar should be engaged, not isolated,” he said.</p>

<p>As a neighbouring country, India will continue to fulfil its responsibility, he added.</p>

<p>The East Asia Summit is an important pillar of India's Act East Policy, he said.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/jvlt6smo_pm-modi-19th-east-asia-summit-_625x300_11_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[PM Modi said a strong and effective Code of Conduct should be created.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/man-clinging-to-cooler-48-km-off-florida-coast-after-hurricane-milton-rescued-6764921]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Nightmare Scenario": Man Rescued 48 Km Offshore After Hurricane Milton]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/man-clinging-to-cooler-48-km-off-florida-coast-after-hurricane-milton-rescued-6764921]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 11 Oct 2024 11:44:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A man, clinging to a cooler in the aftermath of Hurricane Milton, was saved by a Coast Guard helicopter crew on October 10, around 48 kilometres off Longboat Key.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A man, clinging to a cooler in the aftermath of Hurricane Milton, was saved by a Coast Guard helicopter crew on October 10, around 48 kilometres off Longboat Key. The <a href="https://www.news.uscg.mil/Press-Releases/Article/3933279/coast-guard-rescues-man-off-longboat-key-following-hurricane-milton/">rescue operation</a> took place around 1:30 pm and the man was airlifted to Tampa General Hospital for medical evaluation. He was found wearing a life jacket, which played a big role in his survival during the storm.</p>

<p>The Coast Guard's Air Station Miami launched the search mission on Thursday morning after receiving reports of a missing captain. The aircrew, alongside support from Air Station Clearwater, was positioned at the Aviation Training Center Mobile for storm avoidance during Hurricane Milton.</p>

<p>The captain, aboard the fishing vessel Capt. Dave initially contacted Coast Guard Sector St. Petersburg on the afternoon of October 7. He reported that he and a crew member were stranded about 32 kilometres&nbsp;off John's Pass. The Coast Guard promptly dispatched a rescue boat and a helicopter, bringing the pair to safety and then to Air Station Clearwater without injury. Capt. Dave was left adrift while salvage arrangements were made.</p>

<p>On October 9, the vessel's owner notified the Coast Guard that the captain went out to the boat for repairs in the early hours and had not been heard since. However, after a connection was re-established with the captain, he reported that his vessel's rudder had become fouled with a line, rendering the boat inoperable.</p>

<p>At the time, sea conditions were challenging, with 6 to 8-foot waves and winds of about 48 kmph. However, the weather rapidly worsened as Hurricane Milton approached. The Coast Guard instructed the captain to wear a life jacket and remain near the vessel's emergency position indicating a radio beacon. Unfortunately, communication was lost on the evening of October 9.</p>

<p>“This man survived in a nightmare scenario for even the most experienced mariner,” said Lt. Cmdr. Dana Grady, chief of the command centre at Sector St. Petersburg. “To understand the severity of the hurricane conditions, we estimate he experienced approximately 75-90 mph winds, 20-25 foot seas, for an extended period of time to include overnight. He survived because of a life jacket, his emergency position indicating locator beacon, and a cooler.”</p>

<p>Hurricane Milton made landfall on October 9 near Siesta Key, a barrier island located just south of Sarasota on Florida's central west coast. Initially, the storm struck as a formidable Category 3 hurricane, with sustained winds reaching approximately 193 kmph. However, as it moved inland, it weakened to a Category 2 storm.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/kp0do9qo_hurricane-milton_625x300_10_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hurricane Milton made landfall on October 9 near Siesta Key.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-unveils-robotaxi-promises-to-make-it-available-before-2027-6765150]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk Unveils Robotaxi, Promises To Make It Available Before 2027]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-unveils-robotaxi-promises-to-make-it-available-before-2027-6765150]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 11 Oct 2024 11:37:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Elon Musk on Thursday unveiled what he said was a robotaxi capable of self-driving, predicting it would be available by 2027 -- about a decade after he first promised an autonomous vehicle.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Elon Musk on Thursday unveiled what he said was a robotaxi capable of self-driving, predicting it would be available by 2027 -- about a decade after he first promised an autonomous vehicle.</p>

<p>The Tesla CEO said the fully electric car -- which has no steering wheel or pedals -- would be priced under $30,000, would be charged wirelessly with inductive technology and would be "10 to 20 times safer" than human-driven cars.</p>

<p>"You can think of the car in an autonomous world as being like just a little lounge," he told a crowd at the Warner Brothers Studio lot near Los Angeles.</p>

<p>"You're just sitting in a comfortable little lounge, and you can do whatever you want while you're in this comfortable little lounge, and when you get out, you will be at your destination."</p>

<p>Few details were given about the vehicle, whose gullwing doors are reminiscent of the Delorean made famous by the "Back to the Future" films, but Musk said Tesla already had 50 of them.</p>

<p>He said the company was expecting to begin "fully autonomous, unsupervised" driving in Texas and California next year with existing models, and then move on to production of what he called the "cybercab".</p>

<p>"I tend to be a little optimistic with time frames, but in 2026, so yeah, before 2027. Let me put it that way."</p>

<p><strong>Robovan and Optimus robot</strong></p>

<p>The evening, which started almost an hour late, was heavy on sunny visions of the future, but light on specifics.</p>

<p>But it also showcased a mass passenger vehicle that Musk called "The Robovan."</p>

<p>The vehicle, which looks like an enormous moving toaster, has no steering wheel, pedals or driver.</p>

<p>It can seat up to 20 people or could be converted to carry goods, Musk said.</p>

<p>He gave no details about production or any timeline.</p>

<p>Musk also brought out dancing humanoid robots called Optimus that he said would one day be able to do menial tasks, as well as offer friendship.</p>

<p>"I think this will be the biggest product ever of any kind," he said, adding that he expected the robot to retail for $20,000 to $30,000.</p>

<p>He gave no timeline on this, either, and it was not clear from the livestream what the robot's capabilities were, although it was shown walking amongst audience members, handing out plaques and serving drinks.</p>

<p><strong>Trump</strong></p>

<p>Musk's bullish pronouncements and dedicated fanbase have helped build Tesla into one of the world's most valuable companies.</p>

<p>While he was once the darling of the political left for his environmentalist moves towards electrifying transport, he has become increasingly controversial.</p>

<p>Since buying Twitter -- which he renamed X -- the free speech absolutist cut staffing on the platform, leading many long-time users and advertisers to abandon the forum.</p>

<p>And he's currently spending time and money promoting Republican Donald Trump, echoing the billionaire presidential candidate's dire warnings about migrants and a crumbling America, including during an exuberant appearance at a weekend Trump rally that was widely mocked.</p>

<p>Thursday night's robotaxi reveal was a long time coming.</p>

<p>Musk first said in 2016 a fully automated car was two years away; a year later he was touting a vehicle by 2019 so clever that customers would be able to sleep while it drove them around.</p>

<p>But as many automakers have found, self-driving is tricky.</p>

<p>While lots of cars nowadays have limited automation, theoretically allowing the driver to cede some of the boring bits of driving to an onboard computer, the person behind the wheel still has to pay attention and jump in if the car does something unpredictable.</p>

<p>That's because computers, unlike people, are not very good at reacting to unexpected events or situations they have never seen before.</p>

<p>Other companies, such as Google's Waymo and General Motors' Cruise, have operated heavily regulated and limited pilot robotaxi programs for a few years already.</p>

<p>Anything Tesla tries to put on the road will face the same kind of regulatory hurdles, as well as skepticism from the general public, many of whom have never seen a car without a driver.</p>

<p>Immediate reaction to the reveals was mixed.</p>

<p>"Delusional nonsense from a liar who has been promising a robotaxi every year for a decade," wrote user @goodandnormal on X.</p>

<p>Others on the platform were more enthusiastic, with some predicting that Tesla's share price will soar when US markets open.</p>

<p>"Tesla self-driving 'Robovan.' The future looks promising," wrote @CollinsEbot1.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/h8qpa7l_elon-musk-robotaxi_625x300_11_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Robotaxi, which has no steering wheel or pedals, would be priced under $30,000,]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/yes-she-can-barack-obama-electrifies-pennsylvania-rally-for-kamala-harris-6764806]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Yes She Can": Barack Obama Electrifies Pennsylvania Rally For Kamala Harris]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/yes-she-can-barack-obama-electrifies-pennsylvania-rally-for-kamala-harris-6764806]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 11 Oct 2024 10:38:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Barack Obama cast the Republican nominee Donald Trump as a selfish businessman concerned only with his own accumulation of wealth and power, in contrast with Kamala Harris.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Before Barack Obama's ascent to the White House, Diana Vahabzadeh was a registered Independent who had never voted for a Democrat in her life.</p>

<p>But the first Black president of the United States won the now 63-year-old over during his initial 2008 campaign and she's leaned left ever since.</p>

<p>He was back on the trail Thursday and so was she, along with thousands of people at a rally in Pittsburgh backing Kamala Harris, which kicks off Obama's stumping blitz across swing states vital to winning November's neck-and-neck election.</p>

<p>Vahabzadeh has "loved him for years," she said: "This is a great opportunity to be able to see him and also support the ticket."</p>

<p>A playlist of pop classics and TikTok hits spun in the university gym where the marquee speaker's "Yes We Can" slogan from 2008 was repurposed as "Yes She Can," a message emblazoned on both homemade posters and an electric scoreboard in the field house.</p>

<p>"We love you Barack!" shouted one rallygoer as he appeared, soundtracked by U2's "City of Blinding Lights," a frequent track during his own presidential bids.</p>

<p>Flashing his megawatt smile, Obama cast the Republican nominee <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/has-donald-trump-ever-changed-a-diaper-barack-obama-at-kamala-harris-rally-6764162">Donald Trump as a selfish businessman</a> concerned only with his own accumulation of wealth and power, in contrast with Harris, who he said "is as prepared for the job as any nominee for president as ever been."</p>

<p>"That's who Kamala is."</p>

<p>In closing, he tapped the crowd-rousing vigor that propelled him to the top of the Democratic party decades ago, his voice rapidly amplifying as he dropped his demands: "Do not just sit back and hope for the best -- get off your couch and vote."</p>

<p>"Put down your phone, and vote!" he shouted to cheers. "Vote for Kamala Harris as the next president of the United States."</p>

<p><strong>'Powerful'</strong></p>

<p>The energy hit for Tia Douglas, a 20-year-old college student who was on the cusp of primary-school age when Obama first won office.</p>

<p>"It felt so powerful to be able to hear him speak," she told AFP with bright eyes and a wide smile following the rally.</p>

<p>"Listening to him made me even more excited to get out there in the next 26 days."</p>

<p>The Harris campaign is hoping the 63-year-old former president -- who led the US from 2009 to 2017 -- can imbue their White House bid with star power and help fend off Trump's potential return.</p>

<p>Obama walked out to ardent applause at the Pittsburgh field house, which was packed with a crowd diverse in background and age.</p>

<p>"I love seeing and hearing his articulate self," said Valerie Brown, a 66-year-old retired public schoolteacher.</p>

<p>She told AFP she hopes his words "might stimulate some others who are reluctant" to vote Harris.</p>

<p>Vice President Harris enjoyed a honeymoon surge in the polls when she replaced President Joe Biden as the Democratic nominee over the summer, capturing the social media zeitgeist and raking in a reported billion dollars in fundraising.</p>

<p>But whether she ultimately can bat back Republican Trump, who is seeking a second term and still maintains a fervent base of support, remains anyone's guess, with key battleground states like Pennsylvania still vacillating between the candidates in the polls.</p>

<p>"I get it, why people are looking to shake things up," Obama said onstage, before drawing chuckles after riffing on his own former platform: "I mean, I'm the hopey-changey guy."</p>

<p>"I understand people feeling frustrated and people feeling we can do better," he continued. "What I cannot understand is why anybody would think that Donald Trump will shake things up in a way that is good for you, Pennsylvania."</p>

<p><strong>Also Read:&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/has-donald-trump-ever-changed-a-diaper-barack-obama-at-kamala-harris-rally-6764162">"Has Donald Trump Ever Changed A Diaper": Barack Obama At Kamala Harris Rally</a></p>

<p><strong>'Lifetime icon'</strong></p>

<p>In the lead-up to the evening rally supporters snaked around the block of the University of Pittsburgh field house hoping for a spot inside.</p>

<p>To see Harris and Obama "join forces for the greater good," Douglas said, "I think is really amazing."</p>

<p>Douglas's friend Julia Palchikoff, a 20-year-old journalism major, said maturing in the Trump era made her appreciate Obama even more.</p>

<p>"Being in a swing state in an election like this, it's just a historical moment, and I feel like I have to do my part," said the Alaska native who moved to Pennsylvania for school.</p>

<p>"When I heard Obama was coming here, I was, like, I loved him as a kid -- and Kamala, honestly, it just feels like we're on the precipice of something really great."</p>

<p>Was it the Obama she expected?</p>

<p>"It totally was," she said, before lavishing a little more praise on the former leader: "Lifetime icon."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/6hsamhqg_us-elections-barack-obama_625x300_11_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Former US President Barack Obama spoke at a campaign event for Kamala Harris.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/this-couple-walked-great-wall-of-china-from-opposite-ends-mets-in-the-middle-and-broke-up-6764804]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[A Couple Walked Great Wall Of China From Opposite Ends Only To Break Up]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/this-couple-walked-great-wall-of-china-from-opposite-ends-mets-in-the-middle-and-broke-up-6764804]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 11 Oct 2024 10:37:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Serbian artist Marina Abramovic and German artist Ulay started from opposite ends of the Great Wall to meet and marry, but their trek, titled The Lovers, ended as a symbol of their separation.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Two renowned performance artists embarked on a unique journey along the Great Wall of China in 1988. Serbian performance artist Marina Abramovic and German artist Frank Uwe Laysiepen, known as Ulay, started from opposite ends, to meet in the middle and marry in what would be a symbol of their enduring love and artistic collaboration. However, their ambitious trek, titled <em>The Lovers</em>, became a metaphor for their separation.<br />
<br />
Abramovic and Ulay met in Amsterdam in 1976 on their shared birthday, November 30, and there was an instant connection. Ulay described Abramovic&nbsp;as “witchy and otherworldly,” while she found him “wild and exciting.” They became inseparable, referring to themselves as a “two-headed body.”<br />
<br />
They spent years performing together, often in physically demanding and extreme situations, the Guardian reported. One of their famous performances, <em>Rest Energy</em>, involved Ulay holding a drawn bow aimed at Abramovic's heart. Meanwhile, the tension in their performances mirrored the tension in their relationship.<br />
<br />
For years, the couple lived a nomadic life, travelling in a van and performing in small towns and villages. As their relationship deepened, they envisioned<em> The Lovers</em> as their ultimate artistic expression – a journey of emotional and physical endurance, culminating in a symbolic wedding at the centre of the Great Wall. But that didn't go as planned.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
However, the project was fraught with challenges from the start. Chinese bureaucracy slowed the process as the couple faced years of delays. They were forced to repeatedly apply for permissions, deal with visa rejections and convince the Chinese authorities that walking the Great Wall as an art project was indeed a legitimate endeavour. By the time the walk was finally approved in 1988, five years had passed. Both Abramovic and Ulay had changed.<br />
<br />
When the walk began on March 30, 1988, Abramovic started her trek from the Bohai Sea, known as the “dragon's head,” while Ulay began from the Gobi Desert at the “dragon's tail”. Abramovic's journey was arduous, with treacherous terrain, steep mountains, and occasional near-death experiences. She walked through remote villages, seeking out local legends from the elders, many of which revolved around dragons. Ulay walked through desert landscapes. His journey was also not without its own challenges.<br />
<br />
When the two finally met after 90 days and roughly 2,000 km each, it was not for a wedding, but for a breakup. On a stone bridge in Shenmu, Shaanxi province, they embraced but the affection was bittersweet.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
Both changed during the long wait for the journey to begin. They both had affairs, communication broke down and the pressures of fame affected them in different ways. Abramovic embraced the success and recognition their work was getting, while Ulay, a self-described anarchist, shunned the commercialisation of their art.<br />
<br />
Their reunion came years later, in 2010, during Abramovic's retrospective at the Museum of Modern Art in New York, titled <em>The Artist Is Present.</em> In the performance, Abramovic sat silently for 750 hours, inviting visitors to sit across from her and share a moment of silent connection.<br />
<br />
On the opening night, Ulay made a surprise appearance and sat across from each other for the first time in over two decades. They locked eyes, smiled and started crying. In a break from the rules of the performance, Marina Abramovic reached out and took Ulay's hands.&nbsp;<br />
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="315" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/xlf68X2qEpM?si=xjApNOpoj69k9YFr" title="YouTube video player" width="560"></iframe><br />
After 22 years apart, their silent interaction, filled with emotion, touched millions.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/ra4p75kg_great-wall-of-china_625x300_11_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/1-dead-12-trapped-after-elevator-malfunction-at-colorado-gold-mine-6764785]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[1 Dead, 12 Trapped After Elevator Malfunction At Colorado Gold Mine]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/1-dead-12-trapped-after-elevator-malfunction-at-colorado-gold-mine-6764785]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 11 Oct 2024 10:31:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The incident occurred during the Mollie Kathleen Gold Mine Tour, which takes visitors 1,000 feet (300 meters) underground in the western US state.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>One person died and a dozen people remain trapped deep in a disused Colorado gold mine after the shaft's elevator system malfunctioned during a tour Thursday, local police said.</p>

<p>The incident occurred during the Mollie Kathleen Gold Mine Tour, which takes visitors 1,000 feet (300 meters) underground in the western US state.</p>

<p>A group of visitors were on board the elevator trolley system when the mechanical failure occurred, killing one person and injuring four.</p>

<p>Officials did not release further details about what went wrong, citing an active investigation.</p>

<p>"We did have one fatality that occurred during this issue at 500 feet," Teller County sheriff Jason Mikesell told a press conference.</p>

<p>The other 11 people on board the elevator at the time, including two children, were brought safely to the surface with the assistance of the mine operators and fire department officials.</p>

<p>Aside from the fatality, the four people hurt in the incident suffered only minor injuries, said Mikesell.</p>

<p>A further 12 people remain in a tunnel at the bottom of the mine.</p>

<p>They are safe and are accompanied by a mine employee, but cannot be moved until the elevator system is cleared as safe to be used again, said Mikesell.</p>

<p>Emergency officials with ropes are standing by in case they are required.</p>

<p>Chairs, blankets, and water have been provided to those in the mine.</p>

<p>"The atmospherics are good inside the tunnel," said Mikesell.</p>

<p>Those still inside the mine have not been informed of the fatality.</p>

<p>"We're just trying to keep down the worry of what's going on, so that nobody gets excited," added Mikesell.</p>

<p>The mine outside the small city of Cripple Creek, around 100 miles south of Denver, offers a chance to "Experience the 'Old West' as it was for hard rock gold miners of 'The World's Greatest Gold Camp,'" according to its official website.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/974u7ae_colorado-gold-mine_625x300_11_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[One dead and four injured during mechanical failure at Colorado gold mine.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>