<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Tue, 05 Nov 2024 22:53:54 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-election-donald-trump-feels-very-confident-about-winning-back-the-white-house-amid-vote-6951918]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Very Confident" About Winning Back The White House, Says Trump]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-election-donald-trump-feels-very-confident-about-winning-back-the-white-house-amid-vote-6951918]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 05 Nov 2024 22:50:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump feels "very confident" about winning back the White House, the Republican said Tuesday after casting his Election Day ballot in Florida in one of the most contentious US elections in decades.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump feels "very confident" about winning back the White House, the Republican said Tuesday after casting his Election Day ballot in Florida in one of the most contentious US elections in decades.</p>

<p>"I feel very confident," Trump told reporters at a voting facility in West Palm Beach, adding he believes he "ran a great campaign" against his Democratic rival Kamala Harris. Opinion polls show the race is a dead heat.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/0baohu9g_donald-trump_625x300_03_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Republican candidate and Former President Donald Trump believes he ran a great campaign. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/how-the-cold-sore-virus-can-reach-and-infect-your-brain-6951887]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How The Cold Sore Virus Can Reach And Infect Your Brain]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/how-the-cold-sore-virus-can-reach-and-infect-your-brain-6951887]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 05 Nov 2024 22:47:00 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The virus affects critical brain regions tied to sleep, mood, and hormonal control, potentially linking HSV-1 to neurodegenerative diseases.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The herpes simplex virus type 1 (HSV-1), which causes cold sores, has long been known to have effects on the brain and central nervous system.</p>

<p>Researchers from the University of Colorado and the University of Bourgogne in France have recently conducted <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://journals.asm.org/doi/10.1128/jvi.00968-24"><em>a study</em></a> that provides new information on how this virus spreads inside the brain.</p>

<p>Researchers mapped the areas affected by the virus by using mouse models to study how HSV-1 affected different parts of the brain. Their findings reveal that HSV-1 can access the central nervous system through two main pathways: the trigeminal nerve, which connects the face and brain, and the olfactory nerve, responsible for the sense of smell. Despite identifying these entry points, the exact mechanism of how HSV-1 spreads further within the brain remains unclear.</p>

<p>"Recently, this common virus has been implicated in neurodegenerative diseases, such as Alzheimer's disease, but no clear route of central nervous system invasion has been established," says Christy Niemeyer, PhD, assistant professor of neurology at the University of Colorado Anschutz Medical Campus and co-first and corresponding author. "Identifying how HSV-1 can get into the brain and what brain regions are vulnerable is key in understanding how it initiates disease."</p>

<p>Once HSV-1 enters the brain, researchers also wanted to determine if the virus migrates at random or to specific areas. They were able to map where and how the virus travels within the brain and infects critical brain regions that control many vital functions, such as the brain stem, which controls sleep and movement. Researchers also found HSV-1 in regions of the brain that produce serotonin and norepinephrine, as well as the hypothalamus, a critical center of appetite, sleep, mood, and hormonal control within the brain.</p>

<p>"Even though the presence of HSV-1 is not causing full-blown encephalitis in the brain, it can still affect how these regions function," <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://news.cuanschutz.edu/news-stories/silent-intruder-how-the-cold-sore-virus-maps-its-way-through-the-brain"><em>says Niemeyer.</em></a></p>

<p>Niemeyer and coauthors also show how HSV-1 interacts with the brain's key immune cells; microglia. They found that microglia became "inflamed" when interacting with HSV-1, but in some brain regions, inflamed microglia persisted even after the virus was no longer detected.</p>

<p>"Identifying the role of microglia provides helpful clues to the consequences of HSV-1 infection, and how it triggers neurological diseases," says Niemeyer. "persistently inflamed cells can lead to chronic inflammation, a known trigger for a number of neurological and neurodegenerative diseases. This research offers important takeaways in better understanding how viruses interact with overall brain health as well as the onset of pervasive neurological diseases."</p>

<p>This study adds to the understanding of HSV-1's impact on the brain, a crucial step towards developing treatments to limit its effects on the nervous system.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/gusq3f1o_brain_625x300_05_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[HSV-1 interacts with microglia, the brain's immune cells.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/google-cleared-in-lawsuit-alleging-profit-from-gift-card-scams-6951795]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Google Cleared In Lawsuit Alleging Profit From 'Gift Card Scams']]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/google-cleared-in-lawsuit-alleging-profit-from-gift-card-scams-6951795]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 05 Nov 2024 22:30:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A federal judge dismissed a proposed class action lawsuit accusing Google of illegally profiting from Google Play gift card scams by refusing to refund millions of dollars stolen from victims.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A federal judge dismissed a proposed class action lawsuit accusing Google of illegally profiting from Google Play gift card scams by refusing to refund millions of dollars stolen from victims.</p>

<p>In a late Monday decision, US District Judge Beth Labson Freeman said the complainant Judy May lost money because scammers induced her to buy gift cards, and failed to show that Google caused her losses or knew it was receiving stolen funds.</p>

<p>The San Jose, California-based judge also said Google was not liable for keeping 15% to 30% commissions on purchases that scammers made with the gift cards, because Google's conduct was unrelated to the original fraud.</p>

<p>May said she lost $1,000 in April 2021 when a scammer posing as a relative instructed her to contact a supposed government agent, who told her she was eligible for federal grant money if she bought Google Play gift cards.</p>

<p>The Brownsville, Indiana resident said she provided the codes on the back to cover supposed upfront costs, but the scammers used the codes to make purchases.</p>

<p>May said she would not have bought the cards had Google warned on the packaging about scams, and that anyone demanding payment with the cards was a scammer.</p>

<p>Lawyers for May did not immediately respond on Tuesday to requests for comment. Google, a unit of Alphabet, did not immediately respond to similar requests.</p>

<p>Freeman said May could try to refile her lawsuit, but dismissed a claim seeking triple damages for good. Alphabet is based in Mountain View, California.</p>

<p>In 2023, Americans lost $217 million in gift card or reload card fraud, according to the Federal Trade Commission.</p>

<p>The actual amount is likely much higher because the data cover only reported cases. Citing FTC data from 2021, May said Google Play cards account for about 20% of gift card scams.</p>

<p>The case is May v Google LLC et al, US District Court, Northern District of California, No. 24-01314.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-01/uspt4bmg_google-generic-reuters_625x300_20_January_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[In 2023, Americans lost $217 million in gift card fraud, according to FTC. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/60-indian-americans-expected-to-vote-for-kamla-harris-ex-indian-envoy-to-us-6951793]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["60% Indian Americans Expected To Vote For Harris": Ex Indian Envoy To US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/60-indian-americans-expected-to-vote-for-kamla-harris-ex-indian-envoy-to-us-6951793]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 05 Nov 2024 22:30:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Arun Kumar Singh, former Indian Ambassador to the US, shared his thoughts on the 2024 US presidential election.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Arun Kumar Singh, former Indian Ambassador to the US, shared his thoughts on the 2024 US presidential election. "Each election is unique, but similarities exist with 2016 and 2020 campaigns, as Trump defined issues, highlighting America's decline."</p>

<p>Speaking to ANI on Tuesday, India envoy said, "Each election, of course, is unique, but I would say that to some extent, there's a similarity to the kind of campaign that was there in 2016 and in 2020, when earlier also President Trump was a candidate, because he defined the issues in a certain way, trying to highlight as if America was not doing well, other countries had exported America, Americans were being exported by immigrants."</p>

<p>"So he was painting all the negative dimensions of what was happening in the US, trying to project that he was not a part of the establishment, although he's a very successful businessman himself, and therefore people should vote for him," he added.</p>

<p>Further, Singh highlighted Kamala Harris's historic candidacy as the first African American and Indian American woman to run for president. However, pre-poll surveys revealed unexpected trends, with many groups that were expected to support her not doing so.</p>

<p>"According to pre-poll surveys, the majority of African American males were not supporting her. The majority of Latino males did not support her. And if you look at the Indian American vote, again, according to pre-poll surveys. 80% had voted for Hillary Clinton in 2016, and about 70% had voted for Joe Biden in 2020. But this year, the expectation was that only 60% of Indian Americans would vote for her, although she is a person partially of the same ethnic origin." he said.</p>

<p>"So these were some of the trends that were to be, were unexpected, but they were there. And I think this was a reflection of the fact that for the voting public, among the issues that were prominent were the issues related to the economy, inflation, jobs, where there was a sense that they were not doing well," he added.</p>

<p>Singh stated that many pre-poll services suggested a large majority of Americans felt the country was headed in the wrong direction, which would negatively impact the Biden-Harris administration and Kamala Harris's candidacy.</p>

<p>"And again, many pre-poll services suggested that a large bulk of Americans felt that the country was not heading in the right direction. And therefore, if they felt that, then obviously they would take that, hold that against the current administration, the Biden-Harris administration, and then Kamala Harris naturally suffered as a result of that," the envoy said.</p>

<p>Singh's comments come as the US election reaches its climax, with Harris facing a tough contest against Donald Trump.</p>

<p>The election outcome remains uncertain, with multiple battleground states, including Pennsylvania, North Carolina, and Georgia, still up for grabs.</p>

<p>The voters in the US are heading to vote in one of their most consequential elections, which will decide the direction of not just the US but also have an influence on global geopolitics for the next four years.</p>

<p>The polling hours will vary across the states, but most locations will vote between 6 am and 8 pm on Tuesday (local time). Though exit polls will start coming once voting starts, the final results will come only after counting is closed in all states.</p>

<p>The first polls will close at around 7 pm ET (5:30 am IST) in six states, including Georgia. The final polls will close in the blue state of Hawaii and in the red state of Alaska at 12 am ET (10:30 am IST).</p>

<p>Total votes will close by 1 pm ET (11:30 am IST), following which counting will start. The results in small states can be projected soon after polling states; some key battleground states may take hours to project the winner.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/mlebf85g_ambassador-arun-k-singh-_625x300_05_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Arun Kumar Singh's comments come as the US election reaches its climax. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/harris-campaign-spends-final-hours-reminding-pennsylvania-of-trump-allys-joke-about-puerto-rico-6951578]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Harris Reminds Pennsylvania Of Trump Ally's Joke About Puerto Rico]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/harris-campaign-spends-final-hours-reminding-pennsylvania-of-trump-allys-joke-about-puerto-rico-6951578]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 05 Nov 2024 21:56:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Tony Hinchcliffe's joke at the Madison Square Garden rally cost Trump the endorsement of popular Puerto Rican artist Nicky Jam and earned Harris the support of superstar Bad Bunny, also from Puerto Rico.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The day before Election Day, 17-year-old girl Carmen Hernandez held a cardboard sign with the Puerto Rican flag outside Trump's rally in Reading, Pennsylvania, a city that is two-thirds Hispanic.<br />
"What you call trash is our treasure," the sign read.</p>

<p>While Trump's campaign had quickly distanced itself from a comic's slam on Puerto Rico as a "floating island of garbage," Kamala Harris' campaign and other Democrats spent the last hours of the 2024 campaign in the nation's largest battleground state linking him to the joke.</p>

<p>Harris devoted much of her final full day on the campaign trail to reaching Latino voters in Pennsylvania, a swing state that Democrats consider part of their "blue wall" in the Electoral College. She made multiple stops in what is known as the 222 Corridor, after the highway that connects small cities and towns west and north of Philadelphia.</p>

<p>More than 315,000 people who are 18 and older identify as Puerto Ricans in Pennsylvania. And in a state where small margins could decide who gets 19 votes in the Electoral College, that community could be crucial for both Democrats, who are seeking to hold onto voters who have long favored their party, and Republicans, who are trying to make further inroads among this demographic.</p>

<p>Tony Hinchcliffe's joke at the Madison Square Garden rally cost Trump the endorsement of popular Puerto Rican artist Nicky Jam and earned Harris the support of superstar Bad Bunny, also from Puerto Rico.</p>

<p>Reading Mayor Eddie Moran, the first Latino to hold the office in his city's 276-year history, said he found it ironic that the next president "is going to potentially be decided by Pennsylvania, but even more so by Latinos," in communities like Reading, by "some of the individuals that in the past have been least respected to make that decision."</p>

<p>"He continues to insult us to coming knocking at our door here in Reading, a community that is 70% Latino. And of those, about 30,000 are Puerto Ricans," Moran said of Trump. "And yet, here he is in a rally today. How insulting is that?"</p>

<p>Carmen Hernandez, the teenager holding the sign outside Trump's rally, said that although she can't vote Tuesday, her whole Puerto Rican family would vote for Harris.</p>

<p>"I'm here because I want to feel a sense of pride about protecting and defending my island," said the high school senior.</p>

<p>In Allentown, Harris touted her "longstanding commitment" to the island, whose residents are American citizens but who don't get a say in the Electoral College. Fat Joe, a rapper with Puerto Rican heritage, spoke shortly before Harris and urged voters to support the Democrat.</p>

<p>"The other day at Madison Square Garden, that was no joke, ladies and gentlemen. That was no joke," Fat Joe said. "Calling Puerto Rico the island of garbage, my Latinos, where is your pride?"</p>

<p>In Reading, a crowd gathered outside a Puerto Rican restaurant called Old San Juan Cafe to catch a glimpse of the vice president. Flanked by Pennsylvania Gov. Josh Shapiro and New York Rep. Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez, Harris asked diners about the restaurant and what kind of food she should order to go, opting for a bag of plantains, cassava and rice.</p>

<p>"I'm so excited," said Claudia Guzman, 52, who had not voted. "I never thought the vice president would come here. Tomorrow I vote for Kamala. Women are coming to power."</p>

<p>U.S. Sen. Marco Rubio, a Cuban American, spoke to Trump supporters in Spanish at a Reading rally on Monday, telling them that Spanish "sounds more passionate" and asking for understanding as he jokingly said he spoke Cuban.</p>

<p>"But the Boricuas will understand," he said, referring to a term used for Puerto Ricans, "and the Dominicans, too."</p>

<p>Trump, he said in Spanish, is "the only candidate who from now on says you will be a priority, not shipping jobs abroad, not sending factories to other countries, not worrying about the needs of people from other countries," he said.</p>

<p>Rubio didn't directly address the comic's joke and neither did Trump. Instead, the former president has hailed his relationship with the island, saying "we helped Puerto Rico more than anybody."</p>

<p>In September 2020, after criticism for a slow response to Hurricane Maria in 2017, Trump released $13 billion in assistance to repair years-old hurricane damage. It took Trump two weeks to visit the island after the storm. He was criticized for an appearance where he threw rolls of paper towels into a crowd.</p>

<p>Emilio Feliciano, 43, dismissed the joke. While his family is Puerto Rican, he said he cared more about the economy and still plans to vote for Trump on Tuesday.</p>

<p>"Boo hoo. We've got bigger fish to fry. I will never cry over Puerto Rico being called garbage," he said at the Reading event. "Is the border going to be safe? Are you going to keep crime down? That's what I care about."</p>

<p>But Luis Colon, 45, a Puerto Rican who lives in Reading, walked into the same rally even as he planned to vote for Harris. He said the comments at the Trump rally were a "disgrace."</p>

<p>"I'm just going in to see the stupidity, the nonsense. I don't vote for Trump; I don't root for Trump. Trump is not going for the Latinos; he's against us. Trump is going to throw us under the bus," Colon said.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/pq4qlj0o_kamala-harris-reuters_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Harris devoted much of her final full day on the campaign trail to reaching Latino voters in Pennsylvania]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/on-night-before-election-day-kamala-harris-brings-in-celebrities-donald-trump-is-unimpressed-6951176]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Before Election Day, Harris Brings In Celebrities. Trump Is Unimpressed]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/on-night-before-election-day-kamala-harris-brings-in-celebrities-donald-trump-is-unimpressed-6951176]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 05 Nov 2024 20:55:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[On the night before Election Day, at campaign events across the country, celebrities turned out in force for Kamala Harris' presidential bid.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On the night before Election Day, at campaign events across the country, celebrities turned out in force for Kamala Harris' presidential bid.<br />
The battleground state of Pennsylvania was particularly starry: In Pittsburgh, the vice president's rally featured Cedric the Entertainer, Katy Perry and Andra Day. In Philadelphia, the finale of Harris' daylong dash across Pennsylvania, performers and presenters included DJ Cassidy, Fat Joe and Ricky Martin.</p>

<p>Republican Donald Trump was decidedly unimpressed with Harris' celebrity lineup.</p>

<p>At his own rally in Pittsburgh, which overlapped with Harris' event in the city, the former president criticized Harris for one celebrity endorsement in particular: Beyoncé. He spoke dismissively about Beyoncé's appearance at a Harris rally with Harris in Houston last month, drawing boos for the megastar from his supporters.</p>

<p>"Beyoncé would come in. Everyone's expecting a couple of songs. There were no songs. There was no happiness," Trump said.</p>

<p>Beyoncé did not perform at the event but was joined onstage by her Destiny's Child bandmate Kelly Rowland, and gave a joyful, impassioned speech met with cheers.</p>

<p>Previously, Beyoncé allowed the Harris campaign to take on her 2016 track "Freedom," a cut from her landmark 2016 album "Lemonade," as its anthem.</p>

<p>Trump added that Harris should have learned a lesson from Hillary Clinton and had Beyoncé speak after her, saying, "That way the people stay."</p>

<p>In 2016, Beyoncé performed at a campaign event for Democratic nominee Clinton in Cleveland in the days leading up to the election.</p>

<p>"They booed like hell, but the press didn't play that," Trump continued in his description of Beyoncé's appearance at the Harris event.</p>

<p>He insisted his campaign doesn't need celebrities to pack in a crowd, adding: "We don't need a star because we have policy. We have great policy."</p>

<p>At another point in the same rally, though, he enthused: "So many celebrities here, it's incredible: Mike Pompeo, please stand up," introducing his former secretary of state.</p>

<p>Trump also was joined by Megyn Kelly and baseball star Roberto Clemente's son.</p>

<p>Harris lined up performers to speak and play at campaign rallies in all seven battleground states on Monday, and melded them all into one Democratic get-out-the-vote livestream.</p>

<p>In Las Vegas, performers included Christina Aguilera and electro-dance duo Sofi Tukker. In Raleigh, North Carolina, Sugarland, the country music duo of Jennifer Nettles and Kristian Bush, took the stage.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/oh3m2dlg_donald-trump-kamala-harris_625x300_31_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Trump was decidedly unimpressed with Harris' celebrity lineup.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/wives-react-in-shock-as-50-men-stand-in-trial-for-mass-rape-case-in-france-6950992]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Wives React In Shock As 50 Men Stand In Trial For Mass Rape Case In France]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/wives-react-in-shock-as-50-men-stand-in-trial-for-mass-rape-case-in-france-6950992]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 05 Nov 2024 20:29:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The wives and girlfriends of dozens of men on trial in France accused of raping another woman while she was drugged by her husband have reacted with anger and disbelief, although some say they will stand by the accused.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The wives and girlfriends of dozens of men on trial in France accused of raping another woman while she was drugged by her husband have reacted with anger and disbelief, although some say they will stand by the accused.</p>

<p>In a court case that has shocked France, Dominique Pelicot, 71, has admitted to drugging his then wife Gisele with sedatives so that strangers could sexually abuse her in her own bed for almost a decade until 2020.</p>

<p>Another 50 men, aged 26 to 74, are also on trial in the southern city of Avignon accused of responding to his invitation to rape her.</p>

<p>Some, including Pelicot, are in custody, and one is being tried in absentia, but 32 of the defendants are attending as free men.</p>

<p>Among the women who have testified at the trial, Vanessa P. said she no longer had any respect for her former partner Quentin H., 34, who was a prison guard when he allegedly abused Gisele Pelicot.</p>

<p>"When you see what they are accusing him of, you start doubting everything," said the childcare worker, accusing him of being "manipulative".</p>

<p>Emilie O., 33, similarly described her ex-partner Hugues M., a 39-year-old charged with "attempted rape" in the trial.</p>

<p>"I thought I was living a peaceful and fulfilling life, but I was wrong," she said, adding she would always fear that she too was raped.</p>

<p>Emilie O. separated from her partner in 2020, when police uncovered the years-long abuse of Gisele Pelicot and she discovered Hugues M. had had several affairs.</p>

<p><strong>'He was always respectful'</strong></p>

<p>Gisele Pelicot, now 71, has become a feminist icon at home and abroad since the trial started in September, refusing to be ashamed and demanding the trial be open to the public.</p>

<p>Like her, Cilia M. was also drugged and raped.</p>

<p>Her husband Jean-Pierre M., 63, is the only defendant in the trial not accused of abusing Gisele Pelicot.</p>

<p>Instead he and Dominique Pelicot have been charged with repeatedly drugging and sexually assaulting Cilia M. between 2015 and 2018, using the same method.</p>

<p>"He was wonderful, but he destroyed us," said the mother of his five children, one of whom is disabled.</p>

<p>Cilia M. told the court she would "never forgive" her husband, who has claimed his own father sexually abused him as a child.</p>

<p>She has since separated from him, but has not pressed charges in order to "protect" her children.</p>

<p>Corinne M. had already separated from her husband, former builder Thierry P., 54, when the Pelicot case came to light, after the death of their son in a traffic accident had driven him to become alcoholic.</p>

<p>She was confused by his behaviour.</p>

<p>When it came to sex, "he was always respectful. When it was no, it was no... I really don't understand why he is here today," she said at the trial.</p>

<p>Veronique Le Goaziou, a sociologist specialising in the subject of sexual abuse, told AFP partners of defendants were usually "stunned".</p>

<p>They often struggled to imagine the alleged violence as it went "beyond their understanding", she said.</p>

<p>"In some cases... they simply cannot or will not believe it."</p>

<p><strong>'It's not him'</strong></p>

<p>Samira T. said she was still trying to understand why her partner Jerome V. six times raped Gisele Pelicot in her home in the southern town of Mazan in 2020.</p>

<p>But she would stand by him to "support" him.</p>

<p>"If we met it's no coincidence," she said. "I was given this mission."</p>

<p>Jerome V., a 46-year-old former minimart employee who claims he has slept with 89 people, told the court he was unable to control his sexuality.</p>

<p>Samira T. said that she had sought to satisfy his high libido, complying with his requests for sex almost every day "at 10 at night" and agreeing to having naked pictures taken of her or going on walks in the nude.</p>

<p>"He had no reason to go look elsewhere," she said, crying.</p>

<p>Another woman, Hien B., blamed herself.</p>

<p>During a period when she was looking after her sick mother, she had brushed Jean-Luc L. off consistently when he wanted sex.</p>

<p>"I think that, as a man, he decided to turn elsewhere," she said.</p>

<p>Among the partners of the accused in Avignon, Sonia R. has been dating Patrice N. for just over a year.</p>

<p>She said she wanted to look forward to the future.</p>

<p>"I support him and trust him wholeheartedly," she said.</p>

<p>Lucie B. also stood by Gregory S., her partner of seven years. She is pregnant with their third child.</p>

<p>"I don't see him as a rapist. It's not him," she said.</p>

<p>After they met in 2017, she said, he had told her about visiting the Pelicot home earlier the same year.</p>

<p>"He told me it was a husband and his wife's idea of fun, that she was drunk," she added.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/2fo0mps_france-mass-rape-trial_625x300_05_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Another 50 men, aged 26 to 74, are also on trial in the southern city of Avignon. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/tim-cook-and-mark-cuban-rely-on-these-ai-tools-to-save-time-its-changed-my-life-6950953]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Tim Cook And Mark Cuban Rely On These AI Tools To Save Time]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/tim-cook-and-mark-cuban-rely-on-these-ai-tools-to-save-time-its-changed-my-life-6950953]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 05 Nov 2024 20:22:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Tim Cook receives over 800 emails while Mark Cuban gets more than a thousand emails a lot of which are repetitive'.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Apple CEO Tim Cook starts his day between 4 and 5 a.m. by checking his iPhone for emails and overnight sales reports. Given that he receives over 800 emails daily, including feedback from Apple customers, keeping up with them all is a challenge.</p>

<p>To manage this, Mr Cook, 64, uses Apple's latest AI tool, Apple Intelligence, which provides brief summaries of his emails. This feature automatically generates short overviews under each email in the Mail app, streamlining his inbox. "If I can save time here and there, it adds up over a day, a week, or a month," Mr Cook told the <em>Wall Street Journal Magazine</em>, adding, "It's changed my life. It really has."</p>

<p>Mr Cook isn't the only billionaire using AI to tackle an overflowing inbox. Entrepreneur and Shark Tank judge Mark Cuban also relies on AI for email management. Mr Cuban, who receives thousands of emails daily-many of them repetitive-uses Google's generative AI assistant and suggested replies in Gmail, calling it "the ultimate time-saving hack."</p>

<p>"It's reduced the need for me to write out routine replies," Mr Cuban told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.cnbc.com/2024/11/04/mark-cuban-and-tim-cook-swear-by-this-time-saving-email-hack.html" rel="nofollow, noindex"><em>CNBC Make It</em></a>. "I can spend 30 seconds evaluating its response and hit 'send' versus typing it all out myself." With AI handling his routine messages, Mr Cuban said he can dedicate more time to strategic tasks, enhancing his productivity and effectiveness as a leader.</p>

<p>“I'll use different generative AI tools to edit my kids' homework assignments for spelling and grammar mistakes, which has helped me a lot as a parent,” he added. “And to make sure they're not using AI to write their papers.”</p>

<p><br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/jnvq0l38_tim-cook-and-mark-cuban_625x300_05_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mr Cook isn't the only billionaire using AI to tackle an overflowing inbox.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/anti-trust-body-recalls-probe-into-competition-law-breach-by-flipkart-6950697]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Anti-Trust Body Recalls Probe Into Flipkart's Competition Law Breach: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/anti-trust-body-recalls-probe-into-competition-law-breach-by-flipkart-6950697]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 05 Nov 2024 19:47:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India's antitrust body has recalled its investigation report into competition law breaches by e-commerce giant Walmart's Flipkart, a document shows, the second such move after a report on Apple was revoked in August.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India's antitrust body has recalled its investigation report into competition law breaches by e-commerce giant Walmart's Flipkart, a document shows, the second such move after a report on Apple was revoked in August.</p>

<p>China's Xiaomi had complained to the Competition Commission of India (CCI) that the report - which found Flipkart, some of its sellers, and smartphone players in violation of competition laws - contained commercial secrets that should have been redacted, Reuters reported in September.</p>

<p>According to two sources and an internal CCI document dated October 1 seen by Reuters on Tuesday, the watchdog has told recipients of the Flipkart report to destroy it and give an undertaking to that effect to avoid further distribution.</p>

<p>Xiaomi argued the report contained its model-wise sales, which are sensitive information.</p>

<p>The CCI document noted some data and information was "inadvertently" included in the report and provided the parties involved with a new report, though it did not spell out what changes it was making.</p>

<p>Xiaomi declined to comment, while the CCI and Flipkart did not respond to Reuters' queries.</p>

<p>In August, the CCI recalled an antitrust report on Apple after the company complained commercial secrets were disclosed to some of the parties involved.</p>

<p>In a lengthy investigation that started in 2020, the CCI found Flipkart, as well as e-commerce rival Amazon, gave preference to select sellers and prioritised certain listings, and also colluded with companies like Xiaomi, Samsung and Vivo to launch phones exclusively on their websites.</p>

<p>Much of the investigation process, however, remains on hold after Vivo and some online sellers of the two e-commerce companies challenged their inclusion in the probe and obtained court injunctions.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-02/qk443pro_flipkart_625x300_01_February_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Xiaomi argued the report contained model-wise sales, which are sensitive information. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/childrens-reading-habit-hits-record-low-survey-reveals-alarming-decline-6950605]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Children's Reading Habit Hits Record Low, Survey Reveals Alarming Decline]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/childrens-reading-habit-hits-record-low-survey-reveals-alarming-decline-6950605]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 05 Nov 2024 19:38:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The 2024 survey, which included over 76,000 responses, shows that only 34.6% of children aged 8 to 18 enjoy reading in their free time.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In worrying news for educators, a recent survey indicates that children's reading habits are approaching a "crisis" point, with the percentage of pupils who like reading books currently at its lowest level in nearly two decades.</p>

<p>According to a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://literacytrust.org.uk/research-services/research-reports/children-and-young-peoples-reading-in-2024/">report by the National Literacy Trust (NLT)</a> organisation, the percentage of young people who say they enjoy reading has decreased dramatically over the past year, particularly among boys.</p>

<p>This report is based on 76,131 responses to NLT's Annual Literacy Survey from children and young people aged 5 to 18 in early 2024. It includes findings on reading enjoyment, frequency, and motivation and explores responses by age, gender, socio-economic background, and geographical region.</p>

<p>The NLT's Annual Literacy Survey indicates a steady decline in the number of children and young people who report enjoying reading and engaging in daily reading during their free time.</p>

<p>According to the survey, launched in 2005 to track children's interest in reading, this year has recorded the lowest percentage of children and young people who say they enjoy reading since the survey's inception.</p>

<p><strong>Key findings from the survey:</strong></p>

<ul>
	<li>Just 1 in 3 (34.6%) children and young people aged 8 to 18 said that they enjoyed reading in their free time in 2024. Reading enjoyment levels have decreased by 8.8 percentage points over the past year alone.</li>
	<li>Only 1 in 5 (20.5%) 8- to 18-year-olds said that they read something daily in their free time in 2024, again, the lowest levels we've recorded since 2005, with daily reading levels decreasing by 7.5pp in the last year alone.</li>
</ul>

<p>"With children and young people's enjoyment of reading at an all-time low and high numbers leaving primary and secondary school without the reading skills they need to thrive, the futures of a generation are being put at risk," NLT chief executive Jonathan Douglas told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2024/nov/05/report-fall-in-children-reading-for-pleasure-national-literacy-trust"><em>The Guardian.</em></a></p>

<p>"For a report focused largely on reading enjoyment, much of this is not an enjoyable read," concluded the report. "The declining levels of reading enjoyment and reading frequency are, frankly, shocking and dispiriting."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ab8tei18_reading-habits-of-children_625x300_05_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The reading habits of children have reached a "crisis" point.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/stabbing-attack-at-melbourne-shopping-centre-in-australia-leaves-3-injured-6950442]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Stabbing Attack At Melbourne Shopping Centre, In Australia, Leaves 3 Injured]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/stabbing-attack-at-melbourne-shopping-centre-in-australia-leaves-3-injured-6950442]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 05 Nov 2024 19:14:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A man has been arrested after he allegedly stabbed multiple people at a shopping centre in Melbourne on Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A man has been arrested after he allegedly stabbed multiple people at a shopping centre in Melbourne on Tuesday.</p>

<p>Police in the state of Victoria said in a statement that emergency services were called to the Fountain Gate shopping centre in Melbourne's southeast at about 2:25 pm local time on Tuesday following reports that three people were attacked at a bus stop.</p>

<p>The three victims, two men and a woman were taken to a nearby hospital with non-life-threatening injuries, Xinhua news agency reported.</p>

<p>Local media reported that they were slashed with a box cutter.</p>

<p>Police said that the alleged perpetrator, a 30-year-old local man, fled the scene but was later arrested inside the shopping centre.</p>

<p>One witness posted on social media that there was a major police presence at the centre in response to the incident and that the arrested man had blood on his face.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/5u9pe4ro_australia-police-generic-afp_625x300_15_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The three victims, two men and a woman, were taken to a nearby hospital. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/as-voting-begins-what-harris-and-trump-need-to-win-the-presidency-6950033]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[As Voting Begins, What Harris And Trump Need To Win The Presidency]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/as-voting-begins-what-harris-and-trump-need-to-win-the-presidency-6950033]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 05 Nov 2024 18:24:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[There are 4 important issues when it comes to the deciding factor. The economy, immigration and border control, abortion issues and safeguarding democracy.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The U.S. presidential election is going down to the wire, with polls showing a deadlocked race between Kamala Harris and Donald Trump. The swing states of Pennsylvania, Michigan, Wisconsin, Nevada, Arizona, Georgia, and North Carolina will play a crucial role in determining the outcome.<br />
Trump's favorability rating is stuck at 43 per cent, and he has never topped 50 per cent since leaving office. This means he has hit a ceiling in his support and may struggle to win the national popular vote.</p>

<p>There are 4 important issues when it comes to the deciding factor. The economy, immigration and border control, abortion issues and safeguarding democracy.</p>

<p>The country is in a bad mood, with 60-70 per cent of Americans believing the country is on the wrong track which means the election will change. Historically, when Americans feel the country is on the wrong track, the incumbent president tends to lose favor, giving their challenger a significant advantage in the election and Harris is facing this blow.</p>

<p>Trump is seen as the better candidate to manage the economy, leading by a 15-point margin in swing states, since during the Biden administration, the cost has risen between 10-40 per cent.</p>

<p>Trump has made immigration a central issue, and voters view him as the best candidate to manage the border. The first three years of Biden's term saw immigration troubles, however the rates have fallen now.</p>

<p>Harris is seen as the champion of reproductive rights, and polling shows her leading Trump among women voters in swing states by 15 points or more. Abortion rights are decided at the state level and it is on the ballot in two key swing states - Nevada and Arizona which is a positive aspect for Harris.</p>

<p>Half the country sees Trump as a threat to American democracy, an authoritarian, while Harris has pledged to unite the country and even get the Republicans and Democrats working.</p>

<p>If Harris wins, it will be because she has successfully sealed the deal with voters and made the election a referendum on Trump. Her ground game, which includes a USD 1 billion machine to reach voters in swing states, will be crucial.</p>

<p>If Trump wins, it will mean voters trusted him to manage inflation, immigration, and crime. Unease about Harris, a Black and South Asian woman, as president may also play a role.</p>

<p>The outcome is far from certain, and the next 24 hours will be intense. Will Harris' ground game deliver, or will Trump's economic message resonate with voters? The country holds its breath as it waits for the results.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/knofc75_donald-trump-kamala-harris_625x300_31_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The U.S. presidential election is going down to the wire, with polls showing a deadlocked race]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-election-donald-trump-or-kamala-harris-will-inherit-joe-bidens-mixed-legacy-on-key-issues-6950032]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Or Harris? Who Will Inherit Biden's Mixed Legacy On Key Issues]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-election-donald-trump-or-kamala-harris-will-inherit-joe-bidens-mixed-legacy-on-key-issues-6950032]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 05 Nov 2024 18:24:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Americans head to the polls on Tuesday in a mood of discontent and division, with opinion polls showing nearly two-thirds of voters believe the country has been heading in the wrong direction under President Joe Biden.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Americans head to the polls on Tuesday in a mood of discontent and division, with opinion polls showing nearly two-thirds of voters believe the country has been heading in the wrong direction under President Joe Biden.</p>

<p>While the United States economy is the envy of the industrialized world, emerging from COVID shutdowns with strong job growth and wage increases, many Americans complain those gains were gobbled up by high grocery and housing prices.</p>

<p>Biden's promise of a return to a more humane immigration regime than under Republican former President Donald Trump soon collided with the reality of a spike in illegal border crossings.</p>

<p>The Supreme Court upended the legal landscape around abortion rights by overturning Roe v. Wade, inflaming one of the most divisive issues in American politics.</p>

<p>And despite Biden's pledge that America would serve as a stabilizing force in the world, overseas conflicts have overshadowed his presidency.</p>

<p>Whoever triumphs in the election - Trump or Vice President Kamala Harris - will inherit the legacy of a Biden administration that made good on some promises, saw others swept off-course by events, and others still only partially fulfilled. Here's how Biden fared on the defining issues of his presidency.</p>

<p><strong>IMMIGRATION</strong></p>

<p>Biden, a Democrat, started his presidency by reversing many of Trump's restrictive immigration policies. He haltedconstruction of Trump's border wall; rescinded bans targeting people from certain majority-Muslim countries and other nations; and wound down the "remain in Mexico" program, which forced non-Mexican asylum seekers to wait in Mexico as they pursued their US cases.</p>

<p>But months into his presidency, illegal crossings spiked, particularly among unaccompanied children from Central America, overwhelming US border processing centers and fueling Republican criticism.</p>

<p>Illegal crossings reached record levels in 2022 and 2023 as more migrants arrived from Cuba, Haiti, Nicaragua and Venezuela and countries outside the hemisphere.</p>

<p>In response, Texas Governor Greg Abbott, a Republican, in 2022 beganbusing arriving migrants north to Democratic cities including New York City and Chicago, which struggled to house them.</p>

<p>In January, Biden backed a bipartisan bill that aimed to tighten border security. After the bill was defeated in the US Senate amid Trump's opposition, Biden in June bannedasylum for most migrants crossing the border illegally.</p>

<p>The number of migrants caught crossing illegally dropped dramatically, undercutting Trump's false claims that Harris and Democrats support an open border.</p>

<p>Despite the political pressures surrounding migration, Biden created new legal pathways for hundreds of thousands of migrants and oversaw the restoration of the US refugee program, which admitted more than 100,000 refugees in fiscal year 2024, the most in 30 years.</p>

<p><strong>ABORTION</strong></p>

<p>The biggest upheaval on abortion access in decades occurred during Biden's presidency - but because of a decision by the Supreme Court.</p>

<p>In June 2022, the conservative majority formed by Trump's judicial appointments to the court eliminated the nearly 50-year-old federal right to abortion under Roe v. Wade.</p>

<p>The decision ushered in a period in which individual states set their own laws on abortion access. More than a dozen states banned abortion in all or most cases.</p>

<p>Biden condemned the Supreme Court ruling, and his administration, through the Department of Health and Human Services and the Justice Department, laid out guidelines to ensure access to emergency abortion care under federal law and defended the use of the abortion pill before the Supreme Court.</p>

<p>The administration also pushed for expanded access to reproductive health services like contraception through the Affordable Care Act.</p>

<p>The administration won its biggest victory in June when the Supreme Court rejected a case brought by anti-abortion advocates seeking to roll back the Food and Drug Administration's approval of mifepristone, one of two medications used in the abortion pill regimen.</p>

<p>But the court dismissed on procedural grounds the administration's case arguing that Idaho's severe abortion ban conflicted with a federal law requiring medical providers to offer stabilizing emergency care, including abortions. In October, the court declined to hear a similar administration case about Texas' strict abortion ban.</p>

<p>While devoutly Catholic Biden was openly uncomfortable about abortion from early in his political career, mitigating the impacts of the dissolution of Roe v. Wade has become a pillar of his presidency.</p>

<p>Democrats more broadly made abortion rights central to their platform in the 2022 midterm elections. In March, Harris became the first sitting vice president or president to visit an abortion clinic.</p>

<p><strong>ECONOMY</strong></p>

<p>Joe Biden may go down in history as overseeing the best economy that everyone hated.</p>

<p>Since 2021, as the country emerged from a global pandemic that briefly created historic job losses and brought the economy to a near-standstill, employers have added nearly 16.5 million new jobs. The unemployment rate has averaged just 4.2%, including the longest run at 4% or below since the 1960s.</p>

<p>Gross domestic product growth has averaged 3.2% per quarter, well above what most economists view as the US economy's long-term potential. Incomes and wages have grown above trend. Collective US household net worth has climbed to a record $163.8 trillion, thanks to a booming stock market and rising home values.</p>

<p>But survey after survey over most of Biden's term has shown little of that registering with average Americans. Why? Because all of that occurred against the backdrop of the worst inflation breakout in a generation.</p>

<p>As the economy reopened, a mix of tangled supply chains, worker shortages and hot consumer demand, supported by roughly $5 trillion of government stimulus from Biden's and Trump's administrations, sent prices climbing - fast.</p>

<p>By the summer of 2022, the Consumer Price Index was rising by 9.1% year-over-year and the widely followed gauge of household satisfaction with the economy - the University of Michigan's Consumer Sentiment Index - tumbled to a record low.</p>

<p>While inflation has receded and sentiment has begun to recover, surveys show Americans still feel the sting of lingering high prices, and they blame Biden and Democrats for it.</p>

<p><strong>RACIAL JUSTICE</strong></p>

<p>On his first day in the White House, Biden signed an executive order aimed at addressing racism, police brutality, poverty and inequities impacting Black people and other communities of color.</p>

<p>But reform has been slow. The George Floyd Justice in Policing Act, introduced in 2021 to stop aggressive law enforcement tactics and racial bias, stalled in Congress.</p>

<p>In 2022, Biden issued an executive order directing the Department of Justice to create a national database of misconduct by federal law enforcement officers and requiring federal law enforcement agencies to investigate the use of deadly force or deaths in custody. It also restricted federal agencies from using chokeholds and "no knock" entries.</p>

<p>While Biden's Justice Department revived investigations into civil rights abuses, which had largely stopped under Trump, it has failed to secure a single binding settlement in the 12 investigations opened into possible police civil rights abuses since Biden took office.</p>

<p>On the economic front, Black unemployment fell to a historic low last year. This year alone, the administration directed $1.5 billion in loans to Black-owned businesses. It has also invested more than $16 billion in historically Black colleges and universities and distributed $2.2 billion to more than 43,000 Black and other farmers who experienced discrimination. Last year, the Biden administration allocated $470 million to improve maternal health.</p>

<p><strong>FOREIGN POLICY</strong></p>

<p>From wars in Ukraine and Gaza to civil bloodshed in Sudan, overseas conflicts have dominated Biden's foreign policy agenda.</p>

<p>Biden came to office promising to restore US global leadership in the world and determined to push back on an increasingly aggressive China.</p>

<p>In some ways, his administration has done just that. After the chaotic 2021 withdrawal of US troops from Afghanistan, Biden rallied US allies the following year to oppose Russia's invasion of Ukraine and has also revitalized alliances across Asia to pressure China's leadership.</p>

<p>But the US has struggled to bring the grinding conflicts to an end, and hasn't been able to prevent the deepening ties between Russia, China, Iran and North Korea.</p>

<p>Now in its third year, the war of attrition in Ukraine continues despite billions of dollars in US military aid and massive losses on both sides. The conflict is increasingly international, with Western accusations that Moscow is receiving weapons and soldiers from North Korea, missiles and drones from Iran and technical and other support from China.</p>

<p>The war between Israel and Palestinian militants in the Gaza Strip, which started when Hamas fighters staged a deadly attack into Israel, has metastasized into conflict between Israel and Lebanese militants Hezbollah and sparked reprisal attacks between Israel and Iran.</p>

<p>Biden's staunch support for Israel has divided his party and undercut the United States' ability to criticize others on human rights and violations of international law.</p>

<p>A conflict in Sudan has triggered ethnic violence and famine conditions in Sudan's Darfur region, where violence about 20 years ago led to the International Criminal Court charging former Sudanese leaders with genocide and crimes against humanity. The United States has been trying to help broker an end to the 18-month-long conflict.</p>

<p><strong>ENERGY TRANSITION</strong></p>

<p>Biden entered the White House with huge ambitions to fight climate change by transitioning the US economy away from fossil fuels to cleaner, renewable sources - all while creating new green, unionized jobs and re-shoring US manufacturing. Among his goals: put an end to federal oil and gas leasing, expand deployments of solar and wind energy to decarbonize the power grid, electrify the nation's vehicle fleet, and ultimately put the economy on a path to become carbon-neutral by 2050.</p>

<p>On the win side of the ledger, Biden signed into law three pieces of legislation that have driven a massive investment in the clean energy economy: the Inflation Reduction Act, the bipartisan infrastructure law and the CHIPS Act, which aims to establish a domestic semiconductor supply chain that could insulate the domestic energy sector from supply shocks.</p>

<p>Under the IRA, companies have invested hundreds of billions of dollars in new solar, wind, electric vehicles and infrastructure, battery storage and other climate-friendly projects that have sped up the energy transition and created jobs - largely in Republican states whose lawmakers did not support the legislation.</p>

<p>The administration has awarded $90 billion in grants to climate, clean energy, and other projects under the IRA, or about 70% of the law's climate-focused grant money, according to administration officials.</p>

<p>The Biden administration also expanded federal leasing for renewable energy projects, and passed new regulations to curb greenhouse gas emissions from vehicles, power plants and oil and gas operations.</p>

<p>On the loss side, his administration's attempts to end federal oil and gas leasing failed in the courts, and his policies failed to prevent a massive surge in US oil and gas output - mostly on privately owned lands in Texas and New Mexico - that has made the US the world's top petroleum producer.</p>

<p>And in perhaps the best litmus test of Biden's climate actions, projections from the Rhodium Group show US greenhouse gas admissions set to decline by 32-43% by 2030 under current policies, short of Biden's 50-52% goal.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/7nq7hpqo_us-election_625x300_05_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Overseas conflicts have overshadowed Joe Biden's presidency. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kim-kardashian-slammed-for-wearing-princess-dianas-200-000-cross-necklace-6949900]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kim Kardashian Slammed For Wearing Princess Diana's $200,000 Cross Necklace]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kim-kardashian-slammed-for-wearing-princess-dianas-200-000-cross-necklace-6949900]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 05 Nov 2024 18:09:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kim Kardashian's choice of a plunging neckline and the sacred symbolism of the Renaissance-style cross has sparked mixed reactions online]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kim Kardashian, the American media personality and socialite, is known for making bold statements by wearing iconic fashion artefacts. Over the years, she has worn pieces once owned by Marilyn Monroe, Janet Jackson, and Jackie Kennedy, among others. On Saturday, Ms Kardashian debuted another piece of cultural history: a diamond-studded cross pendant that was a favourite of Princess Diana. She wore the striking piece at the LACMA Art + Film Gala in Los Angeles.</p>

<p>Ms Kardashian acquired the pendant for approximately $212,000 in a Sotheby's auction in January 2023, securing it in the final moments of bidding. Her appearance at the event marked the first public outing of the necklace since Diana's passing in 1997.</p>

<p>The pendant, crafted by British court jewellers Garrard in the early 20th century, measures 5.4 inches by 3.7 inches, with approximately 5.25 carats of diamonds. In the 1980s, it was purchased by the late Palestinian-British businessman Naim Attallah, who loaned it to Diana several times- most famously for a 1987 charity gala where she paired the bold piece with a matching maroon velvet gown by Catherine Walker.</p>

<p>Ms Kardashian opted for a different styling, shortening the pearl chain and layering it with other jewellery, including a six-strand pearl choker. Rather than matching her outfit to the pendant's amethyst colour, she used it as a pop of colour against an all-white ensemble.</p>

<p>However, her choice of a plunging neckline and the sacred symbolism of the Renaissance-style cross has sparked mixed reactions online. Some feel the daring cut clashes with the religious nature of the piece, while others are concerned about Ms Kardashian's access to historical treasures and the risk of potential damage.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Kim Kardashian is facing backlash for wearing Princess Diana's $200K cross necklace for the first time ? <a href="https://t.co/h3byhMQJVn">pic.twitter.com/h3byhMQJVn</a></p>
— FearBuck (@FearedBuck) <a href="https://twitter.com/FearedBuck/status/1853419907997716506?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 4, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>"Why are we still giving this woman precious heirlooms like Diana's necklace after she broke Marilyn's dress," a user wrote on Instagram.</p>

<p>Another user wrote, "Kim Kardashian can't be compared with a single hair of Princess Diana. This is Class vs Trash."</p>

<p>"Just because you can buy something doesn't mean you should. Some items carry historical significance that money can't measure," the third user commented on X.&nbsp;<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/65nalk7g_kim-kardashian_625x300_05_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Ms Kardashian acquired the pendant for approximately $212,000 in a Sotheby's auction]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/last-set-of-disengagement-between-india-china-ended-oct-21-s-jaishankar-6949556]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Last Set Of Disengagement Between India, China Ended Oct 21: S Jaishankar]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/last-set-of-disengagement-between-india-china-ended-oct-21-s-jaishankar-6949556]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 05 Nov 2024 17:29:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India and China concluded the last lot of disengagement on October 21 and the implementation process is going on, External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar said on Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India and China concluded the last lot of disengagement on October 21 and the implementation process is going on, External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar said on Tuesday, while calling this a "positive development."</p>

<p>The Foreign Minister was holding a joint presser with his Australian Counterpart Penny Wong in Canberra.</p>

<p>Being asked about the recent disengagement between India and China, Jaishankar said, "On October 21st we concluded the last lot of disengagement agreements, we had done some earlier. These are currently in the process of being implemented. The last agreement was primarily around patrolling rights of the two sides. So we think all in all it's a positive development."</p>

<p>The EAM said that Prime Minister Modi and Chinese President Xi Jinping have agreed for meetings between the national security advisors and foreign ministers of the two countries.</p>

<p>"The fact that with that, once it's done the disengagement process is completed, we have other challenges to address including de-escalation of forces but at Kazan on the sidelines of the BRICS meeting Prime Minister Modi and President Xi had a meeting. It was agreed that the foreign ministers and the national security advisors would meet, so we will have to look at further building on this," he added.</p>

<p>PM Modi and Chinese President Xi held a bilateral meeting on the sidelines of the BRICS Summit in Kazan, Russia. Prime Minister Modi stated that ties between the two nations are important for the people of India and China and for regional and global peace and stability.</p>

<p>The sentiment was also reiterated by India's Defence Minister Rajnath Singh, who last week said, "At some areas along the LAC, discussions have been ongoing between India and China at both diplomatic and military levels to resolve conflicts. Following recent talks, there has been a broad consensus to restore the ground situation. This consensus has developed on the basis of equal and mutual security. The agreement includes rights related to patrolling and grazing in traditional areas".</p>

<p>He added, "Based on this consensus, the disengagement process is nearly complete. We will strive to move beyond just disengagement, but for that, we will need to wait a little longer."</p>

<p>This came after both India and China confirmed that an agreement had been reached between the two nations regarding patrolling arrangements along the Line of Actual Control (LAC) in the India-China border areas.</p>

<p>The border standoff between India and China began in eastern Ladakh along the LAC in 2020, sparked by Chinese military actions. This incident led to prolonged tensions between the two nations, significantly straining their relations.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Spokesperson of MFA: The Chinese and Indian troops are implementing the resolutions that the two sides reached on issues concerning the border area, which is going smoothly at the moment. <a href="https://t.co/iB7mWPQUfs">pic.twitter.com/iB7mWPQUfs</a></p>
— Yu Jing (@ChinaSpox_India) <a href="https://twitter.com/ChinaSpox_India/status/1853689080099344881?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 5, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Earlier in the day, the spokesperson of the Chinese Embassy in India announced on the social media platform, X, "The Chinese and Indian troops are implementing the resolutions that the two sides reached on issues concerning the border area, which is going smoothly at the moment".</p>

<p>Chinese Ambassador to India Xu Feihong had also earlier said that he hoped the bilateral ties would move forward smoothly and ties between both countries would not be restricted or interrupted by specific disagreements.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/i29d7k4_s-jaishankar_625x300_03_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[EAM Jaishankar was holding a joint presser with Penny Wong in Canberra. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/key-counties-in-battleground-states-to-watch-in-us-election-6949431]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Key Counties In Battleground States To Watch In US Election]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/key-counties-in-battleground-states-to-watch-in-us-election-6949431]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 05 Nov 2024 17:15:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Seven battleground states are expected to play a decisive role in Tuesday's US presidential election between Democrat Kamala Harris or Republican Donald Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Seven battleground states -- Arizona, Georgia, Michigan, Nevada, North Carolina, Pennsylvania and Wisconsin -- are expected to play a decisive role in Tuesday's US presidential election between Democrat Kamala Harris or Republican Donald Trump.</p>

<p>Here are ten counties to watch in those states. Early results based on partial returns may not be predictive of the final vote tallies in the counties.</p>

<p>MARICOPA COUNTY, ARIZONA</p>

<p>Home to Phoenix, Maricopa County, Arizona, is key to winning the southwestern state as it makes up about 60% of the statewide vote. In the 2020 election, President Biden won this county by 2.2 percentage points while former President Donald Trump won the county by almost 3 percentage points in 2016.</p>

<p>COBB COUNTY, GEORGIA</p>

<p>Large and racially diverse Cobb County in Atlanta's northern suburbs is a spot Democrats could pick up the large number of votes needed to win the state, as Democratic President Joe Biden did in 2020 when he won the county by about 14 percentage points. In 2016, Democratic candidate Hillary Clinton carried Cobb county by just 2 percentage points and lost the state to Trump.</p>

<p>BALDWIN COUNTY, GEORGIA</p>

<p>In central Georgia, Baldwin County is much smaller than Cobb but an indicator of Black voter turnout, as about 40% of voters in this county are Black. This is one place in Georgia where Biden's 2020 margin was narrower than Clinton's in 2016.</p>

<p>WAYNE COUNTY, MICHIGAN</p>

<p>Home to Detroit's 1.7 million residents, Wayne County, Michigan, is about 40% Black. Biden in 2020 won this county with more than 68% of the vote, helping him clinch the state.</p>

<p>WASHOE COUNTY, NEVADA</p>

<p>In the northwest corner of Nevada around Reno, Washoe County is less racially diverse than the Las Vegas area, but has been trending more Democratic in recent elections. Biden won this county by more than 4 percentage points in 2020 over Trump.</p>

<p>WAKE COUNTY, NORTH CAROLINA</p>

<p>The city of Raleigh in Wake County, North Carolina, has boosted statewide turnout for Democrats in recent elections, as was the case when Biden in 2020 won 65% of the vote in the area. That was not enough to keep Trump from carrying the state in 2020.</p>

<p>ERIE COUNTY, PENNSYLVANIA</p>

<p>Erie County in northwest Pennsylvania has voted for the winning presidential candidate in the last four elections, including Biden in 2020 when he won the county by 1 percentage point. In 2016, Trump won this county by 2 percentage points.</p>

<p>BUCKS COUNTY, PENNSYLVANIA</p>

<p>North of Philadelphia, Bucks County, Pennsylvania, is another highly competitive county due to its large population of working class voters -- a demographic group where Trump has made major inroads in his eight years on the national political stage. Trump is looking to win back the state -- as he did in 2016 -- but Biden won this county in 2020 by 4 percentage points, which helped him clinch the state.</p>

<p>CUMBERLAND COUNTY, PENNSYLVANIA</p>

<p>The suburbs of Harrisburg, Pennsylvania's capital, have supported Trump in the last two elections. But Democrats could cut those gains in Cumberland County by attracting the area's growing population of white collar workers. In 2020, Trump won this county by 11 percentage points.</p>

<p>WAUKESHA COUNTY, WISCONSIN</p>

<p>The populous western suburbs of Milwaukee, Wisconsin, have been another stronghold for Trump in his past two campaigns and the Republican won Waukesha County by more than 20 percentage points each time. Voters here will need to vote for Trump again at similar levels in order for Republicans to win back the state that Biden carried in 2020.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/vrolrrl_us-voting_625x300_05_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Voting booth on Election Day for the 2024 US Presidential Election in New York. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-launches-55-satellites-including-2-private-iranian-device-into-orbit-6949339]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russia Launches 55 Satellites, Including 2 Iranian Devices Into Orbit]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-launches-55-satellites-including-2-private-iranian-device-into-orbit-6949339]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 05 Nov 2024 17:05:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russia launched 55 satellites into orbit on Tuesday, including two privately built Iranian devices, amid deepening ties between Moscow and Tehran.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russia launched 55 satellites into orbit on Tuesday, including two privately built Iranian devices, amid deepening ties between Moscow and Tehran.</p>

<p>A Soyuz rocket blasted off from the Vostochny Cosmodrome in Russia's Far East at 02:18 Moscow time (2318 GMT on Monday) carrying the satellites, Russia's Roscosmos space agency said.</p>

<p>In total, Roscosmos said 51 Russian satellites, one Russian-Chinese device and a Russian-Zimbabwean satellite were put into orbit, as well as the two Iranian satellites.</p>

<p>It said it was a "record number of Russian satellites simultaneously put into orbit."</p>

<p>The two Iranian imaging and communications satellites -- Koswar and Hodhod -- were designed and built by Iran's Omid Faza Company, and are aimed to support environmental monitoring and communications in remote areas.</p>

<p>Tehran said it was the first time Russia had launched privately built Iranian satellites.</p>

<p>The two countries have deepened political, economic and military ties amid Russia's offensive in Ukraine and the war in the Middle East, raising concerns in the West.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/acn0u3h_satellite-generic_625x300_07_April_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[In total 51 Russian satellites were put into the orbit. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-introduces-law-to-create-first-smoke-free-generation-6949261]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK Introduces Law To Create First "Smoke-Free Generation"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-introduces-law-to-create-first-smoke-free-generation-6949261]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 05 Nov 2024 16:57:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A new UK-wide law aimed at creating the first "smoke-free generation" will on Tuesday be introduced in parliament, as part of a world-leading ban.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A new UK-wide law aimed at creating the first "smoke-free generation" will on Tuesday be introduced in parliament, as part of a world-leading ban.</p>

<p>The proposals come after New Zealand revoked plans to introduce a so-called "generational smoking ban" that would have stopped sales of tobacco to anyone born after 2008.</p>

<p>"This is a groundbreaking piece of public health legislation. It will mean that we are creating the first ever smoke-free generation in our country. So children growing up in our country today will never, never legally be able to buy cigarettes," said Health Secretary Wes Streeting.</p>

<p>The UK's Tobacco and Vapes Bill will prevent anyone born after January 1 2009 from legally smoking by gradually raising the age at which tobacco can be bought.</p>

<p>The legislation is similar to a bill proposed by the last Conservative administration, which was shelved earlier this year when prime minister Rishi Sunak called a general election.</p>

<p>Sunak's successor Keir Starmer's new Labour government, however, has revived the proposals, which are part of a drive to increase preventative health measures and ease long-term pressure on the UK's state-funded National Health Service (NHS).</p>

<p>The bill will introduce restrictions on vape advertising and sponsorship, as well as restricting flavours, displays and the packaging of e-cigarettes to reduce their appeal to children and young people.</p>

<p>Last month the government announced that disposable vapes will be banned next year under separate legislation.</p>

<p><strong>Outdoor spaces</strong></p>

<p>New Zealand last November announced it would bin its own proposed anti-smoking legislation.</p>

<p>Under a law that had been due to come into force later that year anyone born after 2008 would have been prevented from buying tobacco.</p>

<p>The back pedalling came after new premier Christopher Luxon took the helm as head of a new coalition government and said he would prioritise tackling inflation and lowering interest rates.</p>

<p>The new UK bill also proposes extending existing smoking bans to outdoor spaces such as children's playgrounds and outside hospitals.</p>

<p>But Streeting said there would be no ban on smoking in pub gardens in England.</p>

<p>Pub and restaurant industry figures criticised the idea after it was leaked in August, arguing it could deter customers in a market already struggling with the long-term fallout from the pandemic and cost-of-living pressures.</p>

<p>"The UK hospitality sector has taken a battering in recent years, and we don't want to add to their pressure so we're not proposing to go ahead with an outdoor hospitality ban at this time," Streeting added.</p>

<p>England, Wales and Northern Ireland outlawed smoking in enclosed public places and workplaces in 2007 following a similar ban in Scotland in 2006.</p>

<p>The Action on Smoking and Health charity has said there was a 2.4-percent reduction in hospital admissions for heart attacks in England a year after the ban, saving the state-funded National Health Service (NHS) millions of pounds.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-11/46vcvfcg_vape-reuters_625x300_28_November_23.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[UK's Tobacco and Vapes Bill will prevent anyone born after 2009 from legally smoking. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-how-democrats-moved-from-supporting-slavery-to-backing-kamala-harris-6949195]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Once Pro-Slavery, Democratic Party Now Champions Kamala Harris]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-how-democrats-moved-from-supporting-slavery-to-backing-kamala-harris-6949195]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 05 Nov 2024 16:48:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Founded by Thomas Jefferson, the Democratic Party is the oldest political party in the US.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Democratic Party, once a defender of slavery, has transformed into a force for diversity and progressive politics in the United States. Now, with Kamala Harris, the first Black and Asian American woman running for President in the US Elections, the shift is clear. Despite this new direction, the party remains tied to its complex past, which included supporting policies that contradicted the ideals of freedom and equality it advocates today.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Founded by Thomas Jefferson, the Democratic Party (Democratic-Republican Party) is the oldest political party in the US. Initially rooted in agrarian ideals and a defence of states' rights, it attracted support from rural Americans, particularly in the South.&nbsp;</p>

<p>By the early 1800s, the party became a champion for ordinary citizens, yet also found itself at odds over slavery, leading to divisions that later gave rise to the Republican Party.&nbsp;</p>

<p>As the nation expanded, so did the debate over slavery. The Democratic Party, by its 1852 convention in Baltimore, officially pledged to maintain the institution, refusing compromise. This stance alienated many, who left to join the fledgling Republican Party, founded on principles of abolition and individual freedom. This split foreshadowed a century of political rivalry, where the Republicans and Democrats would shape American politics by representing contrasting visions of governance.</p>

<p>The Democratic Party redefined itself in the early 20th century under President Woodrow Wilson, who advocated progressive reforms including labour rights and women's suffrage. The Great Depression further reshaped American politics. Franklin D. Roosevelt's New Deal, a series of government programmes designed to revitalise the economy, won over a broad coalition, including African Americans, labour unions, and immigrant groups. This shift helped the Democrats solidify support among working-class Americans and minorities.</p>

<p>By the 1950s and 1960s, the Democratic Party underwent another transformation. With leaders like President John F. Kennedy and Lyndon B. Johnson advocating for civil rights, the party gained significant African-American support. In contrast, Southern conservatives began aligning more with Republicans, who appealed to their values of limited government and opposition to civil rights legislation.</p>

<p>Today, the Democratic Party promotes social equality, advocating for voting rights, LGBTQ+ rights, and reproductive choice. It supports immigration reforms that create pathways to citizenship and family reunification. The party's stance on gun control, shaped by tragedies and increasing public concern, has led to legislation like the Gun Control Act of 1968 and the Brady Bill.</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/io2k2jk8_kamala-harris-_625x300_05_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[If Kamala Harris wins, she will be the first woman president in the US' history]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/voting-begins-in-the-us-america-chooses-between-kamala-harris-and-donald-trump-6949183]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Harris Or Trump: US Votes In Extraordinary Presidential Election]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/voting-begins-in-the-us-america-chooses-between-kamala-harris-and-donald-trump-6949183]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 05 Nov 2024 16:45:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Voting for the 2024 US Presidential election has begun in the eastern time zone in America. New Hampshire is the first state where the polling started at 6 am local time (4:30 pm IST).]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Voting for the 2024 US Presidential election began with the eastern time zone in America. New Hampshire was the first state where polling started.&nbsp;Dixville Notch, a small town in the state of New Hampshire became the first place in the country where voters cast their ballot.</p>

<p>Voting across the country begins at 6 am local time. Since the US is divided in different time zones, the eastern part of the country sees polling first. At 6 am local time (4:30 pm India time), eight states which fall in the Eastern Time zone or ET, began polling. These include the states of Connecticut, New Jersey, New York, New Hampshire and Virginia.</p>

<p>Tens of millions of voters across the United States have already cast their vote early. These votes were sent in either by mail or by visiting the polling station in person. According to data from the University of Florida's Election Lab more than 82 million voters across the US had already voted before the main election day.</p>

<p>This is the final opportunity for Americans to vote in the tightly contested 2024 presidential race between Republican Donald Trump and Democrat Kamala Harris hurtled toward an uncertain finish.</p>

<p>The bitterly contested election campaign witnessed two assassination attempts against Trump, President Joe Biden's surprise withdrawal and Harris' rapid rise - remained too close to call, even after billions of dollars in spending and months of frenetic campaigning.</p>

<p>The candidates were running neck and neck in the campaign's final days in each of the seven states likely to determine the winner - Arizona, Georgia, Michigan, Nevada, North Carolina, Pennsylvania and Wisconsin - showed opinion polls.</p>

<p>The winner may not be known for days if the margins in the key states remain as slim as they are expected.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/h6f1vgsg_harris-trump-split_625x300_10_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Americans citizens are voting to decide who will be the next US President - Harris or Trump]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>