<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Thu, 04 Jul 2024 21:31:44 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-woman-murdered-parents-lived-with-their-dead-bodies-for-several-years-6034977]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK Woman Murdered Parents, Lived With Their Dead Bodies For Several Years]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-woman-murdered-parents-lived-with-their-dead-bodies-for-several-years-6034977]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 04 Jul 2024 21:21:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The woman lied to the doctors and relatives that her parents were unwell, on holiday or on vacation to cover her tracks.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A woman from the United Kingdom pleaded guilty to murdering her parents and living in their home for several years after, as per a report in the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/crime/virginia-mccullough-murder-parents-chelmsford-b2573910.html"><em>Independent</em></a>. Virginia McCullough, 36, entered a guilty plea to the murders of Lois McCullough, aged 71, and John McCullough, aged 70, between June 17 and June 20, 2019, during her appearance via prison video call at Chelmsford Crown Court on Thursday. She hid their bodies inside the house and kept residing at that location.</p>

<p>The woman lied to the doctors and relatives that her parents were unwell, on holiday or on vacation to cover her tracks. Her actions came to light on September 15, 2023, when Essex police executed a warrant at the Pump Hill residence after her parents' doctors expressed concerns about missing visits. At that point, the 36-year-old admitted to stabbing her mother and poisoning her father with prescription drugs, according to the cops.</p>

<p>McCullough confirmed her identity, entered guilty pleas to both counts and stated that she understood the judge's remarks. She will be sentenced on October 10 and 11.</p>

<p>As per the outlet, Judge Christopher Morgan said, "You will understand that there is a single sentence that can be passed upon you in these circumstances. Consideration however has to be given to the minimum term."</p>

<p>Meanwhile, people living around the neighbourhood described the woman as "quite chatty" and a "little bit odd", according to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/article/2024/jul/04/woman-virginia-mccullough-pleads-guilty-murdering-parents-family-home-essex"><em>The Guardian</em></a>. Dave Oldershaw, a neighbour, said McCullough was "carrying on, going up to the Chinese (takeaway) like nothing has happened". He "thought she lived on her own" at the house and stated that he "only knew her to say hello to - she wasn't trouble."</p>

<p>A worker at a nearby shop said the woman had told him her parents had moved to be by the seaside. He said he had not seen them since the Covid-19 pandemic but would previously "see them two or three times per week".</p>

<p>According to the employee, McCullough appeared "a little bit odd sometimes." "She would come in and go 'do you want a coffee' then five minutes later, there would be a coffee sitting there," the worker continued.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/k2l02g1o_earplifting_625x300_04_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[She will be sentenced on October 10 and 11.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/french-far-right-may-fall-short-of-absolute-majority-opinion-poll-shows-6034933]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[French Far Right May Fall Short Of Absolute Majority, Opinion Poll Shows]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/french-far-right-may-fall-short-of-absolute-majority-opinion-poll-shows-6034933]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 04 Jul 2024 21:15:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[France's far-right National Rally (RN) party is expected to fall short of an absolute majority in the second round of parliamentary elections on Sunday, an opinion poll showed on Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>France's far-right National Rally (RN) party is expected to fall short of an absolute majority in the second round of parliamentary elections on Sunday, an opinion poll showed on Thursday.</p>

<p>It was the second survey in as many days to show Marine Le Pen's RN winning more seats than any other party - but also missing the 289 threshold required for an absolute majority.</p>

<p>This suggested that a "republican front," by which more than 200 candidates across the political spectrum pulled out of three-way second rounds to clear the path for whoever was best placed to defeat the RN runner in their district, seemed to be working.</p>

<p>The IFOP poll for LCI and Le Figaro showed the RN winning 210 to 240 seats, down from 240-270 before the withdrawals.</p>

<p>The leftist New Popular Front was seen in second place, with 170 to 200 seats, ahead of President Emmanuel Macron's centrist Together group with 95 to 125 seats. The conservative Republicans were forecast to win 25 to 45 seats.</p>

<p>On Wednesday, a Harris Interactive poll forecast 190 to 220 seats for the RN.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-04/cp6v7gqo_marine-le-pen-france-afp-650_625x300_07_April_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/make-in-india-initiative-can-add-to-engines-of-global-growth-pm-narendra-modi-at-sco-summit-6034611]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Make In India Can Add To Engines Of Global Growth": PM Modi At SCO Summit]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/make-in-india-initiative-can-add-to-engines-of-global-growth-pm-narendra-modi-at-sco-summit-6034611]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 04 Jul 2024 20:32:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Narendra Modi on Thursday said the 'Make in India' initiative can add to engines of global growth and help democratise the global economy, and highlighted the importance of creating multiple, reliable and resilient supply chains.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi on Thursday said the 'Make in India' initiative can add to engines of global growth and help democratise the global economy, and highlighted the importance of creating multiple, reliable and resilient supply chains.</p>

<p>External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar, who is in Astana to attend the SCO Summit, delivered PM Modi's remarks at the extended format meeting of the Shanghai Cooperation Organisation (SCO) Council of Heads of State here in the Kazakh capital.</p>

<p>PM Modi said that India has contributed significantly to enhancing the economic agenda of the SCO grouping with institutionalised mechanisms such as the SCO Startup Forum and Special Working Group on Startup and Innovation.</p>

<p>With 130,000 startups in India, including 100 unicorns, our experience can be useful to others, a Ministry of External Affairs statement cited the prime minister as saying in his remarks.</p>

<p>"When it comes to geo-economics, the need of the day is to create multiple, reliable and resilient supply chains. This is an important takeaway from the Covid experience. 'Make in India' can add to engines of global growth and help democratise the global economy. India is open to partnering with others in capacity building, especially nations of the Global South," the statement said.</p>

<p>The prime minister said technology not only held great promise in his times but was increasingly a game changer in both development and security. "The digital era needs more trust and transparency. AI and Cyber security raise crucial issues of their own," he said.</p>

<p>"When it comes to medical and wellness tourism, you may be aware that World Health Organisation has set up a Global Centre for Traditional Medicine in Gujarat. In SCO, India has taken the initiative for a new SCO Working Group on Traditional Medicine," the prime minister said.</p>

<p>"Enhancing education, training, and capacity-building are key pillars of India's international cooperation. We are committed to further building on them, be it with the C5 partners, or those of 'Neighbourhood First' or the extended neighbourhood." "India has shown that digital public infrastructure and digital financial inclusion can make such a huge difference. Both were discussed during our SCO Presidency. They also expand the scope for international cooperation, involving SCO members and partners," he said.</p>

<p>"While standing resolute on challenges, it is equally important to actively and collaboratively explore avenues of progress. The current global debate is focused on creating the new connectivity linkages that would better serve a rebalanced world," he said.</p>

<p>"If this is to gather serious momentum, it requires the joint efforts of many. It must also be respectful of the sovereignty and territorial integrity of states and be built on the foundation of non-discriminatory trade and transit rights to neighbours," he said, in a veiled jibe at China, whose President Xi Jinping was present at the summit.</p>

<p>China has invested billions in various power projects and road networks in Pakistan under the USD 65 billion China-Pakistan Economic Corridor (CPEC) project.</p>

<p>The CPEC is opposed by India as it is being laid through Pakistan-occupied Kashmir (PoK).</p>

<p>For the SCO extended family, "we flag the progress made on Chabahar port recently through a long-term agreement between India and Iran. This not only holds great value to landlocked Central Asian states but also de-risks commerce between India and Eurasia," Modi said.</p>

<p>India and Iran in May signed a 10-year contract for the operation of a terminal at the strategically important Chabahar port in Iran, a move that will boost regional connectivity as well as trade ties.</p>

<p>This is the first time India will take over the management of an overseas port that will also have a multiplier effect on trade among India, Iran and Afghanistan as efforts continue to directly tap the potential in Central Asia, bypassing neighbouring Pakistan.</p>

<p>Talking about Afghanistan, PM Modi said India and its people have a historical relationship with Afghanistan that is the bedrock of the ties between the two countries. "Our cooperation covers development projects, humanitarian assistance, capacity building and sports. India remains sensitive to the needs and aspirations of the Afghan people," Modi said.</p>

<p>The prime minister also touched upon granting English the status of a third official language, which he said was crucial as more countries sought association with SCO as Observers or Dialogue Partners.</p>

<p>"We must strive to communicate better and deepen our consensus." Congratulating the Kazakh side for hosting a successful summit, Modi said India as a 'Vishwa Bandhu', or the friend of the world will always strive to deepen cooperation with all its partners.</p>

<p>The prime minister also extended its best wishes to the success of the upcoming Chinese presidency of SCO.</p>

<p>India became a member of SCO in June 2017 at a summit in Kazakhstan.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ocsk6acg_pm-modi_625x300_04_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["If this is to gather serious momentum, it requires the joint efforts of many."]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/vladimir-putin-says-taliban-russias-allies-in-fighting-terrorism-6034602]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Vladimir Putin Says Taliban Russia's "Allies" In Fighting Terrorism]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/vladimir-putin-says-taliban-russias-allies-in-fighting-terrorism-6034602]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 04 Jul 2024 20:31:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russian President Vladimir Putin said Thursday that the Taliban, a banned group in Russia, are Moscow's "allies" in fighting terrorism because they are in control of Afghanistan.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russian President Vladimir Putin said Thursday that the Taliban, a banned group in Russia, are Moscow's "allies" in fighting terrorism because they are in control of Afghanistan.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Moscow has for years fostered relations with the Taliban, despite being a banned organisation in Russia since 2003, and Putin last month called for Moscow to "build up" relations with the Taliban government.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"We must assume that the Taliban control the power in the country. And in this sense the Taliban are, of course, our allies in the fight against terrorism, because any authorities are interested in stability in the state they govern," Putin said in Astana. &nbsp;</p>

<p>The Taliban have been fighting against jihadist rival Islamic State Khorasan (IS-K) in Afghanistan for years.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In March, IS-K fighters killed more than 140 people in an assault on a Moscow concert hall, the deadliest terror attack in Russia for almost two decades.</p>

<p>Since taking over Afghanistan in 2021, the Taliban have enforced an extreme form of Islamic law that effectively bans women from public life. &nbsp;</p>

<p>Putin said that the Taliban have "taken on some responsibilities" but that there are still "issues that need constant attention inside the country and from the international community".&nbsp;</p>

<p>"I am sure that the Taliban are interested in everything being stable in Afghanistan," he added.</p>

<p>Moscow has warmed relations with Afghanistan -- with which it has a complicated history after the Soviet invasion in the 1980s -- since the US exit from the country.&nbsp;</p>

<p>But it has fallen short of officially recognising the Taliban government and what it calls the "Islamic Emirate of Afghanistan".<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/n5pp894_vladimir-putin_625x300_14_June_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["I am sure that the Taliban are interested in everything being stable in Afghanistan," he added (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-targets-kamala-harris-says-she-is-so-pathetic-6034409]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["So Bad, Pathetic": Trump Targets Kamala Harris Amid Biden Replacement Buzz]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-targets-kamala-harris-says-she-is-so-pathetic-6034409]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 04 Jul 2024 20:07:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Mr Trump also questioned Mr Biden's ability to deal with foreign adversaries, including Russia's President Vladimir Putin and China's President Xi Jinping]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump's campaign and some of his supporters have launched a pre-emptive political offensive on US Vice President Kamala Harris, moving to discredit her amid speculation among some of her fellow Democrats that she may replace President Joe Biden atop the party's 2024 presidential candidate. Amid this, a clip of Mr Trump attacking Ms Harris and calling her "pathetic" has emerged on social media.</p>

<p>In the video, Mr Trump, sitting in a golf cart, holding a pile of cash, and with his son Barron said that Joe Biden is withdrawing from the race due to his performance in the June 27 debate. The 78-year-old asked, "How did I do with the debate the other night?"</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Donald Trump claimed he got President Biden out of the race and called him “an old broken down pile of crap” on top of calling Kamala Harris “pathetic.”<br />
<br />
Super rich coming from a guy who just begged strangers for praise.<br />
<br />
He then praised dictators while Barron sat there like a… <a href="https://t.co/79oARteOih">pic.twitter.com/79oARteOih</a></p>
— Art Candee ?? (@ArtCandee) <a href="https://twitter.com/ArtCandee/status/1808681042192310762?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 4, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Talking about President Biden, he said, "He just quit, you know - he's quitting the race. I got him out of the - and that means we have Kamala." Mr Trump stated that he thinks that "she's gonna be better" candidate than the 81-year-old, who he described as an "old, broken-down pile of crap."</p>

<p>"She's so bad. She's so pathetic. She's so f****** bad," he continued.</p>

<p>Mr Trump also questioned Mr Biden's ability to deal with foreign adversaries, including Russia's President Vladimir Putin and China's President Xi Jinping. He said in the now-viral footage, "Can you imagine that guy dealing with Putin? And the president of China - who's a fierce person. He's a fierce man, very tough guy. And they see him."</p>

<p>Towards the end of the clip, the former President added, "But they just announced he's probably quitting."</p>

<p>Meanwhile, White House spokeswoman Karine Jean-Pierre rejected rumours and said that he is "absolutely not" pulling out of the presidential race and has <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-absolutely-not-pulling-of-us-presidential-race-says-white-house-6032827">no intention of withdrawing</a>. "The president is clear-eyed and he is staying in the race," she told reporters.</p>

<p>Mr Biden told a call with campaign and party staffers that he is going nowhere, as per a report in news agency AFP. "I'm in this race to the end and we're going to win because when Democrats unite, we will always win. Just as we beat Donald Trump in 2020, we're going to beat him again in 2024," he said, according to a source close to the campaign. He repeated that message in an emergency meeting with Democratic governors, who pledged their continued support, attendees said afterwards.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/qqdlqmm_donald-trump_625x300_04_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["She's so bad. She's so pathetic," the 78-year-old said.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/man-in-us-left-with-stinger-in-eye-after-bee-attack-6034391]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Man In US Left With Stinger In Eye After Bee Attack]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/man-in-us-left-with-stinger-in-eye-after-bee-attack-6034391]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 04 Jul 2024 20:05:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The sting was found stabbed in his cornea, a key part of the eye that performs the initial refraction onto the lens, which further focuses the light onto the retina.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A man in the US was found to have been stung by a bee, in one of the most unfortunate spots - in his eye. And the bee stinger was found stuck in his right eye. According to a case study, published in <a href="https://www.nejm.org/doi/full/10.1056/NEJMicm2400652">The New England Journal of Medicine</a>, the 55-year-old man from Philadelphia went to a local eye hospital complaining of "worsening vision and pain in his right eye". The man first went to the emergency department of a local hospital on the day of the sting, but the staff was unsuccessful in removing the bee sting entirely.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/bee-sting-man-eye-hospital-1920809">As per <em>Newsweek</em></a>, the man's vision and pain worsened dramatically, and the iris began to bleed. The man was not able to see at all from the injured eye, which prompted him to visit the ophthalmologic clinic.</p>

<p>"A man suffered a bee sting directly to his eye, resulting in an intense ocular inflammatory response which affected his vision," Wills Eye Hospital ophthalmologist Talia Shoshany told the outlet. "The patient reports walking by a bee hive at work and being stung. He was not otherwise tending to the bees."</p>

<p>The sting was found stabbed in his cornea, a key part of the eye that performs the initial refraction onto the lens, which further focuses the light onto the retina.</p>

<p>"On physical examination at the current presentation, vision in the right eye was limited to counting fingers," the doctors wrote in the paper.</p>

<p>It "showed conjunctival injection, inferior corneal edema [swelling of the cornea], and an infiltrate [collection of inflammatory cells] at the nasal limbus [region of the cornea] with a piece of retained stinger. A hyphema [blood collecting within the eye] which was attributed to iris trauma from the buried stinger and bleeding iris vessels, was also observed", the study further said.</p>

<p>The doctors removed the stinger fragment from his eye using hyper-precise tweezers.</p>

<p>Sting from a bee is extremely painful as it injects venom through its stinger into the skin. The venom contains proteins that affect skin cells and the immune system, leading to pain and swelling around the sting site.</p>

<p>"He improved with steroid and antibiotic drops, although eventually required both cataract surgery and a corneal transplant from the sequelae of the topical steroids and the toxic effect of the venom on the cornea. The patient fully recovered his vision after several months of treatment," Dr Shoshany said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/knpuuj08_bee-stinger-in-eye-1200_625x300_04_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The doctors removed the stinger fragment using hyper-precise tweezers.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russian-pranksters-who-target-western-politicians-get-state-award-report-6034260]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russian Pranksters Who Target Western Politicians Get State Award: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russian-pranksters-who-target-western-politicians-get-state-award-report-6034260]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 04 Jul 2024 19:43:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A duo of Russian pranksters who often target and compromise people the Russian state is interested in have been given a top state award in the Kremlin, the RIA state news agency reported on Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A duo of Russian pranksters who often target and compromise people the Russian state is interested in have been given a top state award in the Kremlin, the RIA state news agency reported on Thursday.</p>

<p>RIA published a picture of the two pranksters Vladimir Kuznetsov and Alexei Stolyarov, who use the aliases "Vovan and Lexus," at a Kremlin award ceremony wearing what appear to be Order of Friendship awards as they clutched flutes of champagne.</p>

<p>It said the ceremony had taken place on Wednesday.</p>

<p>The award is given to Russian and foreign nationals for strengthening peace, friendship, cooperation and understanding between Russia and other nations, among other criteria.</p>

<p>There was no immediate word from the Russian pranksters who last month released footage of a video call they did with British Foreign Secretary David Cameron after tricking him into thinking he was speaking to a former Ukrainian president.</p>

<p>The duo is well-known inside Russia having duped a string of politicians over the years, including Italian Prime Minister Giorgia Meloni, Turkish President Recep Tayyip Erdogan, and, in 2022, Britain's then-defence minister, Ben Wallace.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/4auj7je_russian-pranksters_625x300_04_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Vladimir Kuznetsov (R) and Alexei Stolyarov (L)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/political-policy-debates-silenced-for-poll-day-as-uk-votes-in-historic-election-6034249]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Political Debates Silenced For Poll Day As UK Votes In Historic Election]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/political-policy-debates-silenced-for-poll-day-as-uk-votes-in-historic-election-6034249]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 04 Jul 2024 19:41:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The UK is voting in a landmark general election on Thursday, with an estimated 46 million registered voters set to make their ballot count at 40,000 polling stations across the country where any discussion or analysis of political issues remains]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The UK is voting in a landmark general election on Thursday, with an estimated 46 million registered voters set to make their ballot count at 40,000 polling stations across the country where any discussion or analysis of political issues remains silenced on the polling day.</p>

<p>On polling day, the UK's Office of Communications (Ofcom) media watchdog rules mean all political and policy debates should be wrapped up before 7 am local time when the polling booths open. From then on, any discussion or analysis of political issues is silenced until 10 pm local time, when the customary election night exit poll results are beamed around the world.</p>

<p>"Discussion and analysis of election and referendum issues must finish when the poll opens," reads the Ofcom guidelines under Section 6 of its code.</p>

<p>"Broadcasters may not publish the results of any opinion poll on polling day itself until the election or referendum poll closes," it adds.</p>

<p>The rules are intended to prevent any influence over how people choose to vote on election day, though many would have already made their choice through a postal ballot.</p>

<p>The coverage rules for polling day have meant that images of dogs waiting for their owners outside polling stations become the highlight of election day coverage, symbolic of the long wait ahead before the first results start pouring in close to midnight local time.</p>

<p>Thursdays are the designated polling day for all British elections, a tradition that dates back to the 19th century because Fridays being payday for workers historically meant a weekend election would suppress turnout as they would be more inclined to choose the pub over a polling booth.</p>

<p>Thursday, therefore, is seen as the calm before the proverbial storm during a UK general election, followed by frenetic activity as the final outcome after all the votes have been counted expected by around 10 am (local time) on Friday.</p>

<p>The choreography for the day after polling day is very finely tuned, with the losing party leader making his way to Buckingham Palace to officially concede defeat. This is followed soon after by the winner meeting the British monarch, who formally asks them to form a new government.</p>

<p>In the case of a hung Parliament, this smooth schedule takes a hit while some hectic horse-trading takes place behind the scenes. However, if the opinion polls are even close to predicting the final outcome this time, the winning party is expected to be handed a clear majority.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/jjcg5slg_uk-election_625x300_03_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["Broadcasters may not publish the results of any opinion poll on polling day itself."]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-election-brings-few-hopes-or-fears-to-cautious-city-of-london-6034139]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK Election Brings Few Hopes Or Fears To Cautious City Of London]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-election-brings-few-hopes-or-fears-to-cautious-city-of-london-6034139]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 04 Jul 2024 19:28:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The UK financial sector is warming to Labour's pro-business overtures and pledges to provide stability and support, but many in the City remain wary it could be targeted to prop up Britain's stretched public finances further down the line.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The UK financial sector is warming to Labour's pro-business overtures and pledges to provide stability and support, but many in the City remain wary it could be targeted to prop up Britain's stretched public finances further down the line.</p>

<p>Under leader Keir Starmer, the Labour Party - expected to win Thursday's UK election - has assiduously courted the City of London, mindful that his plans for boosting economic growth will need a big dose of private capital.</p>

<p>In the last election in 2019, Starmer's predecessor Jeremy Corbyn set out a radical manifesto to increase public investment by raising taxes on companies and top earners, resulting in Labour's worst result since the 1930s.</p>

<p>"The most important change is that there has been a big shift in mindset by Labour towards the City in the past few years," William Wright, managing director of think-tank New Financial told Reuters.</p>

<p>"That is reflected in a strong sense of continuity in the reforms to capital markets and pensions underway," Wright said.</p>

<p>Labour, whose Rachel Reeves, a former economist at the Bank of England, is expected to become Britain's finance minister, has backed the Conservative government's post-Brexit 'Edinburgh Reforms' aimed at protecting the City's global competitiveness.</p>

<p>The party has also promised a review of the pensions and savings industry, which could help Britain's capital markets as well as boosting the financial resilience of the population.</p>

<p>But there is also speculation about changes to how capital gains and wealth are taxed, as well as Reeves' plans to change the way private equity is taxed, which would likely hit hard.</p>

<p>Michael Moore, chief executive of BVCA, a private equity industry body, said Labour was, however, showing willingness to back up its "pro-business mood music with engagement on substance".</p>

<p>Reeves had vowed to end a "loophole" that allows a portion of private equity earnings to be taxed as capital gains, rather than at the higher income tax rate, but last month signalled to the Financial Times that favourable tax treatment would continue in instances where fund managers put their own capital at risk.</p>

<h3><strong>Sanguine After Brexit And Truss</strong></h3>

<p>Many of Britain's top bankers and financiers are taking the prospect of a left-leaning Labour government in their stride after the hit from Brexit, and the impact on the UK government bond market in September 2022 from then-Prime Minister Liz Truss's plans for unfunded tax cuts.</p>

<p>"The industry has had positive and constructive conversations with Labour since 2019. If they win, very few new governments will have entered office better briefed on what our ecosystem needs to help act as a dynamo for growth and competitiveness," said Miles Celic, chief executive of TheCityUK, which represents the UK financial sector globally.</p>

<p>The Labour Party did not respond to a request for comment.</p>

<p>Fixing the damage to investor confidence and leakage of financial services activities to the EU caused by Brexit - arguably the most enduring legacy of the Conservative Party's 14 years in power - will be tough for Labour to fix.</p>

<p>France's central bank said last year transactions between French-based financial services firms and the rest of the world hit a record 10.4 billion euros in 2022 - double the volume seen at the time of the 2016 Brexit vote.</p>

<p>According to figures published by CityUK in January, the UK had a 16% share of cross-border bank lending in 2016 but this fell to 14% by end Q2 2023.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Amsterdam has overtaken London to become Europe's top share trading venue since euro-denominated share trading by EU investors had to stop in Britain on Dec. 31, 2020.</p>

<h3><strong>Seeking Certainty And Stability</strong></h3>

<p>Starmer has repeatedly made clear that rejoining the single market, essential for the City to regain direct access to the EU, is a red line he won't cross.</p>

<p>Many market participants just want to see financial sector reforms already agreed properly implemented under Labour, to protect the industry's massive contribution to state coffers.</p>

<p>A study by PwC for the City of London Corporation and TheCityUK published in May estimated the total tax contribution of the financial and related professional services industry was 110.2 billion pounds ($140 billion) in 2023.</p>

<p>This is equivalent to 12.3% of total UK tax receipts, more than the UK government's education budget, or more than half the health budget.</p>

<p>Imminent changes to Britain's rules on stock market listings have been designed to bring in more big-ticket initial public offerings, which could potentially include China-founded fast-fashion retailer Shein, and other similar deals that bring handsome paydays for those involved.</p>

<p>The Financial Conduct Authority is set to publish its listings revamp after the election, which could spur a flurry of corporate activity from end-July.</p>

<p>Britain's economy pulled out of recession at a faster pace than previously thought in the first three months of this year, but the broader economic backdrop remains fragile.</p>

<p>UK public debt is high, nearly equivalent to GDP, with prospects of tepid growth, leaving analysts to conclude that taxes will inevitably rise to shore up health and other services, making the financial sector a potential target.</p>

<p>"It's pretty simple really, business wants certainty," said Naresh Aggarwal, associate policy &amp; technical director at the Association of Corporate Treasurers.</p>

<p>M&amp;G Investments said in a note to clients that a Labour election was unlikely to fundamentally alter the direction of the UK equity market where valuations are depressed compared with Wall Street.</p>

<p>But New Financial's Wright cautioned that Labour may be more radical in government than it has been in opposition, a view echoed by Samuel Gregg of the American Institute for Economic Research.</p>

<p>"The City should recognise Labour is a more left-leaning outfit these days than it was in Tony Blair's heyday," said Gregg, speaking of the New Labour stronghold of the early 2000s.</p>

<p>"That cannot help but make life more uncertain for the City under a Labour government with a huge majority."</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/d559hh88_london_625x300_04_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/thought-he-was-sleeping-mans-death-goes-unnoticed-for-30-hours-in-china-internet-cafe-6034056]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Man's Death Goes Unnoticed For 30 Hours In China Internet Cafe]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/thought-he-was-sleeping-mans-death-goes-unnoticed-for-30-hours-in-china-internet-cafe-6034056]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 04 Jul 2024 19:13:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The employees of the cafe thought the man was fast asleep and they didn't bother to wake him up.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a bizarre incident, staff at an internet cafe in China's&nbsp;Wenzhou failed to notice that one of their customers had died and instead assumed that he was simply sleeping. According to the<em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3268636/thought-he-was-sleeping-man-29-dies-china-internet-cafe-demise-goes-unnoticed-30-hours"> South China Morning Post</a></em>, the man, whose identity remains unknown, had begun an extended gaming session on June 1. The employees of the cafe thought the man was fast asleep and they didn't bother to wake him up.</p>

<p>However, on the night of June 3, at 10 pm, a cafe worker attempted to wake him, only to find him unresponsive and his body cold. The alarmed worker contacted the police, who confirmed his death.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Based on the breakfast residuals left on the desk, he did not have lunch on June 2. He possibly died suddenly on the morning of June 2,'' said a police officer, according to Jimu News.</p>

<p data-qa="Component-Component" datatype="p">The man's brother-in-law, surnamed Chen, said the exact time of death was not confirmed because his family did not permit pathologists to perform an autopsy.</p>

<p data-qa="Component-Component" datatype="p">He also questioned the cafe employees and expressed frustration&nbsp;over how the death went unnoticed for so long.&nbsp;</p>

<p data-qa="Component-Component" datatype="p">''He sat in an open area instead of a closed partition. There should have been employees checking on him and noticing his strange behaviour,'' said Chen.</p>

<p data-qa="Component-Component" datatype="p">The internet cafe manager informed that the man looked healthy, and was a regular customer&nbsp;who usially stayed for six hours at a time.&nbsp;He added that gamers routinely fall asleep between their gaming sessions and&nbsp;the two staffers on duty at the time did not realise the man had ''slept'' for such an extended period.&nbsp;</p>

<p data-qa="Component-Component" datatype="p">''The employees thought he was having a rest, so they did not wake him up. Often, when we wake a sleeping customer, they become irritable and scold us,'' he said.</p>

<p>As per the local police, the case is still under investigation.</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/r6nimmmg_cafe_625x300_04_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[As per the local police, the case is still under investigation.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/big-salamander-like-creature-with-fangs-roamed-namibia-280-million-years-ago-6033900]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Big Salamander-Like Creature Roamed Namibia 280 Million Years Ago]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/big-salamander-like-creature-with-fangs-roamed-namibia-280-million-years-ago-6033900]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 04 Jul 2024 18:51:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[About 280 million years ago, a large creature built somewhat like a salamander but with frightful fangs prowled the swamps and lakes of what is now Namibia, ambushing prey as a top predator in a chilly ecosystem l]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>You might call it the "swamp thing." About 280 million years ago, a large creature built somewhat like a salamander but with frightful fangs prowled the swamps and lakes of what is now Namibia, ambushing prey as a top predator in a chilly ecosystem long before the dinosaurs.</p>

<p>The creature, named Gaiasia jennyae, lived during the Permian Period and measured at least 8 feet (2.5 meters) long - and perhaps up to 13 feet (4 meters), according to researchers who announced the discovery of its fossilized remains. Its large, round, flat skull measured more than 2 feet (60 cm) long, and it had interlocking fangs at the front of its mouth.</p>

<p>"Wide flat heads in modern animals usually are used to generate strong suction to ambush prey by suddenly sucking it into their mouths. Gaiasia combines that with huge fangs for grabbing and killing large prey," said Jason Pardo, a postdoctoral fellow in paleontology at the Field Museum in Chicago and one of the leaders of the research published this week in the journal Nature.</p>

<p>The fossils were unearthed in Namibia, a country in southwest Africa. Because of the gradual movement over time of the crustal plates that form Earth's outer layer - a process called plate tectonics - this place was even further south when Gaiasia lived, almost even with Antarctica's current northernmost point. The bodies of water it inhabited may have sat alongside patches of ice and glaciers.</p>

<p>"In the far south, where Gaiasia lived, an ice age was ending, and it was still quite cold, with large glaciers at even low altitudes," Pardo said.</p>

<p>Roughly 100 million years before Gaiasia existed, the first land vertebrates had evolved from fish with fleshy fins. These are called the stem tetrapods. They lived an amphibious lifestyle though were not true amphibians. The term tetrapod, meaning "four feet," refers to all land vertebrates. The earliest ones, the stem tetrapods, spawned evolutionary lineages that led to true amphibians, reptiles and mammals.</p>

<p>While this was taking place, some stem tetrapods persisted, especially in remote places like Namibia was at the time. Gaiasia was one of these.</p>

<p>"Most of what we know of terrestrial life at this time comes from the ancient equator, preserved in rocks from Europe and North America. From that, we had thought early tetrapods were trapped in the tropics by their physiology," Pardo said, until they disappeared amid competition from newly evolved competitors.</p>

<p>"Gaiasia shows clearly that this is not correct. Stem tetrapods were thriving at high latitudes in very cold environments, and those ecosystems were dominated by some very unexpectedly primitive animals. That forces us to rethink a lot about early tetrapod evolution," Pardo said.</p>

<p>So Gaiasia was a stubborn holdover.</p>

<p>"Gaiasia is very different from anything else we've seen, so it could be a lone survivor, but it could also be part of a vibrant ecosystem of similarly strange animals that were no longer important parts of the ecosystem in the tropics," Pardo said.</p>

<p>Evolution was moving in leaps and bounds during the Permian.</p>

<p>"At this time we see a flurry of evolution in the forerunners of mammals, such as Dimetrodon, an animal the size of a mountain lion that looked something like a big lizard with a giant sail on its back and was the top predator in most of these ecosystems. We also see forerunners of reptiles diversifying in interesting ways that mirror modern lizards, and the first true amphibians," Pardo said.</p>

<p>The Permian ended about 252 million years ago with Earth's worst mass extinction. The first dinosaurs appeared roughly 230 million years ago during the Triassic Period.</p>

<p>The creature's name Gaiasia refers to the Gai-as rock formation in Namibia where it was found, and jennyae honors the late British paleontologist Jenny Clack, who studied early tetrapods. But how about a catchy nickname for it?</p>

<p>"'Swamp thing' is excellent," Pardo said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/6l5cdga8_gaiasia-jennyae_625x300_04_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The fossils were unearthed in Namibia, a country in southwest Africa.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-man-65-hits-woman-for-not-giving-him-seat-in-metro-detained-6033709]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[China Man, 65, Hits Woman For Not Giving Him Seat In Metro, Detained]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-man-65-hits-woman-for-not-giving-him-seat-in-metro-detained-6033709]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 04 Jul 2024 18:26:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The man said in the clip, "Call the police, we'll go to the police station, and you can say I'm harassing you."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 65-year-old man from China was detained following a heated argument with a young woman on a metro. The man had asked the woman to give up her seat so that he could sit. When she refused, he then screamed at her and hit her with his cane, as per the Beijing Police.</p>

<p>According to a report in the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.globaltimes.cn/page/202406/1314873.shtml"><em>Global Times</em></a>, the unsettling episode took place on Beijing Subway Line 10. In the now-viral video on social media, the elderly man is seen asking a young woman to give up her seat for him. She refused and said that she would offer her seat to someone else. He then swept his cane between her legs and hit her with his hands, further escalating the situation.</p>

<p>The man said in the clip, "Call the police, we'll go to the police station, and you can say I'm harassing you." The video footage also documents the efforts of subway security to resolve the conflict.</p>

<p>Since being shared, the video has amassed several reactions likes on the microblogging platform.</p>

<p>"Embarrassing. That guy is a clown," said a user.</p>

<p>Another wrote, "Not typical in China. My wife and I (late-70s Americans) visited my daughter in China for a month. On boarding a public transit bus for the 3 hour ride back from the Great Wall to Beijing we had more than a few people get up from their seats and insist we sit while they stood for the entire 3 hours. I kept insisting they take a break and sit for a while but they would not hear of it."</p>

<p>"That old man needs to chillax," stated a third person.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/0376ee5_beijing-metro_625x300_04_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The incident took place on Beijing Subway Line 10.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-polls-cost-of-living-for-british-indian-voters-could-trump-rishi-sunaks-pride-6033639]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Cost Of Living For British Indian Voters Could Trump Rishi Sunak's Pride]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-polls-cost-of-living-for-british-indian-voters-could-trump-rishi-sunaks-pride-6033639]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 04 Jul 2024 18:16:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The UK's historic general election on Thursday marks the first real test at the ballot box for Rishi Sunak when pride in Britain's first Prime Minister of Indian heritage might be trumped by the cost-of-living crisis and sheer fatigue with 14 long ye]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The UK's historic general election on Thursday marks the first real test at the ballot box for Rishi Sunak when pride in Britain's first Prime Minister of Indian heritage might be trumped by the cost-of-living crisis and sheer fatigue with 14 long years of a Conservative Party-led government.</p>

<p>Exactly how the votes stack up will start to unfold only once polling closes but YouGov's final large-scale poll for 'The Times' on the eve of the election suggests the Opposition Labour could be handed a so-called "supermajority" - indicating a 212-seat parliamentary majority and the highest in decades.</p>

<p>But whatever the final outcome, this pattern is more a reflection of the political turmoil that ultimately brought Mr Sunak into 10 Downing Street than a vote against his own leadership.</p>

<p>"I think for British Indian voters, in particular, this election is similar to the rest of the electorate; they've been given a chance to choose to keep or remove the government and after 14 years of a Conservative government, the mood is much more for change than for maintaining it," reflected Sunder Katwala, Director of the British Future think tank.</p>

<p>"There'll be a sense, I think, of regret and disappointment that this didn't go better for Rishi Sunak as there was great pride... but people aren't going to make their voting choice on that basis. And that's why I think, more British Indian voters are going to vote for change than vote for keeping Rishi Sunak, even though they appreciate his historic achievement in being the first British Prime Minister of Indian heritage," he noted.</p>

<p>Against this backdrop, the issues that would influence British Indian voters would echo wider concerns such as the cost-of-living crisis, the National Health Service (NHS) waiting lists and getting a grip on illegal migration.</p>

<p>While Mr Sunak did meet his pledge to bring down inflation from the soaring levels he inherited in the aftermath of the chaotic terms of predecessors Boris Johnson and Liz Truss, it may not prove enough to get him over the line at the ballot box.</p>

<p>"I don't know why he's not going around to every single member of the Tory party inside of the government saying, 'I told you so'... We've now reduced inflation down from the high of 11 per cent down to 2 per cent. We've seen the underlying economic outlook for the country improving since Mr Sunak took office in October 2022.</p>

<p>"But the problem we have is that people have long memories of a time when we forgot what it was to be a Conservative," Andrew Boff, Tory Chair of the London Assembly, said during an election debate hosted by 'Eastern Eye' earlier this week.</p>

<p>"Rishi Sunak, at one level, was a breath of fresh air because he's clearly an extremely bright, decent man attempting to do his best... [but] not much has changed since he became Prime Minister," said Lord Richard Newby, Leader of the Lib Dems in the House of Lords, during the event.</p>

<p>For Anneliese Dodds, Labour Party chair and shadow secretary of state for women and equalities, Mr Sunak's term marked a "huge amount of continuity" with his embattled predecessors.</p>

<p>However, if the outcome of the election indicates a definitive shift among British Indian voters towards Labour, it would be seen more as a vote in favour of change rather than a decisive ballot in favour of party leader Keir Starmer - who is simply being viewed as a "choose-able alternative", according to poll analysts.</p>

<p>Once the final outcome is clear on Friday, the conversation will instantly shift towards 44-year-old Sunak's political future.</p>

<p>An immediate resignation as Tory leader is expected only if the party's performance really is close to the disastrous levels forecast by some opinion polls.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/s14jc9gg_rishi-sunak-afp_625x300_04_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Rishi Sunak did meet his pledge to bring down inflation from the soaring levels (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/suspect-in-slovak-pm-shooting-faces-charge-of-carrying-out-terrorist-attack-6033638]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Suspect In Slovak PM Shooting Faces Charge Of Carrying Out Terrorist Attack]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/suspect-in-slovak-pm-shooting-faces-charge-of-carrying-out-terrorist-attack-6033638]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 04 Jul 2024 18:16:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The man detained over the shooting of Slovak Prime Minister Robert Fico will face prosecution on the charge of carrying out a terrorist attack, Slovakia's general prosecutor said on Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The man detained over the shooting of Slovak Prime Minister Robert Fico will face prosecution on the charge of carrying out a terrorist attack, Slovakia's general prosecutor said on Thursday.</p>

<p>Fico is recovering after being shot four times at close range when he greeted supporters at a government meeting in the central Slovak town of Handlova in mid-May. That left him needing hours of surgery.</p>

<p>A man identified by prosecutors as 71-year old Juraj C. was detained on the spot after the attack and charged with attempted premeditated murder.</p>

<p>"On the basis of the gathered evidence, the prosecuted act will be further legally qualified as the particularly serious crime of terrorist attack," General Prosecutor Maros Zilinka said on Facebook on Thursday, without providing further details.</p>

<p>The accused, if found guilty, could face life in prison under the new classification, according to Slovakia's criminal laws. Previously he had faced 25 years or life in prison.</p>

<p>The attack has highlighted the deep polarisation of politics in the central European country.</p>

<p>The detained man has, according to court documents, said he wanted to hurt the prime minister, but not kill him, because he disagreed with government policies including cancelling a special prosecutor's office and stopping state military aid to Ukraine.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/o0g1en2g_robert-fico_625x300_05_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Slovak Prime Minister Robert Fico (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/saudi-netflix-show-creator-faces-terrorism-charge-13-year-travel-ban-6033229]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Saudi Netflix Show Creator Faces Terrorism Charge, 13-Year Travel Ban]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/saudi-netflix-show-creator-faces-terrorism-charge-13-year-travel-ban-6033229]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 04 Jul 2024 17:19:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Saudi TV creator Abdulaziz Almuzaini, whose animated Netflix show has made waves for breaking social taboos, said he had been convicted by an anti-terrorism court, prompting condemnation from rights advocates.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Saudi TV creator Abdulaziz Almuzaini, whose animated Netflix show has made waves for breaking social taboos, said he had been convicted by an anti-terrorism court, prompting condemnation from rights advocates.</p>

<p>The kingdom's Specialised Criminal Court, established in 2008 to try suspects accused of terrorism, "issued against me (a sentence of) 13 years, followed by a 13-year travel ban", Almuzaini said in a video posted online last week that was subsequently deleted.</p>

<p>In a second video posted this week, which is still available on social media platform X, Almuzaini filmed himself inside a car, saying: "I am banned from travelling" out of Saudi Arabia.</p>

<p>Saudi officials did not immediately respond to a request for comment from AFP on Thursday, and there was no word of Almuzaini -- who was not available for comment -- having been incarcerated.</p>

<p>His satirical show "Masameer County", billed as "a humorous view on a changing Saudi", debuted in 2021.</p>

<p>Episodes tackled topics such as disputes among tribes and Islamic militancy, and even featured oblique references to homosexuality, a potential capital crime in Saudi Arabia.</p>

<p>The Wall Street Journal on Thursday reported that court documents in the case referred to online posts by Almuzaini which "ridiculed Arab regimes... or voiced support for women's rights".</p>

<p>Almuzaini said in the since-deleted video that the court accused him of promoting homosexuality and militancy.</p>

<p>He also said that, amid mounting pressure from Saudi authorities, he was forced to close his company, Myrkott Animation Studio.</p>

<p>"The services of all the employees of the Myrkott company were terminated a week ago," he said.</p>

<p>"Those are people who have families, people who have worked with us since 2012. I had to stand up and apologise to them all and announce to them that Myrkott had ended."</p>

<h3><strong>Appeal to the prince</strong></h3>

<p>The video included a direct appeal to Saudi Arabia's de facto ruler, Crown Prince Mohammed bin Salman, who became first in line to the throne in 2017 and has overseen sweeping social and economic reforms.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"I believe that we are in a country ruled by a rational family, and if one of its citizens is subjected to injustice, I have faith that my voice reaching His Highness the crown prince will correct some of what happened to me," Almuzaini said.</p>

<p>Saudi Arabia has been criticised for what activists describe as a fierce crackdown on even vaguely critical online speech.</p>

<p>In the past two years the Saudi judiciary has "convicted and handed down lengthy prison terms on dozens of individuals for their expression on social media", human rights groups Amnesty International and ALQST said in April.</p>

<p>Saudi officials say the accused had committed terrorism-related offences.</p>

<p>High-profile examples include two women who received decades-long sentences in 2022 for posting and sharing critical online posts, as well as a retired teacher who last year was sentenced to death after denouncing alleged corruption and human rights abuses on social media.</p>

<p>Prince Mohammed in a September interview with Fox News said he disapproved of that judgement and raised the possibility that the retired teacher, Mohammed al-Ghamdi, might be spared death.</p>

<p>Unlike in these cases, Almuzaini does not seem to have been jailed.</p>

<p>The proceedings against him nevertheless appeared to continue a trend of shutting down free speech, said Abdullah Alaoudh, senior director for countering authoritarianism at the US-based Middle East Democracy Center.</p>

<p>"Saudi Arabia's creative industries will not thrive -- let alone attract investment -- until the authorities recognise and fully respect the human rights of all its citizens," Alaoudh said.</p>

<p>Lina al-Hathloul, head of monitoring and communication for ALQST, denounced the imposition of a travel ban, as was the case with her sister, prominent women's rights activist Loujain al-Hathloul.</p>

<p>"We all would like to live in the country, but in safety and without these violations and the arbitrary and unjustified travel ban that has exhausted many, including my family," the London-based Lina al-Hathloul said on X.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/gumddr88_abdulaziz-almuzaini_625x300_04_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Almuzaini said in the since-deleted video that the court accused him of promoting homosexuality]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-swedish-citizens-given-death-sentences-in-iraq-over-shooting-6033150]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[3 Swedish Citizens Given Death Sentences In Iraq Over Shooting]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-swedish-citizens-given-death-sentences-in-iraq-over-shooting-6033150]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 04 Jul 2024 17:09:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Three Swedish citizens have been sentenced to death in Iraq over their involvement in a shooting and a fourth may also face the same punishment over a separate crime, the Swedish foreign ministry said on Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Three Swedish citizens have been sentenced to death in Iraq over their involvement in a shooting and a fourth may also face the same punishment over a separate crime, the Swedish foreign ministry said on Thursday.</p>

<p>The government summoned Iraq's charge d'affaires last month to protest the death sentence against one of the three involved in the shooting.</p>

<p>Sweden does not have the death penalty and opposes its use in all circumstances.</p>

<p>The foreign ministry said it had now received confirmation that two more Swedes have been convicted in relation to the same crime and received the death penalty.</p>

<p>"The information we have received on the death penalties is extremely serious and we are working to ensure the sentences will not be carried out," the foreign ministry said in an emailed statement.</p>

<p>In June, the Daily Aftonbladet reported that the men had been involved in the shooting of another Swedish citizen in Iraq in January.</p>

<p>The ministry said it had received a report that a fourth Swede was given a death sentence for a different, drug-related crime, but that it could not confirm the information.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/court-generic_625x300_1527245477936.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sweden does not have the death penalty and opposes its use in all circumstances (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russian-armour-piercing-tank-rounds-to-be-made-in-india-says-moscow-firm-6033010]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russian Armour-Piercing Tank Rounds To Be Made In India, Says Moscow Firm]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russian-armour-piercing-tank-rounds-to-be-made-in-india-says-moscow-firm-6033010]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 04 Jul 2024 16:49:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russia's vast state-owned Rostec corporation said on Thursday that its weapons export unit had organised the production in India of armour-piercing rounds for Russian-made battle tanks.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russia's vast state-owned Rostec corporation said on Thursday that its weapons export unit had organised the production in India of armour-piercing rounds for Russian-made battle tanks.</p>

<p>Rostec issued its statement ahead of a July 8-9 visit to Russia by Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi who will hold talks with President Vladimir Putin.</p>

<p>The "Mango" projectiles that will be made in India are designed to be fired from the guns of T-72 and T-90 tanks which India's land forces use, Rostec said.</p>

<p>"The rounds allow you to hit modern tanks equipped with combined protection. Various modifications of these combat vehicles are in service with India," it said in its statement.</p>

<p>Rostec said it also had plans to localise the production of gunpowder in India as part of the Indian government's drive to have more foreign goods made in India.</p>

<p>Moscow has long supplied the Indian military with equipment.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/9si8qcp_rostec_625x300_04_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Moscow has long supplied the Indian military with equipment.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/putin-xi-rally-against-external-influence-at-central-asian-summit-6032968]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Putin, Xi Rally Against External Influence At Central Asian Summit]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/putin-xi-rally-against-external-influence-at-central-asian-summit-6032968]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 04 Jul 2024 16:42:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The leaders of China and Russia on Thursday urged their allies and partners to resist malign external influence, advancing their shared anti-Western agenda at a regional summit in Central Asia.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The leaders of China and Russia on Thursday urged their allies and partners to resist malign external influence, advancing their shared anti-Western agenda at a regional summit in Central Asia.</p>

<p>Russian President Vladimir Putin and his Chinese counterpart Xi Jinping were in the Kazakh capital of Astana for a gathering of leaders from the Shanghai Cooperation Organisation (SCO), a regional bloc that Moscow and Beijing see as a counterweight to US "hegemony" on the world stage.</p>

<p>Xi called on the countries to "resist external interference" while Putin claimed "new centres" of political and economic might were on the rise.</p>

<p>"We should join hands to resist external interference, firmly support each other, take care of each other's concerns... and firmly control the future and destiny of our countries and regional peace and development in our own hands," Xi told the summit.</p>

<p>"It is of vital importance to the world that the SCO be on the right side of history and on the side of fairness and justice," he added.</p>

<p>In a joint declaration, published by the Kremlin, the group noted "tectonic shifts in global politics" and called for the bloc to play an enhanced role in global and regional security.</p>

<p>"The use of force is increasing, the norms of international law are systemically being violated, geopolitical confrontation and conflicts are growing, and risks to stability in the world and the SCO region are multiplying," it stated.</p>

<p>It did not refer to Russia's invasion of Ukraine or China's dispute with Taiwan but said the group had "mutual respect for sovereignty, independence and territorial integrity of states".</p>

<p>Both Russia and China regularly rail against what they say is the US dominance of global affairs and are seeking to boost their influence and control, particularly in regions close to their borders.</p>

<p>"The multipolar world has become a reality," Putin said in remarks at the summit.</p>

<p>He also hailed the accession of Russia's close ally Belarus to the bloc, becoming its tenth member.</p>

<p>"The circle of states that stand for a just world order and are ready to resolutely defend their legitimate rights and protect traditional values is expanding," Putin said.</p>

<p>"New centres of power and economic growth are strengthening," he added.</p>

<p>Western-sanctioned Iran joined as a full member last year.</p>

<h3><strong>Competition&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>The SCO was founded in 2001 but has come to prominence in recent years. Alongside China, Russia and Belarus, its full members are: India, Iran, Kazakhstan, Kyrgyzstan, Uzbekistan, Pakistan and Tajikistan.</p>

<p>It is intended to be a platform for cooperation in competition with the West, with a focus on security and economics and Central Asia in particular, and claims to represent 40 percent of the global population and about 30 percent of its GDP.</p>

<p>But it is a disparate group with many internal disagreements, including territorial disputes.</p>

<p>Russia's invasion of Ukraine has further increased major powers' interest in Central Asia, where Moscow is seeking to maintain its traditional sway but where China now has strong ties through its flagship Belt and Road infrastructure project.</p>

<p>The West is also vying for influence in the strategically important region, rich in oil and gas and a crucial transport route between Asia and Europe.</p>

<p>Despite the tussle for influence, at the summit on Thursday, the SCO's common anti-Western agenda was on clear display.</p>

<p>In the final declaration, the bloc criticised the "unilateral and unrestricted build-up" of missile defence systems by unnamed countries and regional alliances -- a common complaint of both Moscow and Beijing aimed at the United States.</p>

<p>They also called for an "early, complete and sustainable ceasefire" in Gaza with a "comprehensive and just settlement of the Palestinian question."</p>

<p>Pakistan's foreign ministry on Thursday announced it would host the next summit of leaders in October.</p>

<p>Mumtaz Zahra Baloch, the ministry's spokesperson, said "all heads of governments of SCO member states" would be welcomed when asked if Prime Minister Narendra Modi, the leader of neighbouring rival India, would be invited.</p>

<p>Modi did not attend this summit, but is expected in Moscow in the coming days, his first visit to the country since Russia invaded Ukraine.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/afr09tr8_putin-and-xi_625x300_15_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Both Russia and China regularly rail against what they say is the US dominance of global affairs.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-absolutely-not-pulling-of-us-presidential-race-says-white-house-6032827]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden "Absolutely Not" Pulling Of US Presidential Race, Says White House]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-absolutely-not-pulling-of-us-presidential-race-says-white-house-6032827]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 04 Jul 2024 16:21:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Joe Biden is "absolutely not" pulling out of the US presidential race, his spokeswoman said Wednesday, as pressure mounted following his disastrous debate performance against Donald Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Joe Biden is "absolutely not" pulling out of the US presidential race, his spokeswoman said Wednesday, as pressure mounted following his disastrous debate performance against Donald Trump.</p>

<p>Panic has gripped his Democratic Party in the wake of last week's TV debate, and internal rumblings about finding a replacement candidate before November's election have been amplified by polls showing Trump extending his lead.</p>

<p>The New York Times and CNN reported that Biden, 81, had acknowledged to a key ally that his reelection bid was on the line if he failed to quickly reassure the public that he was still up to the job.</p>

<p>White House spokeswoman Karine Jean-Pierre rejected those reports outright, insisting Biden has no intention of withdrawing.</p>

<p>"The president is clear-eyed and he is staying in the race," she told reporters.</p>

<p>Biden told a call with campaign and party staffers that he is going nowhere.</p>

<p>"I'm in this race to the end and we're going to win because when Democrats unite, we will always win. Just as we beat Donald Trump in 2020, we're going to beat him again in 2024," he said, according to a source close to the campaign.</p>

<p>He repeated that message in an emergency meeting with Democratic governors, who pledged their continued support, attendees said afterward.</p>

<p><br />
"As the president continued to tell us, and show us, that he was all in... we said that we would stand with him," Maryland Governor Wes Moore, seen as a rising star and potential future presidential candidate, told reporters alongside Minnesota's Tim Walz and Kathy Hochul of New York.</p>

<p>Walz said Biden was "fit to serve."</p>

<p>Michigan Governor Gretchen Whitmer, who also attended the meeting at the White House and is seen as one of the top picks to replace Biden if he should drop out, said on social media platform X that "he is in it to win it and I support him."</p>

<p>Biden has admitted he performed poorly in the debate, and was blunt in a radio interview recorded Wednesday with Wisconsin's Civic Media.</p>

<p>"I screwed up. I made a mistake. That's 90 minutes on stage. Look at what I've done in 3.5 years," he said.</p>

<p>He echoed that sentiment in an interview with Pennsylvania's WURD radio on Thursday, saying "I had a bad debate."</p>

<h3><strong>Aftermath</strong></h3>

<p>The Biden campaign has been desperate to reassure Democratic donors and voters that the president's performance against Trump was a one-off.</p>

<p>But party figures have voiced bafflement over what they see as deflection and excuses from the president and his aides.</p>

<p>Netflix co-founder Reed Hastings, one of the Democratic Party's biggest donors, told the New York Times that Biden should withdraw.</p>

<p>"Biden needs to step aside to allow a vigorous Democratic leader to beat Trump and keep us safe and prosperous," he said in an email to the paper.</p>

<p>The concern was compounded by a New York Times poll conducted after the debate that showed Trump with his biggest lead ever over Biden -- 49 percent to 43 percent of likely voters.</p>

<p>It wasn't until Wednesday -- six days after the debate -- that Biden completed a round of calls with Democratic congressional leaders, and staffers have also voiced consternation over the glacial pace of the outreach.</p>

<p>"We are getting to the point where it may not have been the debate that did him in, but the aftermath of how they've handled it," a senior Democratic operative told Washington political outlet Axios.</p>

<p>Biden may be tested on his ability to think on his feet when he sits with ABC News on Friday for his first television interview since the debate, and he will also hit the swing states of Wisconsin and Pennsylvania in the coming days.</p>

<h3><strong>'More worrisome'</strong></h3>

<p>The president has cited fatigue as a new explanation for his poor debate showing, saying that he was unwise to travel "around the world a couple times" before the debate.</p>

<p>But he had been back in the United States for nearly two weeks and spent two days relaxing and six days preparing before the debate.</p>

<p>Democratic lawmakers have begun to go public with their doubts. Arizona congressman Raul Grijalva became the second sitting Democrat to call on Biden to drop out.</p>

<p>"If he's the candidate, I'm going to support him, but I think that this is an opportunity to look elsewhere," Grijalva said, according to the Times.</p>

<p>In the street where the president grew up in Scranton, Pennsylvania, there was sympathy for Biden -- but no campaign signs for either candidate.</p>

<p>"I was embarrassed for him. I felt he didn't feel well and he probably shouldn't have gone on the stage," said 73-year-old Jamie Hayes.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/o44j52qo_joe-biden_625x300_03_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Biden told a call with campaign and party staffers that he is going nowhere (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-campaign-targets-kamala-harris-amid-rising-joe-biden-replacement-talks-6032722]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump's Campaign, Allies Target Kamala Harris Amid Biden Replacement Buzz]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-campaign-targets-kamala-harris-amid-rising-joe-biden-replacement-talks-6032722]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 04 Jul 2024 16:09:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump's campaign and some of his allies have launched a pre-emptive political strike on Vice President Kamala Harris, moving swiftly to try to discredit her amid talk among some of her fellow Democrats that she might replace President Biden.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump's campaign and some of his allies have launched a pre-emptive political strike on Vice President Kamala Harris, moving swiftly to try to discredit her amid talk among some of her fellow Democrats that she might replace President Joe Biden atop the party's 2024 presidential ticket.</p>

<p>On social media and in a flurry of statements over the past 48 hours, Trump's campaign and his Republican allies appear to be laying the groundwork for an all-out assault on Harris should the 81-year-old Biden decide to end his re-election bid following his feeble debate performance last week.</p>

<p>While Biden has insisted he is not quitting the race four months before the Nov. 5 election, and Harris has stood firmly behind him, the Trump campaign has little to lose by attacking the vice president now, so if Harris does emerge as the nominee, she might do so in a weakened state.</p>

<p>Republicans have regularly criticized Harris, 59, during Biden's term in office, but the attacks this week represented a sharp and seemingly coordinated escalation that appeared to be linked to increased talk about her possibly replacing Biden as the Democratic presidential candidate.</p>

<p>The National Republican Congressional Committee, which oversees House Republican races, called her Biden's "enabler in chief."</p>

<p>MAGA Inc., a fundraising super PAC supporting Trump, meanwhile released a statement calling her the "invasion czar." In March 2021 Biden said Harris would lead efforts with Mexico and Central American nations to address illegal immigration.</p>

<p>Republicans have since seized on that to accuse her of failing to stem the flow of millions of migrants crossing illegally into the United States, although she was never directly responsible for securing the southern border.</p>

<p>"Kamala Harris is incompetent. She's proven to be the weakest, worst vice president in history, and she has 100% supported Joe Biden in every single disastrous policy that he has implemented over the last four years," said Karoline Leavitt, a spokesperson for the Trump campaign.</p>

<p>The Biden campaign pushed back against the escalating Republican criticism without addressing the question of whether the vice president is waiting in the wings.</p>

<p>"Vice President Harris is proud to be President Biden's running mate," said Rhyan Lake, a campaign spokesperson for Harris. "No matter what false attacks Trump and his extreme allies make, she will continue to defend the Biden-Harris record and prosecute the case against Donald Trump."</p>

<p>The swipes at Harris by Trump's camp were reminiscent of a similar tactic that the Republican Trump, president from 2017-2021, used to successfully undermine Ron DeSantis, his main Republican rival before the Florida governor jumped into their party's 2024 election primary race last year.</p>

<p>Corey Lewandowski, a longtime Trump adviser, told Reuters Harris was politically vulnerable given her role in addressing illegal immigration, among other issues that are part of extensive research the party has gathered on her record.</p>

<h3><strong>TRUMP'S UNUSUAL SILENCE</strong></h3>

<p>A former senior staffer in the Trump White House who is still in contact with the Trump campaign said the newfound emphasis on Harris made sense.</p>

<p>"If Joe Biden stays on top of the ticket, given what we've seen, she takes on even more importance. But if he does step aside, she's the potential candidate. This is about defining her," the staffer said, pointing to her low approval ratings in public opinion polls.</p>

<p>Despite her consistently low approval ratings, a Reuters/Ipsos poll earlier this week showed Harris to be as formidable an opponent to Trump as Biden. In a hypothetical matchup, Trump led Harris by a single percentage point, 43% to 42%.</p>

<p>The clamor by Trump's allies is in stark contrast with the unusual silence from the normally voluble former president. Since Biden's poor debate performance, Trump has laid low, making few public appearances or public statements.</p>

<p>"This shows a maturation of the candidate himself. You can teach an old dog new tricks. He's showing increased discipline and message control," said a senior adviser to the Trump campaign familiar with internal discussions.</p>

<p>Even before the June 27 debate, the Trump campaign was beginning to turn its attention to Harris, releasing an attack ad online that mocked her for repeating lines in her speeches.</p>

<p>An online meme promoted by Republicans showed Harris repeating the same phrase "unburdened by what has been" again and again in remarks.</p>

<p>Harris' defenders say she has become more of a target because of her leading role in attacking Trump over abortion rights and her vigorous defense of Biden on the campaign trail.</p>

<p>If Biden were to exit the race before the Democratic National Convention in August, there is no guarantee Harris would be the nominee. But as vice president, she likely would be first in line. She would benefit from Biden's immense campaign war chest and likely see a large segment of Democrats rally around her in a bid to avoid a bitter intra-party battle.</p>

<p>And as the first Black vice president in U.S. history, she provides a bridge to the party's most dependable voting bloc. Her background and relative youth would make for a sharp contrast with Trump, 78.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/neq82hv8_kamala-harris_625x300_04_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Trump's campaign appears to be laying the groundwork for an all-out assault on Harris.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>