<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Wed, 27 Nov 2024 09:05:39 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-influencer-sentenced-to-10-years-in-prison-for-attempting-to-kill-3-people-including-online-critic-7114799]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Influencer Sentenced To 10 Years In Prison Over Attempting To Kill 3 People]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-influencer-sentenced-to-10-years-in-prison-for-attempting-to-kill-3-people-including-online-critic-7114799]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 27 Nov 2024 08:28:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Acting U.S. Attorney Reagan Fondren announced on Monday, Nov. 18, that Grayson was found guilty of a murder-for-hire conspiracy.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Texas influencer Ashley Grayson has been sentenced to 10 years in federal prison for attempting to hire someone to murder three people- including a business rival and someone who trashed her on social media, the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/11/25/us-news/influencer-gets-10-years-for-60kmurder-for-hire-plot/" rel="noindex,nofollow"><em>New York Post </em></a>reported.</p>

<p>According to a press release from the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.justice.gov/usao-wdtn/pr/texas-woman-sentenced-10-years-imprisonment-connection-murder-hire-plot" rel="noindex,nofollow"><em>U.S. Attorney's Office for the Western District of Tennessee</em></a>, Grayson, 35, gained fame on social media for her online business and courses teaching others how to monetize their skills. &nbsp;</p>

<p>Acting U.S. Attorney Reagan Fondren announced on Monday, Nov. 18, that Grayson was found guilty of a murder-for-hire conspiracy. &nbsp;</p>

<p>The press release revealed that in September 2022, Grayson offered to pay a Memphis-based couple to kill three targets: her ex-boyfriend, a woman who had criticized her on social media, and a Mississippi woman with a similar business model. Grayson believed the latter had created fake profiles to disparage her work online. &nbsp;</p>

<p>The Tennessee U.S. Attorney's Office reported that "Grayson valued each of these killings at no less than $20,000." During a recorded video call with the Memphis couple, Grayson expressed urgency in targeting the Mississippi woman, offering an additional $5,000 if the murder was carried out within a week. &nbsp;</p>

<p>Using photos of police cars from an unrelated incident, the couple falsely claimed they had attempted the murder-for-hire. They demanded half the agreed payment and travelled to Dallas to meet Grayson and her husband, ultimately receiving $10,000 for their fabricated "attempt." &nbsp;</p>

<p>In July 2023, a grand jury in the Western District of Tennessee indicted Grayson and her husband, Joshua Grayson, on a single count of "Use of Interstate Facility in Commission of Murder-for-Hire," according to the U.S. Attorney's Office press release. On Oct. 31, 2024, United States District Court Judge Thomas L. Parker sentenced Grayson to the maximum penalty of 120 months in prison. &nbsp;</p>

<p>"This was a twenty-first-century crime where online feuds and senseless rivalries bled into the real world," said Fondren, as quoted in the press release. "The defendant tried to hire someone to murder a woman over things that happened exclusively on the internet."</p>

<p>He continued, "Fortunately, no one was physically hurt in this case, but the victim and her family still felt a severe and emotional impact as the result of the defendant's actions. The proactive response from the investigating agencies and our prosecutors prevented an even more serious crime from occurring."</p>

<p><br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ublaidm8_ashley-grayson-_625x300_27_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Grayson offered to pay a Memphis-based couple to kill three targets]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jay-bhattacharya-covid-lockdown-critic-to-be-trumps-health-agency-head-7114686]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump's Indian-Origin Pick To Head Health Agency Was Covid Lockdown Critic]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jay-bhattacharya-covid-lockdown-critic-to-be-trumps-health-agency-head-7114686]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 27 Nov 2024 07:57:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[President-elect Donald Trump has announced Indian-origin Dr Jay Bhattacharya as the Director of National Institutes of Health, the country's top public funder of medical research with a budget of around $47.3 billion.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>President-elect Donald Trump has announced Indian-origin Dr Jay Bhattacharya as the Director of National Institutes of Health, the country's top public funder of medical research with a budget of around $47.3 billion.</p>

<p>Announcing his nomination, Trump said Stanford academic and US COVID policy critic Dr Bhattacharya would work with Robert F. Kennedy Jr. to "restore the NIH to a Gold Standard of Medical Research as they examine the underlying causes of, and solutions to, America's biggest health challenges, including our crisis of chronic illness and disease".</p>

<h3><strong>All about Jay Bhattacharya:</strong></h3>

<ul>
	<li>
	<p>Jay Bhattacharya was born in Kolkata in 1968.</p>
	</li>
	<li>
	<p>Dr Bhattacharya earned a doctorate in medicine from Stanford in 1997 and earned a Ph.D in economics from the same university three years later.</p>
	</li>
	<li>
	<p>Dr Bhattacharya is a Professor of Health Policy at Stanford University and a research associate at the National Bureau of Economics Research. He directs Stanford's Center for Demography and Economics of Health and Aging.</p>
	</li>
	<li>
	<p>His research focuses on the health and well-being of vulnerable populations, with a particular emphasis on the role of government programs, biomedical innovation and economics.</p>
	</li>
	<li>
	<p>Dr Bhattacharya's recent research focuses on the epidemiology of Covid-19 as well as an evaluation of policy responses to the epidemic.</p>
	</li>
	<li>
	<p>Dr Bhattacharya was a prominent critic of the federal government's Covid-19 response, co-writing an October 2020 open letter known as the Great Barrington Declaration that called for rolling back coronavirus-related shutdowns while keeping "focused protections" for vulnerable populations, such as older Americans.</p>
	</li>
	<li>
	<p>He has published 135 articles in top peer-reviewed scientific journals in medicine, economics, health policy, epidemiology, statistics, law and public health, among other fields.</p>
	</li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/d4tnpau_jay-bhattacharya-twitter_625x300_24_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Jay Bhattacharya was born in Kolkata in 1968.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ceasefire-in-israel-hezbollah-war-begins-7114651]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ceasefire In Israel-Hezbollah War Begins]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ceasefire-in-israel-hezbollah-war-begins-7114651]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 27 Nov 2024 07:46:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A ceasefire between Israel and Hezbollah in Lebanon took effect on Wednesday after more than a year of fighting that has killed thousands of people.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A ceasefire between Israel and Hezbollah in Lebanon took effect on Wednesday after more than a year of fighting that has killed thousands of people.</p>

<p>The truce, which began at 4:00 am (0200 GMT), should bring to a halt a war that has forced tens of thousands of people in Israel and hundreds of thousands more in Lebanon to flee their homes.</p>

<p>The war has seen swathes of Lebanon pounded by air strikes, and Israeli troops deployed across the border to battle Hezbollah militants.</p>

<p>It began with Hezbollah launching cross-border strikes in support of its Palestinian ally Hamas following its October 7, 2023 attack on Israel.</p>

<p>US President Joe Biden announced the ceasefire agreement on Tuesday, as Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said his ministers had agreed to a halt.</p>

<p>The United States is Israel's key ally and military backer, and Biden hailed the deal as "good news" and a "new start" for Lebanon.</p>

<p>Netanyahu thanked Biden for his involvement in brokering the deal, and said it would allow Israel to focus on Hamas in Gaza and Iran.</p>

<p>Under the terms of the Lebanon truce, Israel will maintain "full" freedom to act against Hezbollah should the Iran-backed group pose any new threat, Netanyahu said.</p>

<p>Lebanon says at least 3,823 people have been killed in the country since exchanges of fire began in October 2023, most of them in the past several weeks, when Israel escalated its campaign against Hezbollah.</p>

<p>On the Israeli side, the hostilities with Hezbollah have killed at least 82 soldiers and 47 civilians, authorities say.</p>

<p>The hours before the truce took effect were some of the most violent in the war.</p>

<p>Israel conducted a spate of strikes on the heart of the Lebanese capital on Tuesday, while Hezbollah claimed attacks on northern Israel after the truce was announced.</p>

<p>Hezbollah did not participate in any direct talks for the truce, with Lebanese parliamentary speaker Nabih Berri mediating on its behalf.</p>

<p>It has yet to formally comment on the truce.</p>

<p><strong>Focus on Iran</strong></p>

<p>The war in Lebanon has left Hezbollah massively weakened but not crushed.</p>

<p>It lost its longtime leader Hassan Nasrallah in a massive air strike in September, as well as a string of top commanders in other raids.</p>

<p>A truce in Lebanon, Netanyahu said, will permit Israel to redirect its efforts back to Gaza, where it has been at war with Hamas since October of last year.</p>

<p>"When Hezbollah is out of the picture, Hamas is left alone in the fight. Our pressure on it will intensify," Netanyahu said.</p>

<p>The agreement will also enable "focusing on the Iranian threat" and give Israel's military time to resupply, he added.</p>

<p>Iran is the main backer of both Hezbollah and Hamas, as well as other regional proxies that profess to be at war with Israel.</p>

<p>Iran itself has fired two barrages of missiles and drones at Israel since the outbreak of the war in Gaza, most of which were intercepted by Israel or its allies.</p>

<p>Hezbollah's attacks on northern Israel forced tens of thousands of Israelis from their homes, and Israeli officials have said they are fighting so they can return safely.</p>

<p>Some northern residents questioned whether that would be possible under a ceasefire.</p>

<p>"In my opinion, it would be a serious mistake to sign an agreement as long as Hezbollah has not been completely eliminated," said Maryam Younnes, 29, a student from Maalot-Tarshiha.</p>

<p><strong>'Blown away'</strong></p>

<p>In Lebanon, the war has forced nearly 900,000 people to flee their homes, the UN says.</p>

<p>Biden said the ceasefire deal was designed to be a "permanent cessation of hostilities" between Israel and Hezbollah.</p>

<p>Under the agreement, the Lebanese army would take control of the border area on their side and "what is left of Hezbollah and other terrorist organisations will not be allowed... to threaten the security of Israel again", he said.</p>

<p>Hezbollah was the only armed group that refused to surrender its weapons after the 1975-1990 Lebanese civil war ended.</p>

<p>To date, the group has maintained a strong presence in parts of Lebanon and its arsenal is believed to be more powerful than the national army's.</p>

<p>Divided Lebanon has been in crisis for years and will struggle to return to a semblance of normalcy even after a truce.</p>

<p>The United States and France would ensure the deal was fully implemented, Biden said.</p>

<p>Netanyahu said in his speech that Israel would maintain "full" freedom to act, even after the ceasefire.</p>

<p>The announcements followed a flurry of strikes on central Beirut as well as on Hezbollah's bastion in the southern suburbs.</p>

<p>One strike hit the normally busy Hamra district, home to residential buildings, restaurants, offices, shops, the American University of Beirut and its associated hospital.</p>

<p>Earlier, Lebanon's state-run National News Agency reported that three strikes hit the central Nweiri neighbourhood and destroyed a "four-storey building housing displaced people".</p>

<p>The health ministry said one of those strikes killed seven people and wounded 37 others.</p>

<p>"We were blown away and the walls fell on top of us," said Rola Jaafar, who lives in the building opposite.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/f20pqih_israel-hezbollah-reuters_625x300_21_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The war forced tens of thousands of people in Israel and Lebanon to flee their homes.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-lebanon-war-middle-east-conflict-west-asia-tensions-israel-hezbollah-ceasefire-begins-after-months-of-all-out-war-7114614]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel-Lebanon Ceasefire Begins After Months Of All-Out War: 10 Points]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-lebanon-war-middle-east-conflict-west-asia-tensions-israel-hezbollah-ceasefire-begins-after-months-of-all-out-war-7114614]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 27 Nov 2024 07:38:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel has begun a ceasefire in Lebanon after an all-out war with the Hezbollah amid global calls for peace in the Middle East. But fighting will continue in Gaza, where Israel has vowed to destroy the Palestinian Hamas group.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<ol class="CetSht_ol">
	<li class="CetSht_li">The Israeli cabinet approved the ceasefire deal - brokered by the US and France - last evening by a vote of 10-1. Announcing the "good news", US President Joe Biden said the ceasefire would take effect from 4 am (7:30 am IST) and that it was a "new start" for Lebanon.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Hezbollah, the only armed group that had refused to surrender its weapons after the Lebanese civil war in 1990, was not present during the truce talks. Lebanese parliamentary speaker Nabih Berri participated in the talks on behalf of Hezbollah.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">During the ceasefire, firing will stop from both sides, an official said. However, any violation by Hezbollah would see a forceful retaliation from Israel, Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu added.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">He said the truce will allow them to focus on Gaza and the "Iranian threat", giving the Israeli military time to resupply. "When Hezbollah is out of the picture, Hamas is left alone in the fight. Our pressure on it will intensify," Netanyahu said.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">"We will complete the task of obliterating Hamas, we will bring home all of our hostages, we will ensure that Gaza no longer poses a threat to Israel and we will return the residents of the north back home safely," the Prime Minister added.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">As part of the truce, Lebanese forces will begin their deployment towards the south over a 60-day period, during which Israel will have a phased withdrawal from Lebanese territory, an official said. The deal also requires Hezbollah to retreat from the southern border and move up the Litani River.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">The ceasefire announcement followed the day of heaviest Israeli raid in Beirut since September. Even early Wednesday morning, less than an hour before the ceasefire began, air strikes hit south Beirut - about two hours after the Israeli army ordered evacuation.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">War has been raging across the Middle East with Israel fighting the Hamas in Gaza and the Iran-backed Hezbollah group in Lebanon. Israel and Iran have also exchanged fire over their support to these groups.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">President Biden said the ceasefire was designed to "permanently" end hostilities in Gaza and that the US and its allies would provide all assistance to ensure the deal was implemented effectively.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">An US official said the Lebanon ceasefire could be a "stepping stone" towards ensuring end of hostilities in Gaza and freeing the hostages.</li>
</ol>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ivvie8q_beirut-afp_625x300_27_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hezbollah-ceasefire-deal-5-key-points-7114578]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel-Hezbollah Ceasefire Deal: 5 Key Points]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hezbollah-ceasefire-deal-5-key-points-7114578]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 27 Nov 2024 07:27:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[After two months of all-out war between Israel and Iran-backed Lebanese militant group Hezbollah, a ceasefire deal brokered by the US and France is meant to end the devastating conflict.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After two months of all-out war between Israel and Iran-backed Lebanese militant group Hezbollah, a ceasefire deal brokered by the United States and France is meant to end the devastating conflict.</p>

<p>The ceasefire is aimed at facilitating the peaceful withdrawal of Israeli troops from southern Lebanon over the next 60 days, a senior US official with knowledge of the negotiations said.</p>

<p><strong>READ </strong>|&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-agrees-to-ceasefire-deal-with-lebanon-report-7113141">Israel Agrees To Ceasefire Deal With Lebanon. Here's What The Pact States</a></p>

<p><strong>When does the ceasefire begin?</strong></p>

<p>The ceasefire will go into effect at 4:00 am local time Wednesday in Israel and Lebanon (0200 GMT), at which point "all fire will stop from all parties," the US official, who spoke on condition of anonymity, told reporters.</p>

<p><strong>What happens next?</strong></p>

<p>Israeli forces will hold their positions, but "a 60-day period will start in which the Lebanese military and security forces will begin their deployment towards the south," the official said.</p>

<p>That will give them time to reach the Israeli positions, at which point Israel can begin a phased withdrawal without any vacuum forming that could see Hezbollah or others rush in, the official explained.</p>

<p>The withdrawal should take no longer than 60 days, the official said.</p>

<p>Hezbollah must also withdraw from the southern border with Israel and move further north up the Litani River -- something it has not done despite a UN Security Council resolution calling for it in 2006 (UN Resolution 1701).</p>

<p>"Hezbollah terrorist infrastructure in southern Lebanon will not be allowed to be rebuilt," emphasized US President Joe Biden in comments explaining the deal.</p>

<p><strong>What if something goes wrong?</strong></p>

<p>Biden said that the United States, with the support of France and other allies, would "provide the necessary assistance to make sure this deal is implemented fully and effectively."</p>

<p>However, that does not mean US boots on the ground, he said.</p>

<p>Instead, "if Hezbollah or anyone else breaks the deal and poses a direct threat to Israel, then Israel retains the right to self-defense consistent with international law," Biden stated.</p>

<p>The United States and France will join the tripartite mechanism created after the 2006 war between Israel and Hezbollah, bringing together the United Nations Interim Force in Lebanon (UNIFIL), Israel and Lebanon.</p>

<p>This mechanism, which going forward will be chaired by the United States, will be tasked with maintaining communication between the various parties and ensuring that whenever any violation is identified it is dealt with to avoid any escalation, the US official said.</p>

<p>A military committee involving the armies of "several other countries" will also provide additional support to the Lebanese army in terms of equipment, training and financial resources.</p>

<p>"We remain committed to be on the ground, day to day, watch what's happening and to let everybody know ... that the world is watching," the official said.</p>

<p><strong>What next for Lebanon?</strong></p>

<p>Given that "Hezbollah is extremely weak at this moment, both militarily and politically," the ceasefire presents "the opportunity for Lebanon to reestablish its sovereignty over its territory," the US official said.</p>

<p>"Over the next 60 days, the Lebanese Army and the State Security Forces will deploy and take control of their own territory once again," Biden stated in his comments, calling it a "new start" for Lebanon.</p>

<p><strong>What does the deal mean for Gaza?</strong></p>

<p>The ceasefire in Lebanon could become "a stepping stone towards getting a ceasefire deal in Gaza and bringing the hostages home," the US official said.</p>

<p>In large part that will be because the Palestinian militant group Hamas -- which attacked Israel on October 7, 2023, prompting the invasion of Gaza -- will realize that "Hezbollah has decided to abandon them and delink the two conflicts," he said.</p>

<p>"There's no one coming for their support anymore. I think that's a powerful change of reality on the ground... If anyone in Hamas thought that there was broad support for their cause, I think today they have learned that that is not the case," the official said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/7s7i1ds8_israel-lebanon-afp_625x300_25_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The ceasefire will go into effect at 4:00 am local time Wednesday in Israel and Lebanon (0200 GMT).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-names-lawyer-jamieson-greer-his-us-trade-envoy-7114546]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump Names Lawyer Jamieson Greer His US Trade Envoy]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-names-lawyer-jamieson-greer-his-us-trade-envoy-7114546]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 27 Nov 2024 07:14:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump named Jamieson Greer his trade envoy, a key figure in rolling out the US president-elect's economic agenda -- in which tariffs are set to play a significant role.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump on Tuesday named Jamieson Greer his trade envoy, a key figure in rolling out the US president-elect's economic agenda -- in which tariffs are set to play a significant role.</p>

<p>"Jamieson played a key role during my First Term in imposing Tariffs on China and others to combat unfair Trade practices," said Trump of Greer, who served as chief of staff to US Trade Representative Robert Lighthizer during Trump's first administration.</p>

<p>Trump also cited Greer's experience in helping to see through a trade deal between the United States, Mexico and Canada.</p>

<p>Greer was most recently a partner at law firm King &amp; Spalding.</p>

<p>During Trump's first term from 2017 to 2021, the United States introduced tariffs on billions of dollars worth of imports -- notably on China but also America's allies.</p>

<p>In particular, the Trump administration imposed levies on some $300 billion in Chinese goods, as Washington and Beijing engaged in an escalating tariff war.</p>

<p>Lighthizer emerged as the US strongman in trade talks at the time, as he sought to force changes in Beijing's economic policies.</p>

<p>If confirmed by the Senate, Greer, who is viewed as Lighthizer's protegee, will be charged with rolling out Trump's tariff policy and negotiating trade deals.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/j9g5e88g_jamieson-greer_625x300_27_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Jamieson Greer was most recently a partner at law firm King & Spalding.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/terror-suspect-on-us-most-wanted-list-arrested-in-uk-fbi-7114274]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Terror Suspect On US' Most-Wanted List Arrested In UK: FBI]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/terror-suspect-on-us-most-wanted-list-arrested-in-uk-fbi-7114274]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 27 Nov 2024 05:40:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An alleged animal-rights extremist on the U.S. most-wanted terrorist list since 2009 in connection with the bombing of a California biotechnology firm has been arrested in the United Kingdom, the FBI said on Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p>

<p>An alleged animal-rights extremist on the U.S. most-wanted terrorist list since 2009 in connection with the bombing of a California biotechnology firm has been arrested in the United Kingdom, the FBI said on Tuesday.</p>

<p>The suspect, Daniel Andreas San Diego, was arrested in Wales on Monday in an operation carried out by Britain's National Crime Agency, Counter Terrorism Policing and the North Wales Police in coordination with the FBI, the FBI said in a statement. It was not immediately clear if San Diego, who is now in detention pending extradition, has legal representation.</p>

<p>San Diego was charged in connection with a bomb blast at biotechnology firm Chiron Inc near Oakland, California, in August 2003. A second bomb found there was deactivated by authorities and possibly intended to target first responders. Authorities accuse San Diego of planting a third bomb at another California company a month later.</p>

<p>No one was injured in any of the incidents, the FBI said.</p>

<p>An entity calling itself the Revolutionary Cells claimed responsibility for the attacks in statements posted to a pro-animal rights website, citing the targeted firms' alleged links to Huntingdon Life Sciences, which had been criticized by animal rights activists over its use of animal testing and is now part of the firm Inotiv.</p>

<p>In 2004 a federal grand jury returned an indictment charging San Diego with two counts of destroying or attempting to destroy property with explosives and two counts of use of a destructive device in a crime of violence.</p>

<p>The FBI has said that San Diego openly expressed extreme views advocating the use of violence to achieve the goals of the animal rights movement.</p>

<p>FBI Director Christopher Wray said the arrest showed that no matter how long a suspect is on the run, the bureau would not stop its pursuit.</p>

<p>"There's a right way and a wrong way to express your views in our country, and turning to violence and destruction of property is not the right way," Wray said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-02/5ld2mts4_fbi-generic_625x300_01_February_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The suspect, Daniel Andreas San Diego, was arrested in Wales on Monday (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/australias-social-media-ban-gets-support-from-senate-committee-7114189]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Australia's Social Media Ban Gets Support From Senate Committee]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/australias-social-media-ban-gets-support-from-senate-committee-7114189]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 27 Nov 2024 05:18:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An Australian Senate committee has backed a bill that would ban social media for children under 16 but said social media platforms should not force users to submit personal data such as passport and other digital identification to prove their age.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An Australian Senate committee has backed a bill that would ban social media for children under 16 but said social media platforms should not force users to submit personal data such as passport and other digital identification to prove their age.</p>

<p>Australia plans to trial an age-verification system that may include biometrics or government identification to enforce a social media age cut-off, some of the toughest controls imposed by any country to date.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese's centre-left Labor government is rushing to pass the bill, largely supported by the opposition Liberal party, by the end of the parliamentary year on Thursday.</p>

<p>In its report published late on Tuesday, the Senate's environment and communications legislation committee said social media platforms "must set out alternative methods for assuring age as reasonable steps with consideration given to the age assurance trial."</p>

<p>A progress report on the age assurance trial must be submitted by the communications minister to the parliament by Sept. 30, 2025, the committee said as it urged the government to "meaningfully engage" with youth when framing the law.</p>

<p>"Young people, and in particular diverse cohorts, must be at the centre of the conversation as an age restriction is implemented to ensure there are constructive pathways for connection," committee Chair Senator Karen Grogan said.</p>

<p>Some independent lawmakers have criticised the government for trying to pass the legislation in a week. The bill was introduced last Thursday, submissions on it closed on Friday, and a brief hearing was held on Monday.</p>

<p>In separate submissions, Google and Facebook-owner Meta Platforms said the social media ban should be delayed until the age-verification trial finishes. Bytedance's TikTok said the bill needed more consultation, while Elon Musk's X said the proposed law might hurt children's human rights.</p>

<p>The planned law would force social media platforms to take reasonable steps to ensure age-verification protections are in place. Companies could be fined up to A$49.5 million ($32 million) for systemic breaches.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/qgjpdvdo_social-media-ban-unsplash_625x300_21_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Australia plans to trial an age-verification system to enforce a social media age cut-off.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-appeals-court-grants-dismissal-of-donald-trumps-classified-documents-case-7113939]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Appeals Court Grants Dismissal Of Trump's Classified Documents Case]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-appeals-court-grants-dismissal-of-donald-trumps-classified-documents-case-7113939]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 27 Nov 2024 03:47:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An appeals court on Tuesday granted a request by prosecutors to drop the case against US President-elect Donald Trump for mishandling classified documents.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An appeals court on Tuesday granted a request by prosecutors to drop the case against US President-elect Donald Trump for mishandling classified documents.</p>

<p>Special Counsel Jack Smith had asked the court on Monday to dismiss the case because of a long-standing Justice Department policy of not prosecuting a sitting president.</p>

<p>A Trump-appointed district court judge in Florida threw out the documents case earlier this year, but Smith had appealed the ruling to the 11th Circuit Court of Appeals.</p>

<p>The appeals court granted Smith's request to dismiss the case without comment.</p>

<p>Smith is continuing, however, to pursue the case against Trump's two co-defendants, his valet, Walt Nauta, and Mar-a-Lago property manager Carlos De Oliveira.</p>

<p>Trump, 78, was accused of removing large quantities of top secret documents after leaving the White House at the end of his first term and obstructing efforts to retrieve them.</p>

<p>The former president was also accused by the special counsel of conspiring to overturn the results of the 2020 election won by Joe Biden. A judge on Monday granted a request by Smith to drop that case.</p>

<p>The special counsel paused both federal cases this month after Trump defeated Vice President Kamala Harris in the November 5 presidential election.</p>

<p>The former and incoming president also faces two state cases -- in New York and Georgia.</p>

<p>He was convicted in New York in May of 34 counts of falsifying business records to cover up a hush money payment to porn star Stormy Daniels on the eve of the 2016 election to stop her from revealing an alleged 2006 sexual encounter.</p>

<p>Judge Juan Merchan has postponed sentencing while he considers a request from Trump's lawyers that the conviction be thrown out in light of the Supreme Court ruling in July that an ex-president has broad immunity from prosecution.</p>

<p>In Georgia, Trump faces racketeering charges over his efforts to subvert the 2020 election results in the southern state, but that case will likely be frozen while he is in office.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/3b2qqm0o_donald-trump-reuters_625x300_19_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The former and incoming president also faces two state cases -- in New York and Georgia. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-claims-attacks-on-israel-after-ceasefire-deal-announcement-7113936]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hezbollah Claims Attacks On Israel After Ceasefire Deal Announcement]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-claims-attacks-on-israel-after-ceasefire-deal-announcement-7113936]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 27 Nov 2024 03:40:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hezbollah announced attacks on troops in north Israel late on Tuesday amid news of a ceasefire between the Lebanese group and Israel after more than a year of hostilities and two months of all-out war.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hezbollah announced attacks on troops in north Israel late on Tuesday amid news of a ceasefire between the Lebanese group and Israel after more than a year of hostilities and two months of all-out war.</p>

<p>In separate statements, the Iran-backed Hezbollah said its fighters targeted "a gathering of Israeli enemy forces" across the border in Shtula and in Kiryat Shmona, each with "a salvo of rockets".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-10/6e8i71v_missile-generic_650x400_17_October_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The ceasefire deal was announced after more than a year of hostilities. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-emmanuel-macron-hail-israel-hezbollah-ceasefire-as-step-toward-lasting-calm-7113849]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden, Macron Hail Israel-Hezbollah Ceasefire As Step Toward "Lasting Calm"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-emmanuel-macron-hail-israel-hezbollah-ceasefire-as-step-toward-lasting-calm-7113849]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 27 Nov 2024 03:18:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A ceasefire to end hostilities between Israel and Lebanon will protect Israel from the threat of Iran-backed militant group Hezbollah and create the conditions for a "lasting calm", US President Joe Biden and French President Emmanuel Macron said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A ceasefire to end hostilities between Israel and Lebanon will protect Israel from the threat of the Iran-backed group Hezbollah and create the conditions for a "lasting calm", US President Joe Biden and French President Emmanuel Macron said on Tuesday.</p>

<p>"The announcement today will cease the fighting in Lebanon, and secure Israel from the threat of Hezbollah and other terrorist organizations operating from Lebanon," the two leaders said in a joint statement.</p>

<p>Earlier, the Israeli government approved the truce with Hezbollah in Lebanon.</p>

<p>Hailing "many weeks of tireless diplomacy", Biden and Macron said the deal "will create the conditions to restore lasting calm and allow residents in both countries to return safely to their homes" on both sides of the border.</p>

<p>The United States and France will work "to ensure this arrangement is fully implemented, and enforced, and remain determined to prevent this conflict from becoming another cycle of violence", they added.</p>

<p>Paris and Washington will meanwhile also lead international efforts for "capacity-building" of the Lebanese army, they said.</p>

<p>The two countries will also seek to support economic development throughout Lebanon "to advance stability and prosperity in the region", the joint statement said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-10/h8hfa1os_-biden-macron_625x300_06_October_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Earlier, the Israeli government approved the truce with Hezbollah in Lebanon. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hezbollah-ceasefire-good-news-joe-biden-on-israel-hezbollah-ceasefire-deal-in-lebanon-7113708]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Good news": Joe Biden On Israel-Hezbollah Ceasefire Deal In Lebanon]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hezbollah-ceasefire-good-news-joe-biden-on-israel-hezbollah-ceasefire-deal-in-lebanon-7113708]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 27 Nov 2024 02:29:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden on Tuesday welcomed as "good news" a US and French-brokered ceasefire between Israel and Hezbollah in Lebanon.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden on Tuesday welcomed as "good news" a US and French-brokered ceasefire between Israel and Hezbollah in Lebanon.</p>

<p>The deal will come into force on Wednesday at 4:00 am local time (0200 GMT), Biden said, speaking at White House as Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's office announced his ministers had approved the deal.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/cdsiem5o_joe-biden-afp_625x300_07_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/brazilian-police-report-links-ex-president-jair-bolsonaro-to-alleged-2022-coup-plot-7113703]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Brazilian Police Report Links Ex President Bolsonaro To Alleged Coup Plot]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/brazilian-police-report-links-ex-president-jair-bolsonaro-to-alleged-2022-coup-plot-7113703]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 27 Nov 2024 02:24:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Brazil's Federal Police found proof that former hard-right President Jair Bolsonaro plotted a coup to overturn the outcome of the October 2022 election he lost to leftist challenger Luiz Inacio Lula da Silva, the police investigation report said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Brazil's Federal Police found proof that former hard-right President Jair Bolsonaro plotted a coup to overturn the outcome of the October 2022 election he lost to leftist challenger Luiz Inacio Lula da Silva, the police investigation report said.</p>

<p>The 884-page final police report, which was made public on Tuesday after it was sent to the country's top prosecutor by the Supreme Court, listed eight main pieces of evidence to back up the formal accusation against Bolsonaro for the alleged coup attempt.</p>

<p>The evidence included a meeting Bolsonaro called in December 2022 with the three armed forces commanders where they were presented a plan for a coup d'état and asked to join the conspiracy.</p>

<p>The Army and Air Force commanders refused, while the Navy commander, now retired Admiral Almir Garnier, said he was ready to back the plan, the police investigation found.</p>

<p>Garnier was one of the 37 people, most retired and some active duty military officers, who along with Bolsonaro were formally accused by the police for involvement in the coup plan. Prosecutor General Paulo Gonet must decided whether to indict Bolsonaro and the other alleged coup plotters.</p>

<p>Bolsonaro, who was formally accused for the attempted coup d'état, violent abolition of the democratic rule of law and criminal organization, has denied having committed any crime.</p>

<p>Supreme Court Justice Alexandre de Moraes authorized on Tuesday the lifting of the seal on the police findings.</p>

<p>The police report said Bolsonaro was responsible for drawing up a draft of a decree for the coup that would block Luiz Inacio Lula da Silva from taking office.</p>

<p>Police also found that Bolsonaro knew of a plan to assassinate President-elect Lula and Vice President-elect Geraldo Alckmin based on telephone conversations of the plotters and meetings at the presidential Alvorada residence.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/l8agkah_jair-bolsonaro-reuters_625x300_27_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Jair Bolsonaro has denied having committed any crime. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-signs-2-million-project-agreement-with-international-solar-alliance-7113635]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India Signs $2 Million Project Agreement With International Solar Alliance]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-signs-2-million-project-agreement-with-international-solar-alliance-7113635]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 27 Nov 2024 02:02:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Ministry of External Affairs signed a Project Implementation Agreement with the International Solar Alliance to operationalize a solar project worth USD 2 million in Fiji, Comros, Madagascar, and the Seychelles, according to an official release.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Ministry of External Affairs on Tuesday signed a Project Implementation Agreement with the International Solar Alliance to operationalize a solar project worth USD 2 million in Fiji, Comros, Madagascar, and the Seychelles, according to an official release.</p>

<p>This development comes after India committed to invest USD 2 million in new solar projects in these Indo-Pacific countries under Quad Climate Working Group initiative</p>

<p>Following the signing of the agreement, MEA Spokesperson Randhir Jaiswal took to social media platform X to highlight India's commitment to renewables and just energy transitions in island nations of the Indo-Pacific.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">New chapter in Quad Climate Initiatives.<br />
<br />
A Project Implementation Agreement was signed between Ministry of External Affairs and International Solar Alliance to operationalise solar projects in Comoros, Fiji, Madagascar and Seychelles.<br />
<br />
These projects underscore ??'s Quad… <a href="https://t.co/GrIScJxXTP">pic.twitter.com/GrIScJxXTP</a></p>
— Randhir Jaiswal (@MEAIndia) <a href="https://twitter.com/MEAIndia/status/1861333349614153848?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 26, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>As per a study undertaken by the ISA, the countries under consideration for solar projects have energy issues related to the perishability of agriculture products, unreliable electricity supply in health centers, and irrigation purposes in remote areas where grid power supply or solar mini grids are not available yet, the release stated.</p>

<p>Solar projects in these countries are focused on the areas of cold storage, solarization of health care facilities, and solar water pumping systems are under consideration, the release stated.</p>

<p>The successful execution of these projects is expected to enhance energy access, create employment, and provide reliable and quality power supply in these Indo-Pacific countries, the release stated.</p>

<p>Solar energy is a viable solution to help these countries address climate change-related challenges.</p>

<p>"The latest round of clean energy investments by India in these countries strengthens the nation's commitment of the Quad to address the challenges posed by climate change and facilitate their transition to a clean energy economy for the people, planet and our shared prosperity," the MEA release added.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/5m0ecvp8_ministry-of-external-affairs-and-international-solar-alliance_625x300_27_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Solar energy is a viable solution to help these countries address climate change-related challenges.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/all-you-need-to-know-about-us-brokered-israel-hezbollah-ceasefire-deal-7113446]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[All You Need To Know About US-Brokered Israel-Hezbollah Ceasefire Deal]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/all-you-need-to-know-about-us-brokered-israel-hezbollah-ceasefire-deal-7113446]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 27 Nov 2024 01:03:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel and Lebanese armed group Hezbollah are set to implement a ceasefire on Wednesday as part of a U.S.-proposed deal for a 60-day truce to end more than a year of hostilities.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel and Lebanese armed group Hezbollah are set to implement a ceasefire on Wednesday as part of a U.S.-proposed deal for a 60-day truce to end more than a year of hostilities.</p>

<p>The text of the deal has not been published and Reuters has not seen a draft.</p>

<p>Israel's security cabinet has approved the deal and it will be put to the whole cabinet for review. Lebanon and Hezbollah have agreed to the proposal and the Lebanese cabinet will meet on Wednesday to formalise its approval.</p>

<p>The deal, negotiated by U.S. mediator Amos Hochstein, is five pages long and includes 13 sections, according to a senior Lebanese political source with direct knowledge of the deal.</p>

<p>Here is a summary of its key provisions.</p>

<p><strong>HALT TO HOSTILITIES</strong></p>

<p>The halt to hostilities is set to begin 12 hours after an anticipated announcement on Tuesday night, with both sides expected to cease fire by Wednesday morning, two senior Lebanese political sources with direct knowledge of the deal said.</p>

<p>One of them said Israel was expected to "stop carrying out any military operations against Lebanese territory, including against civilian and military targets, and Lebanese state institutions, through land, sea and air."</p>

<p>All armed groups in Lebanon - meaning Hezbollah and its allies - would halt operations against Israel, the source said.</p>

<p><strong>ISRAELI TROOPS WITHDRAW</strong></p>

<p>Two Israeli officials said the Israeli military would withdraw from southern Lebanon within 60 days.</p>

<p>Lebanon had earlier pushed for Israeli troops to withdraw as quickly as possible within the truce period, Lebanese officials told Reuters. They now expect Israeli troops to withdraw within the first month, the senior Lebanese political source said.</p>

<p><strong>HEZBOLLAH PULLS NORTH, LEBANESE ARMY DEPLOYS</strong></p>

<p>Hezbollah fighters will leave their positions in southern Lebanon to move north of the Litani River, which runs about 30 kilometres (20 miles) north of the border with Israel.</p>

<p>Their withdrawal will not be public, the senior Lebanese political source said. He said the group's military facilities "will be dismantled" but it was not immediately clear whether the group would take them apart itself, or whether the fighters would take their weapons with them as they withdrew.</p>

<p>The Lebanese army would deploy troops to south of the Litani to have around 5,000 soldiers there, including at 33 posts along the border with Israel, a Lebanese security source told Reuters.</p>

<p>"The deployment is the first challenge - then how to deal with the locals that want to return home," given the risks of unexploded ordnance, the source said.</p>

<p>More than 1.2 million people have been displaced by Israeli strikes on Lebanon, many of them from south Lebanon. Hezbollah sees the return of the displaced to their homes as a priority, Hezbollah lawmaker Hassan Fadlallah told Reuters.</p>

<p>Tens of thousands displaced from northern Israel are also expected to return home.</p>

<p><strong>MONITORING MECHANISM</strong></p>

<p>One of the sticking points in the final days leading to the ceasefire's conclusion was how it would be monitored, Lebanon's deputy speaker of parliament Elias Bou Saab told Reuters.</p>

<p>A pre-existing tripartite mechanism between the United Nations peacekeeping force in southern Lebanon (UNIFIL), the Lebanese army and the Israeli army would be expanded to include the U.S. and France, with the U.S. chairing the group, Bou Saab said.</p>

<p>Israel would be expected to flag possible breaches to the monitoring mechanism, and France and the U.S. together would determine whether a violation had taken place, an Israeli official and a Western diplomat told Reuters.</p>

<p><strong>UNILATERAL ISRAELI STRIKES</strong></p>

<p>Israeli officials have insisted that the Israeli army would continue to strike Hezbollah if it identified threats to its security, including transfers of weapons and military equipment to the group.</p>

<p>An Israeli official told Reuters that U.S. envoy Amos Hochstein, who negotiated the agreement, had given assurances directly to Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu that Israel could carry out such strikes on Lebanon.</p>

<p>Netanyahu said in a televised address after the security cabinet met that Israel would strike Hezbollah if it violated the deal.</p>

<p>The official said Israel would use drones to monitor movements on the ground in Lebanon.</p>

<p>Lebanese officials say that provision is not in the deal that it agreed, and that it would oppose any violations of its sovereignty.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/p22sb3lg_beirut_625x300_27_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The official said Israel would use drones to monitor movements on the ground in Lebanon. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hong-kong-top-court-backs-housing-inheritance-rights-for-same-sex-couples-7113202]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hong Kong Top Court Backs Housing, Inheritance Rights For Same Sex Couples]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hong-kong-top-court-backs-housing-inheritance-rights-for-same-sex-couples-7113202]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 26 Nov 2024 23:59:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[This decision marks a significant victory for the LGBTQ+ community in Hong Kong, who have traditionally faced discrimination and fewer rights compared to heterosexual couples.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hong Kong's top court has made a landmark ruling in favour of same-sex married couples, upholding their rights to subsidised housing benefits and equal inheritance.</p>

<p>This decision marks a significant victory for the LGBTQ+ community in Hong Kong, who have traditionally faced discrimination and fewer rights compared to heterosexual couples.</p>

<p>According to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://apnews.com/article/hong-kong-lgbtq-housing-inheritance-same-sex-ad09f4280d718b6718aba98025293c33" rel="noindex,nofollow">Associated Press</a>, Court of Final Appeal's unanimous decision dismissed the government's appeals, ending years-long legal battles over the differential treatment of same-sex couples married overseas.</p>

<p>Government lawyer Monica Carss-Frisk claimed that Hong Kong's housing policy aimed to promote "procreation" among heterosexual couples.&nbsp;</p>

<p>However, Chief Justice Andrew Cheung disagreed, stating that excluding same-sex couples from public rental flats and subsidised flats under the Home Ownership Scheme was unjustifiable.</p>

<p>"[For] needy same-sex married couples who cannot afford private rental accommodation, the [government's] exclusionary policy could well mean depriving them of any realistic opportunity of sharing family life under the same roof at all," Cheung said.</p>

<p>The ruling also declared that disputed provisions in inheritance laws are "discriminatory and unconstitutional." Hong Kong's government respects the court's decision and will study the judgments to determine next steps.</p>

<p>Currently, Hong Kong does not recognise same-sex marriage, but the city does recognise same-sex marriage for certain purposes, such as taxation and civil service benefits.&nbsp;</p>

<p>This ruling is a significant step towards equality, but activists remain hopeful that Hong Kong will eventually legalise same-sex marriage, following in the footsteps of Taiwan and Thailand.</p>

<p>Nick Infinger, who was the first to launch a judicial review against the Housing Authority in 2018, told reporters that the rulings "acknowledged same-sex couples can love each other and deserve to live together."</p>

<p>"This is not only fighting for me and for my partner, but this is fighting for all the same-sex couples in Hong Kong," he added.</p>

<p>This landmark ruling is a significant milestone in the fight for LGBTQ+ rights in Hong Kong, and activists hope it will inspire further progress towards equality.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ap53lqmg_hong-kong-same-sex-couple-rights-reuters_625x300_26_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hong Kong's top court has made a landmark ruling in favour of same-sex married couples]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-agrees-to-ceasefire-deal-with-lebanon-report-7113141]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Agrees To Ceasefire Deal With Lebanon. Here's What The Pact States]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-agrees-to-ceasefire-deal-with-lebanon-report-7113141]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 26 Nov 2024 23:47:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In a significant development in West Asia, Israel has agreed to a ceasefire with Lebanon. The agreement comes into effect at midnight (Israel time) on November 27.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a significant development in West Asia, Israel has agreed to a ceasefire with Lebanon. The agreement comes into effect at midnight (Israel time) on November 27.</p>

<p>Israel's Security Cabinet, the country's top decision-making body under the government has agreed to the ceasefire. "The length of the ceasefire depends on what happens in Lebanon. We will enforce the agreement and respond forcefully to any violation. We will continue united until victory," Prime Minister Netanyahu said in his speech after the agreement.</p>

<p>"We will complete the task of obliterating Hamas, we will bring home all of our hostages, we will ensure that Gaza no longer poses a threat to Israel and we will return the residents of the north back home safely. The war will not end until we realize all its goals, including the return of the residents of the north safely home. And I tell you, it will happen, just like it happened in the south," Mr Netanyahu added.</p>

<h2><strong>He then gave 3 reasons why Israel agreed to the ceasefire:</strong></h2>

<p><big><em>"The first reason is to focus on the Iranian threat, and I won't expand on that.</em></big></p>

<p><big><em>The second reason is to give our forces a breather and replenish stocks. And I say it openly, it is no secret that there have been big delays in weapons and munitions deliveries. These delays will be resolved soon. We will receive supplies of advanced weaponry that will keep our soldiers safe and give us more strike force to complete our mission.</em></big></p>

<p><big><em>And the third reason for having a ceasefire is to separate the fronts and isolate Hamas. From day two of the war, Hamas was counting on Hezbollah to fight by its side. With Hezbollah out of the picture, Hamas is left on its own. We will increase our pressure on Hamas and that will help us in our sacred mission of releasing our hostages."</em></big></p>

<p>Israel and Lebanon-based, Iran-backed militant group Hezbollah have been at war for several months now. Hezbollah had started attacking Israel with rockets and projectiles for over a year leading to a retaliation from Tel Aviv. Hezbollah has been backing Hamas, another Iran-backed militant group which it considers its ally.</p>

<p>Israel and Hamas have been at war since October 2023, when the terrorists breached the Israel-Gaza border and took Israeli hostages at a concert. Hamas is based in Gaza, which is where the war began after Israel retaliated to the terror attack. Since then, the war in West Asia, popularly called the Middle-East, has led to large-scale destruction and death of tens of thousands of people in the region.</p>

<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu has agreed to the ceasefire and so has his security cabinet.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Netanyahu has however, warned that if Hezbollah breaks the deal, Israel will not honour it either and will strike back with full force. The peace deal has been achieved with the intervention of the United States and France, and US President Joe Biden and French President Emmanuel Macron are expected to make an official announcement shortly.</p>

<p>US Secretary of State Antony Blinken has been working closely with top Israeli officials to negotiate the ceasefire which comes into effect at midnight tonight.</p>

<h2><strong>Here are some of the key points from the Israel-Lebanon Ceasefire Agreement:</strong></h2>

<ul>
	<li>Hezbollah and all other armed militant groups in Lebanese territories will not carry out any offensive operations against Israel.</li>
	<li>In return, Israel will not conduct any offensive military operations against targets in Lebanon, (land, air, or sea).</li>
	<li>Israel and Lebanon acknowledge the importance of United Nations Security Council Resolution 1701.</li>
	<li>These commitments do not negate the right of either Israel or Lebanon to exercise their natural right to self-defense.</li>
	<li>The official Lebanese security forces and army will be the only armed groups allowed to carry weapons or operate forces in southern Lebanon.</li>
	<li>Any sale, supply, or production of weapons or related materials in Lebanon will be subject to oversight and control by the Lebanese government.</li>
	<li>All unauthorised facilities involved in the production of weapons or related materials will be dismantled.</li>
	<li>All unlicensed infrastructure and military sites will be dismantled, and all weapons not compliant with these commitments will be confiscated.</li>
	<li>A committee acceptable to both parties, Israel and Lebanon, will be formed to supervise and assist in ensuring the implementation of these commitments.</li>
	<li>Israel and Lebanon will report any potential breaches of these commitments to the committee and to UNIFIL.</li>
	<li>Lebanon will deploy its official security forces and army along all borders, crossing points, and the line delineating the southern region as outlined in the deployment plan.</li>
	<li>Israel will gradually withdraw from south of the Blue Line within a period of up to 60 days.</li>
	<li>The United States will facilitate indirect negotiations between Israel and Lebanon to reach an agreement on recognized&nbsp;land&nbsp;borders.</li>
</ul>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/p5hltaio_benjamin-netanyahu-reuters-_625x300_01_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel has agreed to a ceasefire with Lebanon today after a months-long conflict with Hezbollah]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-president-elect-donald-trump-vows-big-tariffs-on-mexico-canada-and-china-7113022]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump Vows Big Tariffs On Mexico, Canada and China]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-president-elect-donald-trump-vows-big-tariffs-on-mexico-canada-and-china-7113022]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 26 Nov 2024 23:25:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President-elect Donald Trump said Monday he intends to impose sweeping tariffs on goods from Mexico, Canada and China in response to illegal drug trade and immigration.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President-elect Donald Trump said Monday he intends to impose sweeping tariffs on goods from Mexico, Canada and China in response to illegal drug trade and immigration.</p>

<p>In a series of posts to his Truth Social account, Trump vowed to hit some of the United States' largest trading partners with sweeping tariffs on all goods entering the country.</p>

<p>"On January 20th, as one of my many first Executive Orders, I will sign all necessary documents to charge Mexico and Canada a 25 percent tariff on ALL products coming into the United States, and its ridiculous Open Borders," he wrote.</p>

<p>In another post, Trump said he would also be slapping China with a 10 percent tariff, "above any additional Tariffs," on all of its products entering the US in response to what he said was its failure to tackle fentanyl smuggling.</p>

<p>Tariffs are a key part of Trump's economic agenda, with the Republican president-elect vowing wide-ranging duties on allies and adversaries alike while he was on the campaign trail ahead of his November 5 victory.</p>

<p>Trump's first term in the White House was marked by an aggressive and protectionist trade agenda that also targeted China, Mexico and Canada, as well as Europe.</p>

<p>While in the White House, Trump launched an all-out trade war with China, imposing significant tariffs on hundreds of billions of dollars of Chinese goods.</p>

<p>At the time he cited unfair trade practices, intellectual property theft, and the trade deficit as justifications.</p>

<p>China responded with retaliatory tariffs on American products, particularly affecting US farmers.</p>

<p>The US, Mexico and Canada are tied to a three-decade-old free trade agreement, now called the USMCA, that was renegotiated under Trump after he complained that the US businesses, especially automakers, were losing out.</p>

<p>"Mexico and Canada remain heavily dependent on the US market so their ability to walk away from President-elect Trump's threats remains limited," Wendy Cutler, vice president at the Asia Society Policy Institute, and former US trade official, told AFP.</p>

<p>"He would undoubtedly be challenged in US courts but that will take time to work through the legal process," she added.</p>

<p>By citing the fentanyl crisis and illegal immigration, Trump appeared to be using national security concerns as a means to break that deal, something that is allowed under the rules set by the World Trade Organization.</p>

<p>But most countries and the WTO treat national security exceptions as something to be used sparingly, not as a routine tool of trade policy.</p>

<p>Trump in 2018 cited national security justifications to impose tariffs on steel and aluminum imports that targeted close allies like Canada, Mexico, and the European Union.</p>

<p>This led to retaliatory measures from the trading partners.</p>

<p><strong>'No cause of concern'</strong></p>

<p>The EU ambassador to the United States on Friday said that Europe would be ready to respond in case of renewed frictions with the US over trade.</p>

<p>Shortly after Trump's victory, Mexican President Claudia Sheinbaum reassured her citizens that Trump's return was "no cause for concern" despite the virulent trade threats.</p>

<p>Many economists have warned that tariffs would hurt growth and push up inflation, since they are primarily paid by importers bringing the goods into the US, who often pass those costs on to consumers.</p>

<p>But those in Trump's inner circle have insisted that the tariffs are a useful bargaining chip for the US to push its trading partners to agree to more favorable terms, and to bring back manufacturing jobs from overseas.</p>

<p>Trump has said he will put his commerce secretary designate Howard Lutnick, a China hawk, in charge of trade policy.</p>

<p>Lutnick has expressed support for a tariff level of 60 percent on Chinese goods alongside a 10 percent tariff on all other imports.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/sbpbpa4g_linda-mcmahon_625x300_21_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US President-elect Donald Trump.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/imran-khans-supporters-reach-islamabad-6-security-men-killed-in-violence-7112914]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Fight Till The Last Ball": Imran Khan's Message To Supporters From Jail]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/imran-khans-supporters-reach-islamabad-6-security-men-killed-in-violence-7112914]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 26 Nov 2024 23:02:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Pakistan's former prime minister Imran Khan on Tuesday evening asked his supporters who camped in Islamabad to "fight till the last ball and do not retreat".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pakistan's former prime minister Imran Khan on Tuesday evening asked his supporters who camped in Islamabad to "fight till the last ball and do not retreat".</p>

<p>"I salute the people of Pakistan and Pakistan Tehreek-e-Insaf workers who are standing up for their rights, participating in peaceful protests, and boldly confronting the mafia imposed on our country to demand true freedom and justice," Khan said in a message from Rawalpindi's Adiala Jail where he has been incarcerated since August 2023 in multiple cases.</p>

<p>"To my team, my message is clear: Fight till the last ball. We will not back down until our demands are fully met," he said, urging those who haven't yet joined the protest march to reach D-Chowk in Islamabad for a peaceful protest and not leave till their demands are met.</p>

<p>The 72-year-old former premier issued a "final call" on November 13 for nationwide protests on November 24, denouncing what he termed as the stolen mandate, the unjust arrests of people and the passage of the 26th amendment, which he said has strengthened a "dictatorial regime".</p>

<p>The PTI supreme leader also revealed that he was threatened with being tried in a military court.</p>

<p>"To those threatening me with trial in military courts, I have a clear message: Do whatever you want, I will not waver from my stance," Khan said.</p>

<p>Khan further said that on Federal Interior Minister Mohsin Naqvi's orders, Rangers and police opened fire and shelled PTI workers, killing and injuring peaceful citizens.</p>

<p>"Naqvi will be held accountable for this. Despite the brutality, our people not only remained peaceful but also helped rescue injured police and Rangers personnel who had attacked them," he said.</p>

<p>The former premier also thanked Pakistanis living abroad who are mobilising support, sending funds, and organising historic protests in their respective countries.</p>

<p>"To our social media warriors around the world, keep amplifying our demands and exposing the injustices happening in Pakistan. Your efforts are crucial in keeping the world informed," Khan said.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Naqvi said no talks will be held with protesters and the government will clear Islamabad from them.</p>

<p>Khan's supporters reached the heart of Pakistan's capital on Tuesday after battling police in clashes that killed six security personnel and injured dozens.</p>

<p>TV channels showed footage of Khan's supporters facing tear gas and climbing on the shipping containers placed on the roads leading to D-Chowk, which is located close to several important government buildings: the Presidency, the PM Office, the Parliament, and the Supreme Court.</p>

<p>The top leaders of the PTI, who led protesters from other parts of the country to Islamabad, have vowed to remain in the city until Khan was released from jail.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, a case was registered under the anti-terrorism act against the former premier and other PTI leaders over their alleged role in the killing of a police officer during the protest march, it emerged Tuesday.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/1e4teupo_pakistan-protests_625x300_26_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Authorities fire tear gas to scatter protesters in Islamabad.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nato-vows-ukraine-backing-after-russian-missile-intimidation-7112691]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[NATO Vows Ukraine Backing After Russian Missile 'Intimidation']]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nato-vows-ukraine-backing-after-russian-missile-intimidation-7112691]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 26 Nov 2024 22:28:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Putin said the missile attack was in response to Ukraine firing weapons supplied by the United States and Britain into Russia.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>NATO pledged support for Ukraine at talks in Brussels Tuesday after Russia's attempt to "intimidate" Kyiv's backers by firing an experimental hypersonic intermediate-range missile last week.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Russia on Thursday carried out a strike on the Ukrainian city of Dnipro which President Vladimir Putin said was a test of its new Oreshnik missile.</p>

<p>Putin said the missile attack was in response to Ukraine firing weapons supplied by the United States and Britain into Russia.</p>

<p>The Kremlin leader warned that Moscow felt "entitled" to hit military facilities in countries that allow Ukraine to use their weapons against Russia.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"During the meeting, NATO allies reaffirmed their support for Ukraine," the alliance said in a statement after the talks. &nbsp;</p>

<p>"The attack, which targeted Dnipro, is seen as another attempt by Russia to terrorise the civilian population in Ukraine and intimidate those who support Ukraine as it defends itself against Russia's illegal and unprovoked aggression."</p>

<p>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky had called the strike "the latest bout of Russian madness" and appealed for updated air-defence systems to meet the new threat.</p>

<p>Kyiv called for "concrete and meaningful outcomes" after calling the meeting of the NATO-Ukraine Council.&nbsp;</p>

<p>A NATO official said Ukraine identified air defence systems that it needs to try to counter the new missile threat from Moscow ahead of a gathering of alliance foreign ministers in Brussels next week.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Some allies hinted that they could make announcements at the meeting next week on fresh air defences for Kyiv, the official said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The escalating tensions over Ukraine come as questions hang over the future of Western support following the re-election of Donald Trump in main NATO power the United States.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Moscow on Tuesday pledged "retaliatory actions" to fresh Ukrainian air attacks inside Russia using US-supplied ATACMS missiles.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In a rare admission, Russia said the fresh strikes had caused damage to military hardware and wounded some of its personnel on the ground in the Kursk region.</p>

<p>Trump has cast doubt on maintaining Washington's vast military aid for Kyiv and pledged a quick deal to end the war. &nbsp;</p>

<p>On the battlefield, Ukraine's fatigued troops are struggling to halt advances by Russian forces in the east of the country.&nbsp;</p>

<p>NATO and Ukraine established the joint council in 2023 that allows Kyiv to call meetings with the alliance when it sees fit.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ijptq1r8_-storm-shadow-missiles-afp_625x300_26_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[After US Missile, Ukraine Fires UK's 'Storm Shadow' Into Russia]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>