<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Nov 2024 17:12:20 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/now-that-he-has-won-will-trump-try-to-unite-america-again-7026345]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: Will Trump Try To Unite America? What His Nominations Tell Us]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/now-that-he-has-won-will-trump-try-to-unite-america-again-7026345]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Nov 2024 16:46:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[If you're looking for an insight that helps explain what happened in the US election and why it happened, consider this observation from a key player in US politics: "There is a difference between what offends people and what affects them."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/8iek7258_donald-trump-afp_625x300_09_November_24.jpeg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>If you're looking for an insight that helps explain what happened in the US Presidential election and why it happened, consider this observation from a key player in US politics: “There is a difference between what offends people and what affects them.”</p>

<p>Donald Trump offends people as if it were a religion. His constant lying offends; his cruelty offends; his racism offends; his misogyny offends; his open contempt for “losers” offends; his lack of remorse offends; his vanity offends; his affinity for chaos offends; his admiration for dictators offends; his vow for retribution and revenge against the “enemies of the people” (anyone who has crossed him or might cross him) offends; his promise to begin “mass deportation” of “25 million” illegal immigrants on Day 1 offends; his vow to upend world trade by imposing a 20% tariff on all goods and 60% on Chinese goods offends; his promise to “protect women whether they like it or not” offends; his commitment to dismiss climate change and pursue a “drill, baby, drill” energy policy offends; his commitment to end Obamacare offends. The list is endless.</p>

<h2><strong>It's Trump's World...</strong></h2>

<p>Yet, Trump is the first Republican in 20 years to win the popular vote, and the MAGA movement has given him unfettered power by securing both the Senate and the House. The US Supreme Court is already aligned with him 6-3 and has effectively granted him virtual immunity from any presidential acts. Project 2025 has a blueprint ready to fulfil his promise to crush the “Deep State” (i.e., federal officials committed to the Constitution and the rule of law) and replace up to 50,000 federal employees with loyalists. The independence of the Federal Reserve and the Justice Department will be under threat. All of this has been clear as daylight since Trump announced his re-run in December 2022.</p>

<p>But Trump won because he successfully positioned himself as the Agent of Change (‘Trump will Fix It'), addressing the issues that affect his core voter base—62% of Americans without a college degree. These voters, who typically show little interest in politics but are deeply focused on improving their material well-being and preserving their cultural values, were key to his success.</p>

<p>And what affects them? Some of the most important issues include rising costs over the last four years: grocery prices up 20%, rents up 40%. There are also concerns about men's self-image: girls outperforming boys in school and college, the #MeToo movement, and college-educated women seeing the highest increases in income and status. Then there is what many perceive as the imposition of ‘Wokeism': it's not just about accepting the full rights and recognition of the LGBTQ community, but also about children having the right to change their gender before adulthood.</p>

<h2><strong>The Fear Of Immigrants</strong></h2>

<p>In some cases, there are deeply held beliefs based on fear and misinformation. I know a Texas-based psychotherapist whose patient confided that she was afraid to go out at night due to fear of immigrants, even though she employs a migrant—likely an undocumented worker—as a housekeeper. Another patient believes Trump was sent by God and that the opposition party was sent by the Devil. Neither patient suffers from psychosis; these are culturally sanctioned beliefs, according to the therapist.</p>

<p>Finally, there are outright misconceptions—such as the belief that tariffs won't raise the cost of household goods, or that Trump's first term, with no new wars, proves he could end the Ukraine and Middle East conflicts immediately upon taking office. There is also the notion that the mass deportation of illegal immigrants would not cripple industries that rely heavily on immigrant labour, like the US meat industry. According to The Economist, roughly half of the labour on US farms is undocumented.</p>

<p>This same Texas-based psychotherapist couldn't believe his eyes when he saw a massive billboard in rural Texas proclaiming, “Born in New York, Thinks Like a Texan.” That's the story Trump sold to voters. And in politics—especially electoral politics—perception is reality.</p>

<h2><strong>Is There Really A Tectonic Shift?</strong></h2>

<p>Yet, even in the face of what some view as an impending apocalypse for the Democratic Party, it's important to note that Trump's win in the popular vote was narrow: 75.8 million votes (50.2%) to Kamala Harris's 72.8 million votes (48.2%), with nearly all votes counted. In 2016, Biden led Trump by 7 million votes. But credit where it's due—Trump won the popular vote by actively pursuing it, rallying supporters in New York and California, even though those blue states' electoral college votes were never in play for him. This effort came in the final weeks of the campaign when conventional wisdom would suggest focusing on the seven key swing states.</p>

<p>How true is the talk of a tectonic shift in the vote and the creation of a new Republican social coalition? It is true that the identity that moved the non-White vote to Trump was their working-class, non-college-educated identity. These voters believed that Trump would do a better job of bringing back jobs lost to Mexico, addressing their affordability crisis, preserving their conservative cultural values, and securing their legal immigrant status by deporting illegal immigrants.</p>

<p>None of this should have come as a surprise. Pre-election polls from <em>The New York Times </em>found a surprising affinity between Trump's views and those of Latinos and Black voters. Four out of ten Hispanic voters and one out of five Black voters had a favourable impression of Trump. A majority of them sympathized with his “America First” foreign policy. Only 20% of Hispanic voters and 26% of Black voters felt that the economic conditions were good or excellent. Median weekly wages for full-time Black workers had risen steeply during Trump's presidency but essentially stagnated under Biden.</p>

<p>However, in absolute numbers, the shift in the non-White vote has not been as significant as it is often portrayed, as columnist Thomas Edsall points out in the <em>NYT</em>. “Roughly six in ten Hispanics voted for Joe Biden; five in ten for Kamala Harris. Nine out of ten Black voters chose Biden; eight in ten for Harris. More than four-fifths of Trump's votes came from White voters.”</p>

<p>Trump won because he has excellent political instincts and because people know exactly what he stands for. His views on trade and immigration were shaped years before he entered politics. “I believe very strongly in tariffs,” he told a journalist in 1989. “America is being ripped off.” In his 2000 book,&nbsp;<em>The America We Deserve</em>, he wrote that “our current laxness toward illegal immigration shows a recklessness and disregard for those who live here legally.”</p>

<h2><strong>Rich-Poor Divide</strong></h2>

<p>What is particularly disturbing for the Democratic Party is that this election has reinforced the post-2012 electoral reality: the less well-off are siding with Trump, while the college-educated, coastal elites are aligned with the Democrats. With White Americans comprising 67% of the population and 62% of Americans lacking a college degree, the Democrats will need to look beyond conventional politicians—those who twist and turn their positions to conform, always erring on the side of caution—to lead the fightback.</p>

<p>Yet, as we all know, Trump can be his own worst enemy. He is entirely transactional. For him, loyalty is always one-way. His insecurity prevents him from sharing the limelight with anyone else. His vanity leaves him vulnerable to manipulation. Not surprisingly, he is not the best judge of character, and his loyalists continue to cycle through a revolving door.</p>

<h2><strong>Team Trump, 2.0</strong></h2>

<p>The quote at the beginning of this column is from Kellyanne Conway, the Republican pollster who worked with Trump from 2013 and managed his 2016 campaign. She later joined the first Trump administration but left amid a public feud with her teenage daughter in August 2020, who lambasted her personally and politically and even threatened legal separation.</p>

<p>Conway is not the only person who was once with Trump but is no longer. Steve Bannon, Trump's chief ideologue and speechwriter, is not in the fold anymore. In his place is Stephen Miller, the architect of Trump's hardline immigration policies. Trump's daughter Ivanka and son-in-law Jared Kushner have been replaced by Don Jr., who is now in charge of conducting the “loyalty test” for anyone seeking to join the administration. John Kelly, Trump's longest-serving Chief of Staff who called him a “fascist,” has been replaced by Susie Wiles, Trump's campaign manager. Wiles is known for her discipline and focus on facilitating whatever catches Trump's fancy. The big question is: how long will she last?</p>

<p>The <em>New York Times</em>—which Trump both loathes and loves to read—has come in for criticism for suggesting that Trump will be a “lame duck” president, given that the 22nd Amendment to the US Constitution prohibits a third presidential term. Critics accused the paper of sour grapes. However, in an unintended way, the paper has highlighted Trump's main dilemma: what legacy does he want to leave behind? He has mined the deep divide and distrust of Washington in US society to become the most dominant figure in American politics for the past decade. Does he now pivot to statesmanship and attempt to unite the country? Or does he pander to his MAGA base and give full rein to his thirst for revenge?</p>

<h2><strong>Rein Of Uncertainty</strong></h2>

<p>The early signs are ominous. Trump's nomination of the highly controversial Congressman Matt Gaetz, who is under investigation for ethics violations, as Attorney General has even alarmed <em>The Wall Street Journal</em>. “He's a nominee for those who want the law used for political revenge, and it won't end well,” the paper warned.</p>

<p>Similarly, the case of <em>Fox News </em>host Pete Hegseth, who has been outspoken against the Pentagon's “woke” policies regarding racial and transgender equity, and the appointment of former Democratic presidential contender Tulsi Gabbard, now a Trump loyalist, as Director of National Intelligence, raise further concerns. Gabbard has shown no evidence of expertise in intelligence. No one should be surprised by this turn of events.</p>

<p><em>(Ajay Kumar is a senior journalist. He is the former Managing Editor, Business Standard, and former Executive Editor, Economic Times.)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/8iek7258_donald-trump-afp_625x300_09_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-anura-kumara-dissanayake-president-of-sri-lanka-7026120]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Meet Anura Kumara Dissanayake, Sri Lanka's New President]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-anura-kumara-dissanayake-president-of-sri-lanka-7026120]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Nov 2024 16:18:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Anura Kumara Dissanayake was born in Thambuththegama, Sri Lanka, into a working-class family.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sri Lankan President <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sri-lanka-election-results-president-anura-dissanayakes-national-peoples-power-party-wins-parliamentary-majority-7023890">Anura Kumara Dissanayake</a>'s leftist coalition, the National People's Power (NPP), secured a decisive victory in snap legislative elections, with voters rejecting establishment parties widely criticised for sparking an economic crisis. The election results, released Friday, showed overwhelming support for Mr Dissanayake's anti-corruption platform and promise to recover assets lost due to corruption.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The self-avowed Marxist called for swift parliamentary polls to consolidate backing for his reform agenda. Friday results showed his decision paid off, with the NPP capturing at least 123 seats in the 225-member parliament, with projections suggesting further gains. Early tallies showed the NPP with 62 per cent of the vote, far ahead of opposition leader Sajith Premadasa's party, which trailed with just 18 per cent.<br />
<br />
<strong>Here are some facts about Anura Kumara Dissanayake:</strong></p>

<ul>
	<li>Anura Kumara Dissanayake was born on November 24, 1968, in Thambuththegama, Sri Lanka, into a working-class family. His father was a labourer, and his mother a housewife. Mr Dissanayake was involved in the Janatha Vimukthi Peramuna (JVP) party during his school years and was the first student from the college chosen for admission into the university.</li>
	<li>He studied at the University of Peradeniya before leaving due to threats during the political unrest of the 1987-1989 JVP insurrection. Mr Dissanayake later graduated from the University of Kelaniya with a degree in physical science in 1995.</li>
	<li>Mr Dissanayake rapidly rose through the ranks of the JVP. By 1995, he was appointed the National Organiser of the Socialist Students Association and joined the JVP's Central Working Committee. By 1998, he secured a position in the JVP's Politburo. This was significant as the JVP re-entered mainstream politics under Somawansa Amarasinghe, initially supporting President Chandrika Kumaratunga's government before eventually criticising it over various issues.</li>
	<li>In 2004, Mr Dissanayake was appointed as a cabinet minister in President Chandrika Kumaratunga's government. He handled portfolios like agriculture, livestock, land, and irrigation. A year later, Mr Dissanayake and other JVP ministers resigned in protest against a joint agreement between the Sri Lankan government and the LTTE for tsunami relief coordination.&nbsp;</li>
	<li>Mr Dissanayake became the leader of the JVP in 2014, succeeding Somawansa Amarasinghe. He ran as the JVP's presidential candidate in 2019, securing third place with 3 per cent of the vote. He again announced his candidacy for the 2024 presidential elections under the banner of the National People's Power (NPP), a leftist coalition he built. He made a remarkable comeback, winning 42.31 per cent of the vote in the first round and 55.89 per cent in the second round.</li>
	<li>Anura Kumara Dissanayake was inaugurated as president on September 23. He is a Marxist politician who made history by becoming the country's first president from a third party. He has been a vocal critic of Sri Lanka's economic policies, particularly those that he views as necessary to the country's working class. He strongly opposed the IMF's conditions for a $2.9 billion bailout, advocating for a renegotiation of terms, tax reductions like the Pay-As-You-Earn tax, and the elimination of VAT on essential goods.</li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/g6mc2kfg_anura-kumara-dissanayake_625x300_15_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sri Lankan President Anura Kumara Dissanayake]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/saudi-minister-dr-osama-faqeeha-cites-indias-efforts-in-fighting-land-degradation-drought-7026029]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Saudi Minister Cites India's Efforts In Fighting Land Degradation, Drought]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/saudi-minister-dr-osama-faqeeha-cites-indias-efforts-in-fighting-land-degradation-drought-7026029]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Nov 2024 16:04:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[As Saudi capital Riyadh gets ready to host the Conference of the Parties (COP16) of the United Nations Convention to Combat Desertification (UNCCD), Dr Osama Faqeeha, Deputy Minister of Environment, Water and Agriculture, has praised India's efforts.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As Saudi capital Riyadh gets ready to host the Conference of the Parties (COP16) of the United Nations Convention to Combat Desertification (UNCCD), Dr Osama Faqeeha, Deputy Minister of Environment, Water and Agriculture, has praised India's efforts on combating land degradation and drought.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Dr Faqeeha, who is also an advisor to the UNCCD COP16 Presidency, in an email interview, mentioned the "success stories" from Rajasthan and Andhra Pradesh. "For instance, in Rajasthan's Lapodia village, the revival of traditional water harvesting systems has not only raised water tables but also regenerated degraded grasslands, inspiring over 50 neighbouring villages to adopt similar practices," he said.</p>

<p>Lapodia village today stands out like a green oasis in Rajasthan. This village, with a little over 300 households is just two hours from state capital Jaipur, transformed itself into a drought-proof village mostly through the revival of traditional water-harvesting structures.</p>

<p>Highlighting another Indian success story, Dr Faqeeha spoke about "the remarkable transformation achieved by Renuka Bio Farms in Andhra Pradesh's Tirupati district". "It shows how combining traditional wisdom with modern techniques can convert barren wetland into thriving agro-ecological systems".</p>

<p>&nbsp;"These stories demonstrate the transformative power of local initiatives in combating land degradation. These initiatives exemplify exactly what we hope to showcase and amplify at COP16 in Riyadh - practical, community-driven solutions that can be adapted and replicated globally," he said.</p>

<p>Highlighting similarities between Saudi and Indian desert region of Rajasthan, the Saudi minister emphasised &nbsp;on creating natural opportunities for collaboration and knowledge exchange.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The arid climate challenges we face in Saudi Arabia share many similarities with regions like Rajasthan. In Saudi Arabia we are focusing on utilizing renewable water resources, leveraging water conservation practices, and pursuing ambitious rural development programmes."<br />
&nbsp;<br />
"Successful initiatives like the Ghandivan project in Jaipur, which has transformed barren wasteland into a thriving ecosystem through community-driven efforts, offer valuable insights that can be adapted across different regions."<br />
&nbsp;<br />
He added that Riyadh will create platforms for sharing such experiences and best practices to benefit countries, regions, and the planet at COP16.</p>

<p>Speaking on the Saudi's primary goals for the presidency of COP16, Dr Faqeeha stated that the focused is on raising awareness of the impact of land degradation, drought, and desertification. "The scale of our challenge is stark: globally, we lose land equivalent to four football fields every second, amounting to 100 million hectares annually."</p>

<p>"COP16 in Riyadh represents a crucial turning point in our global response to land degradation and drought. By bringing together stakeholders from across sectors and generations, we will catalyse a new era of environmental action characterised by concrete commitments, innovative solutions, and meaningful collaboration."</p>

<p>The Conference of the Parties (COP16) of the United Nations Convention to Combat Desertification (UNCCD) will take place in Riyadh from 2 to 13 December 2024.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/usht4ru_saudi-min_625x300_15_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Dr Osama Faqeeha, Deputy Minister of Environment, Water and Agriculture in Saudi Arabia]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/more-than-80-of-indians-exposed-to-climate-related-health-risks-ex-who-chief-scientist-7025881]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[More Than 80% Of Indians Exposed To Climate-Related Health Risks]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/more-than-80-of-indians-exposed-to-climate-related-health-risks-ex-who-chief-scientist-7025881]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Nov 2024 15:42:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Almost everyone in India is now vulnerable to the impacts of climate change, former chief scientist of the World Health Organisation Dr Soumya Swaminathan has said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Almost everyone in India is now vulnerable to the impacts of climate change, former chief scientist of the World Health Organisation Dr Soumya Swaminathan has said, underscoring the urgent need for cross-ministerial and international collaboration to address its effects on health, gender and economic stability in the country.</p>

<p>Swaminathan pointed to women and children as especially vulnerable to these climate-driven health risks.</p>

<p>In an interview with PTI on the sidelines of global climate talks COP29 here in Azerbaijan's capital, Swaminathan called for a concerted approach, saying, "practically everyone in India is now vulnerable to climate change impacts, from extreme heat to vector-borne diseases. Addressing this requires close cooperation."</p>

<p>"We know that climate change has disproportionate impacts on women and children," she explained, noting how women, particularly in rural areas, face increased health risks due to continued reliance on solid fuels for cooking.</p>

<p>She emphasised that "access to clean energy for everyone is a priority."</p>

<p>This, she argued, would not only reduce health risks associated with indoor air pollution but also lessen India's carbon footprint, marking a crucial step toward sustainable development.</p>

<p>Climate-related health risks in India are varied, ranging from immediate effects such as respiratory illnesses due to air pollution, to long-term issues like malnutrition stemming from disrupted agricultural cycles.</p>

<p>Swaminathan noted that more than 80 per cent of India's population is now exposed to these risks, emphasizing that "everybody is now vulnerable," from rural farmers to urban migrants.</p>

<p>She highlighted the specific challenges faced by the urban poor, especially migrants who live in peri-urban areas with inadequate housing and sanitation, which exposes them to greater risks during floods and extreme weather events.</p>

<p>With health as a central theme, Swaminathan stressed the benefits of green public transportation, an initiative she described as a "win-win solution."</p>

<p>"Carbon-neutral public transport will not only reduce air pollution but also promote physical activity and thereby improve health," she said, adding that reducing pollution would positively impact public health by curbing respiratory and cardiovascular diseases.</p>

<p>She also highlighted that India's urban centres are hotspots for these health issues due to dense populations and high pollution levels.</p>

<p>Swaminathan called for policies that integrate both health and climate objectives, stressing that this approach can drive development while building resilience against climate risks.</p>

<p>"If we do that kind of analysis, we can invest in actions that promote both development and reduce our carbon footprint," she noted, advocating for policies that prioritise "development with a climate-resilient focus."</p>

<p>Examples of such integrated actions include promoting clean cooking fuels, improving access to safe drinking water, and investing in infrastructure that can withstand extreme weather.</p>

<p>Dr Swaminathan went further to advocate for a gendered approach to climate policy, urging policymakers to "put a spotlight on women but also the poorest communities."</p>

<p>She argued that gender equity and social equity are essential to effective climate policy, explaining that "by taking a gendered perspective in all policies, we can ensure more inclusive and effective climate action."</p>

<p>Swaminathan called for greater research on climate impacts that are gender-specific, noting that this data would help policymakers create more targeted, meaningful interventions.</p>

<p>The economic costs of climate-driven health impacts are also severe.</p>

<p>Swaminathan pointed to recent studies indicating that climate-related air pollution alone costs the global economy trillions of dollars annually, affecting productivity, agriculture, and even tourism.</p>

<p>"If you look at the GDP loss and workplace productivity lost due to air pollution, it's enormous - in the trillions," she said. This, she argued, makes climate action not just a moral imperative but an economic necessity.</p>

<p>Addressing air pollution as a cross-border issue, Swaminathan noted that pollution does not recognise borders, making it crucial for India and other nations to engage in global collaborations.</p>

<p>"Air pollution today is the single largest risk factor to health," she said, adding "It's not a problem one country can solve on its own."</p>

<p>She referenced the Our Common Air (OCA) Commission, a global effort she is part of, which has been working with international bodies like WHO and UNEP to promote global standards and monitoring mechanisms for air quality.</p>

<p>"We need a system where every country has air quality monitors and updates its data, including on super pollutants like methane and black carbon," Swaminathan said, adding that these pollutants are highly dangerous yet often overlooked.</p>

<p>Swaminathan further explained the value of local data, which she argued would give a more accurate picture of pollution's impact on different regions of India.</p>

<p>"Policymakers want to see data from their own regions; it makes the issue real for them and helps design local solutions," she said.</p>

<p>Reflecting on the invisible nature of pollution's health impacts, Swaminathan commented, "When the air pollution is visible, people recognize it as a problem, but often it's invisible, and people become accustomed to it."</p>

<p>She stressed that while death rates from pollution-related illnesses are often discussed, policymakers should focus on the widespread chronic illnesses caused by poor air quality.</p>

<p>"It's not only about death - it's about chronic ill health that impacts quality of life and productivity," she said, pointing out that young children and the elderly are especially vulnerable.</p>

<p>For Swaminathan, tackling climate change is fundamentally linked to India's development goals.</p>

<p>"For us, development is still a key priority," she asserted. While India has made strides in increasing access to electricity and clean water, she stressed that much work remains, especially in rural areas where communities lack basic infrastructure.</p>

<p>Her vision for India's climate adaptation involves not only mitigating health risks but also ensuring that development initiatives - from housing to sanitation - are climate-resilient.</p>

<p>Swaminathan expressed optimism about India's potential to lead in climate adaptation through innovation, global cooperation, and commitment to sustainable development goals.</p>

<p>She pointed to Indian cities as potential leaders in air quality initiatives and green infrastructure, stating that "India can be a model for sustainable urbanization if we prioritize both development and environmental health."</p>

<p></p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/q316ihd8_pollution_625x300_15_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[More than 80 per cent of India's population is now exposed to climate-related health risks]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/demand-for-abortion-pills-soars-in-us-after-trump-win-7025760]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Demand For Abortion Pill Requests Soars In US After Trump Win]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/demand-for-abortion-pills-soars-in-us-after-trump-win-7025760]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Nov 2024 15:26:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Aid Access, the leading supplier of abortion pills by mail in the US, received over 5,000 requests in less than 12 hours.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There's been a massive rise in the demand for abortion pills in the United States after Donald Trump's re-election to the White House. It stems from fears that under Trump 2.0, the country may face unprecedented restrictions as far as reproductive care is concerned.</p>

<p>Aid Access, the leading supplier of abortion pills by mail in the US, received over 5,000 requests in less than 12 hours. “I can see all the new requests ticking in as we're talking,” founder Rebecca&nbsp;Gomperts told <a href="http://https://amp.theguardian.com/us-news/2024/nov/07/abortion-pills-hormones-trump " rel="nofollow,noindex">the Guardian</a>. “We've never seen this before.”</p>

<p>For Ms Gomperts, this wave of demand was not unexpected. Aid Access has established a streamlined system where physicians in abortion-legal states prescribe and ship pills to those in states with bans. Still, the sheer volume on Wednesday was huge. “We have an extremely streamlined process... but it's much more [than usual],” Ms Gomperts remarked.</p>

<p>Similar trends were observed across the country. Telehealth services like Wisp saw a 300 per cent increase in requests for emergency contraception, while Plan C, an abortion pill finder site, experienced a 625 per cent surge in traffic. “People are trying to plan for the reproductive apocalypse that we anticipate will be happening under a Trump presidency,” said Elisa Wells, co-founder of Plan C.</p>

<p>Women's health providers also experienced a dramatic rise in demand for emergency contraception. Wisp tripled its daily sales of Plan B by mid-morning Wednesday, with bulk orders increasing from 30 per cent of monthly sales to nearly 90 per cent in a single day. Similarly, Winx, another telehealth service, reported selling six times more doses of Plan B by Wednesday afternoon than in the previous week.</p>

<p>Transgender healthcare providers also faced a deluge of requests. Dr Crystal Beal, founder of QueerDoc, received an influx of inquiries from trans patients worried about access to hormone therapy. QueerDoc received more patient messages in one day than it typically would in a week. “Some of it is ‘How can I safeguard my access to medication?'” Ms Beal shared, citing concerns about the potential rollback of trans healthcare rights under Trump's administration. QueerDoc is now advising patients to stockpile hormone medications within the bounds of state laws and insurance limits.</p>

<p>Donald Trump's stance on abortion has oscillated, but his judicial appointments have consistently called for abortion restrictions, particularly in conservative states. Despite his campaign promise not to impose a nationwide abortion ban, experts say there are indirect ways his administration could restrict access.</p>

<p>A focus is likely on abortion pills, which accounted for 63 per cent of abortions in 2023. Measures could include stricter FDA rules requiring in-person dispensing or legal challenges under the 1873 Comstock Act, which could target pill distribution.</p>

<p>Although state-level decisions remain important, Trump's previous stance and actions, like appointing justices to overturn Roe v Wade, are&nbsp;a cause of concern.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-01/o2m0025_abortion_625x300_04_January_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/ai/elon-musk-escalates-legal-feud-with-sam-altman-alleges-openai-a-monopolist-7025722]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk Escalates Legal Feud With Sam Altman, Alleges OpenAI A "Monopolist"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/ai/elon-musk-escalates-legal-feud-with-sam-altman-alleges-openai-a-monopolist-7025722]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Nov 2024 15:20:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Musk said in the filing that the company "has attempted to starve competitors of AI talent by aggressively recruiting employees with offers of lavish compensation and is on track to spend $1.5 billion on personnel for just 1,500 employees."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Elon Musk is ramping up his feud with Sam Altman, alleging in a court filing that OpenAI is trying to corner the market for generative artificial intelligence and sacrificing safety in a race to get ahead.</p>

<p>In a revised version of a lawsuit he filed in August, Musk highlighted antitrust concerns about OpenAI's journey from its nonprofit roots in 2015 - when he and Altman worked together as founders - to its current effort to restructure as a for-profit company following billions of dollars in outside investment by Microsoft and others.</p>

<p>Musk, who launched his xAI startup last year, said OpenAI has now abandoned all pretence of proceeding as a charity to benefit humanity with a focus on openness and safety as it tries to complete its restructuring under a two-year deadline.</p>

<p>"Microsoft and OpenAI, apparently unsatisfied with their monopoly, or near so, in generative artificial intelligence ("AI") are now actively trying to eliminate competitors, such as xAI, by extracting promises from investors not to fund them," lawyers for the billionaire wrote in the amended complaint filed late Thursday in federal court in Oakland, California.</p>

<p>OpenAI didn't immediately respond outside regular business hours to a request for comment. In October, it called Musk's federal suit - which followed a state-court suit that Musk dropped - the latest bid in an "increasingly blusterous campaign to harass OpenAI for his own competitive advantage."</p>

<p>The revised suit lists 26 legal claims and runs 107 pages, compared with 15 claims in the 83-page original complaint.</p>

<p>Thursday's filing adds California Attorney General Rob Bonta as a defendant. The company is in early talks with Bonta's office over the process to change its corporate structure, Bloomberg News reported this month.</p>

<p>Representatives of Bonta's office didn't immediately respond outside regular business hours to a request for comment.</p>

<p>To back up his claim that OpenAI is becoming more anticompetitive, Musk said in the filing that the company "has attempted to starve competitors of AI talent by aggressively recruiting employees with offers of lavish compensation and is on track to spend $1.5 billion on personnel for just 1,500 employees."</p>

<p>Musk also expressed concern that OpenAI has "started to contract with the Department of Defence" and removed a clause from its usage policies banning the use of its technology for "activity that has a high risk of physical harm" such as "weapons development" or "military and warfare."</p>

<p>According to the filing, "droves" of security researchers are resigning in protest, or being forced out, and safety teams have been dissolved, "all to make way for 'security' personnel whose real job is to facilitate military contracting.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/3372eojg_sam-vs-elon_625x300_15_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/five-under-the-radar-travel-destinations-the-un-says-you-should-visit-7025678]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Five Under-The-Radar Travel Destinations The UN Says You Should Visit]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/five-under-the-radar-travel-destinations-the-un-says-you-should-visit-7025678]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Nov 2024 15:15:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[55 small, rural escapes around the world, earned a spot in the 2024 edition of UN Tourisms "Best Tourism Villages."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As a year of travel that was marked largely by overtourism protests in Barcelona, Oaxaca and Venice draws to a close, the appeal of offbeat vacations continues to grow.</p>

<p>To wit, consider these spots you've likely never heard of: secluded Graciosa Island on the Azores, the remote fishing village Roches Noires in northeastern Mauritius, or mountainous Wukirsari, Indonesia, 270 miles east of Jakarta. They're among the 55 small, rural escapes around the world that earned a spot in the 2024 edition of UN Tourism's “Best Tourism Villages.” The list of winning destinations, previewed exclusively by Bloomberg News, was released on Nov. 14 at the organization's Executive Council meeting in Cartagena, Colombia.</p>

<p>The initiative, started in 2021, aims to raise awareness of lesser-known places worth visiting—and also reward responsible tourism management. Put simply, these destinations are using visitation funds in a way that boosts their cultural practices, preserves biodiversity and improves quality of life for locals. Each village also counts fewer than 15,000 inhabitants and maintains traditional activities such as agriculture and fishing.</p>

<p>“The Best Tourism Villages initiative not only recognizes the remarkable achievements of these villages but also highlights the transformative power of tourism,” says UN Tourism Secretary-General Zurab Pololikashvili.</p>

<p>Among this year's worthy escapes are rural villages in Panama and Guatemala, two countries appearing on the list for the first time. Panama's historic northern port of Portobelo, for example, draws smaller crowds despite its tranquil Caribbean beaches and significant colonial past. But it also stood out because tourism there helps fund cultural heritage preservation activities for youth through the Bahía de Portobelo Foundation, as well as coral reef restoration projects.</p>

<p>Appearing on this coveted list can lead to increased visitation from higher-spending travelers, too. For instance, in Aragon, Spain, the village of Alquezar's mountain trekking, canyoning and hiking used to draw mostly visitors from France and Spain, but since its win in 2022, international visitors from Japan and China have vacationed there, according to Alquezar Mayor Ana Blasco Castillo. Sandra Carvao, who helps develop rural tourism as a director at UN Tourism, sees this as one of the major pluses of the Best Tourism Villages initiative, in addition to diverting travelers from major hot spots. “It's really to make sure that the sector can benefit places which wouldn't necessarily be top of your mind,” she says.</p>

<p>This year's winners were selected from 260 nominations that UN Tourism received from more than 60 member countries. We highlighted five that are easily accessible.</p>

<p><strong>Splugen, Switzerland</strong></p>

<p>Splugen, in the Swiss Alps near the Italian border, is smaller in size as a ski getaway than, say, the busier and glitzy St. Moritz just an hour-and-a-half scenic drive east. But that's exactly the draw: It's a quieter winter sports vacation destination that doubles as an under-the-radar spot in the spring and summer, with access to crystal clear lakes and Beverin Regional Nature Park. Splügen became part of this protected area in 2020, joining more than 10 communities living here who've committed to play a part in preserving it. Next year boutique property Speluca Brewery Hotel is set to open; its design makes use of formerly abandoned spaces on the village's outskirts, including an old barn and a former hotel from the 1960s, plus new structures that will reflect the village's traditional timber aesthetic. Splügen's communities want to attract more year-round visitors as well, whom they expect once the future Rheinwald Resort AG project is completed, featuring a mix of rooms and a campsite for long-term stays.</p>

<p><strong>San Rafael de la Laguna, Ecuador</strong></p>

<p>San Rafael de la Laguna serves as a reminder of Ecuador's outsize natural riches—sitting in the foothills of the Andes, just under a two-hour drive north of Quito. It's close to Imbakucha, or the lake of the gods, also commonly known as Lago San Pablo. You can hop on guided tours to spot herons and ducks from traditional boats made from totora reeds, a local aquatic plant growing abundantly in the area. Cycling enthusiasts will find routes that traverse the Otavalo Valley, and the village also celebrates vibrant Indigenous rooted festivals. The Pawkar Raymi marks the start of the agricultural season in early March, in alignment with the spring equinox, and the Inti Raymi celebrates the winter solstice in the Southern Hemisphere. Expect plenty of community events for both, including traditional Andean music and dance. If you're more into hands-on experiences, craft workshops teach you to make baskets, trays and hats out of totora reeds.</p>

<p><strong>Gharb Suhayl, Egypt</strong></p>

<p>If you're set on visiting the Grand Egyptian Museum in 2025, it would be worth including a stop in Aswan, south of Giza. From there, hop on a 30-minute boat ride south to reach the peaceful, ancient Nubian village of Gharb Suhayl, set on the banks of the Nile. Beyond its brightly painted homes in blue, yellow and ocher, you'll find striking art murals, said to give the area the feel of a living outdoor museum. You're likely to be invited into a Nubian family's home to learn about the way of life, and you could also spend time shopping in souks for crafts, jewelry and spices. A handful of luxury tour operators, such as Black Tomato, offer stops in Aswan, continuing down the Nile to Abu Simbel.</p>

<p><strong>Pissouri, Cyprus</strong></p>

<p>On Cyprus' rugged southwestern coast, Pissouri offers a quieter alternative to resort town Limassol, which lies just a 30-minute drive east. You'll have your pick of outdoor activities in Pissouri, including the Cape Astrot hiking trail, tucked along gigantic rock formations, for jaw-dropping vistas over a turquoise bay and its pebble sand beach. The agricultural village's cobblestoned square is lined with local tavernas where you can dine on Cypriot meze—small plates of local cheeses, olives, seafood and grilled meats, as well as dips. For a deeper dive into Pissouri's heritage, get a guided tour at G Theophamous Winery on the history of Pissouri's Sultanina grape and winemaking traditions. To draw more visitors in the future, this small agricultural village is working on an accessible hiking trail for disabled travelers, as well as a House of Halloumi Museum— named after Cyprus' signature cheese—that will showcase this region's dairy products.</p>

<p><strong>Uaxactún, Guatemala</strong></p>

<p>Most people head to Tikal National Park and unknowingly bypass Uaxactún, an ancient Mayan historical site located just a 30-minute drive north. But it counts uncrowded forest trails where you can observe the area's temples, including a ceremonial complex, stelae and an astronomy observatory that the Maya once used to mark celestial events. Uaxactún was at its peak from 600 A.D. to 900 A.D., when it was an important center for art and astronomy. In March the eponymous village celebrates the spring equinox festival through sacred ceremonies at the site that include chants, fires and drumming. Inquire about a craftmaking workshop with local women's group Brisas de la Selva Maya, where you'll learn to make necklaces and bracelets from forest-sourced elements such as seeds, mushrooms and flowers.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/mscu02j8_switzerland_625x300_15_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/passengers-to-witness-two-sunrises-on-the-worlds-longest-flight-taking-off-in-2026-7025593]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Passengers To See 2 Sunrises On World's Longest Flight Taking Off In 2026]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/passengers-to-witness-two-sunrises-on-the-worlds-longest-flight-taking-off-in-2026-7025593]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Nov 2024 15:03:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Passengers will experience two sunrises on this record-breaking journey, made possible by specially designed Airbus A350 aircraft.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Long-haul flights have become a common feature of contemporary travel, with trips lasting ten to fifteen hours now being accepted as normal. The 17-hour journey from Perth to London and well-known destinations like Dubai or New York for city vacations no longer seem unusual.</p>

<p>However, Australian airline Qantas, one of the leading airlines in the world, is trying to revolutionise long-haul air travel with its bold Project Sunrise, according to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://metro.co.uk/2024/11/14/longest-flight-world-passengers-see-two-sunrises-set-take-off-2026-21992081/"><em>The Metro</em></a>. The airline plans to introduce nonstop flights from Sydney to London and New York, which will cover 19 to 22 hours of distance. These ultra-long-haul flights aim to reduce travel time by up to four hours compared to current options.</p>

<p>The <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.qantas.com/au/en/about-us/our-company/fleet/new-fleet/project-sunrise.html">project </a>is named after the kind of experience that its passengers will have to undergo: that of seeing two sunrises in a row, breaking the world record of the longest commercial flight currently held by Singapore Airlines. It is this route from Singapore to New York, which was not met 18 hours long.</p>

<p>While saving time is appealing, spending nearly a full day in the air presents a significant challenge for travelers. Qantas initiated <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.qantas.com/au/en/about-us/our-company/fleet/new-fleet/project-sunrise.html">Project Sunrise</a> discussions in 2017, collaborating with Boeing and Airbus to develop ultra-long-range versions of their widebody aircraft.</p>

<p>Despite the challenges faced by the aviation industry in recent years, Qantas remains committed to pushing the boundaries of air travel. The first flights under Project Sunrise are expected to take off in 2026, marking a new milestone in aviation history.</p>

<p>According to<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/michaelgoldstein/2024/10/29/inside-project-sunrise-bold-qantas-plan-to-bring-australia-closer/"><em> Forbes,</em></a> Vanessa Hudson, who took over as Qantas CEO last fall, spoke at an event in a hangar at LAX to celebrate Qantas and the upcoming Project Sunrise non-stop flights from Sydney to London and New York. She said that the project speaks to 'Australians hunger to fly point to point.' The upcoming long flights, she said, "are a great way for Australians to break out and see the world on the A350."</p>

<p>As a Qantas website put it, "Our fleet of specially designed Airbus A350s [will]overcome the tyranny of distance, with the ability to travel between Australia and almost any city in the world." Qantas is assuring potential flyers that research and design will make the flights comfortable and safe.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/o2ricpf_qantas_625x300_15_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Qantas is set to redefine air travel with its ambitious Project Sunrise, launching in 2026.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/brother-of-late-mohamed-al-fayed-harrods-owner-accused-of-sexual-violence-report-7025590]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Brother Of Late Harrods Owner Accused Of Sexual Violence: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/brother-of-late-mohamed-al-fayed-harrods-owner-accused-of-sexual-violence-report-7025590]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Nov 2024 15:03:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Three women formerly employed by Harrods have accused the brother of its late boss Mohamed Al-Fayed of sexual violence.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Three women formerly employed by Harrods have accused the brother of its late boss Mohamed Al-Fayed of sexual violence, following hundreds of similar claims against the former owner of the luxury London store, the BBC reported Thursday.</p>

<p>They say the late Salah Fayed assaulted them during the period when he jointly owned the department store with his brother, the broadcaster said.</p>

<p>The women alleged they were abused in London, the south of France and Monaco between 1989 and 1997.</p>

<p>The report follows a slew of claims in recent weeks by hundreds of women against the Egyptian former Harrods and Fulham Football Club owner Mohamed Al-Fayed of sexual assault including rape.</p>

<p>Salah Fayed died in 2010 and Mohamed Al-Fayed died last year aged 94.</p>

<p>One of the three women behind the most recent accusations, named Helen, who waived her right to anonymity, told the BBC that she had been working for the retailer for two years when Mohamed Al-Fayed raped her in 1989 during a business trip in Dubai.</p>

<p>He then offered her a personal assistant job with his brother Salah, who she said went on to drug her and rape her while she was unconscious.</p>

<p>Mohamed Al-Fayed "shared me with his brother," she said.</p>

<p>She said he had stayed silent about the experience, having signed a non-disclosure agreement, a document the BBC reported having seen.</p>

<p>The second woman said Salah Fayed abused her during a trip to Monaco, while the third woman, who was hired at the age of 19 in 1997, said she was sexually assaulted in his Monaco apartment.</p>

<p>Contacted by AFP, Harrods said it "supports the bravery of these women in coming forward" and encourages survivors "to come forward and make their claims" to the company, which is offering compensation and counselling support.</p>

<p>"We also hope that they are looking at every appropriate avenue to them in their pursuit of justice, whether that be Harrods, the police or the Fayed family and estate," the company said.</p>

<p>On Tuesday, the New York Times published the claims of a victim accusing another brother of Mohamed Al-Fayed, Ali, aged 80, of knowing about the "trafficking" of women.</p>

<p>Allegations have mounted since the airing of a BBC documentary in September that detailed multiple claims of rape and sexual assault by Mohamed Al-Fayed.</p>

<p>The Justice for Harrods Survivors group said it had received more than 420 inquiries, mainly related to the store but also regarding Fulham Football Club, the Ritz Hotel in Paris and other Fayed entities.</p>

<p>London's Metropolitan Police said earlier this month that it was "actively reviewing 21 allegations reported to the Metropolitan Police prior to Mohamed Al-Fayed's passing... to determine if any additional investigative steps are available or there are things we could have done better."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2016-12/rape-sexual-violence-women_650x400_41480857449.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Salah Fayed, brother of Mohamed Al-Fayed, who died in 2010 is acused of sexual violence.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nearly-260-million-americans-will-be-overweight-or-obese-by-2050-study-7025586]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Nearly 260 Million Americans Will Be Overweight Or Obese By 2050: Study]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nearly-260-million-americans-will-be-overweight-or-obese-by-2050-study-7025586]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Nov 2024 15:02:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The US overweight and obese population will rise significantly in the next quarter century if current trends continue, and new weight-loss treatments wont be sufficient to stem the tide, researchers said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The US overweight and obese population will rise significantly in the next quarter century if current trends continue, and new weight-loss treatments won't be sufficient to stem the tide, researchers said.</p>

<p>Nearly 260 million Americans will be overweight or obese by 2050, straining the health-care system and boosting medical costs, according to a study published Thursday in The Lancet medical journal. Rates among adult men will rise to 81% from 76% in 2021, and to 82% from 73% among women.</p>

<p>While medical institutions have been slow to recognize obesity as a disease, it raises the risk for a variety of dangerous, pervasive health outcomes, including diabetes, heart disease and cancer. The success of weight-loss drugs shouldn't be allowed to overshadow the need for measures — such as promotion of healthy diet and exercise — that are crucial to slowing the growth of the crisis, said Marie Ng, a co-author of the study.</p>

<p>“All of these factors combined have contributed to the continuous rise in obesity prevalence over the past three decades,” said Ng, who's an affiliate associate professor at the University of Washington's Institute for Health Metrics and Evaluation in Seattle. “If these drivers persist, the obesity crisis will likely continue to worsen.”</p>

<p>Obesity and overweight are both defined by body-mass index, a measure calculated using both height and weight. People with obesity are more severely affected than overweight people.</p>

<p>GLP-1 drugs like Novo Nordisk A/S's Wegovy and Eli Lilly &amp; Co.'s Zepbound have been shown to help patients safely shed pounds while decreasing some associated health risks. Use of the drugs has been hampered by insufficient supplies and spotty insurance coverage, along with costs of about $1,000 a month for the injections.</p>

<p>“Equitable access is very important if we're to leverage this medication,” Ng said in an interview. Uncertainty remains about the implications of long-term use of the drugs in large populations, she said.</p>

<p>US obesity rates doubled over the three decades ending in 2021, fueled by factors such as growing availability of high-calorie foods, sedentary lifestyles and decreasing access to healthy foods, particularly in lower-income communities, Ng said. About one in five children and at least one in three adolescents are expected to be living with obesity in 2050, according to the study.</p>

<p>While Southern states are expected to remain among those most affected, the biggest gains in men by 2050 are expected in Colorado and New Mexico, and in Kansas and Colorado for women, according to the study. No particular region is exempt from the anticipated increases, Ng said.</p>

<p>Obesity is “an issue not just for one particular state,” she said, “but the whole nation.”</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-05/7bqgah7o_obesity-650-_625x300_14_May_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US obesity crisis expected to worsen by 2050, study warns.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-determined-to-get-wokeness-out-of-education-7025526]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump Determined To Get "Wokeness" Out Of Education]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-determined-to-get-wokeness-out-of-education-7025526]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Nov 2024 14:57:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump's vision for education revolves around a single goal: to rid America's schools of perceived "wokeness" and "left-wing indoctrination".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump's vision for education revolves around a single goal: to rid America's schools of perceived "wokeness" and "left-wing indoctrination".</p>

<p>The president-elect wants to keep transgender athletes out of girls' sports. He wants to forbid classroom lessons on gender identity and structural racism. He wants to abolish diversity and inclusion offices.</p>

<p>Throughout his campaign, the Republican depicted schools as a political battleground to be won back from the left. Now that he's won the White House, he plans to use federal money as leverage to advance his vision of education across the nation.</p>

<p>Trump's education plan pledges to cut funding for schools that defy him on a multitude of issues.</p>

<p>On his first day in office, Trump has repeatedly said he will cut money to "any school pushing critical race theory, transgender insanity, and other inappropriate racial, sexual or political content on our children".</p>

<p>On the campaign trail, Trump said he would "not give one penny" to schools with vaccine or mask requirements.</p>

<p>He said it would be done through executive action, though even some of his supporters say he lacks the authority to make such swift and sweeping changes.</p>

<p>Trump's opponents say his vision of America's schools is warped by politics - that the type of liberal indoctrination he rails against is a fiction. They say his proposals will undermine public education and hurt the students who need schools' services the most.</p>

<p>"It's fear-based, non-factual information, and I would call it propaganda," said Wil Del Pilar, senior vice president for Education Trust, a research and advocacy organization. "There is no evidence that students are being taught to question their sexuality in schools. There is no evidence that our American education system is full of maniacs."</p>

<p>Trump's platform calls for "massive funding preferences" for states and schools that end teacher tenure, enact universal school choice programmes and allow parents to elect school principals.</p>

<p>Perhaps his most ambitious promise is to shut down the US Education Department entirely, a goal of conservative politicians for decades, saying it has been infiltrated by "radicals".</p>

<p>America's public K-12 schools get about 14 per cent of their revenue from the federal government, mainly from programs targeting low-income students and special education. The vast majority of schools' money comes from local taxes and state governments.</p>

<p>Colleges rely more heavily on federal money, especially the grants and loans the government gives students to pay for tuition.</p>

<p>Trump's strongest tool to put schools' money on the line is his authority to enforce civil rights - the Education Department has the power to cut federal funding to schools and colleges that fail to follow civil rights laws.</p>

<p>The president can't immediately revoke money from large numbers of districts, but if he targets a few through civil rights inquiries, others are likely to fall in line, said Bob Eitel, president of the conservative Defence of Freedom Institute and an education official during Trump's first term.</p>

<p>That authority could be used to go after schools and colleges that have diversity and inclusion offices or those accused of antisemitism, Eitel said.</p>

<p>"This is not a Day One loss of funding," Eitel said, referencing Trump's campaign promise. "But at the end of the day, the president will get his way on this issue, because I do think that there are some real legal issues."</p>

<p>Trump also has hinted at potential legislation to deliver some of his promises, including fining universities over diversity initiatives.</p>

<p>To get colleges to shutter diversity programs - which Trump says amount to discrimination - he said he "will advance a measure to have them fined up to the entire amount of their endowment".</p>

<p>His platform also calls for a new, free online university called the American Academy, to be paid for by "taxing, fining and suing excessively large private university endowments".</p>

<p>During his first term, Trump occasionally threatened to cut money from schools that defied him, including those slow to reopen during the COVID-19 pandemic and colleges he accused of curbing free speech.</p>

<p>Most of the threats came to nothing, though he succeeded in getting Congress to add a tax on wealthy university endowments, and his Education Department made sweeping changes to rules around campus sexual assault.</p>

<p>Universities hope their relationship with the administration won't be as antagonistic as Trump's rhetoric suggests.</p>

<p>"Education has been an easy target during the campaign season," said Peter McDonough, general counsel for the American Council on Education, an association of university presidents. "But a partnership between higher education and the administration is going to be better for the country than an attack on education."</p>

<p>Trump's threats of severe penalties seem to contradict another of his education pillars - the extraction of the federal government from schools. In closing the Education Department, Trump said he would return "all education work and needs back to the states".</p>

<p>"We're going to end education coming out of Washington, DC," Trump said on his website last year. In his platform, he pledged to ensure schools are "free from political meddling".</p>

<p>Rather than letting states and schools decide their stance on polarising issues, Trump is proposing blanket bans that align with his vision.</p>

<p>Taking a neutral stance and letting states decide wouldn't deliver Trump's campaign promises, said Max Eden, a senior fellow at AEI, a conservative think tank. For example, Trump plans to rescind guidance from President Joe Biden's administration that extended Title IX protections to LGBTQ+ students. And Trump would go further, promising a nationwide ban on transgender women in women's sports.</p>

<p>"Trump ran on getting boys out of girls' sports. He didn't run on letting boys play in girls' sports in blue states if they want to," Eden said.</p>

<p>Trump also wants a say in school curriculum, vowing to fight for "patriotic" education. He promised to reinstate his 1776 Commission, which he created in 2021 to promote patriotic education. The panel created a report that called progressivism a "challenge to American principles" alongside fascism.</p>

<p>Adding to that effort, Trump is proposing a new credentialing body to certify teachers "who embrace patriotic values".</p>

<p>Few of his biggest education goals can be accomplished quickly, and many would require new action from Congress or federal processes that usually take months.</p>

<p>More immediately, he plans to nullify executive orders issued by Biden, including one promoting racial equity across the federal government. He's also expected to work quickly to revoke or rewrite Biden's Title IX rules, though finalizing those changes would require a lengthier rulemaking process.</p>

<p>Trump hasn't detailed his plans for student loans, though he has called Biden's cancellation proposals illegal and unfair.</p>

<p>Most of Biden's signature education initiatives have been paused by courts amid legal challenges, including a proposal for widespread loan cancellation and a more generous loan repayment plan. Those plans could be revoked or rewritten once Trump takes office.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/j546pg1o_donald-trump_625x300_07_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[During his first term, Trump occasionally threatened to cut money from schools that defied him]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nasa-microsoft-s-new-earth-copilot-to-enhance-understanding-on-our-planet-7024349]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[NASA-Microsoft's New Earth Copilot To Enhance Understanding On Our Planet]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nasa-microsoft-s-new-earth-copilot-to-enhance-understanding-on-our-planet-7024349]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Nov 2024 14:56:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US space agency NASA has partnered with Microsoft to develop an easier-to-access and user-friendly Artificial Intelligence-based chatbot that can help people decode scientific data about Earth.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US space agency NASA has partnered with Microsoft to develop an easier-to-access and user-friendly Artificial Intelligence-based chatbot that can help people decode scientific data about Earth.</p>

<p>The new Earth Copilot can answer people “through plain language queries” ranging from monitoring wildfires to tracking climate change -- transforming how people interact with Earth's data.</p>

<p>NASA IMPACT worked with Microsoft to Earth Copilot to simplify access to data and encourage a wider range of users to interact with its Earth Science data.</p>

<p>The AI model leverages Microsoft's Azure cloud platform and comes with advanced AI capabilities that will transform how people can search, discover and analyse NASA's complex geospatial data, which so far has been accessible only to a limited number of researchers and scientists.</p>

<p>“NASA's repository of geospatial data contains key insights on everything from climate and air quality to urban planning and disaster response -- but its scale and complexity make it difficult to parse. With Earth Copilot, they're making it easier than ever for anyone to access that data,” said Satya Nadella, Chairman and CEO at Microsoft, in a post on X.</p>

<p>Earth Copilot also democratises access to space-borne data, enabling users -- from researchers to climate scientists to teachers to policymakers -- to engage with NASA's science data.</p>

<p>Researchers can now spend less time on data retrieval and more on analysis and discovery. It can help climate scientists quickly access historical data to study trends, while agricultural experts can gain insights into soil moisture levels to improve crop management.</p>

<p>Educators and teachers can use real-world examples to engage students in Earth Science, and policymakers can leverage the data to make informed decisions on critical issues like climate change, urban development, and disaster preparedness.</p>

<p>“We've designed the system to handle complex queries and large datasets efficiently, ensuring that users can quickly find the information they need without getting bogged down by technical complexities,” said Juan Carlos Lopez, former NASA engineer and current Azure Specialist at Microsoft.</p>

<p>--IANS</p>

<p>rvt/</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-07/qs785scg_nasa-logo-650_625x300_31_July_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[NASA IMPACT worked with Microsoft to Earth Copilot to simplify access to data.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-2-0-wont-slow-climate-progress-much-former-us-vice-president-7025439]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump 2.0 "Won't Slow" Climate Progress "Much": Former US Vice President]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-2-0-wont-slow-climate-progress-much-former-us-vice-president-7025439]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Nov 2024 14:48:00 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former US Vice President Al Gore believes a second Donald Trump term in the White House may have little impact on the "momentum" of the world's fight against climate change.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former US vice president Al Gore believes a second Donald Trump term in the White House may have little impact on the "momentum" of the world's fight against climate change.</p>

<p>The return of Trump, who has pledged to pull the United States from the Paris agreement for a second time, has cast a pall over UN COP29 climate talks in Baku this week.</p>

<p>But Gore echoed statements from President Joe Biden's climate team who sought to remind other countries that global action survived Trump's first presidency.</p>

<p>"We've been through this before," Gore told reporters Thursday ahead of Friday's release of the latest data findings from Climate TRACE, an independent tracker of global emissions he co-founded.</p>

<p>"He tried one time before and the world continued to reduce emissions even during his four years as president the last time," he said.</p>

<p>"There is so much more momentum that even a new Trump administration is not going to be able to slow it down much. I hope I'm right about that," he said.</p>

<p>The Nobel Peace Prize laureate said market forces were "giving us a tailwind", with renewable energy getting cheaper and increasingly used to generate electricity.</p>

<p>"Many people around the world are not simply waiting with bated breath to see what the United States is going to do, they're moving on their own," he said.</p>

<p>While a US retreat from its commitments "would not be a good thing", Gore said, "I think the progress is likely to continue, regardless."</p>

<p>Climate TRACE's new data showed Friday that greenhouse gas emissions rose 0.7 percent in 2023 and will likely increase by 0.48 percent this year.</p>

<p>The group, which uses artificial intelligence to analyse satellite images from around the planet, said it now has inventories for every state and province in the world as well as over 9,000 urban areas.</p>

<p><strong>'Petrostates have seized control'</strong></p>

<p>The former US vice president had singled out the emissions of the United Arab Emirates when he presented Climate TRACE data at last year's COP28 conference hosted by the oil power.</p>

<p>This year, Gore showed slides of the 200 largest emissions sites in COP29 host Azerbaijan, a country whose economy is highly dependent on oil and gas production and exports.</p>

<p>Azerbaijani President Ilham Aliyev hailed oil and gas as a "gift of God" when he addressed fellow leaders at COP29 on Tuesday.</p>

<p>"It's unfortunate that the fossil fuel industry and the petrostates have seized control of the COP process to an unhealthy degree," Gore said Thursday.</p>

<p>While the Dubai summit produced a global agreement on "transitioning away" from fossil fuels, the follow-up commitment "has been very weak" and the issue "is hardly even mentioned" at COP29, he said.</p>

<p>"I have to think that one of the reasons for that is that the petrostates have too much control over the process," he said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/528jaq88_trump-coal_625x300_12_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump has pledged to pull the US from the Paris agreement for a second time.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-china-defence-ministers-to-meet-in-laos-rajnath-singh-dong-jun-meeting-post-disengagement-in-ladakh-7025414]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India, China Ministers To Meet, 1st High-Level Talks Post Disengagement]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-china-defence-ministers-to-meet-in-laos-rajnath-singh-dong-jun-meeting-post-disengagement-in-ladakh-7025414]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Nov 2024 14:43:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Defence Minister Rajnath Singh will meet Chinese counterpart Dong Jun - the first ministerial-level meeting since the two militaries disengaged in eastern Ladakh last month and India resumed patrolling in Depsang last week.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Defence Minister <a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/topic/rajnath-singh" target="_blank">Rajnath Singh</a> will meet Chinese counterpart Dong Jun - the first ministerial-level meeting since the two militaries completed <a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/topic/india-china-ladakh-disengagement" target="_blank">disengagement in eastern Ladakh</a> last month and the India resumed patrolling in the Depsang region last week - sources told NDTV Friday.</p>

<p>Mr Singh and Mr Dong, a former naval Commander appointed in December last year, will meet on the sidelines of a two-day, 10-nation ASEAN summit in Laos that begins November 20.</p>

<p>This will also be the first time the Defence Ministers have met since April last year, when China's Li Shangfu travelled to Delhi for the Shanghai Cooperation Organisation summit.</p>

<p>The meeting is being seen as a key confidence-building measure as Delhi and Beijing rebuild bridges burnt after violence in the Galwan and Pangong Lake areas in May and June 2020, in which 20 Indian soldiers were killed in action and both sides ramped up military deployment.</p>

<p>This is the second in a series of planned high-level meetings - after <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-modi-chinas-xi-jinping-bilateral-starts-in-russia-first-since-2020-6856030" target="_blank">Prime Minister Narendra Modi and President Xi Jinping met</a> in Russia last month - NDTV has learned, each of which will be seen as another step in what will be an extended deepening of India-China engagement.</p>

<p><strong>NDTV Explains |</strong>&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-india-china-border-patrol-agreement-and-why-it-is-important-6844560" target="_blank">India-China Border Patrol Deal: What Is It, Why Is It Important</a></p>

<p>At this time, it is unclear what the next steps will be or if there will be subsequent meetings - either between the Defence Ministers or similar high-level sit-downs - to push for a deeper disengagement from both sides that will allow soldiers to withdraw to pre-2020 positions.</p>

<p>The two militaries, however, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/indian-chinese-troops-exchange-diwali-sweets-after-border-disengagement-6913668" target="_blank">exchanged sweets during Diwali for the first time in years</a>.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/75fhi9f_india-china-ladakh-diwali-sweets-exchange_625x300_31_October_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>A key point here is the scale of military build-up over the past four years; the Chinese put in a lot of work to set up new bases and infrastructure, such as bridges to hasten deployment of troops and equipment. And the sizes of some of these bases had not gone unnoticed.</p>

<p>Last month senior Indian military sources who analysed satellite imagery of a new base on the northern bank of the Pangong Lake said it was "unlike any other" on the Chinese side of the LAC.</p>

<p><strong>NDTV Exclusive |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/satellite-pics-chinas-new-base-near-pangong-lake-unlike-any-other-site-6787676" target="_blank">China's New Base Near Pangong Lake "Unlike Any Other Site"</a></p>

<p>That camp lay 15km east of a new bridge across the high-altitude Pangong Lake that Beijing built to step up pressure in areas near the LAC that were previously unoccupied.</p>

<p>In July NDTV reported on fortified sites to the north, including a surface-to-air missile battery.</p>

<p>However, following the agreement, China began walking back.</p>

<p><strong>NDTV Exclusive |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ndtv-exclusive-1st-images-of-chinese-troops-disengagement-in-ladakh-6874634" target="_blank">1st Images Of Chinese Troops' Disengagement In Ladakh</a></p>

<p>Days after the deal, NDTV accessed satellite images showing withdrawal in the Depsang and Demchok regions. And, ten days ago, India said it had completed patrolling to a point in Depsang.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/army-successfully-completes-patrolling-to-key-point-in-ladakhs-depsang-6944072" target="_blank">Army Completes Patrolling To Key Point In Ladakh's Depsang</a></p>

<p>Last month, after multiple rounds of military- and government-level talks, the two countries announced a patrolling agreement that has seen both withdraw to pre-April 2020 positions.</p>

<p>External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar, speaking exclusively to NDTV, confirmed the agreement and, a day later, Army chief General Upendra Dwivedi said the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/india-china-patrolling-agreement-ladakh-galwan-valley-clashes-trying-to-restore-trust-army-chief-on-india-china-patrolling-deal-6845928" target="_blank">Indian military is "trying to trust"</a>&nbsp;China again.</p>

<p>But perhaps the biggest signal India-China relations are moving towards some normalcy came after Prime Minister Modi met President Xi at the BRICS Summit in Russia last month.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-modi-xi-jinping-bilateral-summit-brics-summit-russia-india-china-patrolling-agreement-pm-modi-xi-welcome-complete-disengagement-between-soldiers-al-6857182" target="_blank">PM Modi, Xi Jinping Welcome "Complete Disengagement" Along LAC</a></p>

<p>Disenagement and patrolling in Depsang and Demchok follows similar positive actions on the north and south banks of the Pangong Lake in 2021, and in the contentious Gogra-Hot Springs area in September a year later. In each case the two sides withdrew to pre-April 2020 positions.</p>

<p><em>NDTV is now available on WhatsApp channels. <a href="https://www.whatsapp.com/channel/0029Va4lixw7z4kcvZI9JM12">Click on the link</a> to get all the latest updates from NDTV on your chat. </em></p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/hnvb7s5o_rajnath-singh_625x300_18_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Defence Minister Rajnath Singh last met a Chinese counterpart in April 2023 (File).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pregnancy-associated-cancers-on-the-rise-heres-why-7025300]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Pregnancy-Associated Cancers On The Rise. What Researchers Say About It]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pregnancy-associated-cancers-on-the-rise-heres-why-7025300]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Nov 2024 14:30:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Cancer diagnoses during pregnancy and in the year following the birth are rare. But such cases are becoming more common in parts of the world.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former winner of TV show Alone Australia Gina Chick was diagnosed with breast cancer just days after finding out she was pregnant.</p>

<p>She describes in her recent book her experience with chemotherapy and what followed.</p>

<p>Thankfully, cancer diagnoses during pregnancy and in the year following the birth are rare. But such cases are becoming more common in parts of the world, including Australia. Researchers aren't exactly sure why.</p>

<p>Here's what researchers know so far, and the options for treatment.</p>

<h2><br />
<strong>How rare is it?</strong></h2>

<p>A New South Wales study found that in 1994 there were about 94 cancer diagnoses during pregnancy or within one year of birth per 100,000 women giving birth. That rose to about 163 per 100,000 in 2013. Although these statistics are more than ten years old, these are the most recent and rigorous data available in Australia.</p>

<p>A 2023 Swedish study of pregnancies in 1973-2017 had similar findings.</p>

<p>Both studies found about one-quarter of pregnancy-associated cancers are diagnosed before birth, with the rest diagnosed in the year after birth.</p>

<h3><br />
<strong>What type of cancers are we talking about?</strong></h3>

<p>The United Kingdom's first comprehensive assessment of cancer during pregnancy looked at diagnoses in 2016-2020.</p>

<p>This study, the NSW study, and others, have found breast and skin cancers (often melanoma) were the most common pregnancy-associated cancers. There were also high rates of thyroid, gynaecological (particularly cervical and ovarian) and blood cancers in this group.</p>

<p>The UK study found about 92 per cent of cancers were new diagnoses and about 82 per cent had symptoms. The majority (81 per cent) were treated with the aim to cure and about 82 per cent of pregnancies associated with a cancer diagnosis resulted in a live birth.</p>

<p>However, 20 per cent of mothers died by the end of the five year study period. Gastrointestinal (gut) cancers were particularly concerning. They had the highest mortality rate at about 46 per cent and were associated with diagnosis at a more advanced stage of cancer.</p>

<p>This may be because many symptoms of gastrointestinal cancers such as abdominal pain, fatigue and acid reflux overlap with those of pregnancy. In other words, some cancer symptoms can be mistaken for pregnancy symptoms, "masking" or delaying a cancer diagnosis.</p>

<h3><br />
<strong>Why are cases like this rising?</strong></h3>

<p>The broad range of cancers presenting during and after pregnancy suggests a variety of contributing factors.</p>

<p>In high socioeconomic countries women are having children later in life and the biggest risk factor for many cancers is increasing age. However, the evidence for age being a major factor in pregnancy-related cancer is inconclusive. This may account for some but not all cases.</p>

<p>Another factor may be the rising use of prenatal genetic screening tests in early pregnancy. These analyse DNA derived from the mother's blood to detect chromosomal abnormalities in the developing fetus. But these tests can also give information about the mother's chromosomes. This has led to diagnoses of Hodgkin disease, breast and colorectal cancer in pregnant women without symptoms.</p>

<p>Oestrogen and progesterone are two hormones important for growth and development of breast tissue and to support other aspects of a healthy pregnancy.</p>

<p>These may also contribute to cancer development, particularly breast cancer. However, it's not clear whether this is linked to rising rates of pregnancy associated cancers.</p>

<p>Other cancers, such as skin cancer, are associated with environmental factors such as UV exposure. Notably, melanoma was the leading pregnancy-associated cancer in the NSW study, reflecting the high rate of skin cancer in the local population.</p>

<p>Other environmental factors, such as smoking and human papillomavirus, are associated with cervical cancer. Again we're not sure whether such factors are linked with rising rates of pregnancy associated cancers.</p>

<h3><br />
<strong>What happens after a diagnosis?</strong></h3>

<p>Pregnancy complicates a cancer diagnosis, as any potential treatment for the mother may risk the health and viability of the fetus. So some aspects of treatment may need to be adjusted.</p>

<p>Surgery can usually be undertaken during any trimester depending on where the cancer is located.</p>

<p>Radiotherapy needs careful planning because the impact of radiation on the fetus depends on the developmental stage, where the radiation is applied to the body, and the dose.</p>

<p>Chemotherapy should be avoided in the first trimester due to potential toxic effects on the fetus. But it can usually be given in the second and third trimester.</p>

<p>Chemotherapy should be avoided within three weeks of the birth to reduce the chance of bleeding and infection in the newborn, who may also have a weakened immune system from the chemo.</p>

<p>More targeted immunotherapies are generally given to the mother after she's given birth. Depending on the treatment, she may be advised not breastfeed. That's because the medicine can pass from the mother via breastmilk to the baby.</p>

<h3><strong>What happens to the babies?</strong></h3>

<p>Reassuringly, the NSW data found no increase in the rate of babies dying around the time of birth if they were born to mothers with a pregnancy-associated cancer.</p>

<p>However, there were more planned preterm births. This is because women are offered an induction of labour and/or a caesarean to facilitate cancer treatment for the mother, while reducing treatment-related risks to the unborn child.</p>

<p>There were also higher rates of babies born with a low birth weight and low Apgar scores (indicators of a baby's condition shortly after birth) - possibly related to being born pre-term.</p>

<h3><strong>What do researchers want to know?</strong></h3>

<p>We have much to learn about what's behind the increasing rates of pregnancy-associated cancers, and what women diagnosed with these cancers can expect.</p>

<p>We also need to combine cancer and obstetric data in national databases. This would allow us to see which areas to prioritise for further research, inform clinical guidelines to screen for cancers during and after pregnancy, and would help evaluate responses to screening programs or therapies in the future.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/h1t744d8_pregnancy_625x300_04_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Breast and skin cancers (often melanoma) were the most common pregnancy-associated cancers]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/wars-trump-presidency-to-dominate-g20-summit-in-brazil-7025272]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Wars, Trump Presidency To Dominate G20 Summit In Brazil]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/wars-trump-presidency-to-dominate-g20-summit-in-brazil-7025272]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Nov 2024 14:29:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The G20 summit is set to be dominated by differences over wars in the Middle East and Ukraine, and the implications of Donald Trump's White House return.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>G20 leaders gather in Brazil on Monday for a G20 summit set to be dominated by differences over wars in the Middle East and Ukraine, and implications of Donald Trump's White House return.</p>

<p>Security considerations -- always high at such meetings -- were elevated further after a failed bomb attack late Wednesday outside Brazil's Supreme Court in Brasilia.</p>

<p>Police were probing the two blasts as a possible "terrorist act" committed by a Brazilian perpetrator, whose death was the sole casualty.</p>

<p>The summit venue is in Rio de Janeiro, in the city's stunning bayside museum of modern art, which is the epicenter of a massive police deployment designed to keep the public well away.</p>

<p>Brazil's leftwing President Luiz Inacio Lula da Silva will be using the opportunity to highlight his position as a leader championing Global South issues while also being courted by the West.</p>

<p>That role will be tested in the months and years ahead as Latin America and other regions navigate "America First" policies promised by Donald Trump when he becomes US president in January.</p>

<p>At this G20, it will be outgoing President Joe Biden who will represent the world's biggest economy, but as a lame duck the other leaders will be looking beyond.</p>

<p>Just before the Rio summit, on Sunday, Biden will make a stop in Brazil's Amazon to underline the fight against climate change -- another issue that Trump is hostile towards.</p>

<p><strong>Putin absent</strong></p>

<p>The G20 meet is happening at the same time as the UN's COP29 climate conference in Azerbaijan -- and as the world experiences dramatic climate phenomena, including in Brazil where flooding, drought and forest fires have taken heavy tolls.</p>

<p>At the last G20, in India, the leaders called for a tripling of renewable energy sources by the end of the decade, but without explicitly calling for an end to the use of fossil fuels.</p>

<p>One invited leader who declined to come to Rio is Russian President Vladimir Putin, who said his presence could "wreck" the gathering.</p>

<p>Putin denied an International Criminal Court warrant out against him, for Russia's actions in Ukraine, was a factor in his decision. His foreign minister will represent Russia in Rio.</p>

<p>China's President Xi Jinping, however, will be attending, and will even extend his stay after the summit to make an official visit to Brasilia on Wednesday.</p>

<p>China is Brazil's biggest trading partner, and the two countries have been touting themselves as mediators to help end Russia's war in Ukraine, so far without success.</p>

<p>That conflict, along with Israel's offensives in Gaza and Lebanon, will loom large at the summit.</p>

<p>"We are negotiating with all the countries on the final declaration's passages about geopolitics... so that we can reach consensual language on those two issues," Brazil's chief diplomatic official for the G20, Mauricio Lyrio, said.</p>

<p>Those conflicts will be "the elephant in the room," Flavia Loss, international relations specialist at the School of Sociology and Politics of Sao Paulo (FESPSP), told AFP.</p>

<p>But that should not prevent Brazil from finding consensus on issues that it has made priorities under its G20 presidency, she said, such as the fight against hunger or taxing the world's super-rich.</p>

<p>Lula, heading up Latin America's biggest economy, set out his line in May when he said: "A lot of people insist on dividing the world between friends and enemies. But the more vulnerable are not interested in simplist dichotomies."</p>

<p><strong>Tax on billionaires</strong></p>

<p>The Rio G20 summit will open on Monday with Lula officially launching a "Global Alliance against Hunger and Poverty".</p>

<p>The initiative aims to rally nations and international bodies to free up financing for that campaign, or to replicate programs that have previously had success.</p>

<p>And on the issue of taxing billionaires, the G20 countries already declared a desire to cooperate to bring that about, as set out by their finance ministers who met in Rio in June.</p>

<p>It remained to be seen, though, whether the leaders at the summit would pursue that goal, and on what terms.</p>

<p>Following the summit, Brazil hands over the G20 presidency to South Africa.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/a3rrgh88_russia-ukraine-war_625x300_10_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Conflict, along with Israel's offensives in Gaza and Lebanon, will loom large at the G20 summit.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-supreme-court-a-check-or-an-enabler-of-second-trump-presidency-7025233]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Supreme Court: A Check Or An Enabler Of Second Trump Presidency?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-supreme-court-a-check-or-an-enabler-of-second-trump-presidency-7025233]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Nov 2024 14:21:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump appointed three right-wing justices to the top court during his first term and may have the opportunity to name more during his second stint in the Oval Office.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump returns to the White House shielded with presidential immunity by the Supreme Court and with the prospect of cementing a conservative majority on the bench for at least a generation.</p>

<p>The Republican President-elect appointed three right-wing justices to the top court during his first term and may have the opportunity to name more during his second stint in the Oval Office.</p>

<p>Archconservatives Clarence Thomas, 76, and Samuel Alito, 74, who wrote the opinion overturning the nationwide right to abortion, are the two oldest justices on the court and they could choose to step down knowing their replacements would be nominated by Trump.</p>

<p>"It certainly presents the opportunity for them to retire with some assurance that their successor would continue their philosophy," said Christopher Peters, a law professor at the University of Akron. "And I certainly wouldn't be surprised if that happened."</p>

<p>Steven Schwinn, a law professor at the University of Illinois Chicago, said if Thomas or Alito have any inclination to quit he expects it to happen "fairly quickly" -- before the 2026 midterm elections, when Republicans could potentially lose control of the Senate.</p>

<p>Supreme Court justices are appointed by the president for life but are subject to confirmation by the Senate.</p>

<p>Trump, the only former US president to be convicted of a crime -- falsifying business records to cover up a hush money payment to a porn star -- will take office in January emboldened by the top court's ruling in July that an ex-president has broad immunity from criminal prosecution, Schwinn said.</p>

<p>Trump was charged by Special Counsel Jack Smith with conspiring to overturn the results of the 2020 election but a trial was delayed by appeals that eventually landed in the Supreme Court, where conservatives enjoy a 6-3 majority.</p>

<p>In an opinion penned by Chief Justice John Roberts, the court ruled that a former president has broad immunity from prosecution for official acts taken while in office, but can be pursued for unofficial acts.</p>

<p>Smith, the special counsel, is winding down the election interference case against Trump in light of the long-standing Justice Department policy that a sitting US president cannot be indicted or criminally prosecuted.</p>

<p><strong>'King above the law'</strong></p>

<p>Schwinn said the immunity ruling "not only allows, but affirmatively invites, a president to engage in illegal behavior and provides a kind of roadmap for doing that while also immunizing themselves.</p>

<p>"And then the question is, 'Is a particular president willing to abuse that power or not?'" he said. "And you know, for my money, I guess a President Trump seems more likely to do that."</p>

<p>Justice Sonia Sotomayor, one of the three liberals on the court, warned in her blistering dissent to the immunity ruling that it makes the president a "king above the law."</p>

<p>Steve Vladeck, a law professor at Georgetown University, noted that the Supreme Court did check Trump on a number of occasions during his first term in the White House.</p>

<p>The court initially blocked his Muslim travel ban, protected the young undocumented immigrants known as "Dreamers," and declined to be dragged into lawsuits filed by Trump surrogates falsely claiming he had won the 2020 election.</p>

<p>With Republicans controlling both chambers of Congress this time, the Supreme Court will be "the last institution standing between Mr Trump and whatever he wants to do," Vladeck said in a New York Times essay.</p>

<p>But the court, Vladeck noted, has its own problems with approval ratings at near record lows and perceived ethics questions surrounding luxury vacations taken by Thomas and Alito that were paid for by powerful Republican billionaires.</p>

<p>"Without that public support, what would happen if Mr Trump simply ignored a decision by the nation's highest court that he doesn't like?" Vladeck asked.</p>

<p>"If the court rules against Mr Trump and he tells the justices to pound sand, what will happen then?"</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/dmlqqgeo_donald-trump_625x300_10_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump, the only former US president to be convicted of a crime, will take office in January 2025.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/more-than-700-ufo-reports-received-but-no-proof-of-alien-activity-7024724]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Annual UFO Report Finds Over 700 New Cases, But No Proof Of Alien Activity]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/more-than-700-ufo-reports-received-but-no-proof-of-alien-activity-7024724]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Nov 2024 14:16:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Between May 1, 2023, and June 1, the Pentagon's All-Domain Anomaly Resolution Office (AARO) received 757 reports of UFO sightings.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Over 20 reports of unidentified anomalous phenomena (UAP), commonly referred to as UFOs, remain unexplained, the US Defence Department's annual UAP program report has revealed. Between May 1, 2023, and June 1, the Pentagon's All-Domain Anomaly Resolution Office (AARO) received 757 reports of UFO sightings, with 485 being new and the rest occurring between 2021 and 2022, <a href="https://www.newsnationnow.com/politics/ap-politics/ap-new-pentagon-report-on-ufos-includes-hundreds-of-new-incidents-but-no-evidence-of-aliens/ " rel="nofollow,noindex">Newsnation</a> reported.</p>

<p>Among these reports, AARO director Jon Kosloski shed light on 21 that warrant further investigation, some of which he described as “true anomalies.” While the majority of sightings were in the air, at least 49 reportedly took place in space. However, none of the space domain reports originated from space-based sensors, it noted. Instead, they came from military or commercial pilots and ground observers, with UAPs reported at altitudes of about 100 km, in line with US Space Command's area of responsibility.</p>

<p>“AARO notes that none of the space domain reports originated from space-based sensors or assets; rather, all of these reports originated from military or commercial pilots or ground observers who reported UAP located at altitudes estimated at 100 kilometres [about 62 miles] or higher, consistent with US [sic] Space Command's astrographic area of responsibility,” the report <a href="https://nypost.com/2024/11/14/us-news/pentagon-says-nearly-two-dozen-ufo-sightings-cant-be-explained-true-anomalies/ " rel="nofollow,noindex">said</a>.</p>

<p>While the data continues to roll in, the report also acknowledged that no verifiable evidence of extraterrestrial beings, activity, or technology has been noted. “AARO has discovered no verifiable evidence of extraterrestrial beings, activity, or technology,” Mr Kosloski told reporters on Thursday.</p>

<p>None of the sightings substantiated concerns about advanced foreign adversarial capabilities or breakthrough aerospace technologies, which some defence experts had speculated, it revealed.</p>

<p>Despite a surge in reported sightings, AARO has struggled to resolve the cases. Of the 757 reports, just 118 were resolved, with the objects identified as “various types of balloons, birds, and drones.” Another 174 cases, suspected to involve more routine explanations, are pending.</p>

<p>However, a significant number of reports remain unresolved. Currently, AARO is investigating 444 cases.</p>

<p>“AARO's ability to resolve cases remains constrained by a lack of timely and actionable sensor data,” the report acknowledged. “AARO continues to address this challenge by working with military and technical partners to optimize sensor requirements, information-sharing processes, and the content of UAP reporting.”</p>

<p>In an effort to address these ongoing investigations, AARO is working with international partners to improve information sharing and best practices for resolving UAP cases.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/gchagi9g_ufos_625x300_14_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The majority of sightings were in the air, at least 49 reportedly took place in space.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-election-results-after-donald-trumps-victory-us-election-falsehoods-shift-left-7025181]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[After Donald Trump's Victory, US Election Falsehoods Shift Left]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-election-results-after-donald-trumps-victory-us-election-falsehoods-shift-left-7025181]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Nov 2024 14:14:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Right-wing falsehoods about voter fraud fell off a cliff after Donald Trump's victory in the US election, but American liberals took a page from their playbook to push wild conspiracy theories that have fueled doubt about the democratic process.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Right-wing falsehoods about voter fraud fell off a cliff after Donald Trump's victory in the US election, but American liberals took a page from their playbook to push wild conspiracy theories that have fueled doubt about the democratic process.</p>

<p>The left-wing warping of reality underscores how disinformation is peddled across both sides of the political aisle, feeding information chaos on increasingly unmoderated social media platforms that has made it harder for users to decipher fact from fiction.</p>

<p>The falsehoods promoted on sites including the Elon Musk-owned X and Meta's Threads range from unfounded claims about fraudulent vote tallies in key swing states to allegations that Trump "cheated" to win against his Democratic rival Kamala Harris.</p>

<p>Left-leaning social media users also spread the unfounded theory that Musk -- the world's richest man and a vociferous Trump backer –- used his Starlink satellite internet company to rig the election by manipulating the vote count, AFP's fact-checkers reported.</p>

<p>"What we're seeing now is an uptick in election fraud claims from the left, particularly in the days following Election Day -- and these narratives are being amplified by bot networks," Dan Brahmy, chief executive of the disinformation security company Cyabra, told AFP.</p>

<p>"It's a reminder that disinformation and exploitation tactics don't belong to one political ideology -- they're weaponized across the board to influence public perception."</p>

<p><strong>'Shared vulnerability'</strong></p>

<p>The Democratic leadership has not questioned the election's outcome, with both Biden and Harris conceding the loss and deeming the November 5 election free and fair.</p>

<p>But just hours after the election, X was flooded with over 30,000 mentions of the hashtag "Do Not Concede Kamala" alongside the words "rigged," "fraud," or "stolen," according to the misinformation watchdog NewsGuard.</p>

<p>Some pro-Harris influencers implored her to "demand a recount" in posts that garnered millions of views.</p>

<p>Cyabra said it uncovered a "highly coordinated disinformation campaign" on X promoting the false notion that the election was "stolen," a narrative that initially gained traction through a network of fake profiles and was later amplified by real influencers.</p>

<p>Some users deployed a deliberate tactic, misspelling the vice president's name in their hashtags as "Kamila" to evade detection while amassing engagement.</p>

<p>The misspelling tactic, Cyabra said, was used to circumvent platform moderation as it "reduces the likelihood of automated content takedowns."</p>

<p>"The recent shift in election fraud claims reveals a deeper, shared vulnerability" on both sides of the political divide," Brahmy said.</p>

<p>"Narratives that may start as fringe beliefs can, under the right conditions, permeate mainstream discourse, regardless of political alignment."</p>

<p><strong>'Information warfare'</strong></p>

<p>Left-leaning social media users picked up what researchers call the misinformation baton from Trump's right-wing supporters, who vigorously pushed unfounded claims of voter fraud since the Republican's 2020 election defeat.</p>

<p>This time around, right-wing claims flooded social media platforms right up to Election Day, but began tapering off as Trump's decisive victory took shape.</p>

<p>"You could call it a role-reversal," said Sam Howard, NewsGuard's political editor.</p>

<p>"As Trump's win became more apparent, there were fewer fraud claims from the right. But now there is a disbelief on the left that Harris's defeat was legitimate."</p>

<p>Such claims have spread unchecked as many platforms have gutted trust and safety teams and scaled back content moderation efforts once used to tame misinformation.</p>

<p>"Right-wing election deniers were largely placated by the results of the election, but it's not so much that disinformation is no longer a problem or that it has suddenly, miraculously, disappeared," Nora Benavidez, senior counsel at the nonprofit watchdog Free Press, told AFP.</p>

<p>"Information warfare is only becoming more pernicious and, when given time to take root, serves as a critical building block to advance authoritarianism and bigotry," she added.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/862i9kmo_donald-trump_625x300_12_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Democratic leadership has not questioned US election outcome.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/final-supermoon-of-the-year-aligns-with-leonid-meteor-shower-this-weekend-7024636]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Final Supermoon Of The Year Aligns With Leonid Meteor Shower This Weekend]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/final-supermoon-of-the-year-aligns-with-leonid-meteor-shower-this-weekend-7024636]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Nov 2024 14:10:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Skygazers across the world better be ready to catch this week's supermoon.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Skygazers across the world better be ready to catch this week's supermoon. The next one won't come around for a bit. But on Thursday, the fourth and last supermoon of the year will pass within roughly 225,000 miles of Earth, appearing larger and brighter than usual. It will take until Friday to attain its full lunar phase. While seeing a supermoon in itself is a delight, the Leonid meteor shower could make for a dazzling bonus as it reaches its peak on Saturday night and into early Sunday, reported <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/11/14/science/full-beaver-moon-leonids-meteor-shower/index.html">CNN </a>quoting the American Meteor Society.</p>

<p>The full moon in November is referred to as "the beaver moon," a reference to the start of the animal's hibernating season. The upcoming full moon will reach the summit of its full phase on Friday at 4:29 pm Eastern Time. However, it will be visible to the naked eye as full one day prior to and after its peak, said Noah Petro, chief of NASA's Planetary Geology, Geophysics and Geochemistry Laboratory.</p>

<p>Petro said, “There is a moment in time when the moon is at its fullest, but if it's cloudy or you're busy, going out any other time either a day before, later in the evening or the following day you will still see the beauty that is the full moon.”</p>

<p>A supermoon, more of a popular word than a scientific one, happens when a full lunar phase coincides with an exceptionally close orbit around the Earth. This phenomenon occurs only three or four times a year and consecutively because of the moon's ever-changing oval orbit.</p>

<p>The full moon in November will be a little further away than the one in October, which was the closest moon of 2024 and was photographed worldwide.</p>

<p>If local weather conditions allow, the beaver moon will be visible to those in the Northern and Southern Hemispheres. They may even be able to witness a Leonid meteor burning brightly in the night sky.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-06/aecncqfg_supermoon-afp_625x300_15_June_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The full moon in November will be a little further away than the one in October.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>