<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 20:25:29 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/when-diljit-dosanjh-met-fan-from-pakistan-borders-drawn-by-politicians-6685655]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Borders Drawn By Politicians": When Diljit Dosanjh Met Fan From Pakistan]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/when-diljit-dosanjh-met-fan-from-pakistan-borders-drawn-by-politicians-6685655]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 19:56:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A heartwarming gesture by popular Punjabi singer Diljit Dosanjh has been winning hearts. He met one of his fans during his "Dil-luminati Tour" in Manchester and gifted her a box of shoes.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A heartwarming gesture by popular Punjabi singer Diljit Dosanjh has been winning hearts. He met one of his fans during his "Dil-luminati Tour" in Manchester and gifted her a box of shoes. On learning that she was from Pakistan, he gave a priceless and powerful message of love and peace.</p>

<p>"Hindustan and Pakistan are the same for me. Punjabis have love for all in their hearts. The borders are drawn by politicians. Punjabis don't care, Punjabis love everyone," he said amid a thunderous round of applause.</p>

<p>"I welcome those who have come from my country India and also those who have come from Pakistan," Mr Dosanjh, dressed in an all-black traditional Punjabi attire, addressed the crowd gathered to see him perform.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Diljit Dosanjh Love For Pakistan<br />
<br />
Singer Diljit Dosanjh taking Aman Ki Asha, "BhaiChara" &amp; Ganga-Jamuni Tehzeeb to new heights!<br />
<br />
~ During his recent Manchester Concert, He said: For us, India &amp; Pakistan are same. POLITICIANS Divided us. There's no difference." <a href="https://t.co/jPJeueTOKC">pic.twitter.com/jPJeueTOKC</a></p>
— Shivraj_meena (@shivrajlalsotya) <a href="https://twitter.com/shivrajlalsotya/status/1840726935984337004?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 30, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>Another video of the singer went viral recently when he introduced his mother and sister at the Manchester show.</p>

<p>He interacted with the audience gathered at the Co-op Live internal arena on Saturday night as he sang his popular track "Hass Hass". Unexpectedly, the singer then held an elderly woman's hand and raised it in the air before declaring through the microphone: "By the way, this is my mom".</p>

<p>Mr Dosanjh's mother became emotional as he bowed in front of her and hugged her through the barricades.</p>

<p>He then pointed towards his sister: "She is my sister. My family is also here today."</p>

<p>Diljit Dosanjh, known for songs such as "GOAT", "Mombattiye", "Proper Patola", and "Do You Know?" will visit India next month to kick off the "Dil-Luminati Tour" on October 26 in New Delhi.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/79v7051o_diljit-dosanjh-with-fan_625x300_30_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Diljit Dosanjh gave a priceless and powerful message of love and peace.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/two-thirds-of-buildings-in-gaza-damaged-since-war-began-last-year-un-6685216]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Two-Thirds Of Buildings In Gaza Damaged Since War Began Last Year: UN]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/two-thirds-of-buildings-in-gaza-damaged-since-war-began-last-year-un-6685216]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 19:08:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Two-thirds of the buildings in the Gaza Strip have been damaged or destroyed since the Gaza war began in October 2023, the United Nations said on Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Two-thirds of the buildings in the Gaza Strip have been damaged or destroyed since the Gaza war began in October 2023, the United Nations said on Monday.</p>

<p>Updating its damage assessment, the UN Satellite Centre (UNOSAT) said very high-resolution imagery collected on September 3 and 6 showed a clear deterioration.</p>

<p>"This analysis... shows that two-thirds of the total structures in the Gaza Strip have sustained damage," UNOSAT said.</p>

<p>"Those 66 per cent of damaged buildings in the Gaza Strip account for 163,778 structures in total," it said.</p>

<p>The last assessment, based on images from early July, determined that 63 per cent of structures in the Palestinian territory had been damaged.</p>

<p>Monday's update said the damage now included "52,564 structures that have been destroyed; 18,913 severely damaged; 35,591 possibly damaged structures; and 56,710 moderately affected".</p>

<p>Gaza City has been notably affected, with 36,611 structures destroyed, it added.</p>

<p>UNOSAT and the UN's Food and Agriculture Organization said that approximately 68 per cent of the permanent crop fields in the Gaza Strip showed "a significant decline in health and density" in September.</p>

<p>Hamas's unprecedented October 7 attack on Israel resulted in the deaths of 1,205 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli official figures that include hostages killed in captivity.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory military offensive has killed at least 41,615 people in Gaza, most of them civilians, according to figures provided by the Hamas-run territory's health ministry. The UN has described the figures as reliable.</p>

<p>Part of the UN Institute for Training and Research (UNITAR), Geneva-based UNOSAT says its satellite imagery analysis helps the humanitarian community assess the extent of conflict-related damage and helps shape emergency relief efforts.</p>

<p>"Over the past year, UNOSAT's team has worked tirelessly to provide the world with precise and timely insights into the impact of the conflict on buildings and infrastructure in Gaza," said UNITAR's executive director Nikhil Seth.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/45959ij8_gaza-afp_625x300_25_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Gaza City has been notably affected, with 36,611 structures destroyed.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/cash-strapped-sri-lanka-records-first-deflation-since-1995-6685087]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Cash-Strapped Sri Lanka Records First Deflation Since 1995]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/cash-strapped-sri-lanka-records-first-deflation-since-1995-6685087]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 18:49:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Cash-strapped Sri Lanka's economy recorded falling consumer prices for the first time in 29 years, official data showed Monday, with the September inflation figure dipping to negative 0.5 per cent.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Cash-strapped Sri Lanka's economy recorded falling consumer prices for the first time in 29 years, official data showed Monday, with the September inflation figure dipping to negative 0.5 per cent.</p>

<p>Census and Statistics Department data showed price drops in both food and non-food goods contributing to deflation in September, compared to inflation of 0.5 per cent in August.</p>

<p>Sri Lanka last recorded deflation in March 1995 with a figure of negative 0.9 per cent. The previous price fall to that was in 1985 when inflation was negative 2.1 per cent.</p>

<p>Inflation peaked at 69.8 per cent two years ago at the height of an unprecedented economic crisis in the island nation.</p>

<p>Acute shortages of food, fuel and medicines led to months of protests that eventually forced then-president Gotabaya Rajapaksa to temporarily flee the country and resign in July 2022.</p>

<p>His successor Ranil Wickremesinghe secured a $2.9 billion International Monetary Fund bailout and raised taxes and prices to stabilise the economy.</p>

<p>Wickremesinghe lost office after a presidential election this month.</p>

<p>The winner of that contest, President Anura Kumara Dissanayake, has vowed to maintain the IMF programme but relax some of the austerity measures it imposed.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-12/pqpaltag_sri-lanka-generic_625x300_13_December_23.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Inflation peaked at 69.8 per cent two years ago.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/lebanon-pm-calls-for-ceasefire-with-israel-as-strikes-intensify-6684481]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Lebanon PM Calls For Ceasefire With Israel As Strikes Intensify]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/lebanon-pm-calls-for-ceasefire-with-israel-as-strikes-intensify-6684481]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 17:40:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Lebanon's Prime Minister Najib Mikati on Monday called for a ceasefire in the fighting between Israel and Hezbollah during a meeting with French Foreign Minister Jean-Noel Barrot in Beirut.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lebanon's Prime Minister Najib Mikati on Monday called for a ceasefire in the fighting between Israel and Hezbollah during a meeting with French Foreign Minister Jean-Noel Barrot in Beirut.</p>

<p>"The key to the solution is to put an end to the Israeli aggression against Lebanon and to revive the appeal launched by the United States and France... in favour of a ceasefire," Mikati said, according to a statement from his office.</p>

<p>Barrot arrived in Beirut Sunday, the first foreign diplomat to visit Lebanon since Israel escalated its strikes against Hezbollah strongholds.</p>

<p>Mikati added that the "priority is applying resolution 1701" of the United Nations Security Council, which ended the 2006 war between Israel and Hezbollah.</p>

<p>The French envoy's visit came as a deadly strike hit a building in the centre of the Lebanese capital.</p>

<p>Israeli strikes have been largely concentrated on Hezbollah's strongholds in the south and east of the country, and in south Beirut.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/ch043to8_israel-strike-lebanon-reuters_625x300_29_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israeli strikes have been largely concentrated on Hezbollah's strongholds.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-ukraine-war-vladimir-putin-vows-to-achieve-all-goals-in-ukraine-as-russia-claims-new-ground-6684429]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Putin Vows To Achieve All "Goals" In Ukraine As Russia Claims New Ground]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-ukraine-war-vladimir-putin-vows-to-achieve-all-goals-in-ukraine-as-russia-claims-new-ground-6684429]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 17:36:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russian President Vladimir Putin vowed Monday to achieve all his "goals" in Ukraine and celebrated the second anniversary of annexing four Ukrainian regions, as his army claimed fresh advances in the conflict.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russian President Vladimir Putin vowed Monday to achieve all his "goals" in Ukraine and celebrated the second anniversary of annexing four Ukrainian regions, as his army claimed fresh advances in the conflict.</p>

<p>Moscow has captured dozens of Ukrainian towns and villages this year, pressing forward even as Kyiv mounts a cross-border offensive into Russian territory.</p>

<p>"The truth is on our side. All goals set will be achieved," Putin said in a video address marking what he calls "Reunification Day" -- when Moscow annexed four southern and eastern Ukrainian regions in 2022.</p>

<p>He also repeated his justification for sending troops into Ukraine, saying he was protecting Russian speakers against a "neo-Nazi dictatorship" that aimed to "cut them off forever from Russia, their historic homeland".</p>

<p>"Together we are defending a safe, prosperous future for our children and grandchildren," Putin said.</p>

<p>Russia claimed to annex the Ukrainian regions of Lugansk, Donetsk, Zaporizhzhia and Kherson in September 2022, but it does not fully control any of them.</p>

<p>The Kremlin has pursued a relentless assault in eastern Ukraine in recent months, pressing its advantage as Ukrainian soldiers grapple with exhaustion and relentless bombardment.</p>

<p>The Russian army said Monday its troops had "liberated" the Ukrainian village of Nelipivka, which had a population of around 1,000 before the conflict.</p>

<p>It lies just north of the Ukrainian town of New York, where Kyiv claimed to have made rare gains earlier in September.</p>

<p>The main target of Moscow's assault in recent months has been the Ukrainian logistics hub of Pokrovsk, a city on road and rail routes that supply Kyiv's forces across the frontline.</p>

<p><strong>- 'One-on-one talks' -</strong></p>

<p>Putin's comments came shortly after Russia launched a fresh wave of missile and drone attacks at Ukraine overnight, some of which were aimed at the capital Kyiv.</p>

<p>"The enemy carried out another massive attack with drones on the Kyiv region overnight. Air defence forces worked effectively in the region," the head of the Kyiv regional military administration, Ruslan Kravchenko, said.</p>

<p>Wreckage from some of the downed barrage caused fires but there were no casualties or hits on critical infrastructure, he added.</p>

<p>Ukraine's Foreign Minister Andriy Sybiga was in Budapest on Monday to meet Hungarian counterpart Peter Szijjarto.</p>

<p>Hungarian Prime Minister Viktor Orban is the only EU leader to have maintained close ties with the Kremlin since the conflict began in 2022 and has refused military support for Kyiv.</p>

<p>"The one-on-one talks between Andriy Sybiga and Peter Szijjarto lasted about an hour, twice as long as planned," the Ukrainian foreign ministry said, without elaborating.</p>

<p>Hungary has previously blocked substantial funds for Ukraine, a source of frustration for Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky and his EU allies.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/14dvuelo_vladimir-putin-afp-putin-in-office-afp_625x300_27_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Kremlin has pursued a relentless assault in eastern Ukraine in recent months.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/one-in-a-million-china-woman-with-two-uteruses-delivers-a-baby-from-each-6684330]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["One In A Million": China Woman With 2 Uteruses Delivers A Baby From Each]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/one-in-a-million-china-woman-with-two-uteruses-delivers-a-baby-from-each-6684330]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 17:26:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The condition known as uterus didelphys affects only 0.3% of women worldwide.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A woman in northwest China has made international headlines after giving birth to twins from two separate uteruses, a rare medical phenomenon. The condition known as uterus didelphys affects only 0.3% of women worldwide. What's remarkable is that both uteruses were fully formed, complete with ovaries and oviducts. According to the <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3280157/1-million-china-woman-2-uteruses-gives-birth-1-child-each-womb">South China Morning Post</a></em>, the woman&nbsp;surnamed Li,&nbsp;delivered a boy and girl in early September at Xi'an No 4 Hospital in Shaanxi province when she was eight and a half months pregnant.&nbsp;The babies were born healthy, with the boy weighing 3.3kg and the girl 2.4kg.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Cai Ying, a senior obstetrician at the hospital, described Li's pregnancy as a "one in a million" event. "Being pregnant in each of the two uteruses through natural conception is very rare. We have only heard of a couple of such cases from both China and abroad," Cai told <em>SCMP.</em></p>

<p>Li, whose age remains undisclosed, experienced a miscarriage at 27 weeks in a previous pregnancy due to unknown factors. When she became pregnant again in January, doctors at Xi'an No 4 Hospital developed a specialised plan to ensure her safety.</p>

<p>To minimize risks, Li underwent a caesarean section. Fortunately, she and her newborn twins – a boy and a girl – were discharged from the hospital just four days after birth.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to China state broadcaster CCTV, a similar case occurred in December last year in the US state of Alabama. A woman gave birth to twin girls, each developing in a separate uterus. Notably, this mother had previously given birth to three children, but those pregnancies involved only one of her two uteruses.</p>

<p><strong>The Double Uterus Condition:</strong></p>

<ul>
	<li>Uterus didelphys occurs when two small tubes in the female fetus fail to join during development, resulting in two distinct uteruses&nbsp;</li>
	<li>In some cases, each uterus has its cervix, and a thin tissue wall may divide the vagina into two separate chambers.</li>
	<li>Women who have two uteruses face no symptoms till they become pregnant</li>
	<li>During pregnancy, they face&nbsp;a high risk of miscarriage, fetal underdevelopment, premature birth, and post-partum haemorrhages.</li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/r2jmtnl_twins_625x300_30_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The condition known as uterus didelphys affects only 0.3% of women worldwide.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/solar-eclipse-on-october-2-how-fast-it-will-travel-6683968]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Solar Eclipse On October 2: How Fast It Will Travel]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/solar-eclipse-on-october-2-how-fast-it-will-travel-6683968]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 16:47:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The much-anticipated annular solar eclipse is set to grace the skies on October 2. The eclipse will begin at 9:13 pm IST on October 2 and conclude at 3:17 pm IST the next day.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The much-anticipated annular solar eclipse is set to grace the skies on October 2. The eclipse will begin at 9:13 pm IST on October 2 and conclude at 3:17 pm IST the next day. During this time, the Moon will appear smaller than the Sun, creating a brilliant <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/feature/ring-of-fire-solar-eclipse-2024-check-timing-visibility-in-india-and-other-details-6671693 ">“ring of fire”</a> effect – a halo of sunlight visible around the darkened centre.</p>

<p><strong>How fast the eclipse will travel</strong></p>

<p>During the upcoming annular solar eclipse, the speed of the Moon's shadow across Earth will vary significantly depending on location. In some areas, it will travel faster than 10 million kmph, while in others, it will slow to about 2,057 kmph, roughly the speed of a fighter jet, reported <a href="https://www.space.com/how-fast-will-the-annular-solar-eclipse-october-2-travel ">Space.com</a>.</p>

<p><strong>Path of the eclipse</strong></p>

<p>The Moon's shadow will move from northwest to southeast, and due to Earth's curvature and the Moon's changing distance and orbital speed, the shadow's velocity will fluctuate dramatically across different regions. The eclipse will start with an eclipsed sunrise, peak at midday and end with an eclipsed sunset.</p>

<p><strong>Where the eclipse will touch and leave Earth</strong></p>

<p>The Moon's shadow will first strike south of Hawaii in the Pacific Ocean, moving at 8.55 million kmph. When it leaves Earth near the island of South Georgia, it will travel at 10 million km/h. However, these extreme speeds occur as the shadow touches and leaves Earth, rendering them less meaningful.</p>

<p><strong>Where can you view the eclipse?</strong></p>

<p>The shadow's speed will be slower when the eclipse is visible at the horizon, around 8,258 kmph at sunrise and 14,312 kmph at sunset. The slowest speed of 2,057 kmph will be observed in the Pacific Ocean northwest of Easter Island, where the ‘ring of fire' will last for 7 minutes and 25 seconds. This slower speed is due to the Moon's shadow being nearly perpendicular to Earth at local midday – the longest duration of the eclipse.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-10/hii8n5ng_ring-of-fire-annual-solar-eclipse_625x300_08_October_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Moon's shadow will first strike south of Hawaii in the Pacific Ocean (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rescue-operations-continue-as-over-200-people-killed-in-floods-landslides-in-nepal-6683768]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[200 Killed In Floods, Landslides In Nepal, Rescue Operations Continue]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rescue-operations-continue-as-over-200-people-killed-in-floods-landslides-in-nepal-6683768]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 16:21:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Search and rescue operations continued in Nepal for the third consecutive day on Monday after monsoon-induced floods and landslides killed more than 200 people in one of the worst rain-related disasters in the Himalayan nation in recent years.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Search and rescue operations continued in Nepal for the third consecutive day on Monday after monsoon-induced floods and landslides killed more than 200 people in one of the worst rain-related disasters in the Himalayan nation in recent years.</p>

<p>Incessant rainfall over the weekend triggered floods and landslides, wreaking havoc in Kathmandu and most of the districts of Nepal.</p>

<p>At least 204 people have been killed in the continuous rainfall, floods, landslides and inundation, MyRepublica news portal reported, quoting the Armed Police Force (APF).</p>

<p>It added that 89 others have also been injured nationwide in the disaster, while 33 others remain missing.</p>

<p>An all-party meeting convened on Sunday by Officiating Prime Minister Prakash Man Singh at the Prime Minister's Office in Singha Durbar decided to enhance rescue, relief, and re-establishment efforts during the ongoing disaster caused by heavy rains.</p>

<p>The Home Ministry said it would provide grants for temporary housing construction, repair blocked roads to restore transportation and ensure effective free health treatment for citizens injured in disaster incidents.</p>

<p>A task force was also formed to assess the details of the damage caused within a 15-day deadline, the news portal reported.</p>

<p>The Disaster Management Executive Committee&nbsp;said it will provide a relief amount to the families of those missing. If the missing person is not found within 10 days, their family will be provided the same amount as that given to the kin of a person killed in the rain-induced disaster, the report said.</p>

<p>The Home Ministry said all security agencies have been deployed for relief efforts following the floods and landslides, and the Nepal Army, Nepal Police and Armed Police Force personnel have rescued around 4,500 disaster-affected individuals so far.</p>

<p>While those injured are receiving free treatment, food and other emergency relief materials have been provided to others affected by the floods.</p>

<p>Hundreds of people are facing a shortage of food, safe drinking water and sanitation in Kathmandu following the natural disaster, according to eyewitnesses.</p>

<p>Market prices have also soared as vegetables coming from India and other districts of the country have been temporarily halted due to obstruction in major highways due to landslides.</p>

<p>Numerous roads throughout the nation are severely damaged, and all routes leading to the capital city, Kathmandu, are still blocked, leaving thousands of travellers stranded, The Kathmandu Post newspaper reported.</p>

<p>Home Ministry Spokesperson Rishiram Tiwari said efforts are underway to clear the obstructed highways to resume transportation.</p>

<p>At least 20 hydropower plants with a combined capacity of 1100 MW suffered damages due to floods and landslides triggered by the incessant rainfall in the past three days, which has led to the disruption in power supply in Kathmandu and other major cities.</p>

<p>"Heavy rains since Friday have caused widespread flooding across Kathmandu Valley, and across Nepal. This is the worst flooding experienced in recent years," said Jagan Chapagain, the Chief Executive Officer and Secretary General of the International Federation of Red Cross and Red Crescent Societies, in a post on X.</p>

<p>"In response to the crisis, local branches of the @NepalRedCross are working closely with authorities and (the) Emergency Operations Centre of Nepal Red Cross to coordinate rescue and relief operations," he added. Kathmandu's main river, the Bagmati, was flowing above danger levels after incessant rain lashed large swathes of eastern and central Nepal on Friday and Saturday, a report published by the International Centre for Integrated Mountain Development (ICIMOD) said.</p>

<p>"A low-pressure system in the Bay of Bengal and the more northerly than usual position of the monsoon trough was the reason" behind the exceptionally intense rain, it said on Saturday.</p>

<p>Scientists say that while climate change is changing the amount and timing of rainfall across Asia, a key reason for the rise in the impact of floods is the built environment, including unplanned construction, especially on floodplains, which leaves insufficient areas for water retention and drainage.</p>

<p>The floods and landslides have thrown life out of gear in many parts of the country, with many highways and road stretches disrupted, hundreds of houses and bridges buried or swept away, and hundreds of families displaced.</p>

<p>Thousands of passengers have been stranded in various places due to road disruption.</p>

<p>During the all-party meeting, it was also decided that the Ministry of Health and Population will conduct awareness programmes and other initiatives in potential and suitable locations to prevent the spread of diseases, as epidemics can spread after such disasters.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/f2ibqhho_nepal-floods-ians_625x300_30_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Heavy rains since Friday have caused widespread flooding across Kathmandu Valley.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-tesla-catches-fire-inside-florida-garage-flooded-from-hurricane-helene-6683715]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Tesla Catches Fire Inside Florida Garage Flooded From Hurricane Helene]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-tesla-catches-fire-inside-florida-garage-flooded-from-hurricane-helene-6683715]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 16:17:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Officials advised people not to charge, drive, or store their EVs or E-bikes in their homes or garages.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dramatic video footage released by Pinellas County officials shows a Tesla bursting into flames inside a Florida garage flooded by Hurricane Helene. The shocking incident serves as a warning to electric vehicle owners in areas affected by the storm. Surveillance footage reveals the fire starting underneath the car and spreading rapidly, fully engulfing it in under a minute. Thick smoke quickly fills the cluttered garage.</p>

<p>The warning comes after Hurricane Helene brought widespread flooding to parts of Florida, North Carolina, and other southeastern states. Pinellas County Government posted the surveillance video to Facebook on Saturday to warn electric vehicle owners of the risk.</p>

<p>''Electric Vehicles that have been flooded in saltwater can catch fire.&nbsp;If you evacuated and left an electric vehicle or golf cart in your garage or under a building and you are not able to get to it or move it, we want you to let us know,'' the county said in a Facebook post.</p>

<p><strong>Watch the video here:</strong></p>

<p><iframe allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="true" frameborder="0" height="329" scrolling="no" src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/video.php?height=329&amp;href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2FPinellasGov%2Fvideos%2F1886706438505288%2F&amp;show_text=false&amp;width=560&amp;t=0" style="border:none;overflow:hidden" width="560"></iframe></p>

<p></p>

<p>Officials also urged electric car owners to take precautions to prevent similar incidents. Pinellas county advised people not to charge, drive, or store their EVs or E-bikes in their homes or garages. They added that the electric vehicle should be moved 50 feet away from combustible material and towed to a dealership for inspection.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Hurricane Helene made landfall in Florida's Big Bend region late Thursday as a Category 4 storm, bringing 140 mph winds and widespread devastation. As it swept through Georgia, the Carolinas, and Tennessee, Helene uprooted trees. splintered homes, caused creeks and rivers to overflow, spawned tornadoes and strained dams.&nbsp;The powerful hurricane left at least 93 people dead and left millions without power, as per<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/09/29/us-news/shocking-video-shows-entire-bridge-washed-away-by-hurricane-helen-floodwater/" rel="nofollow, noindex"><em> </em></a><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/09/29/us-news/tesla-erupts-into-flames-inside-flooded-fla-garage-following-hurricane-helene-video/"><em>New York Post.&nbsp;</em></a></p>

<p>President Joe Biden is planning to visit areas affected by Hurricane Helene this week, but only if it doesn't hinder ongoing rescue and recovery efforts. He assured that his administration is providing all available resources to support the affected states in their response. The American Red Cross has launched a massive relief effort, deploying over 1,400 disaster workers and opening hundreds of shelters for those affected.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/g48e3m9o_-tesla-car-on-fire_625x300_30_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The garage where the incident took place was flooded with saltwater by the storm.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/google-paid-2-7-billion-to-rehire-ai-genius-noam-shazeer-to-co-lead-gemini-report-6683643]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Google Paid $2.7 Billion To Rehire AI Genius To Co-Lead Gemini: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/google-paid-2-7-billion-to-rehire-ai-genius-noam-shazeer-to-co-lead-gemini-report-6683643]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 16:08:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Google re-hired its long-time researcher, Naom Shazeer, to co-lead its AI models in a $2.7 billion deal, the Wall Street Journal reported. Mr Shazeer quit Google in 2021 after being a part of the company for 21 years.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Google re-hired its long-time researcher, Noam Shazeer, to co-lead its AI models in a $2.7 billion deal, the Wall Street Journal reported. Mr Shazeer quit Google in 2021 after being a part of the company for 21 years.&nbsp;</p>

<p>He reportedly quit when the company refused to launch a chatbot head had built along with a colleague. He went on to head the Character. AI.</p>

<p>He was a co-author of a seminal 2017 research paper which catalyzed the current AI boom. Character.AI utilizes the technical advancements pioneered in the paper. It has raised $193 million and was valued at $1 billion last year by venture capitalists.</p>

<p>Character.AI reached a valuation of $1 Billion last year. Google paid $2.7 Billion to Character.AI for a transfer of technology and bringing back Mr Shazeer to Google, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.wsj.com/tech/ai/noam-shazeer-google-ai-deal-d3605697" rel="no follow, no index">the report said</a>.</p>

<p>AI-boom has prompted startups to release new features to their chatbots as competitors such as Microsoft-backed OpenAI, Google and Amazon-backed Anthropic are looking to gain market share by engaging new users.</p>

<p>Last year, Google was in talks to invest hundreds of millions of dollars in Character.AI, but chose to bring him back.</p>

<p>The deal, which resembles similar moves by Amazon and Microsoft to nab top talent from AI startups, comes at a time when the Big Tech companies are facing regulatory scrutiny.</p>

<p>Shazeer is serving as a technical lead on Gemini - Google's AI chatbot - joining the other co-leaders Jeff Dean and Oriol Vinyals. Gemini is the line of AI models being developed by DeepMind, Google's AI division, and which are being integrated into products such as Search and Pixel smartphones.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/75hvov8o_noam-shazeer-google_625x300_30_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[He quit Google when it refused to launch a chatbot head had built along with a colleague]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-houthis-on-camera-oil-tank-explodes-in-yemen-after-israeli-air-strikes-6683607]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[On Camera, Oil Tank Explodes In Yemen After Israeli Air Strikes]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-houthis-on-camera-oil-tank-explodes-in-yemen-after-israeli-air-strikes-6683607]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 16:04:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli forceslaunched airstrikes on Yemen's Ras Isa Port on Sunday, targeting oil facilities and power stations controlled by the Houthi rebels.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli forces&nbsp;<a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-strikes-houthi-controlled-port-power-plants-in-yemen-6678794 ">launched airstrikes on Yemen</a>'s Ras Isa Port on Sunday, targeting oil facilities and power stations controlled by the Houthi rebels. The strikes were part of Israel's response to recent Houthi missile attacks, including one aimed at Ben Gurion Airport in Tel Aviv. Now, newly surfaced footage shows the aftermath of one of the airstrikes on the nearby port of Hudeidah.<br />
<br />
The video, which has been widely circulated on social media, shows oil tanks at the port engulfed in flames, with thick black smoke billowing into the sky. “When an oil tank exploded inside the port of Hudaidah in Yemen; As a result of bombing by @Israel,” the caption of the video read.&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">When an oil tank exploded inside the port of Hudaidah in Yemen; As a result of bombing by <a href="https://twitter.com/Israel?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Israel</a>. <a href="https://t.co/7lGTDCnkd8">pic.twitter.com/7lGTDCnkd8</a></p>
— Jordan ???????????????????????????????????????? (@Mhmmd_Jordan) <a href="https://twitter.com/Mhmmd_Jordan/status/1840472084108960143?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 29, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Houthi-controlled Al-Masirah TV reported that four workers -- a port employee and three engineers -- were killed and over 30 sustained injuries. Rescue operations are underway.</p>

<p>Eyewitnesses saw plumes of smoke and fire from oil tanks struck by Israeli missiles that also hit power stations in the area.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to the Israeli military, dozens of aircraft, including fighter jets, refuelling planes and reconnaissance aircraft, participated in the operation. “Today's operation was a significant escalation in our response to the Houthi threat,” Israel's military spokesperson, Captain David Avraham, told AFP. “We will not tolerate attacks on Israeli territory, and we will take all necessary measures to protect our citizens.”</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">The IAF struck military targets belonging to the Houthi terrorist regime in Yemen in response to their recent attacks against Israel.<br />
<br />
The targets included power plants and a seaport, which were used by the Houthis to transfer Iranian weapons to the region, in addition to…</p>
— Israeli Air Force (@IAFsite) <a href="https://twitter.com/IAFsite/status/1840412854630973725?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 29, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>According to the Israeli Defense Forces (IDF), the airstrikes targeted power plants and a seaport used by the Houthi regime to import oil and transfer Iranian weapons and military supplies. These facilities were reportedly used by the Houthis to support their ongoing military campaign, which has been funded and directed by Iran, with cooperation from Iraqi militias.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="rtl" lang="iw">מבצע אווירי רחב היקף בתימן:<br />
עשרות כלי טיס של חיל-האוויר בהם מטוסי קרב, מטוסי תדלוק ומודיעין, תקפו כ-1,800 ק״מ מגבול ישראל, מטרות אשר בשימוש צבאי של שלטון הטרור החות׳י, במרחבים ראס עיסא וחודידה שבתימן.<br />
<br />
במבצע הותקפו תחנות כוח ונמל ימי, אשר משמשים לייבוא נפט, באמצעותם השלטון החות׳י… <a href="https://t.co/5I6Ud4TnVP">pic.twitter.com/5I6Ud4TnVP</a></p>
— Israeli Air Force (@IAFsite) <a href="https://twitter.com/IAFsite/status/1840404744789188823?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 29, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>This latest strike comes as part of Israel's broader regional military offence, which has intensified in recent weeks. Last week, Israeli airstrikes in Lebanon killed over 1,000 people and displaced hundreds of thousands. Israel's ongoing assault on Gaza, which began on October 7 last year, has already killed over 42,000 Palestinians and displaced nearly the entire population of the narrow strip.</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/7hcpg3sg_oil-tank-explosion_625x300_30_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Israel strikes targeted ports and oil stations.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-makes-a-person-seem-wise-various-cultures-differ-according-to-study-6683476]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What Makes A Person Seem Wise? Various Cultures Differ, According To Study]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-makes-a-person-seem-wise-various-cultures-differ-according-to-study-6683476]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 15:48:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[We all admire wise people, dont we? Whether its a thoughtful teacher, a compassionate doctor, or an elder in the community, we recognise wisdom when we see it.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="theconversation-article-title"><span style="font-size: 13px;">We all admire wise people, don't we? Whether it's a thoughtful teacher, a compassionate doctor, or an elder in the community, we recognise wisdom when we see it. But have you ever thought about how people in different cultures perceive wisdom? Does someone in Morocco view a wise person in the same way as someone in Ecuador? Our recent </span><a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-50294-0" style="font-size: 13px;">study</a><span style="font-size: 13px;"> explored how people across cultures think of wisdom.</span></p>

<div class="theconversation-article-body">
<p>This large-scale project required a joint effort of 34 researchers across fields of philosophy, psychology, anthropology, social science and psychometrics – and from all over the world, connected in a research consortium called <a href="https://www.geographyofphilosophy.com/">The Geography of Philosophy</a>.</p>

<p>What we found was somewhat surprising. Wisdom may appear to be shaped by cultural differences, but the core aspects of what makes someone wise are largely the same across cultures. From urban college students in Japan to villagers in South Africa, participants associated wisdom with two key characteristics: reflective orientation and socio-emotional awareness. We explain what that means below.</p>

<p>Contrary to widespread stereotypes, people recognise the wisdom in a similar way across East and West, South and North. Despite the divisions of the world, we see wisdom in the same individuals and associate it with similar traits. Are we indeed more alike than we are different when it comes to how we perceive wisdom? And what characterises wise people?</p>

<h3><strong>These are the characteristics of wise people</strong></h3>

<p>There are two key characteristics. Reflective orientation is about people who think before acting, carefully consider different perspectives, and use logic and past experiences to guide their decisions. They're the type of person who keeps their cool in difficult situations, taking time to weigh all the options before making a move.</p>

<p>The second is socio-emotional awareness. Wise people are good at understanding and caring about the thoughts and feelings of others. They pay attention to emotions and consider different views on the situation. Such an individual might be skilled at mediating conflicts by understanding each party's point of view, or be adept at providing emotional support during difficult times.</p>

<p>Together, these two dimensions combine to form the global image of wisdom. The study suggests that the wisest people are those who balance both, showing strong abilities in reasoning while also being emotionally and socially aware.</p>

<p>A highly reflective person who is suppressing their own emotions but doesn't notice the social context of the problem wouldn't be called wise. Likewise, someone who is entirely driven by emotion and the social environment but fails to make logical connections wouldn't be called wise either. Real wisdom, according to our study, is about finding a balance between thoughtful reasoning, social understanding, and emotional awareness.</p>

<h3><strong>Cultures do differ, but not as much as you might think</strong></h3>

<p>To uncover these dimensions, we employed a method sometimes called <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2007/12/09/magazine/09wwln-idealab-t.html">experimental philosophy</a>. Participants across 16 different cultures in 12 countries on five continents compared a set of targets to each other. For example, one of the questions asked participants to compare whether a doctor or a religious person was more likely to think logically when making a hard life decision with no right or wrong answers. Our participants also rated themselves. Then we asked how wise each of these persons were.</p>

<p>When we started this project, we expected to find big differences between cultures. <a href="https://www.simonandschuster.com/books/The-Geography-of-Thought/Richard-Nisbett/9780743255356">Previous research</a> suggested that people in “the West” use and value analytical thinking, which tends to dismiss social and emotional parts of the situation. In contrast, individuals in “the East” emphasise holistic thinking, that is, all-encompassing views of complex situations.</p>

<p>But that's not what we found. While there were some small differences – people in South Africa, for example, placed more importance on nature and divinity when thinking about socio-emotional awareness – the overall picture was strikingly similar. Across the globe, people rated individuals who were both reflective and socially and emotionally aware as the wisest. For instance, they named a doctor and a 75-year-old person as the wisest, and at the same time the highest on both dimensions.</p>

<p>What was particularly fascinating was that people tended to rate themselves differently from how they rated others. Most people saw themselves as less reflective but more socially and emotionally aware than the “wise” figures they were asked to rate. In other words, people were ready to admit a moderate level of their own intellectual capabilities, but they were quite confident in their ability to understand and care for others.</p>

<h3><strong>Why this matters</strong></h3>

<p>This research defies stereotypes of a cold analytical ideal of “the west” and a social-minded and emotionally driven image of “the east” and “the south”. The idea that wisdom is purely intellectual, or conversely, purely social or divine, is too simplistic. It also highlights that wisdom manifests in a balance of traits traditionally attributed to different cultures.</p>

<p>In a time when global cooperation is more important than ever, recognising our shared appreciation for certain qualities can help bridge cultural divides.</p>

<p>The study opens up new avenues for research. Could these dimensions of wisdom help us understand how to solve global problems? Are people more likely to trust leaders who show both reflective thinking and socio-emotional awareness? And how do these qualities affect the way we handle personal relationships, difficult decisions, or conflicts?</p>

<p>One thing is clear: wisdom is something we all value, no matter where we come from. By understanding it better, we can not only become wiser ourselves but also learn to appreciate wisdom in others, wherever they may be.<!-- Below is The Conversation's page counter tag. Please DO NOT REMOVE. --><img alt="The Conversation" height="1" referrerpolicy="no-referrer-when-downgrade" src="https://counter.theconversation.com/content/238808/count.gif?distributor=republish-lightbox-basic" style="border: none !important; box-shadow: none !important; margin: 0 !important; max-height: 1px !important; max-width: 1px !important; min-height: 1px !important; min-width: 1px !important; opacity: 0 !important; outline: none !important; padding: 0 !important" width="1" /><!-- End of code. If you don't see any code above, please get new code from the Advanced tab after you click the republish button. The page counter does not collect any personal data. More info: https://theconversation.com/republishing-guidelines --></p>

<p><em><span><a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/maksim-rudnev-2208633">Maksim Rudnev</a>, Research Associate, Department of Psychology, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/university-of-waterloo-1284">University of Waterloo</a> and <a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/veli-mitova-2208636">Veli Mitova</a>, Professor in Philosophy and Director of the African Centre for Epistemology and Philosophy of Science, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/university-of-johannesburg-1275">University of Johannesburg</a></span></em></p>

<p><em>This article is republished from <a href="https://theconversation.com">The Conversation</a> under a Creative Commons license. Read the <a href="https://theconversation.com/what-makes-a-person-seem-wise-global-study-finds-that-cultures-do-differ-but-not-as-much-as-youd-think-238808">original article</a>.</em></p>
</div><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/hvh3lkhg_brain_625x300_29_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Reflective orientation is about people who think before acting (Representational).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/singer-songwriter-kris-kristofferson-dies-at-88-6683365]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Singer-Songwriter Kris Kristofferson Dies At 88]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/singer-songwriter-kris-kristofferson-dies-at-88-6683365]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 15:35:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kris Kristofferson, who became one of the most influential American singer-songwriters of his time with works such as "Me and Bobby McGee," as well as becoming a successful actor, died Saturday at the age of 88, according to a family statement.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kris Kristofferson, who became one of the most influential American singer-songwriters of his time with works such as "Me and Bobby McGee," as well as becoming a successful actor, died Saturday at the age of 88, according to a family statement.</p>

<p>Kristofferson had been suffering from memory loss since he was in his 70s. A family spokesperson said in a statement that Kristofferson died peacefully at his home in Maui, Hawaii, surrounded by family, but a cause of death was not listed.</p>

<p>Kristofferson was a Renaissance man - an athlete with a poet's sensibilities, a former Army officer and helicopter pilot, and a Rhodes scholar who took a job as a janitor in what turned out to be a brilliant career move.</p>

<p>Kristofferson first established himself in the music world as a songwriter in the country music capital of Nashville - writing hits such as the Grammy-winning "Help Me Make It Through the Night," "For the Good Times," and one-time girlfriend Janis Joplin's plaintive No. 1 hit, "Me and Bobby McGee."</p>

<p>In the early 1970s, he became well-known as a performer with a rumbling, unpolished baritone, as well as an in-demand actor, notably opposite Barbra Streisand in "A Star Is Born," one of the most popular films of 1976.</p>

<p>Kristofferson was born in Brownsville, Texas, on June 22, 1936, and moved frequently because his father was a general in the Air Force. After graduating from Pomona College in California, where he played football and rugby, Kristofferson attended Oxford University on a Rhodes scholarship and then fulfilled the family tradition by joining the Army.</p>

<p>He went through the Army's elite Ranger School, learned to pilot helicopters and reached the rank of captain. In 1965 Kristofferson was offered a position teaching English - he was enthralled by the works of poet William Blake - at the U.S. Military Academy in West Point, New York, but he turned it down in order to head to Nashville.</p>

<p>Kristofferson became a janitor at the Columbia Records studio because it would give him a chance to offer his songs to the big-name stars recording there. He also worked as a helicopter pilot ferrying workers between Louisiana oilfields and offshore drilling rigs.</p>

<p>During that time Kristofferson wrote some of his most memorable songs, including "Help Me Make It Through the Night," which he said he penned atop an oil platform.</p>

<p>His most audacious song pitch came when he landed his helicopter on Johnny Cash's lawn - although he denied Cash's version of him climbing out of the cockpit with an audio tape in one hand and a beer in the other. Cash would later have a No. 1 hit with Kristofferson's "Sunday Morning Comin' Down" lament.</p>

<h3><strong>"NOTHING LEFT TO LOSE"</strong></h3>

<p>Kristofferson's best songs were filled with seekers, wastrels and broken souls trying to find love, redemption or relief from the hangover that life had given them. The broken-hearted narrator of "Bobby McGee," a song Kristofferson said was inspired by the Federico Fellini film "La Strada," summed it up with the line, "Freedom's just another word for nothing left to lose."</p>

<p>"Kris brought (country music) kind of from the dark ages up to the present-day time, made it acceptable and brought great lyrics - I mean, the best possible lyrics," Willie Nelson, an early role model for Kristofferson, told CBS's "60 Minutes" in a 1999 interview. "Simple but profound."</p>

<p>Kristofferson recorded four albums with Rita Coolidge, the second of his three wives, in the 1970s and joined Nelson, Cash and Waylon Jennings in the country music supergroup the Highwaymen in the 1980s and '90s.</p>

<p>Kristofferson's rugged good looks led to roles in movies such as "Cisco Pike," "Pat Garrett &amp; Billy the Kid," "The Sailor Who Fell from Grace with the Sea," "Convoy," "Heaven's Gate," "Lone Star" and "Blade."</p>

<p>Kristofferson lived hard during his heyday. There was a long line of girlfriends and performances he could not remember because he was drunk. He gave up drinking - but not marijuana - when a doctor told him he was killing himself.</p>

<p>"It was fun," Kristofferson told "60 Minutes." "It was the way that I thought an artist was supposed to live. I always agreed with Blake when he said that the road of excess leads to the palace of wisdom. ... I think God protects fools and songwriters."</p>

<p>After his initial stardom, Kristofferson took on causes such as the United Farm Workers and spoke out against US government involvement in Nicaragua and El Salvador in the 1980s.</p>

<p>Kristofferson began experiencing debilitating memory loss in his mid-70s and his performances suffered for it. Doctors told him it appeared to be the onset of Alzheimer's disease or dementia, possibly brought on by blows to the head while boxing and playing football and rugby in his younger days.</p>

<p>But in 2016, his wife, Lisa, told Rolling Stone magazine that Kristofferson had been diagnosed with Lyme disease, which can cause memory problems, and that after treatment and stopping Alzheimer's medication, his memory began to return partially.</p>

<p>Kristofferson kept active with a 2016 tour that included performances with Nelson and stops in Europe. That year he also marked his 80th birthday by releasing "The Cedar Creek Sessions," an album featuring live versions of his best-known songs.</p>

<p>Kristofferson and his third wife, Lisa, whom he married in 1983, lived on the Hawaiian island of Maui for more than 30 years. He had eight children.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/0n0r1bi_kris-kristofferson_625x300_30_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kris Kristofferson's best songs were filled with seekers, wastrels and broken souls trying to find love]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-opens-additional-250-000-visa-appointments-for-indian-travelers-6683307]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Opens Additional 2.5 Lakh Visa Appointments For Indian Travelers]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-opens-additional-250-000-visa-appointments-for-indian-travelers-6683307]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 15:29:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The US Mission to India opened an additional 250,000 visa appointments for Indian travelers, including tourists, skilled workers, and students.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The US Mission to India opened an additional 250,000 visa appointments for Indian travelers, including tourists, skilled workers, and students.</p>

<p>The recently released new slots will help hundreds of thousands of Indian applicants take timely interviews, facilitating the travel which is the backbone of the people-to-people ties that underpin the US-India relationship, the US embassy in New Delhi announced in an official statement on Monday.</p>

<p>Sharing a post on X, the US embassy in India wrote, "The US Mission to India has opened an additional 250,000 visa appointments for Indian travelers, including tourists, skilled workers, and students."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">The U.S. Mission to India has opened an additional 250,000 visa appointments for Indian travelers, including tourists, skilled workers, and students. <a href="https://t.co/DnPYNNkONN">pic.twitter.com/DnPYNNkONN</a></p>
— U.S. Embassy India (@USAndIndia) <a href="https://twitter.com/USAndIndia/status/1840667092355268929?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 30, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The US Mission to India has already surpassed one million nonimmigrant visa applications for the second consecutive year, according to the statement of the US embassy in New Delhi.</p>

<p>During our student visa season this summer, we continued to process record numbers, and all first-time student applicants could obtain an appointment at one of our five consular sections around India. We are now focused on bringing families together, connecting businesses, and facilitating tourism.</p>

<p>"More than 1.2 million Indians have traveled to the United States year to date in 2024, a 35 per cent increase over the same period in 2023," the statement added.</p>

<p>At least six million Indians already have a nonimmigrant visa to visit the United States, and each day, the Mission issues thousands more.</p>

<p>As US Ambassador to India Eric Garcetti recently noted, "Prime Minister Narendra Modi and President Joe Biden set an ambitious goal to improve and expedite the visa process and I'm proud to say that we have delivered on that promise. Our consular teams at the embassy and four consulates work tirelessly to ensure that we meet the surging demand."</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-07/nkk22sq8_us-generic-650_650x400_27_July_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[At least six million Indians already have a nonimmigrant visa to visit the US. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/why-the-vance-walz-debate-boils-down-to-contrasting-versions-of-masculinity-6683266]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Why The Vance-Walz Debate Boils Down To Contrasting Versions Of Masculinity]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/why-the-vance-walz-debate-boils-down-to-contrasting-versions-of-masculinity-6683266]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 15:20:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump's running mate JD Vance and Kamala Harris's vice-presidential pick Tim Walz -- set to debate each other Tuesday -- embody different versions of masculinity in an election that is dividing American men and women like never before.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump's running mate JD Vance and Kamala Harris's vice-presidential pick Tim Walz -- set to debate each other Tuesday -- embody different versions of masculinity in an election that is dividing American men and women like never before.</p>

<p>Vance, on the Republican ticket, has a conservative definition of family.</p>

<p>The Ohio senator has been criticized for denouncing "childless cat ladies" who have no "direct interest" in the welfare of the country, he alleged, because they have no children.</p>

<p>As a former soldier from a lower-class family, Vance sees himself as the spokesman for the downtrodden Americans with whom he grew up.</p>

<p>Stringently opposed to abortion, Vance also criticizes progressive ideas of family which, in his view, encourage "people to shift spouses like they change their underwear."</p>

<p>On the other side, Democrat Tim Walz strives to project a different image of the good family man -- one who does not hesitate to show a more vulnerable side of himself, like when discussing the fertility problems he faced with his wife Gwen.</p>

<p>"I can remember praying each night for a phone call," he recounted at the Democratic National Convention.</p>

<p>"The pit in your stomach when the phone would ring, and the absolute agony when we heard the treatments hadn't worked."</p>

<p>The Minnesota governor, a former teacher, also frequently retells the story of how he helped create the first LGBTQ student club at the high school where he taught, long before gay rights were widely socially accepted.</p>

<h3><strong>'Toxic masculinity' alternatives&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Walz, who also coached high school football and served 24 years in the National Guard, still plays into a classic male archetype, whether he is discussing his favourite hardware store on TikTok or boasting about his hunting skills.</p>

<p>In reference to Vance, for instance, Walz said: "I guarantee you he can't shoot pheasants like I can."</p>

<p>"The Harris campaign is offering alternatives to the 'toxic masculinity' that has captured the Republican party," said Karrin Vasby Anderson, a communications studies professor at Colorado State University.</p>

<p>And Walz isn't alone, she added.</p>

<p>Harris's husband, Doug Emhoff, enthusiastically supports his wife and has no problem making himself the butt of the joke, including when he describes the awkward voicemail he left her after their first date.</p>

<p>The posturing is a far cry from Donald Trump's "macho man" stance -- one that he references by playing the Village People hit of the same name to open his rallies.</p>

<p>Anderson argues that societal gains by women and people of colour have "required white men to make adjustments to how they speak, what jokes they tell, how they comport themselves in romantic relationships, how they conduct themselves at work."</p>

<p>"Some men don't like having to change," she added.</p>

<h3><strong>Gender divide&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>According to recent polls, a growing number of young men are throwing their support behind Trump, whose rhetoric centres on strength, authority and even violence.</p>

<p>The Republican is capitalizing on this well of support by increasing the number of events he holds with influencers involved in cryptocurrency, video games and combat sports, many of whom have followings in the tens of millions.</p>

<p>In the extremely close race for the White House, Trump hopes to motivate an electorate that historically has not had a strong turnout at the polls.</p>

<p>Harris, on the other hand, often says that "the true measure of strength is based on who you lift up, not who you beat down."</p>

<p>The Democrat, who fiercely defends abortion rights, is banking on mobilizing women, who vote in greater numbers than men in the United States.</p>

<p>The 2020 election saw 82.2 million women go to the polls, compared with 72.5 million men, according to the Center for American Women and Politics.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/4hjdk9n8_tim-walz-jd-vance-split_625x300_29_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[JD Vance slams progressive ideas of family while Tim Walz projects a different image of a good family man]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/frenchman-on-mass-rape-trial-absent-from-court-for-being-unwell-6683064]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Frenchman On Mass Rape Trial Absent From Court For Being "Unwell"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/frenchman-on-mass-rape-trial-absent-from-court-for-being-unwell-6683064]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 14:54:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Dominique Pelicot, 71, has been on trial since September 2 over raping and recruiting strangers to rape his heavily sedated wife Gisele for nearly a decade.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The main defendant in a mass rape trial that has sparked horror and protests in France was absent on Monday because he is "unwell" and must undergo medical treatment, the presiding judge said.</p>

<p>Dominique Pelicot, 71, has been on trial since September 2 over raping and recruiting strangers to rape his heavily sedated wife Gisele for nearly a decade.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The trial had already been briefly suspended in mid-September due to the absence of Dominique Pelicot, who was suffering from intestinal problems.</p>

<p>"He's unwell. He has to have medical treatment this afternoon," Judge Roger Arata said at the start of the hearing on Monday in the southeastern city of Avignon. "We'll see tomorrow," he added.</p>

<p>Dominique Pelicot had already been excused from the hearing on Friday to undergo a medical examination.&nbsp;</p>

<p>His lawyer Beatrice Zavarro had told AFP on Sunday that the examination "went well."</p>

<p>Pelicot has admitted to the charges against him.</p>

<p>He is being tried along with 50 other men aged between 26 and 74, many of whom have denied the rape charge. Most risk up to 20 years in jail if convicted of aggravated rape.</p>

<p>Seven more defendants will be called to testify on Thursday.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Among them is 46-year-old Jerome V., a former grocery store employee, who sexually assaulted Gisele Pelicot six times in 2020 at the couple's home in the town of Mazan in southeastern France.</p>

<p>Gisele Pelicot, Dominique's ex-wife who only discovered the abuse in 2020 after being told of it by police, has requested that the trial be open to the public to raise awareness about the use of drugs to commit sexual abuse.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/5m5tlorg_gisele-pelicot-french-mass-rape-survivor-afp_625x300_14_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Gisele Pelicot, Dominique's ex-wife discovered the abuse only in 2020. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-to-expect-from-natos-new-chief-mark-rutte-6682988]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What To Expect From NATO's New Chief Mark Rutte?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-to-expect-from-natos-new-chief-mark-rutte-6682988]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 14:45:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Incoming NATO chief Mark Rutte brings new leadership this week to one of the world's most powerful-sounding roles -- helming the nuclear-armed Atlantic alliance.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Incoming NATO chief Mark Rutte brings new leadership this week to one of the world's most powerful-sounding roles -- helming the nuclear-armed Atlantic alliance.</p>

<p>But even if the former Dutch prime minister wanted to shake things up after taking over from Jens Stoltenberg, he probably couldn't.</p>

<p>The reality of the NATO job means Rutte will be heading a risk-averse civilian bureaucracy, with hard power ultimately residing with member countries and above all the United States.</p>

<p>And in many ways NATO's 32 nations -- by swapping one mild-mannered, middle-aged, northern European male ex-premier for another -- have opted for more of the same, to steer the alliance in troubled times.</p>

<p>"In such a difficult geopolitical situation, keeping continuation and the same foreign policy and security line is very important," a senior NATO diplomat told AFP, talking on condition of anonymity to discuss internal deliberations.</p>

<p>During his more than 10 years at the helm, Stoltenberg won plaudits for his calm stewardship of the sometimes fractious alliance.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Norwegian helped keep then-US president Donald Trump on board, threw his weight behind Ukraine while making sure NATO didn't get dragged into a war with Russia and kicked off an overhaul of the alliance's defences to face Moscow.</p>

<p>"Allies were looking for somebody who has many of the same qualities as Stoltenberg and will continue in the same direction: prime minister, well-connected, long experience, good address book, has handled Trump," said Jamie Shea, a former senior NATO official now with the Chatham House think tank.</p>

<p>Rutte, a favourite of key powers the US, Britain, France and Germany, ticked all those boxes.</p>

<p>A veteran who led complex coalitions in the Netherlands for 13 years, he has ample experience that can be put to use keeping countries with disparate -- and often competing -- interests on the same page.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"He is a consensus builder with an unflinching commitment to the transatlantic alliance," a senior US official said.</p>

<p>The Dutchman has been a stalwart backer of Kyiv and wasn't afraid to talk frankly to Trump, who could make a comeback after elections in November.&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>Consensus straitjacket?</strong></h3>

<p>Similarities aside, diplomats say the straight-talking Rutte should bring a breath of fresh air to the alliance after Stoltenberg's long tenure.</p>

<p>But Rutte would likely struggle to get through major changes.</p>

<p>While the job of running the alliance sounds like a potent role, the secretary general actually only heads the civilian bureaucracy of some 1,500 staff.</p>

<p>Military power rests with the member countries -- mainly in the hands of an American general as Supreme Allied Commander in Europe.</p>

<p>The NATO head often serves more as a spokesperson-in-chief for the organisation, with Stoltenberg known for carefully parsing the position he could stake out.</p>

<p>All decisions at NATO need to be agreed by each member and the person at the top is constrained by how far allies -- and particularly Washington -- are willing to go.</p>

<p>The direction for the next year was set at the last summit in Washington in July.</p>

<p>"NATO is a consensus organisation. Everything, absolutely everything, from the most mundane to the most strategic, is decided by consensus," said Ian Lesser of the German Marshall Fund think tank.</p>

<p>"So the scope for individual secretary generals to reshape what NATO does and how it does it is obviously very limited."&nbsp;</p>

<p>That said, Rutte does have some levers at his disposal to try to drive through priorities.</p>

<p>"The secretary-general can be instrumental in bringing issues to the agenda for discussion," Lesser said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"That's actually a big role."</p>

<p>Stoltenberg used his pulpit to press allies on supporting Ukraine, paying more attention to the impact of climate change or strengthening ties with partners in Asia-Pacific.</p>

<p>Diplomats say one area where Rutte could push is trying to improve coordination between the European Union and NATO -- long hamstrung by alliance member Turkey's standoff with Cyprus.&nbsp;</p>

<p>But Rutte's main chance to shape the office will likely come if the political situation gets stormier -- with Trump's return to office or a major change in Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Then he'll need all his diplomatic guile -- and lengthy contact list -- to keep the ears and commitment of NATO's diverse leaders.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The skill and personality of a secretary general can make a difference, especially under conditions when the alliance is being tested," Lesser said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/u2qnhp2g_mark-rutte-reuters-_625x300_30_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mark Rutte, a favourite of key powers the US, Britain, France and Germany, ticked all those boxes.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/business-news/global-investment-firm-fidelity-reduces-value-of-elon-musks-x-by-79-per-cent-platform-likely-worth-9-4-billion-6681613]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Investment Firm Fidelity Reduces Value Of Elon Musk's X By 79%]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/business-news/global-investment-firm-fidelity-reduces-value-of-elon-musks-x-by-79-per-cent-platform-likely-worth-9-4-billion-6681613]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 14:05:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Global investment firm Fidelity has reduce the value of its holding in Elon Musk-run X (formerly Twitter) by a massive 78.7 per cent, which implies that the X social media platform is likely valued at just $9.4 billion.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Global investment firm Fidelity has reduce the value of its holding in Elon Musk-run X (formerly Twitter) by a massive 78.7 per cent, which implies that the X social media platform is likely valued at just $9.4 billion.</p>

<p>The tech billionaire had bought the social media company for $44 billion in October 2022 after an intense drama.</p>

<p>As per new estimate from asset manager Fidelity, X is now valued at less than a quarter of its $44 billion purchase price (at August end), reports TechCrunch, citing its filings.</p>

<p>The fund now values its stake in X at approximately $4.18 million. In July, Fidelity valued its shares in X at about $5.5 million.</p>

<p>X, Fidelity or Musk did not immediately comment on the report based on regulatory disclosures.</p>

<p>In May, Musk-run artificial intelligence (AI) company xAI raised $6 billion to accelerate the research and development of future technologies. In a post, the X owner said the pre-money valuation was $18 billion.</p>

<p>xAI, which has unveiled an AI chatbot called 'Grok', raised funds from key investors, including Fidelity Management and Research.</p>

<p>In January this year, the global investment firm Fidelity marked down its investment in Musk-run X Holdings (the parent company of X) by a whopping 71.5 per cent from the original value.</p>

<p>Fidelity took a stake in X Corp for $300 million in October 2022 when Musk acquired the platform, formerly called Twitter, for $44 billion.</p>

<p>In 2023, Fidelity had cut the valuation by 65 per cent, and now, it has further cut X's valuation in a new disclosure.</p>

<p>Musk had reportedly told bankers, after taking $13 billion in loan to fund his Twitter acquisition, that they will not lose any money on the deal. The debt is split between $6.5 billion of term loans, as well as $6 billion of senior and junior bonds and a $500 million revolver. Lenders were unlikely to get even 60 cents on the dollar for the bonds and loans.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-07/83n5a6vo_x-logo-_625x300_29_July_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The fund now values its stake in X at approximately $4.18 million.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-ukraine-conflict-all-goals-set-for-ukraine-will-be-achieved-says-russian-president-putin-6682481]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["All Goals" Set For Ukraine Will Be Achieved, Says Russian President Putin]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-ukraine-conflict-all-goals-set-for-ukraine-will-be-achieved-says-russian-president-putin-6682481]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 13:32:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russian President Vladimir Putin on Monday vowed that Moscow would accomplish all goals it has set for itself in Ukraine, in its third year of conflict.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russian President Vladimir Putin on Monday vowed that Moscow would accomplish all goals it has set for itself in Ukraine, in its third year of conflict.</p>

<p>"The truth is on our side. All goals set will be achieved," Putin said in a video message released to mark the second anniversary of what Russia calls "Reunification Day" when Moscow annexed four Ukrainian regions.</p>

<p>After it sent troops into Ukraine in February 2022, Russia annexed the regions of Lugansk, Donetsk, Zaporizhzhia and Kherson. It does not fully control all territory in these regions.</p>

<p>In his address, Putin repeated his justification for sending troops into Ukraine as protecting Russian speakers against a "neo-Nazi dictatorship" that aimed to "cut them off forever from Russia, their historic homeland".</p>

<p>He also slammed "Western elites" who "turned Ukraine into their colony, a military base aimed at Russia" and who fanned "hate, radical nationalism... hostility to everything Russian".</p>

<p>"Today we are fighting for a secure, prosperous future for our children and grandchildren", he said.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/14dvuelo_vladimir-putin-afp-putin-in-office-afp_625x300_27_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[In his address, Vladimir Putin repeated his justification for sending troops into Ukraine. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-confirms-death-of-its-leader-in-lebanon-in-israeli-airstrike-6682312]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hamas Confirms Death Of Its Leader In Lebanon In Israeli Airstrike]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-confirms-death-of-its-leader-in-lebanon-in-israeli-airstrike-6682312]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 13:06:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Palestinian militant group Hamas said its leader in Lebanon was killed Monday in a strike on the country's south, as official media reported a strike on a Palestinian refugee camp.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Palestinian militant group Hamas said its leader in Lebanon was killed Monday in a strike on the country's south, as official media reported a strike on a Palestinian refugee camp.</p>

<p>"Fatah Sharif Abu al-Amine, the leader of Hamas... in Lebanon and member of the movement's leadership abroad" was killed in an air strike on his "home in the Al-Bass camp in south Lebanon", a Hamas statement said.</p>

<p>It said he was killed with his wife, son and daughter in a "terrorist and criminal assassination".</p>

<p>The official National News Agency reported an air strike on Al-Bass near the city of Tyre, saying it was the "first time" the camp had been targeted.</p>

<p>The statement came hours after the Popular Front for the Liberation of Palestine (PFLP), a secular left-wing group, said three of its members were killed in a strike in Beirut's Kola district early Monday.</p>

<p>Israel has repeatedly targeted Hamas officials in Lebanon since the Gaza war erupted almost a year ago.</p>

<p>A strike in January, which a US defence official said was carried out by Israel, killed Hamas deputy leader Saleh al-Aruri and six other militants in Hezbollah's south Beirut stronghold.</p>

<p>In August, an Israeli strike on a vehicle in the south Lebanon city of Sidon killed Hamas commander Samer al-Hajj.</p>

<p>Lebanon's official Palestinian refugee camps were created for Palestinians who were driven out or fled during the 1948 war at the time of Israel's creation.</p>

<p>By longstanding convention, the Lebanese army stays out of the camps and leaves the Palestinian factions to handle security.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/s5vcg3b8_israeli-airstrike-afp-_625x300_30_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel has repeatedly targeted Hamas officials in Lebanon since the Gaza war.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>