<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Dec 2024 20:13:00 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/missing-hannah-kobayashi-seen-crossing-into-mexico-voluntarily-lapd-says-7164325]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Missing Hannah Kobayashi Seen Crossing Into Mexico Voluntarily, LAPD Says]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/missing-hannah-kobayashi-seen-crossing-into-mexico-voluntarily-lapd-says-7164325]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Dec 2024 20:11:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[New video evidence shows Kobayashi entering Mexico on foot at the San Ysidro port of entry on November 12th.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Los Angeles police have classified Hannah Kobayashi, a 30-year-old who vanished after arriving from Maui, as a voluntary missing person.</p>

<p>New video evidence shows Kobayashi entering Mexico on foot at the San Ysidro port of entry on November 12th.</p>

<p>"As the family is aware, late yesterday after traveling to the US-Mexico border we reviewed video surveillance from US Customs and Border Protection which clearly shows Kobayashi crossing the United States border on foot into Mexico," said LAPD Chief Jim McDonnell during a press conference.</p>

<p>"She was alone with her luggage and appeared unharmed," he added.</p>

<p>Kobayashi's family reported her missing on November 11th after she failed to board her connecting flight to New York from Los Angeles.</p>

<p>Security footage captured her at various locations in LA between November 8th and 11th. &nbsp;Investigators also determined she retrieved her luggage at LAX and used public transportation to reach the border.</p>

<p>"To date the investigation has not uncovered any evidence that Kobayashi is being trafficked or is the victim of foul play. She is also not a suspect in any criminal activity," McDonnell emphasised. "We respect her right to privacy but understand her family's concern."</p>

<p>Prior to leaving Maui, Kobayashi expressed a desire to disconnect from technology, according to police.</p>

<p>Authorities interviewed individuals Kobayashi interacted with in LA, including someone who met her at LAX. Their statements corroborated with the new video evidence.</p>

<p>The LAPD is urging Kobayashi to contact her family, law enforcement, or a US embassy to confirm her well-being.</p>

<p>"We've basically done everything we can do at this point, she's left the country, and in another nation now," Chief McDonnell said. He also added that the investigation will not be carried forward to Mexico. If Kobayashi returns to the U.S., law enforcement will be notified, he said.</p>

<p>The announcement comes after the tragic passing of Kobayashi's father, Ryan, who died by suicide on November 24th while searching for his daughter. He was found dead because of multiple blunt force traumatic injuries according to the LA medical examiner.</p>

<p>A GoFundMe established by the family has raised nearly $47,000 to support search efforts and funeral expenses.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/tvn483a8_hannah-kobayashi-ig_625x300_03_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[New video evidence shows Kobayashi entering Mexico on November 12th]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/saudi-arabia-executed-over-300-people-in-2024-so-far-report-7164013]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Saudi Arabia Executed Over 300 People In 2024 So Far: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/saudi-arabia-executed-over-300-people-in-2024-so-far-report-7164013]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Dec 2024 19:35:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Saudi Arabia has executed more than 300 people this year, a record tally based on official figures, after state media said four more people were put to death on Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Saudi Arabia has executed more than 300 people this year, a record tally based on official figures, after state media said four more people were put to death on Tuesday.</p>

<p>The latest executions were carried out against three people convicted of drug smuggling and another for murder, the official Saudi Press Agency reported, citing the interior ministry.</p>

<p>It brings the total number of executions for the year so far to 303, according to an AFP tally based on state media reports.</p>

<p>The Gulf monarchy had enacted the death penalty 200 times by the end of September, according to the same tally of official data, indicating a rapid rate of executions in recent weeks.</p>

<p>Saudi Arabia executed the third highest number of prisoners in the world in 2023 after China and Iran, according to Amnesty International.</p>

<p>Previously the record number of executions in a single year in the country had stood at 196 in 2022, said the London-based human rights group, which began compiling the annual figures in 1990.</p>

<p>Saudi Arabia carried out 170 executions in 2023, according to an AFP tally of official data.</p>

<p>Taha al-Hajji, legal director of the Berlin-based European Saudi Organisation for Human Rights (ESOHR), condemned the "rocket speed" of executions in 2024, calling it "incomprehensible and inexplicable".</p>

<p><strong>'Unprecedented'</strong></p>

<p>Human rights activists had previously warned Saudi Arabia could exceed 300 executions this year, with one execution being recorded almost every day.</p>

<p>Lina al-Hathloul, head of communications for the London-based ALQST human rights organisation, said the number of executions was "unprecedented".</p>

<p>"This grim milestone shows the Saudi authorities' flagrant disregard for the right to life and contradicts their own pledges to limit use of the death penalty," she said.</p>

<p>Saudi Arabia, the world's largest exporter of oil, has faced consistent criticism over its use of the death penalty, which rights groups have condemned as excessive and in marked contrast to the kingdom's efforts to present a modern image to the world.</p>

<p>In 2022, Crown Prince Mohammed bin Salman told The Atlantic the kingdom had eliminated the death penalty with the exception extreme cases.</p>

<p>But the ESOHR's Hajji said the kingdom's de facto ruler "will address this issue and say that execution is used for the most serious crimes such as murder... but the reality and numbers do not lie and completely contradict these statements".</p>

<p>Although figures before 1990 are unclear, The Washington Post reported that 63 people were beheaded in 1980 after the previous year's seizure by Islamist militants of Islam's holiest place, the Grand Mosque in Mecca.</p>

<p>Riyadh has previously said the death penalty is necessary to "maintain public order" and sentences are only carried out if "the defendants have exhausted all levels of litigation".</p>

<p><strong>Drug-related charges</strong></p>

<p>This year's executions included 103 people convicted on charges related to drug smuggling and 45 people in cases related to terrorism, according to the AFP tally including Tuesday's announcements.</p>

<p>The kingdom ended a three-year moratorium on the execution of drug offenders at the end of 2022, putting 19 to death in a month.</p>

<p>In 2022, the United Nations said imposing the death penalty for drug crimes "contradicts international norms and standards", calling on the Saudi authorities to "halt the implementation of death sentences for drug crimes".</p>

<p>Saudi Arabia also executed 113 foreigners, another record, most of them on drug-related charges.</p>

<p>Saudi Arabia has carried out more than 1,000 executions since King Salman bin Abdulaziz came to power in 2015, according to a joint report by the London-based anti-death penalty organisation Reprieve and ESOHR published early last year.</p>

<p>Among them, 81 people were executed in a single day for terrorism convictions in March 2022, sparking widespread international condemnation.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2018-01/prison-generic-unsplash-650_650x400_61515061532.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Saudi Arabia executed the third highest number of prisoners in the world in 2023 (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-woman-who-killed-and-ate-cat-gets-one-year-in-jail-youve-embarrassed-this-nation-7163995]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Woman Jailed For Killing, Eating Cat: "You've Embarrassed This Nation"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-woman-who-killed-and-ate-cat-gets-one-year-in-jail-youve-embarrassed-this-nation-7163995]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Dec 2024 19:30:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 27-year-old woman in the US who killed and ate a cat has been sentenced to one year in jail after a furious judge slammed her for the stomach-turning act.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 27-year-old woman in the US who killed and ate a cat has been sentenced to one year in jail after a furious judge slammed her for the stomach-turning act. According to the <em>New York Post</em>, Allexis Ferrell committed the gruesome act in August outside her home in Ohio. A bodycam footage from police officers who reached her house showed the 27-year-old on all fours outdoors eating the cat as horrified neighbours looked on. "What did you do? Why did you kill the cat?" a police officer is heard asking the woman in the clip. &nbsp;</p>

<p>On Monday, Stark Country Common Pleas Judge Frank Forchione called Ferrell a national embarrassment. "You've embarrassed this county. You've embarrassed this nation. More importantly, you've embarrassed yourself," the judge said, per the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/12/02/us-news/disgusted-judge-puts-away-woman-who-ate-cat-in-stomach-turning-video-youve-embarrassed-this-nation/" rel="noindex,nofollow">outlet</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"To me, you present quite a danger to our community. This is repulsive to me. I mean, that anyone would do this to an animal. And an animal's like a child. I don't know if you understand that or not. I can't express the disappointment, shock, disgust that this crime has brought to me. I don't know what could prompt anyone to want to eat a cat," Mr Forchione continued.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The judge sentenced Ferrell to one year in jail after she pleaded guilty to a felony charge of animal cruelty. According to the <em>Post</em>, her one-year sentence will be added to a separate 18-month sentence she is facing for two previous crimes including a theft in 201 and a child endangerment case from last year.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Stark County Prosecutor Chelsea Small called the cat incident disturbing. "It's one of the most disturbing cases that I've seen as a prosecutor," she said.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/mma-trained-pastor-fends-off-axe-wielding-burglar-with-bare-hands-in-us-7160458">MMA-Trained Pastor Fends Off Axe-Wielding Burglar With Bare Hands In US</a></strong></p>

<p>Ferrell's attorney Stephen Kandel, however, said that that shocking video makes it clear that the 27-year-old "has an issue with drugs and alcohol, through her evaluation, through her past history". He added that he has arranged for his client to undergo inpatient treatment after her release.</p>

<p>Notably, Ferrell's case became a part of online presidential campaign chatter after Donald Trump and JD Vance claimed that Haitian immigrants in Springfield were eating local pets. Later, officials clarified that Ferrell is not an immigrant and her case is not tied to that claim. She was born in Ohio and graduated from Canton McKinley High School in 2015.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/dacva1d8_allexis-ferrell_625x300_12_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The judge sentenced Ferrell to one year in jail.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/100-year-old-ex-nazi-camp-guard-may-face-trial-in-germany-7163959]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[100-Year-Old Ex-Nazi Camp Guard May Face Trial In Germany]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/100-year-old-ex-nazi-camp-guard-may-face-trial-in-germany-7163959]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Dec 2024 19:28:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[German authorities are pressing for a 100-year-old former Nazi concentration camp guard to face trial almost 80 years since the end of World War II.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>German authorities are pressing for a 100-year-old former Nazi concentration camp guard to face trial almost 80 years since the end of World War II.</p>

<p>The higher regional court in Frankfurt on Tuesday said it had overturned a decision by a lower court under which the suspect had been deemed unfit to stand trial.</p>

<p>The suspect, named as Gregor Formanek by German media, was charged last year with aiding and abetting murder in 3,322 cases while working at the former Sachsenhausen concentration camp near Berlin between July 1943 and February 1945.</p>

<p>However, an expert determined in February that Formanek was not fit to stand trial due to his mental and physical condition and the court in Hanau, Hesse state, eventually decided not to open the proceedings against him.</p>

<p>The Frankfurt court on Tuesday found the expert's decision had not been based on "sufficient facts".</p>

<p>"The expert himself stated that it was not possible to interview the defendant and that the opportunity for extensive psychiatric testing was not available," it said.</p>

<p>Germany has been scrambling to bring the last surviving former Nazi war criminals to justice since a 2011 landmark ruling paved the way for several trials.</p>

<p>One former death camp guard, John Demjanjuk, was convicted on the basis that he served as part of Hitler's killing machine, even though there was no proof he had directly killed anyone.</p>

<p>Since then, several former concentration camp workers have been found guilty of being accessories to murder on the same basis.</p>

<p>However, with time running out, many cases have been abandoned in recent years after the accused died or were physically unable to stand trial.</p>

<p>More than 200,000 people, including Jews, Roma, regime opponents and gay people, were detained at the Sachsenhausen camp between 1936 and 1945.</p>

<p>Tens of thousands died there from forced labour, murder, medical experiments, hunger or disease before the camp was liberated by Soviet troops.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-09/qlg59ghg_nazi-camp_625x300_01_September_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The suspect was charged last year with aiding and abetting murder in 3,322 cases (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-korea-declares-emergency-martial-law-to-counter-threats-posed-by-north-korea-7163931]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[South Korea Declares Emergency, Cites Anti-State Element, Communist Threats]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-korea-declares-emergency-martial-law-to-counter-threats-posed-by-north-korea-7163931]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Dec 2024 19:23:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[South Korea's President Yoon Suk Yeol on Tuesday declared emergency martial law, saying the step was necessary to protect the country from "communist forces" amid parliamentary wrangling over a budget bill.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">South Korea's President Yoon Suk Yeol on Tuesday declared emergency martial law, saying the step was necessary to protect the country from "communist forces" amid parliamentary wrangling over a budget bill.</p>

<p>"To safeguard a liberal South Korea from the threats posed by North Korea's communist forces and to eliminate anti-state elements... I hereby declare emergency martial law," Yoon said in a live televised address to the nation.</p>

<p>"With no regard for the livelihoods of the people, the opposition party has paralysed governance solely for the sake of impeachments, special investigations, and shielding their leader from justice," he added.</p>

<p>The surprise move comes as Yoon's People Power Party and the main opposition Democratic Party continue to bicker over next year's budget bill. Opposition MPs last week approved a significantly downsized budget plan through a parliamentary committee.</p>

<p>"Our National Assembly has become a haven for criminals, a den of legislative dictatorship that seeks to paralyse the judicial and administrative systems and overturn our liberal democratic order," Yoon said.</p>

<p>He accused opposition lawmakers of cutting "all key budgets essential to the nation's core functions, such as combatting drug crimes and maintaining public security... turning the country into a drug haven and a state of public safety chaos."</p>

<p>Yoon went on to label the opposition, which holds a majority in the 300-member parliament, as "anti-state forces intent on overthrowing the regime" and called his decision "inevitable".</p>

<p>"I will restore the country to normalcy by getting rid of anti-state forces as soon as possible."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-11/00kij5ko_south-korea-generic_625x300_10_November_23.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Yoon Suk Yeol called his decision "inevitable" (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-high-commissioner-summoned-by-bangladesh-as-tensions-simmer-between-neighbours-7163255]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hours After Closing Visa Office In Tripura, Bangladesh Summons Indian Envoy]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-high-commissioner-summoned-by-bangladesh-as-tensions-simmer-between-neighbours-7163255]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Dec 2024 17:57:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Bangladesh today summoned India's envoy to Dhaka, hours after closing its visa and consular office in Tripura after a security incident yesterday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bangladesh today summoned India's envoy to Dhaka, hours after closing its visa and consular office in Tripura following a security incident yesterday. Tensions between both countries are high amid violence against Hindu minorities in Bangladesh. Indian High Commissioner Pranay Verma arrived at the Foreign Ministry Office in Dhaka at 4 pm local time.</p>

<p>"The Indian High Commissioner has been summoned by acting foreign secretary Reaz Hamidullah," Bangladesh's state-run news agency said. Hours earlier, a notice from the Bangladesh High Commissioner's office in Tripura stated that "Given the security situation, all visa and consular services at the Bangladesh Assistant High Commission, Agartala will remain suspended until further notice."</p>

<p>It also stated that "This comes into effect immediately".</p>

<p>Around 50 people had participated in a massive protest against the arrest of Hindu monk Chinmoy Krishna Das in Agartala yesterday.</p>

<p>During the protest, they entered the premises of the Bangladesh Assistant High Commission. This drew a sharp response from the interim government in the neighbouring country. Dhaka alleged that local police were "not found to be active in containing the situation". It said the incident had left the mission staff with a "deep sense of insecurity" and called upon New Delhi to take "immediate action".</p>

<p>The Ministry of External Affairs responded that the incident in "deeply regrettable". "Diplomatic and consular properties should not be targeted under any circumstances. Government is taking action to step up security arrangements for the Bangladesh High Commission in New Delhi and their Deputy/Assistant High Commissions in the country," a statement said.</p>

<p>The number of cops at the Bangladesh mission in Agartala has been stepped up after yesterday's incident.</p>

<p>After the meeting, the Indian High Commissioner said, "We have a wide-ranging, multi-faceted relationship, and as I have said before, you cannot reduce it to one issue or one agenda. We are working across many issues. We (India) always wants to build a positive, stable and constructive relationship. There are many interdependencies we have and we want to build on that to mutual benefit."</p>

<p>He further said that "We will keep ensuring that our cooperation benefits our two peoples. The number of positive developments to our relationship in the last few months - from trade, to power transmission, to supplying essential commodities - we have maintained a lot of positivity in our relationship."</p>

<p>"We are also willing to work with the interim government in Bangladesh. We are committed to work with them to fulfil our shared aspirations for peace, security and development."</p>

<p>India has taken up the issue of Hindus being targeted in Bangladesh and priests being arrested by the authorities in Bangladesh. There have also been multiple incidents of violence, vandalism and desecration targeting the minority Hindu community.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/hkqb8nj4_indian-envoy-pranay-verma-bangladesh-foreign-adviser-touhid-hossain_625x300_03_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Indian High Commissioner Pranay Verma with Bangladesh Foreign Affairs Adviser Touhid Hossain]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-administrations-game-changing-defence-deal-with-india-7163155]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden Administration's Game-Changing Defence Deal With India]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-administrations-game-changing-defence-deal-with-india-7163155]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Dec 2024 17:45:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[This will enhance India's submarine warfare capabilities by deterring present and future threats the Defense Security Cooperation Agency told the Congress.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Mere weeks before the completion of his Presidential term, outgoing president Joe Biden approved a crucial sale of defence equipment to India. He notified the Congress about the decision on Monday.<br />
<br />
The US has authorised the sale of MH-60R Multi-Mission Helicopter Equipment and related ones at the cost of USD 1.17 billion.</p>

<p>This will enhance India's submarine warfare capabilities by deterring present and future threats the Defense Security Cooperation Agency told the Congress. As per the contractors, the helicopter&nbsp;brings transformational anti-submarine (ASW) and anti-surface warfare (ASuW) capabilities to navies around the world. Originally designed specifically for the US Navy, the aircraft is described as "rugged, powerful, and reliable".</p>

<p>"This proposed sale will support the foreign policy and national security objectives of the United States by helping to strengthen the United States - India strategic relationship and improving the security of a major defense partner which continues to be an important force for political stability, peace, and economic progress in the Indo-Pacific and South Asia regions," the DSCA said.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">INAS 334 <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Seahawks?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Seahawks</a><br />
The first MH 60R Squadron commissioned into the <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/IndianNavy?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#IndianNavy</a>, today <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/06Mar?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#06Mar</a> 24 at INS Garuda, Kochi, <a href="https://twitter.com/IN_HQSNC?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@IN_HQSNC</a>. <a href="https://t.co/gcZ1JkWcJf">pic.twitter.com/gcZ1JkWcJf</a></p>
â€” SpokespersonNavy (@indiannavy) <a href="https://twitter.com/indiannavy/status/1765361378997723590?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 6, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>It also included advanced data transfer systems; external fuel tanks; AN/AAS 44C(V) forward looking infrared (FLIR) systems; an operator machine interface assistant; spare containers; facilities study, design, construction and support; support and test equipment; munitions; and integration and test support.</p>

<p>The principal contractor for this deal will be Lockheed Martin Rotary and Mission Systems.</p>

<p>20 US government or 25 contractor representatives will be required to travel to India temporarily for the implementation of this sale to provide technical support and management oversight.</p>

<p>On March 6th this year India's Defence took a modern turn as the Indian Navy had commissioned the newly inducted MH 60R Seahawk, a maritime variant of the Blackhawk helicopter, at INS Garuda, Kochi.</p>

<p>Here are some key features of the MH-60R Helicopters:</p>

<ol>
	<li>Advanced digital sensors include the multi-mode radar, electronic support measures system, electro-optical/infrared camera, datalinks, aircraft survivability systems, dipping sonar and sonobuoys.</li>
	<li>The fully-integrated mission system processes sensor data to build a complete situational picture of the ocean surface and subsea domain.</li>
	<li>With actionable knowledge, the crew can track, target and engage ships or submarines effectively and efficiently.</li>
	<li>Weapons include torpedoes, air-to-ground missiles and rockets, and crew served guns.</li>
</ol>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.business-standard.com/external-affairs-defence-security/news/us-okays-1-2-bn-mh-60r-helicopter-equipment-sale-to-india-why-it-matters-124120300570_1.html" rel="noindex,nofollow">Business Standard</a>, the MH-60Rs intended for the Indian Navy are equipped with specialised systems tailored to Indian requirements and have reportedly been customised, including the addition of Identification Friend-or-Foe (IFF) transponder units from Hindustan Aeronautics Limited (HAL).</p>

<p>Lockheed is also collaborating with Bharat Electronics Limited (BEL) for integrating such systems. As stated on their website, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.lockheedmartin.com/en-us/products/sikorsky-mh-60-seahawk-helicopters.html" rel="noindex,nofollow">Lockheed Martin's</a> Performance Based Logistics program for the U.S. Navy MH-60R helicopters enable 95 per cent flight readiness and availability - a rate unmatched by other maritime helicopters.</p>

<p>330 MH-60rs are operational worldwide. Including the Indian Navy, these helicopters are in operation with the U.S. Navy, Royal Danish Navy, Royal Australian Navy and Royal Saudi Naval Forces. These helicopters are additionally designed for search, rescue, medical evacuation, command, control and vertical replenishment missions.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/2eqfqgb8_mh60r-lockheed-martin_625x300_03_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The US has authorised the sale of MH-60R Multi-Mission Helicopter Equipment to India.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/how-beijing-reduced-air-pollution-by-up-to-89-in-a-decade-7163066]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How Beijing Reduced Air Pollution By Up To 89% In A Decade]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/how-beijing-reduced-air-pollution-by-up-to-89-in-a-decade-7163066]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Dec 2024 17:36:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Despite a tripling of vehicle numbers, pollution levels have decreased, making Beijing a model for other cities tackling similar problems.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>China was once nicknamed as the "Kingdom of Bicycles" because of the widespread practice of cycling in this densely populated nation. There was a time when a bicycle was one of the "three rounds" every Chinese house desired, together with a wristwatch and a sewing machine.</p>

<p>However, the country has faced many challenges since it transitioned from bicycles to automobiles and other combustion engines. This shift led to complex problems for the environment, society, and economy. Beijing became known specifically for its poor air quality and a lot of haze.</p>

<p>The fast-growing population, along with high vehicle count and economic expansion, causes this much pressure on Beijing's ecology.</p>

<p>Despite these obstacles, Beijing has improved its air quality significantly in recent years, serving as a model for other cities, particularly in South Asia, facing comparable problems.</p>

<p>As China emerged as the world's largest automobile producer and consumer, it grappled with the detrimental impacts of increased oil consumption, but now China's skies are clearer, and its air quality has drastically improved.</p>

<p>According to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.weforum.org/videos/beijingc-cut-air-pollution/#:~:text=Since%202013%2C%20PM2.,more%20than%20300%20in%202023.">World Economic Forum,</a> the Chinese capital has cut fine particle pollution by 64% and sulphur dioxide by 89% since 2013-now other cities are following its lead.</p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DC15gM5qxMk/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DC15gM5qxMk/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DC15gM5qxMk/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DC15gM5qxMk/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by World Economic Forum (@worldeconomicforum)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p>According to a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://wedocs.unep.org/bitstream/handle/20.500.11822/27645/airPolCh_EN.pdf?sequence=1&amp;isAllowed=y"><em>UN report,</em></a> Beijing has implemented a "coal-to-gas" policy since 2005 and reduced coal combustion by nearly 11 million tonnes by 2017. High-efficiency terminal treatment facilities were continuously renovated, and ultralow emission standards were enforced during this period.</p>

<p>The prevention and control of vehicle pollution have long been critical tasks in Beijing's air pollution control. Focusing on new vehicles, in-use vehicles, and fuel quality, Beijing has implemented a series of local emission standards and comprehensive control measures, as well as strengthened traffic management and economic incentives continuously.</p>

<p>Although the number of vehicles increased threefold in Beijing during the last two decades, the total pollutant emissions decreased remarkably.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/thndh6j8_beijing_625x300_03_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Beijing has successfully reduced fine particle pollution.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/spain-records-warmest-november-in-over-60-years-after-devastating-floods-7163002]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Spain Records Warmest November In Over 60 Years After Devastating Floods]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/spain-records-warmest-november-in-over-60-years-after-devastating-floods-7163002]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Dec 2024 17:26:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Spain has registered its warmest November since record-keeping began more than six decades ago, even after October ended with its worst floods in a generation, official data showed Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Spain has registered its warmest November since record-keeping began more than six decades ago, even after October ended with its worst floods in a generation, official data showed Tuesday.</p>

<p>November's average temperature was 12.4 degrees Celsius (54.3 Fahrenheit), which was 0.5 degrees Celsius higher than the previous record for the month in 1983, and 2.8C higher than the November average between 1991 and 2020, national weather agency AEMET said on social media.</p>

<p>It was the highest average temperature for a month of November since the agency began to keep records in 1961.</p>

<p>"It was also a very dry November overall," the agency said, adding that precipitation was 40 percent below normal levels "despite the abundant rains" during the first days of the month in the Mediterranean.</p>

<p>Torrential rains on October 29 caused flash floods that killed at least 230 people and swept away cars and wrecked homes and businesses, mainly in the eastern region of Valencia on the Mediterranean coast.</p>

<p>The storm was followed by several episodes of heavy rain in the region during the first week of November that hampered the clean-up operation.</p>

<p>Spain endured its second-hottest year on record in 2023 with an average temperature of 15.2C, just below the record 15.5C registered in 2022.</p>

<p>As global temperatures rise because of climate change, scientists have warned that heatwaves and other extreme weather events like droughts and wildfires will become more frequent and more intense.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/b9nk8fn_spain-generic_625x300_09_April_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Spain endured its second-hottest year on record in 2023 (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-korean-actor-park-min-jae-dies-of-cardiac-arrest-at-age-32-7162934]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[South Korean Actor Park Min-jae Dies Of Cardiac Arrest At Age 32]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-korean-actor-park-min-jae-dies-of-cardiac-arrest-at-age-32-7162934]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Dec 2024 17:18:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[South Korean actor Park Min-jae has died at the age of 32, CNA Lifestyle reported citing South Korean news agencies]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>South Korean actor Park Min-jae has died at the age of 32, <em>CNA Lifestyle</em> reported citing South Korean news agencies. Mr Min-jae died from sudden cardiac arrest on November 29, Friday, while travelling to China. Despite his brief career, the actor made significant contributions to several notable Korean dramas including<em> 'Little Women', 'Call It Love', 'The Korea-Khitan War', 'Snap And Spark',</em> and <em>'True To Love'.</em>&nbsp;</p>

<p>"A beautiful actor who loved acting and always did his best, Park Min-jae has gone to heaven," Mr Min-jae's agency Big Title said in a statement. "We will no longer be able to see his acting, but we will always remember him with pride," it continued. The agency also stated that the 32-year-old did not have major health issues before leaving for China, per the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://cnalifestyle.channelnewsasia.com/entertainment/park-min-jae-death-korean-actor-414661" rel="noindex,nofollow">outlet</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Big Title's CEO Hwang Ju Hye also expressed his grief online. "The guy who said he would conquer China and go on a month-long trip has gone on a much longer journey. It was so sudden and so shocking... The family must be feeling unimaginable sorrow... Min Jae, there's still so much we wanted to say and do together. I was grateful to have been your representative, even if only for a short time, and I'm deeply sorry. I will never forget the name, Actor Park Min Jae," he said.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chinese-man-creates-fake-arrest-warrant-out-of-boredom-offers-rs-3-51-lakh-reward-7160703">Chinese Man Creates Fake Arrest Warrant Out Of Boredom, Offers Rs 3.51 Lakh Reward</a></strong></p>

<p>Separately, Mr Min-jae's brother Park Jae-hyung took to Instagram to post details of the actor's funeral service. A wake to honour the late actor will be held in Room 9 of the Seoul National University Hospital Funeral Hall. The funeral is scheduled for December 4. As of now, the location for his burial has not been confirmed.</p>

<p>"Our beloved brother has gone to rest peacefully. We hope as many people as possible can come to see him off. We kindly ask for your understanding as we are unable to personally contact everyone," the actor's brother said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Mr Min-jae's demise also left many of his fans in disbelief. "my condolences to you all," commented one user. "Our deepest condolences to his family, friends, and fans during this difficult time. May he rest in peace," commented another.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/osp80dbo_park-minjae-_625x300_03_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Park Min-jae died from sudden cardiac arrest on November 29.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/japan-to-use-ai-detection-system-to-tackle-online-manga-anime-piracy-7162334]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Japan To Use AI Detection System To Tackle Online Manga, Anime Piracy]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/japan-to-use-ai-detection-system-to-tackle-online-manga-anime-piracy-7162334]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Dec 2024 16:07:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Japan is planning to use AI to police anime and manga pirating websites that the pop-culture powerhouse accuses of costing it billions of dollars in lost revenue every year.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Japan is planning to use AI to police anime and manga pirating websites that the pop-culture powerhouse accuses of costing it billions of dollars in lost revenue every year.</p>

<p>There are at least 1,000 websites illegally offering free downloads of Japanese content, mostly its globally-renowned manga graphic novels, a group of domestic publishers claimed earlier this year.</p>

<p>But under a 300 million yen ($2 million) pilot scheme proposed by Tokyo's cultural agency, AI will scour the web for sites pirating manga books and anime cartoons, using an image and text detection system.</p>

<p>"Copyright-holders spend a significant amount of human resources trying to manually detect pirated content online," cultural agency official Keiko Momii told AFP on Tuesday.</p>

<p>But human moderators can "barely keep up" with constantly proliferating illegal content, the agency said in a written document.</p>

<p>The initiative features in the agency's supplementary budget request for this fiscal year ending in March.</p>

<p>It is inspired by a similar project in South Korea and if successful could also be applied to other illegally shared films and music.</p>

<p>Japan, the birthplace of comic and cartoon epics such as "Dragon Ball" and game franchises from "Super Mario" to "Final Fantasy", sees the creative industries as a driver for growth on par with steel and semiconductors.</p>

<p>In its revised "Cool Japan" strategy released in June, the government said it aims to boost exports of these cultural assets to 20 trillion yen ($130 billion) by 2033.</p>

<p>Around 70 percent of pirating sites offering Japanese content operate in foreign languages including English, Chinese and Vietnamese, Japanese publishers say.</p>

<p>In 2022, Japan's gaming, anime and manga sectors raked in 4.7 trillion yen ($30 billion) from abroad -- close to microchips exports at 5.7 trillion yen, government data shows.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/bp5tb20g_phone-generic_625x300_03_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[In 2022, Japan's gaming, anime and manga sectors raked in $30 billion from abroad. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/all-you-need-to-know-about-parthenon-marbles-200-year-old-debate-over-them-7162267]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[All You Need To Know About Parthenon Marbles, 200-Year-Old Debate Over Them]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/all-you-need-to-know-about-parthenon-marbles-200-year-old-debate-over-them-7162267]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Dec 2024 15:58:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Talks in London on Tuesday between British Prime Minister Keir Starmer and Greek counterpart Kyriakos Mitsotakis have rekindled hopes of a deal for the repatriation of the Parthenon Marbles from the British Museum in 2025.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Talks in London on Tuesday between British Prime Minister Keir Starmer and Greek counterpart Kyriakos Mitsotakis have rekindled hopes of a deal for the repatriation of the Parthenon Marbles from the British Museum in 2025.</p>

<p>Here are some of the key facts concerning the 200-year-old debate:</p>

<p><strong>What are the Parthenon Marbles?</strong></p>

<p>Known in Britain as the Elgin Marbles, the 2,500-year-old sculptures for centuries adorned the Parthenon temple built at the pinnacle of ancient Athens's power at the Acropolis citadel in honour of the city's patron goddess, Athena.</p>

<p>It was partially destroyed during a Venetian bombardment in 1687, and in the early 1800s, workmen took friezes from the monument on the orders of the British ambassador to the Ottoman Empire, Scottish nobleman Thomas Bruce, known as Lord Elgin.</p>

<p>Elgin sold the marbles to the British government, which in 1817 passed them on to the British Museum where they remain one of its most prized exhibits.</p>

<p>The British Museum notes that smaller Parthenon frieze collections and fragments are also in the Louvre and museums in Copenhagen, Munich, Vienna and Wurzburg.</p>

<p><strong>Greek and British positions</strong></p>

<p>Athens has for decades demanded the return of the sculptures, a campaign revived in the 1980s by emblematic Greek actress Melina Mercouri during her stint as minister for culture.</p>

<p>The Greek authorities maintain that the sculptures were looted by Elgin.</p>

<p>But London insists that the sculptures were "legally acquired" by Elgin.</p>

<p>The British aristocrat had long maintained he had received permission from the Ottoman Sultan to remove antiquities from the Acropolis.</p>

<p>But in June, Turkey's spokesperson at a meeting of UNESCO's Intergovernmental Committee for Promoting the Return of Cultural Property to its Countries of Origin or its Restitution in Case of Illicit Appropriation (ICPRCP) said no such document, known as a firman, had been found in Ottoman archives.</p>

<p><strong>Where are we at now?</strong></p>

<p>The Guardian newspaper on Monday said that the talks on returning the sculptures to Athens were "well advanced".</p>

<p>"Sources have said that talks between the Greek foreign ministry and George Osborne, the chair of the British Museum, are moving towards 'an agreement in principle' to reunify the antiquities in Athens," the daily said.</p>

<p>Mitsotakis has made the repatriation of the Marbles a personal priority since coming to power in 2019.</p>

<p>Greek media have reported that his close confidant George Gerapetritis, now foreign minister, years ago was tasked alongside Culture Minister Lina Mendoni with seeing this through.</p>

<p>Mendoni on Tuesday told state TV ERT said there was a "positive climate" globally in favour of the repatriation of antiquities, but that the issue needed "time and appropriate maturation".</p>

<p>Three fragments of Athens's Parthenon temple, kept by the Vatican for centuries, were returned to Greece last year in what Pope Francis called a gesture of friendship.</p>

<p>Public opinion in Britain in past decades has steadily moved in favour of returning the Marbles.</p>

<p>A YouGov poll on Monday found that 53 percent of respondents said the British Museum should return the sculptures to Greece, with 24 percent opposed.</p>

<p>A 1963 British law prevents the museum from giving away treasures.</p>

<p>In October, Greek government spokesman Pavlos Marinakis said a deal could involve "some partnerships on the conservation of antiquities, the exchange of exhibits in temporary exhibitions and other joint initiatives to raise awareness of ancient Greek culture".</p>

<p>Officials have suggested that using the word "deposit" in a possible agreement could enable both sides to skirt the ownership issue entirely.</p>

<p>In 2022, when the Antonino Salinas Museum in Palermo sent to Greece a Parthenon marble fragment, the Greek culture ministry said it was "a deposit, not a loan" and would remain in the Greek capital for the next eight years.</p>

<p>Greece subsequently said it had reached a legal agreement with the Sicilian regional government to make the return permanent.</p>

<p>The Greek culture ministry in 2022 also brokered a deal to acquire 161 Bronze Age antiquities formerly in the collection of US billionaire and philanthropist Leonard Stern.</p>

<p>The agreement involved the artifacts gradually returning to Greece over the next 25 years after being displayed at New York's Metropolitan Museum of Art.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-11/63e5pmm8_parthenon-sculptures_625x300_28_November_23.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Public opinion in Britain in past decades has steadily moved in favour of returning the Marbles. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/why-trump-joked-about-making-canada-51st-us-state-during-trudeau-meet-7162232]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Why Trump Joked About Making Canada '51st US State' During Trudeau Meet]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/why-trump-joked-about-making-canada-51st-us-state-during-trudeau-meet-7162232]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Dec 2024 15:51:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President-elect Donal Trump, during his last week's meeting with Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau, reportedly joked about making Canada the 51st state of the United States to avoid high tariffs.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President-elect Donal Trump, during his last week's meeting with Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau, reportedly joked about making Canada the 51st state of the United States to avoid high tariffs. Mr Trudeau flew to Florida on Friday to have dinner with the incoming US President after the latter threatened to slap high tariffs on Canadian imports unless Ottawa prevents migrants and drugs from crossing the frontier.</p>

<p>During dinner at Mr Trump's private Mar-a-Lago estate, the Canadian Prime Minister reportedly promised the President-elect that Ottawa would toughen controls over the long undefended joint border.&nbsp;Canada sends 75 per cent of all goods and services exports to the United States and tariffs would badly hurt the economy.</p>

<p>However, new details have emerged about the meeting, which Mr Trump had earlier called "very productive."</p>

<p>Quoting two people who heard the discussion, Fox News reported that during dinner, Mr Trump told Mr Trudeau that if Ottawa cannot handle his list of demands, including controlling the border issues and paying the trade deficit, then Canada should become "a state or two" with Mr Trudeau as their governor.</p>

<p>The US President-elect told his northern counterpart that Canada has failed the US border by allowing large amounts of drugs and people across the border, "including illegal immigrants from over 70 different countries." He also raised the issue of the US trade deficit with Canada, which he reportedly estimated to be more than $100 billion.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The President-elect threatened to levy a 25 per cent tariff on all Canadian goods on day one after he takes office on January 20, 2025, if Canada did not fix both issues by then.</p>

<p>When Mr Trudeau opined that Canada cannot levy such a high tariff as it would "kill the Canadian economy completely", Trump asked, "So your country can't survive unless it's ripping off the U.S. to the tune of $100 billion?"</p>

<p>He then jokingly suggested to Trudeau that Canada become the 51st state, which caused the prime minister and others to laugh nervously, sources told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/trump-suggests-canada-become-51st-state-after-trudeau-said-tariff-would-kill-economy-sources" rel="No Follow, No Index" target="_blank">Fox News</a>.</p>

<p>At this moment, "someone at the table chimed in and advised Trump that Canada would be a very liberal state, which received even more laughter," the report said.</p>

<p>To this, Mr Trump reportedly suggested that Canada could become two states-- a conservative and a liberal one-- and told Mr Trudeau that if he cannot handle his list of demands, then "Canada should really become a state or two and Trudeau could become a governor."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/vs81taug_donald-trump-justine-trudeau-afp_625x300_03_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Justine Trudeau flew to Florida on Friday to have dinner with Donald Trump.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-justice-departments-move-against-adani-group-frivolous-trumps-return-set-to-fix-it-mark-mobius-7161860]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Department's Move Against Adani Frivolous: Global Investor Mark Mobius]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-justice-departments-move-against-adani-group-frivolous-trumps-return-set-to-fix-it-mark-mobius-7161860]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Dec 2024 15:03:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The DoJ and the US Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) recently filed an indictment and a civil complaint in the New York District Court against the top Adani Group officials.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The recent indictment by the US Department of Justice (DoJ) of Adani Group officials is nothing but a frivolous expense and once President-elect Donald Trump assumes office, such wasteful exercises involving the government offices with overseas businesses will probably fade away, ace global investor Mark Mobius told news agency IANS on Tuesday.</p>

<p>His comment came as serious questions are now being raised regarding the independence of the US DoJ and its indictment against the Adani Group, and whether it is being used for "politically motivated actions".</p>

<p>"My guess is that Donald Trump will come in and whoever he appoints to run the Justice Department will say, what are you guys doing? Sticking your nose into Indian businesses? Spending all this money on a trial which probably won't go anywhere?" Mr Mobius told news agency IANS.</p>

<p>Mr Mobius, who runs the Mobius EM Opportunities Fund for emerging markets, further stated that there is a "good chance" that the Justice Department will move away from the Adani probe and the trial.</p>

<p>"I believe that there would be another implication where the Justice Department will be reorganised in America, and will be asked to get less and less involved in overseas situations and more and more with domestic issues," said the top investor.</p>

<p>The DoJ and the US Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) recently filed an indictment and a civil complaint in the New York District Court against the top Adani Group officials. However, the Adani Group vehemently refuted the allegations, terming it 'baseless', and said it would seek legal recourse to defend itself.</p>

<p>According to Mobius, a lot of people are now beginning to realise that with Trump assuming office, "this DoJ situation in the US will probably go away".</p>

<p>On Adani Portfolio stocks performing well despite the US-related developments, he said that the situation with the hedge funds going after the Adani Group seemed to have fizzled out.</p>

<p>"A lot of investors began to look at this and said, well, Adani is under pressure but at the end of the day, their business will continue to operate well and probably will continue to do well in the future," Mr Mobius noted.</p>

<p>Adani stocks have roared back from initial hiccups, and are now surging almost daily on the Indian benchmark indices. They added more than Rs 2 lakh crore to their market cap in just a three-day rally.</p>

<p>A Bernstein report on Adani Group companies on Tuesday stated that the Group is currently in a much stronger position than it was during the Hindenburg attack in January 2023.</p>

<p>Despite facing some US-related developments, the Adani Group is on solid footing across four key areas: no share pledge, leverage, debt repayment and valuations, the report mentioned.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/d6oiigag_mark-mobius-ndtv-summit_625x300_21_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The indictment by US DoJ of Adani Group officials is nothing but a frivolous expense, Mr Mobius said.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-china-ties-have-improved-of-late-foreign-minister-s-jaishankar-briefs-parliament-7161483]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[As India-China Ties Thaw, S Jaishankar Flags 3 Key Principles For The Ages]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-china-ties-have-improved-of-late-foreign-minister-s-jaishankar-briefs-parliament-7161483]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Dec 2024 14:12:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India-China ties - "abnormal" since April 2020, when the two militaries clashed in parts of eastern Ladakh, leading to fatalities on both sides for the first time in 45 years - have improved recently, External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/topic/india-china-ties" target="_blank">India-China ties</a> - "abnormal" since April 2020, when the two militaries clashed in parts of eastern Ladakh, leading to fatalities on both sides for the first time in 45 years - have improved recently, External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar told the Lok Sabha Tuesday, explaining that "continuous diplomatic engagement since then (has) set our ties in the direction of some improvement".</p>

<p>India remains committed, Mr Jaishankar said, to engaging with China "through bilateral talks to arrive at a fair, reasonable and mutually acceptable settlement for the border issue".</p>

<p>It is, however evident, he told Parliament, that management of border areas will require further attention in light of our recent experiences. He flagged three key principles to be observed in all circumstances.</p>

<p>The first is that both sides should strictly respect and observe the LAC. The second is that neither should attempt to unilaterally alter the status quo, and the third is that agreements and understandings reached in the past must be fully abided by in their entirety.</p>

<p>"Members will recall the amassing of a large number of troops by China along the LAC (Line of Actual Control) in eastern Ladakh in April-May 2020 resulted in face-offs with our forces at a number of points. The situation also led to disruption of patrolling activities," the EAM began his remarks.</p>

<p>"It is to the credit of our armed forces that despite logistical challenges, and the then prevailing Covid situation, they were able to counter-deploy rapidly and effectively," he said.</p>

<p>"While a determined counter-deployment of adequate capability was the immediate response, there was also the imperative of a diplomatic effort to defuse tensions and restore peace and tranquility."</p>

<p>That diplomatic effort, which included nearly two dozen rounds of talks between military commanders, the most recent on August 29, led to the October agreement, under which Indian and Chinese troops returned to positions, and resumed patrolling routes, prior to the April 2020 face-off.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/we-will-be-able-to-go-back-to-2020-patrolling-s-jaishankar-on-lac-border-row-6839082" target="_blank">"Back To 2020 Patrolling": S Jaishankar To NDTV On India-China Pact</a></p>

<p>Last week the government said that deal had been implemented as agreed.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/army-successfully-completes-patrolling-to-key-point-in-ladakhs-depsang-6944072" target="_blank">Army "Successfully" Completes Patrolling To Key Point In Depsang</a></p>

<p>The agreement - announced hours before Prime Minister Narendra Modi's visit to Russia for a BRICS Summit at which China's Xi Jinping would also be present - was seen as a roadmap to restoration of peace and tranquility along the LAC, a status quo the Indian government has often spoken about as the first, and a necessary, step towards any normalisation of relations between the two countries.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-modi-xi-jinping-bilateral-summit-brics-summit-russia-india-china-patrolling-agreement-pm-modi-xi-welcome-complete-disengagement-between-soldiers-al-6857182" target="_blank">PM Modi, Xi Welcome "Complete Disengagement" Along LAC</a></p>

<p>On that topic, Mr Jaishankar said the immediate priority - of disengagement of troops from friction points in eastern Ladakh, specifically in the Depsang and Demchok areas, had been "fully achieved".</p>

<p>The next priority is to consider de-escalation, which will address amassing of troops along the Line of Actual Control, which serves as the de facto international border, the External Affairs Minister said.</p>

<p>Mr Jaishankar's remarks came two weeks after Defence Minister Rajnath Singh met his Chinese counterpart,&nbsp;Dong Jun, for a first ministerial-level meet since the disengagement in eastern Ladakh.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-china-defence-ministers-to-meet-in-laos-rajnath-singh-dong-jun-meeting-post-disengagement-in-ladakh-7025414" target="_blank">India, China Defence Ministers' 1st High-Level Talks Post Disengagement</a></p>

<p>Mr Singh and Mr Dong, a former naval Commander appointed in December last year, met on the sidelines of a two-day, 10-nation ASEAN summit in Laos that began November 20.</p>

<p>Disengagement and patrolling in Depsang and Demchok follows similar positive actions on the north and south banks of the Pangong Lake in 2021, and in the contentious Gogra-Hot Springs area in September a year later. In each case the two sides withdrew to pre-April 2020 positions.</p>

<p><em>NDTV is now available on WhatsApp channels. <a href="https://www.whatsapp.com/channel/0029Va4lixw7z4kcvZI9JM12">Click on the link</a> to get all the latest updates from NDTV on your chat. </em></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/2e3a69s8_s-jaishankar-in-parliament_650x400_03_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Foreign Minister S Jaishankar spoke on the India-China border situation in the Lok Sabha.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trumps-fbi-pick-kash-patel-plans-to-reshape-bureau-release-epstein-diddy-lists-7161417]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What Kash Patel, Trump's Pick As FBI Chief, Plans To Do After Taking Charge]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trumps-fbi-pick-kash-patel-plans-to-reshape-bureau-release-epstein-diddy-lists-7161417]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Dec 2024 14:06:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kash Pate, President-elect Donald Trumps nominee to lead the FBI, has pledged to make the so-called "Diddy list" and the infamous Epstein files public after taking office.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kash Patel, President-elect Donald Trump's nominee to lead the FBI, has pledged to make the so-called â€œDiddy listâ€ and the infamous Epstein files public after taking office. Speaking on a podcast, the Indian American loyalist of Mr Trump, who shares the president-elect's scepticism of the FBI and intelligence community, said he's committed to restoring trust in federal agencies by exposing decades of alleged corruption.</p>

<p>During the conversation on "Benny Johnson" podcast, Mr Patel said "trust in our agencies and departments" can only be restored by "giving the American people the truth."</p>

<p>â€œAnd that's what they feared about Donald Trump. He's gonna come in there and maybe give them the Epstein list, and maybe give them the P. Diddy list, you know, maybe he's gonna come up there and do all these things, and they're terrified,â€ he said</p>

<p>The term "Diddy list" refers to the names of public figures accused of being associated with the rapper Diddy's alleged "freak-off" parties, where sexual misconduct and grooming allegedly took place.</p>

<p>By picking Kash Patel to lead the United State's premier federal law enforcement agency, the incoming US President signalled his intention to overhaul the intelligence agency he has long criticized.</p>

<p>However, Mr Patel is expected to face an uphill battle to get a Senate confirmation to take over his appointed role, not only for&nbsp;professed fealty to Mr Trump but also his beliefs â€” revealed over the last year in interviews and his own book.</p>

<p>Time and again, the MAGA (Make America Great Again) loyalist has said that the century-old Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) should be radically overhauled. Kash Patel has proposed shutting down the FBI's Washington headquarters at J Edgar Hoover Building and dispersing its employees across the country.&nbsp;</p>

<p>â€œI'd shut down the FBI Hoover Building on day one and reopen it the next day as a museum of the deep state,'" Patel said in a September interview on the â€œShawn Kelly Show."&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Then, I'd take the 7,000 employees that work in that building and send them across America to chase down criminals. Go be cops. You're cops â€” go be cops," he added.</p>

<p>The first FBI employees moved into the current Pennsylvania Avenue headquarters 50 years ago, according to a report by the Associated Press (AP). Since then, the building reportedly housed scores of supervisors and leaders who make decisions affecting offices around the country and overseas.</p>

<p>Mr Patel's plan to completely shut the building would require legal, logistical and bureaucratic hurdles and the plan may reflect more of a rhetorical flourish than a practical ambition, the AP report said.</p>

<p>In a book last year titled, â€œGovernment Gangsters: The Deep State, the Truth and the Battle for Our Democracy,â€ he proposed a more modest reform of having the headquarters moved out of Washington â€œto prevent institutional capture and curb FBI leadership from engaging in political gamesmanship.â€</p>

<p>As it happens, the long-term fate of the iconic building remains in flux regardless of the leadership transition. The General Services Administration reportedly selected last year Greenbelt in Maryland as the site for a new headquarters. However, current FBI Director Christopher Wray has raised concerns about a potential conflict of interest in the site selection process.</p>

<p>Mr Patel has also been a fierce critic of the FBI's use of its surveillance authorities under the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act, and in his â€œShawn Kelly Showâ€ interview, he called for â€œmajor, major reform. Tons."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ej9qilhk_kash-patel-reuters_625x300_13_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kash Patel has also been a fierce critic of the FBI's use of its surveillance authorities.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/after-bill-clinton-donald-trump-biden-in-list-of-us-presidents-pardoning-relatives-7161363]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[After Bill Clinton, Trump, Biden In List Of US Presidents Pardoning Relatives]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/after-bill-clinton-donald-trump-biden-in-list-of-us-presidents-pardoning-relatives-7161363]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Dec 2024 13:59:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US presidents traditionally dole out pardons as they leave office but Joe Biden's "full and unconditional" pardon of his son Hunter is a rare instance involving a family member.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US presidents traditionally dole out pardons as they leave office but Joe Biden's "full and unconditional" pardon of his son Hunter is a rare instance involving a family member.</p>

<p>Bill Clinton granted a pardon to his half-brother Roger, who had served time in prison on 1985 drug charges, on January 20, 2001, his last day in office.</p>

<p>And Donald Trump pardoned Charles Kushner, a fellow real estate magnate whose son Jared is married to Trump's daughter Ivanka, at the end of his first term in the White House.</p>

<p>Trump, now president-elect, nominated Kushner, 70, who pleaded guilty in 2004 to tax evasion, witness tampering and making illegal campaign contributions, on Saturday to be the next US ambassador to France.</p>

<p>Kushner, who served 14 months in prison, admitted hiring a prostitute to seduce his brother-in-law, who was cooperating in the campaign finance inquiry, and sending a videotape of the encounter to his own sister.</p>

<p>Hunter Biden, who has struggled with alcohol and drug addiction, is the first child of a sitting president to receive a pardon.</p>

<p>His father, who leaves office on January 20, had repeatedly said he would not pardon his son -- but in announcing the move on Sunday he claimed that Hunter had been "selectively, and unfairly, prosecuted."</p>

<p>"I believe in the justice system, but as I have wrestled with this, I also believe raw politics has infected this process and it led to a miscarriage of justice," Biden said.</p>

<p>"No reasonable person who looks at the facts of Hunter's cases can reach any other conclusion than Hunter was singled out only because he is my son -- and that is wrong," the president said.</p>

<p>Hunter Biden pleaded guilty to tax evasion in September and was facing up to 17 years in prison. He risked 25 years in prison for the felony gun charge but was not expected to receive such stiff sentences in either case.</p>

<p>Presidents have also used their constitutionally-mandated pardon powers over the years on close friends and political allies.</p>

<p>One of the most controversial pardons in recent years was that of former president Richard Nixon by his successor in the White House, Gerald Ford.</p>

<p>Ford granted a "full and unconditional" pardon to Nixon, who was facing potential prosecution over the Watergate scandal, on September 8, 1974.</p>

<p>Trump is the first former president convicted of a crime -- falsifying business records to cover up a hush money payment to a porn star -- but he will not be able to pardon himself because the case involved state and not federal charges.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/rlndbrjo_joe-biden-accompanied-by-his-son-hunter-biden_625x300_02_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Presidents have also used their constitutionally-mandated pardon powers over the years.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/at-cop16-saudi-arabia-bets-on-climate-tech-to-make-deserts-bloom-7161321]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[At COP16, Saudi Arabia Bets On Climate Tech To Make Deserts Bloom]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/at-cop16-saudi-arabia-bets-on-climate-tech-to-make-deserts-bloom-7161321]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Dec 2024 13:53:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Saudi Arabia is investing in green innovation to transform its deserts, but accusations of greenwashing highlight the challenge of turning ambitious projects into climate solutions.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Saudi Arabia is investing in green innovation to transform its deserts, but accusations of greenwashing highlight the challenge of turning ambitious projects into climate solutions.</p>

<p>This week, Riyadh is hosting the United Nations COP16 conference on drought and desertification -- topics close to home for the Gulf kingdom, whose officials have said they aim to restore 40 million hectares of degraded land.</p>

<p>But while the country is a major investor in climate tech, it has not abandoned its longstanding defence of oil, and critics say its gestures toward environmental friendliness offer only limited benefits.</p>

<p>Saudi Arabia accounts for nearly 75 percent of Middle East investment in climate technology start-ups worldwide, according to a 2023 report by auditor PwC.</p>

<p>But its investment in green tech skews towards energy, with $363 million ploughed into climate-friendly energy solutions -- nearly 10 times as much as was invested in innovations related to food, agriculture and land-use, PwC said.</p>

<p>On a vast campus in the desert north of Jeddah, one project that could prove useful in the parched kingdom is using microorganisms to reduce the energy cost of treating wastewater.</p>

<p>The treatment facility seeks to "purify and treat wastewater in an energy-neutral or even positive way", said Peiying Hong, the environmental science and engineering academic who oversees the facility at the King Abdullah University of Science and Technology.</p>

<p>The process, she said, relies on microorganisms that convert carbon into methane gas, which is collected and used to produce energy for the facility.</p>

<p>The filtered water from the process "can be used to grow micro algae to produce feed for livestock, or to irrigate plants and trees to combat desertification", she added.</p>

<h3><strong>Sand into soil</strong></h3>

<p>Recycled water could prove valuable to the largely desert country with extremely limited water resources.</p>

<p>As part of its so-called Middle East Green Initiative, Saudi Arabia aims to eventually plant 10 billion trees, according to the project's website, and rehabilitate more than 74 million hectares of land.&nbsp;</p>

<p>To achieve these ambitions, efficient management of water and soil resources is essential.</p>

<p>Himanshu Mishra, also an environmental science and engineering expert at KAUST, said his team have developed a product they believe is capable of transforming the kingdom's desert into fertile land.</p>

<p>"We are transforming sand into soil," the professor said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The carbon-enriched compost made from chicken manure -- an abundant and underused resource in Saudi Arabia -- is developed a step further than normal fertiliser.</p>

<p>Mishra explained his innovation "acts like a sponge to retain these nutrients and water, while promoting microbial biodiversity", which plants need to thrive.</p>

<p>The professor's experimental farm has been left teeming with vegetation as a result.</p>

<p>Mishra explained that by selling its carbonated topsoil, made in the kingdom from local waste, Saudi Arabia could become "an exporter of both the product and its technology".</p>

<h3><strong>Greenwashing?</strong></h3>

<p>Despite their potential, deploying such systems on a national or regional level requires financial support and political will.</p>

<p>"We really need venture funding and investment to demonstrate their effectiveness on a large scale," Hong said.</p>

<p>But John Robinson, an investor and partner at Mazarine Ventures, says raising funds for these types of start-ups remains "extremely hard", though some manage to attract private investors.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Saudi Arabia's ambitions have not taken away from its fierce defence of oil, as it continues to be the world's biggest exporter of crude.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In addition to combating desertification, the kingdom is focusing on technologies such as carbon capture and hydrogen production as part of what it calls a "circular carbon economy".</p>

<p>But critics have labelled these efforts greenwashing, saying they aim to allow continued investment in fossil fuels.</p>

<p>In May 2024, the European Centre for Democracy and Human Rights (ECDHR) said the Saudi Green Initiative "conceals the country's ongoing reliance on fossil fuels and contempt for environmental justice behind lofty sustainability promises".</p>

<p>Riyadh justifies the policy as necessary for its energy security.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/pk9n5i9g_cop16_625x300_03_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Saudi Arabia accounts for nearly 75 percent of Middle East investment in climate technology.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pat-gelsinger-after-stepping-down-as-intel-ceo-honour-of-my-lifetime-7160918]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Honour Of My Lifetime": Pat Gelsinger After Stepping Down As Intel CEO]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pat-gelsinger-after-stepping-down-as-intel-ceo-honour-of-my-lifetime-7160918]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Dec 2024 13:30:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Pat Gelsinger has stepped down as the CEO of Intel Corporation effective December 1, just under four years after taking the top job.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pat Gelsinger has stepped down as the CEO of Intel Corporation effective December 1, just under four years after taking the top job. Mr Gelsinger, 63, was reportedly given the option to voluntarily retire or be removed by the company's board. After careful consideration, he chose to retire.</p>

<p>In a post on LinkedIn, Mr Gelsinger wrote, â€œLeading Intel Corporation has been the honour of my lifetime. I am forever grateful for the many colleagues around the world who I have worked with as part of the Intel family and can look back with pride at all that we have accomplished together. Thank you all!â€<br />
<iframe allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="286" src="https://www.linkedin.com/embed/feed/update/urn:li:share:7269395411658792960" title="Embedded post" width="504"></iframe><br />
Pat Gelsinger described his departure from Intel as â€œbittersweetâ€, acknowledging the company had been central to his career for much of his life. â€œThis company has been my life for the bulk of my working career,â€ Mr Gelsinger said in a <a href="https://www.intc.com/news-events/press-releases/detail/1719/intel-announces-retirement-of-ceo-pat-gelsingerÂ " rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">company statement</a>. â€œI can look back with pride at all that we have accomplished together.â€<br />
<br />
He talked about the tough yet essential decisions made to position Intel for the evolving market and expressed deep gratitude for his â€œcolleagues around the worldâ€, recognising their collective efforts as part of the Intel family.<br />
<br />
Intel's board of directors named two senior leaders, David Zinsner and Michelle Johnston Holthaus, as interim co-CEOs, while a search for a permanent replacement is underway. Mr Zinsner, Intel's executive vice president and CFO, and Holthaus, appointed CEO of Intel Products, will lead the company through this transitional period. Frank Yeary, Intel's independent board chair, will step in as interim executive chair.<br />
<br />
Mr Yeary praised Mr Gelsinger for his dedication to Intel. â€œPat helped launch and revitalise process manufacturing by investing in state-of-the-art semiconductor manufacturing while working tirelessly to drive innovation throughout the company,â€ Mr Yeary said.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
Pat Gelsinger's legacy at Intel spans several decades. He started his career at the company in 1979 and became Intel's first Chief Technology Officer before eventually returning to the company as CEO in 2021 during a critical time.<br />
<br />
He was forced out after the board lost confidence in his strategy to revitalise the company, <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-12-02/intel-ceo-pat-gelsinger-retires-amid-chipmaker-s-turnaround-planÂ " rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">Bloomberg</a> reported. The clash reached its peak when Mr Gelsinger met with the board to discuss Intel's progress in regaining market share and competing with Nvidia. He was given the choice to retire or be removed.<br />
<br />
His resignation comes as the company navigates a rapidly changing semiconductor market. Throughout his tenure, he was known for his focus on innovation and his ability to rally the company around urgent strategic priorities. His leadership was seen as crucial to Intel's ongoing efforts to regain its competitive edge in the global chipmaking industry.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/7adetsbo_pat-gelsinger-linkedin_625x300_03_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Pat Gelsinger described his departure from Intel as "bittersweet".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/new-clues-point-to-possible-alien-life-beneath-mars-surface-7161139]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[New Clues Point To Possible Alien Life Beneath Mars' Surface]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/new-clues-point-to-possible-alien-life-beneath-mars-surface-7161139]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Dec 2024 13:26:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[By analyzing data from various Mars missions, the team has identified a subsurface zone, between 4.3 and 8.8 kilometres deep, where conditions could support microbial activity.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Could Mars, once a warm and wet world, still harbour life? A team of scientists led by Andrea Butturini believes so. Their research suggests that the ancient Martian plain of Acidalia Planitia may be a potential haven for microbial life, particularly methanogens, lurking deep beneath the surface, according to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.newscientist.com/article/2458263-life-on-mars-could-be-surviving-in-an-area-deep-underground/" rel="noindex,nofollow"><em>New Scientist</em></a>.</p>

<p>By analyzing data from various Mars missions, the team has identified a subsurface zone, between 4.3 and 8.8 kilometres deep, where conditions could support microbial activity. This subsurface environment, shielded from harsh surface conditions, may retain remnants of ancient water and geothermal heat, crucial elements for life. While the idea of Martian microbes may seem far-fetched, this discovery sparks hope for the possibility of extraterrestrial life and opens new avenues for future exploration.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Taking data from the multitude of orbiters and rovers that have visited Mars, the researchers found that Acidalia Planitia - a 3000-kilometre-wide plain in the northern hemisphere of Mars - seems to have the right conditions for methanogens, methane-producing bacteria, an estimated 4.3 to 8.8 kilometres beneath the surface.</p>

<p>"[It is] a promising target area for future missions in the search for extant life in Mars' subsurface," the researchers write.</p>

<p>To uncover evidence of life on Mars, researchers would need to drill miles beneath its surface- an endeavour requiring advanced crewed missions and technologies that are still years away from feasibility.</p>

<p>This study, however, marks a significant step forward in the search for extraterrestrial life. By pinpointing a location beneath the Martian surface where microbial life might exist, it sets the stage for future investigations that could resolve the long-standing debate over the presence of methane in Mars' atmosphere.</p>

<p>The researchers suggest that methanogens-methane-producing bacteria could thrive under Mars' Acidalia Planitia region. These extremophiles are known to endure harsh environments on Earth, such as high temperatures, radiation, and ultra-salty conditions. They are anaerobic, requiring neither oxygen nor sunlight, and can survive on minimal nutrients. On Earth, methanogens are found in swamps, marshes, decaying organic matter, and even the guts of herbivores.</p>

<p>While the European Space Agency's Rosalind Franklin rover, set to launch in 2028, will include a drill capable of penetrating seven feet into the Martian surface, this depth is insufficient to reach the potentially habitable zone identified by the researchers. The surface of Mars is far too cold and low-pressure for even extremophiles to survive, but below the surface, conditions improve.</p>

<p>The radioactive decay of elements like thorium generates heat and chemical energy, and water remnants from ancient oceans are buried underground. Together, these factors could create a habitable environment for bacteria, likely at depths of up to five miles.</p>

<p>Biogeochemist Butturini of the University of Barcelona and his team used Mars orbiter data to locate regions with high thorium concentrations that could sustain microbial life. They matched this with subsurface ice maps created by missions like China's Zhurong rover. Their analysis identified the southern Acidalia Planitia as the most promising target, a mid-latitude region with signs of groundwater activity and clay and carbonate deposits.</p>

<p>At this depth, temperatures are more favourable, ranging between 32 to 50 Degrees F, potentially allowing for liquid water mixed with Martian soil-an essential ingredient for bacterial life.</p>

<p>Although the findings, currently available on the preprint server arXiv, have yet to undergo peer review, they are drawing attention for providing a specific site to focus the search for Martian life.</p>

<p>"The subsurface of the southern Acidalia Planitia is a putative target region for hosting cold-adapted Methanosarcinaceae-like and/or Methanomicrobiaceae-like methanogens," the study notes. It highlights the region's abundance of radiogenic heat-producing elements and the likelihood of subsurface water.</p>

<p>If proven correct, this research could not only confirm the existence of alien life on Mars but also provide indirect evidence that methane in Mars' atmosphere may have a biological origin.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/jmtbn33g_mars_625x300_12_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[This study marks a significant step forward in the search for extraterrestrial life]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>