<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Sat, 16 Nov 2024 04:22:10 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musks-spacex-preparing-to-launch-tender-offer-in-december-report-7029850]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk's SpaceX Preparing To Launch Tender Offer In December: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musks-spacex-preparing-to-launch-tender-offer-in-december-report-7029850]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 16 Nov 2024 02:30:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Elon Musk's SpaceX is preparing to launch a tender offer in December to sell existing shares at a price of $135 per share, the Financial Times reported on Friday, citing people with knowledge of the discussions.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Elon Musk's SpaceX is preparing to launch a tender offer in December to sell existing shares at a price of $135 per share, the Financial Times reported on Friday, citing people with knowledge of the discussions.</p>

<p>The tender offer would value SpaceX at more than $250 billion, according to the report.</p>

<p>SpaceX did not immediately respond to a Reuters request for comment.</p>

<p>Elon Musk, the world's richest person, is expected to wield significant influence in Washington to secure favorable government treatment for his companies, including SpaceX, after Donald Trump's victory for a second presidency.</p>

<p>Elon Musk's dream of transporting humans to Mars could also become a bigger national priority under Donald Trump, Reuters reported earlier this month.</p>

<p>NASA's Artemis program, which aims to use SpaceX's Starship rocket to put humans on the moon as a proving ground for later Mars missions, is expected to focus more on the Red Planet under Donald Trump and target uncrewed missions there this decade.</p>

<p>Under Donald Trump, SpaceX is also expected to push for even softer regulations on worker safety and safety of participants in private space flights in orbit.</p>

<p>A Reuters investigation last year documented at least 600 worker injuries at SpaceX facilities across the U.S., and how SpaceX disregarded safety regulations and standard practices.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-03/iic38r2g_spacex-generic_625x300_16_March_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The tender offer would value SpaceX at more than $250 billion: Report (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/as-58-year-old-mike-tyson-gets-back-in-ring-to-fight-youtuber-jake-paul-a-look-at-whats-at-stake-7029408]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[As 58-Year-Old Mike Tyson Gets Back In Ring, A Look At What's At Stake]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/as-58-year-old-mike-tyson-gets-back-in-ring-to-fight-youtuber-jake-paul-a-look-at-whats-at-stake-7029408]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 16 Nov 2024 02:20:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Mike Tyson, who terrorised the heavyweight division during an imperious reign in the late 1980s, will face 27-year-old YouTuber-turned-boxer Jake Paul in an officially sanctioned fight at AT&T Stadium, the home of the Dallas Cowboys, in Texas, US.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Nearly two decades after hanging his gloves, 58-year-old Mike Tyson is set to climb back into the ring on Friday for a Netflix-backed bout. Tyson, who terrorised the heavyweight division during an imperious reign in the late 1980s, will face 27-year-old YouTuber-turned-boxer Jake Paul in an officially sanctioned fight at AT&amp;T Stadium, the home of the Dallas Cowboys, in Texas, US.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Tyson, who became the youngest heavyweight champion in history at the age of 20 years and four months in 1986, retired in 2005 after losing to Kevin McBride. At the time, he said he didn't have anything left to give the sport. The boxing legend last fought against Roy Jones Jr. in an exhibition match, with no fans during the pandemic in 2020.</p>

<p>Now, by taking on a man not even half his age, the former world heavyweight champion will become one of the oldest boxers to compete in a sanctioned professional fight. The bout, which according to experts is not an exhibition match, is been described by experts as an "indictment on boxing" &nbsp;and a "competitive fight".</p>

<h2>Tyson Back In The Ring</h2>

<p>So, why is Mike Tyson lacing up the gloves once more after 19 years? Simple answer - the money. As per reports, Mike Tyson is being paid USD 20 million just for this one match. Jake Paul is reportedly getting double of that - USD 40 million.</p>

<p>A showdown is also seen as Netflix's latest one-two punch, as the media giant hopes to cash in on sports' sprint to streaming. The streaming powerhouse will broadcast the event live to a global subscriber list of 280 million. Moreover, a crowd of about 70,000 is expected at the stadium to witness Tyson once again in the ring, according to a BBC report.&nbsp;</p>

<p>For the streaming giant, Tyson vs. Paul is their biggest live sports event to date and an opportunity to ensure that it can handle audience demand with the NFL and WWE on the horizon.</p>

<h3>Concerns Over Health</h3>

<p>The Netflix-backed bout has also drawn widespread condemnation across the boxing world. Though the rules of the game have been altered, experts have weighed in on how Mike Tyson's age might play a factor in the highly anticipated fight. The bout was initially due to take place in July but was postponed in May after Tyson required medical treatment on a flight from Miami to Los Angeles after vomiting blood due to a bleeding ulcer.</p>

<p>Raising the issue, Stephen Hughes, a senior lecturer of medicine at Anglia Riskin University in England, cited Tyson's age and past alcohol abuse as risk factors. In an article published by "The Conversation", Hughes that a head trauma during a fight could put the boxer at greater risk of suffering a subdural hematoma, which is potentially fatal.</p>

<p>Prominent British fight promoter Eddie Hearn also flagged risk to Tyson's health during the fight and said, "Twenty years ago, Mike Tyson retired from boxing, and was shot to pieces, right? I mean, completely shot."</p>

<p>"If anyone thinks that Mike Tyson should be in a ring at this age, you either have absolutely no emotional feelings toward the man, or you're an idiot. It shouldn't be happening," he added.</p>

<p>Hearn's rival promoter Frank Warren echoed those sentiments and said, "Mike Tyson is 58 years of age and he shouldn't be fighting."</p>

<p>"Anyone with an ounce of brains knows that it is ridiculous. You can be on a motorway stuck in a traffic jam and you get to the end of it and all it is is people who have stopped to look at a crash -- and that's what this is," he added.</p>

<h3>Mike Tyson's Reply</h3>

<p>Mike Tyson, who US reports say is being paid around $20 million for Friday's contest, has brushed off the concerns for his well-being, insisting that critics from the boxing world are motivated by jealousy.</p>

<p>"I'm beautiful, that's all I can say," he said earlier this year. "The people who said that wish they were up here. No-one else can do this."</p>

<p>At an open workout in Texas this week, Tyson declared that a gruelling training camp had left him with the conviction "that I'm tougher than I believed I was."</p>

<p>"When I agreed to this fight and started training, I thought 'What was I thinking of?' But I've finished the process. The fight is the party. All the hard work is done."<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/03t59kqo_mike-tyson-jake-paul-x_625x300_15_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mike Tyson, 58, will take on YouTuber-turned-boxer Jake Paul at the AT&T Stadium.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/germanys-olaf-scholz-urges-ukraine-talks-in-first-call-with-vladimir-putin-since-2022-7029411]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Germany's Olaf Scholz Urges Ukraine Talks In 1st Call With Putin Since 2022]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/germanys-olaf-scholz-urges-ukraine-talks-in-first-call-with-vladimir-putin-since-2022-7029411]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 16 Nov 2024 00:23:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[German Chancellor Olaf Scholz on Friday urged Russian President Vladimir Putin to engage in peace talks with Ukraine, in the first call between the leaders in almost two years.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>German Chancellor Olaf Scholz on Friday urged Russian President Vladimir Putin to engage in peace talks with Ukraine, in the first call between the leaders in almost two years.</p>

<p>In the call, Scholz "condemned Russia's war of aggression against Ukraine and called on President Putin to end it and withdraw troops", the chancellor's spokesman Steffen Hebestreit said.</p>

<p>The German leader "urged Russia to show willingness to negotiate with Ukraine with the aim of achieving a just and lasting peace", Hebestreit added in a statement.</p>

<p>Scholz also stressed "Germany's unwavering determination to support Ukraine in its fight against Russian aggression for as long as necessary".</p>

<p>The call comes at a crucial juncture in the war. Ukrainian troops are coming under pressure and the election of Donald Trump in the United States has cast doubt over Washington's continued support for Kyiv.</p>

<p>The Kremlin said Putin had a "detailed and frank exchange of views over the situation in Ukraine" with Scholz, with the call initiated by the German side.</p>

<p>Putin told Scholz that any agreement to end the war in Ukraine "should take into account the security interests of the Russian Federation" the Kremlin added.</p>

<p>An accord should "proceed from the new territorial realities and, most importantly, address the root causes of the conflict".</p>

<p><strong>Ukraine contact</strong></p>

<p>Before picking up the phone to Putin, Scholz spoke with Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky, Scholz's spokesman said.</p>

<p>The German and Ukrainian leaders spoke "beforehand and will do so again after the conversation with the Russian president", the spokesman said.</p>

<p>The call between Scholz and Putin was the first time the two have been in contact since December 2022.</p>

<p>During the hour-long call, Scholz "particularly condemned the Russian air strikes against civilian infrastructure in Ukraine", said a German government source.</p>

<p>"He made it clear that sending North Korean soldiers to Russia for combat missions against Ukraine would lead to a serious escalation and expansion of the conflict," the source added.</p>

<p>Berlin would keep NATO and European Union allies informed over the talks, while the German and Russian leaders had "agreed to remain in contact".</p>

<p>Scholz's December 2022 call with Putin was the last known phone call between the Kremlin chief and the leader of a major Western country.</p>

<p>Putin has spoken to few NATO and Western leaders since 2022, when the EU and the US imposed massive sanctions on Russia for launching its shock Ukraine offensive.</p>

<p>Within the NATO bloc, Putin maintains contact with Hungarian Prime Minister Viktor Orban -- who is critical of Western policy on Russia -- and with Turkish President Recep Tayyip Erdogan.</p>

<p><strong>Trump factor</strong></p>

<p>Ukraine is bracing for the most difficult winter so far in the war, which began in February 2022 when Russia launched its full-scale invasion.</p>

<p>Much of Ukraine's energy infrastructure has been destroyed by Russian bombardments and Kyiv's troops are increasingly on the back foot.</p>

<p>Germany has been one of Ukraine's biggest military supporters, second only to the United States in the aid it has sent to Kyiv.</p>

<p>But the election of Trump, who criticised aid to Ukraine on the campaign trail, has called into question Washington's continued support.</p>

<p>Trump said on the campaign trail that he could end the fighting within hours and has indicated he would talk directly with Putin.</p>

<p>The Kremlin has denied reports that Putin and the president-elect of the United States recently discussed the Ukraine conflict by phone.</p>

<p>Scholz, who did speak with Trump following his election win, told the German daily Sueddeutsche Zeitung on Friday that the incoming US leader had a "more nuanced" position on the conflict than was commonly thought.</p>

<p>Following the Putin-Scholz call, Polish Prime Minister Donald Tusk said he had been updated by the German leader on the discussion.</p>

<p>Tusk was "satisfied" that Scholz had "reiterated the Polish position: 'Nothing about Ukraine without Ukraine'," he said on social media platform X.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/qkhj7ntg_olaf-scholz_625x300_05_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[German Chancellor Olaf Scholz "condemned Russia's war of aggression against Ukraine".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/lawsuit-claiming-elon-musk-rigged-dogecoin-ends-7029340]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Lawsuit Claiming Elon Musk Rigged Dogecoin Ends]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/lawsuit-claiming-elon-musk-rigged-dogecoin-ends-7029340]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 16 Nov 2024 00:05:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A lawsuit accusing Musk of rigging dogecoin is ending. Investors in the cryptocurrency who said theElon Musk and his electric car company Tesla committed fraud and insider trading are withdrawing their appeal from an Aug. 29 dismissal of their case.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A lawsuit accusing Elon Musk of rigging dogecoin is ending.</p>

<p>Investors in the cryptocurrency who said the world's richest person and his electric car company Tesla committed fraud and insider trading are withdrawing their appeal from an Aug. 29 dismissal of their case.</p>

<p>They are also withdrawing a bid to sanction Musk's lawyers for allegedly interfering with the appeal, including by demanding payment of their hefty legal fees.</p>

<p>Musk and Tesla, meanwhile, withdrew their motion to sanction the investors' lawyer for allegedly pursuing a "frivolous" case with ever-changing legal theories to "extort a quick handout."</p>

<p>A stipulation dismissing the appeal and both sides' motions was filed on Thursday night in federal court in Manhattan. It requires approval by US District Judge Alvin Hellerstein.</p>

<p>Lawyers for the investors and Musk did not immediately respond on Friday to requests for comment.</p>

<p>Investors accused Musk of using Twitter posts, an appearance on NBC's "Saturday Night Live" and other stunts to trade dogecoin at their expense, including by timing trades to Musk's public statements and activities.</p>

<p>In the Aug. 29 dismissal, Hellerstein said reasonable investors could not prove securities fraud from relying on Musk's tweets, including that dogecoin was the future currency of Earth and could be flown to the moon by his company SpaceX.</p>

<p>The judge also said he did not understand the investors' related market manipulation and insider trading claims.</p>

<p>Investors originally sought $258 billion, and amended their complaint four times in two years.</p>

<p>Musk bought Twitter in 2022 and rebranded it X.</p>

<p>On Tuesday, President-elect Donald Trump picked Musk and biotechnology company founder Vivek Ramaswany to lead a new Department of Government Efficiency, whose acronym echoes dogecoin's name.</p>

<p>The case is Gorog et al v. Musk et al, US District Court, Southern District of New York, No. 22-05037.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/vvhbh134_elon-musk-reuters_625x300_29_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Musk bought Twitter in 2022 and rebranded it X. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/prince-harrys-lawsuit-against-murdochs-uk-group-moves-towards-trial-7029299]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Prince Harry's Lawsuit Against Murdoch's UK Group Moves Towards Trial]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/prince-harrys-lawsuit-against-murdochs-uk-group-moves-towards-trial-7029299]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Nov 2024 23:59:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prince Harry is continuing his lawsuit against Rupert Murdoch's News Group Newspapers (NGN) over alleged unlawful activities by journalists and private investigators despite dozens of others settling their cases, his lawyer said on Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prince Harry is continuing his lawsuit against Rupert Murdoch's News Group Newspapers (NGN) over alleged unlawful activities by journalists and private investigators despite dozens of others settling their cases, his lawyer said on Friday.</p>

<p>Harry, 40, the younger son of King Charles, is suing the publisher of the Sun and the now-defunct News of the World at the High Court in London, alleging NGN unlawfully obtained private information about him from 1996 until 2011.</p>

<p>The royal's case was one of about 40 lawsuits against NGN, but all but one other litigant - Tom Watson, the former deputy leader of Britain's now-governing Labour Party - have now settled, Harry's lawyer David Sherborne told the court.</p>

<p>Those who have agreed to settle include Spice Girl Melanie Brown, former BBC executive Alan Yentob, "Game of Thrones" actor Alfie Allen and Ted Beckham, the father of former England soccer captain David Beckham.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-06/rrslqoco_prince-harry-called-some-media-houses-incredibly-invasive_625x300_07_June_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/musk-expands-lawsuit-against-openai-adding-microsoft-and-antitrust-claims-7029269]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Musk Expands Lawsuit Against OpenAI, Adding Microsoft And Antitrust Claims]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/musk-expands-lawsuit-against-openai-adding-microsoft-and-antitrust-claims-7029269]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Nov 2024 23:50:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Billionaire entrepreneur Elon Musk expanded his lawsuit against ChatGPT maker OpenAI, adding federal antitrust and other claims and adding OpenAI's largest financial backer Microsoft as a defendant.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Billionaire entrepreneur Elon Musk expanded his lawsuit against ChatGPT maker OpenAI, adding federal antitrust and other claims and adding OpenAI's largest financial backer Microsoft as a defendant.</p>

<p>Musk's amended lawsuit, filed on Thursday night in federal court in Oakland, California, said Microsoft and OpenAI illegally sought to monopolize the market for generative artificial intelligence and sideline competitors.</p>

<p>Like Musk's original August complaint, it accused OpenAI and its chief executive, Samuel Altman, of violating contract provisions by putting profits ahead of the public good in the push to advance AI.</p>

<p>"Never before has a corporation gone from tax-exempt charity to a $157 billion for-profit, market-paralyzing gorgon - and in just eight years," the complaint said. It seeks to void OpenAI's license with Microsoft and force them to divest "ill-gotten" gains.</p>

<p>OpenAI in a statement said the latest lawsuit "is even more baseless and overreaching than the previous ones." Microsoft declined to comment.</p>

<p>"Microsoft's anticompetitive practices have escalated," Musk's attorney Marc Toberoff said in a statement. "Sunlight is the best disinfectant."</p>

<p>Musk has a long-simmering opposition to OpenAI, a startup he co-founded and that has since become the face of generative AI through billions of dollars in funding from Microsoft.</p>

<p>Musk has gained new prominence as a key force in U.S. President-elect Donald Trump's incoming administration. Trump named Musk to a new role designed to cut government waste, after he donated millions of dollars to Trump's Republican campaign.</p>

<p>The expanded lawsuit said OpenAI and Microsoft violated antitrust law by conditioning investment opportunities on agreements not to deal with the companies' rivals. It said the companies' exclusive licensing agreement amounted to a merger lacking regulatory approvals.</p>

<p>In a court filing last month, OpenAI accused Musk of pursuing the lawsuit as part of an "increasingly blusterous campaign to harass OpenAI for his own competitive advantage."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/vvhbh134_elon-musk-reuters_625x300_29_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Musk has a long-simmering opposition to OpenAI, a startup he co-founded (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-khalistani-extremists-say-we-own-canada-ask-canadians-to-go-back-to-uk-europe-7028723]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Video: Khalistan Extremists Target Canadians, Say "Go Back To UK, Europe"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-khalistani-extremists-say-we-own-canada-ask-canadians-to-go-back-to-uk-europe-7028723]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Nov 2024 23:40:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A video, purportedly shot by an alleged pro-Khalistan supporter, has gone viral on social media in which a person can be heard calling Canadians "invaders" and asking them to "go back to England and Europe".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After targeting India, Khalistan extremists and separatists in Canada have found a new enemy - White Canadians. A video, reportedly shot by an alleged Khalistan sympathiser, has gone viral on social media in which an extremist can be heard calling Canadians "invaders" and asking them to “go back to England and Europe”.</p>

<p>The two-minute clip was reportedly shot during a <em>'Nagar Kirtan'</em> procession in the Surrey area of Canada's British Columbia. It shows several people slowly marching in one direction as songs are played in the background. Several men can also be seen waving so-called Khalistan flags in the video.</p>

<p>The man filming the procession can be heard asking for "likes and shares" while shouting inflammatory slogans. He is heard saying, “White people are invaders” and “We are owners of Canada”. He then goes on to ask white Canadians to “go back to England and Europe."</p>

<p>“This is Canada, our own country. You [Canadians] go back," he said further.</p>

<p>The video of the procession was posted on X (formally Twitter) by a user by the name of Daniel Bordman, who wrote: “Khalistanis march around Surrey BC and claim “we are the owners of Canada” and “white people should go back to Europe and Israel. How are we allowing these r*tards to shape our foreign policy?”</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Khalistanis march around Surrey BC and claim “we are the owners of Canada” and “white people should go back to Europe and Israel”.<br />
How are we allowing these r*tards to shape our foreign policy? <a href="https://t.co/9VmEnrVlGP">pic.twitter.com/9VmEnrVlGP</a></p>
— Daniel Bordman (@DanielBordmanOG) <a href="https://twitter.com/DanielBordmanOG/status/1856837451697844720?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 13, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The video surfaced amid heightened tensions between India and Canada. The ties between the two countries have come under severe strain following Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau's allegations in September last year of a “potential involvement" of Indian agents in the killing of Khalistan terrorist Hardeep Singh Nijjar, who held a Canadian passport.</p>

<p>New Delhi rejected Trudeau's charges as “absurd”. India has maintained that the main issue between the two countries is that of Canada giving space to pro-Khalistan elements operating from Canadian soil with impunity.</p>

<p>The row has escalated to a point where both countries have expelled each other's top diplomats.</p>

<p>In recent times, there has also been an increase in incidents of violence against Hindu devotees in Canada.&nbsp;On November 3, extremists carrying so-called 'Khalistani' flags clashed with devotees at a Hindu Sabha temple and disrupted an event co-organised by the temple authorities and the Indian Consulate at Brampton, a city in Ontario's Greater Toronto Area.</p>

<p>India condemned the attack with an expectation that those indulging in violence "will be prosecuted".<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/dg9n5cfo_khalistani-march-canada-twitter_625x300_15_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Khalistani extremists in Canada have now asked white Canadians to "go back to Europe"]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/its-got-to-stop-trump-reiterates-vow-to-stop-wars-in-ukraine-gaza-7029149]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["It's Got To Stop": Trump Reiterates Vow To Stop Wars In Ukraine, Gaza]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/its-got-to-stop-trump-reiterates-vow-to-stop-wars-in-ukraine-gaza-7029149]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Nov 2024 23:27:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President-elect Donald Trump on Thursday promised a "strong military", as he repeated his pledge to end the war between Russia and Ukraine.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President-elect Donald Trump on Thursday promised a "strong military", as he repeated his pledge to end the war between Russia and Ukraine.</p>

<p>Trump, who campaigned on an "America First" foreign policy, has said previously that he wanted to strike a deal between Kyiv and Moscow, without giving details, and end bloodshed in the Middle East.</p>

<p>"We have to get back to a great country with low taxes and a strong military. We're going to fix our military, we did once and now we're going to have to do it again," he said Thursday at a gala organized by the America First Policy Institute at his Mar-a-Lago resort in Palm Beach, Florida.</p>

<p>"We're going to work on the Middle East and we're going to work very hard on Russia and Ukraine. It's got to stop," Trump added.</p>

<p>He also criticized the "big chunk" of US spending on Afghanistan, from where American troops withdrew in 2021 after two decades of fighting an insurgency by the Taliban, which returned to power that year.</p>

<p>Trump's re-election has the potential to upend the almost three-year conflict between Russia and Ukraine, throwing into question Washington's multibillion-dollar support for Kyiv, which is crucial to its defense.</p>

<p>The Republican said on the campaign trail that he could end the fighting within hours and has indicated he would talk directly with Russian President Vladimir Putin.</p>

<p>Trump has not said how he intends to strike a peace deal on Ukraine or what terms he would propose.</p>

<p>Trump has nominated Fox News host and National Guard veteran Pete Hegseth to lead the world's most powerful military as defense secretary, despite a slim CV.</p>

<p>If confirmed by the Senate, Hegseth would command around 3.4 million soldiers and civilians, and oversee an annual budget of about $850 billion.</p>

<p>The president-elect has entrusted Elon Musk, the world's richest man, with the task of proposing cuts of $2 trillion from the federal government's $7 trillion budget.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/c31dbfe8_trump_625x300_14_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Trump has not said how he intends to strike a peace deal on Ukraine (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-says-ready-for-ceasefire-urges-trump-to-pressure-israel-7029137]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hamas Says "Ready For Ceasefire", Urges Trump To "Pressure" Israel]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-says-ready-for-ceasefire-urges-trump-to-pressure-israel-7029137]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Nov 2024 23:21:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A senior Hamas official on Friday said the group is "ready for a ceasefire" in Gaza, urging US President-elect Donald Trump to "pressure" Israel as it continued to pound the Palestinian territory.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A senior Hamas official on Friday said the group is "ready for a ceasefire" in Gaza, urging US President-elect Donald Trump to "pressure" Israel as it continued to pound the Palestinian territory.</p>

<p>It comes nearly a week after Qatar, which hosts much of the Palestinian group's political bureau, announced it was suspending its role as a mediator in the war and urging all parties to show "seriousness".</p>

<p>"Hamas is ready to reach a ceasefire in the Gaza Strip if a ceasefire proposal is presented and on the condition that it is respected" by Israel, Doha-based Hamas political bureau member Bassem Naim told AFP.</p>

<p>"We call on the US administration and Trump to pressure the Israeli government to end the aggression."</p>

<p>On Saturday, Qatar announced it was suspending its role as a mediator in indirect talks towards a ceasefire and hostage release deal in the Gaza war that has ground on for more than a year.</p>

<p>"Qatar would resume those efforts... when the parties show their willingness and seriousness," Doha's foreign ministry spokesman Majed Al Ansari said in a statement.</p>

<p>Friday's announcement by Hamas came as Israel continued to strike Gaza, with residents of the central city of Deir el-Balah searching through the rubble of their destroyed homes after overnight strikes.</p>

<p>"I woke up to the bombing at 2:30 am and was surprised by the rubble and glass falling on me and my children," said Mohamed Baraka, one of the residents, adding that the strike "resulted in three martyrs and 15 injuries".</p>

<p>"Put an end to this war... because there are innocent people who are losing defenceless children who have nothing to do with this," he said.</p>

<p><strong>Hostage video</strong></p>

<p>The war erupted with Hamas's October 7, 2023 attack on Israel which resulted in 1,206 deaths, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally of Israeli official figures.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory campaign has killed 43,764 people in Gaza, most of them civilians, according to figures from the Hamas-run territory's health ministry that the United Nations considers reliable.</p>

<p>Militants also kidnapped 251 hostages during the attack, 97 of whom are still held in Gaza, including 34 whom the Israeli military says are dead.</p>

<p>Earlier Friday, the Hamas-allied militant group Islamic Jihad released a new clip of Israeli hostage Sasha Trupanov, after issuing a first video earlier this week.</p>

<p>Trupanov, 29, is a dual Russian-Israeli citizen who was abducted with his girlfriend, Sapir Cohen, from the Nir Oz kibbutz near the Gaza border.</p>

<p>Russian foreign ministry spokeswoman Maria Zakharova called for the release of Trupanov and another hostage, Maxim Herkin, in comments made before the release of the latest clip.</p>

<p>Fears surged over the fate of the hostages after Qatar announced its withdrawal from mediating talks -- the latest blow in a protracted negotiation process that has hit repeated impasses.</p>

<p><strong>Lebanon strikes</strong></p>

<p>Israel on Friday also continued to strike Lebanon, where it intensified in September its air offensive and later sent in ground troops following a year of low-intensity cross-border exchanges with the Iran-backed Hezbollah group.</p>

<p>A building in Beirut's southern suburbs collapsed in a gigantic cloud of smoke and dust, an AFP photographer reported, as two strikes attributed to Israel hit the Hezbollah bastion.</p>

<p>A series of images from the strike captures a falling projectile slamming into the lower floors of the building, which erupt in a huge fireball, causing the structure to collapse.</p>

<p>Lebanon's state-run National News Agency (NNA) reported a "heavy raid carried out by aircraft of the Israeli enemy" in the Ghobeiri area of southern Beirut.</p>

<p>It said the raid had been preceded by two missile strikes on the same target by an Israeli drone.</p>

<p>The strikes followed a call by the Israeli military to evacuate the area. The evacuation call posted on X by Israeli army spokesman Avichay Adraee told residents to leave, warning of imminent strikes.</p>

<p>"All residents in the southern suburbs, specifically ... in the Ghobeiri area, you are located near facilities and interests affiliated with Hezbollah," Adraee said in an Arabic-language post on X.</p>

<p>"For your safety and the safety of your family members, you must evacuate these buildings and those adjacent to them immediately."</p>

<p>Later in the morning, a second strike hit the Bourj al-Barajneh area of the southern suburbs, an AFP journalist reported.</p>

<p>NNA said two missiles had been fired by an "enemy aircraft".</p>

<p>Lebanese authorities say more than 3,380 people have been killed since October last year, when Hezbollah and Israel began trading fire.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/pgdeos3_gaza-afp_625x300_15_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Friday's announcement by Hamas came as Israel continued to strike Gaza]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/sylvester-stallone-calls-donald-trump-second-george-washington-at-mar-a-lago-gala-7029082]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Sylvester Stallone Calls Donald Trump "Second George Washington"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/sylvester-stallone-calls-donald-trump-second-george-washington-at-mar-a-lago-gala-7029082]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Nov 2024 23:12:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Sylvester Stallone praised President-elect Donald Trump as the "second George Washington" during a speech at the America First Policy Institute Gala at Mar-a-Lago.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Legendary Hollywood star Sylvester Stallone has praised US President-elect Donald Trump, likening him to America's founding father, George Washington, and his own iconic film character, Rocky Balboa. The 78-year-old actor and filmmaker made these statements last night when he was giving a glowing introduction of President-elect Donald Trump at the America First Policy Institute Gala held at the Mar-A-Lago Club in Palm Beach, Florida.</p>

<p>Stallone called Trump the "second George Washington," emphasising his historic role following a decisive electoral win, as captured in a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://x.com/cspan/status/1857244641206177952">C-SPAN video </a>posted to X (formerly known as Twitter).</p>

<p>"We're in the presence of a really mythical character," he said during his speech. "I love mythology. And this individual does not exist on this planet. Nobody in the world could have pulled off what he pulled off, so I'm in awe." Stallone continued, touting Trump as the "second George Washington."</p>

<p>"When George Washington defended his country, he had no idea that he was going to change the world. Because without him, you could imagine what the world would look like. Guess what? We got the second George Washington."</p>

<p>Trump's landslide victory over Democratic nominee and Vice President Kamala Harris marked a significant shift in US politics. He became the first Republican since George W. Bush to secure both the presidency and the popular vote.</p>

<p>During his speech, Stallone also drew parallels between Trump and Rocky Balboa, the underdog boxer he famously portrayed in the 1976 classic. The actor's comments were met with enthusiastic applause from the audience, underscoring his strong support for the president-elect.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/evpgjhng_sylvester-stallones-journey-from-rocky-to-rambo_625x300_06_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sylvester Stallone likened Trump to his iconic Rocky Balboa character.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/lebanon-rescuer-picks-up-pieces-of-father-after-israel-strike-7029081]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Lebanon Rescuer Picks Up "Pieces" Of Father After Israel Strike]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/lebanon-rescuer-picks-up-pieces-of-father-after-israel-strike-7029081]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Nov 2024 23:12:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Suzanne Karkaba and her father Ali were both civil defence rescuers whose job was to save the injured and recover the dead in Lebanon's war.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Suzanne Karkaba and her father Ali were both civil defence rescuers whose job was to save the injured and recover the dead in Lebanon's war.</p>

<p>When an Israeli strike killed him on Thursday and it was his turn to be rescued, there wasn't much left. She had to identify him by his fingers.</p>

<p>Karkaba then rushed back to the bombed civil defence centre to search for her fellow first responders under the rubble.</p>

<p>Israel struck the centre, the main civil defence facility in the eastern Baalbek area, while nearly 20 rescuers were still inside, said Samir Chakia, a local official with the agency.</p>

<p>At least 14 civil defence workers were killed, he said.</p>

<p>"My dad was sleeping here with them. He helped people and recovered bodies to return them to their families... But now it's my turn to pick up the pieces of my dad," Karkaba told AFP with tears in her eyes.</p>

<p>Unlike many first-responder facilities previously targeted during the war, this facility in Douris, on the edge of Baalbek city, was state-run and had no political affiliation.</p>

<p>Israel's military did not immediately respond to a request for comment.</p>

<p>Friday morning, dozens of rescuers and residents were still rummaging through the wreckage of the centre. Two excavators pulled broken slabs of concrete, twisted metal bars and red tiles.</p>

<p>Wearing her civil defence uniform at the scene, Karkaba said she had been working around-the-clock since Israel ramped up its air raids on Lebanon's east in late September.</p>

<p>"I don't know who to grieve anymore, the (centre's) chief, my father, or my friends of 10 years," Karkaba said, her braided hair flowing in the wind.</p>

<p>"I don't have the heart to leave the centre, to leave the smell of my father... I've lost a part of my soul."</p>

<p><strong>'Now we are targets'</strong></p>

<p>Beginning on September 23, Israel escalated its air raids mainly on Hezbollah strongholds in east and south Lebanon, as well as south Beirut after nearly a year of cross-border exchanges of fire.</p>

<p>A week later Israel sent in ground troops to southern Lebanon.</p>

<p>More than 150 rescuers, most of them affiliated with Hezbollah and its allies, have been killed in more than a year of clashes, according to health ministry figures from late October.</p>

<p>Friday morning, rescuers in Douris were still pulling body parts from the rubble, strewn with dozens of paper documents, while Lebanese army troops stood guard near the site.</p>

<p>Civil defence worker Mahmoud Issa was among those searching for friends in the rubble.</p>

<p>"Does it get worse than this kind of strike against rescue teams and medics? We are among the first to... save people. But now, we are targets," he said.</p>

<p>On Thursday, Lebanon's health ministry said more than 40 people had been killed in Israeli strikes on the country's south and east.</p>

<p>The ministry reported two deadly Israeli raids on emergency facilities in less than two hours that day: the one near Baalbek, and another on the south that killed four Hezbollah-affiliated paramedics.</p>

<p>The ministry urged the international community to "put an end to these dangerous violations".</p>

<p>More than 3,400 people have been killed in Lebanon since the clashes began last year, according to the ministry, the majority of them since late September.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/q6to80r_lebanon_625x300_15_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Over 3,400 people have been killed in Lebanon since the clashes with Israel began]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/reliance-asks-telecom-regulator-to-review-reach-of-starlink-amazon-report-7029034]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Reliance Asks Telecom Regulator To Review Reach Of Starlink, Amazon: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/reliance-asks-telecom-regulator-to-review-reach-of-starlink-amazon-report-7029034]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Nov 2024 23:05:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Billionaire Mukesh Ambani's Reliance has asked the telecom regulator to review the potential reach of Elon Musk's Starlink and Amazon's Kuiper before awarding satellite spectrum amid concerns local players could suffer, a letter showed on Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Billionaire Mukesh Ambani's Reliance has asked the telecom regulator to review the potential reach of Elon Musk's Starlink and Amazon's Kuiper before awarding satellite spectrum amid concerns local players could suffer, a letter showed on Friday.</p>

<p>Reliance's letter, which is not public, is Mr Ambani's last-ditch effort in an ongoing face-off with Mr Musk over how India should grant spectrum for satellite services. While Reliance has called for an auction, India has sided with Mr Musk who - in line with global trends - wanted an administrative allocation.</p>

<p>In the letter, reviewed by Reuters, Reliance said it carried about 15 billion gigabyte of data every month in India after spending about $23 billion on spectrum auctions over the years, but Starlink would target the same customers with a potential capacity of nearly 18 billion gigabyte of data via its satellites with a likely much lower outlay.</p>

<p>Experts say auctions tend to mean higher initial investments which could have deterred foreign players in favour of Reliance.</p>

<p>"The authority should critically examine the capacities created by these mega ... constellations such as Starlink and Kuiper," the letter dated November 15 said.</p>

<p>A senior government source at the telecom regulator said all feedback being received would be reviewed before making final recommendations, tentatively before the year end. Starlink, Amazon and Reliance did not respond.</p>

<p>Starlink is seeking security clearance for a licence to offer satellite broadband services in India and will get a permit if it satisfies all conditions, Telecom Minister Jyotiraditya Scindia said this week.</p>

<p>Mr Ambani once gave data for free on his mobile plans, and Mr Musk has adopted similarly aggressive tactics. In Kenya, Mr Musk priced Starlink at $10 per month, versus $120 in the US, unsettling local telecom players.</p>

<p>Mr Ambani, Asia's richest man, has more than 479 million Indian telecom users, making Reliance Jio the No. 1 player. Mr Musk's Starlink, a unit of SpaceX, has 6,400 active satellites orbiting Earth providing low-latency broadband to four million customers.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/j71j1kl_jio-starlink_625x300_15_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Starlink is seeking security clearance for a licence to offer satellite broadband services in India]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-more-nuanced-on-ukraine-than-assumed-says-german-chancellor-olaf-scholz-7028977]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump "More Nuanced" On Ukraine Than Assumed, Says German Chancellor]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-more-nuanced-on-ukraine-than-assumed-says-german-chancellor-olaf-scholz-7028977]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Nov 2024 22:55:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[German Chancellor Olaf Scholz said in an interview published Friday that Donald Trump privately held "more nuanced" positions on Ukraine, days after he spoke with the president-elect of the United States by phone.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>German Chancellor Olaf Scholz said in an interview published Friday that Donald Trump privately held "more nuanced" positions on Ukraine, days after he spoke with the president-elect of the United States by phone.</p>

<p>Trump's reelection in last week's US presidential vote has raised concerns he could withdraw Washington's significant support for Ukraine once back in the White House.</p>

<p>On the campaign trail, the Republican claimed he could end the fighting within hours and that he would talk directly with Russian President Vladimir Putin.</p>

<p>Scholz, who spoke with Trump by phone on Sunday, told the German Sueddeutsche Zeitung daily his call with the president-elect was "perhaps surprisingly, a very detailed and good conversation".</p>

<p>The two discussed the situation in Ukraine "for a while", according to Scholz, as the 1,000-day mark of Russia's full-scale invasion fast approaches.</p>

<p>Without giving many details, Scholz said he got the impression Trump "has a more nuanced position than is often assumed".</p>

<p>Asked by the paper whether Trump would make a deal over the head of the Ukrainians, Scholz said Trump gave "no indication" that he would.</p>

<p>Germany, for its part, would not accept a "peace by diktat", Scholz said.</p>

<p>Separately on Friday, Scholz spoke by phone with Putin, the first call between the two leaders since December 2022.</p>

<p>Scholz urged Putin to end the war and enter negotiations with Ukraine for a "just and lasting peace".</p>

<p>In the newspaper interview, Scholz stressed that Putin "did not succeed in conquering the entire country".</p>

<p>"NATO has gained two additional members, Finland and Sweden, and is stronger than ever," Scholz said.</p>

<p>"Ukraine has become a strong nation with prospects of joining the European Union and a clear orientation towards Western Europe. It is a country with a very strong army.</p>

<p>"We must not underestimate all of this, even if the high number of dead and injured and the incredible destruction in Ukraine are terrible," Scholz said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-05/c21lpumg_olaf-scholz-_625x300_26_May_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Germany, for its part, would not accept a "peace by diktat", Scholz said. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-finalizes-up-to-6-6-billion-funding-for-taiwanese-chip-giant-tsmc-7028929]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Finalises Up To $6.6 Billion Funding For Taiwanese Chip Giant TSMC]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-finalizes-up-to-6-6-billion-funding-for-taiwanese-chip-giant-tsmc-7028929]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Nov 2024 22:47:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United States will award Taiwanese chip giant TSMC up to $6.6 billion in direct funding to help build several plants on US soil, officials said Friday, finalizing the deal before a new administration enters the White House.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United States will award Taiwanese chip giant TSMC up to $6.6 billion in direct funding to help build several plants on US soil, officials said Friday, finalizing the deal before a new administration enters the White House.</p>

<p>"Today's final agreement with TSMC -- the world's leading manufacturer of advanced semiconductors -- will spur $65 billion dollars of private investment to build three state-of-the-art facilities in Arizona," said President Joe Biden in a statement.</p>

<p>The Biden administration's announcement comes shortly before President-elect Donald Trump takes office. Trump has recently criticized the CHIPS Act, a major law passed during Biden's tenure aimed at strengthening the US semiconductor industry.</p>

<p>While the US government has unveiled over $36 billion in grants through this act, including the award to TSMC, much of the funds remain in the due diligence phase and have not been disbursed.</p>

<p>But once a deal is finalized, funds can start flowing to companies that have hit certain milestones.</p>

<p>TSMC is the second company after Polar Semiconductor to finalize its agreement.</p>

<p>"Currently, the United States does not make on our shores any leading-edge chips, and this is the first time ever that we'll be able to say we will be making these leading-edge chips in the United States," said Commerce Secretary Gina Raimondo told reporters Thursday.</p>

<p>"I want to remind everyone that these are the chips that run AI and quantum computing. These are the chips that are in sophisticated military equipment," Raimondo added.</p>

<p>Making these chips in the United States, she noted, helps address a national security liability.</p>

<p>The first of TSMC's three facilities is set to fully open by early-2025, Biden noted.</p>

<p>At full capacity, the three facilities in Arizona are expected to "manufacture tens of millions of leading-edge logic chips that will power products like 5G/6G smartphones, autonomous vehicles, and high-performance computing and AI applications," the Commerce Department said.</p>

<p>It added that "early production yields at the first TSMC plant in Arizona are on par with similar factories in Taiwan."</p>

<p>The investment is anticipated to create around 6,000 direct manufacturing jobs.</p>

<p>A senior US official told reporters on condition of anonymity that they expect at least $1 billion to go to TSMC this year.</p>

<p>Besides the $6.6 billion in direct funding, the United States is also providing up to $5 billion in proposed loans to TSMC Arizona.</p>

<p>While the United States used to make nearly 40 percent of the world's chips, the proportion is now closer to 10 percent -- and none are the most advanced chips.</p>

<p>TSMC shares were down by 0.6 percent in New York early Friday.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/e96j99rg_tsmc_625x300_15_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[TSMC is the second company after Polar Semiconductor to finalize its agreement. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/benefits-outweighed-by-negatives-news-outlets-quit-musks-x-7028911]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Benefits Outweighed By Negatives": News Outlets Quit Musk's X]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/benefits-outweighed-by-negatives-news-outlets-quit-musks-x-7028911]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Nov 2024 22:40:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[News outlets have begun quitting X, formerly Twitter, once a favourite of global media but now accused of enabling the spread of disinformation under its owner, president-elect Donald Trump ally Elon Musk.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>News outlets have begun quitting X, formerly Twitter, once a favourite of global media but now accused of enabling the spread of disinformation under its owner, president-elect Donald Trump ally Elon Musk.</p>

<p>Citing a "harsh and extreme" climate, Sweden's newspaper of reference, the left-liberal Dagens Nyheter (DN), on Friday became third major media outlet to stop publishing its articles on the social media platform.</p>

<p>"Since Elon Musk took over, the platform has increasingly merged with his and Donald Trump's political ambitions," said editor-in-chief Peter Wolodarski.</p>

<p>Already on Wednesday, Britain's centre-left daily The Guardian had announced it would no longer post content from its official accounts on X, which it called "toxic".</p>

<p>A day later, Spain's Vanguardia did the same, saying it would rather lose subscribers than remain on a "disinformation network".</p>

<p>Several users had already wondered back in 2022 whether they should remain on Twitter when Musk -- a businessman best known for running car company Tesla and space company SpaceX -- bought the platform and drastically reduced content moderation in the name of free speech.</p>

<p>The question has flared up again since Trump won this month's presidential election, actively supported by Musk.</p>

<p><strong>'Disturbing content'</strong></p>

<p>"I would expect more publishers to part ways with X," said Stephen Barnard, a specialist on media manipulation at Butler University in the US.</p>

<p>"How many do so will likely depend on what actions X, Musk, and the Trump administration take with regard to media and journalism," he said.</p>

<p>Musk, who is the world's richest man, has been tapped by Trump's team to lead a new Department of Government Efficiency.</p>

<p>The Guardian has nearly 11 million followers on the platform, but it said "the benefits of being on X are now outweighed by the negatives".</p>

<p>It said "often disturbing content" was promoted or found on the platform, singling out "far-right conspiracy theories and racism".</p>

<p>This falling-out stands in stark contrast to the enthusiasm sparked by Twitter in 2008 and 2009.</p>

<p>Back then, media felt they had to be present there to establish direct contact with their audiences as well as with experts and decision-makers.</p>

<p>They found grew "audiences, built brands, developed new reporting practices, formed community, strengthened public engagement", said Barnard.</p>

<p>At the same time, they boosted Twitter's influence.</p>

<p><strong>'Reaping what they sowed'</strong></p>

<p>This increasingly symbiotic relationship may have become detrimental to the media, suggested Mathew Ingram, former chief digital writer for the Columbia Journalism Review.</p>

<p>"Many publishers gave up on reader comments and other forms of interaction and essentially outsourced all of that to social media like Twitter," he said.</p>

<p>"To that extent they are reaping what they sowed."</p>

<p>Criticism of Twitter predates its takeover by Musk and was centred on the network's architecture that was seen favouring polemical debate and instantaneous indignation.</p>

<p>It was also said to give an unbalanced reflection of society, tilting mostly towards higher-income people, and activist users.</p>

<p>The precise impact of the decision by newspapers, already in economic crisis, to leave X is not yet clear, but they already expect readerships to dwindle.</p>

<p>"We will probably lose subscriptions because some readers subscribe after seeing a news story on the social network," Jordi Juan, director of La Vanguardia, told AFP.</p>

<p>But Barnard said any such loss would be limited because, said, "X generates relatively little traffic to news sites compared to other platforms".</p>

<p>In October 2023, six months after American public radio NPR left Twitter, a report from the Nieman Foundation for Journalism deemed the effects of this departure "negligible" in terms of traffic.</p>

<p>One beneficiary of disenchantment with X appears to be Bluesky, a decentralised social media service offering many of the same functions as X.</p>

<p>On Friday, it said it had added one million subscribers within 24 hours. But its 16 million subscribers are still dwarfed by those of X, estimated at several hundreds of millions.</p>

<p>"Strictly speaking, there are no alternatives to what X offers today," Vincent Berthier, head of the technology department at RSF (Reporters Without Borders) told AFP.</p>

<p>"But we may need to invent them."</p>

<p>Berthier called departures from X "a symptom of the failure of democracies to regulate platforms" across the board.</p>

<p>Musk may represent "the radical face of this informational nightmare", said Berthier. "But the problem goes much deeper."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/5g0r9d7_x-generic_625x300_07_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Criticism of Twitter predates its takeover by Elon Musk (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/this-creature-could-take-over-earth-if-humanity-disappears-scientists-warn-7028868]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[This Creature Could Take Over Earth If Humanity Disappears, Scientists Warn]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/this-creature-could-take-over-earth-if-humanity-disappears-scientists-warn-7028868]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Nov 2024 22:37:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[As humanity faces existential threats, scientists have speculated which species could rise to dominance in the event of human extinction.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The human race lives with myriad existential threats that can come at us from all sides, from the immediate threat of artificial intelligence entering every aspect of life to the terrible consequences of climate change and out of sight but inevitable eternal Earth demise. As we live with these, some scientists have pondered a fascinating question: If humans were to become extinct, which species might rise to dominance?</p>

<p>One of the most interesting candidates could be the octopus, which is known for its intelligence and versatility. This marine animal, highly adaptable, has a unique set of abilities that may make it well-equipped to survive and thrive on Earth in the post-human era-a complex nervous system, problem-solving ability, and capacity for learning and innovation, making them different from all other animals.</p>

<p>Professor Tim Coulson of the University of Oxford said octopuses are supremely intelligent' and have the 'dexterity, curiosity, and ability to communicate with each other." This puts them in a 'pole position' to take over the world one day.</p>

<p>"Octopuses are among the most intelligent, adaptable, and resourceful creatures on Earth," he told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://the-european.eu/story-40026/professor-tim-coulson-on-evolution-and-human-extinction-and-his-surprising-pick-for-earths-next-rulers.html"><em>The European.</em></a></p>

<p>"Octopuses are capable of distinguishing between real and virtual objects, solving puzzles, interacting with their environment, handling intricate tools with their thumb-like tentacles, and thriving in a wide variety of habitats, from deep-sea trenches to coastal regions," he said.</p>

<p>This idea has sparked lively discussions among scientists, who have explored the potential of various species to fill the void left by humanity. The octopus, with its remarkable capabilities, has emerged as a strong contender for this role. Its ability to camouflage, its dexterous limbs, and its advanced cognitive functions make it a formidable creature, capable of overcoming challenges and adapting to changing environments.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/0h35apdg_apocalypse_625x300_15_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Every day, we're reminded of the threats to humanity's survival.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/america-demanded-it-comedian-conan-obrien-to-host-oscars-7028664]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["America Demanded It": Comedian Conan O'Brien To Host Oscars]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/america-demanded-it-comedian-conan-obrien-to-host-oscars-7028664]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Nov 2024 22:03:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Comedian Conan O'Brien, a former late-night television host, will be the emcee for the Oscars for the first time, taking over from fellow funnyman Jimmy Kimmel, organizers said Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Comedian Conan O'Brien, a former late-night television host, will be the emcee for the Oscars for the first time, taking over from fellow funnyman Jimmy Kimmel, organizers said Friday.</p>

<p>O'Brien, 61, will preside over Hollywood's biggest night next March, hoping to maintain -- and even perhaps improve -- on an uptick in ratings seen earlier this year.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">America demanded it and now it's happening: Taco Bell's new Cheesy Chalupa Supreme. In other news, I'm hosting the Oscars. <a href="https://t.co/OFIlxI3wh4">https://t.co/OFIlxI3wh4</a></p>
— Conan O'Brien (@ConanOBrien) <a href="https://twitter.com/ConanOBrien/status/1857416782094500170?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 15, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>"America demanded it and now it's happening: Taco Bell's new Cheesy Chalupa Supreme. In other news, I'm hosting the Oscars," O'Brien quipped in a statement from the Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences.</p>

<p>Academy CEO Bill Kramer and President Janet Yang called O'Brien "the perfect person to help lead our global celebration of film with his brilliant humor, his love of movies and his live TV expertise."</p>

<p>"His remarkable ability to connect with audiences will bring viewers together to do what the Oscars do best -- honor the spectacular films and filmmakers of this year," they said in the statement.</p>

<p>Executive producers Raj Kapoor and Katy Mullan hailed O'Brien as "incredibly witty, charismatic and funny."</p>

<p>O'Brien, a five-time Emmy winner, hosted several late-night talk shows, including "The Tonight Show," and currently hosts the podcast "Conan O'Brien Needs a Friend." He previously served as a writer for "Saturday Night Live."</p>

<p>Kimmel first hosted the Oscars in 2017 and 2018. He was then brought back in 2023 after the previous year's ceremony featured actor Will Smith's infamous on-stage slap of Chris Rock. Kimmel also hosted the gala this past March.</p>

<p>Almost 20 million tuned in for the last Oscars -- a welcome upward trend for organizers of live awards shows, which have been shedding viewers as they compete for viewers with streamers and social media highlight clips.</p>

<p>The 97th Academy Awards will be held on March 2, 2025 at the Dolby Theatre in Hollywood.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/b3u7j25o_conan-obrien-afp_625x300_15_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The 97th Academy Awards will be held on March 2, 2025]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/indias-most-advanced-satellite-gsat-n2-launch-from-us-on-spacex-falcon-9-is-elon-musks-trump-card-7028568]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India's Most Advanced Satellite Launch From US Is Elon Musk's 'Trump' Card]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/indias-most-advanced-satellite-gsat-n2-launch-from-us-on-spacex-falcon-9-is-elon-musks-trump-card-7028568]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Nov 2024 21:49:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[SpaceX, the company owned by 'The First Buddy' of US President-elect Donald Trump, is the first big beneficiary of a multi-million dollar deal inked by India's space agency.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>SpaceX, the company owned by 'The First Buddy' of US President-elect Donald Trump, is the first big beneficiary of a multi-million dollar deal inked by India's space agency. Early next week, SpaceX's Falcon 9 rocket will take India's most modern communications satellite GSAT-20, also called GSAT N-2, into orbit.</p>

<p>This is the first of many commercial engagements the Indian Space Research Organisation (ISRO) has with SpaceX. While some say ISRO and SpaceX are competitors for low-cost launches, in the global commercial space market no one doubts that SpaceX is way-way ahead.</p>

<p>It is well-known that Donald Trump and Prime Minister Narendra Modi share a great bond with each calling the other "my friend". The maverick entrepreneur Elon Musk is also friends with both of them, with Elon Musk saying he is "a fan of Modi". The optics and timing of the space launch are just right, but incidentally the deals predate the American election results, and hence the critics of either Washington DC or New Delhi cannot raise "crony capitalism".</p>

<p>The GSAT-N2 will be launched from Cape Canaveral in the US. Made by ISRO, this 4,700 kg satellite was too heavy for Indian rockets to carry, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/isro-preps-us-launch-of-advanced-satellite-gsat-20-for-enabling-in-flight-internet-7026412">hence the foreign commercial launch</a>. India's own rocket 'The Bahubali' or the Launch Vehicle Mark-3 could have at best lifted a maximum of about 4,000-4,100 kg into a geostationary transfer orbit.</p>

<p>India had till now leaned on Arianespace to launch its heavy satellites, but at present it does not have any operational rockets and the only reliable option India had was to go with SpaceX. Chinese rockets are a no-go for India, and Russia is not able to offer its rockets for commercial launches due to the conflict in Ukraine.</p>

<p>"We got a good deal on this maiden launch with SpaceX," Radhakrishnan Durairaj, Chairman and Managing Director of New Space India Ltd (NSIL), the Bengaluru-based commercial arm of ISRO, told NDTV.</p>

<p>"The price for launching this particular satellite... the technical compatibility and also the commercial deals... I would say it was a good deal for us, for launching such a heavy satellite on SpaceX's Falcon 9 rocket," he said.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/vtsqvckg_elon-musk-pm-modi_650x400_10_April_24.jpeg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>ISRO made GSAT-N2, with a lift-off mass of 4,700 kg, and has a mission life of 14 years. It is a purely commercial launch being front-ended by NSIL. The satellite is equipped with 32 user beams, comprising eight narrow spot beams over the northeast region and 24 wide spot beams over the rest of India. These 32 beams will be supported by hub stations located within mainland India. It will also help enable in-flight Internet connectivity.</p>

<p>Elon Musk and former Republican presidential candidate Vivek Ramaswamy will lead the newly created Department of Government Efficiency (DOGE), Donald Trump had announced on Wednesday, according to news agency ANI.</p>

<p>Elon Musk, a fan of PM Modi, during a meeting with the Prime Minister on June 21, 2023 had said, "I'm incredibly excited about the future of India. India has more promise than any large country in the world. He (PM Modi) really cares about India as he's pushing us to make significant investments in India. I am a fan of Modi. It was a fantastic meeting and I like him quite a lot."</p>

<p>It is estimated that this single dedicated commercial launch of the Falcon 9 rocket to lift India's communications satellite will cost $60-70 million.</p>

<p>Over the last few months, the Tesla chief has been asking India to grant SpaceX licence to sell satellite-based Internet services in India using its Starlink Constellation. "I look forward to bringing Starlink to India where it will help remote villages," Elon Musk said in June 2023.</p>

<p>This week, Telecom Minister Jyotiraditya Scindia said Elon Musk-owned Starlink is yet to comply with security norms, and a licence for satellite communications services will be issued only after they meet all the requirements for services in India. The satellite communication services major is in the process of completing all the requirements and will get a licence once they complete the process, the minister added.</p>

<p>"We are more than happy to give them (licence) if they (Starlink) comply with all the conditions. You have to look at it from a security perspective, making sure that all security concerns are addressed. When they do that we will be more than happy to give it. Obviously, they are in the process of doing it," Mr Scindia said.</p>

<p>India has also inked another commercial deal with the Houston-based company Axiom Space to send an Indian astronaut to the International Space Station on-board the SpaceX Falcon 9 and Crew Dragon human space flight system. That deal is expected to cost $60 million. Earnings by SpaceX from the mission to send the astronaut could be much lower as four astronauts are sharing the flight.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-06/64ftumb8_pm-modi-elon-musk-reuters-650-_650x400_21_June_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Elon Musk, during a meeting with PM Narendra Modi, had said he is a "fan" of the Prime Minister]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/six-warning-signs-of-highly-contagious-virus-why-staying-home-is-crucial-7028554]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Six Warning Signs Of Highly Contagious Virus - Why Staying Home Is Crucial]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/six-warning-signs-of-highly-contagious-virus-why-staying-home-is-crucial-7028554]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Nov 2024 21:44:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Common symptoms include nausea, vomiting, diarrhoea, fever, headaches, and exhaustion, with the risk of dehydration, particularly in vulnerable groups.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>One of the new norovirus strains, often called the "winter vomiting bug," is driving a surge in cases, with infections essentially doubling what would have been seen for this point in the year compared with before Covid, new data show.</p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://metro.co.uk/2024/11/15/six-symptoms-kawasaki-virus-people-urged-stay-home-21998603/?ito=article.app.share.top.whatsapp"><em>The Metro, </em></a>the highly contagious virus can also cause diarrhoea and is linked to an especially concerning variant first identified in Kawasaki, Japan. That strain now accounts for nearly 90% of reported infections.</p>

<p>While health officials claim the symptoms of the new strain are not a bit worse than those from previous outbreaks, it is very easy to spread this particular strain, raising concern about the impact of this winter season. While primarily spread through contaminated food, surfaces, and close contact, hygiene measures are important in the prevention of further cases.</p>

<p>"Norovirus is an extremely contagious virus that spreads through contact and can cause sickness and diarrhoea for those infected.Often referred to as the "winter vomiting bug" cases of Norovirus soar over autumn and winter as more people spend time indoors, in close proximity to each other," Dr John Burke, chief medical officer at AXA Health told The Metro.</p>

<p><strong>Norovirus: A Contagious Menace</strong></p>

<p>Norovirus is one of the highly contagious viruses; it spreads as a result of person-to-person contact, touching contaminated surfaces, and many others. While most individuals recover within a few days, it can pose serious health risks, especially for young children, the elderly, and those with weakened immune systems.</p>

<p><strong>Key Symptoms of Norovirus:</strong></p>

<ol>
	<li>Nausea</li>
	<li>Vomiting</li>
	<li>Diarrhea</li>
	<li>Fever</li>
	<li>Headache</li>
	<li>Fatigue</li>
</ol>

<p><strong>Preventing the Spread of Norovirus:</strong></p>

<ul>
	<li>Stay Home: If you're infected, stay home for at least 48 hours after symptoms subside.</li>
	<li>Practice Good Hygiene: Wash your hands frequently with soap and water, especially after using the bathroom and before eating. &nbsp;&nbsp;</li>
	<li>Disinfect Surfaces: Clean and disinfect contaminated surfaces, such as countertops, doorknobs, and toilets.</li>
	<li>Avoid Sharing: Refrain from sharing food, drinks, or utensils with others.</li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/l754hg9g_nausea_625x300_15_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Norovirus spreads easily through contact with infected individuals.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-notices-russian-bomber-aircraft-naval-ships-head-towards-it-scrambles-jets-7028499]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK Notices Russian Bomber, Naval Ships Head Towards It, Scrambles Jets]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-notices-russian-bomber-aircraft-naval-ships-head-towards-it-scrambles-jets-7028499]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Nov 2024 21:34:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[UK today scrambled fighter jets today after it noticed a Russian bomber approach its airspace. While Royal Air Force was tracking the Russian jet, the Royal Navy found two separate groups of Russian Navy ships near its waters in the English Channel.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The UK today scrambled fighter jets today after it noticed a Russian bomber approach its airspace. While the Royal Air Force was tracking the Russian jet, the Royal Navy found two separate groups of Russian Navy ships near its waters in the English Channel.</p>

<p>Russia has upped its military movement in the Pacific, the Atlantic and the seas around Europe - namely the Mediterranean, the Baltic, and the North seas. UK's Royal Navy, which keeps a close watch over the North sea and the English Channel, both off its borders, noticed a large naval fleet on Thursday.</p>

<p>UK scrambled two Royal Air Force Typhoon jets to keep a check on the Russian Bear-F bomber over the near its airspace. The Royal Navy also sent out warships to shadow two groups of Russian Navy vessels - one heading towards the Atlantic Ocean, and the other on course for the Baltic Sea.</p>

<p>UK's Ministry of Defence has said that this was the second time in three months that Russian military aircraft and naval ships were seen close to its waters and airspace.</p>

<p>"Our adversaries should be in no doubt of our steadfast determination and formidable ability to protect the UK," Luke Pollard, British minister for the armed forces, said in a statement.</p>

<p>This comes days after the UK announced a wave of new sanctions against Russia's military industrial complex and Russian-backed mercenary groups. The latest sanctions by the UK, which are 56 in number, is the largest sanctions package against Russia since May 2023.</p>

<p>According to the UK government, the latest sanctions "disrupt the supply of vital equipment for Vladimir Putin's war machine and exposes the corrupt activities of Russian proxy military groups in Africa."</p>

<p>UK's Foreign Secretary David Lammy had said last week that "Today's measures will continue to push back on the Kremlin's corrosive foreign policy." He went on to say that the latest sanctions will "disrupt the supply of vital equipment for Putin's war machine. And smashing the illicit international networks that Russia has worked so hard to forge."</p>

<p>The foreign secretary further said that "Putin is nearly 1,000 days into a war he thought would only take a few. He will fail and I will continue to bear down on the Kremlin and support the Ukrainian people in their fight for freedom."</p>

<p>In September, the UK was the first NATO member state that initiated the process for Ukraine to be allowed to use British cruise missiles deep inside Russian territory. UK's Prime Minister Keir Starmer had even flown to Washington DC to meet Joe Biden over Ukraine's use of its cruise missiles, forcing Moscow to update its nuclear doctrine in a warning to the West that Russia might even use nuclear weapons to defend itself.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/0can5g7s_russian-bear-f-bomber-tupolev-tu142_625x300_15_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[UK scrambled jets after it noticed a Russian Bear-F bomber approach its airspace. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>