<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Sun, 03 Nov 2024 10:56:11 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-slams-biden-government-as-heartless-killing-machine-following-peanut-the-squirrels-death-6932568]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Trump Will Save The Squirrels": Elon Musk Mourns Peanut's Euthanasia]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-slams-biden-government-as-heartless-killing-machine-following-peanut-the-squirrels-death-6932568]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 03 Nov 2024 10:55:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Elon Musk has criticised the Joe Biden administration, labelling it a "mindless and heartless killing machine" following the euthanasia of Peanut, the internet-famous squirrel confiscated by New York state officials.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Elon Musk has criticised the Joe Biden administration, labelling it a “mindless and heartless killing machine” following the euthanasia of Peanut, the internet-famous squirrel confiscated by New York state officials. The Tesla CEO joined thousands online in mourning the beloved pet, who had captivated audiences with his charming antics and heartwarming videos on social media.</p>

<p>“President Donald Trump will save the squirrels” the billionaire wrote on X, alongside a squirrel and crying face emoji, and “RIP P'Nut.” His post included an image of Peanut perched on owner Mark Longo's back.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">President <a href="https://twitter.com/realDonaldTrump?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@realDonaldTrump</a> will save the squirrels ????️ ????<br />
<br />
RIP P'Nut <a href="https://t.co/yoIBV0Okpd">pic.twitter.com/yoIBV0Okpd</a></p>
— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1852738470017700051?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 2, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>He claimed the government was a “mindless and heartless killing machine.”</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">The government is a mindless and heartless killing machine</p>
— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1852750027963187316?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 2, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>In a follow-up tweet, Musk posted an AI generated image of Peanut as <em>Star Wars</em> character Obi-Wan Kenobi, holding a lightsaber. “If you strike me down, I will become more powerful than you could possibly imagine,” he tweeted, adding, “Obi PNut Kenobi.”</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">“If you strike me down, I will become more powerful than you could possibly imagine” Obi PNut Kenobi <a href="https://t.co/dD2Xo0fSkr">pic.twitter.com/dD2Xo0fSkr</a></p>
— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1852745739379658774?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 2, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p><a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-york-authorities-euthanise-instagram-squirrel-star-6927159 ">Peanut the squirrel</a>, who lived with New Yorker Mark Longo for seven years, charmed fans worldwide with his endearing antics, often captured in videos and photos on his Instagram account, @peanut_the_squirrel12.</p>

<p>Peanut's journey to social media stardom began after Mr Longo rescued him as a baby, finding him after his mother had been struck by a car. Mr Longo bottle-fed Peanut and initially attempted to release him into the wild. But the squirrel returned and stayed with Mr Longo, eventually becoming a social media sensation with fans across the globe who followed his waffle-eating, costume-wearing escapades.</p>

<p>On Saturday, the New York State Department of Environmental Conservation (DEC) and Chemung County Health Department reported that both Peanut and a raccoon found in Mark Longo's care were euthanised to test for rabies after a government worker was bitten by Peanut. The DEC indicated that both animals were illegally possessed and cited the risk of human rabies exposure as the reason for the euthanasia.</p>

<p>In an emotional post on Instagram, Mr Longo blamed the authorities and certain individuals who, he claimed, reported Peanut out of spite. “Internet, you WON,” Mr Longo wrote. “To the group of people who called (the DEC), there's a special place in hell for you.”</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/9mhgoao8_elon-musk-peanut-_625x300_03_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Tesla CEO joined thousands online in mourning the beloved pet.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/dramatic-debates-assassination-attempts-key-moments-in-us-election-campaigns-6932549]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Dramatic Debates, Assassination Attempts: Key  Moments In US Elections]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/dramatic-debates-assassination-attempts-key-moments-in-us-election-campaigns-6932549]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 03 Nov 2024 10:20:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Here are key moments from the US election campaigns as candidates Donald Trump and Kamala Harris edge toward election day on Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Courts, bullets and two dramatic debates have made their mark on this year's US election campaign -- one of the most extraordinary in the nation's history.</p>

<p>Here are key moments as candidates Donald Trump and Kamala Harris edge towards Election Day on Tuesday.</p>

<h3><strong>Trump the felon</strong></h3>

<p>"Trump Guilty," is splashed across the world's front pages. On May 30 the Republican becomes the first former US president to be convicted of felony crimes -- 34 counts to be exact.</p>

<p>He is found to have falsified business records to hide a hush money payment to porn star Stormy Daniels on the eve of his 2016 election win, so that she would not publicize their alleged sexual encounter.</p>

<p>In the explosive six-week trial, Daniels shares excruciating details about their apparent one-night stand, including the sex position and Trump's silky pajamas.</p>

<p>The ordeal pulls him from the campaign trail, but huge media attention ensures he keeps the spotlight -- even if it is on his criminality.</p>

<p>Nothing in US law prevents Trump from running for the White House after the guilty verdict, and Republicans double down their unwavering support for the party standard-bearer, who still faces three other criminal cases.</p>

<h3><strong>Debate drama</strong></h3>

<p>Democratic hopes appear shattered after President Joe Biden, the party's presumptive nominee, delivers a disastrous debate performance against Trump on June 27.</p>

<p>The 81-year-old fumbles his words and often appears to forget what he is saying, bolstering fears that he is not fit to run again for president.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Biden brushes it off as a "bad night" but dissenters say otherwise, with donors threatening to pull funding if he does not step aside.</p>

<p>Post-debate polling shows Trump pulling away from Biden but the White House insists there is zero chance he will withdraw.&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>Assassination attempt</strong></h3>

<p>A sun-baked Trump rally in Pennsylvania on July 13 provides the election campaign's most shocking moment yet.</p>

<p>Popping sounds ring out, Trump touches his ear, sees blood, and drops to the stage floor. Secret Service officers surround him as screams ring out in the crowd.</p>

<p>Within seconds Trump is helped back to his feet. "Fight, fight, fight!" he mouths to a now cheering audience, raising his fist to create one of the most iconic images in US political history.</p>

<p>The gunman, 20-year-old Thomas Matthew Crooks, is shot dead at the scene by the Secret Service, and Trump survives with a minor graze to his right ear.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Trump's base is galvanized. "I took a bullet for democracy," he tells his supporters at a later rally.</p>

<h3><strong>Biden says 'bye'</strong></h3>

<p>At 1:46 pm on Sunday, July 21, Biden announces in a tweet that he will not seek reelection.</p>

<p>It makes him the first sitting president since 1968 not to seek reelection, and upends the White House race.</p>

<p>Kamala Harris, the first female, Black and Asian-American to serve as US vice president, gains Biden's endorsement to replace him in the campaign.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Within two weeks she formally secures the Democratic nomination, making her the first woman of color to lead a major party ticket.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Harris re-energizes Democrats and delivers immediate results in opinion polls by clawing back Trump's gains, including in the election-deciding swing states.&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>Trump's second scare</strong></h3>

<p>Trump's weekend round of golf in Florida on September 15 is shattered by the sound of gunshots -- this time fired by a Secret Service agent foiling what the FBI calls an apparent assassination attempt.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Republican nominee is unharmed in the second such scare in two months.</p>

<p>Investigators say the gunman, Ryan Routh, did not shoot at Trump but instead fled when a security agent opened fire after seeing his rifle pointing through a tree line at the golf course.</p>

<h3><strong>The Harris surge</strong></h3>

<p>Within a few weeks, Harris hurtles from being a relatively unknown and unpopular vice president into a surging candidate on an unprecedentedly tight deadline.</p>

<p>A key moment in her campaign is her one and only debate with Trump on September 10. She is widely credited with besting Trump.</p>

<p>Their intense duel climaxes a week ahead of Election Day with big rallies.</p>

<p>For Trump, it's a packed crowd in New York's famed Madison Square Garden arena on October 27, an event quickly criticized for racist jokes, including one speaker's reference to Hispanic-majority Puerto Rico as "garbage."</p>

<p>Harris follows up on October 29 with the biggest crowd of her campaign -- tens of thousands of people -- on the National Mall outside the White House.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/cehubsmo_harris-trump-debate-afp_625x300_11_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Harris re-energized Democrats after Biden dropped out from Presidential re-election.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/70-years-on-british-engineer-behind-apollo-moon-landing-to-be-honoured-with-blue-plaque-6932340]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Honouring Tom Bacon, The Forgotten Hero Of Apollos Moon Landing]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/70-years-on-british-engineer-behind-apollo-moon-landing-to-be-honoured-with-blue-plaque-6932340]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 03 Nov 2024 09:32:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Francis Thomas Bacon invented the hydrogen-oxygen fuel cell a clean, high-efficiency power source that helped propel Apollo 11s historic moon landing in 1969.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Nearly seven decades after revolutionising clean energy, British engineer Francis Thomas Bacon's groundbreaking work is set to be recognised with a blue plaque at his former residence in Little Shelford, Cambridgeshire. Mr Bacon, an Essex-born innovator, invented the hydrogen-oxygen fuel cell - a clean, high-efficiency power source - that helped propel Apollo 11's historic moon landing in 1969 and transformed energy research.</p>

<p>Mr Bacon's fuel cells, later named “Bacon Cells” by NASA, were instrumental in the Apollo missions, supplying secondary power that enabled astronauts to communicate, operate equipment, and even drink water generated by the cells. In a <a href="https://www.bbc.com/ws/av-embeds/articles/cjl31dzp43jo/p07h6gng/en-gb " rel="nofollow,noindex">1969 BBC interview</a>, Mr Bacon explained the device's significance: “Normally, in the course of time, a battery runs down and you've got to recharge it. Now, [with] this device, as long as you go on feeding hydrogen and oxygen into it, and you remove the water formed, it will go on generating power indefinitely – and the astronauts drink the water.”</p>

<p>His work earned high praise, with then-President Richard Nixon reportedly telling him, "Without you, Tom, we wouldn't have gotten to the moon."</p>

<p>The Cambridge-based charity Cambridge Past, Present &amp; Future is championing the plaque as a tribute to Mr Bacon's contributions, which continue to inspire sustainable energy research today.</p>

<p>Professor Sam Stranks of Cambridge University, an expert in energy materials and optoelectronics, emphasised the importance of Mr Bacon's vision. "He was a pioneer," said Mr Stranks, as per the Guardian. "Fuel cell technology was extremely important to the space program because as long as you can continuously supply the gases, you can keep producing electricity."</p>

<p>This efficient, adaptable power source was ideal for remote environments like outer space and has since influenced renewable energy innovations across sectors.</p>

<p>Fuel cells are experiencing renewed interest as a potential green energy source. Mr Stranks pointed out their relevance in modern applications, particularly in powering long-haul trucks, ships and remote facilities where conventional batteries would be impractically large and heavy.</p>

<p>Reflecting Mr Bacon's vision, he added, "I always hoped it would be used for driving vehicles about," and anticipated that "in a modified form, it is going to come."</p>

<p>Mr Bacon's interest in fuel cells began in 1932 after his studies in mechanical sciences at Cambridge. Inspired by the theoretical work of physicist William Grove, who explored the concept of fuel cells in 1839, Mr Bacon began his own experiments. He soon faced an ultimatum from his employer - either abandon the risky research or leave. Choosing the latter, Mr Bacon pursued his work at Cambridge University and then Marshall, a local engineering firm.</p>

<p>For years, he struggled to fund the project until, in 1962, NASA adopted his alkaline fuel cell for the Apollo program. A US company invested $100 million, a major breakthrough for Mr Bacon's once-overlooked invention.</p>

<p>Despite this success, Mr Bacon remained largely unknown outside the scientific community. Professor Clemens Kaminski of Cambridge University said, "British engineers have some of the most brilliant ideas, but turning those ideas into commercial successes is what then often fails, and Bacon faced this. Yet he persevered."</p>

<p>In recognition of his contributions, Apollo 11 astronauts Neil Armstrong, Buzz Aldrin and Michael Collins personally thanked Mr Bacon, gifting him a signed photograph of Mr Armstrong's famous moonwalk.</p>

<p>Though Tom Bacon died in 1992, his legacy continues to inspire. Professor Stranks described him as "a visionary and an unsung hero," believing Mr Bacon's pioneering work on fuel cells still foreshadows today's clean energy efforts.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2019-07/t2ccteug_neil-armstrong-buzz-aldrin-apollo-11-moon-landing-nasa_625x300_21_July_19.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mr Bacon's fuel cells were instrumental in the Apollo missions.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/animals-fear-humans-more-than-lions-in-south-africas-wild-study-6932066]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Animals Fear Humans More Than Lions In South Africa's Wild: Study]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/animals-fear-humans-more-than-lions-in-south-africas-wild-study-6932066]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 03 Nov 2024 08:20:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Over 10,000 recordings showed that 95% of animals reacted more strongly to human sounds than lion roars, challenging the belief that animals would habituate to humans in non-hunting environments.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Despite lions' power, speed, and capacity for pack hunting, a recent study found that animals on the African savanna are more afraid of people than lions. Lions should be the most feared since they are the largest land predators and hunt in packs, according to conservation biologist Michael Clinchy of Western University in Canada.</p>

<p>"Normally, if you're a mammal, you're not going to die of disease or hunger. The thing that actually ends your life is going to be a predator, and the bigger you are, the bigger the predator that finishes you off," <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.eurekalert.org/news-releases/1003161?">says co-author Michael Clinchy</a>, also a conservation biologist at Western University. "Lions are the biggest group-hunting land predator on the planet and thus ought to be the scariest, and so we're comparing the fear of humans versus lions to find out if humans are scarier than the scariest non-human predator."</p>

<p>But after studying more than 10,000 wildlife reaction recordings, scientists discovered that 95% of the animals were more afraid of human noises than lion roars. The idea that animals would grow acclimated to people if they weren't killed is refuted by this widespread and deeply ingrained fear of humans.</p>

<p>The research team from Western University played recordings of various sounds to animals at waterholes in South Africa's Greater Kruger National Park. Even in a protected area known for its large lion population, animals reacted more strongly to human sounds, showing humans are seen as a significant threat.</p>

<p>"We put the camera in a bear box, not because there are bears out in South Africa, but because of the hyenas and leopards that like to chew on them," <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.eurekalert.org/news-releases/1003161?">says first author Liana Y Zanette</a>, a conservation biologist at Western University in Canada. "One night, the lion recording made this elephant so angry that it charged and just smashed the whole thing."</p>

<p>"I think the pervasiveness of the fear throughout the Savannah mammal community is a real testament to the environmental impact that humans have," says Zanette. "Not just through habitat loss and climate change and species extinction, which is all important stuff. But just having us out there on that landscape is enough of a danger signal that they respond really strongly. They are scared to death of humans, way more than any other predator."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/n9tuq1bg_lions_625x300_03_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Lions, as largest group-hunting predators, should be most feared.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-recalls-how-mother-used-to-take-her-to-india-on-diwali-6932033]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris Recalls Mother Taking Her To India On Diwali]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-recalls-how-mother-used-to-take-her-to-india-on-diwali-6932033]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 03 Nov 2024 08:14:00 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[President Kamala Harris, who is the Democratic presidential candidate, in an op-ed, recollected her frequent visit to India as a child, and her mother's mission to cure cancer.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p>

<p>President Kamala Harris, who is the Democratic presidential candidate, in an op-ed on Saturday, recollected her frequent visit to India as a child, and her mother's mission to cure cancer.</p>

<p>"Growing up, my mother raised my sister and me to appreciate and honor our heritage. Nearly every other year, we would go to India for Diwali. We would spend time with our grandparents, our uncles, and our chitthis," Harris said in the op-ed for The Jaggernaut, an online South Asian publication.</p>

<p>"And as Vice President, it has been my honor to host Diwali celebrations in my home - the Vice President's Residence. Not only to celebrate the holiday, but to celebrate the rich history, culture, and heritage of the South Asian American diaspora, which is bound together by a shared sense of possibility and belief in the promise of America," she said.</p>

<p>In her op-ed published three days before the November 5th general elections, Harris wrote that as a 19-year-old, her mother Shyamala Harris crossed the world alone, traveling from India to the United States. "My mother had two goals in her life: to raise her two daughters, my sister Maya and me, and to cure breast cancer," she wrote.</p>

<p>"When I was little, when we traveled to India, we would also visit my grandfather, P.V. Gopalan, in what was then called Madras. My grandfather was a retired civil servant. His morning routine consisted of taking long walks on the beach with his retired buddies. I would join him on those walks and listen to stories about the importance of fighting for democracy and civil rights," she wrote.</p>

<p>"Throughout these walks, I recall my grandfather teaching me lessons about not just what it means to have a democracy but to keep a democracy. Those lessons first inspired my interest in public service. And they continue to guide me today - as Vice President and as a candidate for President of the United States," Harris said.</p>

<p>She said she believes Americans want a president who works for all the American people. "And that has been the story of my entire career," he said.</p>

<p>"South Asian Americans are often overlooked by our healthcare system, especially when it comes to heart health and diabetes. I worked with President Joe Biden to cap insulin prices for seniors at $35, and reduce drug costs. I will protect the Affordable Care Act and expand Medicare to cover home care for seniors. This is personal for me. When my mother had cancer, I helped take care of her and did everything I could to make her comfortable. I understand the burdens of caregiving and will work to ease them for your families," she wrote.</p>

<p>"With respect to fixing our broken immigration system, I reject the false choice between securing our border and creating a system of immigration that is orderly and humane. We can and must do both. The bipartisan border security bill I support does that. It will reduce illegal border crossings through strict enforcement, so that South Asian lives aren't endangered. I will partner with Democrats, Republicans, and independents to ensure we live up to our proud heritage as a nation of immigrants," she said.</p>

<p>"Our role in the world is also at stake in this election, and I will ensure that we strengthen, not abdicate, our global leadership. As Vice President, I have expanded our relationships with key South Asian partners, including India. And unlike Trump, who cozies up to tyrants and whose own national security officials have deemed 'dangerous' and 'unfit', I will never waver in defending America's security and ideals," she wrote.</p>

<p>"Donald Trump is an unserious man, but the consequences of him ever getting back into the White House are brutally serious. Trump and his extremist allies will cut Social Security and Medicare. His economic policies will drive inflation higher, and cause a recession by mid-2025. He intends to impose what I call a 'Trump sales tax' which is at least a 20% tax, if not more, on everyday necessities. Economists have estimated this will cost the American family an additional $4,000 a year," Harris wrote.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/v3qrota_kamala-harris-mother_625x300_03_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kamala Harris with her mother Shyamala Rajagopalan Harris.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/15-year-old-boy-in-uk-given-life-sentence-for-fatally-stabbing-teenager-in-chest-6932008]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[15-Year-Old Boy In UK Given Life Sentence For Fatally Stabbing Teenager]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/15-year-old-boy-in-uk-given-life-sentence-for-fatally-stabbing-teenager-in-chest-6932008]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 03 Nov 2024 08:10:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 15-year-old boy in the UK who fatally stabbed a teenager in Birmingham city centre has been sentenced to life.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 15-year-old boy in the UK who fatally stabbed a teenager in Birmingham city centre has been sentenced to life. According to the <em>BBC</em>, 17-year-old Muhammad Hassam Ali died in hospital in January this year, hours after he and his friend were followed by two masked 15-year-old boys before he was attacked in Victoria Square. The youth, who cannot be named for legal reasons, was found guilty of murder and possessing a knife, and on Friday was given a minimum sentence of 13 years. The second 15-year-old, who was standing nearby, was found guilty of manslaughter and possessing a knife and was sentenced to five years' detention in secure accommodation.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The two boys didn't show any emotion as they were sentenced by Judge Mr Justice Garnham. Sentencing the pair, Mr Garnham said 17-year-old Ali's murder was "yet another illustration of the appalling consequences of carrying knives in public places". "It is perfectly clear to me (Ali) was a much-loved son and brother and his family have been left utterly devastated by his death," he said, per the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c704w1j0ezdo" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>BBC</em></a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Separately, in a statement, Ali's family said, "We as a family still can't even bear to think about how he died, even writing the word murdered destroys a little bit of us again. The loss of Muhammad, or any child, is devastating and life-destroying, but the fact that someone has so brutally taken his life in such a horrific way will always haunt us."</p>

<p>The family continued that the teachers had commented on Ali's kindness towards others, while fellow classmates described him as chatty and friendly. "He dreamt of becoming an engineer and his passion was to work hard to achieve his goal. This dream will no longer come true, not for wanting to work hard but at the hands of another," they said.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, a trial earlier this year heard that the 17-year-old and his friend were simply sitting down, chatting about cricket over a hot chocolate and using their phones when they were approached by the two masked boys. The youths had followed them from Grand Central Shopping Centre before confronting Ali and his friend at Victoria Square.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The defendants wearing Covid-style masks had asked the pair if they knew who had "jumped a mate" of theirs a week before. This prompted a dispute, with Ali telling the pair he did not know what they were talking about. It was then that one of them pulled out a large knife and stabbed Ali in the chest before fleeing from the scene.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sara-sharif-case-father-of-pak-british-girl-10-hit-her-like-crazy-and-made-her-do-sit-ups-all-night-6926762">Sara Sharif Case: Father Of Pak-British Girl, 10, "Hit Her Like Crazy" And Made Her Do Sit-Ups All Night</a></strong></p>

<p>In his evidence, the 15-year-old told the court that he only wanted to "scare" Ali and his friend and that he did not intend to seriously harm or kill anyone. He stated that he carried a knife when he went to busy places for protection as he had been attacked several times before and that he felt "regretful and upset" when he learned he had killed Ali.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The other youth told the cops that he had been "shocked and crying" after the incident. He claimed that he did not know his friend had a knife on him until he produced it. He also said that he had never seen Ali r his friend before and only went along with the killer in case he "got battered".&nbsp;</p>

<p>Michael Ivers KC, representing the defendant, said he was remorseful and prays for Ali and his family regularly. He isn't a man who is in any sense proud of what happened. He truly, truly regrets what happened. If he could turn the clock back, not for his own sake but because of the impact it has had on others, he would," he said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-02/j9dtkci_man-in-jail-generic-man-in-prison-generic_625x300_02_February_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Muhammad Hassam Ali died in hospital in January this year. (Representative pic)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-vows-tooth-breaking-response-us-b-52-bombers-reach-middle-east-6931902]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iran Vows "Tooth-Breaking" Response, US B-52 Bombers Reach Middle East]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-vows-tooth-breaking-response-us-b-52-bombers-reach-middle-east-6931902]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 03 Nov 2024 07:31:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iran's Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei has promised a "tooth-breaking" response to ongoing Israeli military actions.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Iran's Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei has promised a "tooth-breaking" response to ongoing Israeli military actions. This statement follows a dramatic escalation, including an Israeli commando raid in Lebanon, and comes days before the US presidential election, with Washington as Israel's primary military supporter.</p>

<p>"The enemies, both the USA and the Zionist regime, should know that they will definitely receive a tooth-breaking response," he declared, referring to Iran-aligned groups across the Middle East, including Hezbollah in Lebanon and factions in Yemen and Syria.</p>

<p>Adding to these tensions, Kamal Kharrazi, a top advisor to Khamenei, alluded to Iran's nuclear potential, suggesting Iran may reconsider its nuclear policy if faced with an existential threat. "If an existential threat arises, Iran will modify its nuclear doctrine, we have the capability to build weapons and have no issue in this regard," Kharrazi told Lebanese media.</p>

<p>The latest confrontations began with an October 1 missile strike from Iran, which Israel answered with an October 26 bombing campaign targeting Iranian military installations, reportedly killing four Iranian soldiers. Israel claims the airstrikes inflicted significant damage on Iran's missile and air defence capacities, while Iran has vowed reprisal.</p>

<h2><strong>Commandos Target Hezbollah In Lebanon</strong></h2>

<p>In a separate operation, Israeli naval commandos seized a Hezbollah operative in Batroun, Lebanon. The captive, reportedly a senior operative undergoing maritime training, is now in Israeli custody.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"A senior operative of Hezbollah, who serves as an expert in his field, was apprehended," the Israeli military said, as quoted by news agency AFP. "The operative has been transferred to Israeli territory and is currently being investigated."</p>

<p>Lebanese authorities, including Prime Minister Najib Mikati, have decried the raid, with Mikati instructing the foreign ministry to file a complaint with the United Nations. Both Lebanon's army and UN peacekeepers have launched investigations into the incident.</p>

<h2><strong>Humanitarian Crisis Intensifies In Gaza</strong></h2>

<p>As violence expands, conditions in Gaza deteriorate. The World Health Organisation (WHO) reported that a missile strike on a polio vaccination centre in north Gaza injured six people, including four children. WHO's Director-General, Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus, condemned the attack on Sheikh Radwan health centre as "extremely concerning."&nbsp;</p>

<p>Israel's military reported the deaths of dozens of militants in the Jabalia area as their operations persisted. Civilian casualties continue to mount, with Gaza's health ministry reporting over 43,000 deaths since hostilities resumed, though these figures are contested by Israeli sources.</p>

<h2><strong>Escalation On Israel's Northern Border</strong></h2>

<p>In Lebanon, Israeli airstrikes have intensified, killing nearly 2,000 people and displacing thousands, as Hezbollah retaliates with rocket fire into Israeli territory, including attacks on military sites near Haifa and Tel Aviv. In response, the US deployed B-52 bombers to the region, hoping to dissuade further escalation from Iran.</p>

<p>A US official warned Tehran that Washington might not be able to restrain Israel in the event of another Iranian strike. "We told the Iranians: We won't be able to hold Israel back," the official reportedly stated.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/dlju4lpo_us-b52-bombers-reuters-_625x300_03_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The US has deployed B-52 bombers to the region.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/study-uncovers-major-causes-of-gout-debunking-common-myths-6931876]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Study Uncovers Major Causes of Gout, Debunking Common Myths]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/study-uncovers-major-causes-of-gout-debunking-common-myths-6931876]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 03 Nov 2024 07:28:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A major scientific breakthrough has overturned the long-held belief that gout is primarily caused by lifestyle factors like diet and alcohol consumption.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A significant scientific discovery has challenged the long-held notion that lifestyle variables such as diet and alcohol usage are the main causes of gout. The development of gout is significantly influenced by genetics, according to research from the University of Otago. They discovered particular genes that raise the risk of developing gout by examining the DNA of millions of people. This ground-breaking discovery casts doubt on the conventional wisdom of gout and creates new opportunities for creating more potent remedies and prophylactics.</p>

<p>The research that has been published in <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41588-024-01921-5"><em>Nature Genetics</em></a> found inherited genetics is an important part of why some people get gout and most others don't.</p>

<p>Senior author Professor Tony Merriman, of Otago's Department of Microbiology and Immunology, hopes the findings will remove some of the stigma around gout.</p>

<p>"Gout is a chronic disease with a genetic basis and is not the fault of the sufferer-the myth that gout is caused by lifestyle or diet needs to be busted," <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.otago.ac.nz/news/newsroom/study-busts-myths-about-cause-of-gout">he said.</a></p>

<p>"This widespread myth causes shame in people with gout, making some people more likely to suffer in silence and not go and see the doctor to get a preventive drug that lowers urate in the blood and will prevent their pain.</p>

<p>"People need to understand that while specific dietary factors, such as eating red meat, can trigger gout attacks, the fundamental cause is high urate levels, crystals in the joints, and an immune system primed to 'attack' the crystals-genetics plays an important role in all of these processes."</p>

<p>The research identified a large number of immune genes and immune pathways that provide new targets and approaches for preventing gout attacks.</p>

<p><strong>What is gout?</strong></p>

<p>According to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.footankleinstitute.com/conditions/arthritis/gout">Foot Ankle Institute,</a> gout is a type of arthritis that affects the musculoskeletal system, better known as your bones, joints, and muscles. It results from a buildup of uric acid in the joints. When there's an excess of uric acid in the blood, it crystalizes in the joints, usually the big toes. The most common gout symptoms include redness, tenderness, swelling, and pain.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/m18itqig_gout-_625x300_03_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Gout is the most common arthritis, affecting men 3-4 times more than women.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/the-elon-musk-effect-the-impact-of-the-worlds-richest-man-on-us-democracy-6930627]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[The Impact Of The World's Richest Man On US Democracy]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/the-elon-musk-effect-the-impact-of-the-worlds-richest-man-on-us-democracy-6930627]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 03 Nov 2024 00:14:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[How much influence can the worlds richest man have over one of the worlds oldest democracies? Next weeks elections are not just about Donald Trump and Kamala Harris but also a measure of Elon Musks influence on American democracy.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>How much influence can the world's richest man have over one of the world's oldest democracies? Next week's elections are not just about Donald Trump and Kamala Harris but also a measure of Elon Musk's influence on American democracy.</p>

<p>Although Musk has donated modestly to both Republicans and Democrats in the past, including $5,000 to Hillary Clinton in 2016, this time he has spent a whopping $119 million to mobilise Trump's supporters, and has been leveraging his social media platform, X, to spread pro-Trump propaganda. He's also an important presence in Trump's rallies in crucial battleground states, recently unveiling his “Dark gothic MAGA” side.</p>

<p>Musk's involvement has drawn scrutiny, particularly after he skipped a hearing related to a lawsuit over his efforts to give millions to registered voters - a move experts liken to vote buying.</p>

<p>He's also under investigation by the Securities and Exchange Commission and has been reported to have regular communications with Russian President Vladimir Putin, raising national security concerns due to SpaceX's contracts with NASA and the Department of Defence.</p>

<p>Apart from being the eye of the storm when it comes to politics, business and foreign policy, he's now leading America PAC, a super PAC backing Trump's get-out-the-vote effort. Despite initial struggles, Musk brought in new consultants, and on paper, the numbers have improved. Still, Republican officials question the PAC's ground game effectiveness in critical states like Georgia.</p>

<p>Musk's frustration with his PAC has led him to bring in private sector associates like Steve Davis of the Boring company. Moreover, his companies, particularly Tesla, face regulatory challenges, which could be alleviated if Trump wins.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Trump has told Fox News, “Elon has a lot of roles he could take.” The former president has even suggested Musk could play a role in his future administration, focusing on government efficiency - a move that raises significant conflict of interest concerns.</p>

<p>As the election approaches, Musk's influence and controversies will undoubtedly remain in the spotlight.</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/vvhbh134_elon-musk-reuters_625x300_29_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Next weeks elections are not just about Trump and Harris but also about Musk's influence on democracy]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-election-the-changing-face-of-the-oval-office-all-the-us-presidents-since-1900-6611182]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[The Changing Face Of The Oval Office - All The US Presidents Since 1900]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-election-the-changing-face-of-the-oval-office-all-the-us-presidents-since-1900-6611182]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 03 Nov 2024 00:00:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A look at how American leadership has evolved through major historical events and societal changes over the past century]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>United States of America votes on November 5. The stage is set for the 2024 presidential election. The two major political parties - Democrats and Republicans - had nominated their candidates through a series of primaries and caucuses. On the Republican side, it is former President Donald Trump. His opponent, Vice President Kamala Harris, emerged as the Democratic nominee after President Joe Biden chose not to seek re-election.</p>

<h2>As voters prepare to cast their ballots, let's look back at the US Presidents who have shaped the nation's history since 1900.</h2>

<h3><strong>William McKinley (1897-1901)</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/rn3e28o8_former-us-president-william-mckinley-18971901_625x300_02_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>William McKinley was the 25th President of the United States, holding office from March 4, 1897, until his assassination on September 14, 1901. During his presidency, he guided the nation to victory in the Spanish-American War of 1898 and implemented protective tariffs to strengthen American industry. During the 100-day Spanish-American War, the US defeated the Spanish fleet outside Santiago harbour in Cuba, captured Manila in the Philippines, and occupied Puerto Rico.</p>

<h3><strong>Theodore Roosevelt (1901-1909)</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/jk51blbg_former-us-president-theodore-roosevelt-19011909_625x300_02_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Following the assassination of President William McKinley, Theodore Roosevelt, at the age of 42, ascended to the presidency, becoming the 26th and youngest president in American history. Roosevelt infused the office with new energy and purpose, championing progressive reforms and asserting a strong foreign policy. Internationally, Roosevelt made a significant mark by mediating the Russo-Japanese War, earning him the Nobel Peace Prize and solidifying his reputation as a formidable leader.</p>

<h3><strong>William Howard Taft (1909-1913)</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/car3td8s_former-us-president-william-howard-taft-19091913_625x300_02_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>William Howard Taft was elected as the 27th President of the United States, serving from 1909 to 1913. After his presidency, he became the 10th Chief Justice of the United States, holding that position from 1921 to 1930. Taft remains the only individual to have served in both of these significant roles.</p>

<h3><strong>Woodrow Wilson (1913-1921)</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/n1brkc9c_former-us-president-woodrow-wilson-19131921_625x300_02_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Woodrow Wilson, a prominent figure in the Progressive Movement, served as the 28th President of the United States. Initially advocating for a policy of neutrality at the onset of World War I, Wilson later made the decision to lead America into the conflict to "make the world safe for democracy." His leadership during the war and his vision for a post-war order, including the establishment of the League of Nations, marked significant developments in both domestic and international politics.</p>

<h3><strong>Warren G. Harding (1921-1923)</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/m4dmg4f_former-us-president-warren-g-harding-19211923_625x300_02_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Warren G. Harding, an Ohio Republican, served as the 29th President of the United States from 1921 until his death in 1923. While his presidency was marred by significant scandals, most notably the Teapot Dome affair, Harding also championed technological advancements and demonstrated a sensitivity to the challenges faced by minorities and women. His administration aimed for a return to normalcy after World War I, seeking to promote economic stability and growth during a transformative era in American history.</p>

<h3><strong>Calvin Coolidge (1923-1929)</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/mhepj7cc_former-us-president-calvin-coolidge-19231929_625x300_02_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>As the 30th President of the United States, Calvin Coolidge was resolute in his commitment to upholding traditional values of frugality and restraint during a period of substantial material prosperity that many Americans experienced in the 1920s.</p>

<h3><strong>Herbert Hoover (1929-1933)</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/undljb94_former-us-president-herbert-hoover-19291933_625x300_02_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Herbert Hoover's time in office aligned with the beginning of the Great Depression. His opponents in Congress, who he believed were undermining his efforts for their political gain, portrayed him as a callous and uncaring leader. As economic hardships deepened, Hoover became a scapegoat for the nation's struggles, ultimately leading to a significant defeat in the 1932 election.</p>

<h3><strong>Franklin D. Roosevelt (1933-1945)</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/752rn2uo_former-us-president-franklin-d-roosevelt-19331945_625x300_02_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Franklin D Roosevelt remains one of the most iconic presidents in US history. Assuming the presidency at the height of the Great Depression, Roosevelt worked tirelessly to restore the American people's faith in themselves and their government. He offered hope through his promise of prompt and vigorous action, famously declaring once, "the only thing we have to fear is fear itself." His leadership during World War II solidified America's status as a global superpower. As World War II neared its conclusion, Franklin D Roosevelt's health began to decline. On April 12, 1945, while at Warm Springs, Georgia, he passed away from a cerebral haemorrhage.</p>

<h3><strong>Harry S. Truman (1945-1953)</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/3ttunu5_former-us-president-harry-s-truman-19451953_625x300_02_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>After becoming President, Truman faced some of history's most critical decisions. Shortly after Victory in Europe (V-E) Day, the war against Japan was nearing its end. An urgent appeal for Japan to surrender was met with rejection. After consulting with his advisers, Truman made the decisive choice to drop atomic bombs on cities engaged in war production, specifically Hiroshima and Nagasaki. This prompted Japan's surrender, bringing World War II to an end.</p>

<h3><strong>Dwight D. Eisenhower (1953-1961)</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/cq71pe3k_former-us-president-dwight-d-eisenhower-19531961_625x300_02_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Eisenhower, a decorated World War II general, presided over a period of post-war prosperity. Bringing the prestige of a commanding general who led victorious forces in Europe during World War II, Eisenhower secured a truce in Korea and worked throughout his two terms to ease Cold War tensions. He championed moderate policies under the banner of "Modern Republicanism."</p>

<h3><strong>John F. Kennedy (1961-1963)</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/b9h00hu4_former-us-president-john-f-kennedy-19611963_625x300_02_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>John F. Kennedy was the 35th President of the United States and the youngest ever elected to the office. Tragically, on November 22, 1963, just over a 1,000 days into his presidency, JFK was assassinated in Dallas, Texas, making him the youngest president to die in office. His administration is remembered for significant events and initiatives, including the Cuban Missile Crisis and the establishment of the Peace Corps.</p>

<h3><strong>Lyndon B. Johnson (1963-1969)</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/i11aqcfg_former-us-president-lyndon-b-johnson-19631969_625x300_02_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Under Lyndon B. Johnson's leadership, the nation made remarkable strides in space exploration. During the Vietnam War, despite Johnson's efforts to curb Communist aggression and negotiate a settlement, the fighting persisted. By the end of March 1968, the controversy surrounding the war had intensified, leading him to limit the bombing of North Vietnam to initiate peace negotiations.</p>

<h3><strong>Richard Nixon (1969-1974)</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/c0o3srqg_former-us-president-richard-nixon-19691974_625x300_02_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Richard Nixon was elected as the 37th President of the United States after previously holding positions as a US Representative and a Senator from California. He achieved significant milestones, including the withdrawal of American troops from Vietnam and enhancing diplomatic relations with the USSR and China. He ultimately became the first President in history to resign from office due to the Watergate scandal.</p>

<h3><strong>Gerald Ford (1974-1977)</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ll3beh4g_former-us-president-gerald-ford-19741977_625x300_02_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Gerald Ford assumed the presidency following Nixon's resignation, taking on the immense challenge of restoring public trust in the government. He was the first Vice President selected under the provisions of the Twenty-fifth Amendment and succeeded the first President to ever resign from office amid the Watergate scandal. Ford faced formidable tasks, including tackling inflation, revitalising a struggling economy, addressing chronic energy shortages and striving to maintain world peace.</p>

<h3><strong>Jimmy Carter (1977-1981)</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/7mu0762_former-us-president-jimmy-carter-19771981_625x300_02_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Jimmy Carter's presidency is noted for his focus on human rights and environmental issues. He was awarded the Nobel Peace Prize in 2002 for his efforts to resolve international conflicts through peaceful means, promote democracy and human rights and support economic and social development.</p>

<h3><strong>Ronald Reagan (1981-1989)</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/lak4ti28_former-us-president-ronald-reagan-19811989_625x300_02_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Ronald Reagan, a former actor, served as the 40th President of the United States. His presidency marked a period of economic recovery and prosperity domestically, accompanied by a foreign policy aimed at achieving "peace through strength." Reagan's administration focused on reducing government spending, tax cuts, and strengthening the military, which he believed would strengthen America's position on the global stage.</p>

<h3><strong>George H.W. Bush (1989-1993)</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/issbaclk_former-us-president-george-hw-bush-19891993_625x300_02_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>George H.W. Bush's presidency was characterised by key foreign policy successes, particularly the Gulf War, which liberated Kuwait from Iraqi occupation. His biggest challenge arose when Saddam Hussein invaded Kuwait and threatened Saudi Arabia. In response, Bush rallied the United Nations and mobilised American troops, supported by allies. After weeks of air strikes, the ground offensive - Operation Desert Storm - defeated Iraq's million-man army in just 100 hours. This victory initially boosted Bush's popularity. However, back home, economic troubles, rising violence in inner cities and high deficit spending eroded his support.</p>

<h3><strong>Bill Clinton (1993-2001)</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/5jnl25dg_former-us-president-bill-clinton-19932001_625x300_02_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Bill Clinton served as the 42nd President of the United States, stepping into office at the conclusion of the Cold War. As the first president from the baby boomer generation, he represented a shift in American leadership. However, his presidency faced significant turmoil. In 1998, Clinton became the second US president to be impeached by the House of Representatives due to controversies surrounding personal indiscretions with a young White House intern. The Senate, however, voted to acquit Clinton saving his presidency.</p>

<h3><strong>George W. Bush (2001-2009)</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/gneiue84_former-us-president-george-w-bush-20012009_625x300_02_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>George W. Bush, the 43rd President of the United States, became a wartime leader in the wake of the devastating terrorist attacks on September 11, 2001. This event reshaped Bush's presidency, forcing him to set aside many of his initial hopes and plans. His father, George H.W. Bush, the 41st president, remarked that his son was "facing the greatest challenge of any president since Abraham Lincoln."</p>

<h3><strong>Barack Obama (2009-2017)</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/r2hn4bn8_former-us-president-barack-obama-20092017_625x300_02_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Barack Obama served as the 44th President of the United States, embodying the essence of the American dream. His journey reflects core American values: a middle-class upbringing rooted in a supportive family, the belief in hard work and education as pathways to success, and a deep conviction that a fortunate life should be dedicated to serving others.</p>

<h3><strong>Donald Trump (2017-2021)</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/f9t5t5ag_former-us-president-donald-trump-20172021_625x300_02_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Trump, a businessman, brought a disruptive and unconventional style to the presidency. His administration was marked by tax cuts, deregulation and a focus on America-first policies. His handling of the COVID-19 pandemic and the subsequent economic challenges defined much of his final year in office. His refusal to accept the 2020 election results culminated in the January 6 Capitol attack.</p>

<h3><strong>Joe Biden (2021-Present)</strong></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/nu2tlst_former-us-president-joe-biden-20212025_625x300_02_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Biden's presidency has focused on navigating the challenges of the COVID-19 pandemic, economic recovery and addressing social inequalities. His administration passed the American Rescue Plan and launched initiatives to improve infrastructure and climate resilience. Biden also oversaw the withdrawal of US troops from Afghanistan, ending a 20-year war.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-06/7ab6ond_white-house-lawns_625x300_20_June_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The White House is the official residence of the President of the United States of America]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-makes-risky-last-ditch-effort-campaigns-in-new-mexico-and-virginia-6930438]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Makes Risky Last-Ditch Effort: Campaigns In New Mexico And Virginia]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-makes-risky-last-ditch-effort-campaigns-in-new-mexico-and-virginia-6930438]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 02 Nov 2024 23:33:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump is taking a bold move in the final days of his presidential campaign by visiting New Mexico and Virginia, two states that have historically been difficult for Republican candidates to win.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump is taking a bold move in the final days of his presidential campaign by visiting New Mexico and Virginia, two states that have historically been difficult for Republican candidates to win.</p>

<p>The former president campaigned in Albuquerque, New Mexico, on Thursday and was scheduled to visit Salem, Virginia, on Saturday, in an effort to gain momentum and potentially turn these states red.</p>

<p>Trump's team is optimistic about his chances, citing early voting numbers and the possibility of sweeping swing states Nevada and Arizona. However, this strategy carries significant risk, as neither New Mexico nor Virginia has been carried by a GOP nominee since George W. Bush in 2004.</p>

<p>The battleground states have received significant attention since the past few weeks, with billboards, smartphones, televisions bombarding them with political ads. The candidates - presidential and vice-presidential candidates have made 21 appearances in Pennsylvania, 17 in Michigan and 13 in North Carolina since the past two weeks.</p>

<p>Trump's visit to Albuquerque brings attention to his immigration stance in a border state with the nation's highest concentration of Latino voters. About 44% of New Mexico's voting-age population identifies as Hispanic, and the state has been dealing with a surge in migrant deaths along the U.S.-Mexico border.</p>

<p>"If we could bring God down from heaven, he could be the vote counter and we could win this," Trump said. He also added that he's visiting New Mexico because it's "good for my credentials" with Latino voters.</p>

<p>Virginia was once considered a battleground state but has trended toward Democrats in recent years. Trump lost the state to Clinton in 2016 and Biden in 2020. Despite this, Trump believes he has a "real chance" of winning, and his visit may focus on the recent Supreme Court ruling on voter registrations.</p>

<p>Democratic strategist Bob Shrum questions Trump's strategy, stating, "I don't think there's any strategy... I think he insisted on doing it. It makes no sense". Meanwhile, Virginia's Governor Glenn Youngkin believes the state is more competitive than expected.</p>

<p>Susan Swecker,&nbsp;Chairwoman of the Democratic Party of Virginia, holds the opinion that this visit will only make it harder for Trump to gain votes. "Kamala Harris will win Virginia convincingly, as he knows, and any visit from this deranged lunatic will only widen the margin," she said.</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/v5klevj8_donald-trump-afp_625x300_02_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Trump is taking a bold move in the final days of his campaign by visiting New Mexico and Virginia]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/woman-strips-at-iran-university-to-protest-strict-islamic-dress-code-reports-6930391]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Woman Strips At Iran University To Protest Strict Dress Code: Reports]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/woman-strips-at-iran-university-to-protest-strict-islamic-dress-code-reports-6930391]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 02 Nov 2024 23:24:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A young woman stripped to her underwear at an Iranian university on Saturday in an apparent protest against the country's strict Islamic dress code, according to online videos and media reports.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A young woman stripped to her underwear at an Iranian university on Saturday in an apparent protest against the country's strict Islamic dress code, according to online videos and media reports.</p>

<p>A video posted on social media showed security guards at a branch of the Islamic Azad University detaining the unidentified woman. University spokesperson Amir Mahjob said on X that "at the police station,...it was found that she was under severe mental pressure and had a mental disorder".</p>

<p>But some social media users suggested the woman's action was a deliberate protest.</p>

<p>"For most women, being ...in their underwear in public is one of their worst nightmares, ... This is a reaction to the (authorities') stupid insistence on the mandatory hijab," Lei La, a user on X, said in a comment accompanying the video.</p>

<p>The fate of the woman was not known but the mass-circulation daily Hamshahri said on its website: "An informed source said...the perpetrator of this act has severe mental problems and, after investigations, she will most likely be transferred to a mental hospital."</p>

<p>Growing numbers of women have defied authorities by discarding their veils after nationwide protests that followed the death in September 2022 of a young Iranian Kurdish woman in the custody of the morality police for allegedly violating hijab rules. Security forces violently put down the revolt.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/hfoa5qi8_iran-woman-protesting_625x300_02_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Growing numbers of women have defied authorities by discarding their veils.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/some-friends-may-be-more-complicated-s-jaishankar-on-diplomatic-ties-6929502]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Some Friends May Be More Complicated...": S Jaishankar On Diplomatic Ties]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/some-friends-may-be-more-complicated-s-jaishankar-on-diplomatic-ties-6929502]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 02 Nov 2024 23:24:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar on Saturday emphasised that friendships are no longer exclusive, especially in the emerging multipolar world, adding that some global partners might be more complicated than others in the world.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar on Saturday emphasised that friendships are no longer exclusive, especially in the emerging multipolar world, adding that some global partners might be more complicated than others in the world as they might not always share the "same culture of mutual respect or ethos of diplomatic etiquette."</p>

<p>At a book launch event in New Delhi, Mr Jaishankar pointed out that what is perceived as freedom by one nation can be viewed as interference by another and emphasised that sensibilities regarding sovereignty and territorial integrity remain crucial in evaluating international partnerships.</p>

<p>"Some friends may also be more complicated than others. They may not always share the same culture of mutual respect or ethos of diplomatic etiquette. We have, from time to time, seen comments on our domestic issues... However, the same courtesies are rarely accorded to the other side. What is freedom for one can apparently become interference from the other. The fact is that sensitivities like sovereignty and territorial integrity will always be a factor in evaluating partners," Mr Jaishankar said.</p>

<p>The minister underlined that New Delhi seeks to be friends with as many countries as possible while positioning itself as a global friend. He said that India's positioning as a <em>"Vishwamitra"</em> is aimed at cultivating friendships across the globe. He explained that there were cultural and historical factors to develop such friendships, including the fact that India was not a "dogmatic civilisation."</p>

<p>He added that India's capability contributes to its self-confidence in engaging with the world and highlighted three transformations under the leadership of Prime Minister Narendra Modi.</p>

<p>Mr Jaishankar referenced the benefits the US, Japan, and Australia have gained from the Quad partnership, suggesting that these nations have navigated historical hesitations. He also mentioned the evolving comprehensive relationships with the UAE and Israel, stating that much of the credit for all these changes in the last decade goes to Prime Minister Narendra Modi's personal interest and leadership.</p>

<p>"India is today positioning itself as a Vishwamitra. We seek to be friends with as many as possible... If you look deeper, there are cultural and historical factors at work as well, including the fact that we are not a dogmatic civilization. There is a capability aspect as well, which accounts for the self-confidence with which we approach the world... The US, Japan, and Australia have benefitted from the Quad. They are examples of overcoming the hesitations of history. UAE and Israel are from a region that is being engaged comprehensively at last. Russia and France are statements of multipolarity, ours as much as theirs," he said.</p>

<p>"If all these types have changed so much in the last decade, I'm sure you would agree with me that much of the credit should go to PM Modi for his personal interest and leadership. Because, remember, at least three of them had not even seen a high-level visit for three decades. In other cases, there was either pressure on us to limit our interaction or, in a few cases, longstanding ideological doubts to overcome," he added.</p>

<p>Mr Jaishankar was speaking at a book launch, "Friends: India's Closest Strategic Partners" by Sreeram Chaulia at the Silver Oak, India Habitat Centre.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/d83eucg_s-jaishankar_625x300_02_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mr Jaishankar said India's capability contributes to its self-confidence in engaging with the world.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/all-about-kamala-harris-age-family-legacy-net-worth-and-her-impact-on-us-politics-6610619]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[All About Kamala Harris: Life, Family, Wealth And Her Impact On US Politics]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/all-about-kamala-harris-age-family-legacy-net-worth-and-her-impact-on-us-politics-6610619]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 02 Nov 2024 22:43:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kamala Devi Harris was born on October 20, 1964, in Oakland, California, to immigrant parents.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">Kamala Harris has cemented her place as a pioneer in American politics acheiveing many firsts in her inspiring journey - first woman, African-American, South Asian and person of Indian origin to hold the office of US Vice President. From her early days as a student leader to her current role as the Democratic presidential nominee, following Joe Biden's endorsement after his withdrawal from the 2024 race, here is a detailed look at her journey.</p>

<h2 dir="ltr"><strong>Kamala Harris: Age and Early Life</strong></h2>

<p dir="ltr">Kamala Devi Harris was born on October 20, 1964, in Oakland, California, to immigrant parents. She is 60.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Kamala Harris grew up in a multicultural environment, influenced by both her African American and Indian heritage. Raised in the diverse Bay Area, Kamala Harris experienced different cultures and communities firsthand, which significantly shaped her worldview and political outlook.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Her mother, <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/shyamala-gopalan-harris-all-about-kamala-harris-mother-who-grew-up-in-india-and-moved-to-us-6398700">Shyamala Gopalan</a>, was a renowned breast cancer researcher from Chennai who emigrated to the US in the 1960s to pursue a PhD at the University of California, Berkeley. Her father, Donald Harris, originally from Jamaica, is an esteemed economist and professor emeritus at Stanford University. Both parents were active in civil rights movements, and their dedication to social justice had a profound influence on Harris's personal and professional life.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Though her parents divorced when she was young, Harris maintained strong ties to both her Jamaican and Indian roots. She often speaks fondly of her summer trips to India, where she was deeply influenced by her maternal grandfather, a retired civil servant and her visits to her grandmother, who advocated for women's rights in her community.</p>

<h2 dir="ltr"><strong>Kamala Harris: Family and Personal Life</strong></h2>

<p dir="ltr">In 2014, Kamala Harris married Doug Emhoff, a lawyer, making him the first-ever Second Gentleman of the United States when Harris became Vice President. Emhoff's two children from his previous marriage, Cole and Ella, have embraced Harris as their stepmother, affectionately referring to her as “Momala.”</p>

<p dir="ltr">Kamala Harris also has a younger sister, Maya Harris, who is a public policy advocate and lawyer. Maya played a significant role in Kamala's political campaigns.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 dir="ltr"><strong>Kamala Harris: Education and Legal Career</strong></h2>

<p dir="ltr">Kamala Harris earned her undergraduate degree from Howard University, where she majored in political science and economics. Afterward, she attended UC Hastings College of the Law, where she obtained her Juris Doctor in 1989.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Her legal career began with a position in the Alameda County District Attorney's Office as a prosecutor. Here, she focused on cases involving violent crime, particularly sexual assault and child abuse. Kamala Harris's rise in the legal world was swift. In 2003, she was elected as the District Attorney of San Francisco, making her the first woman and first African American to hold the position. During her tenure, she introduced several progressive reforms, including a reentry program aimed at reducing recidivism and increasing opportunities for offenders to reintegrate into society.</p>

<p dir="ltr">In 2011, Harris was elected as California's Attorney General, as the first woman and person of colour to hold the position. As AG, Kamala Harris took on major issues like environmental protection, consumer rights and marriage equality, while also contending with criticism over her stance on law enforcement policies.</p>

<h2 dir="ltr"><strong>Kamala Harris: Political Career</strong></h2>

<p dir="ltr">Kamala Harris's political ascent continued when she was elected as the US Senator from California in 2016, succeeding Barbara Boxer. Her time in the Senate gained national attention when, during high-profile hearings, she questioned key figures like then-Attorney General Jeff Sessions and Supreme Court nominee Brett Kavanaugh.</p>

<p dir="ltr">During her Senate term, Kamala Harris worked on critical issues, including immigration reform, healthcare, criminal justice reform and civil rights. She was a strong advocate for the DREAM Act, aimed at protecting young immigrants, and also co-sponsored legislation addressing the opioid epidemic and climate change.</p>

<p dir="ltr">In 2019, Harris launched her campaign for the Democratic presidential nomination. Although her campaign ended before the primaries, her impact on the political stage was undeniable. In August 2020, Harris was chosen by Joe Biden as his running mate, making history as the first woman of South Asian and African American descent to be nominated for Vice President by a major political party.</p>

<p dir="ltr">On January 20, 2021, Kamala Harris was sworn in as the 49th Vice President of the United States, making history once again as the highest-ranking female official in US history. Her vice presidency is marked by her leadership on issues such as economic recovery, voting rights and foreign policy, and she has emerged as a key figure in the Biden administration's efforts to combat the Covid-19 pandemic and rebuild the economy.</p>

<p dir="ltr">For the 2024 US presidential election, Kamala Harris is the Democratic presidential nominee, with Tim Walz as her running mate. They are going head-to-head against Republican candidate Donald Trump and his running mate, JD Vance.</p>

<h2 dir="ltr"><strong>Kamala Harris: Net Worth</strong></h2>

<p dir="ltr">Kamala Harris's net worth is estimated to be around $8 million, combined with her husband Douglas Emhoff's assets, according to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/kylemullins/2024/05/26/heres-how-much-kamala-harris-is-worth/" rel="No follow, no index" target="_blank">Forbes</a>. This amount is up from $7 million in 2021 and is roughly 20 times the median net worth of Americans in their age bracket.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Kamala Harris has also authored two books – ‘Smart on Crime', a reflection of her criminal justice philosophy, and ‘The Truths We Hold', a memoir recounting her life experiences and political journey – which have contributed to her financial standing.</p>

<h2 dir="ltr"><strong>Kamala Harris: Honours and Recognition</strong></h2>

<p dir="ltr">Throughout her career, Kamala Harris has received numerous accolades for her contributions to public service and social justice. She was named in Time magazine's 100 Most Influential People multiple times.</p>

<p dir="ltr">She has been honoured by organisations such as the NAACP (National Association for the Advancement of Colored People), political action committee EMILY's List and The National Women's Hall of Fame for her work in civil rights, women's empowerment and public policy.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Kamala Harris has also received honorary doctorates from institutions like University of Southern California and Howard University in recognition of her achievements.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/hvdvasi_kamala-harris-reuters_625x300_27_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kamala Harris is the Democratic presidential candidate for the 2024 US presidential election.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kemi-badenoch-is-new-chief-of-uks-conservative-party-succeeds-rishi-sunak-6930167]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kemi Badenoch Is New Chief Of UK's Conservative Party, Succeeds Rishi Sunak]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kemi-badenoch-is-new-chief-of-uks-conservative-party-succeeds-rishi-sunak-6930167]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 02 Nov 2024 22:38:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Conservative Party of the UK elected Kemi Badenoch as the new leader of the party on Saturday (local time), Euro News reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Conservative Party of the UK elected Kemi Badenoch as the new leader of the party on Saturday (local time), Euro News reported. It was a historic moment in the political scene of the UK as she became the first Black woman to lead a major political party there.</p>

<p>Kemi Badenoch succeeds former Prime Minister Rishi Sunak, whose leadership saw the Conservatives experience their worst electoral performance since 1832 in the recently held General Elections, where Keir Starmer won from the Labour Party.</p>

<p>Under Rishi Sunak, the party lost over 200 seats, leaving it with just 121 in the House of Commons.</p>

<p>She won against Robert Jenrick in a vote that included nearly 100,000 party members, taking charge as the Conservatives sought to recover from a significant election defeat that ended their 14 years in power, Euro News reported.</p>

<p>The new leader faces the daunting challenge of restoring the party's reputation amid ongoing division, scandal, and economic instability. Kemi Badenoch will need to effectively critique the policies of Labour Prime Minister Keir Starmer, particularly on issues like the economy and immigration, as she aims to return the Conservatives to power by the next election, anticipated in 2029, as reported by Euro News.</p>

<p>During her victory speech in London, Kemi Badenoch stated, "The task that stands before us is tough but simple," outlining her two primary goals for the party: holding the Labour government accountable and preparing for the next election by formulating appealing Conservative policies along with a clear implementation strategy, as reported by Euro News.</p>

<p>Earlier, Kemi Badenoch served as a business secretary in the former Conservative government. Born in London to Nigerian parents, she spent much of her childhood in Nigeria.</p>

<p>At 44, the former software engineer presents herself as a disruptor, advocating for a low-tax, free-market economy and pledging to "rewire, reboot, and reprogram" the British state.</p>

<p>Kemi Badenoch has been a critic of cultural diversity and has faced backlash for her statements suggesting that "not all cultures are equally valid" and that maternity pay is excessive.</p>

<p>The Conservative leadership contest extended over three months, with lawmakers narrowing the field from six candidates to two finalists presented to the party's wider membership. Both finalists align with the right of the party, seeking to reclaim support from Reform UK, a hard-right party led by Nigel Farage that has been drawing voters away from the Conservatives.</p>

<p>However, the Conservatives have also seen a loss of voters to Labour and the centrist Liberal Democrats, leading some party members to express concern that a shift further to the right could alienate a broader electorate.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ea29pn1_kemi-badenoch_625x300_02_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kemi Badenoch won against Robert Jenrick in a vote that included nearly 100,000 party members]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/19-injured-in-hezbollah-rocket-strike-on-building-in-israels-arab-town-of-tira-6930122]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[19 Injured In Rocket Strike On Building In Israel's Arab Town Of Tira]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/19-injured-in-hezbollah-rocket-strike-on-building-in-israels-arab-town-of-tira-6930122]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 02 Nov 2024 22:28:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A missile strike in Israel's Sharon area wounded 19 people, police said early Saturday, after the army reported three projectiles were fired from Lebanon into central Israel.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A missile strike in Israel's Sharon area wounded 19 people, police said early Saturday, after the army reported three projectiles were fired from Lebanon into central Israel.</p>

<p>All 19, four of whom were "in moderate condition", were taken to hospitals for treatment, the Israeli police added.</p>

<p>Israel's Magen David Adom (MDA) emergency medical service earlier said that several people had been wounded in a strike on the central city of Tira, including "a male around 20 with shrapnel injuries".</p>

<p>Videos posted by the Israeli Foreign Ministry on social media showed fire and smoke spilling from a building into the street and emergency responders swarming the site.</p>

<p>"This is the result of a direct hit of a Hezbollah rocket on a building in the Israeli Arab town of Tira, injuring 19 civilians," the ministry said in the post.</p>

<p>"We cannot and will not rest until Hezbollah is dismantled," it added.</p>

<p>The Israeli army said on Telegram that it had intercepted some of the three projectiles fired from Lebanon.</p>

<p>Tira, a predominantly Arab town, is located around 25 kilometres (15 miles) northeast of Tel Aviv, near the border with the occupied West Bank.</p>

<p>The war raging in the Gaza Strip has spread to Lebanon, where Israel has been carrying out air strikes against Hezbollah, an ally of Palestinian group Hamas.</p>

<p>According to Israeli figures, at least 63 people have been killed on the Israeli side since cross-border exchanges with Hezbollah erupted following Hamas's deadly attack on Israel on October 7, 2023.</p>

<p>On Thursday, rocket fire from Lebanon killed seven people in Metula, northern Israel, including four Thai farmers.</p>

<p>Hamas's October attack on Israel resulted in 1,206 deaths, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally of Israeli official figures.</p>

<p>Israel's response has killed 43,259 Palestinians in Gaza, most of them civilians, according to figures from the Hamas-run territory's health ministry, which are considered reliable by the United Nations.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/3k51s8a_attack-in-israel_625x300_02_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Israeli army said it intercepted some of the three projectiles fired from Lebanon]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/big-march-in-bangladesh-for-hindus-other-minorities-amid-rising-attacks-6930056]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Amid Rising Attacks, Big March In Bangladesh For Hindus, Other Minorities]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/big-march-in-bangladesh-for-hindus-other-minorities-amid-rising-attacks-6930056]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 02 Nov 2024 22:16:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hundreds marched in Bangladesh's capital Saturday to demand protections for Hindus and other minorities who say they have suffered violence and threats since the ouster of autocratic premier Sheikh Hasina.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hundreds marched in Bangladesh's capital Saturday to demand protections for Hindus and other minorities who say they have suffered violence and threats since the ouster of autocratic premier Sheikh Hasina.</p>

<p>Hasina's toppling in an August student-led uprising saw a spate of reprisals on Hindus, who were seen as disproportionate supporters of her regime.</p>

<p>The caretaker government that replaced her, led by Nobel laureate Muhammad Yunus, has acknowledged and condemned attacks on Hindus but said in many cases they were motivated by politics rather than religion.</p>

<p>Regular protests in the months since claim that attacks are continuing and have demanded action from Yunus' administration, an "advisory council" tasked with implementing democratic reforms and staging fresh elections.</p>

<p>"It's deeply regrettable that the council of advisors do not acknowledge the sufferings minorities have endured," Hindu civic leader Charu Chandra Das Brahmachari told AFP.</p>

<p>"I have witnessed the atrocities against them -- their temples, businesses, and homes."</p>

<p>Protest organisers have urged the interim government to introduce a law to protect minorities and mandate a minimum share of minority representation in government, among other demands.</p>

<p>Tensions have been inflamed by the filing of sedition charges this week against 19 people who participated in an earlier minority rights rally in the port city of Chittagong.</p>

<p>The group was accused of disrespecting the Bangladeshi national flag by hoisting a saffron flag -- the emblematic colour of the Hindu faith -- to fly above it.</p>

<p>"Framing our leaders with false charges, like sedition, has made us sceptical of the government's intentions," protest member Chiranjan Goswami told AFP.</p>

<p>Hindus are the largest minority faith in mostly Muslim Bangladesh, accounting for around eight percent of the population.</p>

<p>Attacks have also been reported on Sufi shrines, with suspicion falling on Islamists seeking to curb alternative expressions of the Muslim faith.</p>

<p>Saturday's demonstration came a day after 10,000 people attended a similar rally in Chittagong.</p>

<p>Minority leaders have pledged to hold more protests in the coming weeks.</p>

<p>Hasina, 77, fled by helicopter to neighbouring India in August as protesters flooded Dhaka's streets in a dramatic end to her iron-fisted rule.</p>

<p>Her government was accused of widespread human rights abuses, including the extrajudicial killing of thousands of her political opponents during her 15-year rule.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/o10eiafo_bangaldesh-protest_625x300_02_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Minority leaders have pledged to hold more protests in the coming weeks.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/firms-sanctioned-by-us-not-in-violation-of-indian-laws-centre-6930054]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Indian Firms Sanctioned By US Not In Violation Of National Laws: Centre]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/firms-sanctioned-by-us-not-in-violation-of-indian-laws-centre-6930054]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 02 Nov 2024 22:16:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Ministry of External Affairs (MEA) on Saturday reacted to the recent US sanctions imposed on several Indian firms and nationals, with a spokesperson stating that Indian companies have not violated any national laws.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;The Ministry of External Affairs (MEA) on Saturday reacted to the recent US sanctions imposed on several Indian firms and nationals, with a spokesperson stating that Indian companies have not violated any national laws.</p>

<p>The sanctions announced by the US State Department target 19 Indian companies and two individuals accused of allegedly supplying materials and technology to Russia to support its military amid the ongoing war in Ukraine.</p>

<p>Randhir Jaiswal, MEA spokesperson, stated, "We have seen reports on U.S. sanctions. India has a robust legal and regulatory framework on strategic trade and nonproliferation controls. We are also a member of three key multilateral non-proliferation export control regimes-the Wassenaar Arrangement, the Australia Group, and the Missile Technology Control Regime-and have been effectively implementing relevant UNSC sanctions and UNSC resolution 1540 on non-proliferation."</p>

<p>"Our understanding is that the sanctioned transactions and companies are not in violation of Indian laws. Nevertheless, in keeping with India's established non-proliferation credentials, we are working with all the relevant Indian departments and agencies to sensitise Indian companies on applicable export control provisions, as also inform them on new measures being implemented that could impact Indian companies in certain circumstances," he added.</p>

<p>"Regular strategic trade/export control outreach events for Indian industries and stakeholders are being carried out by agencies of the Government of India. We are also in touch with the US authorities to clarify issues." Mr Jaiswal further said.</p>

<p>Indian companies named in the sanctions, such as Shreegee Impex Private Limited maintain they operate within Indian law and claim the sanctions will not impact their business.</p>

<p>Praveen Tyagi, director of Meerut-based Shreegee Impex Private Limited, expressed confusion over the measures, stating, "I don't know why these measures have been imposed on us. But it will not have any impact on us, because we neither import from the US nor export to US."</p>

<p>Rahul Kumar Singh, Director of TSMD Global, remarked, "I can't understand why the US has put the company under sanction. We are a supplier of Automobile parts and Agricultural Implements Automotive. Our company does not have any business from the USA. US sanctions will not have an impact on the company. We supply automobile parts, electronic components and garments to Russian companies. We are not working against the Indian Government and working as per the business norms. We are not doing any illegal things. Our business with Russia will continue as usual."</p>

<p>Manoranjan Sharma, Chief Economist, Infomerics Ratings says that these measures could be an attempt to influence the American elections which are scheduled on November 5 in the United States.</p>

<p>"This is in certain ways, a message to the government and the private sector of these countries, and could strain in a limited way the relations between U.S. and India, which have already been under some strain because of India's alleged low in the case of the Sikh extremist Guru Patwan Singh Pannu. But we see the limited impact of these measures both on Russia and India," said Manoranjan Sharma, Chief Economist, Infomerics Ratings.</p>

<p>"We do not see much impact on India... this will have an extremely limited impact, " Sharma added.</p>

<p>The sanctioned Indian firms, including companies involved in aviation components, are accused of allegedly facilitating the supply of dual-use goods, which are items that can have both civilian and military applications.</p>

<p>The US Says these sanctions are part of its commitment to hold entities accountable for contributing to what it terms Russia's "illegal war" in Ukraine.</p>

<p>This move follows previous sanctions against Russian entities and is part of ongoing efforts to isolate Moscow economically and politically in the wake of its actions in Ukraine.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2019-04/7eeobneg_india-us-trade-relationsgeneralized-system-of-preferences-reuters_625x300_13_April_19.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The US Says these sanctions are part of its commitment to hold entities accountable.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/diwali-is-reminder-that-americans-of-south-asian-descent-have-enriched-us-blinken-6930017]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Diwali Is Reminder South Asian Americans Have Enriched US: Blinken]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/diwali-is-reminder-that-americans-of-south-asian-descent-have-enriched-us-blinken-6930017]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 02 Nov 2024 22:07:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Diwali is a reminder of the many ways Americans of South Asian descent have enriched the United States, Secretary of State Tony Blinken said Friday as he hosted the annual reception of the festival of lights.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Diwali is a reminder of the many ways Americans of South Asian descent have enriched the United States, Secretary of State Tony Blinken said Friday as he hosted the annual reception of the festival of lights with members of the diplomatic community and Indian-Americans.</p>

<p>At its core, Diwali is about the idea that light will push back against darkness, that compassion, curiosity can overcome ignorance, and that everybody has an obligation to care for the other, he said in his remarks at the Diwali reception he hosted at the Department of State.</p>

<p>"I can't think of a more powerful lesson to take to heart in this time for our world than that," Blinken said.</p>

<p>"It is also a reminder of the many ways South Asian culture -- and Americans of South Asian descent -- have enriched our nation, from the novels of Jhumpa Lahiri to the fashion designs of Prabal Gurung. The United States derives so much strength from this diversity, including the truly remarkable public servants -- I can think of one offhand - the Vice President of the United States Kamala Harris, World Bank President Ajay Banga, our very own Deputy Secretary of State Rich Verma," he said.</p>

<p>He said it was 10 years ago that then Secretary John Kerry hosted the first Diwali reception at the State Department, and since then this annual gathering has become a time-honored tradition.</p>

<p>"This year, more than 1 billion Hindus, Buddhists, Jains, and Sikhs around the world are celebrating Diwali, decorating homes in the vibrant patterns of rangoli, hanging garlands of flowers, lighting diyas. And with Diwali falling on October 31st this year, I understand that there are some people in the United States who have even been throwing 'Diwalloween' parties. And if time permits, we will get to one of those," Blinken said amidst laughter.</p>

<p>Diwali holds different meanings and practices for different communities, he said. "But Bengali poet Tagore perhaps captured the spirit of the holiday best when he wrote, and I quote 'faith is the bird that feels the light when the dawn is still dark'," he said.</p>

<p>In his remarks, Deputy Secretary Verma said Diwali festival is so much more than just a holiday. "It is a integral part of our identities, a powerful tradition that carries deep personal meaning and unites families and friends over shared memories, shared experiences, and shared emotions," he said.</p>

<p>He said he could remember his mother and father telling him their experiences of celebrating Diwali in Punjab, in Jalandhar, and the lights and the great sweets and the community that came together.</p>

<p>"I am reminded of my own family's upbringing in Johnstown, Pennsylvania, where we also celebrated Diwali, enjoying traditional customs in this small town that welcomed us with sweets and colours and so much more. People have said there is Keeping Up with the Kardashians, and you had the 'Jalebis of Johnstown'," Verma said.</p>

<p>India's Ambassador to the US Vinay Mohan Kwatra was also present on the occasion.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/tlr2l40g_antony-blinken_625x300_27_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Diwali is a reminder of the many ways South Asian Americans have enriched the US, Blinken said]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-pits-americans-against-one-another-us-deserves-better-kamala-harris-6929974]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Pits Americans Against One Another, US Deserves Better: Harris]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-pits-americans-against-one-another-us-deserves-better-kamala-harris-6929974]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 02 Nov 2024 21:56:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA["America deserves better than what Donald Trump is offering. America deserves a president who understands our role and responsibility to our people and to the rest of the world to be a model," she said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump pits Americans against one another, his Democratic rival and Vice President Kamala Harris alleged Friday and asserted her pledge to pursue common sense solutions and to be a president for all Americans.</p>

<p>"America deserves better than what Donald Trump is offering. America deserves a president who understands our role and responsibility to our people and to the rest of the world to be a model," she said.</p>

<p>Campaigning in the presidential elections entered the last few days with both Harris and Trump making closing arguments before voters in the key swing states.</p>

<p>"As you have heard me say many a times, my pledge to the American people is to pursue common sense solutions, to listen to those, even those who disagree with me, to listen to experts, and to be a president for all Americans," Harris told reporters in Wisconsin.</p>

<p>"Donald Trump's closing argument is very different. He pits Americans against one another. He spends full time having Americans point their fingers at one another. And he spends a considerable amount of time plotting his revenge on his political opponents," she said.</p>

<p>She said that as of last night, Trump has indicated that the person who would be in charge of healthcare for Americans people is someone who has "routinely promoted junk science and crazy conspiracy theories", and who once expressed support for a national abortion ban. "And who is the exact last person in America who should be setting health care policy for America's families and children."</p>

<p>Harris said Trump is increasingly someone who considers his political opponents his enemy, is permanently out for revenge, and is increasingly "unstable and unhinged". "'His enemies list has grown longer, his rhetoric has grown more extreme, and he is even less focused than before on the needs and the concerns and the challenges facing the American people," she said.</p>

<p>"I have also thought a lot about what this means in terms of our standing in the world. As vice president, I have represented the United States of America around the world, and what I know is that when we walk in those rooms representing the United States of America, we have the earned and self-appointed authority to then talk about the importance of democracy, the importance of rule of law. And as a result, people around the world who are fighting for freedom and opportunity hold us up as a model," she said.</p>

<p>Responding to a question, Harris said there is a real contrast in this race when one looks at who stands for democracy and democratic principles and who does not. "Donald Trump is talking about an enemies list... He talks in a way that suggests that there should be retribution and severe consequences just because people disagree with him," she said.</p>

<p>"My point is very clear. I believe in our democracy. Democracies are complicated, in a wonderful way, because we like debate. We accept and receive differences of opinion, and we work them out. One of the reasons I am going to have a Republican in my Cabinet is because I want different views. I enjoy and benefit from diverse views, from different perspectives that allow me to make the best decisions I can make," she said.</p>

<p>"That's a big difference between me and Donald Trump, and that's the big difference between someone who truly is a leader and someone who is in it for themselves and wants unchecked power," Harris said.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/lvclrp8k_kamala-harris_625x300_30_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Harris said Trump is increasingly someone who considers his political opponents his enemy]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>