<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Dec 2024 22:14:55 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nepal-joins-chinas-belt-and-road-initiative-raises-concerns-for-new-delhi-7173147]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Nepal Joins China's Belt And Road Initiative, Raises Concerns For New Delhi]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nepal-joins-chinas-belt-and-road-initiative-raises-concerns-for-new-delhi-7173147]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Dec 2024 22:03:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A significant agreement was signed in Beijing today paving the way for China to make major inroads in Nepal.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A significant agreement was signed in Beijing today paving the way for China to make major inroads in Nepal. Seven years after an initial understanding for Kathmandu to be part of Beijing's Belt and Road Initiative or BRI, today's agreement lays the framework of how projects will be executed.</p>

<p>Breaking tradition of making New Delhi a Nepalese prime minister's first port of call after election results, KP Sharma Oli chose to visit Beijing instead. He has been in China since Monday to work closely with Xi Jinping and finalise the deal.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/4bccifok_nepal-china-bilateral-talks_625x300_04_December_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>China and Nepal have "signed the framework for Belt and Road Cooperation today," Nepal's foreign office said in a post on X today, but shared no further details.</p>

<p>Sources familiar with the agreement have said that today's deal means both countries will not plan and coordinate the details of each project. It also paves the way for China to fund these projects and how exactly each project would be financed by Beijing.</p>

<blockquote align="center" class="twitter-tweet" data-dnt="true">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">The Government of Nepal and the Government of the People's Republic of China signed the Framework for Belt and Road Cooperation today. <a href="https://t.co/6oTlDvTzIe">pic.twitter.com/6oTlDvTzIe</a></p>
— MOFA of Nepal ?? (@MofaNepal) <a href="https://twitter.com/MofaNepal/status/1864210839940812810?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 4, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>In 2017, Nepal had agreed in-principle to be part of China's mega Belt and Road project - a massive network of roads, transport corridors, airports, and rail lines connecting China with the rest of Asia, Europe and beyond. However, no progress was made in the last seven years because of the lack of a proper framework of executing them. Kathmandu also struggled to find political consensus on the issue. That now seems to have been addressed with today's pact.</p>

<p>China's Belt and Road Initiative, though ambitious, has been a red flag for many countries due to Beijing's suspicious dealings and ulterior motives. Several countries have fallen in a debt trap, often called China's "debt diplomacy" wherein China builds a mega project on credit in a smaller country in terms of economy, and when the country cannot pay back the loan or interest, Beijing either takes over the project for a lifetime or cuts a deal to forward its expansionist agenda.</p>

<p>China's Belt and Road Initiative has also had a history of ignoring the national security concerns and violating the sovereignty of other nations.</p>

<p>Several leaders in Nepal's government and opposition are concerned over debt concerns mounting in an already-stretched economy. Even within Prime Minister Oli's government, there is fierce debate over the potential risks in mega projects executed by China. Nepal Congress, which is a key ally of PM Oli's party, has vehemently opposed any projects funded by Chinese loans.</p>

<p>China had funded the airport project in Pokhra - Nepal's second-largest city - by loaning more than $200 million. Nepal went ahead with the project despite India raising serious concerns and opened the airport last year.</p>

<p>But the airport has had to deal with losses due to lack of international flights. This can partially be due to a slender demand for airlines, but also due to India's refusal to planes using its airspace to do so.</p>

<p>Pokhra, located around 120 kilometers from Kathmandu, is less than 20 minutes from the India border by commercial flight. India had to shut its airspace out of a national security compulsion because Kathmandu ignored New Delhi's concerns that China may use the airport to station its military aircraft and helicopters - a massive national security threat for New Delhi.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/3avksduc_nepal-pm-kp-sharma-oli-meets-xi-jinping-twitter_625x300_04_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Nepal's Prime Minister KP Sharma Oli met Chinese President Xi Jinping in Beijing.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/108-metre-chunri-offered-to-temple-as-nepal-city-celebrates-ram-sita-wedding-7173084]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[108 Metre "Chunri" Offered To Temple As Nepal City Celebrates Ram-Sita Wedding]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/108-metre-chunri-offered-to-temple-as-nepal-city-celebrates-ram-sita-wedding-7173084]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Dec 2024 21:54:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Chunri measuring 108 meters has been offered to the Janaki Temple of Nepal by a trust from Surat (Gujarat, India) on the occasion of 'Bibah Panchami', marking the wedding of Lord Ram with Goddess Sita.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Chunri measuring 108 meters has been offered to the Janaki Temple of Nepal by a trust from Surat (Gujarat, India) on the occasion of 'Bibah Panchami', marking the wedding of Lord Ram with Goddess Sita.</p>

<p>The event set for Friday is the first 'Bibah Panchami' to be held in the city after the Pran Pratishtha at Ram Temple in Ayodhya, Uttar Pradesh.</p>

<p>Stretching far and wide the red-coloured Chunri which was sent by Jin Mata Trust has toured the ancient historic city of Janakpur.</p>

<p>"Today for the first time from Surat (Gujarat, India) Jin Mata Trust has sent 108 meters long Chunri (shawl) to Janakpur. It is the first time that it has been brought to Janakpur, the People of Janakpur are elated that it can't be explained in words and they extended their full support. People took part in the Shobha Yatra and we want to see this continued further with devotees sending it to Janaki Temple and we offer it to the goddess," Manoj Rungata, Chairman of Sitaram Gaushala who facilitated in bringing the Chunri to Janakpur told ANI.</p>

<p>Janakpur, the paternal home of Hindu Goddess Sita is filled with festivity and grandeur ahead of the 'Bibah Panchami' event scheduled for Friday, this week.</p>

<p>This will be the first Bibah Panchami celebrations to be held after the Pranpratistha of Ram Mandir in Ayodhya earlier this year. Every year, on the fifth day of the Margashirsha month, devotees celebrate Bibah Panchami, the day of the divine wedding.</p>

<p>"On the occasion of Bibah Panchami 2081 (2024), a Chunri measuring 108 meters has been offered to Mata Janaki after a de-tour of the Janakpur city. Jin Mata (Trust) has till now offered Chunri in over 475 Bhagwati temples. Today the 476th Chunri that came via the Sitaram Gaushala has been offered to Mata Janaki on the occasion of Bibah Panchami after touring around the city," Nirmal Chaudhary, Chairman of Marwadi Sewa Samiti told ANI.</p>

<p>On Tuesday the Barat of Lord Ram arrived in Janakpur with great pomp and show. Around 500 devotees from Ayodhya, who have come from various corners of India, arrived at Janakpur Dham as baratis at the wedding of Lord Ram.</p>

<p>Forty Vedic Brahmins from Tirupati will be performing the marriage of Sita-Ram in Janakpur Dham. These Vedic Brahmins will directly reach Janakpur to conduct the marriage rituals.</p>

<p>According to the scriptures, Lord Ram, son of King Dasharath of Ayodhya married Goddess Sita, daughter of King Janak of Janakpurdham during the Treta epoch. The marriage was solemnized in Janakpurdham.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/85liros8_janaki-temple-nepal_625x300_04_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Janakpur is the paternal home of Hindu Goddess Sita (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/up-man-given-death-penalty-in-saudi-arabia-on-drug-charges-family-pleads-for-mercy-7172972]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UP Man Given Death Penalty In Saudi On Drug Charges, Family Pleads For Mercy]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/up-man-given-death-penalty-in-saudi-arabia-on-drug-charges-family-pleads-for-mercy-7172972]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Dec 2024 21:39:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A court in Saudi Arabia has sentenced a man from Meerut in Uttar Pradesh to death on charges of drug trafficking, triggering panic and despair among his family members who have pleaded for clemency.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p>

<p>A court in Saudi Arabia has sentenced a man from Meerut in Uttar Pradesh to death on charges of drug trafficking, triggering panic and despair among his family members who have pleaded for clemency.</p>

<p>Meerut Senior Superintendent of Police (SSP) Vipin Tada on Wednesday confirmed receiving a letter in this regard from the Indian consulate in Saudi Arabia via the district administration.</p>

<p>"The letter said Zaid Junaid, a resident of Rachauti village under the Mundali police station area, has been sentenced to death by a court in Mecca for drug smuggling. His family members have been informed about the option of filing a mercy plea," the SSP said.</p>

<p>A notice was also pasted at the entrance of the family house to ensure they were aware of the situation.</p>

<p>Zaid's father Zubair, a farmer, and mother Rehana became inconsolable on hearing the news.</p>

<p>His elder brother Suhail said, "My father has already requested the Indian government to file a mercy plea with the Saudi authorities. The application was submitted on Tuesday." Aged around 35 and the second of seven brothers, Zaid moved to Saudi Arabia in 2018 to work as a driver for a company.</p>

<p>Initially employed by one firm, he later joined Al-Zafar Company, his family members said.</p>

<p>His troubles began when his vehicle was stolen, and was recovered by Saudi police three days later. Subsequently, the vehicle got damaged in a road accident, leading his employer to file a lawsuit to recover the costs.</p>

<p>Unable to bear the financial burden, Zaid left the company and began working as the personal driver for a Saudi police officer, the family said.</p>

<p>However, three months into his new job, Zaid was allegedly implicated in a drug smuggling case after police claimed to have found 700 gm of narcotics from the vehicle he was driving, the family said.</p>

<p>He was arrested on January 15, 2023, and has been imprisoned at the Jeddah Central Jail since then.</p>

<p>"My brother has been framed. He was just doing his job as a driver. We hope the Indian government intervenes and saves his life," Suhail said.</p>

<p>Zaid's father Zubair said, "We've never faced such trouble before. All we want now is Zaid to return alive." Another elder brother of Zaid, Naeem Khan Faisal, who also works as a driver in Saudi Arabia, is in touch with the family to the coordinate efforts for his release.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/jqjk6bh_jail-generic_625x300_21_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Zaid Junaid's father Zubair said, "We've never faced such trouble before. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/united-healthcare-ceo-brian-thompson-shot-dead-in-new-york-gunman-at-large-7172850]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[United Healthcare CEO Brian Thompson Shot Dead In New York, Gunman At Large]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/united-healthcare-ceo-brian-thompson-shot-dead-in-new-york-gunman-at-large-7172850]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Dec 2024 21:22:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Brian Thompson, 50, was shot in Manhattan just before 7 am at a hotel. The shooter fled the scene of the crime after the attack.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Brian Thompson, the CEO of one of the largest health insurance companies, UnitedHealthcare, was fatally shot in the chest in New York on Wednesday according to US media reports.</p>

<p>According to the New York Times, Thompson, 50, was shot in Manhattan just before 7 am at a hotel. The shooter fled the scene of the crime after the attack. Thompson was rushed to the hospital in an unconscious and unresponsive state but was pronounced dead.</p>

<p>A spokesperson for the New York Hilton Midtown said, "We are deeply saddened by this morning's events in the area and our thoughts are with all affected by the tragedy. Additional questions should be directed to the New York Police Department."</p>

<p>The company was scheduled to hold its investor day but cancelled it after reports of the shooting emerged.</p>

<p>"I'm afraid that we - some of you may know we're dealing with a very serious medical situation with one of our team members," UnitedHealth Group staff said. "And as a result, I'm afraid we're going to have to bring to a close the event today, which I'm sure you'll understand."</p>

<p>As per a report in CNBC, the suspect was a white male, wearing black hoodie, black pants and black sneakers with a white trim and a gray backpack. The suspect is also described as possessing a firearm with a silencer.</p>

<p>The investigation is ongoing and no arrests have been made.</p>

<p>The UnitedHealth Group ranks 5th on Fortune 500 and this news has left many in the healthcare and business communities shocked.</p>

<p>Brian Thompson had been the CEO of UnitedHealthcare since April 2021. Before this he led their government programs including Medicare &amp; Retirement and Community &amp; State divisions.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/49kchst_brian-thompson-reuters_625x300_04_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Brian Thompson, the CEO of UnitedHealthcare, was fatally shot in the chest in New York]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/muhammad-yunus-involved-in-genocide-sheikh-hasina-in-1st-public-address-7172709]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Muhammad Yunus Involved In Genocide": Sheikh Hasina In 1st Public Address]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/muhammad-yunus-involved-in-genocide-sheikh-hasina-in-1st-public-address-7172709]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Dec 2024 21:03:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ousted Bangladesh Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina has mounted a stinging attack on the country's interim leader Muhammad Yunus over alleged persecution of minorities.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ousted Bangladesh Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina has mounted a stinging attack on the country's interim leader Muhammad Yunus over alleged persecution of minorities.</p>

<p>In a virtual address at an event in New York, Sheikh Hasina accused Muhammad Yunus of perpetrating "genocide" and failing to protect minorities including Hindus. She also claimed that there were plans to assassinate her and her sister Sheikh Rehana just like their father Sheikh Mujibur Rahman.</p>

<p>Mujibur Rahman was assassinated in 1975.</p>

<p>It was Sheikh Hasina's first public address after taking shelter in India following her resignation in August in the face of massive anti-government protests, though she had commented on the overall situation in Bangladesh.</p>

<p>"The armed protestors were directed towards Ganabhaban. If the security guards opened fire, many lives would have been lost. It was a matter of 25-30 minutes, and I was forced to leave. I told them [guards] not to fire no matter what happened," she said referring to the storming of her official residence in Dhaka on August 5.</p>

<p>"Today, I am being accused of genocide. In reality, Yunus has been involved in genocide in a meticulously designed manner. The masterminds -- the student coordinators and Yunus -- are behind this genocide," she said at the event on Sunday.</p>

<p>Sheikh Hasina said the current ruling dispensation in Dhaka failed to protect the minorities.</p>

<p>"Hindus, Buddhists, Christians -- no one has been spared. Eleven churches have been razed, temples and Buddhist shrines have been broken. When the Hindus protested, the Iskcon leader was arrested," she said in an oblique reference to the arrest of Hindu monk Chinmoy Krishna Das.</p>

<p>"What is this persecution of minorities for? Why are they being ruthlessly persecuted and attacked?" she said.</p>

<p>"People no longer have the right to justice... I never even got the time to resign," she said speaking in Bengali.</p>

<p>Sheikh Hasina said she left Bangladesh in August with an aim to stop the violence, but that did not happen.</p>

<p>The relations between India and Bangladesh came under strain after the interim government headed by Muhammad Yunus came to power. India has been expressing concerns over attacks on minorities, especially Hindus, in that country.</p>

<p>Sheikh Hasina has been staying in India since she left Bangladesh following massive anti-government protests in July and August.</p>

<p>In her speech at the event hosted to mark Bangladesh's 'Vijay Diwas', the Awami League leader also alleged that there was a plot to assassinate her.</p>

<p>"When people were dying indiscriminately, I decided I should leave," she said.</p>

<p>There has been a spate of attacks on minorities including on the Hindu community in Bangladesh in the last few months.</p>

<p>India last week said the interim government in Bangladesh must live up to its responsibility of protecting all minorities as it expressed serious concern over the "surge" of extremist rhetoric and increasing incidents of violence against Hindus.</p>

<p>New Delhi also hoped that the case relating to Das, arrested on a charge of sedition, would be dealt with in a just, fair and transparent manner.</p>

<p>"Our position on the matter is very clear -- the interim government must live up to its responsibility of protecting all minorities," MEA spokesperson Randhir Jaiswal said at his weekly media briefing on Friday.</p>

<p>"We are concerned at the surge of extremist rhetoric, increasing incidents of violence and provocation. These developments cannot be dismissed only as media exaggeration. We once again call upon Bangladesh to take all steps for the protection of minorities," he added.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/pp02ivl_sheikh-hasina-ians_625x300_28_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[It was Sheikh Hasina's first public address after taking shelter in India (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chinese-man-trapped-in-thai-well-for-three-days-as-villagers-mistake-his-cries-for-ghost-sounds-7172638]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Man Trapped In Well For 3 Days As Villagers Mistake Cries For Ghost Sounds]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chinese-man-trapped-in-thai-well-for-three-days-as-villagers-mistake-his-cries-for-ghost-sounds-7172638]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Dec 2024 20:53:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[It wasn't until police dispatched rescue personnel to the forest that they heard a voice responding to their calls.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a bizarre incident near the Thailand-Myanmar border, a Chinese man was trapped in an abandoned well for three days. Villagers had heard strange cries coming from a nearby forest, but mistook them for ghostly sounds, according to Thai media reports. It wasn't until police dispatched rescue personnel to the forest that they heard a voice responding to their calls. The crew located the source of the voice and found 22-year-old Liu Chuanyi at the bottom of a 12-metre-deep well, <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.independent.co.uk/asia/china/thailand-chinese-tourist-abandoned-well-rescue-b2658630.html">Independent</a></em> reported.&nbsp;The rescue operation lasted 30 minutes.</p>

<p>Mr Chuanyi was found in a weakened state and had sustained serious injuries, including a fractured wrist, cerebral concussion, and bruises, after being trapped without food or water for three days and nights. He was rescued and taken to the hospital for medical attention.</p>

<p>According to Mr Chuanyi, he strategically shouted for help once every hour, conserving his energy during his three-day ordeal. Meanwhile, nearby villagers reported hearing strange cries, which they attributed to paranormal activity. As a result, they avoided venturing outside after dark and didn't investigate the noise further.</p>

<p>Authorities believe that Mr. Liu accidentally fell into the well while attempting to navigate his way out of the forest. The circumstances surrounding Mr Liu's presence at the Thailand-Myanmar border remain a mystery, and authorities have reached out to the immigration department to investigate how he ended up in the area. In the meantime, local authorities are taking proactive measures to prevent similar incidents by sealing the well with a cover, ensuring the area is safer for everyone.</p>

<p>The incident has sparked widespread attention on Chinese social media, with many users sharing and discussing the harrowing story.&nbsp;</p>

<p>One user wrote, "A Chinese man shouting for help in the middle of nowhere? Of course, the locals can't understand the language and might think it was a wizard uttering spells."</p>

<p>Another commented, "Kudos to his strength and stamina. Struggling for three days and nights but still yelling; this guy is truly impressive."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/jjjd28lg_well_625x300_04_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[He was rescued and taken to the hospital for medical attention.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/as-french-pm-michel-barnier-faces-no-confidence-vote-all-you-need-to-know-7172566]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[French PM Michel Barnier Faces No Confidence Vote. All You Need To Know]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/as-french-pm-michel-barnier-faces-no-confidence-vote-all-you-need-to-know-7172566]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Dec 2024 20:43:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[France is facing a critical moment as lawmakers vote on a no-confidence motion against Prime Minister Michel Barnier's government. This vote is likely to have significant implications for the country's political and economic stability.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<ol class="CetSht_ol">
	<li class="CetSht_li"><big><strong>No-Confidence Vote:</strong></big> French Prime Minister Michel Barnier faces a critical no-confidence vote on Wednesday, just three months after his appointment.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li"><big><strong>Reason For The Vote:</strong></big> Barnier's budget bill sought to slow down France's deficit through tax rises and spending cuts. The budget remained unacceptable to the opposition but he used a special procedure - Article 49.3 to push it. "I don't think French people will forgive us for choosing party interests over the future of the country," he told MPs while clarifying the reasons for his decisions.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li"><big><strong>Chances Of Survival:</strong></big> Despite Barnier's optimism, opposition parties on the left and right are expected to unite and remove him from office. When asked if there was a chance his government could survive the vote, Barnier replied, "I want this and it is possible. I think it is possible that there is this reflex of responsibility where beyond political differences, divergences, the normal contradictions in a democracy we tell ourselves that there is a higher interest."</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li"><big><strong>Political Instability:</strong></big> France has been experiencing political uncertainty since summer elections produced a divided parliament, and Barnier's ousting could increase pressure on President Emmanuel Macron.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li"><big><strong>Consequences:</strong></big> If Barnier loses the vote, he will remain caretaker prime minister until Macron announces a new government, a process that could take weeks. However, Barnier stressed how important it is to maintain government continuity especially considering France's current economic challenges.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li"><strong><big>Historic Significance:</big></strong> Barnier is expected to become the shortest-lived prime minister in France's Fifth Republic and it would be the first successful no-confidence vote since Georges Pompidou's government in 1962 when Charles de Gaulle was the president.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li"><big><strong>Macron's Next Move:</strong></big> Macron has reportedly begun considering his pick for the next prime minister, but the process could take weeks. Besides that, he has no plans to resign and has made clear that he would "honour [the trust of the French people]... until the very last second of my term to serve the country."</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li"><big><strong>Impact on the French Economy:</strong></big> Political instability could impact the French economy in many ways now since the European Union pressures France to reduce its debt. If he is voted out of office, there will be no budget for 2025 and emergency measures will be taken to keep the country solvent.<br />
	&nbsp;</li>
</ol>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/p06fhas8_michel-barnier-reuters_625x300_04_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[French Prime Minister Michel Barnier faces a critical no-confidence vote.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/unitedhealthcare-ceo-brian-thompson-shot-dead-in-manhattan-report-7172420]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UnitedHealthcare CEO Brian Thompson Shot Dead In Manhattan: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/unitedhealthcare-ceo-brian-thompson-shot-dead-in-manhattan-report-7172420]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Dec 2024 20:23:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Brian Thompson, the CEO of UnitedHealth's insurance unit, was fatally shot in the chest on Wednesday morning outside the Hilton hotel in midtown Manhattan, the NY Post and Bloomberg reported, citing police sources.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Brian Thompson, the CEO of UnitedHealth's insurance unit, was fatally shot in the chest on Wednesday morning outside the Hilton hotel in midtown Manhattan, the NY Post and Bloomberg reported, citing police sources.</p>

<p>UnitedHealth did not immediately respond to a request for comment. The company canceled the remainder of an investor event in Manhattan that had just kicked off.</p>

<p>"We're dealing with a very serious medical situation with one of our team members, and as a result, I'm afraid we're going to have to bring to a close the event today," UnitedHealth CEO Andrew Witty said.</p>

<p>The NYPD deputy commissioner's office said a man was shot in front of the Hilton, located at 1335 6th Avenue in the Midtown North Precinct. He was brought to Mount Sinai West Hospital less than a mile away in critical condition, and was later pronounced dead, the NYPD said.</p>

<p>Investigators told CNN that the gunman was waiting in the area for some time before Thompson's arrival. Reuters has not independently verified that information.</p>

<p>There are no arrests at this time, and the investigation is active and ongoing. The identification of the victim is pending proper family notification, the department said.</p>

<p>Brian Thompson was named UnitedHealthcare CEO in April 2021, and started at the company in 2004, working in several departments, according to the company's web site.</p>

<p>UnitedHealthcare is a unit of UnitedHealth Group.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/vs11kt78_brian-thompson_625x300_04_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[UnitedHealthcare is a unit of UnitedHealth Group. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-eyes-ron-desantis-for-pentagon-amid-reports-of-misconduct-by-pete-hegseth-7171753]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Eyes Ron DeSantis For Pentagon Amid Reports Of Misconduct By Hegseth]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-eyes-ron-desantis-for-pentagon-amid-reports-of-misconduct-by-pete-hegseth-7171753]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Dec 2024 18:46:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[According to The New Yorker, Hegseth in an inebriated condition, chanted "Kill All Muslims! Kill All Muslims!" at a Veterans group event in 2015.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>President-elect Donald Trump is reportedly considering replacing Pete Hegseth with Florida Gov. Ron DeSantis for the Pentagon's head, reports the Wall Street Journal, amid reports and doubts about his current nominee's personal life.</p>

<p>His views on certain issues may raise concerns. For instance, Hegseth opposes women serving in combat roles, arguing it lowers military standards and effectiveness. "Women shouldn't be in combat at all. They're life-givers, not life-takers. I know a lot of wonderful soldiers, female soldiers, who have served, who are great. But they shouldn't be in my infantry battalion," he told Ben Shapiro, a conservative political commentator in an interview.</p>

<p>He supports troops accused or convicted of war crimes and has advocated for their pardon. He also wants to fire senior officers who support "woke policies".</p>

<p>There has been increasing disquiet and scrutiny surrounding Hegseth's sexual assault allegations and drunken public behavior among senators.</p>

<p>Regardless, Hegseth posted this on X.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">I'm doing this for the warfighters, not the warmongers.<br />
<br />
The Left is afraid of disrupters and change agents. They are afraid of <a href="https://twitter.com/realDonaldTrump?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@realDonaldTrump</a>—and me. So they smear w/ fake, anonymous sources &amp; BS stories. They don't want truth.<br />
<br />
Our warriors never back down, &amp; neither will I. <a href="https://t.co/nDQ5aUlv7i">pic.twitter.com/nDQ5aUlv7i</a></p>
— Pete Hegseth (@PeteHegseth) <a href="https://twitter.com/PeteHegseth/status/1864289115149127942?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 4, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>Not only this but a general sense of misconduct allegations have also been floating for the former Fox News anchor.</p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.newyorker.com/news/news-desk/pete-hegseths-secret-history" rel="noindex,nofollow">The New Yorker</a>, Hegseth in an inebriated condition, chanted "Kill All Muslims! Kill All Muslims!" at a Veterans group event in 2015.</p>

<p>However, his attorney Tim Parlatore said, "We're not going to comment on outlandish claims laundered through The New Yorker by a petty and jealous disgruntled former associate of Mr. Hegseth's. Get back to us when you try your first attempt at actual journalism", in response to the allegations by The New Yorker.</p>

<p>In addition to his alleged Islamophobic comments, he has also been shadowed by a secret financial settlement to a woman who accused him of rape in 2017, although he dismissed the claims citing the incident as consensual.</p>

<p>Two veteran non-profit groups - Veterans for Freedom and Concerned Veterans for America have further accused him of multiple allegations including financial mismanagement, sexual impropriety and personal misconduct. He was forced to step down from the organisation because of these concerns.</p>

<p>Hegseth's former colleague at Fox News said, "He had a kind of what-happens-in-Vegas-stays-in-Vegas kind of attitude, while his wife and kids were in Minnesota. He was a huge drinker. I can't say if he had a problem, but he was very handsy with women, too. I've certainly seen him drunk."</p>

<p>With the allegations surfacing with the whistleblower report, Senate Republicans are not comfortable supporting his bid as the leader of the Pentagon.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/nppt01eo_pete-hegseth-afp_625x300_04_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[There has been increasing disquiet and scrutiny surrounding Hegseth's sexual assault allegations]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-advances-in-east-ukraine-zelensky-calls-for-urgent-reinforcements-7171568]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russia Advances In East Ukraine, Zelensky Calls For Urgent Reinforcements]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-advances-in-east-ukraine-zelensky-calls-for-urgent-reinforcements-7171568]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Dec 2024 18:26:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[President Volodymyr Zelensky called on Tuesday for major reinforcement of sectors in eastern Ukraine of the 1,000-km (600-mile) front line, where Russian forces have made consistent gains in recent months.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>President Volodymyr Zelensky called on Tuesday for major reinforcement of sectors in eastern Ukraine of the 1,000-km (600-mile) front line, where Russian forces have made consistent gains in recent months.</p>

<p>Zelensky issued his appeal as Russia's Defence Ministry said its troops had captured two new front-line villages -- one in Donetsk region, the main focus of the 33-month-old war, the other further south in Zaporizhzhia region.</p>

<p>The president was speaking in his nightly video address after a discussion with Ukraine's top commander, Oleksandr Syrskyi. He said much depended on Ukraine's Western allies providing vital weaponry in a timely manner.</p>

<p>"The Donetsk directions require significant reinforcement. This particularly involves the supply of weapons from our partners," Zelenskiy said.</p>

<p>"It's a direct relationship: The greater our army's firepower and technological capabilities, the more we can destroy Russia's offensive potential and protect the lives of our soldiers."</p>

<p>The key, he said, was to boost Ukraine's long-range capabilities, partly by boosting domestic weapons production.</p>

<p>The United States, the biggest supplier of military aid to Ukraine, announced its latest military aid package on Monday, valued at some $725 million. But Ukraine is concerned about the continued flow of weapons under President-elect Donald Trump, who has pledged to put a quick end to the war.</p>

<p>Analysts and war bloggers say that Russian forces in the east are advancing at the fastest rate since the early days of the February 2022 invasion.</p>

<p>Russia's Defence Ministry said its forces had captured the village of Romanivka, south of the embattled town of Kurakhove in Donetsk region. It also said Moscow's forces took control of Novodarivka, just over the border in Zaporizhzhia region.</p>

<p>The Ukrainian military's general staff said Russian forces had launched 38 attacks near Kurakhove, but made no mention of Romanivka. It said nothing about Novodarivka falling into Russian hands, but mentioned the village as one of the areas coming under Russian attack.</p>

<p>Zelenskiy, in a post on his Telegram account, quoted commander Syrskyi as saying conditions were difficult around Kurakhove and Pokrovsk, another target of Russian advances farther north.</p>

<p>But he also spoke of "quite good" results in defending Zaporizhzhia region.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/eef9k824_ukraine-soldiers-reuters_625x300_04_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Soldiers of 24th mechanized brigade load cartridges to a machine gun amid Russia's attack on Ukraine]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/babies-in-spain-develop-werewolf-syndrome-after-parents-use-hair-loss-drug-report-7171421]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Spanish Babies Develop 'Werewolf Syndrome' After Parents Use Hair-Loss Drug]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/babies-in-spain-develop-werewolf-syndrome-after-parents-use-hair-loss-drug-report-7171421]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Dec 2024 18:08:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hypertrichosis, commonly referred to as "Werewolf Syndrome," is a rare condition characterized by excessive hair growth in unusual areas of the body.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A recent report from the Navarra Pharmacovigilance Center in Spain has revealed a shocking trend among infants. Eleven cases of hypertrichosis, also known as "werewolf syndrome," have been detected in babies across Spain since last year, the <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/12/03/world-news/infants-develop-werewolf-syndrome-after-parents-take-hair-loss-drug-report/">New York Post</a></em> reported.&nbsp;The investigation found that caregivers of the infants had used a popular over-the-counter hair-loss treatment containing 5% topical minoxidil. It is believed that the minoxidil was transferred to the babies through skin contact or accidental ingestion. Minoxidil is a medication approved by the U.S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA) that can be sold without a prescription to adults experiencing age-related hair loss.</p>

<p>Notably, Hypertrichosis, commonly referred to as "Werewolf Syndrome," is a rare condition characterized by excessive hair growth in unusual areas of the body. This condition causes fine hair, measuring up to 5cm in length, to grow on the face, arms, and other parts of the body. Currently, there is no cure for hypertrichosis. Individuals affected by this condition must rely on regular hair removal methods, such as shaving and waxing, to manage their symptoms.</p>

<p>A notable case in 2023 brought attention to "werewolf syndrome" after a breastfeeding infant developed excessive hair growth across their body over two months. An investigation by health officials revealed that the father was using a topical 5% minoxidil solution to treat androgenic alopecia.</p>

<p>Upon discontinuing the minoxidil treatment, the child's symptoms completely reversed. Similarly, in all reported cases in Spain, the babies' excessive hair growth subsided once their caregivers stopped using minoxidil solutions.</p>

<p>In a separate case, a two-year-old girl in Malaysia was diagnosed with a rare congenital form of hypertrichosis. The girl's condition was distinct from the cases linked to environmental exposure to minoxidil.</p>

<p>Health experts have cautioned that minoxidil can be hazardous to infants' health and may lead to the development of hypertrichosis. The European Pharmacovigilance Risk Assessment Committee has also highlighted the risks associated with minoxidil exposure in infants.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/k9diphq8_baby_625x300_04_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Health experts have cautioned that minoxidil can be hazardous to infants' health.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/bangladesh-is-sitting-on-a-powder-keg-7171051]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: Bangladesh Is Sitting On A Powder Keg]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/bangladesh-is-sitting-on-a-powder-keg-7171051]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Dec 2024 17:23:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[According to a report by the Bangladesh branch of the Berlin-based human rights group Transparency International, minorities have been targeted in more than 2,000 incidents of violence since Hasina was forced to flee the country.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/1tb27fp8_bangladesh_625x300_01_December_24.jpeg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Relations between India and Bangladesh have continued to plummet ever since then-Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina stepped down in August following weeks of protests led by student groups. When Nobel laureate and microfinance pioneer Muhammad Yunus was selected as the interim chief advisor of Bangladesh, the world had pinned high hopes on the country, which had been ravaged by months of bloody violence.</p>

<p>Contrary to expectations, communal forces have been given a free hand in Bangladesh, with minorities being killed, their houses, places of worship, and businesses attacked and destroyed. Bangladesh's interim government, instead of cracking down on extremists, has chosen to punish the minorities.</p>

<p>According to a report by the Bangladesh branch of the Berlin-based human rights group Transparency International, minorities have been targeted in more than 2,000 incidents of violence since Hasina was forced to flee the country.</p>

<p>The matter has reached the United Nations, and its human rights officials have expressed concern over the violations in the country.</p>

<p>India has expressed deep concern over the developments, as a diplomatic row between the two South Asian neighbours escalates.</p>

<h2><strong>Immediate Triggers</strong></h2>

<p>Arrests of monks and journalists, the desecration of the Indian flag at a university campus, and tough statements by advisers in the Yunus administration are further damaging bilateral relations.<br />
The situation worsened recently after Bangladeshi authorities arrested Hindu monk Chinmoy Krishna Das, an ISKCON monk in Bangladesh, who had been leading protests, on charges of sedition.<br />
On 30 November, a prominent Hindu journalist named Munni Saha was arrested by the police in Dhaka. After much outrage and on grounds of illness, she was released on bail.</p>

<p>Over the last few days, social media has been abuzz with pictures and videos allegedly showing children and adults in Bangladesh stamping on India's flag drawn on roads in educational institutions and public places. While this has naturally drawn criticism from enraged Indians, it has also raised questions. Why are people in Bangladesh showing their resentment towards India? Is it because we sympathise with the Awami League's Sheikh Hasina? Or is it the anger against Hindus? Or both?<br />
“Post 5 August, there is an anti-Awami League and anti-India premise. Forces which have historically been against the creation of Bangladesh, against India and its involvement in Bangladesh, and against the Awami League are active in Bangladesh politics today,” says Sanjay Bhardwaj, Professor of South Asian Studies at the School of International Studies, JNU.</p>

<p>Minorities – Hindus, Buddhists, Christians, indigenous groups, etc. – in Bangladesh have never been safe; however, the ousting of the Hasina government has made them more vulnerable in the country.</p>

<p>Added to this, Yunus' caretaker government has been placating Islamic fundamentalist outfits since coming to power. Yunus inducted the deputy chief of the ultra-Islamist outfit Hefazat-e-Islam, AFM Khalid Hossain, as his adviser for religious affairs in the interim government.</p>

<p>“We are in a terrible situation since the fundamentalists have taken over power. Bangladesh is like Afghanistan and Syria now,” says a senior journalist from Bangladesh, on condition of anonymity, as his accreditation was cancelled and his website blocked since 7 August. The authorities have slapped a murder case against him.</p>

<p>“In my country nowadays, you cannot say anything against the government. Speaking in support of the Awami League is treated as fascism. Supporting India is treated as terrorism,” says the senior journalist. In fact, Yunus has dismissed the recent violence against the country's Hindu minorities as "exaggerated propaganda" with political motives aimed at destabilising the nation.</p>

<p>“Jamaat-e-Islami (JeI) calls the shots in Bangladesh. JeI believes in the ideology or idea of Pakistan and wants to pursue their politics based on Islamic nationalism,” says Bhardwaj. “So, time and again, they have been Islamising Bangladesh and its polity since the split of 1971, against the ethos and values of India. They want to bring Bangladesh out of India's dependency culturally, socially, economically, and of course, politically,” he adds.</p>

<p>The Yunus regime has taken a series of anti-India decisions since taking over. The Dhaka High Court's recent decision to acquit BNP's acting chairperson Tarique Rahman, former minister Lutfozzaman Babar, and others in a 2004 grenade attack will also further damage Bangladesh's ties with India.<br />
Rahman and Babar had collaborated to encourage anti-India insurgent groups from the northeast to operate from Bangladesh's soil.</p>

<p>On the economic front, Indo-Bangladesh trade had shifted from the traditional cotton and jute industries to infrastructure in recent years. Large-scale power plants in India, which exclusively supply power to Bangladesh, have been drawn into unnecessary review by the current establishment, much against the spirit of international trade.</p>

<h2><strong>World Can't Be a Mute Spectator</strong></h2>

<p>The vandalism of Hindu temples, the arrest of Hindu monks, and journalists on sedition charges are violations of international human rights law, and India is perfectly correct in airing its concerns about the violation of minority rights in Bangladesh.</p>

<p>The Western media, which is usually vocal about democratic regimes overthrown through anarchy, have been silent on Bangladesh, despite their well-known stance towards countries leaning towards radical Islam. Just yesterday, in the UK Parliament, British MPs Barry Gardiner and Priti Patel raised concerns over violence against Hindus in Bangladesh.</p>

<p>US President-elect Donald Trump's recent criticism of the ‘barbaric attack' on Hindus gives hope of a shift in US foreign policy, which may be on the horizon.</p>

<p>The Biden administration has been silent on the ongoing human rights violations in Bangladesh. Historically, India and the US have been on opposite sides since Bangladesh's liberation from Pakistan in 1971. The US has worked over the years to undermine the Awami League rule under PM Hasina.<br />
“US Democrats, for their own reasons, don't like the Awami League, and they have also been working with the radicals. Now, Trump has strongly indicated concern about minority issues in Bangladesh,” says Bhardwaj.</p>

<p>“I'm still sceptical about how much personally he will intervene in this issue because the Pentagon and the deep state of America ultimately decide their policy towards Bangladesh,” he adds.<br />
It is quite obvious that, with damaging India-Bangladesh bilateral relations, there has been simultaneous cosying up between Bangladesh and Pakistan.</p>

<p>Pakistan announced a new visa policy allowing citizens of Bangladesh to travel to Pakistan without paying a visa fee. On the sidelines of the UN General Assembly summit in New York in September, there was a meeting between Pakistani Prime Minister Shehbaz Sharif and Yunus on the need to ‘revitalise bilateral cooperation'. In October, Yunus' interim government scrapped the mandatory physical inspection of imports from Pakistan – a worry for India, as it could lead to the illegal supply of arms to militants in the northeast.</p>

<p>Also, in November, a cargo ship from Karachi docked at Chittagong port, marking the first-ever direct maritime contact between Pakistan and Bangladesh. This was described by the Pakistan High Commission in Dhaka as “a major step in bilateral trade.”</p>

<p>The situation in Bangladesh is volatile, and India will have to keep a close watch and react according to the unfolding, complicated crisis.</p>

<p><em>(The author is Contributing Editor, NDTV)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/1tb27fp8_bangladesh_625x300_01_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/old-video-of-pakistani-paraglider-landing-on-chief-guest-during-event-leaves-internet-in-splits-7170791]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Old Video Shows Pakistani Paraglider Landing On Chief Guest During Event]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/old-video-of-pakistani-paraglider-landing-on-chief-guest-during-event-leaves-internet-in-splits-7170791]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Dec 2024 16:55:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An old video of a paraglider making an abrupt landing during an event in Pakistan has surfaced online and left social media users chuckling.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An old video of a paraglider making an abrupt landing during an event in Pakistan has surfaced online and left social media users chuckling. The clip, shared on X by the popular account 'Ghar Ke Kalesh', captures the paraglider landing on the chief guest of the event. According to the <em>Khaleej Times</em>, the incident took place in 2023 at a celebration of Gilgit-Baltistan's 76th Independence Day. The event featured the paraglider making a dramatic entrance, followed by a trail of red and blue smoke.</p>

<p>In the video, the paraglider misestimated his landing time and speed. Instead of landing on the field, he ended up landing straight in the first row, where the chief guest was sitting. The people standing around the chief guest moved away quickly and no one seemed to be injured. The paraglider, on the other hand, was seen trapped in the damaged parachute after landing.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Watch the video below:&nbsp;</strong></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Bud Landed over Chief Guest in Pakistan?<br />
<a href="https://t.co/1y9kjDiOzg">pic.twitter.com/1y9kjDiOzg</a></p>
— Ghar Ke Kalesh (@gharkekalesh) <a href="https://twitter.com/gharkekalesh/status/1863625090530983936?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 2, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Since being shared on X, the video has amassed more than 604,000 views and nearly 8,000 likes.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Reacting to the clip, one user jokingly wrote, "Never a day goes by when Pakistan isn't doing Pakistani things." "He landed like Green Goblin in spiderman movie," commented another.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"We will never run out of funny content as long as Pakistan is there," said a third user. "The people still clapping and the camera man didn't move an inch," pointed out another.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"He might be landed at same spot while practicing.. they arranged VIP seating on the same area...not his fault!!" said one X user. "Average Pakistani when they hear Biryani is distributed for free,," reacted another.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The video was taken at a celebration of Gilgit-Baltistan's 76th Independence Day, which was on November 1, 2023.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/feature/indian-origin-ceo-defends-his-companys-84-hour-workweek-culture-its-a-rocket-launch-7170399">Indian-Origin CEO Defends His Company's 84-Hour Workweek Culture: "It's A Rocket Launch..."</a></strong></p>

<p>Previously, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/pakistan-being-pakistan-viral-video-shows-pilot-cleaning-the-windscreen-6474780">another video </a>from Pakistan which showed an airline pilot cleaning the windscreen of his aircraft just before takeoff had surfaced online. The footage showed a Serene Air pilot leaning out of the plane's side window to clean the view ahead. The incident took place on an Airbus A330-200, operating an international flight between Pakistan and Jeddah, Saudi Arabia.</p>

<p>The video sparked a conversation about airline safety protocols and the duties of ground staff. However, a section of the internet said that it is a normal practice.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/0ml2gqgo_pakistan-paraglider_625x300_04_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The video has amassed more than 604,000 views.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/malaysian-actor-alleges-2-decades-of-domestic-abuse-by-husband-pics-show-bruises-on-her-face-7170560]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Malaysian Actor Alleges Domestic Abuse By Husband, Pics Show Black Eye]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/malaysian-actor-alleges-2-decades-of-domestic-abuse-by-husband-pics-show-bruises-on-her-face-7170560]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Dec 2024 16:25:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ms Wilson's Instagram post sparked widespread outrage and support from fellow celebrities and the public.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Malaysian actor Zahnita Wilson has made shocking allegations of enduring two decades of domestic abuse at the hands of her husband, Abdul Zackery Ghouse. Ms Wilson, 41, shared her harrowing experience in an Instagram story, which included a photo of her with a black eye. "I didn't want to do this, but I am forced to. This is why I left my old house and why I sometimes wear sunglasses," she wrote in another post.</p>

<p>According to Ms Wilson, the abuse occurred when she questioned her husband about his fidelity. She claimed to have filed multiple police reports over the years, but no action was taken against her husband.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont">
<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/mbihkcq8_zahnita-wilson-_625x300_04_December_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>

<p>Ms Wilson's Instagram post sparked widespread outrage and support from fellow celebrities and the public. Actress Sarimah Ibrahim commented, "You don't and never deserve this ever."</p>

<p>Following Ms Wilson's post, police arrested her husband under the Domestic Violence Act and booked him for criminal intimidation. Kuantan police chief assistant commissioner Wan Mohd Zahari Wan Busu confirmed the arrest, <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.independent.co.uk/asia/southeast-asia/malaysian-zahnita-wilson-husband-domestic-abuse-instagram-b2657791.html" rel="nofollow, noindex">Independent</a></em> reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Pahang police chief Datuk Seri Yahaya Othman revealed that the incident that led to Ms Wilson's black eye was triggered by her decision to leave and live separately, which angered her husband and led to the altercation.</p>

<p>"The victim filed a police report on 27 November and her husband was arrested yesterday after reporting to the Kuantan district police headquarters. Today, the suspect was brought to court for a remand application," he said.</p>

<p>The actor, who is also a model, expressed frustration that her previous pleas for help had been ignored. "I've filed police reports for the beatings I endured all these while but no action has been taken. Instead, it backfired on me," she was quoted as saying by the outlet.</p>

<p>The case has drawn widespread attention and renewed calls for stronger protections and justice for victims of domestic abuse in Malaysia. In the past, Malaysia's police force has faced criticism for its handling of domestic abuse cases, with a documented history of inadequate responses. In some instances, authorities have been accused of downplaying the severity of domestic abuse incidents.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to the <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/lifestyle-culture/article/3289124/support-pours-malaysian-actress-zahnita-wilson-over-alleged-abuse">South China Morning Post,</a></em> the number of domestic violence cases surged during the pandemic, with a reported 42 per cent increase in 2021 compared to the previous year, totalling 7,468 cases. The alarming trend continued, with 2,794 cases recorded nationwide from 2021 to 2023, according to Women, Family, and Community Development Minister Nancy Shukri.&nbsp;</p>

<p><br />
&nbsp;</p>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/fd4hgi1_zahnita-wilson_625x300_04_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Following Ms Wilson's post, police arrested her husband under the Domestic Violence Act]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-korean-opposition-submits-motion-to-impeach-president-yoon-10-facts-7169969]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[South Korean Opposition Submits Motion To Impeach President Yoon: 10 Facts]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-korean-opposition-submits-motion-to-impeach-president-yoon-10-facts-7169969]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Dec 2024 15:08:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The lawmakers of South Korea's opposition coalition on Wednesday moved a motion in the Asian country's Parliament to impeach President Yoon Suk Yeol after his shocking imposition of martial law that brought thousands of protesters to the streets.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>
<ol class="CetSht_ol">
	<li class="CetSht_li">The opposition parties in South Korea, whose lawmakers tussled with security forces to vote down the controversial martial law, filed a motion on Wednesday to impeach President Yoon Suk Yeol. "We've submitted an impeachment motion prepared urgently," said Kim Yong-min of the opposition Democratic Party (DP).</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Lawmakers are yet to decide when the impeachment motion will be put to a vote, but it could come as soon as Friday. South Korea's opposition controls the National Assembly. The opposition has threatened to impeach President Yoon if he does not resign voluntarily, following his ill-fated move to impose martial law. In case Mr Yoon quits or is removed from office then, the South Korean constitution mandates that Prime Minister Han Duck-soo steps in to perform presidential duties.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Earlier the DP in a statement said it would file charges of "insurrection," against Yoon, his defence and interior ministers and "key military and police figures involved, such as the martial law commander and the police chief." The National Assembly can impeach the president if more than two-thirds of lawmakers vote for it. A trial is then held by the constitutional court, which can confirm it with a vote by six of the nine justices.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">The opposition in South Korea holds a large majority in the 300-member parliament and needs only a handful of defections from the president's party to secure the two-thirds majority needed to pass the motion. Earlier, even the leader of Yoon's own ruling party, which controls 108 seats in the 300-member legislature, described the attempt to bring the martial law as "tragic" while calling for those involved to be held accountable.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">South Korean stocks sank on Wednesday while the currency won dipping multi-year lows only to rebound later after the shocking announcement on Tuesday night. The hours of martial rule in the country sent shivers through the trading floor in Seoul, with investors keeping a close eye on developments in the country.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">The Kospi index ended down more than one per cent, having shed as much as 2.3 per cent at the open, as traders fretted over the impact of Yoon declaring the Asian country's first martial law in more than four decades. Analysts pointed out that the upheaval comes as authorities steeled for the second US presidency of Donald Trump who has vowed to reignite his hardball trade policy.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">The South Korean finance ministry and central bank looked to provide stability and reassure markets by promising to pour in money if needed to prop up volatile financial markets. "As announced together with the government, it has been decided to temporarily supply sufficient liquidity until the financial and foreign exchange markets stabilise," the Bank of Korea said. It added that "the range of securities eligible for (repo) transactions and the target institutions will be expanded". Deputy Prime Minister Choi Sang-mok, who also holds the economy portfolio, said financial authorities will keep international partners informed about developments.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">South Koreans continued with their lives on Wednesday, with people going to offices, businesses and schools as usual. There were scarcely any visible signs in the capital Seoul that six hours of surprise martial law and high political drama overnight had spilled into everyday life. The city of 9 million started the day normally with the usual morning rush hour in trains and on the streets. "At first, I was scared and very confused. I kept thinking, 'What is going on? Is this something that could actually happen in this era?' I couldn't sleep until the martial law was lifted because I was so frightened," Seoul resident Gang He-Soo, 50, told Reuters.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">President Yoon declared martial law in a live TV address at around 10:30 pm (13:30 GMT) on Tuesday, only to reverse the decree after lawmakers defied police and special forces condoning the National Assembly to vote, forcing him to lift the order. The president's office said the declaration of martial law was done at night to "minimize damage to the national economy and people's lives". South Korean soldiers, equipped with rifles, body armour and night-vision equipment, were seen entering the parliament building in Seoul through smashed windows, while helicopters hovered in the night sky above the building.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Soon after the news broke of the martial law broke, thousands of protesters stepped out on the streets, asking for the decree's reversal and removal of the President. Flag-waving protesters kept vigil outside parliament braving freezing temperatures through the night in defiance of Mr Yoon's martial law order. Several senior aides working for Mr Yoon also offered Wednesday to resign en masse over the martial law declaration.</li>
</ol>

<p></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/ob78bpk8_south-korea-martial-law-reuters_625x300_04_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[President Yoon Suk Yeol declared martial law in a live TV address on Tuesday night.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/after-aliya-fakhris-arrest-for-double-murder-new-details-from-insiders-7169957]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[After Aliya Fakhri's Arrest For Double Murder, New Details From Insiders]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/after-aliya-fakhris-arrest-for-double-murder-new-details-from-insiders-7169957]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Dec 2024 15:06:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Aliya Fakhri, who was arrested for allegedly killing her ex-boyfriend and his friend, was a "good person", her friends said as they expressed disbelief over the brutal crime.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Actor Nargis Fakhri's sister Aliya Fakhri's arrest for allegedly killing her ex-boyfriend and his friend has left her friends in shock.</p>

<p>Expressing disbelief over the killings, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-aliya-fakhri-actor-nargis-fakhris-sister-arrested-for-killing-ex-boyfriend-7160117">Aliya</a>'s friends described her as a "good person". According to them, the alleged murder may have been an act of "jealousy".</p>

<p>Sade Jean-Baptiste and Jewels Boatwright (name changed) told NDTV that Aliya, who they call 'Athena' (per her stage name) used to work as a stripper.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"She was a good person...passionate. But she lost it that night. This feels like a crime of jealousy," they said, adding that they "loved her".</p>

<p>Aliya Fakhri was arrested on Tuesday for allegedly setting a two-storey garage on fire in Queens, New York, when her former boyfriend Edward Jacobs (35), and his friend, Anastasia Ettienne (33), were asleep.</p>

<p>According to the Queens District Attorney Melinda Katz, Aliya Fakhri arrived at the garage early morning on November 2 and yelled "you are all going to die today" at Jacobs, who lived upstairs. A witness came out hearing her voice and found that the building had been set on fire. Ettienne, who was alerted of the fire, went back upstairs to save Jacobs. But neither of them made it out of the burning building as they died from smoke inhalation and thermal injuries, officials said.</p>

<p>According to Aliya's friends, her former boyfriend, Jacobs, used to live in the garage and worked as a plumber. He leaves behind four children.</p>

<p>Jacobs and Aliya were a part of the same friends' group, they told NDTV, adding that the two were seeing each other "on and off" but it was a "turbulent" relationship.</p>

<p>The victims, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nargis-fakhris-sister-aliya-fakhri-arrested-for-double-murder-in-queens-new-york-7159276">Jacobs</a> and Etienne lived in the same rented house in Queens, along with Jewels and several other people.</p>

<p>At the time of the incident, all the other people had managed to escape.</p>

<p>Presently, the New York police are not allowing Jewels to live in the house as it is a crime scene, he said.</p>

<p>Aliya's friends told NDTV that she spoke "affectionately" about her elder sister and rockstar-fame actor Nargis Fakhri.&nbsp;</p>

<p>However, sources have claimed that Nargis has not been in touch with Aliya <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/nargis-fakhri-not-in-touch-with-murder-accused-sister-for-20-years-sources-7164273">for more than 20 years</a>.</p>

<p>NDTV also reached out to Nargis and Aliya's mother Marie Fakhri in Queens but found her apartment locked.</p>

<p>A neighbour said: "I saw her last two days ago...She is a very friendly, beautiful woman."</p>

<p>Marie has reportedly denied charges against her daughter saying, "I don't think she would be killing someone. She was a person who was caring for everybody. She tried to help everybody."</p>

<p>Aliya, who has been charged with four counts of murder in the first degree, four counts of murder in the second degree, and accused of arson by a grand jury, is scheduled to appear before a court on December 9.</p>

<p>If convicted of a top charge, she can face a maximum of life in prison, the Queens District Attorney said.</p>

<p><em>(With inputs from Natasha Israni)</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/47k6chd8_aliya-fakhri_625x300_03_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The victims, Jacobs and Ettienne lived in the same rented house in Queens.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/daily-life-in-seoul-ticks-on-but-in-shock-after-6-hour-martial-law-drama-7169904]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Daily Life In Seoul Ticks On, But In Shock, After 6-Hour Martial Law Drama]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/daily-life-in-seoul-ticks-on-but-in-shock-after-6-hour-martial-law-drama-7169904]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Dec 2024 15:02:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[South Koreans went to offices, businesses and schools as usual on Wednesday with scarcely any visible signs in the capital Seoul that six hours of surprise martial law and high political drama overnight had spilled into everyday life.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>South Koreans went to offices, businesses and schools as usual on Wednesday with scarcely any visible signs in the capital Seoul that six hours of surprise martial law and high political drama overnight had spilled into everyday life.</p>

<p>The city of 9 million started the day normally with the usual morning rush hour in trains and on the streets after President Yoon Suk Yeol lifted his abortive attempt at banning political activities and censoring news media just before dawn.</p>

<p>But many were in shock at such a sudden turn of events, which pushed stocks down and South Korea's currency to multi-year lows during a time of already faltering economic growth.</p>

<p>There have been more than a dozen instances of martial law being declared in South Korea since it became a republic in 1948, but the last time was more than four decades ago when Gen. Chun Doo-hwan staged a coup and ruled from 1980 to 1988.</p>

<p>Seoul resident Gang He-Soo, 50, said she woke from sleep by chance and saw the news.</p>

<p>"At first, I was scared and very confused. I kept thinking, 'What is going on? Is this something that could actually happen in this era?' I couldn't sleep until the martial law was lifted because I was so frightened," Gang said, walking in Seoul's main commercial and tourist district Gwanghwamun.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/11qrdjng_south-korea-market-reuters_625x300_04_December_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Yoon declared martial law in a live TV address at around 10:30 pm (1330 GMT) on Tuesday, only to reverse course after parliament defied police and special forces cordons around the National Assembly to vote, forcing him to lift the declaration.</p>

<p>The president's office said the declaration of martial law was done at night to "minimize damage to the national economy and people's lives".</p>

<p>South Korean soldiers, equipped with rifles, body armour and night-vision equipment, were seen entering the parliament building in Seoul through smashed windows.</p>

<p>Helicopters hovered in the night sky above the building.</p>

<p>"It was an experience that I've only seen in movies, and I realised how much more serious it is than I had imagined," said 39-year-old Seoul resident Kim Byeong-In, who said he was concerned about the impact on the economy.</p>

<p>"I'm deeply disturbed by this kind of situation, and I'm very concerned about the future of the country," Kim said.</p>

<p>Many people said they stayed up late following the news, which stations continued to report despite Yoon declaring that media subject to martial law.</p>

<p>Just after the news broke, the usually quiet passengers on a Seoul subway train started talking to each other. A man read a news story out to a companion, a Reuters witness said.</p>

<h2><strong>PROTESTS, PANIC BUYING</strong></h2>

<p>Thousands of people streamed to the riverside National Assembly late on Tuesday and into Wednesday calling for Yoon's order to be blocked and then his arrest and resignation.</p>

<p>Almost two-thirds of parliament's 300 members scrambled to the National Assembly at night for a vote to reject the martial law.</p>

<p>A major South Korean convenience store chain, which declined to be identified to avoid association with the current political situation, said sales of canned goods from its stores jumped 337% between 11:00 pm and midnight on Tuesday, compared to the same period a week earlier.</p>

<p>Sales of instant noodle packets jumped 254% and bottled water jumped 141%, a spokesperson told Reuters.</p>

<p>Some companies overnight advised employees to work from home, but business outlets were open and the morning rush hour was as normal.</p>

<p>South Korea's largest union coalition, the Korean Confederation of Trade Unions, said on Wednesday that tens of thousands of its members would strike until Yoon resigns, and will hold a rally in the evening in downtown Seoul.</p>

<p>Several other protests were expected on Wednesday.</p>

<p>"I only knew that martial law had been declared for some reason, but it ended without anything significant, making the reason seem meaningless. It just felt a bit strange to me," said Seoul resident Park Jun-Yeop.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/jj3so3q_south-korea-metro-commuters-reuters_625x300_04_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[When news of the martial law broke, passengers on Seoul's subway started talking to each other.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/why-nasas-sunita-williams-is-growing-lettuce-in-space-7169351]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Why NASA's Sunita Williams Is Growing Lettuce In Space]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/why-nasas-sunita-williams-is-growing-lettuce-in-space-7169351]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Dec 2024 14:41:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[NASA astronaut Sunita Williams, aboard the International Space Station (ISS), is leading an innovative agricultural experiment.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>NASA astronaut Sunita Williams, aboard the International Space Station (ISS), is leading an innovative agricultural experiment.&nbsp;She is growing "Outredgeous" romaine lettuce in microgravity, a study that promises significant benefits for space missions and Earth-based agriculture.</p>

<p>The experiment, known as Plant Habitat-07, is designed to explore how varying levels of water availability influence plant growth in space.</p>

<p>Its primary objectives are optimising plant cultivation techniques for deep-space missions and developing sustainable farming solutions for water-scarce regions on Earth.</p>

<p>This study involves analysing growth rates, nutritional content, and the overall health of lettuce grown in microgravity. By addressing these parameters, the research aims to support NASA's goal of establishing self-sustaining life-support systems for space exploration.</p>

<p>As the lead scientist, Ms Williams has set up the experiment by collecting baseline water samples from the Advanced Plant Habitat's distribution reservoir and installing the Plant Habitat-07 science carrier, which serves as the cultivation chamber for the lettuce.</p>

<p>The implications of this lettuce experiment extend beyond space exploration. For space missions, the research helps reduce reliance on costly resupply missions, ensures astronauts have access to fresh food, and boosts their psychological well-being by allowing them to grow and eat fresh produce. On Earth, the findings could inform water-efficient farming practices in drought-prone areas, improve crop yields with fewer resources, and promote sustainable food production worldwide.</p>

<p>NASA's plant experiments in space have evolved over time, and the Advanced Plant Habitat aboard the ISS provides an advanced platform for these studies. Ms Williams' work builds on past successes, helpful for future innovations that can benefit both space exploration and Earth-based agriculture.</p>

<p>Apart from her agricultural work, Ms Williams contributes to various health studies aboard the ISS. Recently, she supported fellow astronaut Tyler Hague with vascular health monitoring, showcasing the diverse responsibilities astronauts manage during long missions.</p>

<p>The data gathered from this experiment will contribute to NASA's mission of creating self-sustaining habitats for future long-term space missions. It will also provide valuable insights that can help address global food security challenges.</p>

<p>Ms Williams' ongoing mission began on June 5 alongside astronaut Butch Wilmore on Boeing's Starliner spacecraft. She is engaged in routine maintenance tasks and scientific experiments aboard the ISS. Originally planned for an eight-day stay, the mission was extended due to technical issues with the spacecraft's service module.</p>

<p>She will now remain on the ISS until February 2025 and return to Earth aboard the SpaceX Dragon spacecraft. She has taken command of the ISS for the second time in her career.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/217p6adg_sunita-williams-diwali_625x300_29_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sunita Williams is leading an innovative agricultural experiment.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/french-government-risks-falling-in-no-confidence-vote-7169722]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[French Government Risks Falling In No-Confidence Vote]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/french-government-risks-falling-in-no-confidence-vote-7169722]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Dec 2024 14:38:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[France's government on Wednesday faces no-confidence votes that could spell the end of the short-lived administration of Prime Minister Michel Barnier, plunging the country into uncharted waters of political chaos.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>France's government on Wednesday faces no-confidence votes that could spell the end of the short-lived administration of Prime Minister Michel Barnier, plunging the country into uncharted waters of political chaos.</p>

<p>The toppling of the Barnier government after just three months in office would present President Emmanuel Macron with the unenviable choice of picking a viable successor.</p>

<p>The National Assembly is due to debate two motions brought by the hard-left and far-right in a standoff with Barnier over next year's budget, which saw the premier force through a social security financing bill without a vote.</p>

<p>The far-right National Rally (RN) of three-time presidential candidate Marine Le Pen is expected to vote for the motion put forwards by the left, giving it enough numbers to pass.</p>

<p>Asked on French television if there was a chance his government could survive Wednesday's vote, Barnier replied: "I want this and it is possible...I think it is possible that there is this reflex of responsibility where -- beyond political differences, divergences, the normal contradictions in a democracy -- we tell ourselves that there is a higher interest."</p>

<p>But most analysts believe the government is doomed with the far-right teaming up with the left in an unholy alliance.</p>

<p><strong>'Political fiction'</strong></p>

<p>The turmoil follows a snap election called by Macron in the summer which aimed, without success, to halt the march of the far right, and left no party or faction in parliament with a majority.</p>

<p>Barnier took office with the far right under Le Pen holding a sword of Damocles over his head thanks to its ability to topple the administration at any point of its choosing.</p>

<p>No new elections can be called within a year of the previous legislative polls, narrowing Macron's options.</p>

<p>Some have suggested the president, who is wrapping up a state visit to Saudi Arabia, should resign to break the political impasse.</p>

<p>But Macron rejected those calls, saying such a scenario amounted to "political fiction".</p>

<p>"It's frankly not up to scratch to say these things," Macron told reporters on the sidelines of the Saudi Arabia visit.</p>

<p>"I was elected twice by the French people. I am extremely proud of this and I will honour this trust with all the energy that is mine until the last second to be useful to the country," added Macron, who is due to serve until 2027.</p>

<p>Several prominent opposition figures and even some voices closer to the presidential faction have suggested resignation could be Macron's only viable option.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>'Uncertainty just before Christmas'</strong></p>

<p>The head of the Socialist party, Olivier Faure, called on Macron to make his intentions clear should the Barnier government fall.</p>

<p>"Rather than dropping little remarks during a visit to Saudi Arabia, Emmanuel Macron now needs to speak to the French people," Faure told Le Monde daily in remarks published on Wednesday. "How can he leave the French people in this uncertainty just before Christmas?"</p>

<p>Macron, meanwhile, accused Le Pen's RN of "unbearable cynicism" in backing the no confidence motion.</p>

<p>"We must not scare people with these things," he said.</p>

<p>Macron appeared to hold out some hope that the government will survive, saying he could "not believe" that the motion would pass.</p>

<p>Candidates for the hot seat as premier are few and far between, with loyalist Defence Minister Sebastien Lecornu and Macron's centrist ally Francois Bayrou possible contenders.</p>

<p>If the government falls, it would be the first successful no-confidence vote since a defeat for Georges Pompidou's government in 1962, when Charles de Gaulle was president.</p>

<p>The lifespan of Barnier's government would also be the shortest of any administration of France's Fifth Republic, which began in 1958.</p>

<p>Some observers have suggested that Le Pen, 56, is seeking to bring down Macron before his term ends by ousting Barnier.</p>

<p>Le Pen is embroiled in a high-profile embezzlement trial. If found guilty in March, she could be blocked from participating in France's next presidential election.</p>

<p>She has insisted, however, that the standoff is entirely about a budget that she said would make the French poorer.</p>

<p>By following the "catastrophic continuity of Emmanuel Macron", the prime minister "could only fail", she wrote on social media.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/spu3omeg_michel-barnier-afp_625x300_04_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The turmoil follows a snap election called by Emmanuel Macron in the summer.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-vietnamese-property-tycoon-truong-my-lan-masterminded-the-world-s-biggest-bank-fraud-7168565]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How Vietnamese Business Tycoon Masterminded World's Biggest Bank Fraud]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-vietnamese-property-tycoon-truong-my-lan-masterminded-the-world-s-biggest-bank-fraud-7168565]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Dec 2024 14:35:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Truong My Lan, a 68-year-old real estate tycoon, was convicted in April 2024 for using hundreds of ghost companies to control Saigon Commercial Bank and embezzle billions.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/property-tycoon-faces-death-penalty-over-biggest-fraud-in-vietnam-5417298">Truong My Lan</a>, a 68-year-old influential Vietnamese property magnate, has lost the appeal against her death sentence for orchestrating the world's largest bank fraud. The 68-year-old has been battling to avoid execution. Vietnam law stipulated repaying 75 per cent&nbsp;of the stolen amount could reduce her sentence to life imprisonment. Despite her recent plea for leniency, Lan is racing against time to repay $9 billion, three-quarters of the $12 billion she was found to have embezzled.</p>

<p><strong>Where it all began for Truong My Lan</strong></p>

<p>Truong My Lan's journey from a market vendor to one of Vietnam's most powerful figures began in Ho Chi Minh City, where she sold cosmetics with her mother, as per <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cd753r47815o" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">the BBC</a>. Capitalising on the economic reforms of 1986, she expanded her business, amassing a substantial property portfolio that included hotels and restaurants by the 1990s. By the time she became the chairwoman of Van Thinh Phat Group, her real estate empire was vast, and she had significant influence in the sector.</p>

<p><strong>The fraud</strong></p>

<p>Truong My Lan's fraudulent activities were exposed following her arrest in October 2022. Prosecutors revealed she secretly controlled Saigon Commercial Bank (SCB), the country's fifth-largest lender. Between 2012 and 2022, Lan used numerous shell companies and third parties to orchestrate a vast financial scheme involving fake loan applications. This scheme allowed her to siphon off an estimated $12.5 billion. Prosecutors estimated that the total damages from the fraud could have reached US$27 billion, which, in 2022, represented nearly 3% of Vietnam's GDP. This fraud left thousands of ordinary citizens without their life savings, tied up in the bank and their real estate ventures.</p>

<p>To mask the fraud, Lan and her co-conspirators, including former bank executives and government officials, allegedly paid bribes of $5.2 million to state officials — an amount that was the largest recorded bribe in Vietnam's history.<br />
<br />
<strong>The trial</strong></p>

<p>The trial involved 85 defendants, including Lan's husband, a Hong Kong businessman, and her niece. The authorities had to secure 105 boxes of evidence, weighing over six tonnes, and installed security cameras to safeguard the information. In April 2024, Lan was sentenced to death for embezzlement, bribery, and breaches of banking regulations.</p>

<p><strong>The road ahead</strong></p>

<p>Truong My Lan's legal team has been working to raise the $9 billion needed to avoid execution, as she continues to sell assets and seek loans from friends. Despite these efforts, liquidating her holdings, which include luxury real estate and stakes in various ventures, has proven challenging. Her lawyers argue that her death sentence hinders her ability to negotiate the best prices for her assets and claim she would have better prospects if her sentence were reduced to life imprisonment.</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/qfpal6s8_truong-my-lan_625x300_11_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The trial involved 85 defendants, including Lan's husband, a Hong Kong businessman]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>