<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Wed, 21 Aug 2024 12:29:36 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/men-have-a-biological-clock-too-heres-whats-more-likely-when-dads-are-over-50-6383950]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Men Have A Biological Clock Too. What's More Likely When Dads Are Over 50]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/men-have-a-biological-clock-too-heres-whats-more-likely-when-dads-are-over-50-6383950]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 21 Aug 2024 12:24:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[We hear a lot about womens biological clock and how age affects the chance of pregnancy.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We hear a lot about women's biological clock and how age affects the chance of pregnancy.</p>

<p><a href="https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamanetworkopen/fullarticle/2821811#google_vignette">New research shows</a> men's fertility is also affected by age. When dads are over 50, the risk of pregnancy complications increases.</p>

<p>Data from more than 46 million births in the <a href="https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamanetworkopen/fullarticle/2821811#google_vignette">United States</a> between 2011 and 2022 compared fathers in their 30s with fathers in their 50s.</p>

<p>While taking into account the age of the mother and other factors known to affect pregnancy outcomes, the researchers found every ten-year increase in paternal age was linked to more complications.</p>

<p>The researchers found that compared to couples where the father was aged 30–39, for couples where the dad was in his 50s, there was a:</p>

<ul>
	<li>16% increased risk of preterm birth</li>
	<li>14% increased risk of low birth weight</li>
	<li>13% increase in gestational diabetes.</li>
</ul>

<p>The older fathers were also twice as likely to have used assisted reproductive technology, including IVF, to conceive than their younger counterparts.</p>

<h2>Dads are getting older</h2>

<p>In this <a href="https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamanetworkopen/fullarticle/2821811#google_vignette">US study</a>, the mean age of all fathers increased from 30.8 years in 2011 to 32.1 years in 2022.</p>

<p>In that same period, the proportion of men aged 50 years or older fathering a child increased from 1.1% to 1.3%.</p>

<p>We don't know the proportion of men over 50 years who father children in Australia, but data shows the average age of fathers has increased.</p>

<p>In 1975 the <a href="https://www.abs.gov.au/statistics/people/population/births-australia/latest-release">median age of Australian dads</a> was 28.6 years. This jumped to 33.7 years in 2022.</p>

<h2>How male age affects getting pregnant</h2>

<p>As we know from <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/celebrities-dads-first-time-over-age-50#when-he-was-54-simon-cowell-and-girlfriend-lauren-silverman-became-parents-to-their-son-eric-7">media reports</a> of celebrity dads, men produce sperm from puberty throughout life and can father children well into old age.</p>

<p>However, there is a noticeable decline in <a href="https://www.fertstert.org/article/S0015-0282(18)30269-3/fulltext">sperm quality</a> from about age 40.</p>

<p>Female partners of older men take longer to achieve pregnancy than those with younger partners.</p>

<p>A study of the effect of male age on <a href="https://www.fertstert.org/article/S0015-0282(03)00366-2/fulltext">time to pregnancy</a> showed women with male partners aged 45 or older were almost five times more likely to take more than a year to conceive compared to those with partners aged 25 or under. More than three quarters (76.8%) of men under the age of 25 years impregnated their female partners within six months, compared with just over half (52.9%) of men over the age of 45.</p>

<p>Pooled data from ten studies showed that partners of older men are also more likely to experience miscarriage. Compared to couples where the male was aged 25 to 29 years, <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32358607/">paternal age over 45 years</a> increased the risk of miscarriage by 43%.</p>

<h2>Older men are more likely to need IVF</h2>

<p>Outcomes of assisted reproductive technology, such as IVF, are also influenced by the age of the male partner.</p>

<p>A <a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rbmo.2022.03.031">review of studies</a> in couples using assisted reproductive technologies found paternal age under 40 years reduced the risk of miscarriage by about 25% compared to couples with men aged over 40.</p>

<p>Having a male under 40 years also almost doubled the chance of a live birth per treatment cycle. With a man over 40, 17.6% of treatment rounds resulted in a live birth, compared to 28.4% when the male was under 40.</p>

<h2>How does male age affect the health outcomes of children?</h2>

<p>As a result of age-related changes in sperm DNA, the children of older fathers have increased risk of <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC9957550/">a number of conditions</a>. Autism, schizophrenia, bipolar disorders and leukaemia have been linked to the father's advanced years.</p>

<p>A <a href="https://www.fertstert.org/article/S0015-0282(22)01979-3/fulltext">review of studies</a> assessing the impact of advanced paternal age reported that children of older fathers have increased rates of psychiatric disease and behavioural impairments.</p>

<p>But while the increased risk of adverse health outcomes linked to older paternal age is real, the magnitude of <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29471389/">the effect is modest</a>. It's important to remember that an increase in a very small risk is still a small risk and most children of older fathers are born healthy and develop well.</p>

<h2>Improving your health can improve your fertility</h2>

<p>In addition to the effects of older age, some chronic conditions that affect fertility and reproductive outcomes become more common as men get older. They include <a href="https://www.fertstert.org/article/S0015-0282(23)01935-0/fulltext">obesity and diabetes</a> which affect sperm quality by lowering testosterone levels.</p>

<p>While we can't change our age, some lifestyle factors that increase the risk of pregnancy complications and reduce fertility, can be tackled. They include:</p>

<ul>
	<li><a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4639396/">smoking</a></li>
	<li>recreational <a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/pdf/10.1002/tre.414">drug taking</a></li>
	<li><a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/pdf/10.1002/tre.414">anabolic steroid</a> use</li>
	<li>heavy <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5504800/">alcohol consumption</a>.</li>
</ul>

<h2>Get the facts about the male biological clock</h2>

<p>Research shows <a href="https://academic.oup.com/humupd/article/23/4/458/3065332?login=false">men want children</a> as much as women do. And most men want at least two children.</p>

<p>Yet most men <a href="https://academic.oup.com/humupd/article/23/4/458/3065332?login=false">lack knowledge</a> about the limitations of female and male fertility and overestimate the chance of getting pregnant, with and without assisted reproductive technologies.</p>

<p>We need better public education, starting at school, to improve awareness of the impact of male and female age on reproductive outcomes and help people have healthy babies.</p>

<p>For men wanting to improve their chance of conceiving, the government-funded sites <a href="https://healthymale.org.au/">Healthy Male</a> and <a href="https://www.yourfertility.org.au/">Your Fertility</a> are a good place to start. These offer evidence-based and accessible information about reproductive health, and <a href="https://www.yourfertility.org.au/fertility-week-2022">tips</a> to improve your reproductive health and give your children the best start in life.<!-- Below is The Conversation's page counter tag. Please DO NOT REMOVE. --><img alt="The Conversation" height="1" referrerpolicy="no-referrer-when-downgrade" src="https://counter.theconversation.com/content/236892/count.gif?distributor=republish-lightbox-basic" style="border: none !important; box-shadow: none !important; margin: 0 !important; max-height: 1px !important; max-width: 1px !important; min-height: 1px !important; min-width: 1px !important; opacity: 0 !important; outline: none !important; padding: 0 !important" width="1" /><!-- End of code. If you don't see any code above, please get new code from the Advanced tab after you click the republish button. The page counter does not collect any personal data. More info: https://theconversation.com/republishing-guidelines --></p>

<p><em><span>(<strong>Author:</strong> <a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/karin-hammarberg-113096">Karin Hammarberg</a>, Senior Research Fellow, Global and Women's Health, School of Public Health &amp; Preventive Medicine, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/monash-university-1065">Monash University</a>)</span></em></p>

<p><em><span>(<strong>Disclosure Statement:</strong> </span>Karin Hammarberg works for the Victorian Assisted Reproductive Treatment Authority which manages the Your Fertility program)</em></p>

<p><em>This article is republished from <a href="https://theconversation.com">The Conversation</a> under a Creative Commons license. Read the <a href="https://theconversation.com/men-have-a-biological-clock-too-heres-whats-more-likely-when-dads-are-over-50-236892">original article</a>.</em><br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/udpisu08_fatherhood-generic-father-and-baby-generic-pixabay_625x300_21_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[New research shows mens fertility is also affected by age. (Representational Image)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-call-of-duty-black-ops-6-and-borderlands-4-dates-announced-at-gamescom-event-6383823]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[New 'Call of Duty' And 'Borderlands 4' Dates Announced. Release Dates Here]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-call-of-duty-black-ops-6-and-borderlands-4-dates-announced-at-gamescom-event-6383823]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 21 Aug 2024 12:00:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The release dates for new episodes of the "Call of Duty" and "Borderlands" video games were announced Tuesday at the opening of the Gamescom showcase.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The release dates for new episodes of the "Call of Duty" and "Borderlands" video games were announced Tuesday at the opening of the Gamescom showcase.</p>

<p>The announcements set the scene for the leading international video game show that opens to the public in Cologne on Thursday for four days and is expected to draw more than 350,000 visitors.</p>

<p>The launch of the Borderlands 4 game in 2025 was one of the surprises of the opening night show. The games producers promised that players would "blast their way through hordes of enemies" in the latest version of the game that was adapted for cinema this year.</p>

<p>"Call of Duty: Black Ops 6" will be released on October 25. The latest in the series is set in the 1990s with a security team on a mission to target a senator and gain access to a top-secret site in Washington.</p>

<p>"Deadpool" film maker Tim Miller announced that his new "Secret Level" series based on several video games would be released on Amazon Prime in December. "It is our love letter to games," he said.</p>

<p>Another industry veteran Peter Molyneux said his latest project would be "Masters of Albion". Molyneux made Populous in 1989 and Black and White in 2001 but has been more low-key in recent years with several projects cancelled.</p>

<p>Swedish firm Machinegames said that <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/feature/indiana-jones-temple-of-doom-hat-sells-for-over-5-crores-6363901" target="_blank">"Indiana Jones</a> and the Great Circle" will be released on December 9. First announced for Xbox, the game will also come out on Playstation 5 next year, the company said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/0ifu6aq8_call-of-duty-black-ops_625x300_21_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["Call of Duty: Black Ops 6" will be released on October 25.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kenyan-vampire-serial-killer-escapes-from-police-custody-6383769]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kenyan 'Vampire' Serial Killer Escapes From Police Custody]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kenyan-vampire-serial-killer-escapes-from-police-custody-6383769]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 21 Aug 2024 11:59:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kenyan serial killer 'Vampire', who confessed to killing 42 women, including his wife, has escaped from police custody, authorities have reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kenyan serial killer 'Vampire', who confessed to killing 42 women, including his wife, has escaped from police custody, authorities have reported. <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kenyas-ted-bundy-who-killed-mutilated-42-women-including-his-wife-6151844 ">Collins Jumaisi Khalusha</a> was being held at a police station in Nairobi after his arrest in July after&nbsp;10 dismembered bodies and several body parts were discovered stuffed in plastic sacks in the Kware area.&nbsp;</p>

<p>On Tuesday morning, the 33-year-old, along with 12 other inmates, escaped after cutting through wire mesh in their cells and scaling the perimeter wall, said Mohamed Amin, head of the Directorate of Criminal Investigations.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"This was a high-value suspect who was to face serious charges. We are investigating the incident and will take action accordingly," Mr Amin told AP. He described the incident as "unfortunate".</p>

<p>Khalusha confessed to luring, murdering and mutilating 42 women, including his wife, between 2022 and his arrest in July. He would put their body parts in plastic bags and dump them in a garbage dump. Police found evidence of his crimes at his residence. Among the objects recovered from him were a machete, gloves and nylon sacks.</p>

<p>Detectives also found mobile phones and identity cards belonging to the victims. The evidence suggested a calculated and planned approach to the killings, earning him the nickname "Kenyan Ted Bundy" due to the similarities with the infamous American serial killer.</p>

<p>Forensic examination of the bodies revealed gruesome details. Dr Johansen Oduor, a government pathologist, reported that most bags contained severed limbs and torsos, with only one body found intact. None of the victims had bullet wounds, but one was strangled. DNA analysis has identified two victims, while many remain unidentified due to advanced decomposition.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Khalusha was described as a "psychopathic serial killer with no respect for human life."</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Khalusha's lawyer has maintained his client's innocence, claiming he was tortured and forced to confess. Two other suspects arrested in connection with the case will return to court on August 26.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/j1c5hu6g_collins-jumaisi-afp_625x300_20_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Jumaisi Khalusha confessed to luring, murdering and mutilating 42 women.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/worlds-oldest-person-dies-at-117-in-spain-she-never-went-to-hospital-6383788]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[World's Oldest Person Dies At 117 In Spain: "She Never Went To Hospital"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/worlds-oldest-person-dies-at-117-in-spain-she-never-went-to-hospital-6383788]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 21 Aug 2024 11:56:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The world's oldest person, Spain's Maria Branyas Morera, who was born in the United States and lived through two world wars, died Tuesday at the age of 117, her family said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The world's oldest person, Spain's Maria Branyas Morera, who was born in the United States and lived through two world wars, died Tuesday at the age of 117, her family said.</p>

<p>Guinness World Records had officially acknowledged Branyas's status as the world's oldest person in January 2023 following the death of French nun Lucile Randon aged 118.</p>

<p>"Maria Branyas has left us. She died as she wished: in her sleep, peacefully and without pain," her family wrote on her account on social network X. "We will always remember her for her advice and her kindness."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="ca">La Maria Branyas ens ha deixat. Ha mort com ella volia: mentre dormia, tranquil·la i sense dolor.<br />
Fa uns dies ens deia:<br />
“Un dia me n'aniré d'aquí. No tornaré a provar cafè, ni a menjar iogurt, ni a acaronar a la Fada..., deixaré també els meus records, les meves reflexions... ?</p>
— Super Àvia Catalana (@MariaBranyas112) <a href="https://twitter.com/MariaBranyas112/status/1825824972725502093?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 20, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Branyas, who had lived for the last two decades in the Santa Maria del Tura nursing home in the town of Olot in the northeastern region of Catalonia, had warned in a post on Monday that she felt "weak".</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="ca">“I quan la meva veu calli amb la mort, el meu cor et seguirà parlant d'amor” (Tagore).<br />
Em sento feble. S'acosta l'hora. No ploreu, no m'agraden les llàgrimes. I sobre tot no patiu per mi. Ja em coneixeu, allà on vagi serè feliç, doncs d'alguna manera us portaré sempre amb mi.</p>
— Super Àvia Catalana (@MariaBranyas112) <a href="https://twitter.com/MariaBranyas112/status/1825410650400842128?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 19, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>"The time is near. Don't cry, I don't like tears. And above all, don't suffer for me. Wherever I go, I will be happy," she added on the account which is run by her family.</p>

<p>In the wake of Branyas's death, the oldest living person in the world is Japan's Tomiko Itooka, who was born on May 23, 1908 and is 116 years old, according to the US-based Gerontology Research Group.</p>

<p>Branyas, who lived through the 1918 flu, World War I and World War II and Spain's civil war, got Covid-19 in 2020 just weeks after ringing in her 113th birthday but made a full recovery.</p>

<h3><strong>'Endearing woman'</strong></h3>

<p>Her youngest daughter, Rosa Moret, once attributed her mother's longevity to "genetics".</p>

<p>"She has never gone to the hospital, she has never broken any bones, she is fine, she has no pain," Moret told regional Catalan television in 2023.</p>

<p>The head of the regional government of Catalonia, former health minister Salvador Illa, expressed his "heartfelt condolences" to Branyas's family in a message posted on X.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="ca">Ens ha deixat la Maria Branyas, l'àvia de Catalunya i la persona més gran del món. Perdem una dona entranyable, que ens ha ensenyat el valor de la vida i la saviesa dels anys.<br />
<br />
El meu sentit condol a la seva família. EPD <a href="https://t.co/lnPY1jMpBl">https://t.co/lnPY1jMpBl</a></p>
— Salvador Illa Roca (@salvadorilla) <a href="https://twitter.com/salvadorilla/status/1825827773383954618?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 20, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>"We lose an endearing woman, who has taught us the value of life and the wisdom of the years," he said, calling her "Catalonia's grandmother".</p>

<p>Branyas was born in San Francisco on March 4, 1907 shortly after her family moved to the United States from Mexico.</p>

<p>The entire family decided to return to their native Spain in 1915 as World War I was under way, which complicated the ship voyage across the Atlantic.</p>

<p>The crossing was also marked by tragedy -- her father died from tuberculosis towards the end of the voyage, and his coffin was put into the sea.</p>

<h3><strong>'Completely lucid'</strong></h3>

<p>Branyas and her mother settled in Barcelona and in 1931 -- five years before the start of Spain's 1936-39 civil war -- she married a doctor.</p>

<p>The couple lived together for four decades until her husband died aged 72. She had three children, including one who has already died, 11 grandchildren and numerous great-grandchildren.</p>

<p>"I haven't done anything extraordinary, the only thing I did was live," Branyas told Catalan daily newspaper La Vanguardia in 2019.</p>

<p>Manel Esteller, part of a team of researchers from the University of Barcelona who studied Branyas's DNA to determine the source of her longevity told the daily Spanish newspaper ABC in October 2023 he was surprised by her good health.</p>

<p>"Her mind is completely lucid. She remembers with impressive clarity episodes from when she was only four years old, and she has no cardiovascular disease, which is common in the elderly. The only things she has are mobility and hearing problems. It's incredible," the genetics professor said.</p>

<p>The oldest verified person to have ever lived was Frenchwoman Jeanne Louise Calment who died in 1997 at the age of 122 years and 164 days old.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/k6sa27d_maria-branyas_625x300_21_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Guinness World Records acknowledged Maria Branyas's status as the world's oldest person in January 2023.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/authors-sue-claude-ais-company-for-copyright-infringement-over-ai-training-6383700]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Authors Sue Claude AI's maker For Copyright Infringement Over AI Training]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/authors-sue-claude-ais-company-for-copyright-infringement-over-ai-training-6383700]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 21 Aug 2024 11:41:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The complaint, filed on Monday by writers and journalists Andrea Bartz, Charles Graeber and Kirk Wallace Johnson, said that Anthropic used pirated versions of their works and others to teach Claude to respond to human prompts.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p>

<p>Artificial intelligence company Anthropic has been hit with a class-action lawsuit in California federal court by three authors who say it misused their books and hundreds of thousands of others to train its AI-powered chatbot Claude.</p>

<p>The complaint, filed on Monday by writers and journalists Andrea Bartz, Charles Graeber and Kirk Wallace Johnson, said that Anthropic used pirated versions of their works and others to teach Claude to respond to human prompts.</p>

<p>A spokesperson for Anthropic said on Tuesday that the company was aware of the lawsuit and assessing the complaint but declined to comment further, citing pending litigation. An attorney for the authors declined to comment.</p>

<p>The lawsuit joins several other high-stakes complaints filed by copyright holders including visual artists, news outlets and record labels over the material used by tech companies to train their generative artificial intelligence systems.</p>

<p>Separate groups of authors have sued OpenAI and Meta Platforms over the companies' alleged misuse of their work to train the large-language models underlying their chatbots.</p>

<p>The case filed Monday is the second against Anthropic following a lawsuit brought by music publishers last year over its alleged misuse of copyrighted song lyrics to train Claude.</p>

<p>The authors said in their complaint that Anthropic has "built a multibillion-dollar business by stealing hundreds of thousands of copyrighted books." Anthropic has drawn financial backing from sources including Amazon, Google and former cryptocurrency billionaire Sam Bankman-Fried.</p>

<p>According to the complaint, the authors' works were included in a dataset of pirated books that Anthropic used to train Claude.</p>

<p>The lawsuit requested an unspecified amount of monetary damages and an order permanently blocking Anthropic from misusing the authors' work.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/k5tk03f8_anthropic-ai_625x300_21_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Claude is one of the strongest competitors to OpenAI's ChatGPT]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/boeing-suspends-777x-flight-tests-after-parts-connecting-engine-to-plane-fail-6383640]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Boeing Suspends 777X Flight Tests After Parts Connecting To Engine Fail]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/boeing-suspends-777x-flight-tests-after-parts-connecting-engine-to-plane-fail-6383640]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 21 Aug 2024 11:34:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Boeing has suspended flight testing of its new 777X wide-body jet after identifying the failure of a part connecting the engine to the body of the aircraft, the latest in a long line of quality control issues for the troubled US aerospace giant.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Boeing has suspended flight testing of its new 777X wide-body jet after identifying the failure of a part connecting the engine to the body of the aircraft, the latest in a long line of quality control issues for the troubled US aerospace giant.</p>

<p>"During scheduled maintenance, we identified a component that did not perform as designed," the US aerospace giant told AFP in a statement.</p>

<p>"Our team is replacing the part and capturing any learnings from the component and will resume flight testing when ready," it added, confirming an earlier report by specialist website The Air Current.</p>

<p>Boeing has been beset in recent years with concerns about safety and quality control, with a near-catastrophic incident on an Alaska Airlines <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/alaska-airlines-finds-many-loose-bolts-in-boeing-737-max-9-jets-4922057" target="_blank">Boeing 737 MAX</a> in January bringing renewed pressure on the company.</p>

<p>Boeing's new chief executive Kelly Ortberg, 64, took over earlier this month on a pledge to restore trust in the embattled manufacturer, and announced he would be based in Seattle to be close to the firm's commercial airplane programs.</p>

<h3><strong>Trouble in the family</strong></h3>

<p>Boeing's 777X widebody program, unveiled in November 2013, is the latest addition to its popular 777 family.</p>

<p>The new twin-aisle aircraft is destined to be the world's largest twin-engine jet in operation. More than 500 777X aircraft have already been ordered, but have yet to enter commercial service.</p>

<p>The part that brought about the suspension of flight testing is custom to the 777-9 model, and connects the engine to the aircraft structure, Boeing said.</p>

<p>The other 777-9s used for testing are all currently being inspected following the incident, it added.</p>

<p>Boeing's new aircraft will be available in three models: the 777-8, the 777-9 and the 777-8 cargo.</p>

<p>The aircraft's entry into service was originally scheduled for 2020, but due to problems during the certification process it has now been delayed to 2025.</p>

<p>Although the 777X has still not received the go-ahead from the US Federal Aviation Administration (FAA), Boeing did cross an important milestone in July this year.</p>

<p>Following a large number of test flights, it obtained permission to start testing the 777-9 with FAA representatives on board.</p>

<h3><strong>Orders rebound</strong></h3>

<p>Boeing named aerospace veteran <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/boeing-names-ex-aerospace-veteran-robert-kelly-ortberg-as-new-ceo-6234702" target="_blank">Kelly Ortberg</a> as its next CEO on the same day it reported a $1.4 billion loss for the second quarter of the year, with profits hurt by poor performance in its commercial division.</p>

<p>But since then, the company has enjoyed some rare positive news, with new plane orders picking up in July.</p>

<p>Boeing said it had booked 72 orders -- including 57 for its flagship 737 MAX aircraft -- in the wake of the Farnborough International Airshow in the United Kingdom.</p>

<p>And a few days later, Boeing announced that El AL had finalized orders for up to 31 737 MAX aircraft, marking the largest purchase of airplanes in the Israeli flag carrier's 76-year history.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/tav5on6s_boeing-777x_625x300_20_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Boeing's 777X aircraft is destined to be the world's largest twin-engine jet in operation (File).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/five-time-olympian-cyclist-daniela-larreal-chirinos-found-dead-in-las-vegas-apartment-after-choking-on-food-6383580]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Five-Time Olympian Found Dead In Las Vegas Apartment After Choking On Food]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/five-time-olympian-cyclist-daniela-larreal-chirinos-found-dead-in-las-vegas-apartment-after-choking-on-food-6383580]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 21 Aug 2024 11:23:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Police concluded that the 50-year-old's cause of death had been asphyxiation caused by solid food remains found in her trachea.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Venezuelan cycling legend Daniela Larreal Chirinos was found dead at her Las Vegas apartment on August 16, days after she choked to death, <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.foxsports.com.mx/2024/08/18/daniela-larreal-chirinos-encuentran-sin-vida-a-la-cinco-veces-ciclista-olimpica-de-venezuela/">Fox Sports</a><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.foxnews.com/sports/olympic-cyclist-daniela-larreal-chirinos-found-dead-las-vegas"> </a>&nbsp;</em>reported.&nbsp;The 50-year-old former Olympic athlete was discovered after she failed to show up for work at a hotel in Las Vegas, where she was employed. Authorities determined that Chirinos died on August 11 from asphyxiation caused by solid food remains lodged in her trachea.</p>

<p>Chirinos was a trailblazer in Venezuelan cycling, competing in five Olympic Games from 1992 to 2012.&nbsp;She represented her country at five Olympic Games: 1992 Barcelona, 1996 Atlanta, 2000 Sydney, 2004 Athens, and 2012 London Games.&nbsp;She won numerous medals, including two gold medals at the 2002 Central American and Caribbean Games and two silver medals at the Pan American Games in 2003. Her impressive career spanned over two decades, earning her a revered status in the cycling community.</p>

<p>Her untimely death sent shockwaves through the sporting world, with fans and fellow athletes mourning the loss.&nbsp;The Venezuelan Olympic Committee paid tribute to her on X and wrote,&nbsp;"The COV Board of Directors regrets the departure of Daniela Larreal.&nbsp;With an outstanding career in track cycling, she managed to represent us with honour in five Olympic Games, accumulate four Olympic diplomas and triumphs that always filled us with great pride."&nbsp;</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="es">QLa Junta Directiva del COV lamenta la partida de Daniela Larreal<br />
<br />
Con una destacada trayectoria en el ciclismo de pista logró representarnos con honor en cinco Juegos Olímpicos, acumular cuatro diplomas olímpicos y triunfos que siempre nos llenaron de mucho orgullo.<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/QEPD?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#QEPD</a> <a href="https://t.co/YDJpv72X4D">pic.twitter.com/YDJpv72X4D</a></p>
— Comité Olímpico Venezolano (@OfficialCOV) <a href="https://twitter.com/OfficialCOV/status/1824447071908139321?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 16, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The former Olympian was also a vocal and fearless critic of Venezuela's political leadership, particularly strongman Hugo Chavez, whom she accused of embezzling funds through a fake racing driver sponsorship scheme, along with Sports Minister Hector Rodriguez.</p>

<p>When Nicolas Maduro took power in 2013, she denounced the presidency as a dictatorship, leading to her forced exile and a ban from entering Venezuela. In subsequent years, she rebuilt her life in Miami, driving for Uber before relocating to Las Vegas, where she worked as a food server.</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/50j6jmvo_daniela-larreal-chirinos_625x300_21_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Chirinos, who worked at a Las Vegas hotel, is believed to have died on August 11.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/lebanon-says-5-killed-in-fresh-israel-strikes-6383545]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Lebanon Says 5 Killed In Fresh Israel Strikes]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/lebanon-says-5-killed-in-fresh-israel-strikes-6383545]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 21 Aug 2024 11:18:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Lebanon's health ministry said early Wednesday that Israeli strikes in the country's east killed one person and wounded 20 others, hours after it said four people were killed in the south.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lebanon's health ministry said early Wednesday that Israeli strikes in the country's east killed one person and wounded 20 others, hours after it said four people were killed in the south.</p>

<p>The strikes came more than 24 hours after Israel carried out similar raids deep inside east Lebanon and as tensions mounted in the wake of the Israeli killing of a top Hezbollah commander.</p>

<p>"Israeli enemy strikes on the Bekaa" valley killed one person "and wounded 20 others", the health ministry said in an updated toll.</p>

<p>The statement said one person was in critical condition while "eight children and a pregnant woman were moderately wounded".</p>

<p>A Hezbollah source, requesting anonymity, said several strikes hit east Lebanon near the city of Baalbek, including the village of Nabi Sheet, without specifying what was targeted.</p>

<p>A source from a local hospital told AFP that five children no older than 10, all from the same family, were among the wounded.</p>

<p>The strikes around midnight came after similar raids in the Bekaa region on Monday evening that Israel said targeted "Hezbollah weapons storage facilities".</p>

<p>They also came as Hezbollah said four of its fighters had been killed, after the health ministry said Tuesday that four people died in Israeli strikes in the southern border village of Dhayra.</p>

<p>The Iran-backed Hezbollah, an ally of Palestinian armed group Hamas, has traded near-daily cross-border fire with Israeli forces since the Gaza war began in October.</p>

<p>The violence has largely been restricted to the Lebanon-Israel border area, although Israel has repeatedly struck the country's eastern Bekaa valley near the border with Syria where Hezbollah also has a strong presence.</p>

<p>Hezbollah claimed a string of attacks on Israeli troops and positions on Tuesday, including sending barrages of Katyusha rockets at several north Israel military positions in stated retaliation for Israeli strikes, including in Dhayra.</p>

<p>The Shiite Muslim movement also said it launched "squadrons of explosive-laden drones" and "intense rocket barrages" at several Israeli positions in the annexed Golan Heights in response to Monday night's strikes in the Bekaa valley.</p>

<h2>Health workers 'targeted'&nbsp;</h2>

<p>The Israeli military in separate statements said a total of around 115 "projectiles" were identified crossing from Lebanon.</p>

<p>It also said that "numerous suspicious aerial targets were identified crossing from Lebanon", with air defences intercepting some of them.</p>

<p>No injuries were reported, though the military said the incidents sparked fires in some areas.</p>

<p>The military also said air forces struck projectile launchers and several "Hezbollah military" structures in south Lebanon.</p>

<p>Lebanon's health ministry said three emergency personnel from the Hezbollah-affiliated Islamic Health Committee were hurt Tuesday when the Israeli military "targeted them" in south Lebanon, causing "significant damage to the ambulance they were travelling in".</p>

<p>The ministry "condemned in the strongest terms the repeated targeting of health workers in south Lebanon".</p>

<p>Several militant groups in Lebanon operate health centres and emergency response operations, with at least 21 rescue workers killed since October, according to an AFP tally.</p>

<p>Fears of a major escalation have mounted since Hezbollah and Iran vowed to respond to twin killings blamed on Israel late last month.</p>

<p>An Israeli strike on Beirut's southern suburbs killed a top Hezbollah commander, Fuad Shukr, shortly before an attack in Tehran blamed on Israel killed Hamas political leader Ismail Haniyeh.</p>

<p>The cross-border violence has killed some 590 people in Lebanon, mostly Hezbollah fighters but also including at least 128 civilians, according to AFP's tally.</p>

<p>On the Israeli side, including in the annexed Golan Heights, 23 soldiers and 26 civilians have been killed, according to army figures.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/5husnh3_israel-lebanon_625x300_27_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-missing-scissors-caused-36-flight-cancellations-at-a-busy-japan-airport-6383326]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How Missing Scissors Caused 36 Flight Cancellations At A Busy Japan Airport]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-missing-scissors-caused-36-flight-cancellations-at-a-busy-japan-airport-6383326]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 21 Aug 2024 10:42:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The suspension of security checks led to a severe backlog, resulting in lengthy queues that stretched for hours, with many passengers being turned away and denied entry to the airport.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Chaos erupted at Japan's New Chitose Airport on Saturday when a pair of scissors went missing, leading to the cancellation of 36 flights and delays for over 200 others, <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cd9d7gg2599o">BBC</a></em> reported. The airport, known for its strict security protocols, was thrown into disarray after a retail outlet reported the missing scissors.&nbsp;A search ensued, during which security checks for incoming passengers were suspended for at least two hours.</p>

<p>The suspension of security checks led to a severe backlog, resulting in lengthy queues that stretched for hours, with many passengers being turned away and denied entry to the airport. The airport was especially congested that day, as travellers were returning home after the Obon holiday, a traditional Japanese festival honouring ancestors.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Trouble at New Chitose Airport (CTS) in Hokkaido, Japan.<br />
It was discovered that baggage in breach of the rules was brought in beyond the security checkpoint.<br />
All passengers in the gate area had to be let out once and the inspection needs to be redone. <a href="https://t.co/ye3HdiKIwE">https://t.co/ye3HdiKIwE</a></p>
— Nobi Hayashi 林信行 (@nobi) <a href="https://twitter.com/nobi/status/1824635992885838270?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 17, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>Many affected travellers expressed their frustration, hoping for better safety practices in the future. One traveller said, ''I don't think we have any choice [but to wait], but I do hope they are a bit more careful about it.''</p>

<p>Another said: ''So many things to worry about these days… it never ends. And I don't feel safe until I get home.''</p>

<p>However, the missing scissors were eventually found in the same shop where they had disappeared, relieving concerns of theft and malicious intent.&nbsp;The found scissors announcement was delayed because the airport needed to confirm that they were the same pair as the missing scissors, according to <a href="https://www3.nhk.or.jp/sapporo-news/20240819/7000069180.html" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">Japanese broadcaster NHK</a>.</p>

<p>The Ministry of Land, Infrastructure, Transport and Tourism asked the airport to investigate the cause to prevent it from happening again.&nbsp;</p>

<p>''We recognize that this occurred as a result of insufficient storage and management systems at the store. We are aware that this is also an incident that could be linked to hijacking or terrorism, and will once again work to ensure thorough management awareness,''&nbsp; a representative from the airport told the&nbsp;<em><a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cd9d7gg2599o" rel="noopener" target="_blank">BBC</a>.</em>&nbsp;</p>

<p>Opened in 1988, New Chitose is the largest airport in Hokkaido and one of Japan's busiest airports.&nbsp;In 2022, the airport welcomed over 15 million passengers, solidifying its position as a critical transportation gateway in northern Japan.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/nrhccm38_japan-airport_625x300_21_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The incident saw over 200 flights delayed, and 36 cancelled altogether.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/momla-and-dougie-kamala-harris-husband-shares-their-love-story-6383149]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Momla" And Dougie: Kamala Harris' Husband Shares Their Love Story]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/momla-and-dougie-kamala-harris-husband-shares-their-love-story-6383149]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 21 Aug 2024 10:03:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[He met Kamala Harris on a blind date, and on Tuesday her husband Doug Emhoff tried to convince Americans to love her too after an equally whirlwind introduction. The first "Second Gentleman" in US history wooed the Democratic National Convention.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>He met Kamala Harris on a blind date, and on Tuesday her husband Doug Emhoff tried to convince Americans to love her too after an equally whirlwind introduction. The first "Second Gentleman" in US history wooed the Democratic National Convention in Chicago with a speech that highlighted the human side of the party's presidential nominee.</p>

<p>Delegates chanted "Doug" as the 59-year-old -- who gave up his high-flying legal career to support Harris as vice president -- regaled them with the tale of how they met and how she then became the stepmother to his kids.</p>

<p>"I love you and I'm so proud of how you're stepping up for all of us," Emhoff said.</p>

<p>And he said their personal history showed she was ready to be the country's first female commander-in-chief -- which would make him its first ever First Gentleman.</p>

<p>"Kamala Harris was exactly the right person for me at an important time in my life. At this moment in this nation's history she is exactly the right president."</p>

<p>Harris posted a picture of herself on Air Force Two, watching him speak while she returned from a rally in Milwaukee. "Love you Dougie," she wrote.</p>

<h2>'Heyyyy, it's Doug'</h2>

<p>The Harris campaign regards Emhoff as something of a secret weapon, a ready-made speaker who can familiarize Americans with the vice president after her rapid rise following Joe Biden's withdrawal from the White House race.</p>

<p>He has taken a very visible role as cheerleader-in-chief for his 59-year-old wife ever since Biden first picked her as his running mate back in 2020.</p>

<p>More recently, the father-of-two has been her attack dog against Donald Trump as the Republican former president unleashes personal and racially tinged insults at the Democrat.</p>

<p>But his speech in Chicago focused on the personal as much as the political.</p>

<p>As the crowd waved "Doug" signs, Emhoff told the story of how he and Harris were set up on a blind date by one of his legal clients.</p>

<p>The day after, Emhoff called Harris early in the morning, got her answerphone and "just started rambling. 'Heyyyy, it's Doug... I was trying to grab the words out of the air and just put them back in my mouth."</p>

<p>Harris, however, thought the message was "adorable", saved it, and they married the following year. Now she plays the message to him every anniversary, he said.</p>

<p>"This Thursday will be our 10th wedding anniversary... that same night I'll be hearing my wife, Kamala Harris accept your nomination for President of the United States."</p>

<h2>'Momala'</h2>

<p>Their marriage made Kamala Harris a stepmother to Emhoff's then-teenage children Cole and Ella -- who both dubbed her "Momala".</p>

<p>Cole Emhoff introduced him on stage, after narrating a video showing snapshots from Emhoff's life and gently ribbing his dad.</p>

<p>His son said their "blended family wasn't used to politics," but when Harris became first a California senator and then vice president, they all stepped up.</p>

<p>"It felt like Doug was a bit out of place on Capitol Hill, I thought 'what is my goofy dad doing here?' But he embraced it."</p>

<p>Emhoff himself has admitted that it didn't all come easily, especially when he took a leave of absence from his entertainment law job, which was earning him around $1 million a year.</p>

<p>Biden helped him at the time, saying to him "I know this must have been tough."</p>

<p>Since then, Kamala has called Emhoff her rock as Harris blazed a trail as the first female, Black and South Asian vice president in US history</p>

<p>He too set a milestone, becoming the first ever Jewish spouse of a US president or vice president.</p>

<p>Under the Biden administration, Emhoff took on an increasingly high profile role, giving speeches calling out anti-Semitism after the October 7 attacks by Hamas on Israel.</p>

<p>He also performed ceremonial duties including leading the US delegation at the closing of the 2024 Paris Olympics.</p>

<p>But for one person at least, Emhoff doesn't take the back seat.</p>

<p>"My mother is the only person in the whole world who thinks Kamala is the lucky one for marrying me," he quipped.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-11/ca4cpu98_kamala-harris-doug-emhoff_625x300_10_November_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-man-sues-hospital-for-allegedly-losing-part-of-his-skull-following-brain-surgery-6383052]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Hospital Sued For Losing Part Of Patient's Skull Following Surgery]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-man-sues-hospital-for-allegedly-losing-part-of-his-skull-following-brain-surgery-6383052]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 21 Aug 2024 09:49:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A man in the United States is suing an Atlanta hospital after staff allegedly lost a piece of his skull after a routine procedure and then billed him for a synthetic replacement when they couldn't find it.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A man in the United States is suing an Atlanta hospital after staff allegedly lost a piece of his skull after a routine procedure and then billed him for a synthetic replacement when they couldn't find it. According to the <em>New York Post</em>, the man, identified as Fernando Cluster, checked in to Emory University Hospital in September 2022 for an intracerebral haemorrhage - commonly known as a brain bleed. At the time, doctors determined a 4.7-by-6-inch piece of skull needed to be removed to reduce pressure. However, after returning to the hospital two months later to have the piece of the skull replaced, the hospital couldn't find it amidst a pile of other unidentified bone fragments from other patients' bodies.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"We inspected the freezer where bone flaps are stored and could not find a bone flap with Mr. Cluster's patient identification," a note left by hospital staff in Cluster's medical file read, per the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/08/18/us-news/atlanta-hospital-allegedly-loses-28-square-inch-chunk-of-mans-skull-and-bills-him-for-replacement-lawsuit/"><em>Post</em></a>. "There were several bone flaps with incomplete or missing patient identification, but we could not be certain which if any of these belonged to Mr. Cluster," it added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>As a result, Mr Cluster's surgery was cancelled while the hospital fabricated a synthetic piece of skull. During that time, he was left with a large depression on the right side of his skull. By the end of November 2022, the replacement had been inserted into the patient's head, however, the hospital charged him over $19,000 for the synthetic bone to replace what that they had allegedly lost.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sperm-from-uk-is-being-exported-to-multiple-countries-sparking-surge-in-half-siblings-worldwide-report-6382712">Sperm From UK Is Being Exported To Multiple Countries, Sparking Surge In Half-Siblings Worldwide: Report</a></strong></p>

<p>However, even after the replacement, Mr Cluster's struggle was far from over. Once the synthetic bone was inserted, he reportedly contracted an infection, needed additional surgery and was left unable to work for a time. By the end of his ordeal, his hospital bill topped $146,800 and the hospital allegedly never offered him and his wife any discounts for the treatment.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"While my clients are obviously upset that they and their insurance company were billed for the costs related to Emory's negligence, I'm sure you can understand that their focus is on the egregiousness of Emory losing a part of his body and then having a flippant attitude about it afterwards," Mr Cluster's attorney Chloe Dallaire said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>As per the outlet, Mr Cluster and his wife are now seeking to have the hospital compensate them for medical bills and emotional damages.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-03/o3j0cls8_hospital-generic_625x300_31_March_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Fernando Cluster checked in to the hospital in 2022 for a brain bleed. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/barack-obama-michelle-obama-donald-trump-obamas-back-kamala-harris-as-president-shred-donald-trump-for-his-lies-6382885]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["He Is Afraid Of Losing To Kamala": Barack Obama Shreds Donald Trump]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/barack-obama-michelle-obama-donald-trump-obamas-back-kamala-harris-as-president-shred-donald-trump-for-his-lies-6382885]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 21 Aug 2024 09:10:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former US President Barack Obama and former First Lady Michelle Obama delivered powerful speeches at the Democratic National Convention underway in Chicago today, rallying the country around the candidacy of Kamala Harris.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former US President Barack Obama and former First Lady Michelle Obama delivered powerful speeches at the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-polls-2024-national-democratic-convetion-day-2-live-roll-call-today-to-select-kamala-harris-as-democratic-candidate-6381127">Democratic National Convention</a> underway in Chicago today, rallying the country around the candidacy of Kamala Harris, who is poised to become the first Black and South Asian woman to secure a major party's nomination for the presidency.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Taking the stage to a rapturous welcome, Barack Obama began his speech with, "Chicago, it's good to be home." He was greeted by thunderous applause from the audience. The former president quickly rekindled the spirit of his successful 2008 campaign, declaring, "I don't know about you, but I'm feeling fired up and ready to go!"</p>

<p>"This convention has always been good to kids with funny names who believe in this country that anything is possible," he said.</p>

<p>Sixteen years after first accepting the Democratic nomination, Mr Obama looked back with pride on his decision to choose Joe Biden as his vice president. "My first big decision was my best - it was to ask Joe Biden to serve as my vice president," he said. "Other than some common Irish blood, we come from different worlds, but we became brothers."</p>

<p>Mr Obama praised Mr Biden for his empathy and decency, qualities he believes are essential for a leader. "I admired Joe's empathy and decency. His belief that everyone in this country deserves a shot," he said.</p>

<h3><strong>Obamas Slam Donald Trump&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Mr Obama, after praising Mr Biden, turned his attention to Donald Trump who is seeking re-election to the Oval Office and is Kamala Harris' main opponent in the presidential race.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Here is a 78-year-old billionaire who has not stopped whining about his problems since he rode down his golden elevator nine years ago," Mr Obama said. "It has been a constant gripe, conspiracy theories and grievance that has been getting worse since he is afraid of losing to Kamala."</p>

<p>"Someone compared Trump to a neighbour who keeps running his leafblower outside your window. From a neighbour it's exhausting, from a president it's dangerous," Mr Obama added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Mr Obama accused Mr Trump of divisive politics. The former president said the United States does not need four more years of chaos.</p>

<p>"Trump wants us to think this country is divided between 'us' and 'them'. Between 'real' Americans who support him and the 'outsiders'. It is the oldest trick in politics. His act has gotten stale. We do not need four more years of chaos as we have seen that movie before and we know the sequel is usually worse," he said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Michelle Obama's address was also a fierce critique of the current state of American politics. The former First Lady did not mince words as she tore into Mr Trump, accusing him of divisive rhetoric and policies.</p>

<p>"For years, Donald Trump did everything to make people fear us," she began. "His limited, narrow view of the world made him feel threatened by two highly successful and educated people who happened to be Black. It is the same old con, doubling down on ugly, misogynistic, racist lies instead of real ideas and solutions".&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>Big Praise For Kamala Harris&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Speaking about Kamala Harris, Mr Obama went back in time to tweak his "Yes We Can" campaign slogan from the 2008 elections to declare, "Yes, she can."&nbsp;</p>

<p>"America is ready for a new chapter and a new story. We are ready for Kamala Harris. She is ready for the job," he said. "Kamala Harris won't be focused on her problems, she will focus on yours. She won't punish those who refuse to kiss the ring and bend the knee."</p>

<p>"We need a president who actually cares about the millions of people across this country. We need a president who will stand up for them and bargain for better wages. Kamala will be that president. Yes, she can," the former president added.</p>

<p>Michelle Obama also spoke passionately about Kamala Harris, whom she described as more than ready to lead. "Kamala Harris and I build our lives on the same foundation of values," she said, drawing parallels between their upbringings and shared beliefs in the promise of America.</p>

<p>"Her mother moved here from India at the age of 19. That's why she taught Kamala about justice," Michelle Obama said. "She often told her daughter, 'don't sit around and complain, do something.' So with that voice in her head, Kamala went out and worked hard, fighting for people, for better wages."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/mk36tq98_obama-afp_625x300_21_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Obamas accused Donald Trump of divisive politics.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sperm-from-uk-is-being-exported-to-multiple-countries-sparking-surge-in-half-siblings-worldwide-report-6382712]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Sperm From UK Is Being Exported Despite 10-Family Limit: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sperm-from-uk-is-being-exported-to-multiple-countries-sparking-surge-in-half-siblings-worldwide-report-6382712]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 21 Aug 2024 08:24:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Sperm donated in the UK is being exported to other countries and can be used to create large numbers of children across the world, violating a strict 10-family limit that applies in the UK, experts warned.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sperm donated in the UK is being exported to other countries and can be used to create large numbers of children across the world, violating a strict 10-family limit that applies in the UK, experts warned. According to <em>The Guardian</em>, while a single donor can be used to create no more than 10 families in UK fertility clinics, there are no restrictions on sperm or eggs from the country being sent abroad. This legal loophole is being exploited in what appears to be an industrial-level practice. It also raises the prospect of some donor-conceived children navigating relationships with dozens of biological half-siblings across Europe and beyond.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Amidst this, experts are calling on the Human Fertilisation and Embryology Authority (HFEA) to tighten restrictions. "If you believe that it's necessary to enforce the 10-family limit in the modern world then logically that should apply wherever the sperm are from," said Prof Jackson Kirkman-Brown, chair of the Association for Reproductive and Clinical Scientists (ARCS), per <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/article/2024/aug/18/uk-sperm-donations-being-exported-to-sidestep-10-family-limit"><em>The Guardian</em></a>. "There is data showing that some of the children who find the really big families struggle with that," he added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Separately, speaking to the outlet, Prof Lucy Frith, of the University of Manchester, who is researching donor-conceived experiences, said that making contact with biological half-siblings is often viewed positively. However, she added that "when numbers of siblings began to grow [it] felt unmanageable to have contact and relationships with a growing and indeterminate number of people."&nbsp;</p>

<p>"There are no hard and fast figures of when the number becomes 'too much' and this depends on individuals, but generally over 10 was felt to be a large group," she said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Once you've frozen sperm it doesn't get any older," said Mr Kirkman-Brown. This means that a donor sperm could continue to be used for years or decades. "You can end up with donor siblings older than your parents, which is not somewhere we've been yet," he added.</p>

<p>Donations are "presented to donors as a beautiful gift to help someone create a family, not as, 'We're going to maximise the number of births from your gametes and make as much money as we can from that,'" said Prof Nicky Hudson, a medical sociologist at De Montford University.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The rule for enforcing the 10-family limit across licensed clinics is controlled by HEFA. According to the regulatory body, 10 is the number people feel comfortable with in terms of the number of potential donor-conceived children, half-siblings and families that might be created.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"As the HFEA has no remit over donation outside of HFEA licensed clinics, there would be no monitoring of how many times a donor is used in these circumstances," said Rachel Cutting, director of compliance and information at the HFEA.</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/science/humans-experience-fastest-aging-at-these-two-ages-reveals-study-6356662">Humans Experience Fastest Aging At These Two Ages, Reveals Study</a></strong></p>

<p>Experts are now asking HEFA to crack down. "The HFEA is limited by its statutory duties, but it could stipulate that it will only import gametes that meet the UK limit (10 families), outside the UK," said Lucy Frith.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The HFEA's position that this is outside its remit is not good enough," said Sarah Norcross, director of the fertility charity Progress Educational Trust. "I'm not against there being more than 10 families if some are outside the UK, but 75, which some of these banks have alighted on, is a heck of a lot of relatives. Even if they say we can't control the number of families abroad, they could insist that the number is made available to the recipient," she added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Notably, according to <em>The Guardian</em>, the United Kingdom was an importer of sperm till five years ago, mainly from the US and Denmark. But between 2019 and 2021, the UK exported 7,542 straws of sperm. Additionally, the world's largest sperm and egg bank Cryos opened a unit in Manchester this April.</p>

<p>"The European Sperm Bank, which accounted for 90% of exports, applies a worldwide limit of 75 families a donor and estimates that its donors help on average 25 families," the report said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The idea of a dad to loads of children already exists in our cultural imagination. We don't have that for women," noted Prof Nicky Hudson, adding that it's not an idea encouraged by women. One of them told her it "felt like human trafficking".&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2019-09/mivjncv_sperm-generic-vials-of-sperm-reuters_625x300_24_September_19.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[There are no restrictions on sperm or eggs from the UK being sent abroad. (Representative pic)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/starbucks-new-ceo-to-supercommute-1-600-km-to-work-on-corporate-jet-6382614]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Starbucks' New CEO To Supercommute 1,600 Km To Work On Corporate Jet]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/starbucks-new-ceo-to-supercommute-1-600-km-to-work-on-corporate-jet-6382614]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 21 Aug 2024 07:54:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Starbucks' CEO Brian Niccol will have an unusually long commute to work as he becomes the coffee giant's new chief next month. Mr Niccol who lives in California will travel 1,600 kilometres every day to the company's headquarters in Seattle.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Starbucks' CEO Brian Niccol will have an unusually long commute to work as he becomes the coffee giant's new chief next month. Mr Niccol who lives in California will travel 1,600 kilometres every day to the company's headquarters in Seattle.</p>

<p>As per his offer letter, Mr Niccol will use a corporate jet for his commute. Even when he is not traveling for work, he will be expected to work from the Seattle office at least three days a week, as per Starbucks' hybrid work policy which has been in place since 2023.</p>

<p>The 50-year-old will be paid a base salary of $1.6 million every year and can earn a cash bonus of $3.6 million to $7.2 million depending on his performance.&nbsp;</p>

<p>He will also be eligible for annual equity awards worth up to $23 million.</p>

<p>This is not the first time Mr Niccol has been part of such a supercommute arrangement. He successfully negotiated a similar deal when he was the CEO of Chipotle in 2018.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Chipotle was headquartered in Colorado, a 15-minute drive from Mr Niccol's last working place. But the Mexican fast food chain moved its headquarters from Denver to California three months after he was appointed CEO.</p>

<p>“Brian's primary office and a majority of his time will be spent in our Seattle Support Center or out visiting partners and customers in our stores, roasteries, roasting facilities and offices around the world. His schedule will exceed the hybrid work guidelines and workplace expectations we have for all partners," a company spokesperson told CNBC.</p>

<p>Such comfortable terms for employment are common for high-ranking executives who have immense bargaining power compared to the average employee.</p>

<p>Hillary Super of singer Rihanna's lingerie brand Fenty x Savage was given a s similar concession when Victoria's Secret made her its new CEO.&nbsp;</p>

<p>She will work from the firm's New York City offices instead of its headquarters near Columbus, Ohio.</p>

<p>But this is not the case for all CEOs.</p>

<p>Amazon's Andy Jassy and JPMorgan Chase's Jamie Dimon are pitching hard to bring back work-from-office policies.</p>

<p>The reason behind Mr Niccol's unusual arrangement at Starbucks is underscored by the coffee giant's falling sales.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In US and China, Starbucks' two largest markets, sales have dropped this year under its current CEO Laxman Narasimhan's tenure.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Mr Niccol is a star candidate for the top post as he has a strong track record of turning around troubled companies. When he was CEO of Chipotle, its stock reportedly soared 773%.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/0pdhdaso_brian-niccol_625x300_21_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/former-nfl-player-jailed-for-murder-of-girl-5-he-forced-to-exercise-and-called-chunky-6382462]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ex-NFL Player Jailed For Murdering 5-Year-Old Girl He Forced To Exercise]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/former-nfl-player-jailed-for-murder-of-girl-5-he-forced-to-exercise-and-called-chunky-6382462]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 21 Aug 2024 07:09:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A former National Football League (NFL) player has received a sentence of 10 years to life after pleading guilty to the murder of a 5-year-old girl who was forced to exercise as a punishment for being "chunky".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A former National Football League (NFL) player has received a sentence of 10 years to life after pleading guilty to the murder of a 5-year-old girl who was forced to exercise as a punishment for being "chunky". According to <em>NBC Sports</em>, the child identified as La'Rayah Davis died in April 2019 after being taken to a hospital with at least 100 bruises, including 20 broken ribs and a laceration to her liver that authorities believe killed her.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The former NFL player Cierre Wood was in a relationship with Amy Taylor, the 5-year-old's mother, at the time. He was arrested and charged with murder earlier this week. Ms Taylor also pleaded guilty to charges of second-degree murder and felony child abuse as part of the deal with the prosecutor, the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.nbcsports.com/nfl/profootballtalk/rumor-mill/news/former-nfl-rb-cierre-wood-gets-life-sentence-after-pleading-guilty-to-murder-of-five-year-old-girl">outlet </a>reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>An investigation into the little girl's death revealed the details of the extensive abuse she suffered prior to her death. The mother reportedly told the cops that she sat on the child while disciplining her. Wood, on the other hand, claimed that the child fell backwards and hit her head while doing sit-ups.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-model-suffers-multiple-injuries-after-swallowing-broken-plastic-from-beverage-sues-american-airlines-6369220">US Model Suffers Multiple Injuries After Swallowing "Broken Plastic" From Beverage, Sues American Airlines</a></strong></p>

<p>According to an arrest warrant, the former NFL player would "make her run sprints in the apartment, do sit-ups and wall squats". Woods told the police that he was "trying to get her on the right path due to her being chunky". On the day of her death, Wood made the child do sit-ups after she did not learn her letters and numbers, he said, per <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://people.com/cierre-wood-ex-nfl-player-sentence-prison-murdering-girlfriend-daughter-8695511"><em>People</em></a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Wood's lawyer, however, claimed that it was Amy Taylor who abused the child and Wood was not home when the abuse took place. The mother was sentenced in July to life in prison with the possibility of parole for the murder charge and eight to 20 years on the abuse charge.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Wood pleaded guilty to second-degree murder and felony child abuse and will be eligible for parole after 10 years. He entered an Alford plea, which is an admission of guilt but also allows him to maintain his innocence.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/r92j4rdo_cierre-wood_625x300_21_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Cierre Wood was in a relationship with Amy Taylor, the 5-year-old's mother.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/google-must-face-class-action-lawsuit-over-chromes-data-collection-us-court-6382128]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Google Faces Class Action Lawsuit Over Chrome's Data Collection]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/google-must-face-class-action-lawsuit-over-chromes-data-collection-us-court-6382128]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 21 Aug 2024 05:11:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A U.S. appeals court said Google must face a revived lawsuit by Google Chrome users who said the company collected their personal information without permission, after they chose not to synchronize their browsers with their Google accounts.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;A U.S. appeals court said Google must face a revived lawsuit by Google Chrome users who said the company collected their personal information without permission, after they chose not to synchronize their browsers with their Google accounts.</p>

<p>The 9th U.S. Circuit Court of Appeals in San Francisco said the lower court judge who dismissed the proposed class action should have assessed whether reasonable Chrome users consented to letting Google collect their data when they browsed online.</p>

<p>Tuesday's 3-0 decision followed Google's agreement last year to destroy billions of records to settle a lawsuit claiming the Alphabet unit tracked people who thought they were browsing privately, including in Chrome's "Incognito" mode.</p>

<p>Neither Google nor its lawyers immediately responded to requests for comment.</p>

<p>Matthew Wessler, a lawyer for the plaintiffs, said he was pleased with the decision and looked forward to a trial.</p>

<p>The proposed class covers Chrome users since July 27, 2016 who did not sync their browsers with their Google accounts.</p>

<p>They said Google should have honored Chrome's privacy notice, which said users "don't need to provide any personal information to use Chrome" and Google would not receive such information unless they turned on the "sync" function.</p>

<p>The lower court judge concluded that Google's general privacy policy allowing data collection governed, because the Mountain View, California-based company would have collected the plaintiffs' information regardless of which browsers they used.</p>

<p>In Tuesday's decision, Circuit Judge Milan Smith called that focus misplaced.</p>

<p>"Here, Google had a general privacy disclosure yet promoted Chrome by suggesting that certain information would not be sent to Google unless a user turned on sync," Smith wrote. "A reasonable user would not necessarily understand that they were consenting to the data collection at issue."</p>

<p>The appeals court returned the case to U.S. District Judge Yvonne Gonzalez Rogers in Oakland, California, who had dismissed it in December 2022.</p>

<p>Google's settlement related to Incognito let users sue the company individually for damages. Tens of thousands of users in California alone have since done so in that state's courts.</p>

<p>The case is Calhoun et al v Google LLC, 9th U.S. Circuit Court of Appeals, No. 22-16993.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/l3dququ_google-logo_625x300_06_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Google's settlement related to Incognito let users sue the company individually for damages.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/un-rights-expert-barred-from-afghanistan-report-6382076]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UN Rights Expert Barred From Afghanistan: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/un-rights-expert-barred-from-afghanistan-report-6382076]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 21 Aug 2024 04:52:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The UN special rapporteur on the human rights situation in Afghanistan has been barred from entering the country, a diplomatic source told AFP on Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The UN special rapporteur on the human rights situation in Afghanistan has been barred from entering the country, a diplomatic source told AFP on Tuesday.</p>

<p>"Richard Bennett was informed of the decision that he would not be welcome to return to Afghanistan several months ago," a diplomatic source confirmed to AFP after local media reported the ban, citing a Taliban government spokesman.</p>

<p>Bennett marked two years in the role on May 1.</p>

<p>Since returning to power in August 2021, Taliban authorities have enforced rules based on a strict interpretation of Islamic law.</p>

<p>Women have borne the brunt of restrictions the United Nations has labelled "gender apartheid" which have pushed them from public life.</p>

<p>They have been barred from secondary and higher education, as well as blocked from working in many jobs or entering public parks, gyms and travelling without a male relative.</p>

<p>The Taliban government remains unrecognised by any other state, with its restrictions on women a key sticking point.</p>

<p>Taliban authorities have systematically dismissed criticism of their policies from the UN and the international community.</p>

<p>However, when the ban was apparently issued months ago, the Taliban government stressed that their issue was not with human rights monitoring and reporting, but with Bennett personally, according to diplomatic sources.</p>

<p>Earlier Tuesday, Afghanistan's Tolo News quoted chief Taliban government spokesman Zabihullah Mujahid as saying that Bennett had been banned "because he was appointed to Afghanistan to spread propaganda and he is not someone whose words we can trust".</p>

<p>"He took small issues and exaggerated them for propaganda," he said.</p>

<p><strong>- Strong statements -</strong></p>

<p>In recent months, Bennett has issued strong statements on women's rights in Afghanistan at moments when the country was in the international spotlight.</p>

<p>Last week, as the Taliban authorities celebrated the third anniversary of their takeover of Afghanistan, Bennett joined 29 other UN experts in a statement urging the international community to "not normalise the de facto authorities or their appalling human rights violations", he said on X.</p>

<p>In late June, Bennett condemned the decision to exclude rights issues from the agenda and Afghan women and civil society representatives from the table at UN-hosted talks in Qatar -- a condition of Taliban representatives' attendance at the meetings with the international community.</p>

<p>"The cost is too high," he wrote in a New York Times opinion piece.</p>

<p>In New York, Stephane Dujarric, a spokesman for UN Secretary-General Antonio Guterres, did not confirm or deny the ban Tuesday but said: "Special rapporteurs play a very critical part in the global human rights architecture. We encourage full cooperation with them."</p>

<p>Special rapporteurs like Bennett are independent experts within the Special Procedures body of the Geneva-based UN Human Rights Council.</p>

<p>The UN Assistance Mission in Afghanistan (UNAMA) maintains a human rights monitoring and reporting function in the country.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-01/sihfbdlo_taliban-afp_625x300_15_January_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Taliban authorities have systematically dismissed criticism of their policies from the UN.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-says-joe-bidens-comments-on-gaza-peace-talks-misleading-6381966]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hamas Says Biden's Comments On Gaza Peace Talks "Misleading"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-says-joe-bidens-comments-on-gaza-peace-talks-misleading-6381966]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 21 Aug 2024 04:12:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hamas has called US President Joe Biden's statements about the movement backing away from the ceasefire agreement in the Gaza Strip "misleading".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;Hamas has called US President Joe Biden's statements about the movement backing away from the ceasefire agreement in the Gaza Strip "misleading".</p>

<p>Hamas said in a statement on Tuesday that it viewed Biden's claims with "great astonishment and disapproval", noting that they "do not reflect the true position of the movement, which is keen to reach a cessation of aggression", Xinhua news agency reported.</p>

<p>It added that the statements are part of American bias toward Israel and a renewed American green light for the Israeli government to "commit more crimes against defenseless civilians in pursuit of the goals of exterminating and displacing our people."</p>

<p>It mentioned that mediators in Qatar and Egypt know Hamas has dealt positively and responsibly in all previous rounds of negotiations and that Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu has always been the one to "obstruct reaching an agreement by setting new conditions and demands."</p>

<p>In the statement, Hamas reaffirmed its commitment to what was agreed upon with mediators on July 2, based on Biden's declaration and the UN Security Council resolution, and called on the mediators to fulfill their responsibilities and urge the occupation to accept it.</p>

<p>On Monday night, Biden accused Hamas of "backing away" from a hostage deal with Israel that would halt the ongoing fighting in Gaza, Israeli media reported.</p>

<p>Biden said after delivering a keynote to the Democratic National Convention, "It's still in play, but you can't predict," and "Israel says they can work it out... Hamas is now backing away," according to Israeli media.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/d48qn25o_israel-gaza-war_625x300_14_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[More than 40,000 people have been killed in Gaza since war began between Israel and Hamas.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-polls-2024-national-democratic-convetion-day-2-live-roll-call-today-to-select-kamala-harris-as-democratic-candidate-6381127]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Yes She Can": Barack Obama Tweaks 2008 Campaign Slogan For Kamala Harris]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-polls-2024-national-democratic-convetion-day-2-live-roll-call-today-to-select-kamala-harris-as-democratic-candidate-6381127]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 21 Aug 2024 03:49:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Highlights: US' four-day National Democratic Convention started yesterday in Chicago with US President Joe Biden's speech. Joe Biden passed the torch to Kamala Harris as the new official Democratic candidate to run against Donald Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US' four-day National Democratic Convention started yesterday in Chicago with US President Joe Biden's speech. Joe Biden passed the torch to Kamala Harris as the new official Democratic candidate to run against Donald Trump, month after he quit the US Presidential race.</p>

<p>Several democrates and Kamala Harris' supporters also delivered speeches during the mega event, including California Representatives Robert Garcia, Maxine Waters, Minnesota Lt Governor Peggy Flanagan, US Congresswoman Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez and more.</p>

<p>With the theme "Bold Vision for America's Future", Democratic Convention's day two is likely to witness a ceremonial roll call vote to select the official Democratic Party candidate for US 2024 Presidential polls.</p>

<h2><strong>Here are the Highlights of the US Democratic Convention day 2:</strong></h2>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/9jgs0hjg_kamala-harris-afp_625x300_05_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Highlights: Theme for day 2 of Democratic Convention is "Bold Vision for America's Future"]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/day-2-of-democratic-convention-obama-set-to-praise-kamala-harris-6381072]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Obamas Headline Democratic Convention Day 2 For Kamala Harris]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/day-2-of-democratic-convention-obama-set-to-praise-kamala-harris-6381072]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 21 Aug 2024 02:56:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Democratic National Convention started with US President Joe Biden giving a fiery speech against Donald Trump, a former US President facing several court cases and survivor of an assassination attempt.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<ol>
	<li>The DNC, the biggest event of the year for the party, officially anointed US Vice President Kamala Harris as a candidate for the 2024 US Presidential Election against Donald Trump, who is seeking a second term.</li>
	<li>The four-day event, which is taking place in Chicago, began yesterday and saw Joe Biden giving a fiery speech against Mr Trump and calling him a "loser". "He called soldiers who gave their lives for this country, suckers and losers. Who does he think he is?" Mr Biden asked. "Trump bows down to (Vladimir) Putin. I never have and Kamala Harris will never do it," President Biden said.</li>
	<li>On day one, President Biden criticised Mr Trump's "America First" doctrine, which he said had damaged the nation's global image, contrasting his own administration's efforts to unite Europe and counter Russian aggression.</li>
	<li>Kamala Harris will make a big speech on August 22, the last day of the event, but one of the notable speakers today will be her husband, Doug Emhoff, a successful lawyer. If Harris wins, then Emhoff will be the first "first gentleman" of the United States.&nbsp;</li>
	<li>The convention also served as a farewell for Joe Biden, who withdrew his nomination in an unprecedented move witnessed in modern US electoral history. In 1968, President Lyndon B Johnson declared in the middle of the Vietnam War that he would not run for re-election.</li>
	<li>What followed after a fiery speech was a four-minute-long standing ovation and Kamala Harris making a surprise appearance to thank President Biden for being "incredible".</li>
	<li>"I love you," the tearful 81-year-old president told the crowd to deafening cheers, less than a month after dropping out of the White House race against Donald Trump and passing the torch to his vice president.</li>
	<li>Today, former US President Barack Obama will hand over the baton of the party's future to Ms Harris. Obama posted on social media that his Democratic National Convention address will lay out "what's at stake" and why Harris and her running mate Tim Walz "should be our next president and vice president."</li>
	<li>Kamala Harris will hold a rally ahead of Obama's speech in the Milwaukee basketball arena where Trump attended the Republican convention just a month ago. The 18,000-seater arena has been chosen deliberately to pinch Trump, who is rattled to see the US President's deputy filling venues. In a recent poll, Ms Harris had a marginal lead against Donald Trump.&nbsp;</li>
	<li>Apart from Obama, Hilary Clinton - the first woman to secure a major US party's nomination for the presidential election, also addressed the delegates yesterday. "As president, she (Kamala Harris) will always have our backs and she will be a fighter for us. She will fight to lower costs for hard-working families, open the doors wide for good paying jobs and, yes, she will restore abortion rights nationwide," Ms Clinton said</li>
</ol>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/4i5380b_kamala-harris-_625x300_20_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kamala Harris will hold a rally ahead of Obama's speech in the Milwaukee basketball arena.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>