<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Wed, 31 Jul 2024 13:16:59 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/quad-summit-india-is-turning-up-the-heat-on-china-and-not-just-in-its-neighbourhood-6229608]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: India Is Turning Up The Heat On China - And Not Just In Its Neighbourhood]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/quad-summit-india-is-turning-up-the-heat-on-china-and-not-just-in-its-neighbourhood-6229608]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 31 Jul 2024 13:02:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The message is very clear - that New Delhi will not relent in pressing ahead with its pushback against Beijing even as the door is open for China to recalibrate its anti-India positioning.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/eah6hivg_south-china_625x300_31_July_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>The week gone by has been a busy period for India in the Indo-Pacific. India's External Affairs Minister, S. Jaishankar, attended the ASEAN Foreign Ministers' Meeting in Laos and the Quad Foreign Ministers' Meeting in Japan. Jaishankar's visit to Laos also featured a bilateral meeting with his Chinese counterpart, Wang Yi, following their last meeting at Astana earlier this year. The context for Jaishankar's visit was set by India's enduring pushback against China in key arenas of its interest. Arguably, China remains the pre-eminent concern for India's national security planners. India's China challenge is multipronged, with unresolved border conflict along the Line of Actual Control (LAC), as well as Beijing's expanding footprint in the Indian Ocean. China's more recent overtures in the Indo-Pacific, especially in the South China Sea region, have also compelled India's Quad partners and several Southeast Asian countries to intensify measures to counterbalance Beijing. Thus, the China question was a natural focal point for Jaishankar during both Laos and Japan visits.</p>

<h2><strong>China, A Critical Cog In The Quad</strong></h2>

<p>At the Quad Foreign Ministers' meeting, the four member countries of the grouping released a joint statement which amply addressed their common concerns with regard to China's belligerent posturing in the Indo-Pacific. The Quad members have long resisted the notion that the formulation of the grouping is directed at countering Beijing, instead emphasising that it seeks to harness the emerging opportunities of collective cooperation in the Indo-Pacific. There is no denying, however, that the China factor is a critical cog in the Quad wheel. The latest joint statement released by the Quad countries evidently suggests that concerns regarding China's overtures in the Indo-Pacific appear to be taking centre-stage in the thinking of the grouping. The joint statement expressed concerns over the evolving situation in the East and South China Seas, alluding to China's unilateral actions by use of force and coercion. The statement decried, without naming, Beijing's use of coast guard and maritime militia in the South China Sea attributing it to 'dangerous manoeuvres' in the region.&nbsp;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Jaishankar's individual remarks about the state of India-China relations have further garnered attention. Upon being questioned about India's relations with China, Jaishankar unequivocally stated that the bilateral ties between the two neighbours are 'not doing very well'. This admission appears to present continuity in India's enduring pushback against China in light of border skirmishes and conflict since 2020. However, in the Indo-Pacific context, a shift appears to be underway in India's approach towards China. In the past, India's response to China's aggressive overtures in the Indo-Pacific had remained relatively subdued. In its stead, Jaishankar's recent comments at the Quad summit and the joint statement demonstrate India's willingness to push back against China in the Indo-Pacific context as well.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>An Eye On Distant Seas</strong></h2>

<p>The question arises, what explains India's pushback against China's unilateral actions in the South China Sea? Even though the South China Sea geography does not fall under India's primary maritime area of interest, it remains vital for India's myriad strategic interests, such as the protection of Sea Lines of Communication (SLOCs), energy security, etc. Moreover, India's sustained advocacy for a free, open, inclusive, and rules-based order at sea, emphasising the need for adherence to the United Nations Convention on the Law of the Sea (UNCLOS), makes it imperative for New Delhi to respond critically against Chinese attempts to change the status quo in the region.</p>

<p>Within the wider Indo-Pacific, China's continued attempts to foray into the Indian Ocean region, more recently by way of sending survey and surveillance vessels into the region, have prompted an enduring security dilemma in New Delhi, of People's Liberation Army Navy's (PLAN) imminent launch of carrier task force patrols in the Indian Ocean by 2025. Thus, upping the ante against China in the Indo-Pacific appears to be a logical progression in India's continued efforts to counter Beijing's advances in geographies of India's core interests at sea.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>India's Message</strong></h2>

<p>Notably, Jaishankar has displayed nuance and complex thinking in India's plans to counter the multipronged challenge that China poses. While on the Indo-Pacific front, India has sought to actively engage in minilateral groupings to counter China, upon being asked if New Delhi would encourage third-party intervention for the resolution of the India-China territorial border conflict along the LAC, Jaishankar reiterated that only bilateral engagement based on 'mutual respect, mutual interest, and mutual sensitivity' can restore normalcy.</p>

<p>The message is very clear: New Delhi will not relent in pressing ahead with its pushback against Beijing even as the door is open for China to recalibrate its anti-India positioning.</p>

<p><br />
<em>(Harsh V Pant is Vice President for Studies at ORF. Sayantan Haldar works with the Maritime Initiative at ORF)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/qcp8g1kg_south-china_625x300_31_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-released-dogs-on-palestinian-detainees-un-report-flags-torture-6229598]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Used Dogs, Waterboarding On Palestinian Detainees: UN Flags "Torture"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-released-dogs-on-palestinian-detainees-un-report-flags-torture-6229598]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 31 Jul 2024 13:02:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Since October 7, thousands of Palestinians -- including medics, patients, residents and captured fighters -- have been taken from Gaza to Israel.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Palestinians detained by Israel during the Gaza war have largely been held in secret and in some cases subjected to treatment that may amount to torture, the United Nations said on Wednesday.</p>

<p>Since October 7, thousands of Palestinians -- including medics, patients, residents and captured fighters -- have been taken from Gaza to Israel, "usually shackled and blindfolded", while thousands more have been detained in the West Bank and Israel, the OHCHR UN human rights office said in a report.</p>

<p>"They have generally been held in secret, without being given a reason for their detention, access to a lawyer or effective judicial review," OHCHR said.</p>

<p>At least 53 detainees from Gaza and the West Bank have died in Israeli detention since the Gaza war began on October 7, the report found.</p>

<p>"The testimonies gathered by my office and other entities indicate a range of appalling acts, such as waterboarding and the release of dogs on detainees, amongst other acts, in flagrant violation of international human rights law and international humanitarian law," said UN human rights chief Volker Turk.</p>

<p>He called on all parties to the conflict to implement a ceasefire, ensure full respect for international law and ensure accountability for violations and abuses.</p>

<p>The report, "Detention in the context of the escalation of hostilities in Gaza", covers the period from October 7 to June 30.</p>

<p>It said that there were "reasonable grounds to believe" that since October 7, Israel and Palestinian armed groups had "committed gross violations and abuses... of the rights to life, liberty and freedom from torture and other ill-treatment as well as rape and other forms of sexual violence, all of which may also amount to war crimes".</p>

<p>The October 7 Hamas attack on southern Israel that started the war resulted in the deaths of 1,197 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on official Israeli figures.</p>

<p>Hamas also seized 251 hostages, 111 of whom are still held captive in Gaza, including 39 the military says are dead.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory military campaign in Gaza has killed at least 39,400 people, according to the health ministry in the Hamas-run Palestinian territory, which does not provide details on civilian and militant deaths.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/4dmff0tg_israel-hamas-war_625x300_31_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Report said 53 detainees from Gaza and the West Bank have died in Israeli detention since October 7]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/india-is-not-responsible-for-climate-crisis-but-commonwealth-head-patricia-scotland-6229306]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India Is Not Responsible For Climate Crisis, But...: Commonwealth Head]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/india-is-not-responsible-for-climate-crisis-but-commonwealth-head-patricia-scotland-6229306]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 31 Jul 2024 12:39:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India is not historically responsible for the climate crisis but it should not emulate polluting practices of the West from the 19th century during its development, Commonwealth Secretary General Patricia Scotland has said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India is not historically responsible for the climate crisis but it should not emulate polluting practices of the West from the 19th century during its development, Commonwealth Secretary General Patricia Scotland has said.</p>

<p>In an interview with news agency PTI, Scotland said India has the opportunity to lead a just and equitable energy transition by sharing expertise and technology within the 56-nation club called Commonwealth, which represents 2.7 billion people.</p>

<p>She also said that India can exemplify a new, clean and safe development model that can serve as a beacon of hope for the Global South.</p>

<p>"India is a developing country, which was not historically responsible for creating this (climate) crisis. So, India is in a similar position to many of the Global South countries. And that is absolutely true," the Commonwealth secretary general said.</p>

<p>Despite not causing the crisis, she said, India is suffering from severe climate consequences, including extreme heat, floods and intense monsoons, and must take action.</p>

<p>"Look at the level of heat in some of the cities in India, look at the floods, look at the monsoons. Our people are suffering. So there is a responsibility on all of us, responsibility which India has committed herself to and has taken action on to make it better," Scotland said.</p>

<p>The Commonwealth secretary general told PTI that India should not emulate the West's development model, which failed and led to the climate crisis.</p>

<p>"Why should India wish to emulate that which others have done before ... (and) failed? I would be very disappointed if India was reaching back to 18th and 19th century solutions and repeating what others have done.</p>

<p>"It is not going to wash for us to say (that) because they (West) created a nightmare from which we are now suffering and dying... (it) justifies us continuing to do what they did. I think we are better than that," she said.</p>

<p>At the 2015 UN climate talks in Paris, countries committed to limiting the global average temperature rise to 1.5 degrees Celsius above the pre-industrial average to avoid the worst impacts of climate change.</p>

<p>The Earth's global surface temperature has already increased by around 1.2 degrees Celsius due to the rapidly increasing concentration of greenhouse gases, primarily carbon dioxide and methane, in the atmosphere.</p>

<p>Poor and middle-income countries often argue that the current global warming is disproportionately caused by the historical emissions of developed countries during their industrialisation phases. They contend that they should have the right to use fossil fuels to alleviate poverty and achieve economic growth.</p>

<p>Scotland said that unlike the West during its development, India understands the consequences of its actions and has the opportunity to lead by creating a new and regenerative model of development using a circular economy.</p>

<p>"India and Prime Minister Mr. Modi have done some extraordinary things in terms of building new cities. What if India can become the exemplar of how you create a regenerative model of development using a circular economy, which actually works out," the Commonwealth secretary general said.</p>

<p>"I would be disappointed if the hope that India is for the Global South were to be diminished. I would be so saddened because India knows that because she has revolutionised development with so many technological innovative approaches which others are emulating. I would want them to emulate the best in India," she added.</p>

<p>Scotland said India's renewable energy makes up "35 per cent of its energy consumption" and the initiatives it is leading, such as the International Solar Alliance and the Coalition for Disaster Resilient Infrastructure, show what is possible through innovation and collaboration.</p>

<p>As part of its updated national climate plan to limit global warming to 1.5 degrees Celsius, India aims to increase the share of non-fossil power capacity to 50 per cent by 2030, which is conditional on international support.</p>

<p>At present, India has a total installed power capacity of 446 gigawatts, with renewable energy accounting for 195 gigawatts.</p>

<p>It also aims to reduce the emissions intensity of its GDP (the amount of greenhouse gas emissions per unit of GDP) by 45 per cent by 2030 compared to the 2005 levels.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/0baidvp_commonwealth-secretary-general-patricia-scotland-ians_625x300_31_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[India not responsible for climate crisis, but shouldn't emulate polluting practices of West, she said.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-over-2-years-of-war-russia-and-ukraine-are-also-fighting-fake-news-6229386]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[In Over 2 Years Of War, Russia And Ukraine Are Also Fighting Fake News]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-over-2-years-of-war-russia-and-ukraine-are-also-fighting-fake-news-6229386]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 31 Jul 2024 12:34:00 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Disinformation and propaganda, long mainstays of war, have been digitally supercharged in the battle for Ukraine, the biggest conflict the world has seen since the advent of smartphones and social media.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In early April, some residents of Kharkiv received a series of chilling text messages from government officials telling them to flee the city before Russian forces surrounded it.</p>

<p>"Due to the threat of enemy encirclement, we urge the civilian population of Kharkiv leave the city by April 22," said one alert, which bore the logo of the State Emergencies Service of Ukraine and mapped out safe escape routes on a slick infographic.</p>

<p>It was fake. Volodymyr Tymoshko knew immediately. He's the police chief of Kharkiv region and would have been one of the first to find out about any official evacuation plans.</p>

<p>"Residents started getting these notifications en masse," the 50-year-old told Reuters as he shared a screenshot of the alert, sent as Russian troops were massing at the border 30 km away.</p>

<p>"This is a psychological operation, it triggers panic. What would an average citizen think when they receive such a message?"</p>

<p>Disinformation and propaganda, long mainstays of war, have been digitally supercharged in the battle for Ukraine, the biggest conflict the world has seen since the advent of smartphones and social media.</p>

<p>Tymoshko said he received about 10 similar messages via SMS and Telegram messenger in April and early May, the weeks leading up to Russia's offensive in northeastern Ukraine that began on May 10 and opened up a new front in the war.</p>

<p>A Ukrainian security official, who requested anonymity to discuss sensitive matters, said the Russians frequently sent large numbers of text messages from devices attached to an Orlan-10 long-range reconnaissance drone which can penetrate dozens of kilometres into Ukrainian airspace.</p>

<p>The devices, known as Leer-3 systems, imitate cellular base stations that phones automatically connect to in search of coverage, he added.</p>

<p>The phone barrage was accompanied by a social media blitz as Russian troops advanced on Kharkiv, according Andriy Kovalenko, head of Ukraine's Centre for Countering Disinformation (CCD), a branch of the national security council.</p>

<p>The average number of social media posts classed as disinformation about the war by Ukrainian authorities spiked to over 2,500 a day when the Kharkiv offensive began in May, up from 200 a day in March, data compiled by the CCD shows.</p>

<p>The CCD chief told Reuters that Ukrainian intelligence had assessed that disinformation campaigns were primarily carried out by Russia's FSB security service and military intelligence agency, commonly known as the GRU.</p>

<p>Russia's foreign ministry and the FSB didn't respond to a request for comment on the Ukrainian assertions, while Reuters was unable to contact the GRU.</p>

<p>Moscow has accused Ukraine and the West of unleashing a sophisticated information war against Russia, using the West's major media, public relations and technology assets to sow false and biased narratives about Russia and the war.</p>

<p>The Ukrainian security official acknowledged his country used online campaigns in an attempt to boost anti-war sentiment among Russia's population, although he characterised this effort as "strategic communications" to spread accurate information about the conflict.</p>

<h3><strong>BOTS AND MICROTARGETING</strong></h3>

<p>Reuters interviewed nine people with knowledge of the information and disinformation war being waged in parallel with battlefield operations, including Ukrainian officials, disinformation trackers and security analysts.</p>

<p>The Ukrainian security official who requested anonymity said that since the full-scale invasion of 2022, intelligence agencies had shut down 86 Russian bot farms located in Ukraine which controlled a collective 3 million social media accounts with an estimated audience reach of 12 million people.</p>

<p>Such facilities are rooms filled with banks of specialised computing equipment that can register hundreds of fake accounts daily on social media networks to pump out false information, the official added, citing one farm that was found by security services in the city of Vinnytsia in central Ukraine last year.</p>

<p>Kovalenko said that at present, the most significant sources of online Russian disinformation were TikTok in Ukraine and Telegram in Europe. Both are widely used in Ukraine.</p>

<p>He said that earlier this year, TikTok had shut down about 30 of the 90 accounts that Ukraine had flagged as Russia-affiliated disinformation spreaders, adding that new accounts often popped up to replace those taken down.</p>

<p>TikTok told Reuters its guidelines prohibited false or misleading content, adding that it had closed down 13 covert influence networks operating from Russia in recent years.</p>

<p>"We prohibit and constantly work to disrupt attempts to engage in covert influence operations by manipulating our platform and/or harmfully misleading our community," a spokesperson said.</p>

<p>Disinformation networks are groups of accounts controlled by the same entity, and often used to push a coordinated narrative.</p>

<p>Telegram said it was developing a tool to add verified information to posts.</p>

<p>"It is Telegram's belief that the best way to combat misinformation is not with censorship but with easy access to verified information," a spokesperson added.</p>

<p>Kharkiv Mayor Ihor Terekhov told Reuters that the Russians were trying to sow panic and distrust, citing an example of social media posts claiming the main road to Kyiv was being resurfaced so that the mayor could flee faster when the Russians came - something he dismissed as a lie.</p>

<p>"They are trying to frighten the population so that people feel uncomfortable and leave the city," he said in an interview in Kharkiv in late May.</p>

<p>By that time, the frontlines of the conflict in the northeast had stabilised about 20 km from the edge of the city after the Russian offensive had initially gained territory to the north before being blunted by Ukrainian reinforcements.</p>

<p>Maria Avdeeva, a Kharkiv-based security analyst who focuses on Russian disinformation, showed Reuters an infographic map, bearing Ukraine's state emblem of a trident, posted on Facebook in early April - around the same time as police chief Tymoshko was sent a different evacuation map in a direct Telegram message.</p>

<p>Unperturbed by a loud explosion from a glide bomb a few kilometres away, she explained how the map and accompanying text included fake road closures and claims that missile strikes were expected in specified areas around the city soon.</p>

<p>Microtargeting - which analyses people's online data to target particular individuals and audiences with specific messages, much like targeted advertising - is complicating the CCD's task of tracking influence campaigns and countering false narratives, Kovalenko said.</p>

<p>"This activity is notably very tactical," said John Hultquist, chief analyst at U.S. cybersecurity firm Mandiant, referring to Russian disinformation campaigns in Ukraine.</p>

<p>"We've seen targeting all the way down to the Ukrainian soldiers in the trenches."</p>

<h3><strong>AIRSTRIKE TAKES OUT TV TOWER</strong></h3>

<p>Ukrainians are particularly vulnerable to digital disinformation; more than three-quarters of the population get their news from social media, far more than any other source of information, according to a study commissioned by USAid in 2023.</p>

<p>That is considerably higher than in any of the 24 European countries surveyed by a 2024 Reuters Institute for the Study of Journalism report, which averaged a rate of 44%.</p>

<p>In late April, as Moscow's forces massed on the border near Kharkiv, a Russian airstrike took out Kharkiv's main television tower, hindering the city's access to information.</p>

<p>Dramatic footage obtained by Reuters showed the main mast of the television tower breaking off and falling to the ground.</p>

<p>While the Kharkiv offensive led to a significant spike in disinformation activity, there have been similar Russian campaigns over the course of the war, according to the people interviewed.</p>

<p>The head of the CCD highlighted a Russian campaign in October 2023 aimed at driving home the idea that Ukraine was facing a tough winter and defeat in the war.</p>

<p>Osavul, a Ukrainian disinformation tracking company, showed Reuters its data for this campaign, which it called "black winter". It counted 914 messages posted by 549 actors which collectively received nearly 25 million views.</p>

<p>Nonetheless, according to Kovalenko, the sheer scale and frequency of Russian influence operations meant Ukrainians were becoming more suspicious of the information they receive, blunting their impact.</p>

<p>The disinformation push during Russia's initial advance towards Kharkiv at the start of the invasion in 2022 - when they got much closer to the city - contributed to the panic and shock that led to hundreds of thousands of residents fleeing, several officials and experts said.</p>

<p>This time around, only a small number left Kharkiv, even though the amount of disinformation messaging aimed at the city was double the level in March 2022, according to CCD data.</p>

<p>Despite the near-daily missiles and bombs falling on the city - attacks that intensified this May - 1.3 million people remain, according to Kharkiv Mayor Terekhov, roughly the same as before Russia's latest military incursion in the region.</p>

<p>The comparative lack of panic also reflects Ukrainians' increasing familiarity with living under attack.</p>

<p>Reuters spoke to nearly two dozen Kharkiv residents in the second half of May, when the city was being hit by several bombs or missiles a day.</p>

<p>Most said they felt no desire to leave and shrugged off the danger, saying they had become used to it. Several said they had stopped following the news.</p>

<p>"This is a psychological mechanism, we get used to danger," Kharkiv-based psychologist Iryna Markevych said.</p>

<p>In late May, Reuters correspondents dived to the ground for cover when they heard the whistle of a guided bomb piercing the air. Seemingly unfazed, mothers with pushchairs continued to stroll through the park and people bathed at a public fountain.</p>

<p>Yulia Oleshko, 55, a nanny pushing a buggy in a central Kharkiv park, said the best way to get through the nightmare was to simply focus on getting on with everyday life.</p>

<p>"Yesterday I was thinking: walking around Kharkiv is walking around a minefield ... but I try not to dwell on these thoughts of fear, otherwise one might fall into depression," she said.</p>

<p>"We abstract ourselves, otherwise we won't survive."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/k8aattc_russiaukraine-war_625x300_31_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Ukrainians are particularly vulnerable to digital disinformation (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/at-tiktoks-parent-company-57-hospitalised-after-mass-food-poisoning-6229314]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[At TikTok's Parent Company, 57 Hospitalised After Mass Food Poisoning]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/at-tiktoks-parent-company-57-hospitalised-after-mass-food-poisoning-6229314]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 31 Jul 2024 12:25:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A mass food poisoning incident led 60 people to fall sick with symptoms of gastroenteritis at the Singapore office of TikTok's parent company, ByteDance on Tuesday. At least 57 of them had to be hospitalized after the incident.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A mass food poisoning incident led to 60 people falling sick with symptoms of gastroenteritis at the Singapore office of TikTok's parent company, ByteDance on Tuesday. At least 57 of them had to be hospitalised after the incident.</p>

<p>According to local media reports, seventeen ambulances had to be sent to the building to treat those who fell sick.</p>

<p>In the wake of this incident, The Singapore Food Agency (SFA), in a joint statement with the city-state's Ministry of Health (MOH), said that food operators need to ensure good food safety practices. T</p>

<p>The BBC reports that no food is prepared or cooked at the ByteDance offices as it uses third-party caterers to supply food. Their statement added, "SFA will not hesitate to take enforcement action against errant food operators," the statement added."</p>

<p>A ByteDance Spokesperson has also reportedly told the BBC that they take the health of their employees very seriously and they have taken immediate steps to support all affected employees with emergency services.</p>

<p>While Byte Dance has said that they will be looking into what caused this mass food poisoning for their employees, an investigation is underway for the health and food safety officials of the city-state.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/vad4j7l8_bytedance-_625x300_31_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Byte Dance has said that they will be looking into what caused this mass food poisoning (file).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/not-celebrating-anymore-video-shows-hamas-chiefs-reaction-to-oct-7-attack-6229312]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Not Celebrating Anymore": Video Shows Hamas Chief React To Oct 7 Attack]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/not-celebrating-anymore-video-shows-hamas-chiefs-reaction-to-oct-7-attack-6229312]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 31 Jul 2024 12:23:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hours after an Israeli strike in Tehran killed Hamas chief Ismail Haniyeh, a video purportedly showing him celebrating the October 7 assault by Hamas on Israel has surface online.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hours after an Israeli strike in Tehran killed Hamas chief Ismail Haniyeh, a video purportedly showing him celebrating the October 7 assault by Hamas on Israel has surface online.</p>

<p>"This was Hamas chief Haniyeh's reaction to the Hamas massacre on October 7. He's not celebrating anymore," Israel War Room said while sharing the video on X.</p>

<p>The Israel War Room X account is based in the US, a Reuters report claimed. NDTV cannot independently verify the authenticity of the video.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">This was Hamas chief Haniyeh's reaction to the Hamas massacre on October 7.<br />
<br />
He's not celebrating anymore. ? <a href="https://t.co/xYsPsSNHZ3">pic.twitter.com/xYsPsSNHZ3</a></p>
â€” Israel War Room (@IsraelWarRoom) <a href="https://twitter.com/IsraelWarRoom/status/1818489113336529293?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 31, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>In the video, Haniyeh can be seen watching Hamas operatives waving guns on a truck driving through a desert on a TV screen. The clip shows Haniyeh surrounded by several others smiling at the screen before bowing his head and kneeling to offer a prayer.</p>

<p>The Hamas chief and one of his bodyguards were killed after their residence was targeted in Iran, the Palestinian group said in a statement today.</p>

<p>Hamas said Ismail Haniyeh was killed in "a treacherous Zionist raid on his residence in Tehran" Tuesday morning. The group said an investigation is on to find out more details about the attack.</p>

<p>Haniyeh was in the Iranian capital to attend the swearing-in of Iran's president Masoud Pezeshkian.</p>

<p>"Brother, leader, mujahid Ismail Haniyeh, the head of the movement, died in a Zionist strike on his headquarters in Tehran after he participated in the inauguration of the new (Iranian) president," the statement read.</p>

<p>Haniyeh was elected head of the Hamas political bureau in 2017 to succeed Khaled Meshaal. Considered a pragmatist, Haniyeh lived in exile and split his time between Turkey and Qatar.</p>

<p>Israel had vowed to kill Ismail Haniyeh and destroy the Hamas group after October 7 attack that resulted in the deaths of 1,195 people, mostly civilians.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/2i0sinb_ismail-haniyeh_625x300_31_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ismail-haniyeh-unacceptable-political-murder-russia-after-hamas-chief-killed-in-strike-6229300]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Unacceptable Political Murder": Russia After Hamas Chief Killed In Strike]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ismail-haniyeh-unacceptable-political-murder-russia-after-hamas-chief-killed-in-strike-6229300]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 31 Jul 2024 12:21:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA["This is an absolutely unacceptable political murder, and it will lead to further escalation of tensions," RIA cited Deputy Foreign Minister Mikhail Bogdanov as saying.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The killing of Hamas' chief political leader <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-chief-ismail-haniyeh-killed-in-irans-capital-report-6228024" target="_blank">Ismail Haniyeh</a> is "an absolutely unacceptable political murder", a deputy Russian foreign minister told RIA state news agency on Wednesday.</p>

<p>"This is an absolutely unacceptable political murder, and it will lead to further escalation of tensions," RIA cited Deputy Foreign Minister Mikhail Bogdanov as saying.</p>

<p>Bogdanov said the killing will also have a negative impact on ceasefire talks in Gaza, RIA added.</p>

<p>Russia, which has relationships with Arab countries, Iran and Hamas as well as with Israel, has frequently condemned violence in the region and accused the United States of ignoring the need for an independent Palestinian state.</p>

<p>Ismail Haniyeh was killed in Iran on Wednesday, the Palestinian group Hamas and Iran's elite Revolutionary Guards said in separate statements.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/bvoc48po_hamas-leader-killed_625x300_31_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Ismail Haniyeh was killed in Iran on Wednesday (Reuters)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/australia-launches-worlds-first-life-saving-deadly-peanut-allergy-treatment-for-babies-6229123]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Australia Launches Life-Saving Peanut Allergy Treatment For Babies]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/australia-launches-worlds-first-life-saving-deadly-peanut-allergy-treatment-for-babies-6229123]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 31 Jul 2024 11:59:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Eligible babies will receive daily doses of peanut powder for two years to build up their tolerance, said officials announcing the initiative on Wednesday. Over time, the infants will be given increasing doses to reduce their peanut sensitivity.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Australian children with potentially deadly peanut allergies will be offered life-saving treatment in a nationwide programme touted as a world first.</p>

<p>Eligible babies will receive daily doses of peanut powder for two years to build up their tolerance, said officials announcing the initiative on Wednesday.</p>

<p>Over time, the infants will be given increasing doses in the hope of reducing their sensitivity to peanuts, under the supervision of doctors at 10 paediatric hospitals around the country.</p>

<p>It is the first national peanut allergy treatment programme offered in hospitals outside of a clinical trial setting, said Kirsten Perrett, head of oral immunotherapy at the National Allergy Centre of Excellence.</p>

<p>At the end of the two years, a food allergy test will determine if the treatment has led to a remission.</p>

<p>"Ultimately we want to change the trajectory of allergic disease in Australia so that more children can go to school without the risk of a life-threatening peanut reaction," Perrett said.</p>

<p>Previously, families have been told to ensure their children strictly avoid foods with peanuts.</p>

<p>Australian children have some of the highest rates of food allergies in the world.</p>

<p>Peanut allergies affect three percent of Australian children by the time they are 12 months old, government data shows.</p>

<p>Of those, only 20 percent will outgrow their allergy by the time they are teenagers.</p>

<p>Nine-month-old Hunter Chatwin, who is among those in the free treatment programme, started developing hives after eating peanut butter.</p>

<p>"We are taking part in the programme to try and improve his chance of being able to safely eat peanut in the future," Hunter's mother Kirsten said.</p>

<p>"Many families are desperate to protect their children from allergic reactions and anaphylaxis," she said.</p>

<p>"To have this programme available and free at public hospitals is a game-changer."</p>

<p>If successful, the programme will be rolled out more broadly, including in regional and remote areas.</p>

<p>Deaths from peanut allergies are rare in Australia, but almost 20 percent of the population has an allergic disease, data from Australia's leading allergy institute found.</p>

<p>This figure is estimated to grow by 70 percent by 2050, impacting 7.7 million Australians.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/jcnnfmr_babies_625x300_10_May_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Peanut allergies affect 3% of Australian children by the time they are 12 months old (Representative)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/thousands-protest-in-venezuela-opposing-nicolas-maduros-disputed-poll-win-6228998]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Thousands Protest In Venezuela Opposing Nicolas Maduro's Disputed Poll Win]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/thousands-protest-in-venezuela-opposing-nicolas-maduros-disputed-poll-win-6228998]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 31 Jul 2024 11:38:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Many in the crowd wore white -- the favorite color of opposition leader Maria Corina Machado -- or national football team shirts and caps. A sea of yellow, blue and red Venezuelan flags also filled the avenue, some worn as capes.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A young violinist accompanied thousands of opposition supporters belting out the Venezuelan national anthem Tuesday at a rally in Caracas, in a peaceful, but firm, rejection of an election victory claimed by strongman <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/video/nicolas-maduro-claims-victory-in-disputed-election-opposition-rejects-result-819828" target="_blank">Nicolas Maduro.</a></p>

<p>Many in the crowd wore white -- the favorite color of opposition leader Maria Corina Machado -- or national football team shirts and caps.</p>

<p>A sea of yellow, blue and red Venezuelan flags also filled the avenue, some worn as capes.</p>

<p>"You can see it, you can feel it, Edmundo is president!" sang the crowd, a chant that rhymes in Spanish.</p>

<p>"Maduro dictator!" shouted some, as others recited: "No to fraud!" and "We are not afraid!"</p>

<p>The demonstrators were among millions of Venezuelans who reject the election win given to Maduro by the regime-aligned CNE electoral council but questioned internationally.</p>

<p>The opposition has cried foul, claiming the rightful winner is 74-year-old Edmundo Gonzalez Urrutia, himself reluctantly thrust to the top of the ticket after Machado was kicked out of the race by authorities.</p>

<p>Against a wall outside the UN offices looking out over the rally, a teenager, his face covered by a flag, banged together two pots, a symbol of protest in Latin America. Incessantly.</p>

<p>At his feet, a small sign read: "We have the evidence, Edmundo is president."</p>

<p>Another youngster skillfully climbed a tall tree to hang a giant Venezuelan flag. People down below applaud.</p>

<h3><strong>We won</strong></h3>

<p>Machado and Gonzalez Urrutia arrived at the rally on top of the same open truck they had used on the campaign, as excited people pulled out their cellphones to capture the moment.</p>

<p>"I told you we were going to win and we won!" said Machado, as the crowd cheered.</p>

<p>The leadership have said they have the voting records to "prove" Gonzalez Urrutia's victory, and by a large margin.</p>

<p>The CNE had given 51 percent to Maduro, though it has not released a breakdown of the results.</p>

<p>Its website has been down since election day.</p>

<p>"We challenge the CNE to give us the tallies. What is the delay? What is the fear?" charged Machado.</p>

<p>"Results are not negotiated. The only thing we are willing to negotiate is a transition with guarantees for all."</p>

<h3><strong>I have faith</strong></h3>

<p>The authorities' response to the protests has been belligerent.</p>

<p>Security forces fired tear gas and rubber bullets at protesters Monday and an NGO said 11 people have been killed. Dozens more were injured.</p>

<p>On Tuesday, Maduro said the opposition would be held responsible for "criminal violence."</p>

<p>In a rambling speech, in which he railed against the United States, imperialism and fascism, Maduro said he had ordered a special deployment of the armed forces against opposition "comanditos" -- volunteer organizing committees.</p>

<p>He claims they are financed by external forces to create chaos in Venezuela.</p>

<p>Gonzalez Urrutia, for his part, urged the armed forces Tuesday not to "repress" the will of the people, saying "there is no reason for so much persecution."</p>

<p>Monday's protests started in the poorest neighborhoods of the capital hardest hit by the economic crisis marked by a GDP drop of 80 percent in 10 years, and the emigration of more than seven million Venezuelans.</p>

<p>"People are tired," said Thais Farais, a 31-year-old administrator from one such area who attended Tuesday's opposition rally.</p>

<p>"They stole the election, 100 percent," said another opposition supporter goer, 25-year-old Jonathan Rada.</p>

<p>"But I have faith that we will get through it."</p>

<p>As the demonstration drew to a close, attendees once more sang the national anthem. In one voice.</p>

<p>But as they left, groups were targeted by teargas, apparently randomly.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/34n1svhg_venezuela-protests-peaceful_625x300_31_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["Maduro dictator!" shouted some as others recited "No to fraud, we are not afraid!" (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/ai-future/olympics-2024-paris-olympics-ai-surveillance-france-is-using-ai-surveillance-systems-to-secure-paris-olympics-6228932]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[France Is Using AI Surveillance Systems To Secure Paris Olympics]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/ai-future/olympics-2024-paris-olympics-ai-surveillance-france-is-using-ai-surveillance-systems-to-secure-paris-olympics-6228932]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 31 Jul 2024 11:27:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The AI system does not collect biometric data, but instead recognises individuals in crowds using unique identification. The algorithm captures and processes the unique physiology of persons and identifies behavior that is suspicious.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Paris Summer Olympic 2024 has had about 28 million viewers tune in to watch the opening ceremony. In person, the event is set to witness an estimated 16 million sports enthusiasts flocking the French capital.<br />
<br />
Securing Paris has become a massive challenge for the French authorities amidst rising threats to the mega event, especially in the backdrop of two global wars that are ongoing in Gaza and Ukraine. According to an AP report, 45000 police personnels and 10,000 soldiers were deployed for the opening ceremony. But what has stood out in the government's response has been the use of Artificial Intelligence for surveillance purposes.</p>

<p>According to a report in Bloomberg Law, The AI system being deployed uses an algorithm to screen CCTV footage from across the French capital to detect any suspicious movements- like persons moving in the opposite direction to the crowd or carrying a gun.</p>

<p>French authorities have allowed AI surveillance at the Paris Olympics using a special law that is only applicable for a specific time period. Although temporary, this decision marks the first time an event of such massive scale has deployed an AI system for surveillance activity.</p>

<p>The AI system does not collect biometric data, but instead recognises individuals in crowds using unique identification. The algorithm captures and processes the unique physiology of persons and identifies behavior that is suspicious.</p>

<p>AI surveillance tools often require collection of biometric data. Studies have shown as low as 0.1 percent efficiency or performing certain types of crime identification. Concerns about inherent bias built into the system through training sets has also raised questions regarding deploying these Ai systems.</p>

<p>Apart from these, there is also the difficulty in establishing different cultural norms for an event that draws people from around the world.</p>

<p>In India, AI systems have made their way to the policing systems. An AI enabled video analytics platform dubbed "Jarvis" has been deployed by the Uttar Pradesh Police. The platform monitors real-time CCTV footage from 700 operative cameras across state prisons. Elsewhere, AI technologies have also been used in Drone systems in India, mainly for military and security surveillance.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/pcepp0s_paris-olympics-security_625x300_31_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Paris Summer Olympics started on 26 June and will go on till 10 August (Disclaimer: AI Generated Image)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/woman-comes-home-to-strangers-in-pool-after-tenant-rents-it-out-for-35-6228787]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Woman Comes Home To Strangers In Pool After Tenant Rents It Out For $35]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/woman-comes-home-to-strangers-in-pool-after-tenant-rents-it-out-for-35-6228787]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 31 Jul 2024 11:02:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The family paid $35 (approximately Rs 2,200) to use the pool, but the homeowner was not the one who posted the listing.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Canadian woman returned home on Sunday to find a family of strangers swimming in her outdoor pool. Maryse Chausse was shocked to discover the family of five, who claimed they rented the pool through Swimply, a mobile app that allows users to lease private pools by the hour.</p>

<p>The fake listing, which included photos of Ms Chausse's pool and deck, was posted without her knowledge or consent. The description allowed loud music, smoking, and alcohol, but forbade parties. Pets were also permitted, with the condition that renters would clean up after them. The family paid $35 (approximately Rs 2,200) to use the pool, but Ms Chausse was not the one who posted the listing.</p>

<p>Ms Chausse told <a href="https://www.noovo.info/nouvelle/sous-le-choc-sa-piscine-louee-sur-swimply-sans-son-consentement.htmlÂ ">Noovo Info</a> that there was a car in the parking lot when she got home. "There was a little family swimming in the pool, with three cute little girls," she said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Swimply removed the listing after Ms Chausse reported it, but couldn't explain how it was posted without her confirmation.&nbsp;</p>

<p>They responded to the incident, saying they had a "robust system" in place to prevent and detect fraudulent activities. "We partner with several best-in-class identity and fraud detection companies to ensure our platform maintains a high standard of safety and can be trusted by our community," the company said in a statement.</p>

<p>However, they acknowledged that "bad actors" sometimes attempt to misuse their platform, and when a fraudulent listing is flagged, they take immediate action.</p>

<p>Ms Chausse believes a former tenant, who moved out in 2022, may be responsible for the fake listing. "Is this the first time she's done this? I can't say. We're not always at home," she said.</p>

<p>She called the police, but they said they couldn't take action since the family hadn't committed a crime.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Maryse Chausse was concerned the situation could have gotten worse. She said the family replaced the ladder she removed after cleaning the pool, and that she could have performed a chemical treatment that morning, potentially putting the family at risk.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In May, a California couple discovered that a stranger rented their backyard pool through Swimply, just a week after they listed their home for sale. The couple only found out about the scam when their pool caretaker spotted an unapproved pool party.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-03/uab1ilu8_swimming-pool-generic_625x300_11_March_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The police couldn't take action since the family hadn't committed a crime.(Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/lavish-blue-lobster-wine-feast-for-king-charles-cost-france-rs-4-crore-6228723]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Lavish Blue Lobster, Wine Feast For King Charles Cost France Rs 4 Crore]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/lavish-blue-lobster-wine-feast-for-king-charles-cost-france-rs-4-crore-6228723]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 31 Jul 2024 10:52:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An extravagant feast for King Charles has cost the French government a whopping $500,000 million (Rs 4 crore), an audit report has found.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An extravagant feast for King Charles has cost the French government a whopping $500,000 million (Rs 4 crore), an <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ccomptes.fr/sites/default/files/2024-07/20240729-S2024-1053-Comptes-et-gestion-de-la-presidence-de-la-Republique_2023.pdf">audit report </a>has found.&nbsp;</p>

<p>President Emmanuel Macron's office planned a lavish spread during the monarch's visit in September last year. The grand state banquet held at the Palace of Versailles was attended by over 150 people as part of an attempt to boost a key alliance between the UK and France.</p>

<p>The event was a star-studded affair with actor Hugh Grant, football manager Arsene Wenger and Rolling Stone's Mick Jagger among those in attendance.</p>

<p>On the menu were blue lobster (a rare French delicacy), crab, poultry marinaded in champagne and a gratin of French mushrooms.&nbsp;</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">?? FRANCE: Images from the royal dinner at the ChÃ¢teau de Versailles/ Images from the royal dinner at the ChÃ¢teau de Versailles.<br />
<br />
50% of the population can't feed themselves and Macron spends the money with the pedophile King Charles ? <a href="https://t.co/5GYXMF6kDe">pic.twitter.com/5GYXMF6kDe</a></p>
â€” Angelus iustitiae (@AIustitiae) <a href="https://twitter.com/AIustitiae/status/1704948750827901233?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 21, 2023</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>An assortment of vintage wines, champagnes and a selection of international cheeses were on offer. For dessert, French macaroons with lychee, rose sorbet and raspberry compote were served.</p>

<p>In its annual report, the French auditing organisation Cour des Comptes warned that spending on state receptions had left the budget nearly $9 million in the red.</p>

<p>According to the new audit report, the whole dinner cost a total of $513,000 of which $179,000 was spent on food and $46,000 on drinks.</p>

<p>Speaking at the banquet, King Charles said President Macron's "generosity of spirit brings to mind how my family and I were so greatly moved by the tributes paid in France to my mother, the late queenâ€.</p>

<p>However, this was not the only lavish state dinner organised by the French government. In 2023, the president's office spent $446,000 on a dinner for Prime Minister Narendra Modi at the Louvre museum.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/1r21ps28_king-charles-afp-_625x300_17_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The grand state banquet held at the Palace of Versailles was attended by over 150 people]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ismail-haniyehs-assassination-will-not-go-unanswered-hamas-6228484]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Ismail Haniyeh's Assassination Will Not Go Unanswered": Hamas]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ismail-haniyehs-assassination-will-not-go-unanswered-hamas-6228484]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 31 Jul 2024 10:20:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A senior Hamas official said Wednesday that the killing of the Palestinian movement's chief Ismail Haniyeh "will not go unanswered".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A senior Hamas official said Wednesday that the killing of the Palestinian movement's chief Ismail Haniyeh "will not go unanswered".</p>

<p>"The assassination of leader Ismail Haniyeh is a cowardly act and will not go unanswered," Hamas political bureau member Musa Abu Marzuk said in a statement.</p>

<p>Hamas said Wednesday its political leader, Ismail Haniyeh, was killed in an Israeli strike in Iran, where he had been attending the inauguration of the country's new president.</p>

<p>Haniyeh's killing came after Israel on Tuesday struck a Hezbollah stronghold in southern Beirut, killing a senior commander of the Iran-backed group it said was responsible for a weekend rocket attack on the Israel-annexed Golan Heights.</p>

<p>"Brother, leader, mujahid Ismail Haniyeh, the head of the movement, died in a Zionist strike on his residence in Tehran after he participated in the inauguration of the new (Iranian) president," the Palestinian group said in a statement.</p>

<p>Iran's Revolutionary Guards also announced the death, saying Haniyeh's residence in Tehran was "hit" and he was killed along with a bodyguard.</p>

<p>"The residence of Ismail Haniyeh, head of the political office of Hamas Islamic Resistance, was hit in Tehran, and as a result of this incident, him and one of his bodyguards were martyred," said a statement by the Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps's Sepah news website.</p>

<p>The Guards said the cause of the incident was not immediately clear but it was "being investigated."&nbsp;</p>

<p>Haniyeh had travelled to Tehran to attend Tuesday's swearing-in ceremony of Iranian President Masoud Pezeshkian.</p>

<p>The Israeli army declined to comment on foreign media reports.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/3mf50igo_ismail-haniyeh_625x300_31_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-ismail-haniyeh-rose-from-being-activist-to-chief-of-hamas-6228472]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How Ismail Haniyeh Rose From Being Activist To Chief Of Hamas]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-ismail-haniyeh-rose-from-being-activist-to-chief-of-hamas-6228472]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 31 Jul 2024 10:16:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ismail Haniyeh, the Hamas leader who was killed in Iran, was the tough-talking face of the Palestinian group's international diplomacy as war raged back in Gaza, where three of his sons were killed in an Israeli airstrike.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ismail Haniyeh, the Hamas leader who was killed in Iran, was the tough-talking face of the Palestinian group's international diplomacy as war raged back in Gaza, where three of his sons were killed in an Israeli airstrike.</p>

<p>But despite the rhetoric, he was seen by many diplomats as a moderate compared to the more hardline members of the Iran-backed group inside Gaza.</p>

<p>Appointed to the Hamas top job in 2017, Haniyeh moved between Turkey and Qatar's capital Doha, escaping the travel curbs of the blockaded Gaza Strip and enabling him to act as a negotiator in ceasefire talks or to talk to Hamas' ally Iran.</p>

<p>"All the agreements of normalisation that you (Arab states) signed with (Israel) will not end this conflict," Haniyeh declared on Qatar-based Al Jazeera television shortly after Hamas fighters launched the Oct. 7 raid.</p>

<p>Israel's response to the strike has been a military campaign that has killed more than 35,000 people inside Gaza so far, according to health authorities in the territory.</p>

<h3><strong>SONS KILLED IN AIRSTRIKE</strong></h3>

<p>Three of Haniyeh's sons - Hazem, Amir and Mohammad - were killed on April 10 when an Israeli air strike struck the car they were driving, Hamas said. Haniyeh also lost four of his grandchildren, three girls and a boy, in the attack, Hamas said.</p>

<p>Haniyeh had denied Israeli assertions that his sons were fighters for the group, and said "the interests of the Palestinian people are placed ahead of everything" when asked if their killing would impact truce talks.</p>

<p>For all the tough language in public, Arab diplomats and officials had viewed him as relatively pragmatic compared with more hardline voices inside Gaza, where the military wing of Hamas planned the Oct. 7 attack.</p>

<p>While telling Israel's military they would find themselves "drowning in the sands of Gaza", he and his predecessor as Hamas leader, Khaled Meshaal, had shuttled around the region for talks over a Qatari-brokered ceasefire deal with Israel that would include exchanging hostages for Palestinians in Israeli jails as well as more aid for Gaza.</p>

<p>Israel regards the entire Hamas leadership as terrorists, and has accused Haniyeh, Meshaal and others of continuing to "pull the strings of the Hamas terror organisation".</p>

<p>But how much Haniyeh knew about the Oct. 7 assault beforehand is not clear. The plan, drawn up by the Hamas military council in Gaza, was such a closely guarded secret that some Hamas officials seemed shocked by its timing and scale.</p>

<p>Yet Haniyeh, a Sunni Muslim, had a major hand building up Hamas' fighting capacity, partly by nurturing ties with Shi'ite Muslim Iran, which makes no secret of its support for the group.</p>

<p>During the decade in which Haniyeh was Hamas' top leader in Gaza, Israel accused his leadership team of helping to divert humanitarian aid to the group's military wing. Hamas denied it.</p>

<h3><strong>SHUTTLE DIPLOMACY</strong></h3>

<p>When he left Gaza in 2017, Haniyeh was succeeded by Yahya Sinwar, a hardliner who spent more than two decades in Israeli prisons and whom Haniyeh had welcomed back to Gaza in 2011 after a prisoner exchange.</p>

<p>"Haniyeh is leading the political battle for Hamas with Arab governments," Adeeb Ziadeh, a specialist in Palestinian affairs at Qatar University, said before his death, adding that he had close ties with more hardline figures in the group and the military wing.</p>

<p>"He is the political and diplomatic front of Hamas," Ziadeh said.</p>

<p>Haniyeh and Meshaal had met officials in Egypt, which has also had a mediation role in the ceasefire talks. Haniyeh travelled in early November to Tehran to meet Iran's supreme leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei, Iranian state media reported.</p>

<p>Three senior officials told Reuters that Khamenei had told the Hamas leader in that meeting that Iran would not enter the war having not been told about it in advance. Hamas did not respond to requests for comment before Reuters published its report, and then issued a denial after its publication.</p>

<p>As a young man, Haniyeh was a student activist at the Islamic University in Gaza City. He joined Hamas when it was created in the First Palestinian intifada (uprising) in 1987. He was arrested and briefly deported.</p>

<p>Haniyeh became a protege of Hamas' founder Sheikh Ahmad Yassin, who like Haniyeh's family, was a refugee from the village of Al Jura near Ashkelon. In 1994, he told Reuters that Yassin was a model for young Palestinians, saying: "We learned from him love of Islam and sacrifice for this Islam and not to kneel down to these tyrants and despots."</p>

<p>By 2003 he was a trusted Yassin aide, photographed in Yassin's Gaza home holding a phone to the almost completely paralysed Hamas founder's ear so that he could take part in a conversation. Yassin was assassinated by Israel in 2004.</p>

<p>Haniyeh was an early advocate of Hamas entering politics. In 1994, he said that forming a political party "would enable Hamas to deal with emerging developments".</p>

<p>Initially overruled by the Hamas leadership, it was later approved and Haniyeh become Palestinian prime minister after the group won Palestinian parliamentary elections in 2006 a year after Israel's military withdrew from Gaza.</p>

<p>The group took control of Gaza in 2007.</p>

<p>In 2012, when asked by Reuters reporters if Hamas had abandoned the armed struggle, Haniyeh replied "of course not" and said resistance would continue "in all forms - popular resistance, political, diplomatic and military resistance".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/dnhoh8vg_ismail-haniyeh_625x300_31_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Haniyeh was appointed to the Hamas top job in 2017]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/world-just-saw-its-hottest-day-ever-heres-how-it-was-analysed-6228036]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[World Just Saw Its Hottest Day Ever, Here's How It Was Analysed]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/world-just-saw-its-hottest-day-ever-heres-how-it-was-analysed-6228036]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 31 Jul 2024 08:49:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[This month's shocking heat findings, announced by the EU's Copernicus Climate Change Service, are based on "reanalysis,"]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On Sunday, July 21, the world had its hottest day on record. Just 24 hours later, that record broke again making last Monday very likely the hottest day in thousands of years.</p>

<p>It may seem improbable for scientists to gauge the world's hottest day given that they don't have temperature monitors in every corner of the world and less than a century of relatively widespread observations. But they've developed a technique that's increasingly useful as the planet heats up.</p>

<p>This month's shocking heat findings, announced by the EU's Copernicus Climate Change Service, are based on "reanalysis," a technique that mixes temperature data and models to provide a global view of the climate. The center creates a nearly real-time picture of the Earth's climate, including temperature, wind and precipitation, for (roughly) every 30-square-kilometer chunk of the planet's surface.</p>

<p>This reanalysis goes back to 1940, and it allows researchers to say with confidence when a record is broken, whether for a day, month or year. Beyond the new daily heat record, the data also shows that 2023 was the hottest year ever recorded and that every calendar month for the past 13 months has been the hottest on record.</p>

<p>Though there aren't thermometers in every corner of the world, Copernicus receives a large amount of weather data that it uses to underpin its reanalysis. "We have this constant flow of information coming into the center," says Carlo Buontempo, director of the Climate Change Service, which is part of the European Centre for Medium-Range Weather Forecasts (ECMWF).</p>

<p>Scientists at the center receive 100 million readings per day about weather conditions from around the world. Observations come from airplanes, satellites, ships, radar and surface-level weather stations - all feeding real-time information about temperature, wind, rain and snow information, as well as other factors like air pollution. This information is fed into a model, known as ERA5, which is already equipped with historic information about the global climate.</p>

<p>There are gaps in these observations because the data sources don't cover every part of the world. Weather conditions like cloudy skies may also reduce the amount of data coming from sources like satellites. To fill these gaps, the scientists take the predictions they have already made, based on the long-term ERA5 model, and test them against the observations. That means a forecast that predicts a particular temperature in a particular place will be tested against all the data researchers receive about the weather in that place and nearby, as well as broader forces like ocean currents and air circulation.</p>

<p>This is done repeatedly while assessing how compatible the prediction is with what's actually been recorded. The model also accounts for any errors in the recorded data, and relies on the laws of physics, including the weather patterns, currents and airflow that govern how the global climate works.</p>

<p>In this way, it's possible to create a complete picture that is as accurate as possible. That's what allows scientists to confidently declare records like when the world experiences the hottest day in human history.</p>

<p>Globally, five weather services - the US's National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration and NASA, the ECMWF, the China Meteorological Administration, and the Japan Meteorological Agency - carry out continuous appraisals of global temperature using this technique. While their models differ slightly, the five groups have come to similar conclusions about record heat in recent months and years.</p>

<p>Historical data is trickier to come by. The longest-running temperature series, the Central England Temperature in the UK, started in the 17th century. Data from before humans were systematically monitoring temperatures comes from sources like bubbles of gas trapped in glacial ice, or tree rings. These sources aren't as specific as a thermometer reading, but it's possible to say with confidence that recent temperatures are likely the highest in around 100,000 years, Copernicus says.</p>

<p>Meteorologists also have a good idea when a particularly significant day, like the hottest day on record, is on its way. This is partly because global mean temperatures usually peak between early July and early August. Last year's hottest day - which was the previous record for the hottest ever - occurred in early July amid a historic oceanic heat wave. An intensifying El Nino - a natural global climate phenomenon that usually means hotter temperatures globally - provided yet another clue that record heat was brewing.</p>

<p>Until this July, it looked for a while like the world wouldn't set a new daily record, says Buontempo. "The global mean temperature for the oceans started rising again," he says. "Some of the people who systematically monitor our predictions started to sound alarm bells." By the start of last week, they were paying extra attention to the reanalysis and getting ready to make an announcement.</p>

<p>This technique isn't just useful for making "hottest day ever" announcements: It's being used to train AI forecasting models, especially for "ensemble" weather forecasts, which represent multiple possible future scenarios. It's also used by solar energy companies to help homeowners work out how much energy their panels might generate, and by wind energy companies to plan where to put wind farms.</p>

<p>Copernicus is currently working on a new model, known as ERA6, which will be more precise - dividing the world into 14 kilometer squares - and incorporate many more historic data sources, including early satellite readings from the 1970s.</p>

<p>For Buontempo, more important than any one day is the recent extraordinary streak of record-breaking months, given that's a better indicator of how rapidly the world is warming. But pinpointing a specific day does make a changing climate feel much more immediate.</p>

<p>"I think we have to make it more tangible, more direct, more visible," he says. "It is important that people are informed."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/059pkdkg_warmer-summer-heatwave-temperature-rise-global-warming-istock_625x300_30_May_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Representational Image]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/4-killed-as-us-carries-out-defensive-air-strike-in-iraq-6228025]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[4 Killed As US Carries Out 'Defensive' Air Strike In Iraq]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/4-killed-as-us-carries-out-defensive-air-strike-in-iraq-6228025]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 31 Jul 2024 08:42:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[American forces carried out a "defensive" air strike on combatants who were attempting to launch drones that were deemed a threat to US and allied troops, a US official said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>American forces carried out a "defensive" air strike on combatants who were attempting to launch drones that were deemed a threat to US and allied troops, a US official said.</p>

<p>The strike -- which Iraqi sources said left at least four people dead -- was the first by American forces in Iraq since February when the US military said it killed a pro-Iran commander who was involved in attacks on the country's troops.</p>

<p>"Tonight, US forces in Iraq conducted a defensive air strike" in Babylon province "targeting combatants attempting to launch one-way attack uncrewed aerial systems", the US defence official said on condition of anonymity, adding that the Central Command assessed the drones "posed a threat to US and coalition forces."</p>

<p>"We maintain the inherent right to self-defence and will not hesitate to take appropriate action," the official added.</p>

<p>The Hashed al-Shaabi -- an alliance of pro-Iran former paramilitary groups that have been integrated into Iraq's security forces -- earlier said apparent missile strikes had left four people dead at a base in Babylon, but made no mention of an attempt to launch drones from the ground.</p>

<p>"Available information suggests that two patrols... were targeted with missiles fired from drones," the Hashed said in a statement.</p>

<p>An official from the alliance told AFP that "four people were killed and others were critically wounded in blasts that hit a base belonging to the Hashed al-Shaabi".</p>

<p>A security source confirmed that four people were killed, adding that the death count was expected to rise.</p>

<h3><strong>Repeated attacks&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>There have been two recent attacks targeting US and allied forces in Iraq.</p>

<p>Several rockets were launched toward the Ain al-Assad base last week, which hosts troops from the US-led coalition against the Islamic State jihadist group, officials said.</p>

<p>And on July 16, two drones were launched toward the same facility, one of which was "successfully destroyed" while another hit the base, causing "minimal damage," according to the Pentagon.</p>

<p>Prior to that, US troops in Iraq and Syria had not been targeted since April. But attacks against them were much more common in the first few months of the Israel-Hamas war in Gaza when they were targeted more than 175 times.</p>

<p>The Islamic Resistance in Iraq, a loose alliance of Iran-backed groups, claimed the majority of the attacks, saying they were in solidarity with Palestinians in Gaza.</p>

<p>In January, a drone strike blamed on those groups killed three US soldiers at a base in Jordan. In retaliation, US forces launched dozens of strikes against Tehran-backed fighters.</p>

<p>Since then, attacks against US troops have largely halted.</p>

<p>Baghdad has sought to defuse tensions, engaging in talks with Washington on the future of the US-led coalition's mission in Iraq.</p>

<p>The US military has around 2,500 troops in Iraq and 900 in Syria.</p>

<p>The coalition was deployed to Iraq at the government's request in 2014 to help combat the Islamic State group, which had taken over vast swathes of Iraq and neighbouring Syria.</p>

<p>IS remnants still carry out attacks and ambushes in both countries.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2015-03/us-air-strikes-in-syria-reuters-650_650x400_41425922819.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The strike was the first by US forces in Iraq since February (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-chief-ismail-haniyeh-killed-in-irans-capital-report-6228024]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hamas Chief Ismail Haniyeh Killed In Iran's Capital, Group Confirms]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-chief-ismail-haniyeh-killed-in-irans-capital-report-6228024]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 31 Jul 2024 08:41:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hamas chief Ismail Haniyeh and one of his bodyguards were killed in Iran, the Palestinian group said in a statement today.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hamas chief Ismail Haniyeh and one of his bodyguards were killed after their residence was targeted in Iran, the Palestinian group said in a statement today.</p>

<p>Hamas said Ismail Haniyeh was killed in "a treacherous Zionist raid on his residence in Tehran" Tuesday morning.&nbsp;The group said an investigation is on to find out more details about the attack.</p>

<p>Haniyeh was in the Iranian capital to attend the swearing-in of Iran's president Masoud Pezeshkian.<br />
<br />
"Brother, leader, mujahid Ismail Haniyeh, the head of the movement, died in a Zionist strike on his headquarters in Tehran after he participated in the inauguration of the new (Iranian) president," the statement read.</p>

<p>Iran's Revolutionary Guards also confirmed his death, saying Haniyeh's residence in Tehran was "hit" and he was killed along with a bodyguard.</p>

<p>Hamas has accused Israel for Haniyeh's killing, calling it "grave escalation".</p>

<p>"This assassination by the Israeli occupation of Brother Haniyeh is a grave escalation that aims to break the will of Hamas," senior Hamas official Sami Abu Zuhri.</p>

<p>Reacting to Haniyeh's killing,&nbsp;Israeli Minister Amichay Eliyahu posted on X - earlier known as Twitter - that "this is the right way to clean the world from this filth."</p>

<p>Israel had vowed to kill Ismail Haniyeh and destroy the Hamas group after October 7 attack that resulted in the deaths of 1,195 people, mostly civilians.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory military campaign in Gaza has killed at least 39,400 people, according to the health ministry in the Hamas-run territory.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Haniyeh was elected head of the Hamas political bureau in 2017 to succeed Khaled Meshaal. Considered a pragmatist, Haniyeh lived in exile and split his time between Turkey and Qatar.</p>

<p>He had travelled on diplomatic missions to Iran and Turkey during the war, meeting both the Turkish and Iranian presidents.</p>

<p>Haniyeh was said to maintain good relations with the heads of the various Palestinian factions, including rivals to Hamas.</p>

<p>He joined Hamas in 1987 when the militant group was founded amid the outbreak of the first Palestinian intifada, or uprising, against Israeli occupation, which lasted until 1993.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Hamas is part of the "axis of resistance" of Iran-backed armed groups arrayed against arch-foe Israel around the Middle East.</p>

<p>Iran has made support for the Palestinian cause a centrepiece of its foreign policy since the 1979 Islamic revolution.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/jq2p0l6g_ismail-haniyeh_625x300_21_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel had vowed to kill Hamas chief Ismail Haniyeh]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-reveals-how-wife-melania-reacted-to-rally-shooting-means-she-loves-me-6227888]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Reveals How Melania Reacted To Rally Shooting: "Means She Loves Me"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-reveals-how-wife-melania-reacted-to-rally-shooting-means-she-loves-me-6227888]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 31 Jul 2024 08:10:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA["She was watching live. It was all over the place, it was on television," Mr Trump said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former United States President Donald Trump recently revealed his wife Melania Trump's first reaction after he was shot at a rally in Butler, Pennsylvania. Mr Trump was hit in the ear in an assassination bid by a gunman at a campaign rally. Blood was visible on his cheeks and mouth. The shooter was identified as 20-year-old Thomas Matthew Crooks. He and a bystander were killed, while two spectators were critically injured.</p>

<p>"What was Melania's reaction, I hope you don't mind me asking, I know this is very personal, when she learned about what happened on that field in Butler?" <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://x.com/RpsAgainstTrump/status/1818144001184190673">Fox News host Laura Ingraham</a> asked the former president. "She was watching live. It was all over the place, it was on television," Mr Trump said.</p>

<p>"And I asked her that, I mean I wasn't there, I was on the ground-when the world started to, when you could talk to people and said, 'So what was your feeling,' and she was ah, she can't really even talk about it-"</p>

<p>The 45th US President continued, "Which is OK, because that means she likes me or she loves me. Let's say if she could talk about it freely, that would be, I'm not so sure which is better but ah, she either likes or loves me, that's nice."</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the former first lady said that the gunman who opened fire at Mr Trump was a "monster". "A monster who recognized my husband as an inhuman political machine attempted to ring out Donald's passion -- his laughter, ingenuity, love of music, and inspiration," Melania Trump said in a statement shared on X.</p>

<p>"When I watched that violent bullet strike my husband, Donald, I realized my life, and Barron's life, were on the brink of devastating change," she said, referencing the couple's 18-year-old son.</p>

<p>"I am grateful to the brave secret service agents and law enforcement officials who risked their own lives to protect my husband," she added.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-11/l20e5rig_donald-trump-melania-trump-afp_625x300_04_November_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Earlier, Melania Trump said that the gunman who opened fire at Mr Trump was a "monster".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-swimmer-ryan-murphy-learns-his-babys-sex-after-winning-olympic-bronze-medal-6227880]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Swimmer Ryan Murphy Learns His Baby's Sex After Winning Olympic Medal]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-swimmer-ryan-murphy-learns-his-babys-sex-after-winning-olympic-bronze-medal-6227880]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 31 Jul 2024 08:09:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Team USA and USA Swimming shared a photo of the moment on Instagram, showing Konttinen holding the sign with a beaming crowd around her.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ryan Murphy received a heartwarming surprise message from his wife, Bridget Konttinen while standing on the pool deck at the Paris Olympics on Monday night. As he looked up into the stands, he saw his wife holding a sign that revealed they were expecting a baby girl.</p>

<p>Mr Murphy had just won a bronze medal in the 100-meter backstroke. After the medal ceremony, he noticed Konttinen holding up a sign that read, "Ryan, it's a girl." This was the first time he learned the gender of their first child, due in January.</p>

<p>Team USA and USA Swimming shared a photo of the moment on Instagram, showing Konttinen holding the sign with a beaming crowd around her. The post was captioned, "Step 1: Win an Olympic medal. Step 2: Find out you're going to be a girl dad." Among the many congratulatory comments was one from Olympic legend Michael Phelps.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/C-BVRXpvXNz/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C-BVRXpvXNz/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C-BVRXpvXNz/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C-BVRXpvXNz/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by USA Swimming (@usaswimming)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p></p>

<p>Rowdy Gaines, a retired Olympic swimmer and current NBC analyst, also commented on the reveal, saying, "This is so much bigger than ANY medal. Congrats Murph!!"</p>

<p>Murphy, who is 29, secured his third consecutive medal in the 100-meter backstroke at the Paris Games, adding to his gold from Rio and bronze from Tokyo. As captain of the 2024 USA team, he still holds the Olympic record in the event from his 2016 win.</p>

<p>Despite the joy of earning his third Olympic medal, Murphy said the news of his future child made the night even more special. "I think that just kind of like lit me up," he said. "And really brought this night to a whole other level."</p>

<p>Murphy will return to the pool on Wednesday to compete in the 200-meter backstroke.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/82qgt5qg_ryan-murphy-_625x300_31_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mr Murphy had just won a bronze medal in the 100-meter backstroke.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hermes-heir-who-promised-rs-10-000-crore-to-gardener-says-wealth-disappeared-6227871]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hermes Heir, Who Promised Rs 10,000 Crore To Gardener, Says He Lost Wealth]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hermes-heir-who-promised-rs-10-000-crore-to-gardener-says-wealth-disappeared-6227871]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 31 Jul 2024 08:04:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The heir to luxury fashion brand Hermes, who promised to leave half his wealth to his former gardener last year, is now claiming the money has vanished.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The heir to luxury fashion brand Hermes, who promised to leave half his wealth to his former gardener last year, is now claiming the money has vanished.</p>

<p>Nicolas Puech, the 81-year-old descendant of Hermes founder Thierry Hermes, told court that the 6 million shares of HermÃ¨s he owned which were worth about $13 billion (Rs 10,000 crore) have suddenly disappeared.</p>

<p>The billionaire has blamed his former wealth manager who worked for him for the last 20 years, claiming he played a part in the loss of the shares, according to a reports.</p>

<p>However, his claims were rejected by a Swiss court after it found that he was unable to provide any proof of wrongdoing. â€œThe â€˜gigantic fraud' to which he was victim was undetectable to common mortals,â€ the court said.</p>

<p>According to reports, it is unclear where the shares, which was deposited in a bank in Geneva in 2012, are now.</p>

<p>Mr Puech, a single man with no children, is one of the heirs to the luxury bag brand and had promised to leave half his fortune to his former gardener and handyman.</p>

<p>In 2023, he said he wants to leave a big portion of his wealth to his former gardener, who he's planning on adopting.</p>

<p>Reports say Mr Puech owns 5.7% of Hermes' shares, which might seem like a small portion but makes him the largest individual shareholder.&nbsp;</p>

<p>As per Forbes, Mr Puech's current net worth is around $11.7 billion, making him the world's 161st-richest person.</p>

<p>Not much is known about the gardener-handyman other than that he has worked for Mr Puech for decades as a residence manager. He is currently 51 and originally from Morocco.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/fh8se4po_nicolas-puech_625x300_31_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>