<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Sep 2024 10:58:15 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/bright-space-rock-to-light-up-sky-this-week-comet-to-visit-after-80-000-years-6644305]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bright Space Rock To Light Up Sky, Comet To Visit After 80,000 Years]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/bright-space-rock-to-light-up-sky-this-week-comet-to-visit-after-80-000-years-6644305]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Sep 2024 10:58:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Comet C/2023 A3 (Tsuchinshan-ATLAS) is set to make a dramatic appearance in our skies over the next few weeks.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Comet C/2023 A3, also known as Tsuchinshan-ATLAS, is returning to Earth. Our ancestors last witnessed this uncommon sight about 80,000 years ago. This comet, which resembles a fuzzy star with a tail, can be seen in the early morning hours of the sky from Friday through Monday. Even a beautiful video of it was taken by NASA astronaut Matthew Dominick, who is presently stationed on the International Space Station.</p>

<p>"So far, Comet Tsuchinshan-ATLAS looks like a fuzzy star to the naked eye looking out the cupola windows. But with a 200mm f/2 lens at 1/8s exposure, you can really start to see it. This comet is going to make for some really cool images as it gets closer to the sun. For now a timelapse preview," Dominick captioned the video in his X post.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">So far Comet Tsuchinshan-ATLAS looks like a fuzzy star to the naked eye looking out the cupola windows. But with a 200mm, f2 lens at 1/8s exposure you can really start to see it. This comet is going to make for some really cool images as it gets closer to the sun. For now a… <a href="https://t.co/JstaSLJ4Ui">pic.twitter.com/JstaSLJ4Ui</a></p>
— Matthew Dominick (@dominickmatthew) <a href="https://twitter.com/dominickmatthew/status/1836916069870751825?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 19, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Stuart Atkinson, a space enthusiast and amateur astronomer based in Cumbria, said the comet will look like 'a fuzzy star with a misty tail'.</p>

<p>Cumbria-based space enthusiast and amateur astronomer Stuart Atkinson said in a social media post that "the comet will look like a fuzzy star with a misty tail, beneath the Moon, very low in the east. You might need binoculars to see it."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">You can use the Moon to find Comet A3 Tsuchinshan-ATLAS in the sky before sunrise later this week. The comet will look like a fuzzy star with a misty tail, beneath the Moon, v low in the east. You might need binoculars to see it. (Charts drawn for UK but visible elsewhere too) <a href="https://t.co/hUISrEqEoT">pic.twitter.com/hUISrEqEoT</a></p>
— Stuart Atkinson (@mars_stu) <a href="https://twitter.com/mars_stu/status/1838136319702102384?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 23, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.skyatnightmagazine.com/advice/comet-c-2023-a3-tsuchinshan-atlas"><em>BBC Sky at Night Magazine,</em></a> "Initial data seems to suggest that Comet C/2023 A3 completes an orbit every 80,000 years. By the end of September 2024, it will be a morning object, perhaps shining as brightly as mag. +0.6 but rising just before the sun. Comet C/2023 A3 will reach perihelion-the closest point to the Sun in its orbit-on 28 September 2024. Our best views of A3 will come when it moves up into the evening sky around 10 October. By then it will have faded slightly but is predicted to still be as bright as mag. +0.8, low in the west after sunset."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/pka6v0oo_comet_625x300_25_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The comet will look like a faint star-like blob with a hazy tail.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sahara-desert-turns-green-nasa-shares-stunning-image-of-transformation-6644222]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Sahara Desert Turns Green, NASA Shares Stunning Image of Transformation]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sahara-desert-turns-green-nasa-shares-stunning-image-of-transformation-6644222]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Sep 2024 10:44:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Historically, the Sahara was once covered in vegetation and lakes between 11,000 and 5,000 years ago]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>One of the driest places on Earth is seeing a surprising burst of greenery, as heavy rainfall has led to vegetation sprouting across the typically barren Sahara Desert.&nbsp;NASA's satellite images reveal patches of plant life emerging in the desert following an extratropical cyclone that drenched parts of northwestern Africa on September 7 and 8. Regions in Morocco, Algeria, Tunisia, and Libya, which rarely receive rain, are now showing traces of green, according to <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://earthobservatory.nasa.gov/images/153320/a-deluge-for-the-sahara" rel="nofollow, noindex">NASA's Earth Observatory</a></em>.</p>

<p>Shrubs and trees are growing in low-lying areas like riverbeds, explained Sylwia Trzaska, a climate variability researcher at the Columbia Climate School. Peter de Menocal, president of the Woods Hole Oceanographic Institution, noted that while it's rare, plant life does respond quickly to heavy rain events in this part of Africa. When substantial rain falls, dunes transform into lush, green landscapes for a brief time as plants take full advantage of the moisture.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">An extratropical cyclone over the Sahara Desert drenched parts of Morocco and Algeria – bringing up to a year's worth of rain to some areas. ?️ <a href="https://twitter.com/NASA?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@nasa</a>'s Terra satellite captured floodwaters and some Saharan lakes, usually dry, filled with water. <a href="https://t.co/cuS1c73RoA">https://t.co/cuS1c73RoA</a> <a href="https://t.co/m8Ga8G0FgO">pic.twitter.com/m8Ga8G0FgO</a></p>
— NASA Earth (@NASAEarth) <a href="https://twitter.com/NASAEarth/status/1836071502384394313?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 17, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>Historically, the Sahara was once covered in vegetation and lakes between 11,000 and 5,000 years ago, de Menocal's past research suggests. Now, even lakes that are typically dry are filling up due to this recent deluge, according to Moshe Armon, a lecturer at the Institute of Earth Sciences, Hebrew University of Jerusalem.</p>

<p>The unusual rainfall event was triggered by the northward movement of the tropical rain belt, known as the Intertropical Convergence Zone, reaching farther north than usual, bringing heavy rains typical of equatorial regions into the Sahara. Some areas saw over half a foot of rain, which far exceeds the typical annual precipitation of just a few inches.</p>

<p>While the rains largely affected sparsely populated areas, devastating floods have killed over 1,000 people and affected around 4 million across 14 African nations, according to the World Food Programme and the Associated Press.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Experts believe the shift in the rain belt is influenced by record-high ocean temperatures and climate change, which could lead to further changes in rainfall patterns across Africa. However, as ocean temperatures balance out globally, the rain belt is expected to shift back south, potentially crossing the equator, according to de Menocal.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/c2uglpr8_sahara-desert_625x300_25_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Some areas saw over half a foot of rain]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sri-lanka-president-anura-kumara-dissanayake-appoints-3-member-cabinet-6641518]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Sri Lanka's President Appoints 3-Member Cabinet]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sri-lanka-president-anura-kumara-dissanayake-appoints-3-member-cabinet-6641518]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Sep 2024 10:01:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Sri Lankan President Anura Kumara Dissanayake appointed a new Cabinet of Ministers on Tuesday evening, with Prime Minister Harini Amarasuriya, lawmaker Vijitha Herath and himself taking on Cabinet portfolios.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sri Lankan President Anura Kumara Dissanayake appointed a new Cabinet of Ministers on Tuesday evening, with Prime Minister Harini Amarasuriya, lawmaker Vijitha Herath and himself taking on Cabinet portfolios.</p>

<p>Dissanayake will now oversee defence, finance, economic development, policy formulation, planning, tourism, energy, agriculture, lands, livestock, irrigation, fisheries and aquatic resources, Xinhua news agency reported.</p>

<p>Dissanayake, 55, has taken the key finance portfolio himself as Sri Lanka looks to emerge from its most punishing economic crisis in 70 years and its first debt default, while keeping promises to aid the nation's poor.</p>

<p>The Marxist-leaning firebrand politician will also hold the economic development and tourism jobs in the cabinet.</p>

<p>Dissanayake's intentions to slash taxes and desire to revisit the terms of a $2.9 billion International Monetary Fund bailout have worried investors, who fear that it could delay a crucial $25 billion debt restructuring.</p>

<p>His comments during Monday's inauguration offered few clues as to how hardline his economic approach will be.</p>

<p>"Our politics needs to be cleaner, and the people have called for a different political culture," the 55-year-old said.</p>

<p>"I am ready to commit to that change."</p>

<p>Dissanayake ran in Saturday's presidential election as the candidate for the National People's Power coalition, which includes his Janatha Vimukthi Peramuna Party that traditionally championed Marxist economic policies centred on protectionism and state intervention. In recent years the party has taken more centrist positions.</p>

<p>Earlier, Amarasuriya was sworn in as the Prime Minister, and was appointed as the Minister of justice, public administration, provincial councils, local government, education, science and technology, labour, women, child and youth affairs, sports, trade, commerce, food security, co-operative development, industries and entrepreneur development, and health.</p>

<p>Herath was assigned the Minister of Buddhist affairs, religious and cultural affairs, national integration, social security, mass media, transport, highways, ports and civil aviation, public security, and foreign affairs, environment, wildlife, forest resources, water supply, plantation and community, infrastructure, rural and urban development, housing and construction.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/b7jfm6hs_sri-lankan-president-anura-kumara-dissanayake-reuters_625x300_24_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Anura Kumara Dissanayake appointed a new Cabinet of Ministers.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/white-house-says-joe-biden-will-be-most-proud-of-deepening-partnership-with-india-6643631]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden Will Be Most Proud Of Deepening Partnership With India: White House]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/white-house-says-joe-biden-will-be-most-proud-of-deepening-partnership-with-india-6643631]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Sep 2024 09:55:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The India-US relationship is "strong and getting stronger", the White House said, adding that President Joe Biden when looks back at his term will be most proud of deepening the partnership with India, making it more inclusive and broadening.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The India-US relationship is “strong and getting stronger”, the White House said, adding that President Joe Biden when looks back at his term will be most proud of deepening the partnership with India, making it more inclusive and broadening.</p>

<p>"I think one word -- well, actually, three words: strong, and getting stronger,” White House National Security Communications Advisor John Kirby said on Tuesday during a press briefing here.</p>

<p>Kirby was responding to a question by Press Trust of India on how he would characterise the trajectory of bilateral relations under Prime Minister Narendra Modi and Biden as his term as the American leader ends soon.</p>

<p>Biden has “invested a lot in our bilateral relationship with India”, Kirby told PTI.</p>

<p>He elevated the Quad group of Australia, Japan, India and the US to the leader level and hosted PM&nbsp;Modi for an official state visit in June last year.</p>

<p>“We've elevated our strategic partnership to the highest level. We are pursuing a defence relationship on various systems that will make not just the Indian people safer, but people safer throughout the Indo-Pacific,” Kirby said.</p>

<p>Kirby said Biden “appreciates” the perspective Modi brings to these discussions.</p>

<p>“I mean, he lives in that neighbourhood; he understands it. And of course, he's the leader of one of the most vibrant democracies in the world.” “So I think as the president looks back at his term, I believe one of the things he'll be most proud of is deepening this partnership with India, but just as critically, making that partnership more inclusive and broadening it so that it is not just a bilateral – it's a strong bilateral relationship," he said.</p>

<p>Biden on September 21 hosted Quad leaders Prime Minister Narendra Modi, Prime Minister Anthony Albanese of Australia, and Prime Minister Kishida Fumio of Japan in Wilmington, Delaware, for the fourth Quad Leaders' Summit.</p>

<p>Kirby said India, as witnessed in Wilmington, “a full-on member of this Indo-Pacific Quad, is a real contributing partner. And it's more than just the security. It's on the economic, it's on technology, it's on energy and clean energy transition, and international investments, on so many levels.” Biden addressed world leaders from the podium of the UN General Assembly on Tuesday, delivering his last address as President of the US as his term comes to an end following his decision to pull out from the presidential election.</p>

<p>The US heads into presidential elections in just over a month with Americans set to vote on November 5 and pick either Democratic nominee Vice President Kamala Harris or Republican candidate former president Donald Trump as their next leader.</p>

<p>Biden announced earlier this summer that he would not seek re-election as President of the United States, passing on the baton to Harris, who has made history as the first woman of Indian and Black heritage to be nominated as an American presidential candidate.</p>

<p>“This summer, I faced a decision whether to seek a second term as President. It was a difficult decision. Being president has been the honour of my life. There's so much more I want to get done. As much as I love this job, I love my country more. I decided, after 50 years of public service, it's time for the new generation of leadership to take my nation forward. My fellow leaders, let us never forget that some things are more important than staying in power. It's your people,” Biden said to a round of huge applause from the world leaders in the UNGA hall.</p>

<p>“We are here to serve the people, not the other way around.”&nbsp;</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/hcuesb_narendra-modi-joe-biden-modi-biden-pti_625x300_25_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/thousands-of-bones-and-weapons-uncover-brutal-3-250-year-old-battle-6643868]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Thousands Of Bones And Weapons Uncover Brutal 3,250-Year-Old Battle]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/thousands-of-bones-and-weapons-uncover-brutal-3-250-year-old-battle-6643868]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Sep 2024 09:46:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Researchers have unearthed a trove of artefacts, including bronze and flint arrowheads, swords, wooden clubs, and human remains.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A new analysis of arrowheads discovered at the Tollense Valley battlefield, Europe's oldest known battlefield, is shedding light on the warriors who clashed there 3,250 years ago, <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/09/23/science/tollense-valley-bronze-age-battlefield-arrowheads/index.html" rel="nofollow, noindex">CNN </a></em>reported.</p>

<p>Researchers have unearthed a trove of artefacts, including bronze and flint arrowheads, swords, wooden clubs, and human remains. By studying these items, they have determined that the battle involved both local groups and an army from a southern region.</p>

<p>This finding suggests that the Tollense Valley battle was the earliest example of interregional conflict in Europe. Previous studies had hinted at the involvement of outsiders, but the arrowhead analysis provides concrete evidence.</p>

<p>"The arrowheads are a kind of 'smoking gun,'" said lead study author Leif Inselmann, a researcher at the Berlin Graduate School of Ancient Studies within the Free University of Berlin, in a statement. "Just like the murder weapon in a mystery, they give us a clue about the culprit, the fighters of the Tollense Valley battle and where they came from."</p>

<p>The researchers compared the arrowheads to known examples from across Central Europe and found that some were made locally, while others originated from a southern region. This suggests that at least one faction in the battle was from a distant location.</p>

<p>The arrowheads, like a murder weapon in a mystery, offer crucial clues about the participants and the nature of the conflict. This groundbreaking research helps piece together the story behind one of Europe's most ancient and brutal battles.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/0adaeft8_ancient-skull-recovered_625x300_25_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[An ancient skull recovered from the Tollense Valley site]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/volodymyr-zelenskyy-on-2nd-peace-summit-to-end-ukraine-conflict-already-invited-india-6643550]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Already Invited India": Zelenskyy On 2nd Peace Summit To End Ukraine Conflict]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/volodymyr-zelenskyy-on-2nd-peace-summit-to-end-ukraine-conflict-already-invited-india-6643550]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Sep 2024 09:37:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskyy told the UN Security Council that "we have to prepare" the second peace summit to end the Russia-Ukraine war "altogether" and he has invited India and other countries to join the peace process.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskyy told the UN Security Council that “we have to prepare” the second peace summit to end the Russia-Ukraine war “altogether” and he has invited India and other countries to join the peace process.</p>

<p>“We all know what needs to be done if we honestly look at the situation and truly want to stop Russia's war. Most importantly, act together, of course in unity, without creating new and unnecessary divisions of the world into blocks or regional groups,” Zelenskyy here on Tuesday told a Security Council meeting on the Ukraine conflict.</p>

<p>Zelenskyy said that unity always works for peace and “we have to prepare the second peace summit to end the war altogether. And I invite all of you, all principle nations to join us in this process, all who truly respect the UN Charter. We invite China. We invite Brazil. I have already invited India. We are working with African nations, all of Latin America, the Middle East, Central Asia, Europe, the Pacific region, and North America. All.” Zelenskyy said all are "equally important for peace, all without exceptions. Just as the UN Charter must work without exceptions”.</p>

<p>The Ukrainian president said this process will “lead us to peace, to a just peace, a real peace, a peace that will last. All of us already know how to achieve it. We have the peace formula, we have the UN Charter and we have all the strength needed to make it happen. What's needed is determination.” Zelenskyy on Monday met Prime Minister Narendra Modi in New York before the Indian leader wrapped up his three-day visit to the US.</p>

<p>PM Modi's meeting with Zelenskyy, requested by the Ukrainian side, came at the sidelines of his other engagements, including participating in the Quad Leaders' Summit and his address to the UN's 'Summit of the Future'.</p>

<p>The meeting between PM Modi and Zelenskyy was their third in a little over three months.</p>

<p>PM Modi met the Ukrainian leader in Kyiv last month, just weeks after he had met Russian President Vladimir Putin in Moscow in July.</p>

<p>In June, PM Modi held a bilateral meeting with Zelenskyy on the sidelines of the G7 Summit in Italy.</p>

<p>“We are committed to implementing the outcomes of my visit to Ukraine last month to strengthen bilateral relations. Reiterated India's support for early resolution of the conflict in Ukraine and restoration of peace and stability,” the prime minister said on X following Monday's meeting with Zelenskyy.</p>

<p>Zelenskyy, noting that this was already the third bilateral meeting this year with PM Modi, said the main focus of their conversation was on “enhancing our interaction on international platforms, particularly at the UN and G20 as well as implementing the peace formula and preparing for the second peace summit. We had a substantive discussion on the available opportunities.” “We are actively developing our relations and working together to strengthen cooperation across various fields,” the Ukrainian president said, adding that he was “grateful for the clear support of our sovereignty and territorial integrity”. Responding to a question during a press briefing on discussions with the Ukrainian leader on a second peace summit, Foreign Secretary Vikram Misri said the discussions covered a lot of issues related to finding a way forward.</p>

<p>Mr Misri said a number of things came up, the peace summit that was held in Switzerland, the ideas that have been floated after that, the efforts that Ukraine is making on its own and the possibility of a second peace summit that Ukraine has been talking.</p>

<p>“But I think we are not right now at a stage where the second peace summit can be discussed in any detail. I think there is a lot of work that remains to be done before that, so there was not a great deal of discussion on that specific issue.” Pavan Kapoor, Secretary (West) at the Ministry of External Affairs, represented India at the 'Summit on Peace in Ukraine' hosted by Switzerland at Burgenstock on June 15-16.</p>

<p>The Indian delegation attended the opening and closing plenary sessions but India did not associate itself with any communique/document emerging from this summit.</p>

<p>“India's participation in the summit and preceding NSA/Political Director-level meetings based on Ukraine's peace formula was in line with our consistent approach to facilitate a lasting and peaceful resolution to the conflict through dialogue and diplomacy. We continue to believe that such a resolution requires a sincere and practical engagement between the two parties to the conflict,” the MEA said.</p>

<p>In this regard, India will continue to remain engaged with all stakeholders and both parties to contribute to all earnest efforts to bring about an early and abiding peace, the MEA added.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/9rqjsdb8_narendra-modi-with-volodymyr-zelenskyy-_625x300_21_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Volodymyr Zelenskyy said that unity always works for peace.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-conducts-first-public-test-launch-of-intercontinental-ballistic-missile-6643677]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[China Conducts 1st Public Test Launch Of Intercontinental Ballistic Missile]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-conducts-first-public-test-launch-of-intercontinental-ballistic-missile-6643677]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Sep 2024 09:08:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Chinese defence ministry said it was a "routine arrangement in our annual training plan" and not directed at any country or target.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>China publicly acknowledged for the first time that it successfully launched an intercontinental ballistic missile into the Pacific Ocean on Wednesday, in a move likely to raise international concerns about the country's nuclear build-up.</p>

<p>The ICBM, carrying a dummy warhead, was launched by the People's Liberation Army Rocket Force at 08:44 a.m. Beijing time (0044 GMT) on Wednesday and "fell into expected sea areas," the Chinese defence ministry said in a statement, adding it was a "routine arrangement in our annual training plan" and not directed at any country or target.</p>

<p>China "informed the countries concerned in advance," according to a separate Xinhua report, which did not clarify the path of the missile or where exactly in the "high seas of the Pacific Ocean" it fell.</p>

<p>The launch "effectively tested the performance of weapons and equipment and the training level of the troops, and achieved the expected goal," Xinhua reported.</p>

<p>The PLA Rocket Force, which oversees the country's conventional and nuclear missiles, has been tasked with modernising China's nuclear forces to deter developments such as improved U.S. missile defences, better surveillance capabilities, and strengthened alliances.</p>

<p>Some analysts, however, argue the speed of China's nuclear build-up goes beyond a credible minimum deterrence.</p>

<p>Beijing says it adheres to a "no first use" policy.</p>

<p>The Chinese military has emphasised that the Central Military Commission, headed by President Xi Jinping, is the only nuclear command authority.</p>

<p>China, which has been frequently criticised by the US for the opacity of its nuclear build-up, scrapped nuclear talks with Washington in July over U.S. arms sales to Taiwan.</p>

<p>China has more than 500 operational nuclear warheads in its arsenal, of which approximately 350 are ICBMs, and will probably have over 1,000 warheads by 2030, the Pentagon estimated last year. China's military is constructing hundreds of secret silos for land-based ICBMs, the Pentagon said in the report.</p>

<p>That compares to 1,770 and 1,710 operational warheads deployed by the U.S. and Russia, respectively. The Pentagon said that by 2030, much of Beijing's weapons will likely be held at higher readiness levels.</p>

<p>Democratically governed Taiwan, which China claims as its own territory, has complained of increased Chinese military activities around the island in the past five years.</p>

<p>Taiwan's defence ministry said on Wednesday it had detected 23 Chinese military aircraft, including J-16 fighters and drones, operating around Taiwan carrying out long-range missions to the southeast and east of the island.</p>

<p>The ministry added it had also recently detected "intensive" Chinese missile firing and other drills, though it did not give details of where that took place.</p>

<p>Taiwan has dispatched its own air and naval forces to keep watch, the ministry said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-08/7tbnnd7o_china-military-drills-reuters-pic_650x400_09_August_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[China has more than 500 operational nuclear warheads in its arsenal (File Photo/Reuters)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pesto-the-22-5-kg-baby-penguin-that-has-gone-viral-6643511]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Pesto: The 22.5 Kg Baby Penguin That Has Gone Viral]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pesto-the-22-5-kg-baby-penguin-that-has-gone-viral-6643511]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Sep 2024 08:29:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Pesto, a nine-month-old penguin chick, is the largest penguin the Sea Life Melbourne has ever seen.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A massive, fluffy brown furball waddled across his Australian aquarium home, towering over the other penguins.&nbsp;Pesto, a nine-month-old penguin chick, has shot to fame for his massive weight of 22.5 kilograms (49.6 pounds).</p>

<p>He is the largest penguin the Sea Life Melbourne has ever seen. With a healthy diet of 25 fish a day, his fluffy frame may grow yet.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Aquarium keeper Michaela Smale said Pesto's parents, Tango and Hudson, weigh only about 11 kilograms each -- making Pesto more than their combined weight.</p>

<p>"When he hatched, he was 200 grams (0.44 pounds)," Smale told Australia's national broadcaster.&nbsp;</p>

<p>She added that king penguin chicks bulk up to protect themselves against the freezing Antarctic temperatures. &nbsp;</p>

<p>Although podgy Pesto is chunkier than most chicks. &nbsp;</p>

<p>"He is a chunky monkey, but he is healthy," she told the ABC. &nbsp;</p>

<p>Pesto's genetics also account for his massive size -- his ancestors were some of the biggest and oldest penguins the aquarium has housed.&nbsp;</p>

<p>As the chicks get older, they shed their fluffy, brown outer layer as their adult feathers develop. &nbsp;</p>

<p>In the wild, king penguins are found in Antarctica and their population remains fairly stable, with about 1.6 million breeding pairs. &nbsp;</p>

<p>During the 19th and 20th centuries, king penguin populations were almost wiped out because they were heavily hunted for their meat, oil and blubber. &nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/qp1iu3p_penguin-_625x300_25_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Pesto is the largest penguin the Sea Life Melbourne has ever seen.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/marcellus-williams-travis-mullis-black-man-who-maintained-he-didnt-kill-reporter-executed-in-us-6643491]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Black Man, Who Maintained He Didn't Kill Reporter, Executed In US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/marcellus-williams-travis-mullis-black-man-who-maintained-he-didnt-kill-reporter-executed-in-us-6643491]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Sep 2024 08:20:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Marcellus Williams, 55, was sentenced to death in the midwestern state of Missouri for the 1998 killing of Felicia Gayle, a former newspaper reporter.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Two men on death row in the United States were executed Tuesday, including a Black man convicted of murder who had maintained his innocence and drawn support from civil rights groups. Marcellus Williams, 55, was sentenced to death in the midwestern state of Missouri for the 1998 killing of Felicia Gayle, a former newspaper reporter.</p>

<p>He was pronounced dead at 6:10 pm local time Tuesday, according to the Missouri Department of Corrections.</p>

<p>Travis Mullis, 38, was also put to death in Huntsville, Texas for stomping his three-month-old son, Alijah Mullis, to death in 2008.</p>

<p>"I do regret the decision to take the life of my son, I apologize to the mother of my son, the victim's family," Mullis said in his last statement.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Undated photo of Travis Mullis" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/crljtvro_travis-mullis_625x300_25_September_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Undated photo of Travis Mullis" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">Undated photo of Travis Mullis<br />
<span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: AFP</span></p>
</div>

<p>Both men were executed by lethal injection, raising the total number of US executions this year to 16.</p>

<p>Williams has insisted he is innocent and the NAACP civil rights group had urged Governor Michael Parson to stay his execution.</p>

<p>Parson on Tuesday said that Williams's execution in Missouri would go ahead despite protests.</p>

<p>"No jury nor court, including at the trial, appellate, and Supreme Court levels, have ever found merit in Mr. Williams's innocence claim. At the end of the day, his guilty verdict and sentence of capital punishment were upheld," Parson said in a statement.</p>

<p>The US Supreme Court had also rejected a last-ditch request to stay Williams's execution on Tuesday.</p>

<p>British billionaire Richard Branson, who bought a full-page advert in the Kansas City Star newspaper decrying a "devastating miscarriage of justice," mourned Williams's execution on social media.</p>

<p>"It's a shameful day for Missouri, and a shameful day for Governor Mike Parson," Branson wrote on X.</p>

<p>Felicia Gayle was found dead at her St. Louis home in Missouri, stabbed 43 times by a kitchen knife during what appeared to be a burglary gone wrong.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Williams, who had previous convictions for burglary and robbery, was convicted on the testimony of a former jail cellmate and an ex-girlfriend, though his DNA was not found on the knife or at the crime scene.</p>

<p>His execution was stayed by the Missouri Supreme Court in 2015, and again by the state's then-governor Eric Greitens in 2017, following the discovery of male DNA on the knife that did not match Williams.</p>

<p>This year, local prosecutors initiated proceedings to overturn his conviction. However, on Monday, the state Supreme Court ruled in a unanimous decision that it would not stop Williams's execution.</p>

<p>The death penalty has been abolished in 23 US states, while six others -- Arizona, California, Ohio, Oregon, Pennsylvania and Tennessee -- have moratoriums in place.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/oqql3lbo_marcellus-williams_625x300_25_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The US Supreme Court had also rejected a last-ditch request to stay Williams's execution on Tuesday.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-woman-rejected-colleagues-sexual-advances-asked-him-to-stop-touching-her-next-day-he-killed-her-6643456]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Woman, 28, Killed Outside Workplace For Rejecting Colleague's Advances]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-woman-rejected-colleagues-sexual-advances-asked-him-to-stop-touching-her-next-day-he-killed-her-6643456]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Sep 2024 08:17:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Carpenter, 38, shot Hammond in the neck in the parking lot of Dubow Textile, where they both worked.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A woman from Minnesota, Nicole Hammond, 28, was tragically killed outside her workplace in October 2022 after repeatedly rejecting the sexual advances of a colleague, Michael J. Carpenter. Carpenter, 38, shot Hammond in the neck in the parking lot of Dubow Textile, where they both worked. Last week, Carpenter was sentenced to life without parole after being found guilty of first-degree premeditated murder and second-degree intentional murder, according to Minnesota Attorney General Keith Ellison.</p>

<p>The murder took place the morning after an argument between the two, in which Ms Hammond had expressed her refusal to be touched or manipulated by Carpenter, as revealed by text messages, the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://people.com/man-sentenced-murdering-coworker-rebuffed-advances-8717319" rel="nofollow, noindex"><em>People </em></a>reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Ms Hammond's coworkers were reportedly aware of Carpenter's repeated harassment, but no formal complaint had been made to upper management, according to her boss, Rob Dubow.</p>

<p>Ellison released a statement expressing his condolences to Hammond's friends and family, remembering her as a "talented, kind, and caring soul who loved art and nature" and noting that she will be greatly missed. He also expressed hope that Carpenter's sentencing would bring some level of peace to Hammond's loved ones.</p>

<p>"Carpenter approached Hammond before her work shift in the parking lot of Dubow Textile, armed with a 9mm pistol, and fired a single shot through Hammond's neck," the attorney general said in a news release.</p>

<p>"My thoughts are with Nicole Hammond's friends, family, and community today. Nicole was a talented, kind, and caring soul who loved art and nature. She will be missed by many," Ellison added in a statement. "I am pleased that today, the Court held Michael Carpenter fully accountable for the crime he committed. I hope this accountability is eventually able to bring some measure of peace to Nicole's loved ones."</p>

<p>Ms Hammond was in the process of starting her own jewellery business at the time of her death. Her obituary described her as a talented writer who loved working on her car with her father and enjoyed outdoor activities such as hiking, kayaking, and photography. She had dreamed of moving to Fort Myers, Florida, and was deeply cherished by those who knew her.</p>

<p><br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/aamau36_michael-j-carpenter_625x300_25_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The murder took place the morning after an argument between the two]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/saudi-arabia-warns-pakistan-to-prevent-beggars-from-entering-country-over-hajj-umrah-visas-6643416]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Saudi Arabia Warns Pakistan To Prevent Beggars From Entering Country]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/saudi-arabia-warns-pakistan-to-prevent-beggars-from-entering-country-over-hajj-umrah-visas-6643416]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Sep 2024 08:06:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Saudi Arabia has allegedly issued a warning to Pakistan to take action against the growing number of Pakistani beggars arriving in the country under the guise of religious pilgrimage.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Saudi Arabia has allegedly issued a warning to Pakistan to take action against the growing number of Pakistani beggars arriving in the country under the guise of religious pilgrimage.</p>

<p>Pakistan's Express Tribune newspaper reported on Tuesday that the Saudi authorities have also warned that if the situation is not controlled, it could negatively affect Pakistani Umrah and Hajj pilgrims.</p>

<p>"The Saudi Ministry of Hajj has issued a warning to Pakistan's Ministry of Religious Affairs, urging action to prevent Pakistani beggars from entering the kingdom under Umrah visas," the newspaper said.</p>

<p>In response, Pakistan's Ministry of Religious Affairs has decided to introduce an "Umrah Act," which aims to regulate travel agencies facilitating Umrah trips, bringing them under legal oversight, the paper said.</p>

<p>The ministry has also asked the Pakistani government to find ways to prevent beggars from travelling to Saudi Arabia under the guise of religious pilgrimage.</p>

<p>In May, the Saudi government issued a fatwa, or edict, prohibiting Hajj without a permit. It fixed a penalty of 10,000 Riyals (around Rs 2.22 lakh) and deportation for the violating visitors.</p>

<p>In September last year, 16 beggars disguised as pilgrims were offloaded from a Saudi Arabia-bound flight and arrested for trying to travel to the Gulf Kingdom to indulge in begging.</p>

<p>According to a report last year, 90 per cent of <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/majority-of-beggars-arrested-abroad-are-from-crisis-hit-pakistan-report-4435362" target="_blank">beggars arrested in foreign countries belong to Pakistan</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/3jc8nur8_saudi-arabia_625x300_25_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Representational Image]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hezbollah-lebanon-hezbollah-missile-chief-killed-in-israeli-airstrike-on-beirut-10-points-6643300]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hezbollah Missile Chief Killed In Israeli Airstrike On Beirut: 10 Points]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hezbollah-lebanon-hezbollah-missile-chief-killed-in-israeli-airstrike-on-beirut-10-points-6643300]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Sep 2024 07:31:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An Israeli airstrike on Beirut on Tuesday killed Ibrahim Qubaisi, the head of Hezbollah's missile division. The cross-border firing between Israel and Hezbollah continued as the Iran-backed militant group fired over 300 rockets towards Israel.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="CetSht_cn">
<ol class="CetSht_ol">
	<li class="CetSht_li">Ibrahim Qubaisi, Hezbollah's commander in charge of its rocket and missile forces, was killed in an Israeli airstrike in the Dahiyeh suburb of Beirut. The Israeli Defense Forces (IDF) confirmed his death, stating that Qubaisi had been a central figure in Hezbollah's missile capabilities for decades.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">The airstrike followed intense cross-border clashes between Hezbollah and Israel, with the militant group launching approximately 300 rockets at northern Israeli cities including Haifa, Safed, and Nazareth. Israeli air raid sirens were triggered across the Galilee region.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">In addition to Qubaisi, the IDF claimed that at least two other high-ranking Hezbollah commanders were eliminated in the strike. These leaders were involved in Hezbollah's missile operations, which have increasingly posed a threat to Israel.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Hezbollah acknowledged Qubaisi's death, releasing a statement describing him as a martyr "on the road to Jerusalem," a term they use for fighters killed by Israeli forces.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">A veteran of Hezbollah, Qubaisi joined the group in the 1980s. Over the years, he commanded various missile and rocket units, including the precision-guided missile program, and was deeply involved in Hezbollah's military strategy against Israel. He had close ties with senior military leaders within the group.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Qubaisi played a key role in Hezbollah's 2000 Mount Dov operation, which involved the abduction of three Israeli soldiers. The soldiers were later found dead, and their bodies were returned in a 2004 prisoner exchange. His involvement in that high-profile attack cemented his status within Hezbollah's military wing.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">The Lebanese Health Ministry reported that the airstrike on the Dahiyeh suburb also killed six civilians and injured 15 others. This is part of a broader escalation that has claimed hundreds of lives in Lebanon in recent days, mostly due to Israeli airstrikes.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Tuesday's missile exchange follows a surge in violence between Israel and Hezbollah since the outbreak of the Gaza war in October 2023. There are growing concerns that this could spiral into a full-blown war involving multiple fronts in the Middle East, drawing in Iran-backed groups from Yemen and Iraq.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">United Nations Secretary-General Antonio Guterres warned that Lebanon is on the brink of disaster, while US President Joe Biden urged both sides to avoid escalating the conflict.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu remained defiant, vowing to continue striking Hezbollah's military targets in Lebanon. "We will continue to hit Hezbollah," Netanyahu declared, stating that any home sheltering missiles would be destroyed.<br />
	&nbsp;</li>
</ol>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/lu2fe8k_beirut-afp-_625x300_25_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hezbollah described Ibrahim Qubaisi him as a martyr "on the road to Jerusalem."]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/artificial-intelligence-uncovers-300-new-nazca-lines-including-knife-wielding-orca-6643270]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[AI Uncovers 300 New Nazca Lines, Including 'Knife-Wielding Orca']]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/artificial-intelligence-uncovers-300-new-nazca-lines-including-knife-wielding-orca-6643270]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Sep 2024 07:28:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[It took nearly a century to discover a total of 430 figurative Nazca geoglyphs, which offer significant insights into the ancient cultures at the Nazca Pampa.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Scientists have always been perplexed by the Nazca Lines, ancient designs etched into the southern Peruvian desert, since they were found almost a century ago. Researchers have just discovered 303 more of these enigmatic figures, adding even more enigma to the mysterious location, thanks to artificial intelligence.</p>

<p>Among the recently found geoglyphs are a number of interesting patterns. While some might be easily identifiable, others might not seem to be. Researchers discovered that some of the pictures resemble killer whales with knives, cats, camels, and even in the shape of the popular Pixar robot character Wall-E. Some photos only acquire an otherworldly aspect that adds more mystery to these extremely ancient pieces of art.</p>

<p>The Nazca Lines have a purpose and meaning that have puzzled researchers for years now, dating back about 400 BC. In this respect, though the meaning of such is unknown, the recently found geoglyphs contribute to adding evidence on how just artistic and ingenious the people of Nazca were.</p>

<p>A joint effort involving scientists at the IBM Thomas J Watson Research Centre in New York and Yamagata University in Japan revealed the discovery, which was published in the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.pnas.org/doi/10.1073/pnas.2407652121"><em>Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences.</em></a> Through the use of artificial intelligence (AI), they were able to decipher patterns concealed beneath the sands of the Nazca Desert that had never been seen before.</p>

<p>According to a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.pnas.org/doi/full/10.1073/pnas.2407652121">release</a>, after training the model on images of existing geoglyphs, the research team used it to look for more. They found 303 that they were able to confirm through site visits by human experts.</p>

<p>As expected, many of the lines comprising the newly found geoglyphs were faint, but the researchers could discern what they depict, mainly humans and domesticated animals, though some were abstract, such as a knife-wielding killer whale. The team plans to continue using the AI app to search for more examples of the ancient art.</p>

<p>Such a discovery is more than sure to reinvigorate interest in the Nazca Lines and encourage further research into the ancient civilisation that created them.</p>

<p><strong>What are Nazca Lines?</strong></p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.livescience.com/archaeology/knife-wielding-orca-and-alien-looking-figures-among-300-nazca-lines-discovered-in-groundbreaking-ai-study"><em>Live Science</em></a>, the Nazca Lines are a group of large human-carved geoglyphs located in a roughly 170-square-mile (440 square kilometres) area of Peru's Nazca Desert. The ancient artworks were likely created between 200 B.C. and A.D. 500 by members of the pre-Incan civilisation, known as the Nazca (or Nasca), who removed the upper layers of the desert's red-tinged surface pebbles to reveal sections of lighter soil in a wide range of different shapes and sizes. Researchers had already found around 430 Nazca Lines since the mysterious shapes were rediscovered by aeroplane passengers in the 1920s. Most of these geoglyphs were identified in the last 20 years with the help of advancements in satellite imagery.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/vie2kja8_knifewielding-orca_625x300_25_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Geoglyphs are motifs created on the ground by manipulating surface stones.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-intel-warns-of-real-specific-iran-threats-to-assassinate-donald-trump-6643134]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Intel Warns Of "Real, Specific" Iran Threats To Assassinate Donald Trump]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-intel-warns-of-real-specific-iran-threats-to-assassinate-donald-trump-6643134]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Sep 2024 06:44:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Trump's campaign said that intelligence officials have identified that Iranian threats have "heightened in the past few months".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump was briefed on Tuesday by US intelligence officials on alleged threats from Iran to assassinate him, Trump's campaign said.</p>

<p>"President Trump was briefed earlier today by the Office of the Director of National Intelligence (ODNI) regarding real and specific threats from Iran to assassinate him in an effort to destabilize and sow chaos in the United States," the campaign said in a statement.</p>

<p>The campaign said that intelligence officials have identified that Iranian threats have "heightened in the past few months" and US government officials were working to protect Trump and ensure the elections were not impacted.</p>

<p>Iran has previously denied US claims of interfering in American affairs. Iran's permanent mission to the United Nations in New York and the ODNI did not immediately respond to requests for comment late on Tuesday.</p>

<p>Earlier this month, a Pakistani man with alleged ties to Iran pleaded not guilty to charges stemming from an alleged plot to assassinate an American politician in retaliation for the 2020 killing by the U.S. of Iranian military commander Qassem Soleimani.</p>

<p>The defendant named Trump as a potential target but had not conceived the scheme as a plan to assassinate the former president, according to a person familiar with the matter.</p>

<p>Federal authorities are separately probing an apparent assassination attempt on Trump at his Florida golf course in mid-September and a July 13 shooting of the Republican presidential candidate at a rally in Pennsylvania. There has been no indication of Iranian involvement in either of those.</p>

<p>US government agencies said last week that Iranian hackers sent emails containing stolen material from the Republican former president's campaign to people involved in Democratic President Joe Biden's then re-election campaign, part of an alleged broader effort by Tehran to influence the US election.</p>

<p>Biden stepped aside as candidate in late July and was replaced by Democratic Vice President Kamala Harris, who faces Trump in a tight race for the November 5 US elections.</p>

<p>In August, the United States accused Iran of launching cyber operations against the campaigns of both US presidential candidates. Iran denied the allegations.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/11vtqnj8_donald-trump_625x300_25_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Iran has previously denied US claims of interfering in American affairs]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-announces-death-of-commander-in-israeli-strike-in-lebanon-6642984]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hezbollah Announces Death Of Commander In Israeli Strike In Lebanon]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-announces-death-of-commander-in-israeli-strike-in-lebanon-6642984]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Sep 2024 05:55:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hezbollah announced on Wednesday the death of a commander, hours after the Israeli army said it had killed him in a strike on Beirut's southern suburbs which Lebanese authorities said killed six people.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hezbollah announced on Wednesday the death of a commander, hours after the Israeli army said it had killed him in a strike on Beirut's southern suburbs which Lebanese authorities said killed six people.</p>

<p>In a statement, the Iran-backed group announced the death of "commander Ibrahim Mohammed Kobeissi", who was "martyred on the road to Jerusalem", the phrase Hezbollah uses to refer to fighters killed by Israeli strikes.</p>

<p>On Tuesday, Israel's army said it "eliminated Ibrahim Mohammed Kobeissi, the commander of the missile and rocket network of the Hezbollah terrorist organisation".</p>

<p>Lebanon's health ministry said in a statement that the "Israeli enemy raid on Ghobeiri in Beirut's southern suburbs killed six people and injured 15".</p>

<p>The Israeli military said Kobeissi commanded several rocket units, including a precision-guided missile unit, and was hit along with other commanders of Hezbollah's missiles and rockets force.</p>

<p>"Kobeissi was an important source of knowledge in the field of missiles and had close ties with senior Hezbollah military leaders," it said.</p>

<p>Israeli military spokesman Rear Admiral Daniel Hagari told a media briefing that "at least two" other commanders from Kobeissi's force were also "eliminated".</p>

<p>The raid came a day after Israel said it had launched another "targeted strike" on Beirut's southern suburbs.</p>

<p>Hezbollah said Ali Karake, its third-in-command, was alive and had moved to safety after a source close to the group told AFP the strike on Monday had targeted him.</p>

<p>Hezbollah and its arch-foe Israel have been exchanging near-daily cross-border fire since the Gaza war erupted last October.</p>

<p>But violence has spiralled dramatically in recent days, raising fears of all-out war.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/e02n2u88_israellebanon-conflict-afp_625x300_07_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Earlier, Israel's army said it "eliminated Ibrahim Mohammed Kobeissi" in airstrike.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-leads-donald-trump-by-38-points-among-asian-american-voters-survey-6642921]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris Leads Trump By 38 Points Among Asian American Voters: Survey]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-leads-donald-trump-by-38-points-among-asian-american-voters-survey-6642921]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Sep 2024 05:39:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Democratic presidential candidate Kamala Harris is leading by 38 points among Asian American voters against her Republican challenger Donald Trump, according to the results of a poll.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Democratic presidential candidate Kamala Harris is leading by 38 points among Asian American voters against her Republican challenger Donald Trump, according to the results of a poll.</p>

<p>The poll was conducted by NORC at the University of Chicago, and its results were released on Tuesday. This is the first survey since President Joe Biden dropped out of the race in July and Vice President Harris became the Democratic Party's presidential nominee.</p>

<p>According to the poll, Harris, 59, leads 78-year-old Trump by 38 percentage points among Asian American voters, expanding Biden's 15-point lead by 23 percentage points since spring.</p>

<p>As many as 66 per cent of Asian American voters plan on voting for Harris, compared to 28 per cent who say they back former president Trump. Those who say they will support another candidate or are undecided account for six per cent.</p>

<p>In the 2024 Asian American Voter Survey (AAVS), conducted in April-May, 46 per cent of Asian American voters backed Biden, and 31 per cent supported Trump, while 23 per cent said they planned to vote for someone else or were undecided.</p>

<p>In the 2020 AAVS, which was conducted in July-September that year, 54 per cent said they planned to vote for Biden, 30 per cent for Trump, and 16 per cent for someone else or were undecided.</p>

<p>Further, Harris' favourability among Asian American voters has increased by 18 points.</p>

<p>According to the survey, 62 per cent of Asian American voters say they have a favourable opinion of Harris, compared to 35 per cent who have an unfavourable opinion of her, up from the 2024 AAVS, in which 44 per cent had a favourable view of her while 42 per cent unfavourable.</p>

<p>On the other hand, 28 per cent of Asian American voters think favourably about Trump, compared to 70 per cent who have an unfavourable opinion of him. In the 2024 AAVS, 34 per cent had a favourable view of him and 62 per cent unfavourable.</p>

<p>The polls revealed that Harris' running mate, Minnesota Governor Tim Walz, was far more popular as a vice presidential candidate than the Republican nominee for vice president, JD Vance.</p>

<p>Fifty-six per cent of Asian American voters have a favourable opinion of Walz, compared to 18 per cent who did not, and 26 per cent did not know enough to have an opinion.</p>

<p>It said that 21 per cent of Asian American voters thought favourably of Vance, compared to 58 per cent who did not and 22 per cent did not know enough to have an opinion.</p>

<p>Thirty-eight per cent of Asian American voters also said Harris' identity as a woman is "extremely" or "very" important to them, compared to 27 per cent who say the same about her identity as an Asian Indian or South Asian.</p>

<p>The polls also showed Asian American voters are far more likely to say they've been contacted by the Democratic Party than the Republican Party.</p>

<p>The presidential elections will be held in the US on November 5.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/mjjmrfoo_kamala-harris_625x300_20_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[As many as 66% of Asian American voters plan on voting for Harris, compared to 28% Trump.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hezbollah-war-at-un-world-leaders-warn-against-full-scale-war-over-lebanon-6642919]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[At UN, World Leaders Warn Against "Full-Scale War" Over Lebanon]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hezbollah-war-at-un-world-leaders-warn-against-full-scale-war-over-lebanon-6642919]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Sep 2024 05:33:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[World leaders lined up at the United Nations on Tuesday to call on Israel to refrain from a full-scale war in Lebanon, with the organization's chief warning the situation was on the "brink."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>World leaders lined up at the United Nations on Tuesday to call on Israel to refrain from a full-scale war in Lebanon, with the organization's chief warning the situation was on the "brink."</p>

<p>The UN General Assembly, the high point of the international diplomatic calendar, comes after Lebanese authorities said Israeli strikes had killed 558 people -- 50 of them children.</p>

<p>"Full-scale war is not in anyone's interest. Even though the situation has escalated, a diplomatic solution is still possible," US President Joe Biden said in his farewell address to the global body.</p>

<p>"In fact, it remains the only path to lasting security to allow the residents from both countries to return to their homes on the border safely," Biden said ahead of an emergency UN Security Council session on Lebanon planned for Wednesday.</p>

<p>Biden's remarks drew disappointment from Lebanon's foreign minister Abdullah Bou Habib who said they were "not promising" and "would not solve the Lebanese problem," as he estimated that the number of people displaced by Israel's strikes has likely soared to reach half a million.</p>

<p>"We should all be alarmed by the escalation. Lebanon is at the brink," UN Secretary-General Antonio Guterres said when he opened the gathering.</p>

<p>Israel's ambassador to the UN Danny Danon said his country was "not eager" for a ground invasion of Lebanon.</p>

<p>"We don't want to send our boys to fight in a foreign country," he said.</p>

<p><strong>- 'End this war' -</strong></p>

<p>It is unclear what progress can be made to defuse the situation in Lebanon, with efforts to broker a ceasefire in Gaza -- which Israel has relentlessly pounded since October 2023 -- coming to nothing.</p>

<p>Biden on Tuesday pushed again for an elusive ceasefire between Israel and Hamas, telling the global body it was time to "end this war."</p>

<p>Mediator Qatar accused Israel of obstructing Gaza ceasefire talks, with Emir Sheikh Tamim bin Hamad Al-Thani saying "there is no Israeli partner for peace" under the government of Benjamin Netanyahu.</p>

<p>But he added: "We will continue our efforts of mediation to resolve the disputes through peaceful means."</p>

<p>Turkish President Recep Tayyip Erdogan accused Israel of dragging the entire region "into war."</p>

<p>"Not only children but also the UN system is dying in Gaza," Erdogan said in a scathing speech.</p>

<p>Guterres cautioned against "the possibility of transforming Lebanon (into) another Gaza," calling the situation in the Palestinian territory a "non-stop nightmare."</p>

<p>European Council President Charles Michel said that Israel had the right to exist and defend itself but without inflicting "collective punishment" on civilians living in areas targeted by its military.</p>

<p>President Masoud Pezeshkian of Iran -- which backs Hezbollah in Lebanon and Hamas in Gaza -- condemned "senseless and incomprehensible" inaction by the UN against Israel.</p>

<p>- 'Charade of hypocrisy' -</p>

<p>Responding to criticism of Israel, Danon called the General Assembly debate an "annual charade of hypocrisy."</p>

<p>"When the UN Secretary-General speaks about the release of our hostages, the UN assembly is silent, but when he speaks about the suffering in Gaza, he receives thunderous applause," Danon said.</p>

<p>Since last year's annual gathering, when Sudan's civil war and Russia's Ukraine invasion dominated, the world has faced an explosion of crises.</p>

<p>The October 7 attack by Palestinian group Hamas on Israel resulted in the deaths of 1,205 people and prompted a military response in Gaza that authorities say has killed at least 41,467 people.</p>

<p>Militants also seized 251 hostages, 97 of whom are still held in Gaza, including 33 the Israeli military says are dead.</p>

<p>Violence has raged across multiple fronts in the Middle East since the crisis erupted, with the conflict exposing deep divisions at the UN.</p>

<p>Palestinian President Mahmud Abbas took his seat alongside the Palestinian delegation, placed in alphabetical order in the General Assembly for the first time on Tuesday after the delegation received upgraded privileges in May.</p>

<p>At the rostrum, Jordan's King Abdullah II on Tuesday ruled out the forced displacement by Israel of Palestinians to his country, which he said would be a "war crime."</p>

<p>Ukraine was also on the agenda Tuesday with President Volodymyr Zelensky addressing a UN Security Council meeting on the Russian invasion.</p>

<p>"Russia can only be forced into peace, and that is exactly what's needed -- forcing Russia into peace," Zelensky said.</p>

<p>Biden said that Russian President Vladimir "Putin's war has failed at its core aim. He set out to destroy Ukraine, but Ukraine is still free."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/h7okrmro_israel-hezbollah_625x300_22_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Turkish President Recep Tayyip Erdogan accused Israel of dragging the entire region "into war."]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/crypto-ceo-and-bankman-fried-ex-caroline-ellison-gets-two-year-sentence-6642857]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Crypto CEO And Bankman-Fried Ex Caroline Ellison Gets Two-Year Sentence]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/crypto-ceo-and-bankman-fried-ex-caroline-ellison-gets-two-year-sentence-6642857]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Sep 2024 05:15:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Caroline Ellison, who testified against her former boyfriend and FTX founder Sam Bankman-Fried at his crypto fraud trial, was sentenced Tuesday to two years in prison for her role in the case, New York prosecutors told AFP.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Caroline <span class="marks8fyogb34" data-markjs="true" data-ogab="" data-ogac="" data-ogsb="" data-ogsc="" style="">Ellison</span>, who testified against her former boyfriend <span class="markz6tuthtlf" data-markjs="true" data-ogab="" data-ogac="" data-ogsb="" data-ogsc="" style="">and</span> FTX founder Sam <span class="mark7eabvdb8a" data-markjs="true" data-ogab="" data-ogac="" data-ogsb="" data-ogsc="" style="">Bankman-Fried</span> at his <span class="mark5iekqul2j" data-markjs="true" data-ogab="" data-ogac="" data-ogsb="" data-ogsc="" style="">crypto</span> fraud trial, was <span class="markfy66jpdo2" data-markjs="true" data-ogab="" data-ogac="" data-ogsb="" data-ogsc="" style="">sentence</span>d Tuesday to two years in prison for her role in the case, New York prosecutors told AFP.</p>

<p>Ellison, the former CEO of cryptocurrency firm Alameda Research, received a much lighter sentence than the maximum 110 years she faced after pleading guilty to seven charges, including fraud.</p>

<p>Her defense team had argued against prison time. Prosecutors with the Manhattan District Attorney's Office said they had not requested Judge Lewis Kaplan issue a specific sentence, instead simply suggesting he take her earlier cooperation into account.</p>

<p>Ellison served as a key witness in the trial of cryptocurrency superstar Bankman-Fried -- known by his initials "SBF" -- who was sentenced to 25 years in March for one of the largest financial fraud cases in history.</p>

<p>He is serving his sentence in prison and has appealed his conviction.</p>

<p>During her court testimony, Ellison accused Bankman-Fried of dipping into customers' funds to drive his more risky projects. He countered by attempting to pin the blame on Ellison, describing her as a bad manager.</p>

<p>A billionaire before he turned 30, Bankman-Fried had been a poster boy for the cryptocurrency boom.</p>

<p>Within the span of a few months, he had turned his small start-up FTX, first launched in 2019, into the world's second largest cryptocurrency trading platform.</p>

<p>However, as exposed by the Bankman-Fried trial, the company had used the assets deposited into FTX to perform riskier transactions via sister company Alameda Research, as well as purchase real estate and make political donations.</p>

<p>FTX imploded in November 2022, reporting more than $8 billion in debt by the time the company filed for bankruptcy.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/35faoikg_caroline-ellison_625x300_25_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Caroline Ellison was sentenced Tuesday to two years in prison for her role crypto fraud case.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-can-only-be-forced-into-peace-volodymyr-zelensky-tells-un-6642604]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russia "Can Only Be Forced Into Peace," Zelensky Tells UN]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-can-only-be-forced-into-peace-volodymyr-zelensky-tells-un-6642604]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Sep 2024 03:47:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky said Tuesday at the United Nations that Russia can only be forced into a peace settlement, as he vowed not to negotiate on Moscow's terms to end the war.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky said Tuesday at the United Nations that Russia can only be forced into a peace settlement, as he vowed not to negotiate on Moscow's terms to end the war.</p>

<p>Addressing a special UN Security Council session attended by a representative of Russia, Zelensky also joined the United States in pressuring Iran and North Korea for alleged military support to Russia.</p>

<p>Zelensky, on a trip in which he is presenting his "victory plan" for Ukraine, questioned the sincerity of Russian President Vladimir Putin, who has suggested freezing lines of control.</p>

<p>"We know some in the world want to talk to Putin," Zelensky said, "to possibly hear from him that he's upset because we are exercising our right to defend our people."</p>

<p>Zelensky, clad in his trademark military fatigues, called such views "insanity."</p>

<p>"Russia can only be forced into peace, and that is exactly what's needed -- forcing Russia into peace," he said.</p>

<p>Zelensky said that any end to Russia's two-year-old invasion has to be based on the UN Charter, which enshrines sovereignty by member states.</p>

<p>"One day in this hall, it will surely be said that Russia's war against Ukraine has ended -- not paused, not forgotten, truly ended," Zelensky said.</p>

<p>"This will happen not because someone got tired of the war, not because someone traded something with Putin. Russia's war against Ukraine will end because the UN Charter will work."</p>

<p>Zelensky will on Thursday meet at the White House with President Joe Biden, who in an address to the United Nations urged international support for Ukraine until victory.</p>

<p>Zelensky's political positioning comes weeks ahead of a US election in which Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump has described billions of dollars of US aid to Ukraine as wasteful and voiced admiration for Putin.</p>

<p>- China calls for peace push -</p>

<p>Zelensky again promised a second "peace summit" and said he was inviting both China and India, key powers that have refused to go along with Western sanctions on Ukraine.</p>

<p>Chinese Foreign Minister Wang Yi, addressing the Security Council, welcomed what he described as rising pressure for diplomacy.</p>

<p>"Dialogue and negotiation are the only viable way to settle the Ukraine crisis. If day after day, peace talks cannot be launched, then misjudgment and miscalculation would build, which leads to even greater crisis," he said.</p>

<p>He insisted China was devoted to peace, saying: "China is not a creator of the Ukraine crisis, nor are we a party to it."</p>

<p>But he spoke ahead of US Secretary of State Antony Blinken, who again charged that China has been fueling Russia's military build-up through the export of items nominally for civilian use including advanced electronics and machine tools.</p>

<p>Blinken rejected suggestions that his criticism was hypocritical when the United States is arming Ukraine.</p>

<p>"There is a profound difference. Russia is the aggressor. Ukraine is the victim," Blinken said.</p>

<p>He called for the United Nations to act against both North Korea, which has ramped up military supplies to Russia, and Iran, recently accused by US intelligence of shipping short-range missiles to Russia.</p>

<p>"Support from Tehran and Pyongyang is helping Putin inflict carnage, suffering and ruin on innocent Ukrainian men, women, children," Blinken said.</p>

<p>Zelensky said of the two countries: "Russia has no legitimate reason -- none at all -- for making Iran and North Korea de facto accomplices in its criminal war in Europe, with their weapons killing us, killing Ukrainians."</p>

<p>Iranian President Masoud Pezeshkian, a self-styled moderate in the cleric-run state, on Monday denied Tehran has sent weapons and criticized Moscow for its "aggression."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/6fdrip3s_volodymyr-zelensky_625x300_25_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Zelensky said that any end to Russia's two-year-old invasion has to be based on the UN Charter.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ryan-routh-charged-with-attempted-assassination-of-trump-cnn-reports-6642572]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Gunman Ryan Routh Charged With Attempted Assassination Of Trump]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ryan-routh-charged-with-attempted-assassination-of-trump-cnn-reports-6642572]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Sep 2024 03:31:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The gunman accused of planning to kill Donald Trump at his Florida golf course was indicted Tuesday on three additional counts, including attempted assassination of a major presidential candidate, the US Department of Justice announced.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The gunman accused of planning to kill Donald Trump at his Florida golf course was indicted Tuesday on three additional counts, including attempted assassination of a major presidential candidate, the US Department of Justice announced.</p>

<p>Ryan Routh, 58, was arrested on September 15 after Secret Service agents spotted him with a gun near the course where Trump was playing.</p>

<p>He has already been charged with two gun crimes in relation to the incident.</p>

<p>The new indictment was issued late Tuesday by a grand jury -- a panel of citizens with investigative powers -- in Miami, Florida, the justice department said in a statement.</p>

<p>Court documents indicated that the case was assigned at random to Judge Aileen Cannon -- a Trump appointee who stopped criminal proceedings against the former president over his retention of top-secret documents at his private residence.</p>

<p>In addition to attempted assassination of a presidential candidate, the new charges also include possession of a firearm in furtherance of a violent crime and assault on a federal officer, who court documents indicated was a Secret Service agent.</p>

<p>Routh's gun was spotted poking out from the bushes by a Secret Service agent as he scouted ahead during Trump's golf game. The agent fired on the suspect, who fled but was later apprehended.</p>

<p>A federal judge ruled on Monday that Routh should remain in custody.</p>

<p>FBI analysis of Routh's phone showed he had been in Florida since August 18, and his devices were located multiple times between that date and September 15 near Trump's golf course and his Mar-a-Lago residence, prosecutors said.</p>

<p>Before being spotted by the Secret Service agent, he had spent nearly 12 hours in the vicinity of the club, according to his phone location data, the prosecution has said.</p>

<p>It was the second attempted assassination attempt on Trump this summer. The first took place on July 13 at a rally in Butler, Pennsylvania, when a gunman opened fire, killing one person and wounding Trump in the ear.</p>

<p>The candidate was otherwise unharmed.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/evuh2p8o_ryan-routh_625x300_25_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Ryan Routh has already been charged with two gun crimes in relation to the incident.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>