<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Sat, 19 Oct 2024 00:21:31 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/we-have-a-lot-of-interest-in-indian-films-russia-president-vladimir-putin-praises-bollywood-6821574]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["We Have A Lot Of Interest In Indian Films": Putin Praises Bollywood]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/we-have-a-lot-of-interest-in-indian-films-russia-president-vladimir-putin-praises-bollywood-6821574]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 19 Oct 2024 00:21:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russian President Vladimir Putin on Friday praised 'Bollywood' and said that Indian films are most popular in the country in a media briefing ahead of the BRICS Summit.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russian President Vladimir Putin on Friday praised 'Bollywood' and said that Indian films are most popular in the country in a media briefing ahead of the BRICS Summit.</p>

<p>On being asked if Russia will give incentives to BRICS member states for shooting films in the country, Russian President Putin said, "If we look at BRICS member states, I think in this country Indian films are most popular. We have a special TV channel with Indian movies being shown on it round the clock. We have a lot of interest in Indian films. We hold the BRICS film festival. This year Moscow International Film Festival introduces films from BRICS nations. We are positive that if Indian films are interested then we will find some common ground and promote them in Russia. Pharmaceuticals will also be a good undertaking. I am ready to talk to the Prime Minister of India and we will come to terms and there will be no difficulty..."</p>

<p>Putin said that he would talk to his 'friend', Prime Minister Narendra Modi about this proposal and was confident that the two would come to terms.</p>

<p>"I'm ready to talk with our friend, the Prime Minister of India when he arrives in Kazan. I'm sure we will come to terms 100 per cent. No difficulties, I observe there... It would be fascinating to see not only Indian films but those featuring BRICS countries' actors representing their cultures, an Indian actor, a Chinese and Ethiopian actor. Well, you know, we discussed it with the colleagues from BRICS nations that we should organize a festival of theatrical art and we established the cinema academy," he said.</p>

<p>Notably, Bollywood movies are very famous in Russia, as both societies are arguably similar, and their tastes too appeared to match - they loved a rags-to-riches story about the underdog and a clear division between good and evil. The highest-grossing Indian film in the erstwhile Soviet Union was Disco Dancer (1982), written by Rahi Masoom Raza and starring actor Mithun Chakraborty. In terms of footfalls, the only Indian films estimated to have sold 100 million tickets overseas were Awaara and Disco Dancer.</p>

<p>Raj Kapoor was already a known cultural figure in Russia. When his movie Awaara came out in 1951, it immediately became a buzz in Russia. Moreover, The images of distant fabulous India inspired Russian thinkers, poets, composers, and artists. The influence of cultures was mutual -- the enormous spiritual influence that Leo Tolstoy had on the formation of the views of Mahatma Gandhi is well known.</p>

<p>Putin also said that he, alongwith other BRICS nations will create music festivals in the future.</p>

<p>"Jointly, we will pursue this track in future and popular music festivals also need to be created so there is an open field for work and we'll be interested and the media definitely outlets I think will gladly cover and participate," he said.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi will visit Russia at the invitation of Russian President Vladimir Putin from October 22-23 to attend the 16th BRICS Summit in Kazan.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/dcvjqtfg_vladimir-putin_625x300_16_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[" We have a special TV channel with Indian movies being shown on it round the clock", Putin said.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/meta-releases-ai-model-that-can-check-how-other-models-work-6821254]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Meta Releases AI Model That Can Check How Other Models Work]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/meta-releases-ai-model-that-can-check-how-other-models-work-6821254]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 18 Oct 2024 23:19:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Facebook owner Meta said on Friday it was releasing a batch of new AI models from its research division, including a "Self-Taught Evaluator" that may offer a path toward less human involvement in the AI development process.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Facebook owner Meta said on Friday it was releasing a batch of new AI models from its research division, including a "Self-Taught Evaluator" that may offer a path toward less human involvement in the AI development process.</p>

<p>The release follows Meta's introduction of the tool in an August paper, which detailed how it relies upon the same "chain of thought" technique used by OpenAI's recently released o1 models to get it to make reliable judgments about models' responses.</p>

<p>That technique involves breaking down complex problems into smaller logical steps and appears to improve the accuracy of responses on challenging problems in subjects like science, coding and math.</p>

<p>Meta's researchers used entirely AI-generated data to train the evaluator model, eliminating human input at that stage as well.</p>

<p>The ability to use AI to evaluate AI reliably offers a glimpse at a possible pathway toward building autonomous AI agents that can learn from their own mistakes, two of the Meta researchers behind the project told Reuters.</p>

<p>Many in the AI field envision such agents as digital assistants intelligent enough to carry out a vast array of tasks without human intervention.</p>

<p>Self-improving models could cut out the need for an often expensive and inefficient process used today called Reinforcement Learning from Human Feedback, which requires input from human annotators who must have specialized expertise to label data accurately and verify that answers to complex math and writing queries are correct.</p>

<p>"We hope, as AI becomes more and more super-human, that it will get better and better at checking its work, so that it will actually be better than the average human," said Jason Weston, one of the researchers.</p>

<p>"The idea of being self-taught and able to self-evaluate is basically crucial to the idea of getting to this sort of super-human level of AI," he said.</p>

<p>Other companies including Google and Anthropic have also published research on the concept of RLAIF, or Reinforcement Learning from AI Feedback. Unlike Meta, however, those companies tend not to release their models for public use.</p>

<p>Other AI tools released by Meta on Friday included an update to the company's image-identification Segment Anything model, a tool that speeds up LLM response generation times and datasets that can be used to aid the discovery of new inorganic materials.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/s6ovor1g_meta-ai_625x300_18_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Meta's researchers used entirely AI-generated data to train the evaluator model. (Representation)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-searching-for-yahya-sinwars-replacement-outside-gaza-report-6821136]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hamas Searching For Yahya Sinwar's Replacement Outside Gaza: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-searching-for-yahya-sinwars-replacement-outside-gaza-report-6821136]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 18 Oct 2024 22:57:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Palestinian militant group Hamas will likely replace Yahya Sinwar with a new political leader based outside Gaza while his brother - Mohammad Sinwar - is expected to assume a bigger role directing the war against Israel in the territory.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Palestinian operator group Hamas will likely replace Yahya Sinwar with a new political leader based outside Gaza while his brother - Mohammad Sinwar - is expected to assume a bigger role directing the war against Israel in the territory, experts say.</p>

<p>In its leadership deliberations, Hamas must consider not only the preferences of its main backer - Iran - but also the interests of the Gulf Arab state of Qatar, where all the main candidates to take over as politburo chief currently reside.</p>

<p>Sinwar, a mastermind of the October 7, 2023 attack that ignited the devastating Gaza war, was killed by Israeli forces in a gunbattle on Wednesday -- the second time in less than three months that Hamas has lost its top leader.</p>

<p>Its previous chief, Ismail Haniyeh, was assassinated in Iran in July almost certainly by Israel.</p>

<p>When Sinwar replaced him, he fused together both the military and political leadership in Gaza, but that does not appear likely this time around.</p>

<p>After more than a year of ferocious Israeli attacks that have pounded Hamas, killed thousands of its fighters and eliminated senior figures both inside and out of Gaza, it is not clear how the Islamist group will emerge from this latest blow.</p>

<p>Sinwar's deputy Khalil Al-Hayya, who is viewed as a potential successor, struck a defiant note on Friday, saying Israeli hostages would not be returned until Israeli troops withdrew from Gaza and the war ended.</p>

<p>Hamas has a history of quickly and efficiently replacing its fallen leaders, with its top decision-making body, the Shura Council, tasked with naming a new head.</p>

<p>The Shura Council represents all Hamas members in the Gaza Strip, the West Bank, Israeli prisons and the Palestinian community, meaning the new leader should have the authority to enter ceasefire talks even if he is not in Gaza, where Hamas gunmen still hold dozens of Israelis hostage.</p>

<p>Besides Hayya, who is Hamas' chief negotiator, the other main leadership contenders are Khaled Meshaal, Haniyeh's predecessor, and Mohammad Darwish, a little-known figure who chairs the Shura Council, according to analysts and a Hamas source.</p>

<p>Hamas will need to notify Qatar, which has played a major role in rounds of so far fruitless ceasefire talks, and other regional capitals ahead of its decision, the source said.</p>

<p><strong>Dividing Duties</strong></p>

<p>Ashraf Abouelhoul, an expert on Palestinian affairs, expected Sinwar's responsibilities to be split between two roles - one overseeing military affairs and another running the political office, responsible for international contacts and shaping policies.</p>

<p>"Iran is Hamas strongest ally, which supports the group with money and weapons, and their blessing is key to who becomes Sinwar's successor," said Abouelhoul, managing editor of the state-owned newspaper Al-Ahram in Egypt.</p>

<p>He expected Hamas to stick by core demands in future ceasefire talks, chiefly that Israeli forces withdraw from Gaza and stop the war. But it could show more flexibility on some conditions, such as the details of any deal swapping Israeli hostages for Palestinians imprisoned by Israel.</p>

<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu has declared Sinwar's killing a milestone but that the war is not yet over, saying fighting would continue until the hostages are released.</p>

<p>Hamas was founded in 1987 and is a branch of the Sunni Islamist Muslim Brotherhood movement. Its decisions are usually taken through consensus in Hamas institutions.</p>

<p>With Sinwar dead, the Hamas leadership for Gaza has temporarily passed to his Qatar-based deputy, Hayya.</p>

<p>But the ongoing war and communication difficulties might impose limits on just how much day-to-day contact Hayya can have with men on the ground, leaving the armed wing - the Qassam Brigades - in the driving seat, experts say.</p>

<p>A Hamas source said Hayya was expected to encounter no problems exercising his role as "de facto Gaza leader". The source noted that Hayya had maintained good relations with the military wing and had been close to both Sinwar and Haniyeh.</p>

<p>Akram Attallah, a Palestinian political analyst, said he expected the armed wing to respect Hayya's authority - even from afar. He also expected Mohammad Sinwar to emerge as a more significant figure in the armed wing and in Hamas in general.</p>

<p>A veteran commander of the Qassam Brigades, Mohammad Sinwar has seldom appeared in public, has long been on Israel's most-wanted list and has survived several attempts on his life, Hamas sources said.</p>

<p>Hamas-led gunmen killed 1,200 people and abducted another 250 during the Oct. 7 attack, according to Israeli tallies. This prompted an Israeli offensive which, according to Palestinian authorities, has killed more than 42,000 Palestinians, laid waste to Gaza, and driven nearly all its population from their homes.</p>

<p>Sinwar's appointment in August was seen as both a show of defiance and internal unity by Hamas.</p>

<p>His close ties to Iran were seen as a factor supporting his candidacy. Both Darwish and Hayya are also seen as close to Tehran, whose support will be vital for Hamas to recover after the war.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the prospects of the prominent former Hamas leader Khaled Meshaal have been clouded by a record of friction with Tehran after his support for the Sunni Muslim-led revolt in 2011 against Syrian President Bashar al-Assad.</p>

<p>Attallah said Hayya's ties to Iran stood him in better stead than Meshaal. But if Iran softened its opposition to Meshaal, he may have a chance, he said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/158kral_yahya-sinwar_625x300_17_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Yahya Sinwar's deputy Khalil Al-Hayya is viewed as a potential successor.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/barack-obama-and-michelle-obama-team-up-with-kamala-harris-in-historic-campaign-appearance-6820643]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Obamas And Kamala Harris Team Up In Historic Campaign Appearance]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/barack-obama-and-michelle-obama-team-up-with-kamala-harris-in-historic-campaign-appearance-6820643]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 18 Oct 2024 22:55:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[With just three weeks remaining in the presidential campaign, the polls still find it to be an even-steven affair. Harris hopes to tap into some political charisma from the Obamas, especially with her losing ground to Trump as polls suggest.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With just three weeks remaining in the presidential campaign, the polls still suggest it to be an even-steven situation. Kamala Harris hopes to tap into some political charisma from the Obamas, especially with her losing ground to Donald Trump as the latest polls suggest.</p>

<h2><strong>HARRIS, TRUMP NECK-AND-NECK</strong></h2>

<p>As per the latest three polls on Sunday, Kamala Harris's lead has gone southward in the final dash to the election in November. According to the latest NBC News poll, the Democratic and Republican nominees are currently deadlocked in national polls, with each holding 48% support, just ahead of the November 5 election.</p>

<p>Harris is currently leading Trump by a narrow margin of 50% to 48% among likely voters, according to the latest ABC News/Ipsos poll, and the latest CBS News/YouGov poll reveals a tight presidential race, with Kamala Harris holding a narrow lead over Donald Trump among likely voters, 51% to 48%.</p>

<p>To support Harris in her political endeavor, the Obamas are set to hit the campaign trail in separate events starting next week as they are still significantly popular with the Democratic base and hope to drive turnout in the swing states.</p>

<p>On 26th October in Michigan, former first lady Michelle Obama will campaign alongside Kamala Harris this election season and former president Barack Obama will also be seen with her next Thursday in Georgia. Apart from this, he is also set to visit other states solo.</p>

<h3><strong>OBAMA FACES FURY</strong></h3>

<p>The polls have been notably concerning for the Democrats, and although Harris is leading among women of all races, she is struggling to get considerable buttress from men, including Hispanics and African Americans. Obama had addressed this quandary for which he drew some backlash.</p>

<p>He had rebuked Black men for not showing as much enthusiasm to Harris as he had received back in 2008 and 2012 and firmly urged them to support the idea of a woman being president.</p>

<p>"You're coming up with all kinds of reasons and excuses, I've got a problem with that," Obama said at a campaign rally in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. "Because part of it makes me think - and I'm speaking to men directly - part of it makes me think that, well, you just aren't feeling the idea of having a woman as president, and you're coming up with other alternatives and other reasons for that."</p>

<p>Obama also posted on X saying, ".@KamalaHarris has spent her life fighting on behalf of people who need a voice and a chance – and she's going to keep fighting for you. That's the kind of person I'm proud to vote for and that's the kind of president that we need."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">.<a href="https://twitter.com/KamalaHarris?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@KamalaHarris</a> has spent her life fighting on behalf of people who need a voice and a chance – and she's going to keep fighting for you. That's the kind of person I'm proud to vote for and that's the kind of president that we need. <a href="https://t.co/IGbZfR5TJA">pic.twitter.com/IGbZfR5TJA</a></p>
— Barack Obama (@BarackObama) <a href="https://twitter.com/BarackObama/status/1847025764929015846?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 17, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>Kamala Harris was a strong supporter of Barack Obama's presidential run back in 2008, and now the tables have turned. As the Democratic Party's standard-bearer for the 2024 election, Harris is receiving behind-the-scenes support from Obama himself.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/1pbfhqts_barack-obama-kamala-harris-obama-harris-getty_625x300_18_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Barack Obama and Michelle Obama will jon Kamala Harris on Campaign in key election push]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/singapore-teen-arrested-for-allegedly-planning-isis-inspired-terror-attack-6820858]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Singapore Teen Arrested For Allegedly Planning ISIS-Inspired Terror Attack]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/singapore-teen-arrested-for-allegedly-planning-isis-inspired-terror-attack-6820858]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 18 Oct 2024 22:08:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Singapore has arrested a teenage boy who was allegedly planning an ISIS-inspired terror attack on a busy suburb, the interior minister said Friday, adding it was a "very close shave".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Singapore has arrested a teenage boy who was allegedly planning an ISIS-inspired terror attack on a busy suburb, the interior minister said Friday, adding it was a "very close shave".</p>

<p>After watching Islamic State propaganda glorifying knife attacks, the 17-year-old visited the suburb to rehearse his attack before he was arrested in August, Home Minister K. Shanmugam said.</p>

<p>"He was quite serious because he actually practised stabbing motions with the scissors. He checked out which place would cause death -- basically the neck area -- so he practised hitting at the neck," Shanmugam told reporters.</p>

<p>"I would say this was a very close shave. It is very fortunate that ISD (Internal Security Department) arrested him in time."</p>

<p>The teenager, detained under the Internal Security Act, had allegedly planned a stabbing spree to coincide with school holidays in September when the area would be teeming with people.</p>

<p>In a statement released on Friday, ISD said the teenager was exposed to the deluge of online extremist materials posted by the Islamic State group after Hamas' attack on Israel on October 7 last year.</p>

<p>"He joined various online groups which provided updates on ISIS's activities and bought into ISIS's rhetoric of promoting the use of violence to establish an Islamic caliphate," ISD said.</p>

<p>By January, "the youth had become a staunch ISIS supporter and aspired to die as a martyr while fighting for the group," it added.</p>

<p>He took a pledge of allegiance to IS and intended to travel to Syria to fight there, according to ISD.</p>

<p>The teenager acted alone as he was unable to radicalise other people, ISD added.</p>

<p>His family noticed him watching videos of radical preachers and advised him to stop, but he continued, using "codewords" when discussing his beliefs online, the department said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2015-11/singapore-policeman-afp_650x400_71446877230.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The teenager was detained under Internal Security Act. (Representation)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/timebomb-damaged-ship-carrying-explosive-cargo-stranded-in-north-sea-for-weeks-6820748]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Damaged Ship Carrying Explosive Cargo Stranded In North Sea For Weeks]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/timebomb-damaged-ship-carrying-explosive-cargo-stranded-in-north-sea-for-weeks-6820748]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 18 Oct 2024 21:48:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A damaged ship, spurned by European ports because of its potentially explosive cargo, has been stranded in the North Sea for weeks while authorities work out what to do with it.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A damaged ship, spurned by European ports because of its potentially explosive cargo, has been stranded in the North Sea for weeks while authorities work out what to do with it.</p>

<p>The Maltese-flagged Ruby is the latest example of an unwanted vessel left in limbo because no-one dares to handle it. Such vessels, sometimes nicknamed "timebombs", remain stuck for weeks, even months.</p>

<p>Ruby, a Handymax bulk carrier, has 20,000 tonnes of ammonium nitrate on board. That is more than seven times the amount of ammonium nitrate -- used in fertilisers as well as in explosives -- that detonated in Lebanon in 2020, devastating the port of Beirut.</p>

<p>After the vessel set off from the Russian port of Kandalaksha on August 22, it ran into a storm in the Barents Sea and limped, damaged, into the Norwegian port of Tromso for damage inspection.</p>

<p>It was subsequently ordered to leave and proceed with the aid of a tug to another port elsewhere for repairs.</p>

<p>It was turned away by Lithuania, which insisted the ship must offload its volatile cargo first, and continued southwards.</p>

<p>Since September 25, it has been anchored off southeastern England near the Dover Strait, which is one of world's busiest shipping lanes.</p>

<p><strong>Combustion agent</strong></p>

<p>British coastguards said the Ruby was seaworthy, stressing: "The vessel has appropriate safety certificates approved by the vessel's flag state and is able to make its own way."</p>

<p>But it has remained stuck in mooring since September, with its mainly Syrian crew still on board.</p>

<p>The Ruby's Dubai-based managers said they hoped to offload the cargo in a UK port so the vessel could be put in dry dock for repairs.</p>

<p>"It has been logistically challenging to find an adequate solution, which partly explains the delay," the managing company told AFP.</p>

<p>Ports willing to accept a potentially hazardous load are few and far between.</p>

<p>"People associate it (the Ruby) with Beirut but I think it's entirely possible to manage this situation," said Eric Slominski, an expert in shipping dangerous goods.</p>

<p>The Ruby's cargo was destined to make fertiliser while the ammonium nitrate in Beirut had been specifically intended to manufacture explosives, he pointed out.</p>

<p>"It's not a product you can mess around with but it isn't explosive," Nicolas Tanic, from French marine pollution organisation Cedre, said of the Ruby's cargo.</p>

<p>"It's a combustion agent for fuelling fires," said Tanic, whose organisation has analysed the ship's load.</p>

<p><strong>Erika disaster</strong></p>

<p>He said the chemical compound's Russian origins and haunting memories of the Beirut port disaster had triggered alarm and a media frenzy.</p>

<p>But the French shipowners' body said ports could have other reasons too for spurning the Ruby.</p>

<p>"If a vessel gets grounded in your channel, it shuts your port. If it grounds at one of your docks, the dock's unusable for a couple of months. It's a big risk to accept a vessel in difficulty," said managing director Laurent Martens.</p>

<p>In addition, unloading a cargo like the Ruby's is a lengthy operation that "costs hundreds of thousands of euros", Martens explained.</p>

<p>In the wake of the Erika disaster in 1999 -- when an oil tanker of that name broke apart off the western coast of France -- the European Union tightened its laws on maritime safety.</p>

<p>The Erika spilled around 20,000 tonnes of heavy fuel oil into the sea, polluting 400 kilometres (250 miles) of coastline and killing between 150,000 and 300,000 seabirds.</p>

<p>EU states are now required to provide places of refuge for ships in distress to avoid environmental pollution.</p>

<p>But the rules are subject to interpretation.</p>

<p>In 2012, France denied access to the MSC Flaminia for a month while it drifted, crewless, off the coast of Brittany after a fire on board the ship, which was carrying 151 containers labelled "dangerous" goods.</p>

<p>The stricken vessel was ultimately towed to the Germany port of Wilhelmshaven.</p>

<p>In 2015, the same North Sea port provided haven to the Purple Beach, which had burst into flames with 5,000 tonnes of fertiliser on board.</p>

<p>The Purple Beach spent nearly two years in Germany while it was inspected and the authorities cast around for somewhere to send the fertiliser.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/d7s6fc38_ship-generic-unsplash_625x300_17_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Ruby, a Handymax bulk carrier, has 20,000 tonnes of ammonium nitrate on board. (Representation)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-next-for-hamas-after-its-chief-yahya-sinwars-killing-6820429]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Can Hamas Recover After Yahya Sinwar's Killing? What Experts Say]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-next-for-hamas-after-its-chief-yahya-sinwars-killing-6820429]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 18 Oct 2024 20:54:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel's killing of Hamas leader Yahya Sinwar dealt a huge blow to the Palestinian group, and while it leaves a gaping void at the top of the movement, its militants remain determined to fight.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel's killing of Hamas leader Yahya Sinwar dealt a huge blow to the Palestinian group, and while it leaves a gaping void at the top of the movement, its militants remain determined to fight.</p>

<p>Sinwar masterminded the October 7, 2023 attack on Israel that sparked the Gaza war, and became the leader of Hamas in August after the death of his predecessor, Ismail Haniyeh.</p>

<p>While Israel has hailed Sinwar's killing as a major win, analysts say Hamas could use his legacy to mobilise a new generation of militants, who grew up suffering the consequences of Israel's retaliatory war.</p>

<p>Here is a look at what could come next for Hamas.</p>

<p><strong>How harsh a blow?</strong></p>

<p>Confirming Sinwar's death in a video statement on Friday, Hamas official Khalil al-Hayya said the group was mourning the loss of its "great leader".</p>

<p>Sinwar's killing was not just "an extremely symbolic event" but created "a leadership vacuum in this very networked organisation", Middle East analyst Andreas Krieg of King's College London said.</p>

<p>His death comes little more than two months after the death in Iran of Hamas's political chief Ismail Haniyeh.</p>

<p>Hamas and Iran have blamed Israel for Haniyeh's death, though Israel has not offered comment.</p>

<p>Krieg said differences had emerged between Hamas's political leadership, in exile mostly in Qatar, and the military and operational wings in Gaza.</p>

<p>In July Israel also said it killed Hamas military chief Mohammed Deif in Gaza, which Hamas has denied.</p>

<p>"Different cells of Hamas will continue fighting, but at the core of the movement, there's a vacuum there, and that will make it very difficult to coordinate," Krieg said.</p>

<p>James Dorsey, of the National University of Singapore's Middle East Institute, said Sinwar was an "exceptional" figure in Hamas who enjoyed "broad support within the movement from both the political and the military wing".</p>

<p><strong>Who could replace Sinwar?</strong></p>

<p>Following his predecessor's death, Sinwar emerged from a field of contenders for the Hamas leadership that included relative moderates based outside of Gaza like Musa Abu Marzuk, an adviser and negotiator seen as close to Haniyeh.</p>

<p>Dorsey said other exiled Hamas figures like Qatar-based Hayya, close to Sinwar and lead negotiator in unsuccessful talks for a Gaza truce and hostage exchange, could once again become contenders for the top post.</p>

<p>Other exiled leaders who could take over, he said, include Khaled Meshaal, who served as Hamas chief until he was replaced by Haniyeh in 2017.</p>

<p>Sinwar's selection as leader over members of its political wing in August was widely viewed as a restructuring of the movement around armed struggle, with the focus on the war in Gaza.</p>

<p>Krieg said "the next leader is inevitably going to be someone from the operational level".</p>

<p>Should the leadership be handed to a man on the battlefield, one name has emerged as a favourite: that of Sinwar's younger brother Mohammed Sinwar.</p>

<p>Krieg said the brother "doesn't have the charismatic leadership appeal that Yahya had. But he has a good reputation... as a militant and fighter."</p>

<p><strong>Can Hamas recover?</strong></p>

<p>In his defiant statement on Friday, Hayya said Sinwar's death would help strengthen the movement, adding his killing had set him among "the leaders and symbols of the movement who preceded him".</p>

<p>Krieg said that, despite a "tactical, operational defeat" for Hamas with the killing of its leader, Sinwar's death was "not going to change armed resistance against Israel within Gaza".</p>

<p>Dorsey said Hamas was a movement that had "as a matter of principle proven very resilient".</p>

<p>"Hamas's history... is a history of Israel assassinating its leaders. Yahya Sinwar joins the list," he added.</p>

<p>The killed leader's legacy would "obviously" be tied to the legacy of the October 7 attack, said Dorsey.</p>

<p>But whether the war sparked by the attack could continue to swell Hamas's ranks has as much to do with the sheer levels of desperation in Gaza as it does with Sinwar.</p>

<p>"This is a generation that has lost all hope... certainly in Gaza. If you have no hope, you've got nothing and nowhere to go, you've got nothing to lose," Dorsey said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/7464fuuo_yahya-sinwar_650x400_17_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Analysts say Hamas could use Yahya Sinwar's legacy to mobilise a new generation of militants. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/australias-northern-territory-to-resume-jailing-10-year-olds-to-reduce-youth-crime-rates-6820198]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Australia's Northern Territory To Soon Resume Jailing 10-Year-Olds]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/australias-northern-territory-to-resume-jailing-10-year-olds-to-reduce-youth-crime-rates-6820198]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 18 Oct 2024 20:21:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Australian Northern Territory (NT) will soon allow children as young as 10 to be jailed again, after a reversal of the previous government's decision to raise the age of criminal responsibility to 12.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Australian Northern Territory (NT) will soon allow children as young as 10 to be jailed again, after a reversal of the previous government's decision to raise the age of criminal responsibility to 12. According to the <em>BBC</em>, the new Country Liberal Party (CLP) government, which was elected in August, said a reversal is necessary to reduce youth crime rates. It argued that returning the age to 10 will ultimately protect children, even though doctors, human rights organisations and Indigenous groups have disputed this logic.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cpqz8gyp500o" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>BBC</em></a>, the Australian Northern Territory already jails children at a rate 11 times higher than any other jurisdiction in the country. Critics have said that this new law will not reduce crime, instead, it will disproportionately affect Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander children.&nbsp;</p>

<p>However, NT Chief Minister Lia Finocchiaro said her government had been given a mandate after their landslide election victory, and that the change would allow courts to put young offenders through programmes designed to address the root causes of their crimes - which, according to statistics, are most commonly break-in and assault offences.</p>

<p>"We have this obligation to the child who has been let down in a number of ways, over a long period of time," Ms Finocchiaro told the parliament on Thursday. "And we have [an obligation to] the people who just want to be safe, people who don't want to live in fear anymore," she added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Moreover, the NT has also tightened bail rules and introduced penalties for "posting and boasting" about crime on social media. "We make no apologies for delivering on our commitments to reduce crime for all Territorians," Ms Finocchiaro said.</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/company-hacked-after-accidentally-hiring-north-korean-cyber-criminal-for-remote-job-6819772">Company Hacked After Accidentally Hiring North Korean Cyber Criminal For Remote Job</a></strong></p>

<p>Opposition Leader Selena Uibo, however, called it a "dark day" for the territory. "We know - because all of the evidence tells us this - that the earlier a child comes into contact with the criminal justice system, the more prolonged their involvement is likely to be," she said.</p>

<p>"We want to see children held accountable for bad behaviour but then supported to get on a better path," Ms Uibo added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Notably, the change will come into effect at a later date that is yet to be confirmed. Only the Australian Capital Territory has raised the age of criminal responsibility above 10. Victoria has passed legislation to do so, which will come into effect next year. The Tasmanian government has also said it will raise the age to 14 by 2029.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-02/c9cdh8ao_us-prison-generic-us-jail-generic-getty_625x300_24_February_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The change will come into effect at a later date. (Representative pic)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/company-hacked-after-accidentally-hiring-north-korean-cyber-criminal-for-remote-job-6819772]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Company Hacked After Accidentally Hiring North Korean Cyber Criminal]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/company-hacked-after-accidentally-hiring-north-korean-cyber-criminal-for-remote-job-6819772]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 18 Oct 2024 19:20:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A company recently found itself in a difficult situation after it accidentally hired a North Korean IT worker, who later stole sensitive data and attempted to extort the company after being fired.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A company recently found itself in a difficult situation after it accidentally hired a North Korean IT worker, who later stole sensitive data and attempted to extort the company after being fired. According to the <em>BBC</em>, the unidentified firm, which is based in the UK, US and Australia, hired the North Korean cyber criminal after he faked his employment history and personal details. He was hired in the summers as a contractor and worked for the firm for four months. Once he had access to the company's computer network, he downloaded sensitive company data and sent a ransom demand.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/ce8vedz4yk7o" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>BBC </em></a>reported that the man used the firm's remote working tools to log into the corporate network. He then secretly downloaded as much company data as possible as soon as he had gained access to internal systems.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Once the company fired him for poor performance, it reportedly received emails containing some of the stolen data and a demand to be paid a six-figure sum in cryptocurrency. If the company did not pay, the hacker said he would publish or sell the stolen information online.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The company did not wish to be named. It also did not disclose whether they paid the ransom or not. However, the firm allowed cyber responders from Secureworks to report the hack to spread awareness and warn others.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Secureworks reported that this incident is the latest in a string of cases of Western remote workers being unmasked as North Koreans. Once hired, these cyber criminals use their employee access to download sensitive company data. In some cases, they use the data to extort their former employers.</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/organ-donor-in-us-wakes-up-on-operating-table-as-doctors-prepare-to-remove-his-heart-6819128">Organ Donor In US Wakes Up On Operating Table As Doctors Prepare To Remove His Heart&nbsp;</a></strong></p>

<p>Cybersecurity authorities have been warning about the rise of North Korean infiltrators since 2022. The US and South Korea have also accused North Korea of tasking thousands of staff to take on multiple well-paid Western roles remotely to earn money for the regime and avoid sanctions. However, according to Rafe Pilling, Director of Threat Intelligence at Secureworks, secret IT workers turning on their employers with cyber attacks is rare.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"This is a serious escalation of the risk from fraudulent North Korean IT worker schemes," Mr Pilling was quoted as saying by the <em>BBC</em>. "No longer are they just after a steady pay check, they are looking for higher sums, more quickly, through data theft and extortion, from inside the company defences."</p>

<p>Authorities warned employers to be vigilant about new hired if they are fully remote.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-03/7u5267bg_hacker-generic_625x300_20_March_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[It is not clear whether the company paid the demanded ransom. (Representative pic)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kyiv-says-bodies-of-501-ukrainian-soldiers-killed-fighting-russia-returned-6819700]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kyiv Says Bodies Of 501 Ukrainian Soldiers Killed Fighting Russia Returned]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kyiv-says-bodies-of-501-ukrainian-soldiers-killed-fighting-russia-returned-6819700]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 18 Oct 2024 19:11:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kyiv said Friday it had received the bodies of 501 servicemen killed fighting Russian forces, mainly in eastern Ukraine.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kyiv said Friday it had received the bodies of 501 servicemen killed fighting Russian forces, mainly in eastern Ukraine.</p>

<p>The exchange of prisoners and bodies of killed military personnel remains one of the few areas of cooperation between Moscow and Kyiv since Russia invaded in 2022.</p>

<p>"As a result of repatriation measures, 501 bodies of fallen Ukrainian defenders were returned to Ukraine," the Coordination Headquarters for the Treatment of Prisoners of War said in a statement.</p>

<p>The announcement represents one of the largest repatriations of killed Ukrainian servicemen since the beginning of the war.</p>

<p>Most of the bodies were returned from the eastern Donetsk region, said the agency. Russian forces have been advancing steadily there since their capture of the industrial hub of Avdiivka in February.</p>

<p>Several state bodies had helped coordinate the return including the defence forces, the agency added, acknowledging the help of the International Committee of the Red Cross.</p>

<p>"Representatives of law enforcement agencies and forensic experts will identify the victims," the coordination centre said in its statement.</p>

<p>"After identification, the bodies of our defenders will be handed over to their families for a proper burial."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-06/0ghrt3i_russia-ukraine-war-afp_625x300_19_June_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Most of the bodies were returned from the eastern Donetsk region (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/senior-isis-leader-3-others-killed-in-iraqi-strike-us-military-6819588]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Senior ISIS Leader, 3 Others Killed In Iraqi Strike: US Military]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/senior-isis-leader-3-others-killed-in-iraqi-strike-us-military-6819588]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 18 Oct 2024 18:54:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iraqi air strikes killed a senior Islamic State group leader and three other terrorists, the US military announced Friday, saying the strikes were enabled by intelligence from the international anti-jihadist coalition.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Iraqi air strikes killed a senior Islamic State group leader and three other terrorists, the US military announced Friday, saying the strikes were enabled by intelligence from the international anti-jihadist coalition.</p>

<p>"Iraqi security forces (ISF) conducted precision airstrikes in northeastern Iraq on October 14 that killed four members of the terrorist organization ISIS, including a senior leader," the US Central Command (CENTCOM) said in a statement on social media, using an acronym for the Islamic State group.</p>

<p>"The Iraqi-led strikes were conducted to disrupt and degrade ISIS attack networks in Iraq and were enabled by technical support and intelligence from coalition forces," CENTCOM said.</p>

<p>It said the leader who got killed was the group's most senior official in northern Iraq, identifying him as Shahadhah Allawi Salih Ulaywi al-Bajjari and saying he was also known as Abu Issa.</p>

<p>Iraq's Joint Operations Command had previously said in a statement that F-16 warplanes carried out strikes on October 14 in Kirkuk province that killed four terrorists, "one of them an important leader."</p>

<p>The strikes came after US and Iraqi forces conducted a joint operation in late August that CENTCOM said killed 14 Islamic State group members, among them four leaders.</p>

<p>The United States has about 2,500 troops in Iraq and 900 in Syria as part of the coalition, which Washington and Baghdad announced last month will end its decade-long military mission in Iraq within a year.</p>

<p>The announcement followed months of talks between the United States and Iraq on the future of the coalition, which was established in 2014 to help local forces retake swathes of territory seized by the jihadists there and in neighboring Syria.</p>

<p>The coalition will continue its military operation in Syria, with international troops permitted to support anti-jihadist operations there from Iraq until September 2026.</p>

<p>IS was defeated in Iraq in 2017 and in Syria in 2019, but jihadist fighters continue to operate in remote desert areas although they no longer control territory.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2017-02/iraqi-forces-mosul-afp_650x400_61487582267.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[IS was defeated in Iraq in 2017 and in Syria in 2019 (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-confirms-yahya-sinwar-killed-by-israel-wont-free-hostages-until-6819238]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hamas Confirms Yahya Sinwar Killed By Israel, Won't Free Hostages Until...]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-confirms-yahya-sinwar-killed-by-israel-wont-free-hostages-until-6819238]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 18 Oct 2024 18:10:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hamas leader Yahya Sinwar, architect of the group's cross-border raids in 2023 that became the deadliest day in Israel's history, was killed in combat, Khalil Al-Hayya, deputy Gaza Hamas chief and the group's chief negotiator, said on Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hamas leader Yahya Sinwar, architect of the group's cross-border raids in 2023 that became the deadliest day in Israel's history, was killed in combat, Khalil Al-Hayya, deputy Gaza Hamas chief and the group's chief negotiator, said on Friday.</p>

<p>Sinwar's death, which follows Israeli assassinations of other Hamas leaders and commanders, will deal a huge blow to the Islamist group which has faced relentless air strikes since it attacked Israel on Oct. 7, 2023, killing 1,200 people, according to Israeli tallies.</p>

<p>It also dragged about 250 people back to Gaza, creating a hostage crisis for Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's government which has vowed to eliminate Hamas.</p>

<p>Sinwar will be remembered as a ruthless enforcer among Palestinians who collaborated with Israel and an implacable enemy of the country which jailed him for many years. Sinwar was named the group's paramount leader on August 6, as a successor to former political chief Ismail Haniyeh, who was assassinated in Tehran on July 31.</p>

<p>Widely known as the architect of the Oct. 7, 2023 attack, the most devastating event for Israel in decades, Sinwar has been in Gaza, defying Israeli attempts to kill him since the start of the war.</p>

<p>Born in a refugee camp in the southern Gaza city of Khan Younis, Sinwar, 62, was elected as Hamas' leader in Gaza in 2017. The controversial leader, who spent half his adult life in Israeli prisons, was the most powerful Hamas leader left alive following the assassination of Haniyeh.</p>

<p><strong>Won't Release Hostages: Hamas</strong></p>

<p>Hamas today said it won't release hostages until Israel ends its war on Gaza, withdraws from the territory and frees jailed Palestinians. The hostages "will not return... unless the aggression against our people in Gaza stops, there is a complete withdrawal from it, and our heroic prisoners are released from the occupation's prisons," Khalil al-Haya said in a video statement, news agency AFP reported.</p>

<p><strong>With inputs from Reuters and AFP</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/nqrfg8sg_yahya-sinwar_650x400_17_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hamas leader Yahya Sinwar was killed in combat]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/organ-donor-in-us-wakes-up-on-operating-table-as-doctors-prepare-to-remove-his-heart-6819128]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Man Wakes Up On Operating Table As Doctors Prepare To Remove His Heart]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/organ-donor-in-us-wakes-up-on-operating-table-as-doctors-prepare-to-remove-his-heart-6819128]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 18 Oct 2024 17:59:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A nightmarish incident unfolded at a US hospital when an organ donor woke up on the operating table just as doctors prepared to remove his heart.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A nightmarish incident unfolded at a US hospital when an organ donor woke up on the operating table just as doctors prepared to remove his heart. According to the <em>New York Post</em>, the incident took place in October 2021 when the organ donor, identified as Thomas T.J. Hoover, was taken to Baptist Health Richmond Hospital in Kentucky due to cardiac arrest following a drug overdose. Doctors declared him braindead and proceeded to conduct tests to see whether his organs were worth harvesting. However, when Mr Hoover was wheeled into the operating room, staff members noticed he was still showing signs of life.</p>

<p>"He was moving around - kind of thrashing. And then when we went over there, you could see he had tears coming down. He was crying visibly," Natasha Miller, a staffer involved in organ preservation, said, per the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/10/18/us-news/hospital-nearly-removes-living-mans-organs-for-donations-witnesses/" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>Post</em></a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The donor's condition shocked several people in the operating room and caused two doctors tasked with the procedures to refuse to participate. But what was more shocking was when the case coordinator for Kentucky Organ Donor Affiliates (KODA) requested new doctors to proceed with the organ retrieval, Ms Miller claimed.</p>

<p>"So the coordinator calls the supervisor at the time. And she was saying that he was telling her that she needed to 'find another doctor to do it' - that 'we were going to do this case. She needs to find someone else'," Ms Miller said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Another KODA worker said that while reviewing Mr Hoover's case she made a jarring discovery. Nyckoletta Martin claimed that she was shocked to find out that the donor had previously shown signs of life as doctors examined his heart to see if it was viable for transplantation. "The donor had woken up during his procedure that morning for a cardiac catheterization. And he was thrashing around on the table," Ms Martin said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to case file records, the doctors merely sedated the struggling Mr Hoover when he started thrashing around and then proceeded with their plans to harvest his organs.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/video-travel-influencer-questioning-absence-of-women-on-islamabad-streets-sparks-debate-6818228">Video: Travel Influencer Questioning Absence Of Women On Islamabad Streets Sparks Debate</a></strong></p>

<p>Separately, the donor's sister, Donna Rhorer, said her brother opened his eyes while being wheeled from an intensive care unit and into an operating room, but were told that the moment was reflexive and didn't mean he was alive. "It was like it was his way of letting us know, you know, 'Hey I'm still here'," she said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The procedure was ultimately cancelled. The <em>Post </em>reported that this incident has caused several members of the KODA team to resign their positions. However, KODA officials have denied that any member of the organisation instructed doctors to proceed with an organ-harvesting operation on a living patient.</p>

<p>Kentucky's state attorney general said investigators were reviewing the matter. The Fed's Health Resources and Services Administration is also investigating the allegations.</p>

<p>Mr Hoover is currently living with his sister. He has made a full recovery but he still has some issues with his memory, walking, and talking.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-02/e5i30qh8_doctor-generic_625x300_17_February_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The case is being investigated. (Representative pic)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/completely-devastated-one-direction-bandmates-on-liam-paynes-death-6818771]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Completely Devastated": One Direction Bandmates On Liam Payne's Death]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/completely-devastated-one-direction-bandmates-on-liam-paynes-death-6818771]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 18 Oct 2024 17:19:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Liam Payne's One Direction bandmates said they were completely devastated by his death, with singer-songwriter Harry Styles taking to social media to say he would forever cherish the years they spent together.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Liam Payne's One Direction bandmates said they were completely devastated by his death, with singer-songwriter Harry Styles taking to social media to say he would forever cherish the years they spent together.</p>

<p>Liam&nbsp;Payne, who shot to global fame with boy band One Direction, died at the age of 31 after falling from a third-floor hotel room balcony in Buenos Aires on Wednesday, triggering an outpouring of tributes from fans around the world.</p>

<p>A joint statement was signed by singers Harry Styles, Louis Tomlinson, Zayn Malik and Niall Horan.</p>

<p>"In time, and when everyone is able to, there will be more to say. But for now, we will take some time to grieve and process the loss of our brother, who we loved dearly," Liam&nbsp;Payne's former bandmates said.</p>

<p>They also said that their thoughts were with the English singer's family, friends and fans, concluding: "We will miss him terribly. We love you Liam."</p>

<p>In a separate statement posted on Instagram on Thursday, Harry Styles said Liam&nbsp;Payne's greatest joy was making people happy.</p>

<p>"The years we spent together will forever remain among the most cherished years of my life," Harry Styles said.</p>

<p>Zayn Malik also posted on Instagram about the late singer, along with a photo of them dozing off next to each other.</p>

<p>"I lost a brother when you left us and can't explain to you what I'd give just to give you a hug one last time," he wrote.</p>

<p>Along with a picture of Liam&nbsp;Payne embracing him at a gig, Louis Tomlinson wrote he was beyond lucky to have had Liam&nbsp;Payne in his life.</p>

<p>"I'm really struggling with the idea of saying goodbye," he said. "I would have loved to share the stage with you again but it wasn't to be."</p>

<p><strong>'JUST A KID'</strong></p>

<p>Other celebrities have paid tribute to Liam&nbsp;Payne, with former footballer David Beckham describing him as a generous person and musician Ed Sheeran saying he was at loss for words and urging everyone to be kind.</p>

<p>Prosecutors in Buenos Aires said on Thursday an initial search suggested Liam&nbsp;Payne's fall from the hotel balcony came after substance abuse.</p>

<p>Police earlier said they had found the room in "total disorder" in a search after his death, with various things smashed and medications scattered around.</p>

<p>Sharon Osbourne, former judge of TV talent show X Factor, where One Direction was formed, said on Instagram that the music industry had let Liam&nbsp;Payne down.</p>

<p>"Where was this industry when you needed them? You were just a kid when you entered one of the toughest industries in the world. Who was in your corner?" Osbourne questioned.</p>

<p>Auditions for "Britain's Got Talent" in Blackpool, England, were postponed on Thursday "due to the tragic passing of Liam Payne," Applause Store, the ticket provider for the show, said in an Instagram story.</p>

<p>Music mogul Simon Cowell, who signed One Direction to his label, is the creator of both X Factor and Britain's Got Talent.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/ur6qjlj8_one-direction_625x300_18_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Liam Payne died at the age of 31 (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-people-left-hanging-upside-down-after-carnival-ride-malfunctions-in-us-6818685]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[People Left Hanging Upside Down After Carnival Ride Malfunctions In US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-people-left-hanging-upside-down-after-carnival-ride-malfunctions-in-us-6818685]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 18 Oct 2024 17:05:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Visitors at an amusement park in the US were stuck upside down for about 15 minutes after their ride experienced a malfunction, according to the New York Post.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Visitors at an amusement park in the US were stuck upside down for about 15 minutes after their ride experienced a malfunction, according to the <em>New York Post.</em> The incident took place at the Arkansas State Fair on Saturday on the X-Drive, a 16-seater attraction that places riders on the other end of the spinning arm and features rotating seats that flip the riders freely. In a statement, North American Midway Entertainment Services VP Scooter Korek said that the "ride's computer received a fault" because of which it was stuck for about 10-12 minutes. Maintenance staff responded and eventually got the ride to spin, the outlet reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The ride's computer received a fault. What it does is when it finds something that it doesn't like, it shuts it down. So, the ride was in the air, not in its landing position, for about 10-12 minutes," Mr Korek, per the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/10/18/us-news/arkansas-mom-ally-metzger-left-panicked-as-her-kids-left-dangling-upside-on-state-fair-ride/" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>Post</em></a>. He also stated that he still trusts the ride's safety.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Let me break it down to you in a nutshell. Any of my family members can go on any of our rides any day. That's how good I feel about our programs, our safety programs, and the people who work for us to operate and take care of these rides," he said.</p>

<p>However, a mother, whose two children were stuck upside down on the ride, slammed the organisers. Sharing a video on Facebook, Ally Metzger claimed that her kids, 8 and 11, were raised several feet off the ground when the ride stopped working. "They're trying to get my kids down, they've been stuck upside down for 15 minutes at least," she wrote as workers attempted to manually spin the ride to help the stranded passengers.&nbsp;</p>

<p><iframe allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="true" frameborder="0" height="476" scrolling="no" src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/video.php?height=476&amp;href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2F61555637497452%2Fvideos%2F1334071007616573%2F&amp;show_text=false&amp;width=267&amp;t=0" style="border:none;overflow:hidden" width="267"></iframe></p>

<p>"There's a bunch of people trying to get the ride to spin, and they would get it almost halfway down. Then it would go right back up to the very top, with my kids still upside down. So, I'm panicking. My partner's panicking," Ms Metzger told a local media outlet.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Ms Metzger's 11-year-old separately said that she doesn't remember much of what happened. "She told me when she came home that she only remembered crying, and then, like, just got dizzy. Her legs were hurting. I guess because the circulation was out," the mother said.</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/video-travel-influencer-questioning-absence-of-women-on-islamabad-streets-sparks-debate-6818228">&nbsp;Video: Travel Influencer Questioning Absence Of Women On Islamabad Streets Sparks Debate</a></strong></p>

<p>Following the incident, Ms Metzger railed against the fair, demanding her money back and calling out one of the employees. "After what was spent to get in this place? RUN ME MY REFUND," she wrote on Facebook. "Oh and I filled out a cute complaint," she added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The complaint was aimed at one ride attendant who allegedly told the parents to "calm down its only been four and a half minutes and you're making it worse." "Shout out to the nice lady at the med tent who made sure my babies were ok and gave us our money back. I remember why I don't come here," she added.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/8qeb1qk_arkansas-state-fair-_625x300_18_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The incident took place at the Arkansas State Fair on Saturday.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/india-plans-to-limit-laptop-import-to-boost-domestic-manufacturing-report-6818653]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India Plans To Limit Laptop Import To Boost Domestic Manufacturing: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/india-plans-to-limit-laptop-import-to-boost-domestic-manufacturing-report-6818653]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 18 Oct 2024 17:01:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India is expected to limit imports of laptops, tablets and personal computers after January, two government sources with direct knowledge of the matter said, a move to push companies such as Apple to increase domestic manufacturing.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India is expected to limit imports of laptops, tablets and personal computers after January, two government sources with direct knowledge of the matter said, a move to push companies such as Apple to increase domestic manufacturing.</p>

<p>This plan, if implemented, could disrupt an industry worth $8 billion to $10 billion and reshape the dynamics of the IT hardware market in India, which is heavily reliant on imports.</p>

<p>A similar plan to restrict imports was withdrawn last year following backlash from companies and lobbying from the United States. India has since monitored imports under a system set to expire this year and has asked firms to seek fresh approvals for imports next year.</p>

<p>The government feels it has given the industry enough time to adapt, said the sources, who did not want to be identified as discussions are private.</p>

<p>One of the sources said New Delhi will begin consultations with all sides starting next week. It could delay implementing the import restrictions by a few months if needed, the source added.</p>

<p>India's Ministry of Electronics and Information Technology (MeitY) is working on a new import authorisation system, where companies will have to get prior approvals for their imports, one of the two sources said.</p>

<p>Under the current regime, laptop importers are free to bring in as many devices after an automated online registration.</p>

<p>The industry is dominated by the likes of HP, Dell, Apple, Lenovo and Samsung, with two-thirds of Indian demand being currently met through imports, a significant amount from China. India's IT hardware market, including laptops, is estimated at nearly $20 billion, of which $5 billion is domestic production, according to consultancy Mordor Intelligence.</p>

<p>The government is considering minimum quality standards under its 'compulsory registration order' for laptops, notebooks and tablets, as one of the ways to weed out low quality devices, the officials said.</p>

<p>"We are working on such restrictions as global treaties stop us from any tariff action on laptops and tablets. It leaves us with few policy options to limit imports," the second official said.</p>

<p>The federal electronics ministry did not respond to request for comment. The trade ministry said an appropriate decision on the import management system would be taken after consultation with the electronics ministry and other stakeholders.</p>

<p>Such a move will benefit contract manufacturers such as Dixon Technologies who have entered separate pacts with global firms like HP to make laptops and computers in India. Dixon aims to cater to 15% of India's total demand.</p>

<p><strong>LOCAL PRODUCTION</strong></p>

<p>Limits to India's imports should be calibrated based on India's domestic production capacity, an industry source who is part of the government's consultations said.</p>

<p>The nation's key production incentive scheme for IT hardware has drawn participation from global firms including Acer, Dell, HP and Lenovo. Most of the approved participants are ready to start manufacturing, India's electronic minister said last year.</p>

<p>India has federal subsidies worth nearly $2.01 billion to promote domestic production.</p>

<p>Data from research firm Counterpoint shows imports of laptops completely assembled abroad in the first five months of 2024 fell 4% from a year earlier, with firms such as Lenovo and Acer increasing local assembly for entry-level laptops.</p>

<p>India has been long emphasised the need for "trusted sources" for electronics and communication devices amid growing concerns over cyberattacks and data theft.</p>

<p>In 2022, Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi said India should cut reliance on foreign countries for communication technology such as servers.</p>

<p>India will implement mandatory testing of "essential security parameters" for all CCTV cameras from April 2025.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-08/uka9e3og_computer-generic-laptop-generic-unsplash_625x300_26_August_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The government is considering minimum quality standards to weed out low quality devices. (Representation)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/lebanon-issues-rare-rebuke-to-iran-over-interference-6818486]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Lebanon Issues Rare Rebuke To Iran Over "Interference"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/lebanon-issues-rare-rebuke-to-iran-over-interference-6818486]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 18 Oct 2024 16:44:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Lebanon's caretaker prime minister on Friday made a rare rebuke to Iran and said Tehran's envoy should be summoned over reported comments by a senior Iranian official that it would be ready to help "negotiate" to implement a UN resolution on Lebanon.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lebanon's caretaker prime minister on Friday made a rare rebuke to Iran and said Tehran's envoy should be summoned over reported comments by a senior Iranian official that it would be ready to help "negotiate" to implement a UN resolution on Lebanon.</p>

<p>Lebanese PM Najib Mikati said in a statement the comments amounted to "a blatant interference in Lebanese affairs".</p>

<p>Criticism of Iran by top Lebanese officials is unusual, particularly given Tehran's sponsorship of the powerful Lebanese armed group Hezbollah, which is currently locked in battles against Israeli troops along Lebanon's southern border.</p>

<p>In an interview published in France's Le Figaro on Thursday, Iranian parliament speaker Mohammad Baqer Ghalibaf was quoted as saying his country would be ready to "negotiate" with France to implement United Nations Resolution 1701.</p>

<p>That resolution, which ended the last round of conflict between Israel and Hezbollah in 2006, calls for southern Lebanon to be free of any troops or weapons other than those of the Lebanese state.</p>

<p>Mikati said on Friday that he was "surprised" by Ghalibaf's comments and said they were an attempt to "establish a rejected guardianship over Lebanon".</p>

<p>He said such a negotiation was the prerogative of the Lebanese state and asked Lebanese Foreign Minister Abdallah Bou Habib to summon Iran's Chargé d'Affaires in Beirut.</p>

<p>There was no immediate comment from Ghalibaf or from Iran's embassy in Beirut.</p>

<p>An unnamed Iranian source close to Ghalibaf denied the interpretation of the speaker's comments, telling pro-Iran broadcaster Al-Mayadeen that any collaboration with Europe would aim to reach a ceasefire that is backed by Lebanon's government and "resistance," in a reference to Hezbollah.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/pln7unf8_lebanon-caretaker-prime-minister_625x300_18_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Najib Mikati said that he was "surprised" by Iranian parliament speaker's comments. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/how-indian-americans-just-1-of-us-population-are-gaining-political-clout-6818240]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: How Indian Americans - Just 1% Of US Population - Are Gaining Political Clout]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/how-indian-americans-just-1-of-us-population-are-gaining-political-clout-6818240]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 18 Oct 2024 16:08:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Indian American community is critical for both parties because even though they make up only 1% of the US population, about a third of them reside in Presidential battleground states like Michigan and Georgia.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/ev2s0738_us-election_625x300_18_October_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>The roughly 2.1 million Indian American voters are just a small section of the 161 million-plus-strong US electorate. Even then, they have emerged as a notable force in the country's politics. With one of their own, Kamala Harris, on the Presidential ballot, the deeply aspirational community is charged up. Having established themselves as an educated and affluent group, they understand that having their voice heard in the corridors of power is crucial. And their importance is growing not just as voters but also as candidates, mobilisers and fundraisers.</p>

<h2><strong>Unprecedented Fundraising</strong></h2>

<p>Political fundraisers are 'witnessing a remarkable surge' in terms of participation from Indian Americans. Ajay Bhutoria, a member of the Democratic National Finance Committee and fundraiser for over two decades, says, "More than ever, people are stepping up, contributing larger sums, and actively engaging in the political process."&nbsp;</p>

<p>The $145,000 median income of Indian American households is 21% higher than the overall US median. Shekar Narasimhan, founder and chairman of the AAPI Victory Fund, the largest Super PAC (political action committee) in the Asian American diaspora, says that even though it is not easy to find accurate data on how much finance Indian Americans are pumping into campaigns, there are huge donors in the community. This is evident from the fact that the Democratic National Finance Committee is 5% Indian-American even as their share in the US population is only 1%. At the same time, small-dollar donors are important too, adds Narasimhan.</p>

<p>M.R. Rangaswami, Indiaspora's Founder &amp; Chairman, also notes the remarkable volume of funds being generated. "Now we have two healthy PACs with the AAPI Victory Fund and the Indian American Impact Fund, so more and more money is coming in," he says. The Indian American Impact, the largest desi PAC, is also identifying and training the next batch of leaders.</p>

<p>Dr Sangay Mishra, associate professor of Political Science at Drew University and author of <em>Desis Divided: The Political Lives of South Asian Americans</em>, found in his research that since 2012, Indian Americans have been "very visible" in "bundling" contributions for campaigns. "We have seen that kind of outsized influence because of the number of very wealthy fundraisers organised in the community networks," he says.</p>

<p>It's a popular saying that the road to the White House goes through Silicon Valley - the hub of affluent Indians in tech. Harris's recent California fundraisers generated $55 million over a weekend; she has raised a billion dollars since becoming the nominee. Powerful fundraisers, including the one hosted by the billionaire AI investor and technologist Vinod Khosla for the Democratic campaign this election cycle, made news waves. There are more than 60 Indian names on the list of VCs for Kamala. Other business leaders and founders endorsing her include corporate leaders like Indra Nooyi.</p>

<h2><strong>The Enduring Republican Vote</strong></h2>

<p>While Harris's candidacy has further loosened the purse strings of enthused Democrats, Donald Trump's Indian American supporters, including Vivek Ramaswamy, have stayed loyal to the Republican Party.</p>

<p>Sampat Shivangi, an old-time Republican faithful and the only Indian American delegate at the Republican National Convention this year, has been elected to the body for the sixth time. He is sending a big cheque for Trump's campaign. Then there is hotelier Danny Gaekwad, who has contributed to the campaigns of every Republican Presidential candidate since George Bush. "The October event involved an insane amount of money. People known to me are calling me - Bhau, I want to go, my wife wants to go," Gaekwad says about a sold-out fundraiser.</p>

<p>Republicans like Shivangi say they support Trump because "Harris is not a friend of India". Along with accusations of "diluting" her Indian American identity, they point out that she failed to visit India during her years as Vice-President.</p>

<p>Republicans, however, do acknowledge that the fervour among Indian American supporters of the party, especially Hindus, has waned since 2020, when President Trump and Prime Minister Narendra Modi's friendly ties created a huge buzz. "{Perhaps because] he is a third-time candidate," Gaekwad reasons.</p>

<p>Though wooed by both parties, by and large, Indian Americans have voted for Democrats. A 2024 AAPI Data survey found that 55% of Indian Americans identify as Democrats, 25% as Republicans and 15% as Independents.</p>

<h2><strong>Sway In Swing States</strong></h2>

<p>The Indian American community is critical for both parties because even though they make up only 1% of the US population, about a third of them reside in Presidential battleground states like Michigan and Georgia, where they can play a huge role in shaping the results. Recalling the narrow Democratic victory in Georgia in 2020, Mishra says, "In a state like that, it matters because the margin was so thin. Indian Americans voted one way and the election went that way, if they had voted the other way results might have been different." The last few Presidential elections have been close calls, decided by narrow gaps in a handful of states. Polls show that the current one seems evenly poised. There are nearly 4,00,000 voters of South Asian descent in the 10 most contested swing states. "There is a sizeable number of Indian Americans who can make a difference," says Dr Mishra.</p>

<p>Thus, volunteers of the highly politically engaged community utilise their resources strategically in pivotal states. Based in the Democratic stronghold California, Sangeeta Ramakrishnan is They See Blue's 'lead' for swing state calls. She says, "There are more of us in blue states and because you don't need to knock those many doors here, it's better to use our resources effectively."&nbsp;</p>

<p>Every election, Pennsylvania's Buck's County gains the reputation of being the "swingiest county in the swingiest state". Rupa Mohan, a volunteer at They See Blue, says, "We have phone banks run by Gujarati volunteers, Malayalam speakers, Urdu speakers. We have a whole pile of different volunteers lined up."</p>

<p>Overall as well, the political participation of the 4.8 million-strong young immigrant community is soaring. In the last two presidential elections, they had the highest voter turnout among Asian Americans, on par with white voter turnout. As many as 71% of eligible Indian Americans voted in 2020, a 9-point increase from 2016. This trend is expected to continue. A recent Asian American voter survey shows that around 91% of Indian Americans plan to vote in this election.</p>

<h2><strong>Office Dreams</strong></h2>

<p>It's not only electoral numbers that elevate the Indian Americans' political profile - they also nurture strong ambitions for office. From the highest level - the Presidential post - to Congress, state senates, assemblies, district attorneys, city councils, to school boards, their numbers are huge.&nbsp;</p>

<p>No one really has a count of how many Indian American candidates are in the 2024 race. But there are five Indian Americans in the current US Congress, and, after the coming election, says Narasimhan, the community will likely have seven. Getting to that number took decades since the first Indian American was voted to the Congress in 1956. But the rise in the last 20 years has been exponential, thanks to second-generation Indian Americans and their education levels, which are far higher than the US average.</p>

<p>As for their numbers in administration, while Indian Americans constitute just 0.6% of the adult citizen population in the US, they hold about 4.4% of senior positions in government. There are over 150 Indian Americans in the Biden-Harris administration, and that is projected to increase by over 50 if Harris becomes President.</p>

<h2><strong>The Pursuit Of Influence</strong></h2>

<p>Having conquered every metric on the ladder of ascent - votes, money and candidates - Indian American leaders are aspiring for political representation similar to what the much older Jewish American population enjoys. Jews constitute about 2% of the American population but make up 10% of the US Congress. "In force, we have been here for about 30 years," says Rangaswami. "We are 7% of US physicians, 10% of the American IT sector and are well-represented in academia and government, so why not have clout."&nbsp;</p>

<p>Already, with early voting having begun, supporters of both parties are canvassing aggressively through door-to-door promotions, postcards, phone calls, and texts. "It's going to heat up in the next few weeks!" says Shobha Chokkalingam, Atlanta-based leader of the Georgia chapter of the American Hindu Coalition. But it's 'desi' Democratic supporters for whom this election is particularly special. With Kamala Harris in the race, the Indian American community is eager to play a part in making history. Rangaswami sums it up well: "If Kamala Harris becomes president - I mean keep in mind there's been no Jewish president in the US - this could be a huge thing. So let's see!"</p>

<p><em>(Savita Patel is a San Francisco Bay Area-based journalist and producer. She reports on the Indian diaspora, India-US ties, geopolitics, technology, public health, and the environment. She tweets at @SsavitaPatel.)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/qemb10ng_us-election_625x300_18_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-silent-on-its-chief-yahya-sinwars-death-says-group-cant-be-eliminated-6818211]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hamas Silent On Its Chief's Death, Says "Group Can't Be Eliminated"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-silent-on-its-chief-yahya-sinwars-death-says-group-cant-be-eliminated-6818211]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 18 Oct 2024 16:02:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A senior Hamas official said the Palestinian militant group cannot be eliminated with the killing of its leaders, but stopped short of confirming the death of its chief, Yahya Sinwar.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A senior Hamas official said the Palestinian group cannot be eliminated with the killing of its leaders, but stopped short of confirming the death of its chief, Yahya Sinwar.</p>

<p>"Hamas is a liberation movement led by people looking for freedom and dignity, and this cannot be eliminated," Basem Naim, senior member of Hamas's political bureau, told AFP.</p>

<p>In a statement, he listed several Hamas leaders killed in the past, and said their deaths had boosted the group's popularity.</p>

<p>"It seems that Israel believes that killing our leaders means the end of our movement and the struggle of the Palestinian people," Naim said.</p>

<p>"Hamas each time became stronger and more popular, and these leaders became an icon for future generations to continue the journey towards a free Palestine."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/dnlapn8o_yahya-sinwar_625x300_07_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["Hamas is a liberation movement led by people looking for freedom," said the official (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/alarming-rise-in-ai-produced-child-abuse-material-warns-regulatory-body-6817927]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Alarming Rise In AI-Produced Child Abuse Material, Warns Regulatory Body]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/alarming-rise-in-ai-produced-child-abuse-material-warns-regulatory-body-6817927]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 18 Oct 2024 15:22:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[AI is being used to create highly realistic child sexual abuse content that is increasingly accessible online.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The negative impacts of artificial intelligence, which have already led to the proliferation of fake and deepfake videos of celebrities online, are now extending to children. AI-generated child sexual abuse content is increasingly being found on publicly accessible areas of the internet.</p>

<p>According to a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.iwf.org.uk/news-media/news/public-exposure-to-chilling-ai-child-sexual-abuse-images-and-videos-increases/">report by the Internet Watch Foundation</a> (IWF), AI-generated child sexual abuse content is exposing even more people to the harmful and horrific imagery.</p>

<p>Many of the images and videos of children being hurt and abused are so realistic that they can be very difficult to tell apart from imagery of real children and are regarded as criminal content in the eyes of UK law, much in the same way as 'traditional' child sexual abuse material would be, as per the IWF.</p>

<p>In the past six months alone, analysts at the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.iwf.org.uk/news-media/news/public-exposure-to-chilling-ai-child-sexual-abuse-images-and-videos-increases/">IWF </a>have seen a 6% increase in confirmed reports containing AI-generated child sexual abuse material, compared with the preceding 12 months.</p>

<p>The IWF is warning that almost all the content (99%) was found on publicly available areas of the internet and was not hidden on the dark web. Most of the reports have come from members of the public (78%) who have stumbled across the criminal imagery on sites such as forums or AI galleries. The remainder were actioned by IWF analysts through proactive searching.</p>

<p>Analysts say that viewing AI-generated content of children being sexually abused can be as distressing as seeing real children in abuse imagery if a person is not prepared or trained to cope with seeing such material.</p>

<p>Some AI child sexual abuse material is classified as non-photographic imagery, such as cartoons, and is also regarded as harmful to view and accordingly assessed by IWF analysts.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/q5am60i_aiproduced-child-abuse-material_625x300_18_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[This poses a significant threat to children's safety and well-being.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>