<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 19:49:01 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-ukraine-war-sandbags-bomb-shelters-on-crimea-beaches-after-deadly-missile-strike-6069020]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Sandbags, Bomb Shelters On Crimea Beaches After Deadly Missile Strike]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-ukraine-war-sandbags-bomb-shelters-on-crimea-beaches-after-deadly-missile-strike-6069020]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 19:42:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Tourists thronging the Black Sea beaches of the Russian-annexed Crimean peninsula this summer share the space with a grim new arrival: bomb shelters and sandbags.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Tourists thronging the Black Sea beaches of the Russian-annexed Crimean peninsula this summer share the space with a grim new arrival: bomb shelters and sandbags.</p>

<p>For more than two years, the beaches of the peninsula, which Moscow annexed in 2014, have been only one step removed from the raging battles of the war in Ukraine.</p>

<p>Last month, fragments from Ukrainian missiles killed four people, including two children, on a beach in the city of Sevastopol, injuring 151 more. Footage on Russian state television showed some victims being carried off on sun loungers.</p>

<p>Thousands of Ukrainian civilians have been killed since the start of the more than two-year-old war, and a much smaller number of civilians inside Russia or in parts of Ukraine, such as Crimea, that Russia claims to have annexed.</p>

<p>At the beach in Uchuyevka, on the outskirts of Sevastopol, bathers now share a pebbled shoreline with a concrete bomb shelter, reinforced with sandbags - a reminder of the unwelcome ways in which the war that Moscow calls a "special military operation" has encroached on the lives of ordinary people.</p>

<p>Irina, a tourist from the close Russian ally of Belarus, said: "In my opinion (the bomb shelters) are necessary."</p>

<p>"We are visiting friends here and we were told that it is very scary here, but here there are shelters and all safety measures are observed, I think it is very important."</p>

<p>Sevastopol's Russian-installed governor Mikhail Razvozhaev said last Friday that additional defence measures were necessary and accused Ukrainian authorities of being unhinged.</p>

<p>Ukraine has carried out multiple air and naval strikes on Russian military targets in Crimea. But legions of Russian tourists continue to visit each year for their annual holiday.</p>

<p>A Russian tourist, Alexander Zhukovskiy, said: "Probably, it will be calmer to be on the beach, to rest when you are sure that at any moment you can get under protection. So yes, they are needed."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/v6nfivqg_crimea_625x300_09_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Ukraine has carried out air and naval strikes on Russian military targets in Crimea (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/disgrace-greeces-main-opposition-party-slams-6-day-working-week-6068783]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Disgrace": Greece's Main Opposition Party Slams 6-Day Working Week]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/disgrace-greeces-main-opposition-party-slams-6-day-working-week-6068783]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 19:08:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Greece's main opposition party Syriza said Tuesday that the recent introduction of a six-day working week for certain companies was a "disgrace".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Greece's main opposition party Syriza said Tuesday that the recent introduction of a six-day working week for certain companies was a "disgrace".&nbsp;</p>

<p>The measure was brought into force by the right-wing ruling New Democracy party in early July. &nbsp;</p>

<p>Greece has been facing a shortage of skilled workers since the financial crisis of the late 2000s, which drove young people abroad in search of better prospects.&nbsp;</p>

<p>But the policy has attracted domestic and international attention as it goes against the grain of many Western countries, where the four-day week is being debated to boost productivity.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Such things are unacceptable. The government must understand that this policy has consequences," said Syriza spokesperson Voula Kehagia on private television channel Skai.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Kehagia added that it "shamed the country" by "ridiculing it abroad".&nbsp;</p>

<p>The six-day working week only applies to certain companies, including those that operate seven days a week, 24 hours a day.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Workers will be paid at least 40 percent more for the sixth day of work.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Government spokesman Pavlos Marinakis emphasised on Facebook that it is intended to address "emergency needs" with "qualified personnel".&nbsp;</p>

<p>Athens said the move combats undeclared work and addresses work shortages exacerbated by a declining population.&nbsp;</p>

<p>While the Greek average working week was the longest in the European Union at 39.8 hours last year, their productivity was lower than the average, according to Eurostat.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-03/9qq70s9c_tech-office-generic_625x300_30_March_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The six-day working week only applies to certain companies (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/plane-mechanic-in-iran-dies-after-getting-sucked-into-boeing-jets-engine-6068640]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Plane Mechanic In Iran Dies After Getting Sucked Into Boeing Jet's Engine]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/plane-mechanic-in-iran-dies-after-getting-sucked-into-boeing-jets-engine-6068640]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 18:48:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The incident happened when local technician Abolfazl Amiri was pulled into the engine of a Boeing passenger jet while performing routine maintenance work.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a tragic incident, an aviation mechanic&nbsp;died after getting sucked into a Boeing passenger jet's engine. The incident happened on July 3 at&nbsp;Chabahar Konarak airport in southern Iran when&nbsp;local technician Abolfazl Amiri was pulled into the engine of a Boeing passenger jet while performing routine maintenance work.</p>

<p>According to<a href="https://www.bild.de/news/ausland/nach-der-landung-mechaniker-von-triebwerk-angesaugt-tot-668cce13bdb18e1605d7d2cb" rel="nofollow noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">&nbsp;<em>Bild</em>,</a>&nbsp;the Boeing arrived in Tehran early at 7:15 am and landed safely in Chabahar Konarak airport. As per standard practice, the engine on the right-hand side was turned on for a test check with the cover flaps open. A safety area had also been set up around the engine as required.&nbsp;</p>

<p>However, when Mr Amiri realised he had forgotten a tool on the engine, he went back towards the plane to retrieve it.&nbsp;As he went close to the turbine, he was sucked in and killed before the engine caught fire.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Although the airport fire brigade arrived quickly and extinguished the fire with water, rescuers were only able to recover the remains of the mechanic. The plane operated by domestic carrier Varesh Airlines was grounded for repairs, and an investigation into the accident was ordered by Iran's aviation authority.</p>

<p>In May, a similar incident happened when a man lost his life after being pulled into the engine of a KLM passenger plane at<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c0dd9pxnd0lo"> Amsterdam's Schiphol Airport</a>.&nbsp;Passengers and crew members reportedly witnessed the tragic death before emergency services rushed to the scene. Speaking to the Dutch newspaper De Telegraaf, witnesses said there was a "hellish noise" as the person was sucked into the jet turbine.&nbsp;It is understood the man died after deliberately climbing into the engine.</p>

<p>Last year, a 27-year-old airport employee died after being sucked into a Delta passenger plane engine in San Antonio, Texas.</p>

<p></p>

<p></p>

<p style="padding-bottom:32px; text-align:start"></p>

<p></p>

<div class="float-container" style="text-align:start"></div>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/mikekg18_boeing-passenger-jet_625x300_09_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The fatal incident occurred in Chabahar Konarak airport in southern Iran]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/artificial-intelligence/ai-startups-ai-funding-ai-startup-funding-more-than-doubles-in-q2-crunchbase-data-shows-6068570]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[AI Startup Funding More Than Doubles in Q2, Crunchbase Data Shows]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/artificial-intelligence/ai-startups-ai-funding-ai-startup-funding-more-than-doubles-in-q2-crunchbase-data-shows-6068570]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 18:38:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Overall startup funding grew 16% sequentially to touch $79 billion in the last quarter, primarily driven by investments in AI, which became the largest sector for the first time, followed by healthcare and biotech.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Investments in artificial intelligence (AI) startups surged to $24 billion from April to June, more than doubling from the previous quarter, according to data from Crunchbase, highlighting the growing appetite for the new technology.<br />
Overall startup funding grew 16% sequentially to touch $79 billion in the last quarter, primarily driven by investments in AI, which became the largest sector for the first time, followed by healthcare and biotech.</p>

<h2>Why Is It Important?</h2>

<p>The runway success of OpenAI's ChatGPT has unleashed a race to adopt the latest AI technology in areas such as business productivity, healthcare, and manufacturing. Investors and Big Tech firms, however, say that meaningful gains from their massive investments in AI will only materialize over the next few years.</p>

<h2>In Numbers</h2>

<p>Five out of six billion-dollar funding rounds went to AI companies.</p>

<p>Top deals included Elon Musk's xAI raising $6 billion and AI infrastructure provider CoreWeave's raising $1.1 billion in its latest funding round. Also on the list, automated driving company Wayve and data preparation company Scale AI.</p>

<p>Outside of AI, cybersecurity company Wiz raised a billion-dollar in its latest funding round.</p>

<h2>Broader Landscape</h2>

<p>Despite last quarter's uptick, startup funding remains low compared to the levels seen in the past three years.</p>

<p>Global funding declined 5% to $147 billion in the first half of the year and was flat compared to the second half of 2023, according to Crunchbase.</p>

<p>A tight monetary policy in the U.S. has contributed to a slow revival in initial public offerings, hampering what is among the biggest sources of returns for institutional private market investors, who typically invest in startups and sell shares during IPOs.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/49issau8_startup-funding_625x300_09_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Startup funding courtesy of AI becomes the largest sector for investment (Representational Image)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/i-am-back-slovak-pm-robert-fico-returns-to-work-2-months-after-shooting-incident-6068419]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["I Am Back": Slovak PM Returns To Work 2 Months After Shooting Incident]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/i-am-back-slovak-pm-robert-fico-returns-to-work-2-months-after-shooting-incident-6068419]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 18:16:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Slovakia's Prime Minister Robert Fico said he had returned to work on Tuesday, almost two months after a lone gunman had shot him four times on May 15.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Slovakia's Prime Minister Robert Fico said he had returned to work on Tuesday, almost two months after a lone gunman had shot him four times on May 15.</p>

<p>The 59-year-old Fico was shot from close range after a government meeting in central Slovakia and underwent two lengthy surgeries in a nearby hospital.</p>

<p>The gunman, identified by Slovak media as 71-year-old poet Juraj Cintula and prosecuted on terrorism charges, is in custody awaiting trial.</p>

<p>Fico leads a three-party coalition of his centrist Smer-SD party, the centrist Hlas and the far-right SNS governing the EU and NATO member of 5.4 million people.</p>

<p>Slovak media said the nationalist-leaning Fico, who is often criticised by the EU along with Hungarian counterpart Viktor Orban, came to Tuesday's cabinet meeting through a tunnel to avoid journalists.</p>

<p>"Dear progressive liberal media and opposition, I apologise for having survived but I'm back," Fico said on Facebook, posting a picture of himself in his office.</p>

<p><iframe allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="true" frameborder="0" height="250" scrolling="no" src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/post.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2Frobertficosk%2Fposts%2Fpfbid0XrgowSd3BpZ58djzYzQotCGNEERJ7fNx91sMAV7Smph8gFAm3TdzXiFfFThgztVcl&amp;show_text=true&amp;width=500" style="border:none;overflow:hidden" width="500"></iframe></p>

<p>When Fico took office last autumn, Slovakia refused to continue military aid to Ukraine, facing a Russian invasion since February 2022.</p>

<p>The premier himself has been advocating peace talks with Russia, like Hungary's Orban.</p>

<p>Fico's cabinet has also raised eyebrows by approving bills seen as jeopardising judicial and media freedoms.</p>

<p>Fico was released from hospital on May 31 and made his first public appearance at a ceremony near Bratislava last Friday.</p>

<p>In a speech, he hailed Orban's controversial trip to Moscow, saying he "would have loved to join him" if he were healthy enough.</p>

<p>Fico also called on Slovakia to build a wall to stop "progressive and liberal ideologies", likening them to cancer.</p>

<p>Following the assassination attempt, Fico walks with a crutch. He has also visibly lost weight.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/pp61jnj8_robert-fico_625x300_09_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Robert Fico was released from hospital on May 31]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/artificial-intelligence/ai-breast-cancer-cancer-diagnosis-new-research-shows-ai-can-help-fight-breast-cancer-6068156]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[New Research Shows AI Can Help Fight Breast Cancer]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/artificial-intelligence/ai-breast-cancer-cancer-diagnosis-new-research-shows-ai-can-help-fight-breast-cancer-6068156]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 17:48:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The research shows Artificial Intelligence (AI) can help fight breast cancer. Early and accurate diagnosis can be pivotal for treatment amongst patients, and a newly developed AI system promises to do so with near perfect diagnosis.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Breast Cancer accounts for 13.6 percent of all cancer cases (male and female) in India, according to the 2022 World Cancer Report published by IARC (International Agency for Research on Cancer). Amongst women, it goes up to 26 percent of all cancer cases. In the United States, breast cancer accounts for about 30% of all new cancer cases amongst women.</p>

<p>New Research shows Artificial Intelligence (AI) can help fight this menacing disease. Early and accurate diagnosis can be pivotal for treatment amongst patients, and a newly developed AI system promises to do so with near perfect diagnosis.</p>

<p>A research paper titled " Ensemble Deep Learning-Based Image Classification for Breast Cancer Subtype and Invasiveness Diagnosis from Whole Slide Image Histopathology" published in the Cancers Journal last month, details out an AI Model that classifies and identifies different types of breast cancer present in a patient, in addition to ruling out malignancy (cancer) in the first place by identifying benign tumors.</p>

<p>The study - done by researchers of Northeastern University, Boston along with Maine Health Institute for Research - has developed an AI model that analyses high resolution histopathological (tissue-level microscopic) whole slide images of breast tumor tissue.</p>

<p>The AI system, which outperforms earlier machine learning (ML) models in the domain by combining the predictions of other ML models, is capable of identifying and classifying the tumor into malignant (cancerous) or benign (non-cancerous) using historical data fed to the model during training.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/aiek6dd8_ai-ml-ensemble_625x300_09_July_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>It was trained on publicly available datasets called BreakHis (Breast Cancer Histopathological Database) and BACH (Breast Cancer Histopathology images). For BACH, microscopic breast tissue images were meticulously labelled by medical experts, categorising the images into four classes - Normal, Benign, In Situ Carcinoma and Invasive Carcinoma.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Exemplary microscopy images demonstrating the four classes in the BACH dataset (Image Source: Cancers 2024, 16(12), 2222)  " id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/04jfmlh_tumor_625x300_09_July_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Exemplary microscopy images demonstrating the four classes in the BACH dataset (Image Source: Cancers 2024, 16(12), 2222)  " /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">Exemplary microscopy images demonstrating the four classes in the BACH dataset (Image Source: Cancers 2024, 16(12), 2222)</p>
</div>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"></div>
</div>

<p>And for BreakHis, which consists of 9,109 microscopic images of breast tumor tissue, it was used to categorise benign and malignant tumors further into 4 subclasses each- malignant tumors into Ductal carcinoma, Lobular carcinoma, Mucinous carcinoma and Papillary carcinoma, and benign tumors into Adenosi, Fibroadenoma, Phyllodes tumor, and Tubular adenoma.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Representative microscopy images of malignant and benign breast tissues from the BreakHis dataset (Image Source: Cancers 2024, 16(12), 2222)" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ohdtkch_tumor_625x300_09_July_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Representative microscopy images of malignant and benign breast tissues from the BreakHis dataset (Image Source: Cancers 2024, 16(12), 2222)" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">Representative microscopy images of malignant and benign breast tissues from the BreakHis dataset (Image Source: Cancers 2024, 16(12), 2222)</p>
</div>

<p>Put together, the ensemble ML model has an accuracy of 99.84 percent. Such a performance metric during the research and development stage shows optimistic promise for the real-world application of the technology.</p>

<p>"The AI can't miss a tumor in the biopsy and won't be exhausted after diagnosing 10 or 20 people," said Saeed Amal to Northeastern Global News. Amal is a professor of bioengineering at Northeastern university and is leading the ensemble model project.</p>

<p>Apart from diagnosis, AI systems have also made progress in prognosis and predictions related to breast cancers. For example, AI can now predict the neoadjuvant chemotherapy (NAC) response of breast cancer using Hematoxylin and eosin (common stains in tissue imaging) images of pre-chemotherapy needle biopsies. The AI systems responsible for the same have an accuracy of 95.15 percent and have been detailed out in a paper titled "Development of multiple AI pipelines that predict neoadjuvant chemotherapy response of breast cancer using H&amp;E-stained tissues," published in May 2023 in the Journal of Pathology.</p>

<p>Apart from this, AI has also made significant progress in identifying lymph node metastasis (spreading of cancer cells through lymphatic nodes) and evaluation of hormonal status which is important for breast cancer treatment. These and many more advances made by AI interventions over the years in the fight against breast cancer have been stated in a review paper published in Diagnostic Pathology in February.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/qnf4lmpo_health-diagnosis_625x300_09_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The AI model uses histopathological images for accurate diagnosis (Representational Image)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israels-targeted-starvation-campaign-causing-gaza-children-deaths-un-experts-6068143]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel's "Targeted Starvation Campaign" Causing Gaza Children Deaths: UN]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israels-targeted-starvation-campaign-causing-gaza-children-deaths-un-experts-6068143]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 17:45:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[UN rights experts on Tuesday accused Israel of carrying out a "targeted starvation campaign" that has resulted in the deaths of children in Gaza.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>UN rights experts on Tuesday accused Israel of carrying out a "targeted starvation campaign" that has resulted in the deaths of children in Gaza.</p>

<p>"We declare that Israel's intentional and targeted starvation campaign against the Palestinian people is a form of genocidal violence and has resulted in famine across all of Gaza," 10 independent United Nations experts said in a statement.</p>

<p>The UN has not officially declared a famine in the Gaza Strip.</p>

<p>But the experts, including the UN special rapporteur on the right to food Michael Fakhri, insisted there was no denying famine was under way.</p>

<p>"Thirty-four Palestinians have died from malnutrition since 7 October, the majority being children," said the experts, who are appointed by the UN Human Rights Council, but who do not speak on behalf of the United Nations.</p>

<p>Their statement was immediately slammed by Israel's mission to the UN in Geneva, which charged that "Mr. Fakhri, and many so-called 'experts' who joined his statement, are as much accustomed to spreading misinformation, as they are to supporting Hamas propaganda and shielding the terrorist organisation from scrutiny".</p>

<p>The UN experts meanwhile listed three children who had recently died "from malnutrition", after a number of others were said to have starved to death in northern Gaza earlier this year.</p>

<p>"Fayez Ataya, who was barely six months old, died on 30 May 2024, and 13-year-old Abdulqader Al-Serhi died on June 1, 2024 at the Al-Aqsa Hospital in Deir Al-Balah," they said.</p>

<p>Nine-year-old Ahmad Abu Reida died just two days later "in the tent sheltering his displaced family in Al-Mawasi, Khan Younis", they said.</p>

<p>"With the death of these children from starvation despite medical treatment in central Gaza, there is no doubt that famine has spread from northern Gaza into central and southern Gaza," they said.</p>

<p>The experts decried that the world had not done more to avert this disaster.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"When a two-month-old baby and 10-year-old Yazan Al Kafarneh died of hunger on 24 February and 4 March respectively, this confirmed that famine had struck northern Gaza," they said.</p>

<p>"The whole world should have intervened earlier to stop Israel's genocidal starvation campaign and prevented these deaths."</p>

<p>"Inaction is complicity."</p>

<p>Gaza has been facing a deep humanitarian crisis since the war erupted following Hamas's October 7 attack on southern Israel that resulted in the deaths of 1,195 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli figures.</p>

<p>In response, Israel has carried out a military offensive that has killed at least 38,243 people in Gaza, also mostly civilians, according to the health ministry in the Hamas-ruled territory.</p>

<p>The UN has been warning for months of a looming famine in Gaza, especially in the north, but one has not been officially declared.</p>

<p>The Israeli mission highlighted Tuesday that the latest assessment by the Integrated Food Security Phase Classification (IPC) partnership determined that famine had not materialised after aid access improved somewhat.</p>

<p>"Israel has continuously scaled up its coordination and assistance in the delivery of humanitarian aid across the Gaza Strip," it said, claiming Hamas "intentionally steal and hide aid from civilians".&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/4odvh4lg_gaza-children_625x300_09_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The UN has not officially declared a famine in the Gaza Strip.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-resolves-rwanda-asylum-cases-after-new-labour-government-drops-policy-6067994]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK Resolves Rwanda Asylum Cases After New Labour Government Drops Policy]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-resolves-rwanda-asylum-cases-after-new-labour-government-drops-policy-6067994]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 17:28:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Three asylum seekers who brought court action to block the UK's attempt to send them to Rwanda had their cases resolved on Tuesday, after the incoming Labour government ditched the policy.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Three asylum seekers who brought court action to block the UK's attempt to send them to Rwanda had their cases resolved on Tuesday, after the incoming Labour government ditched the policy.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Keir Starmer announced on Saturday that the migrant deportation plan forged by the ousted Conservative government was "dead and buried".</p>

<p>There had already been a spate of legal challenges to the scheme, with the UK Supreme Court in November last year ruling that it was illegal under international law as Rwanda could not be considered a safe country for asylum seekers.</p>

<p>Government lawyer James Eadie told the High Court in London on Tuesday: "In relation to the three named claimants, these claimants' cases will be fully disposed of and withdrawn subject to the (interior ministry) paying their costs."</p>

<p>The Labour Party said before last Thursday's general election that it would ditch the scheme, which the Tories said would deter huge numbers of migrants trying to get across the Channel to the UK on small boats from northern France.</p>

<p>Sixty-five people were brought ashore Monday -- the first under the new government -- taking the total number of arrivals so far this year to 13,639, according to an AFP tally of official figures.</p>

<p>Rwanda, home to 13 million people in Africa's Great Lakes region, claims to be one of the most stable countries on the continent and has drawn praise for its modern infrastructure.</p>

<p>But rights groups accuse veteran President Paul Kagame of ruling in a climate of fear, stifling dissent and free speech.</p>

<p>A spokesman for his government said Monday that "Rwanda takes note of the intention of the UK government to terminate the Migration and Economic Development Partnership Agreement".</p>

<p>As part of the deal, the UK has already paid some £240 million ($307 million) to Rwanda, with a further £50 million scheduled to be sent at a later date.</p>

<p>In January, Kagame said the money was "only going to be used if those people will come. If they don't come, we can return the money".</p>

<p>However, he later specified there was "no obligation" to do so.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/q3o3d22o_uk-rwanda_625x300_03_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/as-iran-gets-new-president-masoud-pezeshkian-will-it-change-its-stance-on-nuclear-standoff-6067652]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[As Iran Gets New President, Will It Change Its Stance On Nuclear Standoff?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/as-iran-gets-new-president-masoud-pezeshkian-will-it-change-its-stance-on-nuclear-standoff-6067652]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 16:45:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The election of relative moderate Masoud Pezeshkian as Iran's president has lifted the hopes of Iranians yearning for social freedoms and better relations with the West, but few expect big policy changes.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The election of relative moderate Masoud Pezeshkian as Iran's president has lifted the hopes of Iranians yearning for social freedoms and better relations with the West, but few expect big policy changes.</p>

<p>Iran's ruling clerics' political fortunes' rely on tackling economic hardship, so Pezeshkian may have a comparatively strong hand to revive the economy, but his scope to permit social freedoms will be limited, insiders and analysts said.</p>

<p>Under Iran's dual system of clerical and republican rule, the president cannot usher in any major policy shift on Iran's nuclear programme or foreign policy, since Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei calls all the shots on top state matters.</p>

<p>However, the president can influence the tone of policy and he will be closely involved in selecting the successor to Khamenei, now 85.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Hardliners, entrenched in institutions Khamenei controls such as the judiciary, armed forces and the media, have in the past blocked either the new opening to the West or domestic liberalisation.</p>

<p>Khamenei has set out guidelines he would like to see in the new government by counselling Pezeshkian to continue the policies of hardline President Ebrahim Raisi, who was killed in a helicopter crash in May.</p>

<p>"Pezeshkian self-identifies as a 'principlist' - someone committed to the ideological principles of the revolution - and has been clear about his devotion to the Revolutionary Guards and Khamenei," said Karim Sadjadpour, an associate at the Carnegie Endowment in Washington.</p>

<h3><strong>Will Iran Change Its Stance On The Nuclear Standoff?</strong></h3>

<p>Pezeshkian, a 69-year-old former heart surgeon, won Iran's run-off presidential vote last week and is yet to be sworn in.</p>

<p>He has pledged to promote a pragmatic foreign policy and ease tensions with the six major powers that have been involved in now-stalled nuclear talks to revive a 2015 nuclear pact.</p>

<p>Undoubtedly, analysts said, Pezeshkian's victory was a setback for hawks such as his rival, hardliner Saeed Jalili, who opposed any opening to the West and revival of the nuclear pact.</p>

<p>Jalili's supporters have criticised a hardline watchdog body for allowing Pezeshkian to run, with insiders suggesting that this decision was made by Khamenei to secure a high turnout amid consistently low participation in elections since 2020.</p>

<p>Pezeshkian hopes that revived talks with the West would lead to a lifting of tough U.S. sanctions, given growing popular discontent over economic hardships.</p>

<p>However, White House spokesperson John Kirby said on Monday the United States was not ready to resume nuclear talks with Iran under the new president.</p>

<p>For Pezeshkian the stakes are high. The president could become politically vulnerable if he fails to revive the pact, which then-U.S. President Donald Trump ditched in 2018 and reimposed harsh sanctions on Iran.</p>

<p>"He has a difficult path ahead ... Pezeshkian's inability to revive the pact will weaken the president and also lead to a backlash against the pro-reform camp who backed him," said a senior reformist former official.</p>

<p>A restoration of ties with the United States, which Iran's rulers have called the "Great Satan" since taking power in a 1979 revolution, remains out of the question.</p>

<h3><strong>Will The Economy See A Boom?</strong></h3>

<p>As the economy remains the Achilles heel for Khamenei, breaking free of the crippling U.S. sanctions, which have cost Iran billions of dollars in income from oil, will remain the top economic goal for Pezeshkian.</p>

<p>Spiralling prices and constricted spending power have left millions of Iranians struggling against a combination of sanctions and mismanagement.</p>

<p>Khamenei knows the economic struggle is a persistent challenge for the ruling clerics, who fear a revival of protests that have erupted since 2017 among lower- and middle-income people angry at enduring hardship.</p>

<p>"Failure to improve the economy will lead to street protests, particularly now that people have high hopes because of Pezeshkian's campaign promises," said an insider who is close to Khamenei.</p>

<p>Iran's economic outlook looks ever more uncertain, analysts say, with the possible return of Trump as U.S. president considered likely to lead to tougher enforcement of oil sanctions.</p>

<h3><strong>Will Strict Social Restrictions Change?</strong></h3>

<p>Pezeshkian enjoys an insider status and close relationship with the theocratic Khamenei, and may be able to build bridges between factions to yield moderation, but this would not enable him to bring about the fundamental changes that many pro-reform Iranians demand.</p>

<p>Pezeshkian, analysts said, is highly likely to end up in a similar position to his predecessors - reformist President Mohammad Khatami and pragmatist Hassan Rouhani - who whetted Iranians' appetite for change but ultimately were blocked by hardliners in the dominant elite of clerics and the powerful Revolutionary Guards.</p>

<p>"Pezeshkian is neither a reformist nor a moderate ... As a foot soldier of Khamanei, Pezeshkian will be subjected to his wishes which clearly has been to rule by violence and repression," said Hadi Ghaemi, executive director of New York-based advocacy group the Centre for Human Rights in Iran (CHRI).</p>

<p>As a lawmaker in 2022, Pezeshkian criticised the establishment over the death in custody of young Iranian woman Mahsa Amini, which triggered months of unrest in Iran.</p>

<h3><strong>Will Iran Change Its Regional Policy?</strong></h3>

<p>Unlikely. The top authority in regional policy is not the president, but the Guards, who answer only to Khamenei.</p>

<p>Pezeshkian is taking office at a time of escalating Middle East tensions over the Israel-Hamas war in Gaza and Hezbollah in Lebanon.</p>

<p>Signalling no change in Iran's regional policies, Pezeshkian reaffirmed on Monday Iran's anti-Israel stance and its support for resistance movements across the region</p>

<p>"Supporting the resistance of the people in the region against the illegitimate Zionist regime (Israel) is rooted in the fundamental policies of the Islamic Republic," Pezeshkian said in a message to the Hezbollah leader Hassan Nasrallah.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/aslhaiv8_masoud-pezeshkian_625x300_09_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Masoud Pezeshkian, 69-year-old, is former heart surgeon]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/brain-eating-amoeba-kills-israeli-man-25-after-he-went-swimming-on-beach-6067544]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Brain-Eating Amoeba Kills Israeli Man, 25, After He Went Swimming On Beach]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/brain-eating-amoeba-kills-israeli-man-25-after-he-went-swimming-on-beach-6067544]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 16:31:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Israeli man is thought to have potentially come into contact with the amoeba while swimming at Gai Beach on the shores of the Kinneret in northern Israel.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 25-year-old man has died after being infected with 'brain-eating amoeba', likely during a swim at a popular beach in Israel. According to <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.timesofisrael.com/man-dies-after-contracting-brain-eating-amoeba-in-israels-2nd-ever-recorded-case/">Times Of Israel,</a></em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.timesofisrael.com/man-dies-after-contracting-brain-eating-amoeba-in-israels-2nd-ever-recorded-case/">&nbsp;</a>the&nbsp;Israeli man, who officials have not publicly named, is thought to have potentially come into contact with the amoeba while swimming at Gai Beach on the shores of the Kinneret in northern Israel.</p>

<p>The man, without underlying health conditions, was initially admitted to Sharon Hospital last Tuesday after presenting with symptoms including fever, headaches, and vomiting. After his condition worsened, he was transferred to Beilinson Hospital in Petah Tikvah. Despite the best treatments, he died on Sunday.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The hospital said, ''Medical teams used everything at their disposal, including drug treatments and surgical interventions to save the patient's life, but his condition continued to deteriorate.''</p>

<p>Notably, this is the second-ever case recorded in Israel. A&nbsp; healthy 36-year-old man from northern Israel died of severe brain inflammation after contracting the amoeba in August 2022.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In India, the&nbsp;rare brain infection has claimed three lives. Last week, a&nbsp;14-year-old boy in Kerala died from the infection he contracted while swimming in contaminated water.&nbsp;The first instance was the death of a five-year-old girl from Malappuram on May 21 and the second was a 13-year-old girl from Kannur who died on June 25.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><b>What is Naegleria&nbsp;fowleri, the brain-eating amoeba?</b></h2>

<p>The&nbsp;<em>Naegleria fowleri</em>&nbsp;amoeba, commonly described as brain-eating amoeba because it destroys brain tissue, is typically found in bodies of warm freshwater such as lakes, rivers, or hot springs, and more rarely in poorly maintained under-chlorinated swimming pools.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Swimming or diving in water containing this amoeba can enter their bodies through the nose. Once in the nasal passages, Naegleria&nbsp;fowleri&nbsp;can travel to the brain, resulting in inflammation of the brain tissue and&nbsp;causing a severe infection called primary amebic meningoencephalitis (PAM), as per the&nbsp;<a href="http://%20https//my.clevelandclinic.org/health/diseases/24485-brain-eating-amoeba">Cleveland Clinic</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Symptoms can include headaches, fever, nausea, and vomiting, and the illness "usually leads to coma and death after 5 days," according to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.&nbsp;Other symptoms can include a stiff neck, confusion, lack of attention to people and surroundings, loss of balance, and hallucinations.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The mortality rate from encephalitis caused by the amoeba is extremely high, and while infection is extremely rare, it is often fatal. The US Centres for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) states that most people with PAM die within 1 to 18 days after symptoms start to appear.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Scientists have not found any effective treatments for PAM yet. Currently, doctors have been managing the disease with a combination of drugs.&nbsp;Only some 400 cases have ever been diagnosed worldwide.</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-09/p66hm678_braineating-amoeba-generic_625x300_29_September_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Naegleria fowleri amoeba is typically found in lakes, rivers, or hot springs]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-how-this-year-of-elections-is-going-to-reshape-global-politics-6067513]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: How This Year Of Elections Is Going To Reshape Global Politics]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-how-this-year-of-elections-is-going-to-reshape-global-politics-6067513]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 16:30:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Elections are taking place this year in countries home to almost half of the world's population, from Taiwan's general election in January to the U.S. presidential race in November.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Elections are taking place this year in countries home to almost half of the world's population, from Taiwan's general election in January to the U.S. presidential race in November.</p>

<p>The votes come amid growing economic and geopolitical strife, with the Ukraine war, conflicts in the Middle East and rising trade tensions between the United States and China, the world's two largest economies.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In some countries, there are concerns about the resilience of democracy itself as political discourse has polarized or been warped by disinformation. Many of this year's elections will not be free and fair - or their results will be disputed.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Half-way through the biggest year for elections in history, here are some common themes that have emerged in Reuters' reporting from around the world:</p>

<h3><strong>Cost Of Living</strong></h3>

<p>From the price of green onions in Indonesia to higher fuel bills across Europe, rises in the price of food, energy and other basics have hit the living standards of households across the world. Incumbent governments and leaders are paying for it.</p>

<p>Polling showed that cost of living concerns were a powerful factor in a fall in support for Prime Minister Narendra Modi's party in India, losses suffered by mainstream parties in June's European Parliament elections and the poll rout of Britain's ruling Conservatives.</p>

<p>In Africa, discontent over living standards and unemployment contributed to the ANC's loss of its majority in South Africa's election. Worsening poverty is likely to help shape the outcome of Ghana's December vote to succeed President Nana Akufo-Addo.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Polling ahead of the U.S. election suggests voters are similarly unimpressed with President Joe Biden's efforts to improve their livelihoods, with many Americans feeling their living standards are falling despite strong headline economic data. One outlier: In Mexico, the ruling MORENA party emerged the winner after offering ample subsidies to low-income voters.</p>

<p>While economic policymakers say there are signs that inflation is returning to normal, they warn it has not yet been fully tamed and many economies remain fragile.</p>

<p>"A number of pressure points could throw the global economy off track," Agustin Carstens, head of the central bank umbrella group the Bank of International Settlements (BIS), warned in June.</p>

<h3><strong>Green Transition</strong></h3>

<p>With the cost of living uppermost in many voters' minds, climate change action has often been crowded out of election campaigns - even as global temperatures break new records and death tolls from extreme heat climb.</p>

<p>While surveys show Europeans still support ambitious action on global warming, the debate there has focused on the perceived cost to livelihoods, with farming and other lobbies stepping up calls for an easing of net-zero policies.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In the EU elections, ecologist Greens shed most of the gains made five years earlier. In Britain, Labour dropped a 28-billion-pound green investment pledge ahead of the July 4 general election, saying the country could not afford it, while their Conservative rivals described themselves as "on the side of drivers", attacking low-traffic and low-emission schemes.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The biggest challenge to the green transition may come from the United States, with Donald Trump campaigning on policies supporting continued fossil fuel use. It remains to be seen how much of Biden's Inflation Reduction Act (IRA) green subsidies stay in place in the event of a Trump victory.</p>

<h3><strong>Swing To The (Far) Right?</strong></h3>

<p>The cost of living crisis has led to rising support for far-right movement in Western countries with a mix of anti-immigration and nationalist policies, often unfunded economic spending plans and populist rhetoric attacking global elites.</p>

<p>Back in March, Portugal's Chega party quadrupled its seats in parliament to become the country's third-largest party. Three months later, its far-right, eurosceptic peers across Europe made gains in elections to the European Parliament.</p>

<p>In France, Marine Le Pen's National Rally failed in elections on Sunday to achieve the majority they were coveting but became the largest single party in a hung parliament that now risks plunging Europe's second-largest economy into policy paralyis.</p>

<p>In Britain, the anti-immigrant, nationalist Reform Party won over four million votes, contributing to the collapse in support for the ruling Conservatives even if Britain's first-past-the-post electoral system meant it only won a handful of seats.</p>

<p>Austria's Sept. 29 election will be closely watched, with polls showing the far-right Freedom Party (FPO) leading rivals after it ranked first in European Parliament elections.</p>

<p>In the United States, Trump has made immigration one of his top domestic campaign issues, declaring he would carry out mass deportations, end birthright citizenship, and expand a travel ban on people from certain countries.</p>

<p>Mohit Kumar, chief economist for investment house Jefferies, noted that immigration as an election theme was hottest in precisely the large Western economies whose ageing populations were creating labour shortages.</p>

<p>"Economically we need immigration but the political dynamics are shifting away from immigration," he said.</p>

<h3><strong>Debt And Election Largesse</strong></h3>

<p>With economic hardship so prevalent, many politicians are offering to spend big and cut taxes in a bid to win power - at the risk of adding to global debt already at record levels after huge post-pandemic stimulus packages in rich-world economies.</p>

<p>Credit rating firm S&amp;P Global has warned the United States, France and other Group of Seven (G7) governments were unlikely to halt rises in their debt "at the present stage in their electoral cycles".&nbsp;</p>

<p>The BIS annual report in June said an election year like this brought an "especially high" risk of fiscal expansion that could complicate efforts to bring inflation down to target.</p>

<p>Budget watchdogs in Britain and France - two countries struggling to balance their budgets - noted that many spending pledges were either unfunded or unrealistically costed.</p>

<p>Trump has pledged to keep in place a broad 2017 tax cut that he signed while in office, and his economic team has discussed a further round of cuts beyond those enacted in his first term.</p>

<p>Biden, meanwhile, proposes raising levies on businesses and rich individuals, while vowing not to increase taxes for households earning less than $400,000 a year and to assist low- and middle-income Americans with childcare costs. U.S. federal government currently has more than $34 trillion in debt.</p>

<p>Such levels of debt are seen making the global economy more vulnerable to financial shocks and the International Monetary Fund has urged governments to reduce their borrowing.</p>

<p>"Unfortunately, fiscal plans so far are insufficient and could be derailed further given the record number of elections this year," its chief economist Pierre-Olivier Gourinchas said in a recent blog.</p>

<h3><strong>Defence And Security</strong></h3>

<p>As geopolitical tensions rise, defence and security matters have been prominent in a number of election campaigns so far this year - particularly in countries near the hotspots.</p>

<p>In February, Finland elected as president Alexander Stubb, who campaigned on the previously non-aligned country fully participating in NATO and allowing the transit of nuclear arms through it. Incumbents in Lithuania won an election dominated by concerns over Russia and calls for higher defence spending.</p>

<p>Taiwan's presidential and parliamentary elections on Jan. 13 focused around arguments on how best to deal with China, which views the island as its own territory. The ruling DPP party secured the presidency for a third term as its candidate vowed to safeguard Taiwan from intimidation while emphasising the need for dialogue with Beijing.</p>

<p>In the United States, Democratic voters' anger over Israel's military action in Gaza - and over Biden's continued support of Israel - has emerged as a major vulnerability for him. American views on the conflict have broken down along party lines with Republicans largely supporting Israel.</p>

<p>While Biden voices unwavering support for NATO, Trump has said that if he is returned to the White House, America would fundamentally rethink NATO's purpose. He has also asserted without evidence that if elected he would end the conflict in Ukraine before even taking office. On that, Biden has retorted that Trump has "no idea what he's talking about".</p>

<h3><strong>Democracy At Stake?</strong></h3>

<p>Pro-democracy watchdogs estimate that nearly three-quarters of the world's population live in autocracies. Observers and human rights groups have signalled concerns about the fairness of elections this year in Bangladesh, Azerbaijan, Belarus, Cambodia, Iran and Russia. Votes in Algeria and Uzbekistan face similar questions.</p>

<p>Modi's electoral setback has been hailed by some commentators as proof of the resilience of its democracy. There was relief at the peaceful handover of power in Senegal in March after moves by the incumbent to delay the vote triggered protests.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Democracy's biggest test this year may, however, be in Washington.</p>

<p>Trump refuses to commit to accepting the election results or to rule out possible violence around the Nov. 5 contest. He is already laying the groundwork to contest a potential defeat.</p>

<p>"We should be quite worried," Steven Levitsky, political scientist and professor of government at Harvard University, told a Brookings think tank event in June.</p>

<p>"A democracy cannot survive if one party in a two-party system is not committed to playing by the democratic rules of the game."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/g7qpj5u_election-generic_625x300_09_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Defence, security matters have been prominent in a number of election campaigns (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-modi-russia-visit-pm-hugs-putin-ukraine-president-volodymyr-zelenskyy-a-huge-disappointment-ukraine-president-reacts-to-pm-modi-putin-hug-6067174]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Huge Disappointment...": Ukraine President Reacts To PM Modi's Russia Visit]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-modi-russia-visit-pm-hugs-putin-ukraine-president-volodymyr-zelenskyy-a-huge-disappointment-ukraine-president-reacts-to-pm-modi-putin-hug-6067174]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 15:45:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ukraine President Volodymyr Zelenskyy has reacted sharply to Prime Minister Narendra Modi's brief visit to Russia and his interaction with Russian President Vladimir Putin.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ukraine President <a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/topic/volodymyr-zelenskyy" target="_blank">Volodymyr Zelenskyy</a> has reacted sharply to Prime Minister <a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/topic/pm-modi" target="_blank">Narendra Modi</a>'s brief visit to Russia and his interaction with Russian President <a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/topic/vladimir-putin" target="_blank">Vladimir Putin</a>.</p>

<p>In a post on X (formerly Twitter) Mr Zelenskyy referred to Russia's attack Monday - in which at least 37 people, including three children, were killed after a missile strike on a children's hospital in Kyiv.</p>

<p>The strike also damaged nearly 100 buildings, including schools and maternity hospitals.</p>

<p>His tweet included photographs of the bombed hospital and babies in ambulances.</p>

<p>Mr Zelenskky's post came after Prime Minister Modi met President Putin in Moscow and shared an embrace. Visuals from their meeting showed the two leaders drinking tea on a terrace at Mr Putin's home in Novo-Ogaryovo outside Moscow, and Mr Modi being driven around in a golf cart.</p>

<p>One photo in particular - of <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/topic/pm-modi-hugs-putin" target="_blank">Mr Modi and Mr Putin hugging</a> - has been widely shared online.</p>

<p><strong>READ |</strong>&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/pm-modi-hugs-putin-on-russia-visit-tea-meet-on-terrace-golf-cart-ride-6064443" target="_blank">PM Hugs Putin On Russia Visit, Tea Meet At Home, Golf Cart Ride</a></p>

<p>And the Ukraine President was particularly critical of that image, posting, "It is a huge disappointment and a devastating blow to peace efforts to see the leader of the world's largest democracy hug the world's most bloody criminal in Moscow on such a day..."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">In Ukraine today, 37 people were killed, three of whom were children, and 170 were injured, including 13 children, as a result of Russia's brutal missile strike.<br />
<br />
A Russian missile struck the largest children's hospital in Ukraine, targeting young cancer patients. Many were… <a href="https://t.co/V1k7PEz2rJ">pic.twitter.com/V1k7PEz2rJ</a></p>
— Volodymyr Zelenskyy / Володимир Зеленський (@ZelenskyyUa) <a href="https://twitter.com/ZelenskyyUa/status/1810437647581716707?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 8, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>PM Modi flew into Moscow on a two-day visit that treads a fine line between maintaining a longstanding relationship and courting closer ties with the West amid the war in Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>

<p>This is the Prime Minister's first visit since he was voted back to power last month.</p>

<p>It is also his first to Russia since the war in Ukraine began.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/pm-modis-advice-to-vladimir-putin-no-solution-can-be-found-on-the-battleground-6064774" target="_blank">At Modi-Putin Dinner, India's Direct Appeal To End Ukraine War</a></p>

<p>Sources have told NDTV that Mr Modi, during his meeting with Mr Putin, stressed no solution - to the violence - could be found on the battlefield. "India has always called for respecting the United Nations Charter, including territorial integrity and sovereignty. There is no solution on the battlefield. Dialogue and diplomacy is the way forward," Mr Modi is believed to have said.</p>

<p>Mr Modi has also spoken to Mr Zelenskyy on numerous occasions, including meeting him in Italy last month <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-narendra-modi-ukraine-president-volodymyr-zelensky-meet-on-sidelines-of-g7-summit-in-italy-5889246" target="_blank">on the sidelines of the G7 summit</a>. The two were photographed sharing a hug. Their first face-to-face meeting since the war started was in May last year, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/pm-modi-meets-ukraine-president-zelensky-for-the-first-time-since-russias-invasion-4051293" target="_blank">at the G7 summit hosted by Japan</a>.</p>

<p>In a phone call with President Zelenskyy in October 2022, PM Modi said there can be "no military solution" and that India is ready to contribute to any peace efforts</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/pm-modi-to-speak-with-ukraine-president-volodymyr-zelensky-today-government-sources-2807514" target="_blank">PM Speaks To Ukraine President, Call With Putin Later Today</a></p>

<p>Ever since the war began India has maintained it can only be resolved through dialogue and diplomacy, and the Prime Minister has said "India is ready to contribute to any peace efforts".</p>

<p><em>NDTV is now available on WhatsApp channels. <a href="https://www.whatsapp.com/channel/0029Va4lixw7z4kcvZI9JM12">Click on the link</a> to get all the latest updates from NDTV on your chat. </em></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-02/3n4vdap8_ukraine-president-volodymyr-zelenskyy-afp_625x300_25_February_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Ukraine President Volodymyr Zelenskyy (File).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/watch-major-bridge-in-new-york-stuck-open-due-to-extreme-heat-6067151]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Watch: Major Bridge In New York Stuck Open After Getting Too Hot]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/watch-major-bridge-in-new-york-stuck-open-due-to-extreme-heat-6067151]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 15:40:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[As a result, traffic was halted on the one-lane structure, leaving multiple vehicles without any option to cross into Manhattan.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A New York City bridge&nbsp;that connects Manhattan to the Bronx&nbsp;became stuck open on Monday afternoon after hot summer weather caused it to overheat. Notably, the Third Avenue Bridge, built in 1898, crosses the Harlem River and serves as the link between the two boroughs. On Monday, temperatures hit 35°C, reportedly resulting in the metal machinery to overheat and swell.</p>

<p>&nbsp;According to <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.foxnews.com/us/major-new-york-city-bridge-gets-unexpectedly-stuck-summer-temps-authorities-investigate">Fox News</a></em>,&nbsp;the metal on the 126-year-old bridge expanded due to extreme heat at about 3 p.m. and caused it to become stuck open.&nbsp;"[There was a] report of bridge stuck halfway open. Marine units standing by as well as land units,'' officials said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Crews on boats spent hours spraying water onto the bridge to cool the metal so they could realign it with the road deck. Aerial footage showed FDNY boats spraying water onto the span and bottom of the open bridge to cool it.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Watch the video here:</strong></p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Third Avenue Bridge Closed in All Directions Due to Overheating Equipment, Causing it to Become Stuck in the Open Position <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/NewYork?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#NewYork</a> <a href="https://t.co/GLT89m7j7I">pic.twitter.com/GLT89m7j7I</a></p>
— William John (@Johnwilliam_123) <a href="https://twitter.com/Johnwilliam_123/status/1810615086484275333?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 9, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>As a result, traffic was halted on the one-lane structure, leaving multiple vehicles without any option to cross into Manhattan. The bridge reopened for vehicles in both directions around 6:40 p.m.&nbsp;Fortunately, no injuries were reported as a result of the incident.</p>

<p data-v-be063cea=""></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Update: The Third Avenue Bridge is now open for vehicles in both directions. <a href="https://t.co/QFLaIaPPKM">https://t.co/QFLaIaPPKM</a></p>
— NYPD NEWS (@NYPDnews) <a href="https://twitter.com/NYPDnews/status/1810444053189664915?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 8, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>This is New York's second heatwave this summer. As per <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://metro.co.uk/2024/07/09/new-york-city-bridge-stuck-open-due-weather-heat-advisory-effect-21189915/">Metro</a></em>, a&nbsp;heat advisory is currently in effect for Bronx, Brooklyn, Manhattan, Northern Queens, Staten Island, and Southern Queens Counties until 8 pm on Wednesday.</p>

<p></p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/e2qrp93_third-avenue-bridge_625x300_09_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The incident caused major traffic delays during one of the hottest days of the year in New York]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukraines-children-hospital-was-probably-directly-hit-by-russian-missile-un-6067064]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kyiv Children Hospital Was Probably Directly Hit By Russian Missile: UN]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukraines-children-hospital-was-probably-directly-hit-by-russian-missile-un-6067064]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 15:29:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United Nations on Tuesday said there was a "high likelihood" that the children's hospital in Kyiv suffered "a direct hit" from a Russian missile.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United Nations on Tuesday said there was a "high likelihood" that the children's hospital in Kyiv suffered "a direct hit" from a Russian missile.</p>

<p>Danielle Bell, head of the UN Human Rights Monitoring Mission in Ukraine, called Monday's strike "one of the most egregious attacks that we've seen since the onset of the full-scale invasion" in February 2022.</p>

<p>She was speaking after Russia attacked cities across Ukraine on Monday with a missile barrage that killed more than three dozen people and ripped open the Okhmatdyt children's hospital in Kyiv, sparking international outcry.</p>

<p>Dozens of volunteers including hospital staff and rescue workers dug through debris from the hospital in a desperate search for survivors after the rare day-time bombardment, AFP journalists on the scene saw.</p>

<p>Russia has denied that it was responsible for the hospital strike, claiming the extensive missile damage in Kyiv was caused by Ukrainian air defence systems.</p>

<p>But Bell told reporters in Geneva that video footage "shows the weapon directly impacting the hospital".</p>

<p>The Okhmatdyt paediatric hospital is a children's specialist facility where families from across the country bring their children for treatment of serious medical conditions, such as cancer and kidney disease, she said, speaking via video-link from Kyiv.</p>

<p>"Analysis of the video footage and assessment made at the incident site indicates a high likelihood that the children's hospital suffered a direct hit, rather than receiving damages due to an intercepted weapons system.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"This must be investigated," said Bell, who said her team and military experts had observed the damage at the hospital and spoken to staff, patients' parents and local residents.</p>

<p>She said that at the time of the attack, 670 child patients and more than a thousand medical staff were present.</p>

<p>Bell said Russia had likely fired from an aircraft a Kh-101 air-to-surface cruise missile armed with several hundred kilogrammes of explosives.</p>

<p>"The factors suggesting that it was a direct hit are based on video footage which shows the technical specification of the type of weapon that was used; it shows the weapon directly impacting the hospital, rather than being intercepted in the air," said Bell.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/r1gln45o_ukraine-children-hospital_625x300_09_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Russia has denied that it was responsible for the hospital strike]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ripcartoonnetwork-become-the-top-trend-is-the-channel-shutting-down-rumour-video-6067053]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: Why RIPCartoonNetwork Has Become The Top Trend]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ripcartoonnetwork-become-the-top-trend-is-the-channel-shutting-down-rumour-video-6067053]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 15:28:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A rumour that Cartoon Network is shutting down sent shockwaves across the Internet. So much so that the hashtag RIPCartoonNetwork became the top trend.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A rumour that Cartoon Network is shutting down sent shockwaves across the Internet. So much so that the hashtag RIPCartoonNetwork became the top trend.</p>

<p>The rumour started with a video posted on X (formerly Twitter) by the account "Animation Workers Ignited", which claimed that the channel was "dead". However, it has since been clarified that the channel is not actually shutting down.</p>

<h3><strong>Why is RIPCartoonNetwork trending?</strong></h3>

<p>The video was intended to bring attention to the struggles faced by the animation industry, which has been heavily impacted by the pandemic. Many workers have been left unemployed for over a year and the industry as a whole is struggling to recover.</p>

<p>The video sparked a widespread reaction, with fans expressing their support for the animation industry and its workers. The hashtag RIPCartoonNetwork was used to show solidarity and raise awareness about the issues faced by the industry.</p>

<p>The video talked about the harsh realities faced by animation workers in the wake of the Covid-19 pandemic. Despite the industry's ability to operate remotely and continue production uninterrupted, studios have been accused of cancelling projects, outsourcing jobs and laying off artists en masse.</p>

<p>The video claimed that big studios are driven by greed, cutting finances by reducing spending and staff, while CEOs and executives continue to reap benefits for themselves. The animation industry is "under attack," the video declared, urging fans to take a stand and show support for the affected artists.</p>

<p>The video called on fans to share their favourite Cartoon Network shows that were cancelled too soon, using the hashtag RIPCartoonNetwork.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Cartoon Network is dead?!?!<br />
<br />
Spread the word about what's at stake for animation!!! Post about your favorite Cartoon Network shows using <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/RIPCartoonNetwork?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#RIPCartoonNetwork</a><br />
<br />
Active members of TAG can help by filling out your survey! Today (7/8) is the last day! <a href="https://t.co/dHNMvA1q0A">pic.twitter.com/dHNMvA1q0A</a></p>
— Animation Workers Ignited (@AWorkersIgnited) <a href="https://twitter.com/AWorkersIgnited/status/1810440310838968397?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 8, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<h3><strong>Is Cartoon Network shutting down?</strong></h3>

<p>Cartoon Network is not shutting down, despite rumours. The channel is adapting to changes in the media landscape and has new programming in development, including spin-offs of popular shows.</p>

<p>New programmes are also in the works, including The Amazing World of Gumball: The Series premiering this year, and spin-offs of Adventure Time, Regular Show, and Foster's Home of Imaginary Friends in development.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-10/d9mn8pdo_cartoon-network-_625x300_14_October_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Cartoon Network is not shutting down, despite rumours]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explainer-why-democrats-are-urging-joe-biden-to-step-out-of-us-presidential-race-6066866]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explainer: Why Democrats Are Urging Biden To Step Out Of Presidential Race]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explainer-why-democrats-are-urging-joe-biden-to-step-out-of-us-presidential-race-6066866]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 14:56:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Citing concerns about his health and ability to take on Donald Trump, prominent House Democrats have doubted Joe Biden's fitness for office and his chances of winning in 2024.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Fifty-six years ago, a US President appeared on television and announced, to the nation's shock, that he'd not seek re-election. His name was Lyndon B. Johnson, the most recent US President to not run for his second elected term. The reasons were many and varied.</p>

<p>In November 1963, Johnson, the then US Vice-President, ascended to the top job following the assassination of then-President John F. Kennedy. A year later, he registered a landslide victory for Democrats in Presidential polls.</p>

<p>However, that changed after he presided over the deeply unpopular Vietnam War. Even though he was elected as the Democratic nominee in 1968, his health, plunging approval ratings and the way he handled the war -- all went against him. Johnson decided it was time for him to make way for someone else.</p>

<p>Fast-forward to 2024, another US President's reelection bid is in jeopardy. This time, it's Joe Biden faced with growing calls from within the party to drop out of the presidential race. Citing concerns about his health and ability to take on Donald Trump, prominent House Democrats have doubted Biden's fitness for office and his chances of winning in 2024.</p>

<p>Despite the mounting pressure, Biden remains defiant, insisting he will stay in the race. But will his determination be enough to overcome the rising dissent against his candidacy?</p>

<p>On Sunday, a group of <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/2024-election/four-democrats-congress-call-biden-step-2024-race-rcna160625">Democratic lawmakers</a>, including Reps Adam Smith, Jerry Nadler, Mark Takano and Joe Morelle, gathered to discuss their party's future. According to sources, they all agreed that President Biden should withdraw from the presidential race. This was also echoed publicly by Rep Adam Smith in a Monday interview with CNN, where he openly called for Biden to drop out.</p>

<p>Rep Angie Craig urged President Biden to <a href="http://https://www.forbes.com/sites/brianbushard/2024/07/05/biden-calls-debate-just-a-bad-episode-i-was-sick-in-abc-interview/ ">withdraw from the presidential race</a> following his interview with ABC News' George Stephanopoulos. Craig cited Biden's disappointing debate performance and his inability to deliver a strong response in the aftermath.</p>

<p>Reps Mike Quigley and Seth Moulton have joined the growing chorus of Democrats calling for President Biden to withdraw from the presidential race. In an interview with <a href="http://https://www.msnbc.com/all-in/watch/dem-rep-mike-quigley-calls-on-biden-to-step-aside-let-someone-else-do-this-214313029546 ">MSNBC</a>'s Chris Hayes, Quigley said that stepping down is the only way for Biden to secure his legacy and prevent a disastrous outcome.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Seth Moulton said he didn't have confidence in Biden's ability to defeat Donald Trump in November, urging him to "step aside and let new leaders rise" in an interview with Boston's <a href="http://https://www.wbur.org/news/2024/07/04/moulton-says-biden-drop-out-election ">WBUR</a>.</p>

<p>Reps Lloyd Doggett and Raul Grijalva were among the first sitting Democrats to urge President Biden to withdraw from the race. Doggett said he was disappointed that Biden failed to defend his accomplishments and expose Trump's lies during the debate, while Grijalva said it was Biden's "responsibility" to step down. Former Secretary of Housing and Urban Development Julian Castro also joined the calls for Biden to withdraw, suggesting Vice President Kamala Harris as a suitable replacement on the Democratic ticket.</p>

<p>President Biden's performance in the first debate was widely criticised, with many saying he appeared weak and disoriented. He struggled to speak clearly, fumbled, gave confusing answers and often looked lost. Even Trump's critics agreed that Biden's performance was disappointing.</p>

<p>In a speech in Raleigh, North Carolina, the day after the debate, Biden addressed the crowd saying he was not as spry as he used to be. "I don't walk as easy as I used to, I don't speak as smoothly as I used to, I don't debate as well as I used to,” he said. "I know what I do know, I know how to tell the truth!"</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/jdufu96_biden3_625x300_06_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/dog-turns-on-stove-in-us-house-apple-homepad-alerts-owners-of-fire-6066726]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Dog Turns On Stove In US House, Apple HomePad Alerts Owners Of Fire]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/dog-turns-on-stove-in-us-house-apple-homepad-alerts-owners-of-fire-6066726]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 14:38:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A pet dog's curiosity almost turned deadly for a family in the US after the family pet accidentally switched on the stove at night while its owners were asleep. The family was saved from disaster after their Apple HomePad sent them an alert.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A pet dog's curiosity almost turned deadly for a family in the US after the family pet accidentally switched on the stove at night while its owners were asleep. The family was saved from disaster after their Apple HomePad, a home assistant device, sent an alert notifying them of "high heat". The episode was caught on camera placed in the kitchen.</p>

<p>The incident occurred in US's Colorado last month at around 4:40 am. A CCTV video showed the dog pawing at the kitchen counter during which it turned on the stove.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The camera showed the dog on its hind legs and switching on the stove. Within moments, a few boxes kept on top of the stove caught fire, quickly setting fire to the kitchen. Another video showed the kitchen engulfed in flames and filled with smoke setting off the fire alarm.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">On Wednesday, June 26th at 4:43 a.m. CSFD was dispatched to a possible structure fire at a home on the 1600 block of Rushmore Dr. Homeowners reported to our call takers that they had experienced a fire on the stove in their home that had been extinguished by one of the… <a href="https://t.co/lohlgUvC2q">pic.twitter.com/lohlgUvC2q</a></p>
— CSFD PIO (@CSFDPIO) <a href="https://twitter.com/CSFDPIO/status/1808255474187526290?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 2, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p></p>

<p>At this moment, the Apple HomePad sent an alert to the owners who were awakened by the "high heat" notification. One of them put off the fire before the fire department arrived.&nbsp;</p>

<p>When the fire department officials arrived they saw the video recorded in the kitchen and shared it on social media. The video has over 13,000 views on X.</p>

<p>The owner was taken to a local hospital to get treated for smoke inhalation. No other injuries were reported.</p>

<p>“This is a good reminder to always have working smoke alarms inside and outside every sleeping area and on every floor of the home, ensure all combustibles are away from your stovetop/oven, and know two ways out of every room in your home in the event of a fire,” the fire department said in a post on X.</p>

<p>X users have slammed the owners for neglect after the incident arguing that flammable boxes should not have been put on top of the stove. Other warned that a similar incident involving a child could also have taken place.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/5rdb2ego_colorado-fire-dog_625x300_09_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The incident occurred in US's Colorado last month at around 4:40 am.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/haw-par-villa-park-singapores-hell-theme-park-dead-serious-about-afterlife-6066649]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Singapore's Hell Theme Park Dead Serious About Afterlife]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/haw-par-villa-park-singapores-hell-theme-park-dead-serious-about-afterlife-6066649]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 14:24:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Gory grottos with demons impaling sinners on stakes and people drowning in a pool of blood are not part of your average theme park experience.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Gory grottos with demons impaling sinners on stakes and people drowning in a pool of blood are not part of your average theme park experience.</p>

<p>But at Hell's Museum in Singapore, the main attraction at the Haw Par Villa park, visitors are welcomed to a kitschy, air-conditioned hell on Earth.</p>

<p>Inside the sprawling park complex with over 1,000 statues and dioramas showcasing Asian culture, faiths and philosophy, Hell's Museum exhibits various religious views on the afterlife.</p>

<p>Visitors are encouraged to learn about the 10 Courts of Hell through intense depictions of punishments for earthly sins.</p>

<p>At court number two, for instance, corruption gets you frozen in ice while rapists at court seven are thrown in boiling oil.</p>

<p>The 10 Courts of Hell are "the result of the mixing of four different religions and philosophies: Buddhism, Taoism, Hinduism, Confucianism", said Eisen Teo, the chief curator of Hell's Museum in the multicultural city-state.</p>

<p>"The sculptures and dioramas are a visual dissection of many classics, stories and moral values that many Singaporeans have and are familiar with," Teo said.</p>

<p>Visitor Gin Goldberg told AFP she wasn't so surprised to learn that many religions had differing opinions on the afterlife.</p>

<p>"One person's heaven would be another person's hell," the American said.</p>

<p><strong>Party in hell</strong></p>

<p>The odd park stands apart from gleaming Singapore's mainstream tourist attractions such as the luxury shops of Marina Bay Sands or the towering "supertrees" of Gardens by the Bay.</p>

<p>Haw Par Villa was built in 1937 by entrepreneur Aw Boon Haw, known for co-developing Asia's much-loved Tiger Balm pain relief rub.</p>

<p>While fondly remembered by older generations, the park has had trouble attracting the Gen Z crowd and younger millenials, according to Journeys, the firm that manages the park.</p>

<p>To broaden appeal, it has held several rave parties and other private events -- but not too near to religious exhibits.</p>

<p>"After they came here (for the parties) they fell in love with the quirky, eccentric park, with these cool sculptures. Fell in love with them and they keep doing repeat visits," said Savita Kashyap, Journeys' executive director.</p>

<p>While Haw Par Villa isn't just about the afterlife, and raves -- it also displays scenes from Chinese folklore such as "Romance of the Three Kingdoms" -- its hellish attraction remains the top draw.</p>

<p>But not for all.</p>

<p>One Filipina visitor told AFP while leaving that she won't be returning anytime soon.</p>

<p>"It's very scary," she said.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/fa0gpj5_haw-par-villa-singapore-afp_625x300_09_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Visitors are encouraged to learn about the 10 Courts of Hell through intense depictions of punishments.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/most-cancer-patients-die-of-cachexia-not-cancer-read-details-6063036]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Most Cancer Patients Die Of "Cachexia", Not Cancer: Read Details]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/most-cancer-patients-die-of-cachexia-not-cancer-read-details-6063036]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 13:48:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[When tumours in cancer patients elevate levels of an immune system molecule called Interleukin-6 (IL-6), it can cause severe brain dysfunction, which leads to a lethal wasting disease called 'cachexia' in about 50 to 80% cancer patients, a study said]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When tumours in cancer patients elevate levels of an immune system molecule called Interleukin-6 (IL-6), it can cause severe brain dysfunction, which leads to a lethal wasting disease called 'cachexia' in about 50 to 80 per cent of cancer patients, a new study said.</p>

<p>As per US-based Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory's (CSHL) Professor Bo Li, "It's a very severe syndrome".</p>

<p>"Most people with cancer die of 'cachexia' instead of cancer. And once the patient enters this stage, there's no way to go back because essentially there's no treatment," he said in a study published in the journal Nature Communications.</p>

<p>Li and other researchers in the team found that blocking 'IL-6' from binding to neurons in a part of the brain called the area postrema (AP) prevents cachexia in mice.</p>

<p>As a result, the mice live longer with healthier brain function.</p>

<p>"Future drugs targeting these neurons could help make cancer cachexia a treatable disease," the researchers suggested.</p>

<p>In healthy patients, 'IL-6' plays a vital role in natural immune response. The molecules circulate throughout the body. When they encounter a possible threat, they alert the brain to coordinate a response.</p>

<p>According to the researchers, cancer disrupts this process as too much IL-6 gets produced, and it begins binding to AP neurons in the brain.</p>

<p>"That leads to several consequences. One is animals and humans alike will stop eating. Another is to engage this response that leads to the wasting syndrome," Li said.</p>

<p>The team took a two-pronged approach to keeping elevated IL-6 out of the brain in mice. Their first strategy neutralised IL-6 with custom antibodies. The second used CRISPR to reduce the levels of IL-6 receptors in AP neurons. Both tactics produced the same results -- the mice started eating again, stopped losing weight, and lived longer, the study noted.</p>

<p>"The brain is so powerful in regulating the peripheral system. Simply changing a small number of neurons in the brain has a profound effect on whole-body physiology. I knew there was an interaction between tumours and brain function, but not to this extent," said Li.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-05/6tvmdl64_hospital-generic_625x300_20_May_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[What's 'cancer cachexia' syndrome, a disease behind most patients' death? (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/samsung-says-no-disruption-to-production-despite-workers-strike-6066401]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["No Disruption" To Production Despite Workers Strike: Samsung]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/samsung-says-no-disruption-to-production-despite-workers-strike-6066401]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 13:44:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[South Korean tech giant Samsung said Tuesday that production was not being disrupted despite a three-day general strike by thousands of workers.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>South Korean tech giant Samsung said Tuesday that production was not being disrupted despite a three-day general strike by thousands of workers.</p>

<p>More than 5,000 members of the National Samsung Electronic Union stopped working Monday, the organisation said, as part of a long-running battle over pay and benefits.</p>

<p>The union has more than 30,000 members -- more than a fifth of the company's total workforce.</p>

<p>"There has been no disruption to production," local media quoted Samsung as saying.</p>

<p>Park Seol, a senior member of the union, told AFP Tuesday that production was being affected.</p>

<p>"But more importantly, the company should understand that we aren't trying just to affect their production line, we want them to hear our voice and understand how desperate we are," he said.</p>

<p>The union has been locked in negotiations with management since January, but the two sides have failed to narrow differences on benefits and a 5.1 percent pay raise offer from the firm was rejected.</p>

<p>In a regulatory filing last week, Samsung Electronics said that its April-June operating profits were expected to rise to 10.4 trillion won ($7.54 billion), up 1,452.2 percent from 670 billion won a year earlier.</p>

<p>Sales, meanwhile, are expected to rise 23.3 percent to 74 trillion won, Samsung said.</p>

<p>Samsung Electronics is the world's largest memory chip maker and accounts for a significant chunk of the global output of high-end chips.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2018-11/e5sr0itg_samsung-generic_625x300_14_November_18.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The union has more than 30,000 members -- more than a fifth of the company's total workforce.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>