<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Thu, 04 Jul 2024 05:49:51 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-has-a-six-point-lead-over-joe-biden-after-debate-report-6029497]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Has A Six Point Lead Over Biden After Debate: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-has-a-six-point-lead-over-joe-biden-after-debate-report-6029497]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 04 Jul 2024 05:49:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump has developed a six per cent lead over his Democratic rival incumbent Joe Biden with 80 percent saying that the current White House occupant is too old to run for a second term, according to a latest poll by The Wall Street Journal.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Presumptive Republican nominee Donald Trump has developed a six per cent lead over his Democratic rival incumbent Joe Biden with 80 percent saying that the current White House occupant is too old to run for a second term, according to a latest poll by The Wall Street Journal.</p>

<p>The Wall Street Journal said Trump's lead over Biden in a two-person matchup, 48 per cent to 42 per cent is the widest in Journal surveys dating to late 2021 and compares with a 2-point lead in February.</p>

<p>The new survey began interviewing voters two days after the debate with Trump that left Democrats panicked about the 81-year-old president's possible cognitive decline and their party's weakening election prospects in November, the daily reported.</p>

<p>According to the survey, Democrats show significant discontent with Biden as their nominee. Some 76 per cent say he is too old to run this year, or about the same share as Republicans who hold that view. Two-thirds of Democrats would replace Biden on the ballot with another nominee, it said.</p>

<p>Importantly, the survey found that Vice President Kamala Harris is non-popular among the respondents.</p>

<p>"Some 35 per cent viewed Harris favorably and 58 per cent unfavorably in the new survey, about the same as in February's poll and roughly in line with views of the president," The Wall Street Journal said.</p>

<p>"The new survey also includes warning signs for the Democratic Party as it tries this fall to retain control of the Senate and retake a majority in the House," it added.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/tif74i68_donald-trump-reuters_625x300_23_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[According to report, Trump has developed a 6% lead over his Democratic rival incumbent Joe Biden.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-absolutely-not-pulling-out-of-us-presidential-race-white-house-6029148]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden "Absolutely Not" Pulling Out Of US Presidential Race: White House]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-absolutely-not-pulling-out-of-us-presidential-race-white-house-6029148]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 04 Jul 2024 03:46:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Joe Biden is "absolutely not" pulling out of the White House race, his spokeswoman said Wednesday, as pressure mounted on the president following his disastrous debate performance against Donald Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Joe Biden is "absolutely not" pulling out of the White House race, his spokeswoman said Wednesday, as pressure mounted on the president following his disastrous debate performance against Donald Trump.</p>

<p>Panic has gripped Democrats in the wake of last week's debate, and internal rumblings about finding a replacement candidate before November's election have been amplified by polls showing Trump extending his lead.</p>

<p>The New York Times and CNN reported that Biden, 81, had acknowledged to a key ally that his reelection bid was on the line if he failed to quickly reassure the public that he was still up to the job.</p>

<p>White House spokeswoman Karine Jean-Pierre rejected those reports outright, and insisted Biden had "absolutely" no intention of withdrawing as the Democratic nominee.</p>

<p>"The president is clear-eyed and he is staying in the race," she told reporters</p>

<p>Biden conceded in a call with campaign and party staffers that his incoherent, unfocused answers against Trump had damaged him, multiple media outlets reported -- but he insisted he was in the race for the long haul.</p>

<p>"Let me say this as clearly as I possibly can -- as simply and straightforward as I can: I am running... no one's pushing me out. I'm not leaving. I'm in this race to the end and we're going to win," the veteran Democrat said, according to Politico.</p>

<p><strong>- Aftermath -</strong></p>

<p>The Biden campaign has been desperate to reassure Democratic donors and voters that the president's performance against Trump was a one-off, and not a fatal blow to his hopes of a second term.</p>

<p>But party figures have voiced bafflement over what they see as deflection and excuses from the president and his aides.</p>

<p>In Congress, lawmakers see Democratic prospects of taking over the House of Representatives, hanging on to the Senate and returning to the White House slipping away.</p>

<p>The concern was compounded by a New York Times poll conducted after the debate that showed Trump with his biggest lead ever over Biden -- 49 percent to 43 percent of likely voters.</p>

<p>It wasn't until Wednesday -- six days after the debate -- that Biden completed a round of calls with Democratic congressional leaders, and staffers have been voicing consternation over the glacial pace of the outreach.</p>

<p>"We are getting to the point where it may not have been the debate that did him in, but the aftermath of how they've handled it," a senior Democratic operative told Washington political outlet Axios.</p>

<p>Aware of growing alarm in the party's grassroots, Biden hits the swing states of Wisconsin and Pennsylvania in the coming days.</p>

<p>He may be tested on his ability to think on his feet and articulate a coherent vision when he sits with ABC News on Friday for his first television interview since the debate.</p>

<p><strong>- 'More worrisome' -</strong></p>

<p>The president has cited fatigue as a new explanation for his poor debate showing, saying that he had been unwise to travel "around the world a couple times" before the debate.</p>

<p>But he had been back in the United States for nearly two weeks and spent two days relaxing and six preparing for the debate.</p>

<p>The Times said people who have interacted with the president had found that his mental fogginess was "growing more frequent, more pronounced and more worrisome."</p>

<p>Democratic lawmakers have begun to go public with their doubts, with two saying Tuesday they expected Biden to lose to Trump in November and another pair calling for him to quit the White House race.</p>

<p>Arizona congressman Raul Grijalva became the second sitting Democrat to call on Biden to drop out.</p>

<p>"If he's the candidate, I'm going to support him, but I think that this is an opportunity to look elsewhere," Grijalva said, according to the Times.</p>

<p>In the street where the president grew up in Scranton, Pennsylvania, there was sympathy for Biden -- but no campaign signs for either candidate.</p>

<p>"I was embarrassed for him. I felt he didn't feel well and he probably shouldn't have gone on the stage," said grandmother Jamie Hayes, 73.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/65e92ut8_joe-biden_625x300_13_June_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[White House said that Biden had "absolutely" no intention of withdrawing as the Democratic nominee.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/9-in-10-gazans-displaced-since-war-began-un-6028778]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[9 In 10 Gazans Displaced Since War Began: UN]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/9-in-10-gazans-displaced-since-war-began-un-6028778]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 04 Jul 2024 01:31:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Around nine in every 10 people in the Gaza Strip have been displaced at least once since the war between Israel and Hamas began, the UN humanitarian agency said Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Around nine in every 10 people in the Gaza Strip have been displaced at least once since the war between Israel and Hamas began, the UN humanitarian agency said Wednesday.</p>

<p>Andrea De Domenico, head of the United Nations' OCHA agency in the Palestinian territories, said that around 1.9 million people are thought to be displaced in Gaza.</p>

<p>"We estimate that nine in every 10 people in the Gaza Strip have been internally displaced at least once, if not up to 10 times, unfortunately, since October," he told reporters in New York and Geneva, speaking from Jerusalem.</p>

<p>"Before we were estimating 1.7 (million) but since that number, we had the operation in Rafah, and we had additional displacement from Rafah," he said, explaining the increase.</p>

<p>"Then we had also operations in the north that has also moved people," he added.</p>

<p>He said such military operations had forced people to reset their lives, over and over again.</p>

<p>"Behind these numbers, there are people... that have fears and grievances. And they had probably dreams and hopes; the less and less, I fear today, unfortunately," De Domenico said.</p>

<p>"People who in the last nine months have been moved around like pawns in a board game."</p>

<p>He said the Gaza Strip had been cut in two by Israel's military operations, with OCHA estimating that there were 300,000-350,000 people living in the north of the besieged territory who were unable to go to the south.</p>

<p>Meanwhile he added that since the war began, an estimated 110,000 people had managed to leave the Gaza Strip before the Rafah crossing into Egypt was closed in early May.</p>

<p>De Domenico said some had remained in Egypt while others had since moved onwards.</p>

<p>The bloodiest-ever Gaza war broke out after Hamas's October 7 attack on southern Israel resulted in the deaths of 1,195 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli figures.</p>

<p>The militants also seized 251 hostages, 116 of whom remain in Gaza including 42 the army says are dead.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory offensive since then has killed at least 37,953 people, also mostly civilians, according to data from the health ministry in the Hamas-run territory.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/1k6ecrdo_israel-gaza-war_625x300_06_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[More than 37,000 people have been killed in Gaza since the war broke out last year in October.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-vows-to-stay-in-2024-us-presidential-race-6028557]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["I Am Running": Biden Vows To Stay In Presidential Race]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-vows-to-stay-in-2024-us-presidential-race-6028557]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 04 Jul 2024 00:24:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden vowed to stay in the 2024 presidential race during a call with campaign staff on Wednesday and sought to reassure top Democrats on Capitol Hill that he is fit for re-election, despite his poor debate performance last week.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>U.S. President Joe Biden vowed to stay in the 2024 presidential race during a call with campaign staff on Wednesday and sought to reassure top Democrats on Capitol Hill that he is fit for re-election, despite his disastrous debate performance last week.</p>

<p>Biden dialed in to a call with worried members of his campaign team and told them he wasn't going anywhere, according to two sources familiar with the call.</p>

<p>"I am running," Biden said, adding he remained the Democratic Party leader and wasn't being pushed out, one source said.</p>

<p>The president will meet with Democratic governors on Wednesday at 6:30 p.m. ET (2230 GMT) to reassure them he is up to the job of standard-bearer for the party after the shaky debate with Republican Donald Trump. Some governors will attend virtually.</p>

<p>Asked Wednesday if Biden was considering stepping down, White House Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre said: "Absolutely not."</p>

<p>Biden spoke to Representative Hakeem Jeffries, the minority leader in the House of Representatives, on Tuesday, and Senator Chuck Schumer, the majority leader in the Senate, on Wednesday, a White House official said. He also spoke with House Democrat Jim Clyburn on Wednesday, whose office said afterward they had a long, private conversation.</p>

<p>Clyburn - a kingmaker of sorts within the Democratic Party and who was instrumental in Biden's 2020 win - told CNN on Wednesday that the party should hold a "mini-primary" if Biden steps aside, the first senior party member to talk publicly about how, exactly, replacing Biden as a candidate would work.</p>

<p>Clyburn, who said on Tuesday that he would back Vice President Kamala Harris as the presidential candidate if Biden were to depart, added: "If she were to be the nominee, we need to have a running mate and a strong running mate. And so all of this would give us an opportunity, not just to measure up who would be good to be at the top of the ticket, but also who would be best in second place."</p>

<p>Biden's halting, shaky debate performance against Trump in Atlanta last week sparked calls for him to step aside as the Democratic presidential candidate for the Nov. 5 election. Trump repeated a well-worn slate of falsehoods, including that he won the 2020 election.</p>

<p>Democrats raised fresh concerns about Biden on Tuesday, with one House member calling for him to drop out and former Speaker Nancy Pelosi, a longtime Biden ally, saying it was legitimate to ask whether Biden's performance in Atlanta was an "episode" or a condition.</p>

<p><strong>COULD A GOVERNOR REPLACE BIDEN?</strong></p>

<p>The president has said he was tired after two foreign trips and the White House has said he had a cold. His campaign has held damage control calls with donors, and Biden has shown no signs so far abandoning his quest for a second term.</p>

<p>White House chief of staff Jeff Zients held a call with demoralized White House staff on Wednesday as well, acknowledging that it had been a challenging few days while stressing that the Biden team had a record to be proud of and more work to do.</p>

<p>A handful of governors are potential rivals to Biden if pressure for him to step aside were to increase, but many of them also speak on Biden's behalf on the campaign trail.</p>

<p>Harris is the likely successor if Biden does step aside, multiple sources told Reuters. However Michigan Governor Gretchen Whitmer, California Governor Gavin Newsom, Illinois Governor J.B. Pritzker, Pennsylvania Governor Josh Shapiro and Kentucky Governor Andy Beshear have all been mentioned as possible replacements to Biden if he decided to bow out as the 2024 candidate.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/pfc27auk_joe-biden-cnn-debate_625x300_03_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[U.S. President Joe Biden vowed to stay in the 2024 presidential race.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rishi-sunak-or-labour-rule-after-14-years-uk-heads-to-general-elections-6028373]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Rishi Sunak 2.0 Or Return Of Labour? UK Votes In Historic Polls Today]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rishi-sunak-or-labour-rule-after-14-years-uk-heads-to-general-elections-6028373]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 03 Jul 2024 23:47:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Britain's political leaders made a final frantic push for votes Wednesday on the last day of an election campaign expected to return a Labour government after 14 years of Conservative rule.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Britain's political leaders made a final frantic push for votes Wednesday on the last day of an election campaign expected to return a Labour government after 14 years of Conservative rule.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Rishi Sunak insisted he was still "fighting hard" despite one of his closest allies conceding that the Tories were heading for an "extraordinary landslide" defeat on Thursday.</p>

<p>The Conservatives suffered a further blow at the 11th hour when The Sun tabloid, famous for backing election winners, endorsed Keir Starmer's Labour.</p>

<p>Polls overwhelmingly predict that Labour will win its first general election since 2005 -- making Starmer the party's first prime minister since Gordon Brown left office in 2010.</p>

<p>That outcome would see Britain swing leftwards back to the centre ground after almost a decade and a half of right-wing Conservative governments, dominated first by austerity, then Brexit and a cost-of-living crisis.</p>

<p>Starmer, 61, criss-crossed the UK in a bid to shore up Labour support and warn against complacency in the campaign's final hours.</p>

<p>"If you want change, you have to vote for it," he told reporters at an event in Carmarthenshire, south Wales, where supporters handed out cakes with red ribbons, the colour associated with the party.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"I'm not taking anything for granted," he added, before flying to Scotland on the same plane that took the England football team to the European Championships in Germany.</p>

<p>Sunak, 44, sought to hammer home his oft-repeated warnings that a Labour government would mean tax rises and weaker national security -- jibes that Labour has branded a desperate attempt to cling to power.</p>

<p>The Tories also stepped up their warnings to voters to stop the prospect of Labour winning a "supermajority", which Labour fears is intended to hit turnout.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Sunak ally Mel Stride, the work and pensions secretary, said Wednesday the electorate would "regret" handing Labour "untrammelled" power without an effective Tory opposition.</p>

<p>- Bigger than Blair? -</p>

<p>"If you look at the polls, it is pretty clear that Labour at this stage are heading for an extraordinary landslide on a scale that has probably never, ever been seen in this country before," he told right-wing broadcaster GB News.</p>

<p>But ex-PM Boris Johnson -- ousted by his own colleagues, including Sunak, in 2022 -- staged his first major intervention of the campaign Tuesday, urging supporters not to see the result as a "foregone conclusion".</p>

<p>Labour has enjoyed a consistent 20-point lead in the polls over the past two years with many voters dissatisfied at the Conservatives' handling of a range of issues including public services, immigration and the economy.</p>

<p>Several surveys predict that Labour will win more than the record 418 seats it won when Tony Blair ended 18 years of Conservative rule in 1997.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Labour requires at least 326 seats to secure a majority in the 650-seat parliament.</p>

<p>Voters head to the polls from 7:00 am (0600 GMT), with results expected to start dropping from about 2230 GMT late Thursday into Friday morning.</p>

<p>The vote is Britain's first July election since 1945, when Labour under Clement Attlee defeated the Conservatives of World War II leader Winston Churchill, ushering in a period of transformational social change.</p>

<p>Attlee's government created the modern welfare state, including the state-run National Health Service (NHS), Britain's most cherished institution after the royal family.</p>

<p>- In-tray -</p>

<p>Starmer's "change" agenda is not so radical this time around and promises cautious management of the economy, as part of a long-term growth plan that includes nursing battered public services back to health.</p>

<p>A Labour government would face a formidable to-do list, ranging from spurring anaemic growth to ending NHS strikes and improving post-Brexit ties with Europe.</p>

<p>Some voters simply eye a respite from politics after a chaotic period of five prime ministers, a succession of scandals and Tory infighting between centrists and right-wingers that shows no sign of abating.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Sun called the Conservatives a "divided rabble, more interested in fighting themselves than running the country", adding: "It is time for a change."</p>

<p>Starmer -- the working-class son of a tool maker and a nurse -- has none of the political charisma or popularity of former leader Blair, who presided over that last Labour victory in 2005.</p>

<p>But the former human rights lawyer and chief public prosecutor stands to gain from a country fed up with the Tories, and a feeling of national decline.</p>

<p>Arch-Eurosceptic Nigel Farage hopes the discontent will see him elected an MP at the eighth time of trying, while the Liberal Democrats are expected to gain dozens of seats.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/u4pllgd8_rishi-sunak-and-keir-starmer_625x300_04_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Polls overwhelmingly predict that Labour will win its first general election since 2005.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/myanmar-shop-owners-are-being-jailed-for-giving-a-raise-to-their-employees-heres-why-6027759]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Myanmar Shop Owners Are Being Jailed For Raising Employee Wages. Here's Why]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/myanmar-shop-owners-are-being-jailed-for-giving-a-raise-to-their-employees-heres-why-6027759]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 03 Jul 2024 22:00:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Wage increases are seen as undermining the regime by making people believe that inflation is rising.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Several business owners in Mynamnar have been arrested for giving their employees a raise amidst the country's soaring inflation.&nbsp;One of at least 10 arrested business owners is Pyae Phyo Zaw, whose three mobile phone shops were shut down by military government's soldiers&nbsp;he&nbsp;increased his workers' pay.&nbsp;He was also charged with inciting public unrest, according to a report by the <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/07/01/world/asia/myanmar-junta-inflation-arrests.html">New York Times</a>.&nbsp;</em></p>

<p>A sign posted outside one of his shops declared that it was shut down due to "disrupting the peace and order of the community."</p>

<p>A legal expert explained that there is no prohibition on wage increases in the country. However, wage increases are seen as undermining the regime by making people believe that inflation is rising.&nbsp;They all potentially face three years of imprisonment.</p>

<p>One of Mr Zaw's employees anonymously said, ''We were very grateful for the salary increase, but now the shop is closed and I don't get paid. Ordinary people like us are suffering from high prices, almost to the point of despair.''</p>

<p>Critics have said it is a desperate attempt to control the narrative around the country's economic collapse as it experiences soaring inflation, the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.bangkokpost.com/world/2821836/myanmar-shop-owners-jailed-for-raising-wages"><em>Bangkok Post</em></a><i>&nbsp;</i>reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>''Arresting shop owners because of the increase in prices is not following any law. In Myanmar, the law exists only in name, so from a legal standpoint, everything the junta is doing is absurd,''&nbsp;said human rights lawyer U Kyee Myint.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Notably, the military's takeover in a coup in 2021 and the subsequent popular uprising against its authority have plunged the country into an economic crisis, reversing the progress made during a decade of quasi-democratic governance.</p>

<p>According to a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.worldbank.org/en/news/press-release/2024/06/12/threat-to-livelihoods-deepens-as-myanmar-economic-outlook-remains-weak">World Bank report</a>, Myanmar's economic output has shrunk by 9 per cent since 2019, and poverty has soared to levels not seen for nearly a decade. A third of the population now lives below the poverty line.</p>

<p>“Myanmar's economy post-2021 has moved on from the crisis, journeyed through chaos, and now arrives at what is surely its near collapse as a formally functioning, developing entity,” Australian economist Sean Turnell told the <em>NY Times.&nbsp;</em></p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/05oj9an8_myanmar-_625x300_03_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Critics say it is a desperate attempt to control the narrative around the country's economic collapse]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ex-senator-among-5-killed-in-blast-near-afghan-border-in-pakistan-6027696]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ex Senator Among 5 Killed In Blast Near Afghan Border In Pakistan]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ex-senator-among-5-killed-in-blast-near-afghan-border-in-pakistan-6027696]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 03 Jul 2024 21:47:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A former Pakistan senator running in a by-election was killed on Wednesday along with four others in a targeted attack on their car near the border with Afghanistan.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A former Pakistan senator running in a by-election was killed on Wednesday along with four others in a targeted attack on their car near the border with Afghanistan.</p>

<p>"It appears that a remote-controlled bomb targeted the car carrying the former senator," a district police spokesman told AFP, who asked not to be named because he was not authorised to speak to the media.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"An investigation is currently underway to ascertain the type of explosives used and who was behind it. But miscreants have stepped up their activities in the region lately."&nbsp;</p>

<p>Former senator Hidayatullah Khan, his two companions and two police guards were killed in Bajaur district, just 45 kilometres (28 miles) from the Afghan border, in an area where militancy has been rising since the Taliban took control of Kabul in 2021.</p>

<p>The deadly blast took place ahead of by-elections due on July 11 in which he was running as an independent candidate.</p>

<p>In January, a candidate supporting jailed former prime minister Imran Khan was shot dead in the same district ahead of the general elections, in an attack claimed by the local chapter of the Islamic State group.</p>

<p>Tehreek-e-Taliban Pakistan (TTP) -- a separate group from the Afghan Taliban but with a similar ideology -- and groups linked to it are the most active in the region, largely targeting security officials.&nbsp;</p>

<p>No group has claimed responsibility for Wednesday's attack, which the TTP denied involvement in.</p>

<p>Last month, the government announced the launch of a new counterterrorism operation to support armed forces in their fight against militancy.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-12/4cv2tjk8_pakistan-police-karachi-afp-file-photo_625x300_11_December_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["An investigation is currently underway to ascertain the type of explosives used."]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/impostors-raising-funds-by-claiming-ltte-chief-velupillai-prabhakaran-is-alive-says-his-family-6027515]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Impostors Raising Funds By Claiming LTTE Chief Is Alive, Says His Family]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/impostors-raising-funds-by-claiming-ltte-chief-velupillai-prabhakaran-is-alive-says-his-family-6027515]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 03 Jul 2024 21:15:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A "mafia gang" which wants to use Prabhakaran as a "brand name", collects funds from Tamils living around the world is operating at a major scale, said Karthic Manoharan, the son of Prabhakaran's elder brother Velupillai Manoharan.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Labelling it as a "major scam", the extended family of Liberation Tigers of Tamil Eelam (LTTE) chief Velupillai Prabhakaran has urged all Tamils in India and around the world not to fall into the trap laid out by certain elements in the diaspora fraternity who have been collecting millions of dollars by saying that the slain Tamil leader is still alive.</p>

<p>Karthic Manoharan, the son of Prabhakaran's elder brother Velupillai Manoharan, told IANS that a "mafia gang" which wants to use Prabhakaran as a "brand name" and collects funds from Tamils living around the world is operating at a major scale.</p>

<p>V. Prabhakaran was killed during the final stages of Sri Lanka's 26-year-long bloody war against the LTTE, which was crushed by the Lankan security forces in May 2009.</p>

<p>"Give due respect to the dead. Not a penny given to the gang of fraudsters, who had been claiming that Prabhakran is alive, will go to the family or the poor and suffering Tamils in war-ravaged Sri Lanka, and instead end up in their pockets," said Karthic, the 43-year-old nephew of the late LTTE supreme leader.</p>

<p>Branding the alleged fraudsters as "liars", Karthic named some Indian Tamil leaders and Lankan-born Tamil Eelam campaigners for running a campaign to resurrect his dead uncle Prabhakaran and his only daughter Dwaraka Prabhakaran.</p>

<p>Manoharan's family has maintained an extremely low profile since they left Sri Lanka in 1983. They finally broke their silence after some diaspora groups in Switzerland enacted a fake drama with an AI-manipulated video speech of Dwaraka Prabhakaran on 'Maaveerar Naal' or 'Great Heroes Day' on November 27, 2023.</p>

<p>"We need to put an end to this nonsense. My uncle with his entire family died during the last stages of the war. This had been confirmed and if any of them were alive, they would have contacted us as we all were quite close and he used to call us from Sri Lanka," the nephew said.</p>

<p>He added that the final conversation his family had with Prabhakaran was in 2008, a year before the war came to an end.</p>

<p>"My uncle, in what turned out to be his last call, said that the situation was really bad in Sri Lanka," Karthic said.</p>

<p>Prabhakaran's parents were taken to India by Karthic's father Manoharan in 1983 along with the rest of the family after the ethnic war broke out in Sri Lanka, with the military hunting for the LTTE leader.</p>

<p>The family lived in Tamil Nadu for 13 years till 1998 and then migrated to Denmark through a UN agency.</p>

<p>"My father was planning to start a business in India but then Rajiv Gandhi's assassination happened and my uncle was the suspect. So, my dad was asked to leave India," the Tamil rebel leader's nephew told IANS.</p>

<p>The family later approached the UNHCR and moved to the Scandinavian country in 1996 which accepted their plea first.</p>

<p>However, Karthic said that because the family was related to the LTTE leader, they received "ill-treatment" from some diaspora groups in Denmark who had been amassing money in the name of the rebel movement.</p>

<p>"Having travelled from India, we were also branded as RAW agents," said Karthic, who expressed gratitude to the Indian government for allowing the family to stay in the country for more than a decade.</p>

<p>Karthic initially believed that his grandparents were also killed during the last days of the war in May 2009. The family later came to know that they were alive and had been kept in an army camp until his grandfather's death was announced in 2010. Prabhakaran's mother also died later.</p>

<p>One of Karthic's aunts (sister of Prabhakaran) still lives in India with her family while another resides in Canada.</p>

<p>However, he said, the extended family still cannot meet each other or travel due to many visa issues and fear of not being able to return.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/prabhakaran-650_625x300_1527421456211.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jeff-bezos-to-sell-5-billion-amazon-shares-after-stock-hits-record-high-6027431]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Jeff Bezos To Sell $5 Billion Amazon Shares After Stock Hits Record High]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jeff-bezos-to-sell-5-billion-amazon-shares-after-stock-hits-record-high-6027431]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 03 Jul 2024 21:01:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Amazon founder and executive chair Jeff Bezos is planning to sell almost $5 billion worth of shares in the e-commerce giant, a regulatory filing showed, after its stock hit a record high.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Amazon founder and executive chair Jeff Bezos is planning to sell almost $5 billion worth of shares in the e-commerce giant, a regulatory filing showed, after its stock hit a record high.</p>

<p>The proposed sale of 25 million shares was disclosed in a notice filed after market hours on Tuesday. The stock had hit an all-time high of $200.43 during the session. It has jumped more than 30% so far this year, outpacing the 4% gain in the Dow Jones Industrial Average index.</p>

<p>After the sale plan, Bezos would own about 912 million Amazon shares, or 8.8% of the outstanding stock.</p>

<p>He sold shares worth roughly $8.5 billion in February, after the stock rallied 80% in 2023.</p>

<p>Bezos is ranked the second-richest person in the world with a net worth of $214.4 billion, according to Forbes. He is also the founder of space company Blue Origin, which launched a six-person crew to the edge of space in May.</p>

<p>Amazon posted upbeat first-quarter results in April, as the Seattle-based technology giant rode the artificial intelligence wave. The company recently replaced Adam Selipsky as the head of its cloud computing unit with insider Matt Garman.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/5jp369v8_jeff-bezos_625x300_03_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[He sold shares worth roughly $8.5 billion in February, after the stock rallied 80% in 2023.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/artwork-created-nearly-51-200-years-ago-discovered-in-indonesian-cave-6027299]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Artwork Created Nearly 51,200 Years Ago Discovered In Indonesian Cave]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/artwork-created-nearly-51-200-years-ago-discovered-in-indonesian-cave-6027299]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 03 Jul 2024 20:41:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[On the ceiling of a limestone cave on the Indonesian island of Sulawesi, scientists have discovered artwork depicting three human-like figures interacting with a wild pig in what they have determined is the world's oldest-known confidently dated]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On the ceiling of a limestone cave on the Indonesian island of Sulawesi, scientists have discovered artwork depicting three human-like figures interacting with a wild pig in what they have determined is the world's oldest-known confidently dated cave painting - created at least 51,200 years ago.</p>

<p>The researchers used a new scientific approach to determine the minimum age of the newly disclosed painting inside the Leang Karampuang cave in the Maros-Pangkep region of South Sulawesi province by using a laser to date a type of crystal called calcium carbonate that formed naturally on top of the painting.</p>

<p>"The method is a significant improvement over other methods and should revolutionize rock art dating worldwide," said Maxime Aubert, a specialist in archaeological science at Griffith University in Australia and one of the leaders of the research published on Wednesday in the journal Nature.</p>

<p>The scene, dominated by a representation of a pig measuring 36 inches by 15 inches (92 cm by 38 cm) that is standing upright along with three smaller human-like figures, is painted in a single shade of dark red pigment. There are other images of pigs in the cave as well.</p>

<p>The researchers interpreted the painting as a narrative scene, which they said would make it the oldest-known evidence of storytelling in art.</p>

<p>"The three human-like figures and the pig figure were clearly not depicted in isolation in separate parts of the rock art panel," said Griffith University archeologist Adam Brumm, another of the study leaders.</p>

<p>"Rather, the juxtaposition of the figures - how they are positioned in relation to each other - and the manner in which they are interacting were clearly deliberate, and it conveys an unmistakable sense of action. There is something happening between these figures. A story is being told. Obviously, we don't know what that story was," Brumm added.</p>

<p>The researchers used the same dating method to reassess the age of another Sulawesi cave painting from a site called Leang Bulu' Sipong 4, also depicting a narrative scene, this time depicting apparent part-human, part-animal figures hunting pigs and dwarf buffalo. It turned out to be at least 48,000 years old, upwards of 4,000 years earlier than previously thought.</p>

<p>"We, as humans, define ourselves as a species that tells stories, and these are the oldest evidence of us doing that," Aubert said.</p>

<p>In the Leang Karampuang painting, the interaction between the human-like figures and the pig, a species still inhabiting the island, is somewhat cryptic.</p>

<p>"Two of these figures are holding objects of some kind, and at least one figure seems to be reaching towards the pig's face. Another figure is positioned directly above the pig's head in an upside down position," Brumm said.</p>

<p>Little is known about the people who created the Sulawesi cave paintings. Aubert said the paintings may turn out to be older than the minimum age determined by the new testing and possibly date to the first Homo sapiens wave to sweep through the region, eventually reaching Australia about 65,000 years ago, on their migration out of Africa.</p>

<p>Until now, the oldest-known cave painting was one at Leang Tedongnge cave, also in Sulawesi, from at least 45,500 years ago.</p>

<p>The Leang Karampuang painting, the researchers said, predates the cave paintings of Europe, the earliest of which is at El Castillo in Spain, dating to about 40,800 years ago.</p>

<p>There is a hand stencil painting from Spain's Maltravieso cave that some scientists have dated to around 64,000 years ago and attributed to Neanderthals. Other scientists have disputed the age of the painting and have argued that it was created by Homo sapiens.</p>

<p>"This discovery of very old cave art in Indonesia drives home the point that Europe was not the birthplace of cave art, as had long been assumed. It also suggests that storytelling was a much older part of human history, and the history of art in particular, than previously recognized," Brumm said.</p>

<p>"The earliest Sulawesi rock art is not 'simple,'" Aubert added. "It is quite advanced and shows the mental capacity of people at the time."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ti3mip4g_worlds-oldest-painting_625x300_03_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The researchers used a new scientific approach to determine the minimum age of the painting.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-russia-ties-at-high-level-xi-jinping-after-meeting-old-friend-vladimir-putin-in-kazakhstan-6027005]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["China-Russia Ties At High Level": Xi After Meeting "Old Friend" Putin]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-russia-ties-at-high-level-xi-jinping-after-meeting-old-friend-vladimir-putin-in-kazakhstan-6027005]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 03 Jul 2024 19:59:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russian President Vladimir Putin told Chinese leader Xi Jinping on Wednesday that relations between Beijing and Moscow were stronger than ever before.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russian President Vladimir Putin told Chinese leader Xi Jinping on Wednesday that relations between Beijing and Moscow were stronger than ever before.</p>

<p>The pair met on the sidelines of the Shanghai Cooperation Organisation (SCO) summit in the Kazakh capital of Astana -- a regional political and economic bloc that the two leaders see as a counterweight to US "hegemony" in international affairs.</p>

<p>Putin hailed the group as "strengthening its role as one of the key pillars of a fair multipolar world order" in opening remarks of a meeting with Xi that were published on Russian state TV.</p>

<p>Alongside Russia and China, four Central Asian states, India, Iran and Pakistan are members of the SOC.</p>

<p>Beijing has become Moscow's key political and economic partner since it invaded Ukraine in February 2022, triggering a raft of Western sanctions.</p>

<p>"Russian-Chinese relations, our comprehensive partnership and strategic cooperation, are experiencing their best period in history," Putin said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In his brief opening comments, Xi called Putin his "old friend" and said Sino-Russian relations were at a "high level."</p>

<p>"In the face of the turbulent international situation and external environment, the two sides should continue to uphold the original aspiration of friendship for generations to come," Xi said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/mkp8a12o_putin-and-xi_625x300_16_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[In his brief opening comments, Xi Jinping called Vladimir Putin his "old friend".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/discussed-global-hotspots-s-jaishankar-meets-un-chief-in-kazakhstan-6026916]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Discussed Global Hotspots": S Jaishankar Meets UN Chief In Kazakhstan]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/discussed-global-hotspots-s-jaishankar-meets-un-chief-in-kazakhstan-6026916]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 03 Jul 2024 19:47:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar on Wednesday met UN chief Antonio Guterres and discussed global hotspots and their larger implications apart from the reform of the UNSC.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar on Wednesday met UN chief Antonio Guterres and discussed global hotspots and their larger implications apart from the reform of the UNSC.</p>

<p>Mr Jaishankar, who is here to represent India at the annual summit of the Shanghai Cooperation Organisation and carrying out various bilateral meetings on the sidelines, also met his Belarusian and Tajikistan counterparts Maksim Ryzhenkov and Sirojiddin Muhriddin respectively.</p>

<p>"Always a pleasure to meet UNSG @antonioguterres. Appreciate his insights on the state of the world. Discussed global hotspots and their larger implications," Mr Jaishankar posted on the social media platform X.</p>

<p>He further said that he spoke about the reform of the United Nations Security Council (UNSC), preparations for the upcoming 'Summit of the Future' in September, and future prospects for meaningful India-UN partnership.</p>

<p>Earlier, he had bilateral meetings with his counterparts from Tajikistan, Belarus and Russia.</p>

<p>"Glad to meet Tajik FM Sirojiddin Muhriddin today in Astana. Took stock of our bilateral partnership and cooperation on multilateral forums. Appreciate the exchange of views on the regional situation," Jaishankar posted on the social media platform X along with the photos of the meeting.</p>

<p>"Pleased to meet FM Maksim Ryzhenkov of Belarus today. Welcome Belarus to the SCO as its newest member. Discussed our bilateral relationship and its future growth potential," the Minister posted earlier on X.</p>

<p>The meeting of the two Foreign Ministers came days after the first-ever India-Belarus Consular Dialogue that was held on June 28 in Minsk.</p>

<p>"The Indian delegation was led by Dr Aman Puri, JS (CPV), while the Belarusian delegation was led by Andrei Kozhan, Head of General Directorate for Consular Affairs, Ministry of Foreign Affairs of Belarus," a statement from the MEA said on Tuesday.</p>

<p>With nine member states -- India, Iran, Kazakhstan, China, Kyrgyz, Pakistan, Russia, Tajikistan and Uzbekistan - the SCO has emerged as an influential economic and security bloc and one of the largest trans-regional international organisations.</p>

<p>Belarus will be the 10th nation to join as a member.</p>

<p>Kazakhstan is hosting the summit in its capacity as the current chair of the grouping.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/s44pt4uo_s-jaishankar-un-chief_625x300_03_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/delta-flight-makes-emergency-landing-after-passengers-served-contaminated-food-6026901]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Delta Flight Makes Emergency Landing After Passengers Served Spoiled Food]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/delta-flight-makes-emergency-landing-after-passengers-served-contaminated-food-6026901]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 03 Jul 2024 19:44:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The airline has not disclosed how the contamination was detected, nor have they provided information on how many of the 277 passengers consumed the meal.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Delta Airlines flight was forced to make an emergency landing in New York after passengers received a meal service that was reportedly "spoiled." According to the <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/07/03/us-news/delta-flight-forced-to-make-emergency-landing-at-jfk-over-contaminated-food/">New York Post</a></em>, the A330 plane, which had 277 customers on board, left Detroit Metropolitan Wayne County Airport just before 11 pm on Tuesday. However, it was diverted to John F. Kennedy International Airport after it was discovered that a portion of the main cabin in-flight meals were spoiled.</p>

<p>According to FlightRadar24 data, the Delta plane was over Saint Pierre and Miquelon, a French archipelago south of Canada's Newfoundland, when it was redirected. The crew reportedly decided to land the aircraft after consulting with medical experts.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the airline has not disclosed how the contamination was detected, nor have they provided information on how many of the 277 passengers consumed the meal or whether any of them exhibited symptoms of food poisoning.</p>

<p>The plane&nbsp;landed safely at JFK at 4 am on July 3.&nbsp;12 passengers were evaluated, but refused medical attention or transportation to the hospital, the Fire Department of New York told <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/travel/airline-news/2024/07/03/delta-flight-emergency-landing-spoiled-food/74288805007/">USA Today</a>.</em></p>

<p>Delta is investigating the incident and has issued an apology to its consumers.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In a statement,&nbsp;Delta Airlines confirmed the incident and said, ''Delta flight 136 from Detroit to Amsterdam diverted to New York's JFK early Wednesday morning after reports that a portion of the Main Cabin in-flight meal service was spoiled.</p>

<p>Medical crews met the aircraft to treat any affected passengers and crew members. Delta's Food Safety team has engaged our suppliers to immediately isolate the product and launch a thorough investigation into the incident. This is not the service Delta is known for, and we sincerely apologize to our customers for the inconvenience and delay in their travels.''</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-06/ljfeqp7o_delta-flight_625x300_19_June_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The crew reportedly decided to land the aircraft after consulting with medical experts.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/alarm-bell-un-rights-chief-volker-turk-on-rising-hate-speeches-during-elections-6026888]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Alarm Bell": UN Rights Chief On Rising Hate Speeches During Elections]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/alarm-bell-un-rights-chief-volker-turk-on-rising-hate-speeches-during-elections-6026888]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 03 Jul 2024 19:42:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The UN rights chief voiced alarm Wednesday at a hardening of rhetoric, including hate speech and dehumanising language against migrants and other minorities, linked to elections in Europe and elsewhere.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The UN rights chief voiced alarm Wednesday at a hardening of rhetoric, including hate speech and dehumanising language against migrants and other minorities, linked to elections in Europe and elsewhere.</p>

<p>"This is an alarm bell," Volker Turk told reporters in Geneva.</p>

<p>He warned of rising populism, hate speech and scapegoating as a record number of countries are holding elections this year.</p>

<p>While refusing to comment on specific election campaigns playing out, as crucial votes loom in Britain and France, he decried that Europe had seen "a rise of hate speech, a rise in discriminatory discourse".</p>

<p>Turk said he was "worried" listening to the rhetoric surround recent votes, including the European parliament elections last month, which handed significant gains to far-right parties.</p>

<p>"I'm always worried when I hear narratives that denigrate the other, that dehumanise the other, that make scapegoats of migrants or refugees or asylum seekers or minority groups," he said.</p>

<p>"We need to be very vigilant, because especially history tells us, in particular in Europe, that the vilification of the other, that the denigration of the other is a harbinger for worse to come."</p>

<p>Turk insisted that those in power should make it very clear: "there should be zero tolerance for all hate speech".</p>

<p>Europe was not the only place Turk said he was concerned about, pointing to scenarios playing out around the world, including around the campaigns in the United States and in India.</p>

<p>He urged voters to study the programmes of political parties to ensure they respect human rights, "and that means the human rights of everyone".</p>

<p>While criticising the populists willing to use denigration and scapegoating to win political points, Turk said mainstream parties bore responsibility too.</p>

<p>"The traditional political parties never are self-reflective about how they actually could do their job in order to respond to legitimate grievances that populations and constituencies have," he said.</p>

<p>"We need to call out the hate speech and the dehumanisation and the scapegoating and the politics of distraction," he said.</p>

<p>"But we also have to push politics to do its job better."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-11/me0j4hf_volker-turk_625x300_16_November_23.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["This is an alarm bell," Volker Turk told reporters in Geneva.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/moscow-swelters-at-32-degree-celsius-beats-record-set-in-1917-6026784]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Moscow Swelters At 32 Degree Celsius, Beats Record Set In 1917]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/moscow-swelters-at-32-degree-celsius-beats-record-set-in-1917-6026784]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 03 Jul 2024 19:29:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Moscow and the surrounding region sweltered Wednesday as temperatures soared to levels unseen in over a century, with the state weather monitor warning of dangerously hot nights.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Moscow and the surrounding region sweltered Wednesday as temperatures soared to levels unseen in over a century, with the state weather monitor warning of dangerously hot nights.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Temperatures in the Russian capital hit 32.5 Celsius (90.5 Fahrenheit) Wednesday, beating a record established in 1917, the director of Rosgidromet weather service, Roman Vilfand, said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Vilfand told RIA Novosti news agency that in the next few nights, the temperature will not fall below 24.5 degrees, saying these "Egyptian nights" were dangerous because they did not allow people to recover from high daytime temperatures.</p>

<p>He said he expected the temperature to go down by 10 degrees in the following days, with storms and strong winds, before the heat returns next week. &nbsp;</p>

<p>Muscovites tried to cool down in public fountains and parks.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"It's very hard," 70-year-old Monira Galimova, who looked tired, told AFP as she sat at a bus stop.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"We do not sleep at night... It's very difficult, especially for our age group."&nbsp;</p>

<p>Olga Kryshina, a 34-year-old working in property refurbishments, sat to cool down by a fountain near the Bolshoi Theatre.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Unlike many Muscovites who have escaped to their traditional summer "dacha" country houses, Kryshina said she had to stay in the city for work and was only "dreaming of travelling" outside of urban areas.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Abnormal temperatures "more than 7 degrees above the climatic norm" are expected until the end of the week, Rosgidromet said on its website.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The heatwave has hit the Moscow region as well as the southern and western Kursk, Belgorod and Voronezh regions.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ae640rl_moscow-heatwave-_625x300_03_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Muscovites tried to cool down in public fountains and parks.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ex-pak-pm-imran-khan-seeks-permission-from-court-to-meet-his-sons-in-jail-6026465]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ex Pak PM Imran Khan Seeks Permission From Court To Meet His Sons In Jail]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ex-pak-pm-imran-khan-seeks-permission-from-court-to-meet-his-sons-in-jail-6026465]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 03 Jul 2024 18:43:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Pakistan's anti-terrorism court in Rawalpindi has asked the government and jail administration to respond to Pakistan Tehreek-e-Insaf chief Imran Khan's request to meet his sons, Pakistan-based daily, The Express Tribune reported on Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pakistan's anti-terrorism court in Rawalpindi has asked the government and jail administration to respond to Pakistan Tehreek-e-Insaf chief Imran Khan's request to meet his sons, Pakistan-based daily, The Express Tribune reported on Wednesday.</p>

<p>The former Prime Minister filed a petition seeking permission to meet his sons, Qasim and Sulaiman, in Adiala Jail.</p>

<p>In his petition, Mr Khan argued that meeting his sons is his constitutional and legal right, emphasising that the meeting would be of a familial nature.</p>

<p>"I wish to meet my sons, Qasim and Sulaiman. This is my constitutional and legal right," Mr Khan stated.</p>

<p>The court has directed the government, the Ministry of Interior, and the jail administration to provide their responses by July 5. The hearing has been adjourned until July 7.</p>

<p>The former Pakistani Prime Minister was jailed on January 30 for 10 years in a case in which he was charged with leaking state secrets. He is already serving a three-year jail term after being convicted of corruption. Imran Khan called all the charges against him politically motivated.</p>

<p>He had urged the public to "take revenge for every injustice with your vote on February 8 while remaining peaceful" in a statement released on his X (formerly Twitter) account. "Tell them that we are not sheep that can be driven with a stick," he added.</p>

<p>Former foreign minister Shah Mahmood Qureshi, vice chairman of Imran Khan's Pakistan Tehreek-e-Insaf party, was also sentenced to 10 years in prison by the special court set up inside Adiala Jail in Rawalpindi.</p>

<p>The case involves the alleged leaking of secret diplomatic correspondence sent by Pakistan's ambassador on Washington to Islamabad when Khan was Prime Minister.</p>

<p>It relates to his appearance at a rally in March 2022, a month before Khan was ousted from power in a parliamentary vote of no confidence. He appeared on stage, waving a piece of paper that he says showed a foreign conspiracy against him.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/t32m7b7o_imran-khan-reuters_625x300_06_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["This is my constitutional and legal right," Mr Khan stated.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-independence-day-2024-will-banks-stock-markets-be-open-on-july-4th-check-here-6026244]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Independence Day 2024: What's Open And Closed On July 4th? Check Here]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-independence-day-2024-will-banks-stock-markets-be-open-on-july-4th-check-here-6026244]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 03 Jul 2024 18:13:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Independence Day arrives Thursday and several offices and businesses will be closed to commemorate the holiday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.ndtv.com/webstories/feature/fourth-of-july-all-about-americas-independence-day-19715">Fourth of July</a>&nbsp;will mark the 278th anniversary of the founding of the United States (US). Since the adoption of the Declaration of Independence by the Continental Congress on July 4, 1776, this day has been an important federal holiday in the US. In 1776, on this day, American colonies gained independence from British rule. Since then, every year, parades, fireworks, carnivals, fairs, political speeches and numerous ceremonies mark this day.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Notably, Independence Day this year arrives Thursday and several offices and businesses will be closed to commemorate the holiday.</p>

<h3><strong>What Will Be Closed?</strong></h3>

<ul>
	<li>All federal offices will be closed, including from the legislature to the courthouse.</li>
	<li>State offices will also be closed, including courts and the legislature.</li>
	<li>All major banks, including Capital One, Bank of America, PNC, Truist, CitiBank, and JPMorgan Chase, will be closed, as per&nbsp;USA Today.</li>
	<li>Stock markets will be closed.&nbsp;The Nasdaq and the New York Stock Exchange will also get the day off.</li>
	<li>Post offices will be closed on July 4 and there will be no mail delivery, caller service or Post Office Box service available for the holiday.&nbsp;</li>
	<li>There will be no UPS pickup or delivery service and some store locations will be closed</li>
	<li>Public libraries,&nbsp;U.S. warehouses and the Department of Motor Vehicles will also be closed.</li>
</ul>

<h3><strong>What Will Be Open?</strong></h3>

<ul>
	<li>Online banking services and ATMs will be available. Capital One Cafes will stay operational for basic banking needs and services.</li>
	<li>FedEx&nbsp;will offer modified service on FedEx Office while FedEx Custom Critical will remain open.&nbsp;UPS Express Critical&nbsp;service will also be available.</li>
	<li>Most grocery stores under Kroger which includes Fred Meyer, Dillons, Food 4 Less, Ralphs and QFC will be open during their regular hours on July 4. Walmart and Target will also maintain regular operating hours, as per <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/07/03/business/fourth-of-july-open-closed/index.html">CNN.</a></em></li>
	<li>Most Whole Foods stores will be open during normal hours, while Trader Joe's locations will close at 5 pm.</li>
	<li>Major pharmacy chains like CVS and Walgreens will likely be open, though some locations might have adjusted hours.</li>
	<li>Museums and zoos will mostly be open.</li>
</ul>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/knssf6ao_us-independence-day-2024_625x300_03_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[All federal offices will be closed, including from the legislature to the courthouse.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/man-in-china-poses-as-doctor-at-prestigious-hospital-dupes-girlfriend-of-rs-3-crore-6026083]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Chinese Man Poses As Doctor, Dupes Girlfriend Of Rs 3 Crore]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/man-in-china-poses-as-doctor-at-prestigious-hospital-dupes-girlfriend-of-rs-3-crore-6026083]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 03 Jul 2024 17:53:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[During their six-year relationship, Zhang portrayed himself as an obstetrician-gynaecologist at a prestigious Shanghai hospital.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p data-qa="Component-Component" datatype="p">A man in China was convicted of fraud for swindling 2.6 million yuan (about Rs 3 crore) from his girlfriend by pretending to be a doctor at a prestigious hospital.&nbsp;Zhang, originally employed at a hotel, received an 11-year, six-month prison sentence and a 250,000 yuan (Rs 29,22,396) fine for his actions.</p>

<p data-qa="Component-Component" datatype="p">The court made the details of the case public in May without specifying the exact dates of the incidents. According to the <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3265279/chinese-man-poses-doctor-dupes-girlfriend-out-us360000-pair-often-meet-hospital-grounds">South China Morning Post,</a></em> Zhang initiated the deception in 2016 after meeting his girlfriend Huang, who was employed at a shopping mall.&nbsp;</p>

<p>During their six-year relationship, Zhang portrayed himself as an obstetrician-gynaecologist at a prestigious Shanghai hospital. He also claimed that he had graduated from a renowned medical school in China. He crafted a compelling image of a "successful professional," and Huang never questioned his narrative. They started dating three months after their initial meeting.</p>

<p>However, one potential warning sign was Zhang's habit of postponing Huang's requests to visit him at the hospital attributing it to a hectic schedule filled with clinical checkups or surgeries. As their relationship deepened, they frequently met for dates on the hospital lawn.</p>

<p>By November 2016, however, Zhang developed a gambling addiction and accrued significant debts. He started taking money from Huang in the name of home investment and spent it on gambling and paying off his debts.&nbsp;During their relationship, Huang transferred more than 2.6 million yuan to Zhang.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Huang's family grew concerned as Zhang began avoiding repayment of the money. Eventually, Huang, frustrated with the situation, verified Zhang's employment with the hospital, only to find out that he was not employed there.</p>

<p data-qa="Component-Component" datatype="p">During the trial, the prosecutor said: ''While love is beautiful, one must also be wary of sweet traps''.</p>

<p data-qa="Component-Component" datatype="p">Many social media users sympathised with Huang after details of the case went viral on social media. One user wrote, ''She was too blinded by love.''</p>

<p data-qa="Component-Component" datatype="p"></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/c0qbe05o_man-poses-as-doctor-_625x300_03_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Zhang portrayed himself as an obstetrician-gynaecologist at a prestigious Shanghai hospital.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-what-happens-in-the-uk-general-election-6025841]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: What Happens In The UK General Election]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-what-happens-in-the-uk-general-election-6025841]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 03 Jul 2024 17:24:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Britain will hold a parliamentary election on July 4 which opinion polls indicate will hand power to Keir Starmer's Labour Party and end 14 years of Conservative Party-led government.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Britain will hold a parliamentary election on July 4 which opinion polls indicate will hand power to Keir Starmer's Labour Party and end 14 years of Conservative Party-led government.</p>

<p><strong>HOW IS THE WINNER DECIDED?</strong></p>

<p>To win outright, one party needs to win at least 326 out of the 650 parliamentary seats. The leader of that party becomes prime minister.</p>

<p>In each of the 650 constituencies, voters elect a local candidate who is usually affiliated with a larger political party. Voters choose one candidate and the candidate with the most votes wins the seat.</p>

<p>A hung parliament occurs if no single party wins a majority. In this case the incumbent prime minister remains in power and is given the first chance to form a government either by building a coalition or governing with a minority.</p>

<p><strong>WHAT IS A SUPERMAJORITY?</strong></p>

<p>During the Conservative Party's campaign, it warned that Labour could win a 'supermajority' that would embolden it to make more radical reforms than those set out in its manifesto.</p>

<p>In some democracies, a supermajority is a legally defined threshold, higher than a simple majority, required to make major changes such as to a constitution.</p>

<p>In Britain, however, there is no definition of a supermajority that gives governments any special powers and the term has no clear meaning in its political lexicon.</p>

<p><strong>WHEN WILL THE RESULTS BE ANNOUNCED?</strong></p>

<p>An exit poll is released by broadcasters immediately after voting ends at 10 p.m. (2100 GMT).</p>

<p>Vote counting begins immediately and first results come within hours. Most are declared overnight and the outcome is usually clear between 5 a.m. and 7 a.m.</p>

<p><strong>WHEN WILL THE NEW PRIME MINISTER TAKE OFFICE?</strong></p>

<p>Once the overall result is clear, and if the governing party has lost, the prime minister would be expected to tender his resignation to the king on Friday.</p>

<p>The leader of the winning party will then meet the king, who will request he or she form a government. They will then head to Downing Street to make a speech to the British public as the new prime minister.</p>

<p><strong>WHAT HAPPENS ONCE A NEW PRIME MINISTER IS IN PLACE?</strong></p>

<p>The new prime minister will begin appointing ministers, starting with senior positions.</p>

<p>Parliament is scheduled to return on July 9. The Speaker of the House of Commons - parliament's lower chamber - will be elected from among members of parliament (MPs).</p>

<p>Each MP will then in turn swear the oath of allegiance to the king or make a solemn affirmation. This usually takes a few days.</p>

<p>The State Opening of Parliament and King's Speech, setting out a government's programme of legislation for the parliamentary session, is due to take place on July 17, although this date could be changed by a new government.</p>

<p><strong>WHO CAN VOTE AND HOW?</strong></p>

<p>Voters must be aged 18 or over on polling day, and be either a British citizen, Irish citizen or qualifying Commonwealth citizen.</p>

<p>Close to 50 million people are registered to vote. Polling stations open from 7 a.m. to 10 p.m. (0600-2100 GMT). Votes can be cast in person, by post, or through a proxy.</p>

<p>Voters must take photo I.D. with them to vote, the first national election at which that has been required.</p>

<p>Overseas British citizens will also get to vote regardless of how long they have been living outside the country.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/mv7kjq3g_uk-election-_625x300_03_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A hung parliament occurs if no single party wins a majority.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/stop-labour-partys-supermajority-rishi-sunaks-final-appeal-ahead-of-uk-polls-6025468]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Stop Labour's Supermajority": Rishi Sunak's Final Appeal Ahead Of UK Polls]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/stop-labour-partys-supermajority-rishi-sunaks-final-appeal-ahead-of-uk-polls-6025468]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 03 Jul 2024 16:40:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Stop Labour's "supermajority" is the final message UK PM Rishi Sunak is trying to drive home on Wednesday, the final day of campaigning ahead of polling day on Thursday]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Stop Labour's "supermajority" is the final message British Prime Minister Rishi Sunak is trying to drive home on Wednesday, the final day of campaigning ahead of polling day on Thursday, as most of the incumbent Conservatives seem to have all but conceded defeat in the general election.</p>

<p>"This is what unites us. We need to stop the Labour supermajority that will put up your taxes. The only way to do that is to vote Conservative tomorrow," said 44-year-old Rishi Sunak on social media, as he focused on drumming up support in the last few hours of the campaign trail.</p>

<p>With his party trailing far behind the Keir Starmer-led Labour Party, the British Indian leader and his team's strategy seems to be to canvas their traditional voters to ensure a strong enough turnout in the polls on Thursday and narrow the gap of their widely expected defeat after Tory victories in the last three elections.</p>

<p>"I totally accept where the polls are at the moment means that tomorrow is likely to see the largest Labour landslide majority - the largest majority that this country has ever seen. Much bigger than 1997," Rishi Sunak's Work and Pensions Secretary Mel Stride told the BBC.</p>

<p>"I have accepted that where the polls are at the moment... that we are therefore tomorrow highly likely to be in a situation where [Labour has] the largest majority that any party has ever achieved," he said, effectively conceding his party's defeat.</p>

<p>It is being seen as a fear tactic to jolt Tory voters into action, with the hope of keeping the Labour majority under that won by former prime minister Tony Blair led Labour Party in 1997 of 179 seats.</p>

<p>"Thursday's vote is now all about forming a strong enough Opposition. One needs to read the writing on the wall: it's over, and we need to prepare for the reality and frustration of the Opposition," Suella Braverman, sacked as home secretary by Rishi Sunak, told 'The Telegraph'.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, former prime minister Boris Johnson - not exactly a close ally of Rishi Sunak ever since the partygate scandal of COVID pandemic law-breaking parties - was also rolled out by the party at a campaign event in London to warn against a "sledgehammer majority" being handed to the Keir Starmer led Labour Party.</p>

<p>"When Rishi asked me to come and help, of course I couldn't say no. We're all here because we love our country," Boris Johnson told a cheering Tory crowd.</p>

<p>"They can achieve nothing in this election except to usher in the most left-wing Labour government since the war with a huge majority, and we must not let it happen," he warned.</p>

<p>The Labour Party, meanwhile, is keen to override this message of victory as a foregone conclusion a day before the polls to fight against any complacency within the ranks and among its own voter base.</p>

<p>"People are saying the polls predict the future - they don't predict the future, every single vote counts, every single vote has to be earned... It isn't 'job done'," said Keir Starmer.</p>

<p>Polling experts have forecast a low turnout, which stood at 67 per cent in the last general election in December 2019 when Boris Johnson won a solid majority on his "get Brexit done" message.</p>

<p>On Thursday, polling booths will open across the country at 7am local time and close at 10pm local time as voters elect their MPs for the UK Parliament's 650 constituencies - with 326 required for a majority and to avert a hung Parliament.</p>

<p>All eyes will then be on the election night exit poll at 10pm, which gives a fair snapshot of what can be expected nationally as the counting commences and centres up and down the UK. If opinion polls are to be believed, the incumbent Tories are in line to win anywhere between 53 and 150 seats, with Labour projected to win a landslide.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/pvs0d6d8_rishi-sunak-afp-_625x300_03_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[UK will vote on July 4. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>