<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Tue, 12 Nov 2024 23:30:34 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/insight-these-countries-offer-assisted-dying-or-are-considering-it-know-the-law-7004789]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[These Countries Offer 'Assisted Dying' Or Are Considering It. How It's Done]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/insight-these-countries-offer-assisted-dying-or-are-considering-it-know-the-law-7004789]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 12 Nov 2024 23:14:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Britain is to debate whether to legalise assisted dying for the terminally ill, potentially paving the way for the law to change. Below is a list of countries which allow people to choose to end their lives or are considering doing so.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<ol class="CetSht_ol">
	<li class="CetSht_li"><strong>SWITZERLAND </strong>- Switzerland legalised assisted dying in 1942 on the condition the motive is not selfish, making it the first country in the world to permit the practice. Doctors can prescribe drugs and administer them or had them over for self-administration. A number of Swiss organisations such as Dignitas offer their services to foreign nationals.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li"><strong>UNITED STATES</strong> - Medical aid in dying, also known as physician assisted dying is legal in 10 states: California, Colorado, Hawaii, Montana, Maine, New Jersey, New Mexico, Oregon, Vermont and Washington, plus the District of Columbia. Oregon was the first state to legalise it under a law which came into effect in 1997. It allows mentally competent patients who are terminally ill and with less than six months to live to ask for life-ending medication. People from outside Oregon may travel to the state to take advantage of the law.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li"><strong>NETHERLANDS </strong>- The "Termination of Life on Request and Assisted Suicide (Review Procedures) Act" came into effect in 2002. A doctor is immune from punishment for euthanasia and assisted suicide where patients are experiencing "unbearable suffering with no prospect of improvement". Minors can request euthanasia from the age of 12 but require parental permission before the age of 16.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li"><strong>BELGIUM </strong>- Belgium legalised medically assisted dying in 2002 for the terminally ill and for people experiencing unbearable suffering, which includes patients with psychiatric conditions. Since 2014, those under the age of 18 who are terminally ill are covered by the law as long as they have parental permission.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li"><strong>CANADA </strong>- Canada introduced "Medical Assistance in Dying" in 2016 for those whose death was deemed to be "reasonably foreseeable". Five years later, the law was extended to permit people with a "grievous and irremediable" medical condition to request assisted dying. The country has delayed until 2027 a plan to extend medical assistance in dying to include those with a mental illness.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li"><strong>AUSTRALIA </strong>- Voluntary assisted dying for the terminally ill or those with a condition that is causing intolerable suffering is legal in most Australian states, after being introduced first in Victoria in 2019. Doctors can prescribe medication for self-administration or administer them where required.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li"><strong>SPAIN </strong>- Spain approved a law in 2021 which allows euthanasia and medically assisted suicide for people with incurable or debilitating diseases who want to end their life.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li"><strong>GERMANY </strong>- Assisted dying had been legal in Germany until 2015 when the country outlawed its provision on an organised or commercial basis, effectively banning it in many cases. Five years later the country's top court ruled in favour of groups providing terminally ill adults with assisted suicide services, but lawmakers are yet to finalise new rules.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li"><strong>FRANCE </strong>- Doctors in France have since 2016 been allowed to put a person who is close to death and in great pain into deep sedation, but not to administer life-ending medication. President Emmanuel Macron earlier this year backed new legislation which would allow assisted dying for those with incurable conditions and a bill was introduced in April, but elections in June and July interrupted the proposed law's progress.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li"><strong>BRITAIN </strong>- A bill to allow terminally ill adults with six months or less left to live the right to end their lives was introduced to parliament earlier in October and will be debated on Nov. 29.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li"><strong>IRELAND </strong>- A cross-party Irish parliamentary committee recommended this year that the government should legalise assisted dying in certain restricted circumstances. A majority of lawmakers in October voted in favour of "noting" the committee's findings. With a national election due on Nov. 29, it will be up to the next government to decide whether to consider proposing a new law.</li>
</ol>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/glaov5c8_graveyad-generic-grave-generic-grave-flowers-istock_625x300_12_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-unveils-its-second-5th-generation-fighter-j-35-looks-exactly-like-this-us-jet-7004553]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[China Unveils Its Second 5th-Gen Fighter, Looks Exactly Like This US Jet]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-unveils-its-second-5th-generation-fighter-j-35-looks-exactly-like-this-us-jet-7004553]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 12 Nov 2024 22:37:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[China's second fifth-generation stealth fighter jet is making a debut at its largest air show, taking centre stage at the event and becoming the second nation in the world after the US to have more than one fifth-generation fighter jet.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>China's second fifth-generation stealth fighter jet is making a debut at its largest air show, taking centre stage at the event and becoming the second nation in the world after the US to have more than one fifth-generation fighter jet.</p>

<p>The Shenyang J-35 stealth fighter is a twin-engine, single-seater supersonic jet developed for multirole missions. J-35 is the second fifth-generation fighter China has developed after the J-20.&nbsp;</p>

<p>J-35's design is similar to the US Lockheed Martin F-35, the only difference is that the former is twin-engine and the latter has one engine. China is known for copying the design of several aircraft - The J-20 and the US F-22 Raptor are similar in design except for canards that are present in J-20, and the Chengdu J-10 also known as the "Vigorous Dragon" is similar to the US F-16.&nbsp;</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="US F-22 Raptor (Left), China J-20 (Right)" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/9s4re0d_f22-j20_625x300_12_November_24.jpg" title="US F-22 Raptor (Left), China J-20 (Right)" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><em>US F-22 Raptor (Left), China J-20 (Right)</em></p>
</div>

<p>Global Times, the mouthpiece of the Chinese Communist Party in a report said, "The aircraft could enhance the country's integrated combat capabilities."&nbsp;</p>

<p>"J-35A functions within both stealth and counter-stealth combat frameworks. Its mission focuses on gaining and maintaining air superiority, eliminating hostile fourth/fifth generation fighter jets and ground/surface air defence forces, as well as intercepting aerial hostile targets including fighters, bombers and cruise missiles," it said.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont">
<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Japan had scrambled its F-35 fighter jets to warn the Russian military. (Photo: Lockheed Martin)" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/i1j8rtds_f35-fighter-jet-f-35-lightning-ii-jet_625x300_01_October_24.jpg" title="Japan had scrambled its F-35 fighter jets to warn the Russian military. (Photo: Lockheed Martin)" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">US F-35 Lighting carrying out formation flying</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>

<h3><strong>'One Aircraft, Multiple Roles'</strong></h3>

<p>China plans to induct the aircraft into the Air Force and the Navy, similar to the US F-35 which has three variants - The F-35A for the Air Force, F-35B for the Marine Corps and F-35C for the US Navy.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The F-35A can take off from an Air Force runway, the F-35B can hover and vertically land on amphibious attack ships of the Marine Corps and the F-35C, with a wide wingspan, is used for aircraft carrier landings by the US Navy.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Earlier this year, China's largest and heaviest aircraft carrier, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sea-trials-begin-of-chinas-new-aircraft-carrier-fujian-what-it-means-for-india-5599654">Fujian</a>, was out for sea trials. The conventionally powered aircraft carrier weighs over 80,000 tons and has the most potent aircraft launch system - EMALS or Electromagnetic Aircraft Launch System, which currently only the US operates on the USS Gerald R Ford, the world's largest operational aircraft carrier.&nbsp;</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Add image caption here" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/hac7a7ro_fujian-_625x300_10_May_24.jpg" title="Add image caption here" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><em>Fujian is China's third aircraft carrier</em></p>
</div>

<p>The US Department of Defence in a report on China's naval modernization and its implications, said "China may be developing a carrier-capable variant of its FC-31/J-31 fifth-generation stealth fighter to complement or succeed the J-15 on catapult-equipped PLA carriers. &nbsp;China reportedly is also developing a carrier-based airborne early warning (NAEW) aircraft, called the KJ-600, that is similar to the U.S. Navy's carrier-based E-2 Hawkeye AEW aircraft,82 and stealth drone aircraft."</p>

<p>The J-35 is reportedly a lighter version of the J-20. However, the combat capabilities of both aircraft remain unknown.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The development of the J-35 fighter jet suggests that China is mirroring the US and aims to combat the latter in the Indo-Pacific. The inclusion in the air show suggests that J-35 is ready for deployment.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Recently, the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-how-us-new-missile-will-be-a-game-changer-in-indo-pacific-6421399">US deployed its new long-range air-to-air missile</a> that could potentially disrupt the balance of power in the region. &nbsp;The AIM-174B missile, onboard the US Navy's F-18 Super Hornet, as seen in many pictures, is known to have an operational range of approximately 400 km.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/j3fpu9q_aim174b-missile_625x300_26_August_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<h3><strong>Other Attractions At The Air Show&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>At the Zhuhai air show, China also unveiled the world's first twin-seat variant of a stealth aircraft. The J-20s was under development for a few years and has broken the cover at the air show. China says the aircraft is a "heavy-duty radar-evading fighter jet with long-range operation and multifunction capabilities."</p>

<p>The J-20 fighter jets flew in a diamond formation at the air show. The Russian Su-57, also a fifth-generation fighter jet, participated in the event.&nbsp;</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Russias Su-57 participated in the air show" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/9211cga_su57_625x300_12_November_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Russias Su-57 participated in the air show" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">Russia's Su-57 participated in the air show<br />
<span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: AFP</span></p>
</div>

<p>The airshow will feature a dedicated drone zone for the first time. The Russia-Ukraine war has shown the world the growing relevance of drones on the battlefield and how it is being used extensively by Kyiv to counter the asymmetry in terms of military strength with Russia.&nbsp;</p>

<p>China unveiled its '<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/military/article/3285955/china-unveils-killer-whale-stealth-drone-ship" rel="noindex,nofollow">Killer Whale</a>' ship ahead of the largest air show. The dual diesel and electric propulsion ship is unmanned and can carry a range of weapons like rockets, anti-ship missiles and ship-to-air missiles. It can also allow take-off and landing of choppers at its helipad.</p>

<p>China's Killer Whale is not the first unmanned surface vessel developed by a country. Earlier this year, the US Navy completed its first deployment of four unmanned ships which spent over four months in the Pacific for sea trials. The unmanned surface vessels - Sea Hunter, Sea Hawk, Mariner and Ranger - departed Southern California in August 2023 and returned in January 2024.</p>

<p><strong>India's AMCA Program</strong></p>

<p>India is developing its 5.5 generation Advanced Medium Combat Aircraft which will have stealth capabilities and the Defence Research and Development Organization chief said the induction is expected by 2035.&nbsp;Air Force's latest induction, the Rafale fighter jet, is a 4.5 generation multi-role aircraft that is deployed in the north in Ambala, Haryana, and Hashimara in Assam.&nbsp;</p>

<p>While China has deployed the J-20 fighter jets close to the Line of Actual Control, experts have inferred that in the event of a conflict, standalone weapon systems like surface-to-air missiles, air-to-air missiles and air defence systems will play a huge role for the Indian Air Force to combat and outmanoeuvre the Chinese.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Watch:&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/video/india-to-induct-5-5-gen-stealth-fighter-jet-amca-by-2035-drdo-chairman-825552">'India To Induct 5.5-Gen Stealth Fighter Jet AMCA By 2035: DRDO Chairman</a></p>

<p>In August, DRDO showcased 40 indigenously developed advanced systems and technologies at the International Defence Aviation Exposition IDAX 2024 during the Tarang Shakti exercise at Tamil Nadu's Sulur. On India's first 5.5-generation stealth aircraft, Advanced Medium Combat Aircraft (AMCA), Chairman of the Defence Research and Development Organisation (DRDO), Dr Samir V. Kamat, said that India's first 5.5-generation stealth aircraft will be inducted by 2035. He further said that India is among the very few nations to develop stealth aircraft.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/l4s3l568_china-j35_625x300_12_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The J-35 is reportedly a lighter version of the J-20.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-vows-to-cut-greenhouse-gas-emissions-by-81-on-1990-levels-by-2035-7004548]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK Vows To Cut Greenhouse Gas Emissions By 81% On 1990 Levels By 2035]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-vows-to-cut-greenhouse-gas-emissions-by-81-on-1990-levels-by-2035-7004548]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 12 Nov 2024 22:36:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The UK will aim to reduce greenhouse gas emissions by 81 percent on 1990 levels by 2035, Prime Minister Keir Starmer announced Tuesday, as his government ramps up its ambitions on climate change.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The UK will aim to reduce greenhouse gas emissions by 81 percent on 1990 levels by 2035, Prime Minister Keir Starmer announced Tuesday, as his government ramps up its ambitions on climate change.</p>

<p>The previous government in London committed in 2021 to curb such emissions by 78 percent over the same period compared to 1990.</p>

<p>Starmer unveiled the new target as he attended the beginning of the COP29 climate conference in Baku, Azerbaijan, where he is one of the only G20 leaders to show up.</p>

<p>The summit's start has been overshadowed by the re-election in the US of longtime climate change sceptic Donald Trump, as well as new warnings that 2024 is on track to break temperature records.</p>

<p>UK Labour party leader Starmer, who took power in July, told a press conference that Britain was "building on our reputation as a climate leader".</p>

<p>"I've had a series of meetings here at COP this week because this government recognises that the world stands at a critical juncture in the climate crisis," he said.</p>

<p>"There is no national security, there is no economic security, there is no global security without climate security."</p>

<p>The British leader insisted his government was not going to "start telling people how to live their lives" in order to meet the new emissions reduction target.</p>

<p>"We're not going to start dictating to people what they do," he added.</p>

<p>Starmer touted efforts already put in place by ministers to meet what he called an "ambitious" but "realisable target", including ending an effective ban on new onshore wind projects.</p>

<p>His Labour government has also said it will not issue any new oil and gas exploration licenses in the North Sea, and closed the UK's last coal power plant in September.</p>

<p>Starmer said that meant Britain was the "first G7 economy to phase out coal power", and that it was now prioritising renewable energy projects.</p>

<p>"Make no mistake, the race is on for the clean energy jobs of the future, the economy of tomorrow," he said.</p>

<p>"And I don't want to be in the middle of the pack. I want to get ahead of the game."</p>

<p>Environmental groups cautiously welcomed the new 2035 target.</p>

<p>Friends of the Earth's head of campaigns, Rosie Downes, called it "a step in the right direction but must be seen as a floor to the level of ambition not a ceiling".</p>

<p>"Deeper, faster cuts are needed to help avert the climate collision course we are on," she added.</p>

<p>"Furthermore, if these targets are to be credible, they must be backed by a clear plan to ensure they are met. The UK's existing 2030 commitment is currently way off course."<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/ertrc5kk_uk-pm-keir-starmer_625x300_14_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[UK will aim to reduce greenhouse gas emissions by 81% on 1990 levels by 2035, PM Starmer said.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-may-soon-bring-assisted-dying-law-lawmaker-explains-its-safeguards-7004474]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK May Soon Bring 'Assisted Dying' Law. Lawmaker Explains Its Safeguards]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-may-soon-bring-assisted-dying-law-lawmaker-explains-its-safeguards-7004474]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 12 Nov 2024 22:23:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A proposed law allowing terminally ill adults in England and Wales to end their lives was published on Tuesday, setting out safeguards such as ensuring the approval of doctors and judges to try to ease concerns in Britain over its possible misuse.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A proposed law allowing terminally ill adults in England and Wales to end their lives was published on Tuesday, setting out safeguards such as ensuring the approval of doctors and judges to try to ease concerns in Britain over its possible misuse.</p>

<p>The proposed law has polarised opinion and has split the governing Labour Party. Lawmakers will vote on the proposed law on Nov. 29, almost 10 years since parliament rejected an earlier bid to legalise assisted dying.</p>

<p>The Labour lawmaker who has proposed the new law, Kim Leadbeater, described it as "very robust", saying the legislation offers layers of safeguards to protect vulnerable people, who some critics fear might feel pressured to end their lives if assisted dying becomes legal.</p>

<p>Assisted dying would only be an option for mentally competent, terminally ill adults with six months or less left to live, as expected, under the proposed new law.</p>

<p>The other safeguards include two doctors confirming seven days apart that the person is eligible and has made their decision free from pressure, while a judge would then speak to one of those doctors before a 14-day period of reflection.</p>

<p>"This is just for terminally ill adults. It's not for anybody else. It's for people who are dying, and it is about shortening death rather than ending life," Leadbeater told BBC radio.</p>

<p>The bill would make it illegal to pressure or coerce someone into ending their life by assisted dying. The offence would be punishable by up to 14 years in prison.</p>

<p>Under current laws assisting suicide is punishable by up to 14 years in jail but Leadbeater argues that current rules do not reflect a shift in public opinion over the issue during the last 10 years.</p>

<p>Supporters of assisted dying say Britain is a laggard after Australia, Canada, New Zealand and some U.S. states legalised it under certain circumstances in recent years. It has been legal in Switzerland since 1942 and in the Netherlands since 2002.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Keir Starmer has said politicians will be able to vote with their consciences on the matter, rather than along party lines. He has supported changing the law in the past while health minister Wes Streeting has said he will oppose it.</p>

<p>Should the proposal, known as the Terminally Ill Adults (End of Life) Members Bill, pass a first vote, it would kick off the formal process for a law change, subjecting it to further scrutiny and requiring approval by both the House of Commons and the House of Lords, the upper house of parliament.</p>

<p>In 2015, British lawmakers voted 330 to 118 against the second reading of proposed legislation to legalise assisted dying.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/2ucce8rk_kim-leadbeater-reuters_625x300_12_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Labour Lawmaker Kim Leadbeater speaks during an interview about the Assisted Dying Bill in Westminster.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-expected-to-pick-south-dakota-governor-kristi-noem-as-chief-of-homeland-security-7004471]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Expected To Pick Kristi Noem As Chief Of Homeland Security]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-expected-to-pick-south-dakota-governor-kristi-noem-as-chief-of-homeland-security-7004471]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 12 Nov 2024 22:22:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump was expected Tuesday to pick South Dakota Governor Kristi Noem to head the US Department of Homeland Security, a powerful post at the center of the incoming president's tough-on-immigration policies.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump was expected Tuesday to pick South Dakota Governor Kristi Noem to head the US Department of Homeland Security, a powerful post at the center of the incoming president's tough-on-immigration policies.</p>

<p>Sources in Trump's transition team told US media including CBS News that he has decided on Noem, a longtime Trump loyalist who was once considered a strong contender to be the Republican nominee's running mate.</p>

<p>Joining Trump's cabinet would be a notable political rebound for Noem, who saw her stock plummet earlier this year when she released a memoir in which she recounted having shot dead an "untrainable" pet dog after a hunting excursion gone awry. Noem has said her action showed she was able to make tough choices.</p>

<p>Homeland Security is a sprawling organization with a budget topping $107 billion, about 15 times that of South Dakota, where Noem is in her second term as governor.</p>

<p>If confirmed as its secretary by the US Senate, the 52-year-old would oversee the US Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) along with protective security operations on the borders with Canada and Mexico, key agencies in any Trump plan for restricting immigration or deporting undocumented migrants.</p>

<p>DHS also controls the Federal Emergency Management Agency, which assists communities in times of natural disasters like hurricanes.</p>

<p>Trump himself has yet to confirm Noem's nomination. If accurate, it would be the latest quick pick as the Republican leader seeks to flesh out his cabinet.</p>

<p>He has already chosen former immigration official Tom Homan as the country's "border czar," tasking him with fulfilling his key domestic promise of mass deportations of undocumented migrants. The DHS secretary would be closely involved in any such operations.</p>

<p>The current homeland security secretary, Alejandro Mayorkas, was impeached in February by the Republican-majority House of Representatives, as Republicans successfully turned immigration and border security into a critical 2024 election issue. The Democratic-held US Senate rejected the effort to convict him.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/omv10r7o_kristi-noem_625x300_12_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[If confirmed by US Senate, Kristi Noem would oversee the US Immigration and Customs Enforcement. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-space-startup-firefly-aerospace-valued-at-over-2-billion-in-latest-funding-round-7004371]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Space Startup Firefly Valued At Over $2 Billion In Latest Funding Round]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-space-startup-firefly-aerospace-valued-at-over-2-billion-in-latest-funding-round-7004371]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 12 Nov 2024 22:06:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Firefly Aerospace has raised $175 million in a late-stage funding round led by RPM Ventures, valuing the space startup at more than $2 billion, it said on Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Firefly Aerospace has raised $175 million in a late-stage funding round led by RPM Ventures, valuing the space startup at more than $2 billion, it said on Tuesday.</p>

<p>Venture capital firms have been investing strongly in rocket makers and satellite manufacturers, marking a shift in the investment trend for such capital intensive businesses, Seraphim Space said in a report last month.</p>

<p>Texas-based Firefly makes small and medium launch vehicles for commercial launches to the earth's orbit. It also offers on-orbit services through its Elytra line of orbital vehicles, providing hosting, rideshare, delivery and servicing missions.</p>

<p>The startup is preparing for its first mission to the moon, dubbed Blue Ghost, as part of NASA's Commercial Lunar Payload Service initiative later this year.</p>

<p>The Series D funding round at Firefly included existing investors as well as new entities, including GiantLeap Capital and Human Element.</p>

<p>Firefly intends to utilize the fresh capital to enhance the market reach of its Elytra spacecraft, transition to full-scale production of its Alpha rocket, and expedite the hardware qualification for newly developing vehicles.</p>

<p>The company said it was simultaneously preparing for multiple launches of the Alpha rocket under contracts with Lockheed Martin, L3Harris and NASA, among others, while collaborating with Northrop Grumman to develop a medium launch vehicle.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/cm02g2v_firefly-aerospace-alpha-rocket-reuters_625x300_12_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Firefly Aerospace's Alpha rocket lifts off from the Vandenberg Space Force Base in California, US]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-how-methane-emissions-threaten-climate-goals-7004322]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: How Methane Emissions Threaten Climate Goals]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-how-methane-emissions-threaten-climate-goals-7004322]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 12 Nov 2024 21:56:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Fast-rising methane emissions could undermine efforts to limit global warming by mid-century, prompting scientists and policymakers to urge aggressive action to curb output of the potent greenhouse gas.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Fast-rising methane emissions could undermine efforts to limit global warming by mid-century, prompting scientists and policymakers to urge aggressive action to curb output of the potent greenhouse gas.</p>

<p>Nearly 160 countries have pledged a 30% cut from 2020 methane emissions levels by the end of this decade.</p>

<p>Over the last five years atmospheric methane levels have risen at their fastest rate since record-keeping began in the 1970s, driven in part by natural sources, according to the 2024 Global Methane Budget report. &nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>Here is why controlling methane emissions is so important:</strong></h2>

<h3><strong>HEAT-TRAPPING POWER</strong></h3>

<p>Methane molecules are more powerful than carbon dioxide (CO2) in trapping heat, meaning it takes fewer of them to cause the same amount of warming and reducing them can have a more immediate effect than reducing CO2.</p>

<p>Tackling methane also makes financial sense. United Nations analyses have found cutting methane emissions is likely cheaper than CO2 cuts for a comparable climate benefit.</p>

<p>While CO2 remains in the atmosphere for centuries, methane breaks down after about a decade - meaning it has less of a long-term impact on temperatures.</p>

<p>Scientists normally compare the overall warming effects of methane versus CO2 over a century, calculating that methane emissions are about 28 times worse than CO2 for global warming.</p>

<p>Over a shorter timespan of 20 years, however, methane is 80 times worse.</p>

<p>Methane has led to around 0.5 degrees Celsius of warming so far, or about one-third of the roughly 1.3 C of warming experienced to date since pre-industrial times.</p>

<h3><strong>SURGING EMISSIONS</strong></h3>

<p>Methane concentrations are rising faster than any other major greenhouse gas, with human activities driving at least two-thirds of global emissions, according to the 2024 Global Methane Budget.</p>

<p>That includes the agriculture sector, including rice farming and livestock, fossil fuel activities, and landfills and other waste.</p>

<p>The report, published every five years, found methane emissions from these human activities have risen overall by 20% over the last two decades.</p>

<p>Most of the methane mitigation efforts under way, including EU legislation, are focused on the oil and gas sector, where the emissions are easier to tackle than in agriculture, according to the food-focused investor initiative called FAIRR.</p>

<h3><strong>NATURAL SOURCES A CONCERN</strong></h3>

<p>The remaining third of the world's methane emissions comes from natural sources such as thawing permafrost, peat bogs and wetlands - and emissions could rapidly increase as temperatures rise.</p>

<p>Animals, including humans, are also a source of methane.</p>

<p>While it is easy to measure atmospheric methane, understanding where it comes from is crucial for tackling the problem.</p>

<p>By analyzing distinct isotope signatures in methane detected, scientists can investigate whether the the gas comes from biological sources or industry.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ofbtq81g_methane-emissions-reuters_625x300_12_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Over the last five years atmospheric methane levels have risen at their fastest rate.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/judge-delays-decision-in-trumps-new-york-criminal-case-to-november-19-7003958]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Judge Delays Decision In Trump's New York Criminal Case To November 19]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/judge-delays-decision-in-trumps-new-york-criminal-case-to-november-19-7003958]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 12 Nov 2024 21:05:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The judge in Donald Trump's New York criminal case has delayed to November 19 a decision on potentially throwing out the US president-elect's conviction, the court said Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The judge in Donald Trump's New York criminal case has delayed to November 19 a decision on potentially throwing out the US president-elect's conviction, the court said Tuesday.</p>

<p>Trump was convicted of 34 felony counts in May after a jury found he had fraudulently manipulated business records to cover up an alleged sexual encounter with a porn star ahead of the 2016 election.</p>

<p>Trump, due to be sentenced on November 26, may receive a reprieve if Judge Juan Merchan decides to dismiss the case following the Supreme Court's recent ruling on presidential immunity.</p>

<p>That landmark ruling saw the court, with a 6-3 conservative majority, decide that presidents have sweeping immunity from prosecution for a range of official acts committed while in office.</p>

<p>Ahead of the election, Trump's lawyers moved to have the case thrown out in light of the Supreme Court decision, a move that prosecutors have firmly rejected.</p>

<p>If Merchan throws out the case on that basis, there will be no sentencing of Trump, 78.</p>

<p>If he does not, Trump's legal team would almost certainly seek to oppose or delay any sentencing, insisting it would interfere with Trump's role as commander-in-chief once he is sworn in on January 20.</p>

<p>"The joint application for a stay of the current deadlines... until November 19, is granted," the court wrote in an email to parties in the case, seen by AFP.</p>

<p><strong>'A severe blow'</strong></p>

<p>An editorial in the Kansas City Star newspaper called for the judge in the case to "do what was once unthinkable -- force a president-elect to take the oath of office in a jail cell."</p>

<p>"The surreal scene, while certainly shocking for the rest of the free world to witness, would send an unmistakable message -- the rule of law still applies in America."</p>

<p>But Trump's former attorney general Bill Barr said that both the New York case as well as others around the country had been "plainly brought for political purposes (and) have now been extensively aired and rejected in the court of public opinion."</p>

<p>"Further maneuvering on these cases in the weeks ahead would serve no legitimate purpose and only distract the country and the incoming administration from the task at hand," he wrote.</p>

<p>Trump has repeatedly derided the case as a witch hunt, saying it "should be rightfully terminated."</p>

<p>Alongside the New York case, brought by state-level prosecutors, Trump faces two active federal cases, one related to his effort to overturn the 2020 election and the other connected to classified documents he allegedly mishandled after leaving office.</p>

<p>However, as president, he would be able to intervene to end those cases, and Jack Smith, the special counsel handling both cases, has reportedly begun to wind them down.</p>

<p>A Trump-appointed federal judge already threw out the documents case, but Smith had sought to appeal that decision.</p>

<p>"Trump's victory means he is unlikely to be held accountable for any of his alleged criminal misconduct," said former prosecutor Randall Eliason in an article on Substack.</p>

<p>"That's a severe blow to the ideal of the rule of law."</p>

<p>The New York conviction, coming just months before an election that Trump won convincingly, was one of several dramatic developments in the race for the White House.</p>

<p>In July, Trump survived an assassination attempt at a rally in Pennsylvania when a bullet grazed his ear.</p>

<p>Later that month, President Joe Biden stepped aside as the Democratic Party's candidate following a disastrous performance against Trump in a televised debate.</p>

<p>That paved the way for Vice President Kamala Harris to become the first woman of color from a major US party to stand for president.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/862i9kmo_donald-trump_625x300_12_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Following his conviction, Trump was scheduled for sentencing on November 26. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/severe-turbulence-injures-11-on-lufthansa-flight-to-frankfurt-7003578]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[11 Injured After Severe Turbulence Onboard Lufthansa Flight To Frankfurt]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/severe-turbulence-injures-11-on-lufthansa-flight-to-frankfurt-7003578]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 12 Nov 2024 20:17:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Eleven people were injured when a Lufthansa flight from Buenos Aires to Frankfurt hit severe turbulence while travelling over the Atlantic, the airline said on Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Eleven people were injured when a Lufthansa flight from Buenos Aires to Frankfurt hit severe turbulence while travelling over the Atlantic, the airline said on Tuesday.</p>

<p>"Unfortunately, five passengers and six crew members suffered mostly minor injuries," a Lufthansa spokesperson told Reuters in an email, confirming a report by the DPA news agency.</p>

<p>"The safety of the flight was not in jeopardy at any time," the spokesperson added.</p>

<p>The injured received medical treatment immediately after the aircraft landed safely at its planned destination on Tuesday at 10:53 am (0953 GMT), according to the airline.</p>

<p>The Boeing 747-8 had been carrying 329 passengers and 19 crew members. The turbulence was brief and occurred in an intertropical convergence zone, the company said.</p>

<p>In May, a passenger died of a suspected heart attack and 30 were injured when a Singapore Airlines passenger plane was severely jolted by an air pocket over the Irrawaddy Basin in Myanmar.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/u3s74fio_german-airline-lufthansa_625x300_11_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Boeing 747-8 had been carrying 329 passengers and 19 crew members. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/starlink-in-india-soon-elon-musk-takes-on-mukesh-ambanis-reliance-jio-7003416]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Starlink In India Soon? Elon Musk Takes On Mukesh Ambani's Reliance Jio]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/starlink-in-india-soon-elon-musk-takes-on-mukesh-ambanis-reliance-jio-7003416]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 12 Nov 2024 19:52:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India's internet and telecom sector is likely to get a new entrant - Elon Musk's Starlink - a game-changer for internet users in the world's most populous nation. Elon Musk will be taking on behemoths like Mukesh Ambani's Jio and Sunil Bharti Mittal.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India's internet and telecom sector is likely to get a new entrant - Elon Musk's Starlink - a game-changer for internet users in the world's most populous country. Elon Musk will be taking on behemoths like Mukesh Ambani's Jio and Sunil Bharti Mittal's Airtel besides national carrier BSNL to provide ultra-high speed connectivity to Indian users.</p>

<p>Whether or not he will be able to match Jio and Airtel on pricing is yet to be seen. India currently has the world's lowest pricing in terms of broadband and WiFi internet. Elon Musk, currently the world's richest person, may aim to compete aggressively in the world's most vibrant internet data market.</p>

<p>Starlink, which provides wireless internet service with the help satellite constellations in near-Earth orbit, is currently seeking the required security clearances for a licence to offer satellite broadband services in India and is expected to get a permit should it satisfy authorities of the conditions laid out, the telecom minister said today.</p>

<p>Starlink has been looking to enter India for years and its plans got a major boost last month when New Delhi said it wouldn't auction spectrum for satellite broadband but rather award it administratively - just as Elon Musk wanted. Rival Indian telecom billionaire Mukesh Ambani had wanted an auction.</p>

<p>India's Telecom Minister Jyotiraditya Scindia confirmed today that Starlink is in the process of obtaining the necessary security clearance, which requires it to satisfy the Government of India that the company processes and stores all data locally in India, and that its satellite signals are encrypted and 100 per cent secure.</p>

<p>"When you check all the boxes, you get the licence. If they (Starlink) do that, we will be very happy," Mr Scindia said.</p>

<p>Mukesh Ambani's Reliance Jio currently dominates India's broadband market with more than 14 million wired subscribers. Jio also has a user base of nearly 500 million mobile internet users. Airtel too has close to 300 million broadband subscribers. However, they are concerned that after spending more than 20 billion dollars in spectrum auctions, they now have the risk of losing customers to Elon Musk's Starlink as satellite technology advances.</p>

<p>As per a Reuters report, Reliance Jio already has the necessary clearances to launch its own satellite broadband service, but hasn't done so yet. Starlink has now informed the Government of India that it is willing to comply with India's rules and regulations for security, data storage, and servers.</p>

<p>When Reliance Jio had first launched services, Mukesh Ambani, then Asia's richest person, had offered broadband services for free to all subscribers to capture a majority market share. Elon Musk, who is the world's richest person is now adopting a similar strategy - In Africa, Musk offers Starlink services for as little as $10 (roughly Rs 800) per month. In the US, Musk offers the same Starlink service for as much as $120 (roughly Rs 10,000) per month.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/aei7klj8_elon-musk-mukesh-ambani-elon-musk_625x300_12_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Elon Musk's Starlink may soon provide satellite internet in India, taking on Mukesh Ambani's Jio]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/11-killed-in-military-air-strike-at-teashop-in-myanmar-7003259]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[11 Killed In Military Air Strike On Teashop In Myanmar]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/11-killed-in-military-air-strike-at-teashop-in-myanmar-7003259]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 12 Nov 2024 19:35:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Eleven people were killed when a teashop in Myanmar was hit by a military airstrike in the town of Naungcho in the northern Shan state on Tuesday afternoon, a spokesperson for a local ethnic armed group said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Eleven people were killed when a teashop in Myanmar was hit by a military airstrike in the town of Naungcho in the northern Shan state on Tuesday afternoon, a spokesperson for a local ethnic armed group said.</p>

<p>The attack, shortly before 3pm local time, comes as the junta battles widespread armed opposition to its 2021 coup and its soldiers accused of bloody rampages and using air and artillery strikes to punish civilian communities.</p>

<p>"They were civilians who came to drink tea and sitting at the shop," Lway Yay Oo, a spokesperson for the Ta'ang National Liberation Army (TNLA) said.</p>

<p>At least four civilians were wounded and were receiving treatment in a hospital, she said.</p>

<p>Local media reported that 11 people had died and that many were injured in an army air attack on Lansan tea shop.</p>

<p>Since last year the military has lost swaths of territory near the border with China in northern Shan state to an alliance of armed ethnic minority groups and "People's Defence Forces" battling to overturn its coup.</p>

<p>The groups have seized a regional military command and taken control of lucrative border trade crossings, prompting rare public criticism by military supporters of the junta's top leadership.</p>

<p>Myanmar has been in turmoil since the military deposed Aung San Suu Kyi's government in 2021 and launched a crackdown that sparked an armed uprising.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/3l6ige4g_myanmar-junta-bans-men-from-applying-abroad_625x300_03_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Since last year the military has lost swaths of territory near the border with China. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/microsoft-may-go-the-apple-way-rebrand-copilot-to-windows-intelligence-7002841]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Microsoft May Go The Apple Way, Rebrand Copilot To Windows Intelligence]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/microsoft-may-go-the-apple-way-rebrand-copilot-to-windows-intelligence-7002841]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 12 Nov 2024 18:42:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The rebranding exercise might put all the AI features offered by Microsoft through a subscription model under the name of "Microsoft Intelligence"]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Microsoft, the big technology company that is at the forefront of artificial intelligence innovation courtesy of its partnership with OpenAI, might just be looking to rebrand what has been its flagship product offering inside Microsoft Suite. Copilot, which was previously known as Bing Chat, offers users a variety of features, including AI web search powered by ChatGPT.</p>

<p>Microsoft has positioned AI features at the centre of its windows ecosystem, launching a line of windows pcs: copilot + PCs. It has now come to notice through a social media post, that a recent update in copilot had a hint inside appprivacy.adml- a settings file on the recently shipped update.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Let Apps Access Windows Intelligence <a href="https://t.co/gbyU4JdmG5">pic.twitter.com/gbyU4JdmG5</a></p>
 https://tero.bsky.social ?? (@teroalhonen) <a href="https://twitter.com/teroalhonen/status/1847290774272045118?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 18, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The rebranding exercise might put all the AI features offered by Microsoft through a subscription model under the name of "Microsoft Intelligence", taking a feather out of the apple hat, who called their suite of AI features Apple Intelligence in as early as June this year.</p>

<p>Such a move would also help windows to further expand into all of its other applications offered under windows operating systems, such as notepad and MS word, with better brand recall than copilot, which has been envisioned as a separate product for the company.</p>

<p>If Windows does indeed go ahead with the rebranding, this won't be the first time Microsoft has "taken inspiration" from its direct rival, the most significant of which is the introduction of voice assistant Cortana in 2014, when Apple had launched Siri as early as 2011.</p>

<p>What would Steve Jobs think of this latest rebranding exercise? "They have absolutely no taste," Steve had said about Microsoft in a 1995 interview.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-03/nkr73rms_copilot-bloomberg_625x300_07_March_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Copilot hosts all the AI features for Microsoft.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-russia-link-banking-systems-in-latest-bid-to-counteract-sanctions-7002802]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iran, Russia Link Banking Systems In Latest Bid To Counter Sanctions]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-russia-link-banking-systems-in-latest-bid-to-counteract-sanctions-7002802]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 12 Nov 2024 18:39:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iranian bank cards can now be used in Russia, state television reported, as the two countries linked their banking systems in the latest bid to counteract sanctions.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Iranian bank cards can now be used in Russia, state television reported, as the two countries linked their banking systems in the latest bid to counteract sanctions.</p>

<p>Iranian banks have been excluded since 2018 from the SWIFT international financial messaging service, which governs the vast majority of transactions worldwide.</p>

<p>The move is part of a raft of sanctions that were re-imposed on Iran after the United States withdrew from a landmark 2015 nuclear deal.</p>

<p>Iranian bank cards can now be used in Russia, state television channel IRINN said on Monday, showing the withdrawal of money using an Iranian bank card from an ATM in Russia.</p>

<p>The operation was made possible by connecting Iran's interbank network Shetab to its Russian equivalent Mir, the channel said.</p>

<p>Iranians can currently withdraw money in Russia, and will in the future be able to use their cards to pay for in-store purchases, it added.</p>

<p>"The plan is also going to be implemented in other countries that have a wide range of financial and social interactions with Iran, for example Iraq, Afghanistan and Turkey," it said.</p>

<p>Both Iran and Russia have sought to counteract the effects of sanctions on their economies.</p>

<p>Since the start of Russia's invasion of Ukraine in 2022, Moscow has faced mounting sanctions, and its ties with Tehran have grown closer in parallel.</p>

<p>Ukraine and its Western allies have since the start of the conflict accused Iran of supplying Russia with both drones and missiles for use in the war.</p>

<p>Tehran and Moscow signed an agreement in June to strengthen their cooperation in the banking sector.</p>

<p>In the future, Russians will also be able to use their bank cards in Iran, IRINN said, without specifying when.</p>

<p>Russia has been pushing for the creation of an international payment platform as an alternative to the SWIFT service, from which key Russian banks have also been excluded since 2022.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/tno0fm4o_credit-card-generic_625x300_15_May_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Iranians will be able to use their cards to pay for in-store purchases in Russia. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-plans-swift-immigration-crackdown-aims-to-end-bidens-entry-programs-7002639]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Plans Immigration Crackdown, Aims To End Biden's Entry Programs]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-plans-swift-immigration-crackdown-aims-to-end-bidens-entry-programs-7002639]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 12 Nov 2024 18:18:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[President-elect Donald Trump is expected to take a slew of executive actions on his first day in the White House to ramp up immigration enforcement and roll back President Joe Biden's flagship legal entry programs.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>President-elect Donald Trump is expected to take a slew of executive actions on his first day in the White House to ramp up immigration enforcement and roll back President Joe Biden's flagship legal entry programs, three sources familiar with the matter told Reuters.</p>

<p>The executive actions would give federal immigration officers more latitude to arrest people with no criminal records, surge troops to the US-Mexico border and restart construction of the border wall, the sources said.</p>

<p>Trump also is expected to end Biden's humanitarian programs that allowed hundreds of thousands of migrants to enter legally in recent years and could encourage those with expired statuses to leave voluntarily, according to the sources who declined to be identified.</p>

<p>"All of these should be on the table," said Mark Morgan, an immigration official in Trump's first term who said he did not speak for the Trump transition team.</p>

<p>Trump's early executive actions would kickstart his immigration agenda, which includes a promise to deport record numbers of immigrants in the US illegally.</p>

<p>The US Department of Homeland Security estimated there were 11 million immigrants without legal status in 2022, a figure that may have increased. Some cities that received migrants including New York, Chicago and Denver struggled to house and aid them.</p>

<p>Trump, a Republican, defeated Democratic Vice President Kamala Harris in last week's presidential election. He made claims that the Biden administration allowed high levels of illegal immigration a focus of his campaign.</p>

<p>Trump's transition effort remains in its early stages and plans could change before his inauguration on January 20. A Trump spokesperson did not respond to a request for comment.</p>

<p>Migrant arrests reached a record during Biden's presidency, straining US border enforcement. But illegal crossings fell dramatically this year as Biden instituted new border restrictions and Mexico stepped up enforcement.</p>

<p>Trump aims to drive illegal crossings even lower and use a whole-of-government approach to arrest, detain and deport large numbers of people.</p>

<p>Trump announced on Sunday night that former hardline US Immigration and Customs Enforcement Acting Director Tom Homan would serve as a White House "border czar" overseeing security and immigration enforcement.</p>

<p>Vice President-elect JD Vance on Monday appeared to confirm that Stephen Miller, architect of Trump's restrictive first-term immigration agenda, would return as deputy chief of staff for policy, assuring the issue will remain central.</p>

<p>Trump's aggressive agenda will likely encounter legal challenges from states governed by Democrats, the American Civil Liberties Union and pro-immigration advocates.</p>

<p><strong>DAY ONE TAKES SHAPE</strong></p>

<p>One of Trump's Day One executive actions is expected to be an order on so-called interior enforcement, arresting and detaining immigrants in the US illegally, the sources said.</p>

<p>Trump intends to scrap Biden administration guidance that prioritized people with serious criminal records for deportation and limited enforcement against non-criminals, they said.</p>

<p>The Trump order would call for deportations to prioritize people charged with felonies and people who have exhausted their legal avenues to remain, but would not restrict officers from picking up other potentially deportable immigrants.</p>

<p>More than 1 million immigrants in the US have exhausted their legal options and been ordered deported, according to the pro-immigration American Immigration Council.</p>

<p>Homan told Fox News on Monday these people would be a priority. "A federal judge said, 'You must go home,' and they didn't," Homan said.</p>

<p>Certain groups - such as international students who support Palestinian operator group Hamas and have violated the terms of their student visas - could also be listed as a priority, two of the sources said.</p>

<p>ICE could use military planes in deportations and seek help from other government agencies to transport deportees, one source said. "All options are on the table," the source said.</p>

<p>Another order would deal with border security, the two sources said. Trump intends to send National Guard troops to the border and declare illegal immigration a national emergency to unlock funds for border wall construction, the sources said.</p>

<p>Wall construction in Arizona - where Democratic Governor Katie Hobbs has opposed Republican enforcement efforts - could be a priority, two sources said.</p>

<p><strong>ENDING BIDEN PROGRAMS</strong></p>

<p>Trump plans to end Biden's temporary humanitarian "parole" programs that have allowed hundreds of thousands of migrants to enter legally and access work permits, the sources said.</p>

<p>The programs include an initiative for certain migrants with US sponsors and another that allows migrants in Mexico to use an app to schedule border appointments.</p>

<p>People in the US with expired parole status who leave voluntarily could be allowed to apply for legal admission without penalties, the sources said.</p>

<p>Trump is also expected to talk with Mexico about reinstating his "Remain in Mexico" program which required non-Mexican asylum seekers to stay in Mexico while their US cases were decided.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/ldvvqfso_us-immigration-agency-reuters_625x300_03_August_18.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The US Department of Homeland Security estimates 11 mn. immigrants without legal status in 2022. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-army-announces-gaza-aid-on-the-eve-of-us-imposed-deadline-7002555]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Army Announces Gaza Aid On Eve Of US-Imposed Deadline]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-army-announces-gaza-aid-on-the-eve-of-us-imposed-deadline-7002555]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 12 Nov 2024 18:05:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel's army announced the opening Tuesday of an additional aid crossing into Gaza, on the eve of a US-imposed deadline to improve humanitarian conditions for Palestinians in the war-ravaged territory.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel's army announced the opening Tuesday of an additional aid crossing into Gaza, on the eve of a US-imposed deadline to improve humanitarian conditions for Palestinians in the war-ravaged territory.</p>

<p>"As part of the effort and commitment to increase the volume and routes of aid to the Gaza Strip, the 'Kissufim' Crossing was opened today," the army said in a joint statement with COGAT, the Israeli defence ministry agency responsible for civilian affairs in the Palestinian territories.</p>

<p>"The operation... includes the delivery of food, water, medical supplies, and shelter equipment to central and southern Gaza," they said, adding it involved the military, COGAT and defence ministry.</p>

<p>"The IDF (Israeli army), through COGAT, will continue to operate in accordance with international law to facilitate and ease the delivery of humanitarian aid to the Gaza Strip."</p>

<p>Last month, US Secretary of State Antony Blinken and Defense Secretary Lloyd Austin warned Israel it had until November 13 to improve aid delivery to Gaza or risk the withholding of some military assistance from the United States, Israel's biggest supporter.</p>

<p>The letter was sent weeks before the November 5 US presidential election won by Donald Trump, who has promised to give Israel freer rein.</p>

<p>Although outgoing President Joe Biden had repeatedly urged Israel to deliver more humanitarian aid and protect civilians, he mostly stopped short of using leverage such as cutting off weapons.</p>

<p>Kissufim, near a kibbutz across from southern Gaza that was attacked in the October 7, 2023 Hamas assault that sparked the war, has mostly been in disuse except by the military since Israel withdrew from Gaza in 2005.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory campaign has killed more than 43,603 people in Gaza, most of them civilians, according to data from the Hamas-run territory's health ministry that the United Nations considers reliable.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/00256qbg_gaza_625x300_03_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The operation includes delivery of food, water, medical supplies, and shelter equipment to Gaza. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-passes-law-banning-child-free-propaganda-amid-demographic-decline-7002487]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russia Passes Law Banning "Child-Free Propaganda" Amid Demographic Decline]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-passes-law-banning-child-free-propaganda-amid-demographic-decline-7002487]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 12 Nov 2024 17:58:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russian MPs on Tuesday passed in the final third reading controversial legislation banning "propaganda" of remaining childless, the latest measure targeting what Moscow depicts as Western liberal ideas.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russian MPs on Tuesday passed in the final third reading controversial legislation banning "propaganda" of remaining childless, the latest measure targeting what Moscow depicts as Western liberal ideas.</p>

<p>Facing an ageing population and low birth rates, Moscow is seeking to reverse a demographic slump -- accentuated by its military offensive on Ukraine -- that threatens its economic future.</p>

<p>MPs in the Duma lower house of parliament voted unanimously in favour of the draft bill, which would apply to materials online, in media, advertising and in films that promote "rejection of childbearing".</p>

<p>The bill targets "destructive content" that promotes a "conscious" rejection of having children.</p>

<p>Violations would be punishable by fines up to 400,000 rubles ($4,000) on individuals to five million rubles for businesses. The bill also includes a provision to deport foreigners.</p>

<p>"This is a fateful law... Without children, there will be no country. This ideology will lead to people stopping giving birth to children," the Duma's speaker Vyacheslav Volodin told MPs ahead of the vote.</p>

<p>He also said the legislation was about "protecting citizens, primarily the generation growing up, from information spread in the media space that negatively affects the development of personality".</p>

<p>This is "so new generations of our citizens grow up orientated towards traditional family values", he said.</p>

<p>The legislation will now be considered by the upper house of parliament on November 20, before being signed into law by President Vladimir Putin.</p>

<p>It would amend existing legislation that already bans any information seen as encouraging LGBTQ relationships or changing gender.</p>

<p>The Duma also passed legislation in the third reading banning foreigners in countries that allow gender reassignment from adopting Russian children.</p>

<p>It is the latest attack and stigmatisation of LGBTQ people by Moscow.</p>

<p>Moscow has long portrayed itself as a bulwark against liberal values, but that trend has hugely accelerated since the Kremlin launched its Ukraine offensive, further rupturing ties with the West.</p>

<p>The bill would ban adoption by citizens of countries that authorise "the change of sex by medical intervention, including with the use of medicine", or allow individuals to change their gender on official identity documents.</p>

<p>Since 1993, foreigners have adopted 102,403 children from Russia, Volodin said, warning that "Western policy towards children is destructive."</p>

<p>Russia has created an inhospitable environment for LBGTQ people for years. In July 2023, it banned the "international LGBT movement" as extremist and made gender reassignment illegal.</p>

<p>Putin himself has repeatedly mocked people who have undergone gender reassignment as well as LGBTQ people.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-05/lo5cedn8_child-generic-pixabay-650_625x300_23_May_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The bill targets "destructive content" that promotes rejection of having children. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/arlington-cemetery-donald-trump-kamala-harris-joe-biden-wipes-away-tears-during-god-bless-america-at-event-to-honour-veterans-7001689]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden Wipes Away Tear During 'God Bless America' At Event To Honour Veterans]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/arlington-cemetery-donald-trump-kamala-harris-joe-biden-wipes-away-tears-during-god-bless-america-at-event-to-honour-veterans-7001689]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 12 Nov 2024 17:39:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[During a Veterans Day ceremony on November 11, US President Joe Biden got emotional while he joined everyone in singing God Bless America.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden was seen wiping away a tear during a rendition of 'God Bless America' at the Veterans Day service on Monday. As the song echoed through the grounds of the Arlington National Cemetery, the President appeared visibly emotional. The event was held to honour the service of those who have served in the US armed forces. A clip shared on X (formerly Twitter) captured the moment, with Biden expressing his emotions while singing along.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">???? Today, at the Veterans Day service at Arlington National Cemetery, President Biden teared up as he joined veterans in singing God Bless America.<br />
<br />
Moments like these show just how much he cares for our country. We're going to miss him. ???????? <a href="https://t.co/oQuXaoFbbg">pic.twitter.com/oQuXaoFbbg</a></p>
 Chris D. Jackson (@ChrisDJackson) <a href="https://twitter.com/ChrisDJackson/status/1856045298591691141?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 11, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>President Biden and Vice President Kamala Harris, in their first joint appearance since Donald Trump's re-election, came together to honour US military veterans.</p>

<p>During the ceremony, Biden and Harris laid a wreath at the Tomb of the Unknown Soldier. Standing side-by-side, they maintained a solemn expression. After placing the wreath, Biden paused for a moment of quiet reflection, making the sign of the cross.</p>

<p>In his speech, Biden shared his sense of gratitude, telling the crowd, "This is the last time I will stand here at Arlington as commander in chief. It's been the greatest honour of my life, to lead you, to serve you, to care for you, to defend you, just as you defended us generation after generation after generation."</p>

<p>He also spoke about his late son, Beau Biden, a major in the Delaware Army National Guard who served in Iraq and died from glioblastoma in 2015. He said, "Like many of you, our son Beau Biden deployed in Iraq for a year. I still remember the day he asked me to pin his bars on him. He stood ramrod straight. How proud Jill and I and our family felt."</p>

<p>Recounting the hardships military families face, he continued, "Like many of you, we remember how hard it was when he was deployed, empty seat at the dinner table, missed holidays, prayers of worry repeated every night. Just as we ask everything of our veterans, we ask everything of their families."</p>

<p>Addressing all military families, especially those with missing loved ones or those who have lost family members in combat, Biden assured them: "For all the military families, for all those with a missing or loved one still unaccounted for, to all those with loved ones who have died in combat. Jill and I want you to know we see you, we thank you, and we will never stop working to meet our sacred obligation to you and your families."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/6b6h9g7g_joe-biden_625x300_12_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Joe Biden and Kamala Harris attended the event at the Arlington National Cemetery.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/car-attack-in-china-kills-35-injures-43-at-zhuhai-sports-center-reports-7001964]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[35 Killed, Over 40 Injured After Car Runs Over Pedestrians In China]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/car-attack-in-china-kills-35-injures-43-at-zhuhai-sports-center-reports-7001964]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 12 Nov 2024 16:57:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Thirty-five people were killed and 43 wounded after a car ploughed into pedestrians Monday evening in the southern Chinese city of Zhuhai, local police said Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A driver has killed 35 people and wounded 43 others in southern China, police said Tuesday, a day after the car ploughed down people exercising in a sports centre in the city of Zhuhai.</p>

<p>After the attack was reported on Monday, Police only said people had been wounded, while videos of the incident appeared to have been scrubbed from social media.</p>

<p>But on Tuesday, police said that a "serious and vicious attack" had occurred at Zhuhai Sports Centre, revealing the death count to be 35.</p>

<p>The 43 people wounded are not currently in life-threatening conditions.</p>

<p>Videos from Monday night geolocated by AFP showed people lying motionless on the ground, while others were seen frantically attempting to resuscitate the unconscious.</p>

<p>Preliminary investigations suggested that the 62-year-old driver, surnamed Fan, had been "triggered by (his) dissatisfaction with the division of property following his divorce", the police said in a statement.</p>

<p>Fan drove "a small SUV through the gate and forced his way into the city's sports centre, ramming people who were exercising on the internal roads of the sports centre", the statement added.</p>

<p>He was "controlled on the spot by the police who rushed to the scene as he attempted to drive away".</p>

<p>The police found Fan in his car cutting himself with a knife, before they stopped him and sent him to hospital.</p>

<p>He is currently in a coma after self-inflicted injuries to his neck and other parts of his body and unable to undergo interrogation, police added.</p>

<p>Chinese President Xi Jinping has urged "all-out efforts" to treat the people injured and has "demanded punishing the perpetrator in accordance with the law", the official Xinhua news agency said.</p>

<p><strong>Lying motionless</strong></p>

<p>Graphic videos circulating on social media on Monday night showed the aftermath of the incident, though most had disappeared by Tuesday.</p>

<p>China's largest airshow showcasing Beijing's civil and military aerospace sector is being held in the same city at the moment.</p>

<p>On Chinese social media platform Xiaohongshu, users expressed their shock at the death count.</p>

<p>"Last night after work, when I watched the news, there weren't this many people reported," one user commented on a photo of the police statement released. "Tonight, suddenly seeing this number -- so many families affected."</p>

<p>In a safety alert, Japan's embassy in China warned its citizens on Tuesday to be on high alert and "refrain from speaking loudly in Japanese and avoid provocative, attention-drawing behaviour such as being loud in groups".</p>

<p>The embassy said it had no information that any Japanese citizens had been wounded in the attack.</p>

<p>China has seen a spate of violent public attacks in recent months.</p>

<p>A man killed three people and wounded 15 in a knife attack at a supermarket in the Chinese megacity of Shanghai in October.</p>

<p>In September, a Japanese schoolboy was stabbed in the southern city of Shenzhen and died of his injuries, prompting outrage from Tokyo.</p>

<p>And in July, police said a vehicle crashed into pedestrians in the central city of Changsha, killing eight.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/g9ac9ei8_zhuhai-car-incident_625x300_12_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A car drove into a group of people outside a sports center in Zhuhai.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/krispy-kreme-to-celebrate-world-kindness-day-with-free-doughnuts-7001866]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Krispy Kreme To Celebrate World Kindness Day With Free Doughnuts]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/krispy-kreme-to-celebrate-world-kindness-day-with-free-doughnuts-7001866]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 12 Nov 2024 16:44:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The offer is valid across the US. Some of its international locations - the chain operates in 40 countries - also have World Kindness Day promotions planned.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It is very important to be kind to each other, to yourself and to the world. To remind people about the importance of the event, November 13 is observed as World kindness Day. Global doughnut chain Krispy Kreme has come up with an innovative idea to make this World Kindness Day extra sweet. It is offering free dozen original glazed doughnuts to eager customers. The offer applies to the first 500 guests in participating stores in various US locations, which means the bakery chain will be doling out approximately 6,000 free doughnuts per store.</p>

<p>"World Kindness Day is a reminder that we can all make a positive impact in people's lives, including through small gestures like sharing a sweet treat. We hope that each dozen Original Glazed doughnuts we give away enables and inspires many dozens of small acts of kindness," Krispy Kreme Global Chief Brand Office Dave Skena said in a release.</p>

<p>The offer is valid across the US. Some of its international locations - the chain operates in 40 countries - also have World Kindness Day promotions planned.</p>

<h3><strong>How to Get Your Free Doughnut</strong></h3>

<p>Participating in this sweet celebration is easy! On November 13th, simply head to your nearest Krispy Kreme store, and you'll be greeted with a warm smile and a free doughnut of your choice. Whether you prefer a classic Original Glazed, a decadent chocolate-filled treat, or something more adventurous, you can enjoy it at no cost.</p>

<p>According to UNESCO, World Kindness Day was first celebrated in 1998 by international NGO World Kindness Movement, which aims to promote goodwill around the world.</p>

<p>The UN body said that the day gives people the opportunity to reflect on one of the most important and unifying human principles - empathy, compassion and kindness. "On a day dedicated to the positive potential of acts of kindness big and small, let us collectively try to promote and spread this crucial quality that brings people of all kinds together," a note on UNESCO website says.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/sskgdkt_doughnuts_625x300_07_June_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[World Kindness Day is celebrated every year on November 13.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-open-to-talks-with-trump-administration-if-interests-align-7001786]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iran Open To Talks With Trump Administration If Interests Align]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-open-to-talks-with-trump-administration-if-interests-align-7001786]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 12 Nov 2024 16:37:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iran will pursue whatever secures its interest, government spokesperson Fatemeh Mohajerani said on Tuesday, when asked if there could be direct talks with the Trump administration.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Iran will pursue whatever secures its interest, government spokesperson Fatemeh Mohajerani said on Tuesday, when asked if there could be direct talks with the Trump administration.</p>

<p>"Whatever secures the country's interest and values of the revolution will be pursued by the government," Mohajerani told a journalist, according to the Iranian Student News Agency.</p>

<p>There have been no reports that Donald Trump or his team are planning any such talks as he prepares to return to the US presidency.</p>

<p>Trump unilaterally pulled the US out of Iran's 2015 nuclear deal with world powers during his last term of office in 2018 and re-applied sanctions which severely impacted the Iranian economy.</p>

<p>"The maximum pressure campaign of Trump has failed, even if people have been burdened by it. What is important will be actions and not words, but we recommend Trump to take into account the failure of his past policies," Mohajerani added.</p>

<p>Indirect talks between Washington and Tehran to revive the nuclear deal were initiated under the administration of US President Joe Biden, but stalled. Iran is still formally part of the deal but has scaled back commitments to honour it due to US sanctions reimposed on the Islamic Republic.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/q0i4c8f_iran_625x300_12_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Trump unilaterally pulled the US out of Iran's 2015 nuclear deal and pushed sanctions. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>