<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Fri, 05 Jul 2024 10:41:52 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/taiwan-urges-china-to-avoid-escalation-amid-renewed-military-activity-6037867]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Taiwan Urges China To Avoid Escalation Amid Renewed Military Activity]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/taiwan-urges-china-to-avoid-escalation-amid-renewed-military-activity-6037867]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 05 Jul 2024 10:03:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Taiwan on Friday reported renewed Chinese military activity nearby with another "combat patrol" as the government called on Beijing not to escalate tensions after the seizure of a Taiwanese fishing boat.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Taiwan on Friday reported renewed Chinese military activity nearby with another "combat patrol" as the government called on Beijing not to escalate tensions after the seizure of a Taiwanese fishing boat.</p>

<p>China, which views democratically governed Taiwan as its own territory, has stepped up its pressure over the past four years, both militarily and politically.</p>

<p>On Tuesday, Chinese officials boarded and detained a Taiwanese fishing boat for illegally operating in the country's waters, in what a senior Taiwan official said may be an act of psychological warfare.</p>

<p>Taiwan's defence ministry said that starting just before 7 a.m. (2300 GMT) on Friday, it had detected 26 Chinese military aircraft, including J-16 fighters, carrying out a "joint combat readiness patrol" with Chinese warships.</p>

<p>The Chinese aircraft flew into airspace to the north, centre and southern part of Taiwan, the ministry said.</p>

<p>Taiwan has detected at least 127 Chinese military aircraft operating near the island since the start of this month.</p>

<p>China's defence ministry did not immediately respond to a request for comment.</p>

<p>Speaking to reporters earlier on Friday, Taiwan Premier Cho Jung-tai said fishermen should raise their alert level and not do anything that could be considered illegal.</p>

<p>"At the same time, I also want to ask the Chinese side not to escalate with any the use of any excessive measures, because this can easily cause tension and unnecessary confrontation which is extremely unnecessary," he added.</p>

<p>China says the root cause of its problems with Taiwan is what Beijing views as the "separatist" views of new President Lai Ching-te.</p>

<p>China staged war games shortly after Lai took office in May, and has rebuffed his repeated calls for talks.</p>

<p>Lai rejects China's sovereignty claims, saying only Taiwan's people can decide their future.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-12/u0mfg8h_china-taiwan_625x300_18_December_23.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Taiwan has detected at least 127 Chinese military aircraft operating near the island]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-gets-its-future-back-labours-keir-starmer-in-victory-speech-6037737]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["UK Gets Its Future Back": Labour's Keir Starmer In Victory Speech]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-gets-its-future-back-labours-keir-starmer-in-victory-speech-6037737]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 05 Jul 2024 09:40:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Labour's Sir Keir Starmer delivered a storming victory speech Friday morning after the party swept the UK general election, declaring the country "gets its future back after 14 years (of a Conservative Party government)".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Labour's Sir <a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://ww.ndtv.com/topic/keir-starmer" target="_blank">Keir Starmer</a> delivered a storming victory speech Friday morning after the party swept the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world/uk" target="_blank">UK general election</a>, declaring the country "gets its future back after 14 years (of a Conservative Party government)". A relieved-looking Prime Minister-elect said, with a grin and to loud cheers, "We did it. You campaigned for it, fought for it, voted for it, and now it has arrived. And it feels good, to be honest."</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/topic/labour-party" target="_blank">Labour</a> crossed the majority mark of 326 - and is on course to match exit poll predictions of over 400 seats, a '<em>400 paar</em>' in the United Kingdom - in the 650-seat House of Commons early this morning, prompting outgoing PM <a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/topic/rishi-sunak" target="_blank">Rishi Sunak</a> to concede and promise a "peaceful and orderly" handover.</p>

<p>Mr Starmer thanked party workers for their hard work - including nearly five years of revamping and rebranding Labour in the face of Tory dominance - and urged them to savour the moment, but warned them of challenges ahead and pledged his government would work for "national renewal".</p>

<p>"We did it. Thank you truly... you have changed our country," Mr Starmer told a sea of supporters at a dawn victory rally in central London, "Four-and-a-half years of work changing this party... this is what it is for. A changed Labour... ready to restore Britain to the service of the working people."</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/i-am-sorry-uk-pm-rishi-sunak-concedes-defeat-in-uk-polls-6037606#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">Labour Sweeps UK Polls, Tories Ousted For 1st Time In 14 Years</a></p>

<p>"... across our country people will be waking up to the news... relieved a weight has been lifted (and) a burden finally removed from the shoulders of this great nation. Now, we can look forward (and) walk into the morning. The sunlight of hope, pale at first, but getting stronger through the day..."</p>

<p>"(But) a mandate like this comes with a great responsibility... Today we start the next chapter... begin the work of change, the mission of national renewal, and start to rebuild our country," he said.</p>

<p><strong>NDTV Explains |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/keir-starmer-on-course-to-be-uk-pm-what-this-means-for-india-6037593#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">Keir Starmer To Be UK PM: What This Means For India</a></p>

<p>"We have to return politics to public service and show out government can be a force for good," he said, even as results trickled in from across the country to add to Labour's already unbeatable lead.</p>

<p>Mr Starmer - who will be sworn in as Prime Minister - won his Holborn and St Pancras seat in despite a sharply reduced majority - from nearly 23,000 votes in 2019 to fewer than 12,000 this time.</p>

<p>Earlier today Rishi Sunak apologised to the Conservative Party and its supporters.</p>

<p>"I am sorry... I take responsibility for the loss," he said.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/i-am-sorry-uk-pm-rishi-sunak-concedes-defeat-in-uk-polls-6037606#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">"I Am Sorry": Rishi Sunak Concedes Defeat In UK Polls</a></p>

<p>Mr Sunak surprised many by calling for an election ahead of schedule - when his party was 20 points behind Labour in opinion polls - believing the gap would reverse, as it has in past elections.</p>

<p>Unfortunately it did not. Mr Sunak did, though, retain his seat of Richmond and Northallerton. He has vowed to continue as an MP even if, as is likely, he will be relieved of party leadership.</p>

<p>"The Labour Party has won this election and I have called Keir Starmer to congratulate him."</p>

<p>The <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-general-election-results-2024-live-keir-starmer-labour-party-tipped-for-historic-sweep-rishi-sunak-conservatives-6034921" target="_blank">Conservative suffered defeats in key constituencies</a>, and has been wiped out entirely in Wales - their worst result since 1997 - with Labour making big gains. The party won 27 of Wales' 32 seats, an increase of five from the last election. Plaid Cymru won four and the Liberal Democrats one.</p>

<p>Labour also made gains in Scotland, where the Scottish National Party - which was defending 48 of 57 seats - has been thumped. First Minister John Swinney called the results "damaging" for his party.</p>

<p>In Glasgow, Labour took all six seats from SNP.</p>

<p><em>NDTV is now available on WhatsApp channels. <a href="https://www.whatsapp.com/channel/0029Va4lixw7z4kcvZI9JM12">Click on the link</a> to get all the latest updates from NDTV on your chat. </em></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/0fukqq6_keir-starmer_625x300_05_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Labour leader Sir Keir Starmer will be the new UK Prime Minister (File).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/i-am-sorry-uk-pm-rishi-sunak-concedes-defeat-in-uk-polls-6037606]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["I Am Sorry": UK PM Rishi Sunak Concedes Defeat In UK Polls]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/i-am-sorry-uk-pm-rishi-sunak-concedes-defeat-in-uk-polls-6037606]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 05 Jul 2024 09:16:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[UK Prime Minister Rishi Sunak has conceded defeat in the country's general elections as the trends showed that the Opposition Labour Party had won over 300 seats, while Sunak's Conservative Party is ahead on 61.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>UK Prime Minister Rishi Sunak has conceded defeat in the country's general elections as the trends showed that the Opposition Labour Party had won over 300 seats, while Sunak's Conservative Party is ahead on 61.</p>

<p>"The Labour Party has won this general election, and I've called Sir Keir Starmer to congratulate him on his victory. Today, power will change hands in a peaceful and orderly manner, with goodwill on all sides. That is something that should give us all confidence in our country's stability and future," Rishi Sunak said while addressing his supporters in Richmond and Northern Allerton.</p>

<p>"I am sorry. I take responsibility for the loss," he added.</p>

<p>Sunak will tender his resignation to head of state King Charles III, with the monarch then asking Starmer, as the leader of the largest party in parliament, to form a government.</p>

<p>Keir Starmer's Labour Party will come to power facing a daunting challenge, with a sluggish economy, creaking public services, and falling living standards - all factors which contributed to the Conservatives' demise.</p>

<p>Keir Starmer will be Britain's next prime minister with his centre left Labour Party expected to win a huge majority in a parliamentary election, ending 14 years of often tumultuous Conservative government by trouncing Rishi Sunak's party.</p>

<p>Despite his convincing victory, polls have suggested there is little enthusiasm for Starmer or his party, and he comes to power at a time when the country is facing a series of daunting challenges.</p>

<p>Britain's tax burden is set to hit its highest since just after World War Two, net debt is almost equivalent to annual economic output, living standards have fallen, and public services are creaking, especially the much cherished National Health Service which has been dogged by strikes.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/um992j2_rishi-sunak-reuters_625x300_23_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/keir-starmer-on-course-to-be-uk-pm-what-this-means-for-india-6037593]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Keir Starmer To Be Next UK PM: What This Means For India]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/keir-starmer-on-course-to-be-uk-pm-what-this-means-for-india-6037593]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 05 Jul 2024 09:11:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Labour Party chief Keir Starmer is on course to replace Rishi Sunak as the Britain Prime Minister, with early election results pointing at a crushing loss for the Conservatives.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Labour Party chief Keir Starmer is on course to replace Rishi Sunak as the Britain Prime Minister, with early election results pointing at a crushing loss for the Conservatives. The first month of a Keir Starmer premiership will be a whirlwind of international diplomacy including meetings with US President Joe Biden and European leaders.</p>

<p>Labour, out of power since 2010, has pledged a foreign policy of "progressive realism", seeing a more volatile world "as it is not as we would want it to be", said David Lammy, who is expected to become foreign secretary.</p>

<p>The party has also pledged to "make Brexit work" and seek "an ambitious" security pact with the European Union.</p>

<p>Another key aspect of Starmer's foreign policy agenda will be strengthening UK-India relations. Acknowledging historical missteps, particularly Labour's stance on issues like Kashmir, Starmer has pledged to forge a new strategic partnership with India. His commitment to a free trade agreement (FTA) and enhanced bilateral cooperation in technology, security, education, and climate change underscores his ambition to elevate relations with one of the world's fastest-growing economies.</p>

<p>His manifesto included a commitment to pursue a "new strategic partnership" with India, emphasizing the trade agreement.</p>

<p>In a bid to repair strained ties with the Indian diaspora in the UK, Starmer during his campaign embarked on domestic outreach efforts, denouncing Hinduphobia and celebrating cultural festivals like Diwali and Holi. These gestures are aimed at fostering greater trust and inclusion within British-Indian communities, a demographic vital to Labour's electoral calculus.</p>

<p>However, challenges loom on the path to realising Starmer's ambitious foreign policy goals, particularly concerning immigration policies and trade agreements. With bipartisan consensus on the need to reduce immigration, negotiations on temporary visas for Indian workers in the UK service industry present a delicate balancing act for Labour.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Rishi Sunak's last-minute attempt to sway voters appears to have fallen short. The Conservatives warned voters that opting for Labour would lead to higher taxes. Led by Keir Starmer, the Labour Party is currently ahead on 220 seats, while Rishi Sunak's party has won just 31. To secure victory, a party needs to win 326 seats in the 650-member House of Commons.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/c6g0o5ag_keir-starmer_625x300_05_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Keir Starmer's Labour Party is heading for a landslide win.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/this-is-a-massacre-conservative-leader-as-labour-heads-for-massive-uk-win-6037516]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["A Massacre": Conservative Leader As Labour Heads For Massive UK Win]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/this-is-a-massacre-conservative-leader-as-labour-heads-for-massive-uk-win-6037516]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 05 Jul 2024 08:56:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Scottish Conservative Party leader Ruth Davison described the UK exit poll prediction of a historic defeat for her party as a "massacre". As the votes are being counted, UK PM Rishi Sunak's Conservative party is staring at a massive loss.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Scottish Conservative Party leader Ruth Davison described the UK exit poll prediction of a historic defeat for her party as a "massacre". As the votes are being counted, UK PM Rishi Sunak's Conservative party is staring at a massive loss against Keir Starmer's Labour Party which has won over 183 seats so far. The Conservatives or Tories have won 31.</p>

<p>"So actually 131 – while, there is no dressing it up, this is a massacre – they've actually, if this is right, pulled a few back from where they thought they were. But it was not as bad as it might have been," she told Sky News.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The exit poll, published jointly by the BBC, ITV and Sky News, suggested that the Labour Party will win in 410 constituencies will the Conservative numbers will plunge to 131. It also predicts 61 seats for the Liberal Democrats, 13 for Reform UK, four for Plaid Cymru and two for the Green Party. Other parties are expected to win 19 seats.</p>

<p>To secure victory, a party needs to win 326 seats in the 650-member House of Commons.</p>

<p>The results of the sudden elections called by Rishi Sunak in May are hardly surprising as throughout the six-week campaign the UK PM trailed behind 61-year-old Starmer.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Indian-origin PM's term was marred by cost-of-living and migration crisis following years of instability under five different Conservative prime ministers since 2016.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/um992j2_rishi-sunak-reuters_625x300_23_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/keir-starmer-on-course-to-become-next-uk-pm-wins-home-constituency-6037270]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Keir Starmer, On Course To Become Next UK PM, Wins Home Constituency]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/keir-starmer-on-course-to-become-next-uk-pm-wins-home-constituency-6037270]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 05 Jul 2024 07:49:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[UK Labour Party chief Keir Starmer has emerged victorious from his home seat in London as he inches closer to replace Rishi Sunak as the Prime Minister.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>UK Labour Party chief Keir Starmer has emerged victorious from his home seat in London as he inches closer to replace Rishi Sunak as the Prime Minister.</p>

<p>Mr Starmer vowed to serve every person in the constituency after winning from Holborn and St Pancras in the early morning results with 18,884 votes. His winning margin, however, was lower than that of previous elections.</p>

<p>Exit polls had projected a Labour sweep after Thursday's elections, drubbing the Sunak-led Conservatives. However, such projections often go wrong.</p>

<p>In his first remarks after the morning victory, Starmer thanked his voters and said it was a "huge privilege" to be re-elected from Holborn and St Pancras. "You have voted. It's now time for us to deliver," BBC quoted him as saying.</p>

<p>The heart of the UK's democracy beats not in Westminster or Whitehall, but in town halls, community centres and in the hands of people who hold the vote, he said. "Change begins in this community with the people who came together to make life better," the Labour leader added.</p>

<p>He said he would work for everyone in his constituency, irrespective of who voted for him. "I will speak out for you, have your back, fight your corner every single day," he said.</p>

<p>The people are ready for change and the change begins right here because this is your democracy, your community, your future, he told his voters.</p>

<p>Votes being counted for yesterday's elections have put the Labour Party at 133 seats as against the Conservatives' 19, showed data at 8:15 am.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/7ufhjkpg_starmer-sunak-afp_625x300_05_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ex-brazil-president-jair-bolsonaro-accused-in-saudi-jewel-scandal-6037267]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ex-Brazil President Jair Bolsonaro Accused In Saudi Jewel Scandal]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ex-brazil-president-jair-bolsonaro-accused-in-saudi-jewel-scandal-6037267]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 05 Jul 2024 07:48:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Brazil's former president Jair Bolsonaro is facing possible money laundering and other charges related to undeclared diamond jewelry gifted by Saudi Arabia, local media reported Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Brazil's former president Jair Bolsonaro is facing possible money laundering and other charges related to undeclared diamond jewelry gifted by Saudi Arabia, local media reported Thursday.</p>

<p>Federal police accused Bolsonaro, who led South America's largest country from 2019-2022, of money laundering, embezzlement and criminal association, Brazilian news outlet G1 reported.</p>

<p>The case stems from an undeclared set of diamond jewellery worth $3.2 million that was seized by customs inspectors in October 2021.</p>

<p>The jewels were inside a satchel from Bolsonaro's Mining and Energy ministry entourage upon returning from a trip to the Middle East.</p>

<p>Bolsonaro has previously denied any criminal activity in the case.</p>

<p>Eleven other people were facing charges alongside the far-right leader, including his attorney Fabio Wajngarten.</p>

<p>Wajngarten reacted on X, saying he had been accused of crimes "for the bizarre reason of having complied with the law."</p>

<p>Bolsonaro's son, the Brazilian senator Flavio Bolsonaro, also slammed the accusations on X as "open and brazen persecution" against his father.</p>

<p>Despite the moves by the federal police, Brazil's Attorney General Office has yet to issue any formal charges against Bolsonaro before the country's Federal Supreme Court.</p>

<p>The new accusations represent the latest legal trouble for the far-right former leader, who is also under investigation for his role in the January 2023 Brazil Congress attack and faces possible charges for forging Covid-19 vaccination documents to travel.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-02/e1uj056g_bolsonaro-generic_625x300_05_February_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Jair Bolsonaro has previously denied any criminal activity in the case.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/openais-internal-system-hacked-ai-tech-details-stolen-in-2023-report-6037225]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[OpenAI's Internal System Hacked, AI Tech Details Stolen In 2023: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/openais-internal-system-hacked-ai-tech-details-stolen-in-2023-report-6037225]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 05 Jul 2024 07:38:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A hacker gained access to the internal messaging systems at OpenAI last year and stole details about the design of the company's artificial intelligence technologies, the New York Times reported on Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A hacker gained access to the internal messaging systems at OpenAI last year and stole details about the design of the company's artificial intelligence technologies, the New York Times reported on Thursday.</p>

<p>The hacker lifted details from discussions in an online forum where employees talked about OpenAI's latest technologies, the report said, citing two people familiar with the incident.</p>

<p>However, they did not get into the systems where OpenAI, the firm behind chatbot sensation ChatGPT, houses and builds its AI, the report added.</p>

<p>Microsoft Corp-backed OpenAI did not immediately respond to a Reuters request for comment.</p>

<p>OpenAI executives informed both employees at an all-hands meeting in April last year and the company's board about the breach, according to the report, but executives decided not to share the news publicly as no information about customers or partners had been stolen.</p>

<p>OpenAI executives did not consider the incident a national security threat, believing the hacker was a private individual with no known ties to a foreign government, the report said. The San Francisco-based company did not inform the federal law enforcement agencies about the breach, it added.</p>

<p>OpenAI in May said it had disrupted five covert influence operations that sought to use its AI models for "deceptive activity" across the internet, the latest to stir safety concerns about the potential misuse of the technology.</p>

<p>The Biden administration was poised to open up a new front in its effort to safeguard the U.S. AI technology from China and Russia with preliminary plans to place guardrails around the most advanced AI Models including ChatGPT, Reuters earlier reported, citing sources.</p>

<p>In May, 16 companies developing AI pledged at a global meeting to develop the technology safely at a time when regulators are scrambling to keep up with rapid innovation and emerging risks.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ioh2ev8_open-ai-reuters_625x300_05_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[OpenAI in May said it had disrupted five covert influence operations that sought to use its AI models.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-election-results-live-rishi-sunak-braces-for-huge-loss-as-early-results-herald-labour-keir-starmer-win-6037190]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Labour Sweeps UK Polls, Rishi Sunak's Party Ousted For 1st Time In 14 Years]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-election-results-live-rishi-sunak-braces-for-huge-loss-as-early-results-herald-labour-keir-starmer-win-6037190]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 05 Jul 2024 07:23:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Keir Starmer's Labour Party scored a landslide victory in the UK general elections, a result that reflects a seismic realignment in British politics as Rishi Sunak's Conservative Party imploded.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<ol>
	<li>Prime Minister Rishi Sunak's last-minute attempt to sway voters fell short as his Conservative Party lost the UK general elections. Ahead of voting, the Conservatives warned voters that opting for Labour would lead to higher taxes.</li>
	<li>Led by Keir Starmer, the Labour Party has crossed the majority mark of 326 in the 650-member House of Commons. Rishi Sunak's party has managed to win just 60 seats yet.</li>
	<li>Conceding defeat, Rishi Sunak said, "Today, power will change hands in a peaceful and orderly manner, with goodwill on all sides. That is something that should give us all confidence in our country's stability and future," Rishi Sunak said while addressing his supporters in Richmond and Northern Allerton. "I am sorry. I take responsibility for the loss," he added.</li>
	<li>Keir Starmer will be appointed the Prime Minister later today. "Tonight people here and around the country have spoken, and they're ready for change," he said. "The change begins right here."</li>
	<li>The official election exit poll had predicted Labour will win 410 seats, the most since Tony Blair's 1997 landslide victory, with a projected majority of 170. In the last six UK elections, only one exit poll has got the outcome wrong.</li>
	<li>In May, Rishi Sunak stunned many in his own party by calling the election earlier than he needed to with the Conservatives trailing Labour by some 20 points in opinion polls.</li>
	<li>He had hoped the gap would narrow, as typically seen in British elections, but the deficit persisted through what is seen as a largely unsuccessful campaign.</li>
	<li>Keir Starmer, the son of a toolmaker and a nurse, has promised "a decade of national renewal" after post-financial crash austerity measures, Brexit upheaval and a cost-of-living crisis.</li>
	<li>But, he faces significant challenges ahead, including sluggish economic growth, strained and underfunded public services due to extensive cuts over the past fourteen years, and financial pressures on households.</li>
	<li>For Sunak, the early trends suggest a defeat that has been on the cards for months. He has said he will stay on as an MP even if he's removed or steps down as Tory leader — though some polls predict he may not keep his seat.</li>
</ol>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/90sbkq5c_rishi-sunak_625x300_05_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bali-reefs-ruined-by-coral-bleaching-as-sea-temperature-rises-6037160]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bali Coral Reefs Ruined By Bleaching As Sea Temperature Rises]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bali-reefs-ruined-by-coral-bleaching-as-sea-temperature-rises-6037160]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 05 Jul 2024 07:11:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Indonesian conservationist Nyoman Sugiarto has been working for 16 years to preserve coral on the reefs of Bali, but the frequency of mass coral bleachings he says is now devastating.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Indonesian conservationist Nyoman Sugiarto has been working for 16 years to preserve coral on the reefs of Bali, but the frequency of mass coral bleachings he says is now devastating.</p>

<p>Ninety per cent of the corals Sugiarto had nurtured on the reefs near his village in Bondalem, on the northern shore of Bali, lost their colour last December.</p>

<p>"It was all white. We were shocked and of course, it also negatively affected the coral we planted. It's not just the natural ones," 51-year-old Sugiarto told Reuters.</p>

<p>When Sugiarto began coral conservation projects in 2008 he was told that coral could retain the living algae which gives it colour for 10 to 20 years.</p>

<p>Yet, the coral reefs off Bondalem were bleached in less than 10 years, he says, blaming warmer sea temperatures triggered by climate change.</p>

<p>Coral bleaching occurs when coral expels the colourful algae living in its tissues. Without the algae, the coral becomes pale and vulnerable to starvation, disease or death.</p>

<p>In April, the U.S. National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) said more than 54% of the reef areas in the world's oceans are experiencing bleaching-level heat stress, the fourth global bleaching event in the last three decades.</p>

<p>Indonesia has roughly 5.1 million hectares of coral reefs and accounts for 18% of the world's total, data from the country's tourism ministry showed.</p>

<p>Coral bleaching in Bali in late 2023 was mainly caused by rising sea temperatures caused by the El Nino phenomenon that hit Indonesia, said Marthen Welly, a marine conservation adviser at the Coral Triangle Center.</p>

<p>Indonesia experienced the most severe dry season last year since 2019 due to the El Nino.</p>

<p>While Indonesia's corals are more resilient and tend to recover faster, Marthen said it will not be enough to withstand the rising ocean temperature.</p>

<p>"It's predicted that the coral bleaching will occur more often, between one or two years with the current temperature," he said, quoting the latest research by the Great Barrier Reef Marine Park Authority and the Australian Institute of Marine Science.</p>

<p>However, Sugiarto says he is determined to continue his campaign to conserve corals and is advocating coral conservation to younger Indonesians and seeking funds to establish a village community to monitor illegal fishing.</p>

<p>"We feel that we have the obligation to guard the sustainability of underwater life, especially corals," he said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/27b0q96g_coral-reef-bleaching-bali_625x300_05_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Coral bleaching in Bali in late 2023 was mainly caused by rising sea temperatures caused by the El Nino.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/labour-heads-landslide-win-in-uk-rishi-sunak-far-behind-early-trends-6037096]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Labour Heads For Landslide Win In UK, Rishi Sunak Far Behind: Early Trends]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/labour-heads-landslide-win-in-uk-rishi-sunak-far-behind-early-trends-6037096]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 05 Jul 2024 06:49:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Britain's main opposition Labour party looks set for a landslide election win, exit polls indicated on Thursday, with Keir Starmer replacing Rishi Sunak as prime minister, ending 14 years of Conservative rule.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Britain's main opposition Labour party looks set for a landslide election win, exit polls indicated on Thursday, with Keir Starmer replacing Rishi Sunak as prime minister, ending 14 years of Conservative rule.</p>

<p>The survey for UK broadcasters suggested centre-left Labour would win 410 seats in the 650-seat House of Commons, with the right-wing Tories managing only 131 -- a record low.</p>

<p>In another boost for the centrists, the smaller opposition Liberal Democrats would get 61 seats, ousting the Scottish National Party on 10 as the third biggest party.</p>

<p>Nigel Farage's hard-right anti-immigration Reform UK party could secure 13, with Welsh nationalists Plaid Cymru four and the Greens doubling their MPs to two.</p>

<p>Labour's majority would be 170 -- more than double than that won by Boris Johnson for the Tories at the last election in December 2019 dominated by Brexit.</p>

<p>"To everyone who has campaigned for Labour in this election, to everyone who voted for us and put their trust in our changed Labour Party -- thank you," Starmer wrote on social media.</p>

<p>Outside Starmer's local pub The Pineapple in north London, pub-goers called the expected result "a new dawn" but there were no wild celebrations.</p>

<p>Starmer's deputy, Angela Rayner, told the BBC the numbers were "encouraging... but I'm not counting my chickens until we've got those results coming in".</p>

<p>Former Conservative leader William Hague told Times Radio the projected result would be "a catastrophic result in historic terms" for the Tories.</p>

<p>The Tories worst previous result is 156 seats in 1906.</p>

<p>But Tim Bale, politics professor at Queen Mary, University of London, said it was "not as catastrophic as some were predicting" and the Tories, riven by ideological infighting, needed now to decide which direction they would take.</p>

<h2>'Brighter future'</h2>

<p>Counting of ballots from some 40,000 polling stations across the country stretches into the night, with official results expected into Friday morning.</p>

<p>The first to declare, just over an hour after polls closed at 2100 GMT, was Houghton and Sunderland South, in northeast England, where Labour's Bridget Phillipson was returned as MP.</p>

<p>Phillipson, nailed on to become education secretary, said in an acceptance speech that Britons seemed to have chosen a "brighter future".</p>

<p>"After 14 years the British people have voted change... Labour will honour the trust that you have placed in us," she told supporters to applause.</p>

<p>The projected overall result bucks a rightward trend among Britain's closest Western allies, with the far-right in France eyeing power and Donald Trump looking set for a return in the United States.</p>

<p>Under Britain's first-past-the-post electoral system, a party needs 326 seats to win an overall majority in parliament.</p>

<p>The leader of the winning party is expected to meet head of state King Charles III on Friday morning, who will ask the leader of the largest party to form a government.</p>

<p>Ministerial appointments are expected to follow soon after an acceptance speech in Downing Street.</p>

<h2>To-do list</h2>

<p>Confirmation of the result would cap a remarkable rise to power for Starmer, 61, who was first elected as a member of parliament in 2015 -- and a stunning turnaround for Labour.</p>

<p>The former human rights lawyer and chief public prosecutor was elected Labour leader in early 2020, succeeding the veteran leftist Jeremy Corbyn, who lost by a landslide to Johnson in 2019 -- Labour's worst performance since 1935.</p>

<p>Starmer has since dragged the party back to the centre ground, making it a more electable proposition and purging infighting with the hard-left and anti-Semitism that lost it support.</p>

<p>Opinion polls have given Labour a consistent 20-point lead over the Tories for almost the past two years, which a largely lacklustre election campaign has failed to change.</p>

<p>Some polls predicted a virtual wipe-out for the Tories, given negative public opinion and the arrival of Reform UK to split the right-wing vote.</p>

<p>That gave an air of inevitability about a Labour win -- the first since Tony Blair in 2005 -- which the party feared could hit turn-out.</p>

<p>Starmer -- the working-class son of a toolmaker and a nurse -- has promised "a decade of national renewal" after post-financial crash austerity measures, Brexit upheaval and a cost-of-living crisis.</p>

<p>But his to-do list is daunting, with economic growth anaemic, public services overstretched and underfunded due to nearly a decade-and-a-half of swingeing cuts, and households squeezed financially.</p>

<p>The Labour leader has also promised a return of political integrity, after a chaotic period of five Tory prime ministers, including three in four months, scandal and sleaze.</p>

<p>His first days in office are set to be packed, representing Britain at the NATO conference in Washington next week, then hosting European leaders later this month at a summit in southern England.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/u4pllgd8_rishi-sunak-and-keir-starmer_625x300_04_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Ministerial appointments are expected to follow soon after an acceptance speech in Downing Street.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistan-to-ban-all-social-media-platforms-for-6-days-to-curb-hate-material-6036754]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Pak To Ban All Social Media Platforms For 6 Days To Curb 'Hate Material']]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistan-to-ban-all-social-media-platforms-for-6-days-to-curb-hate-material-6036754]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 05 Jul 2024 04:50:00 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Pakistan government is now set to ban all social media platforms -- YouTube, WhatsApp, Facebook, Instagram and TikTok -- for six days from July 13 to 18, citing the need to control "hate material" during the Islamic month of Ramadan.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After successfully blocking X, formerly Twitter, for over four months, the Pakistan government is now set to ban all social media platforms -- YouTube, WhatsApp, Facebook, Instagram and TikTok -- for six days from July 13 to 18, citing the need to control "hate material" during the Islamic month of Ramadan.</p>

<p>Chief Minister Maryam Nawaz's cabinet committee on law and order has recommended banning of all social media platforms -- YouTube, X, WhatsApp, Facebook, Instagram, and TikTok, among others --during 6 to 11 Muharram (July 13-18) in Punjab, a province of over 120 million people, to "control hate material, misinformation to avoid sectarian violence", according to a Punjab government notification issued here late Thursday night.</p>

<p>The Punjab government of Maryam Nawaz has requested her uncle Shehbaz Sharif's government at the Centre to notify the suspension of all social media platforms on internet for six days (July 13-18).</p>

<p>Pakistan Army Chief Gen Asim Munir has already declared social media a "vicious media" and underscored the need to fight what he called "digital terrorism".</p>

<p>Pakistan's Deputy Prime Minister Ishaq Dar, who also holds the portfolio of foreign minister, recently called for placing a complete ban on social media.</p>

<p>The Shehbaz government had shut down X in last February following allegations of change of general election results by the Election Commission of Pakistan, apparently on the order of the military establishment to stop Pakistan Tehreek-i-Insaf's jailed founder Imran Khan from coming to power.</p>

<p>Both the military and the government were receiving backlash on social media since the ouster of former prime minister Imran Khan through a no-confidence motion in April 2022.</p>

<p>The government has arrested dozens of social media activists of Khan's party since then.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-06/49ef9qsk_social-media-generic-pixabay_625x300_07_June_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Pakistan government is set to ban all social media platforms between 13 and 18 July.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-elections-who-could-get-key-roles-in-a-uk-labour-government-6036655]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Who Could Get Key Roles In A UK Labour Government?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-elections-who-could-get-key-roles-in-a-uk-labour-government-6036655]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 05 Jul 2024 04:10:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[With Labour predicted to become the biggest party in the UK parliament, here are the contenders for the most prominent ministerial positions.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With Labour predicted to become the biggest party in the UK parliament, here are the contenders for the most prominent ministerial positions.</p>

<p><strong>- Deputy Prime Minister: Angela Rayner -</strong></p>

<p>Rayner, 44, is an outlier in a country long dominated by a ruling class disproportionately educated at private schools and Oxford and Cambridge universities.</p>

<p>She grew up in social housing in northern England, left school without a degree and became a single mother at 16.</p>

<p>A trade unionist before being elected to parliament in 2015, she was elected as Labour's number two in 2020.</p>

<p>Her left-wing background and straight-talking style -- complete with strong northern accent -- contrasts with Starmer's more staid public persona.</p>

<p>"He smooths off my rough edges. I bring him out of his shell," she has famously said of their partnership.</p>

<p>As well as being deputy prime minister -- filling in for Starmer at weekly parliamentary questions when he is unable to attend -- Rayner would be responsible for housing policy and tackling regional inequalities.</p>

<p><strong>- Finance: Rachel Reeves -</strong></p>

<p>The former Bank of England economist is in line to become the first female Chancellor of the Exchequer, living next door to Starmer at 11 Downing Street.</p>

<p>Reeves, 45, has called that prospect shattering "the last glass ceiling in politics".</p>

<p>A central figure in Labour efforts over the last four years to regain the electorate's trust on economic issues, she insists it is now "the natural party of British business".</p>

<p>Using her reputation for economic competence, Londoner Reeves, whose younger sister is also an MP, has pledged "iron discipline" on public finances.</p>

<p>The former child chess champion, an MP since 2010, has vowed to be both "pro-worker" and "pro-business" in her role overseeing the public purse.</p>

<p><strong>- Foreign affairs: David Lammy -</strong></p>

<p>Lammy, 51, a black lawmaker descended from slaves, has honed his vision for UK diplomacy with dozens of foreign trips in the past two years.</p>

<p>He has argued that the foreign ministry needs to "rediscover the art of grand strategy" in the post-Brexit era.</p>

<p>Lammy, an MP since the age of 27 in 2000, is likely to steer Britain towards closer EU ties -- no easy task with both Brussels and Eurosceptic Britons reticent.</p>

<p>He will also likely face pressure from Labour's left flank over issues including its policy towards Israel and its war against Hamas in Gaza.</p>

<p>A friend of former US President Barack Obama, Lammy may also have to deal with the possible White House return of Donald Trump.</p>

<p>He once described Trump as a "neo-Nazi sympathising sociopath" and "profound threat to the international order".</p>

<p><strong>- Home Affairs: Yvette Cooper -</strong></p>

<p>Cooper's decades of political experience will undoubtedly be sorely tested heading the Home Office -- Britain's interior ministry -- a notoriously hard government department to succeed in.</p>

<p>An MP since the late 1990s and a minister in the 2000s, Cooper, 55, has been Labour's home affairs spokesperson over two stints during its 14 years in opposition.</p>

<p>A candidate to be party leader in 2015, plaudits credit her grasp of policy and details as well as stellar communication skills.</p>

<p>Immigration -- a major election campaign issue and potential weak point for Labour -- will likely dominate much of the public discussion around her brief.</p>

<p><strong>- Health: Wes Streeting -</strong></p>

<p>A fresh-faced Labour centrist, Streeting has been one of the most visible Labour figures during the election campaign.</p>

<p>Hailed as one of its best communicators, the 41-year-old from a working-class background in east London is tipped as a potential future leader.</p>

<p>But first he will have to prove himself in one of the toughest jobs in UK government, charged with reversing the decline in the country's cherished but ailing National Health Service (NHS).</p>

<p>Weighed down by years of austerity under the Conservatives and still struggling to recover from the pandemic, Streeting -- a cancer survivor -- will rely in part on his own experience of the system.</p>

<p><strong>- Defence: John Healey -</strong></p>

<p>Party veteran Healey is set to become defence secretary as the policy area gains importance given the war in Ukraine and rising global insecurity.</p>

<p>The 64-year-old, who first became an MP in 1997 when Tony Blair won power for Labour, held a series of government posts during the party's 13-year spell in charge.</p>

<p>Labour has promised to increase military spending to 2.5 percent of GDP (from 2.3 percent this year) "as soon as" economic conditions allow.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/0fukqq6_keir-starmer_625x300_05_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Keir Starmer's Labour Party is set to win the general election after 14 years of Conservative rule.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-will-uk-foreign-policy-look-like-under-labours-keir-starmer-6036608]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What Will UK Foreign Policy Look Like Under Labour's Keir Starmer?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-will-uk-foreign-policy-look-like-under-labours-keir-starmer-6036608]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 05 Jul 2024 03:56:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The first month of a Keir Starmer premiership will be a whirlwind of international diplomacy including meetings with US President Joe Biden and European leaders.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The first month of a Keir Starmer premiership will be a whirlwind of international diplomacy including meetings with US President Joe Biden and European leaders.</p>

<p>His first steps on the world stage will be just days away, at the NATO 75th anniversary summit being held in Washington next Tuesday to Thursday.</p>

<p>Starmer will then play host at Blenheim Palace, near Oxford, in central England, on July 18, at a European Political Community meeting, with France's Emmanuel Macron and Germany's Olaf Scholz expected.</p>

<p>Labour, out of power since 2010, has pledged a foreign policy of "progressive realism", seeing a more volatile world "as it is not as we would want it to be", said David Lammy, who is expected to become foreign secretary.</p>

<p>The party has also pledged to "make Brexit work" and seek "an ambitious" security pact with the the European Union.</p>

<p>Here is a rundown of how a Labour government could approach the major international issues it faces.</p>

<p><strong>- China -</strong></p>

<p>Labour would undertake a "full audit" across all government departments of the UK's relationship with China to "set the direction and course" of its China policy, Lammy told reporters this week.</p>

<p>Starmer last year said the UK needed to "wean itself off" China on issues like trade, commerce and technology while acknowledging the importance of being able to cooperate on issues such as tackling climate change.</p>

<p>The challenge will be to balance the UK's trade and economic interests with security imperatives.</p>

<p>That could be complicated by a possible return of Donald Trump in Washington after the US presidential election in November.</p>

<p>Trump would be expected to ramp up pressure on allies to be tougher with Beijing.</p>

<p><strong>- Israel-Palestinian conflict -</strong></p>

<p>Labour says it is committed to recognising a Palestinian state "as a contribution to a renewed peace process which results in a two-state solution".</p>

<p>But it has not set out any timescale for doing so.</p>

<p>Other commitments include pushing for an immediate ceasefire, the release of all hostages and an increase in the amount of aid getting into Gaza.</p>

<p>- Europe -</p>

<p>Starmer has pledged to work with France's far-right National Rally (RN) party if it wins power.</p>

<p>"I will work with any government in Europe and across the world if we are elected... For me, that's what serious government is about," he said.</p>

<p>He said both bilateral deals with France and agreements with the whole EU, which the UK voted to leave in 2016 leading to a messy divorce, were important to address the issue of migrants crossing the Channel in small boats.</p>

<p>Pressed on RN leader Marine Le Pen's preference for bilateral deals over EU-wide ones, Starmer said the two were not mutually exclusive.</p>

<p>He said existing bilateral agreements with France needed to be strengthened and improved "particularly in relation to smashing the gangs that are running the vile trade of putting people into boats".</p>

<p>"But there are also EU measures," he added. "The security agreement we want with the EU when it comes to dealing with smuggling gangs is really important."</p>

<p><strong>- Ukraine -</strong></p>

<p>The UK has been one of Kyiv's staunchest supporters and has provided money, weapons and troop training to help it repel Russia's invasion.</p>

<p>Labour have stressed continued support for Ukraine if they win, and Starmer would be expected to meet Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky early to reaffirm that message in person.</p>

<p>Starmer has said a meeting with Russian President Vladimir Putin is "simply not an issue" at the moment and described him as "the aggressor in Ukraine".</p>

<p>"The most important thing is to be absolutely clear that our support for Ukraine is on a united front in this country," he said.</p>

<p><strong>- Defence spending -</strong></p>

<p>A strategic defence review would be carried out within the first year of government to set out a path to an increase in defence spending to 2.5 percent of GDP.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/cin2484_uk-labour_625x300_05_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Starmer last year said the UK needed to "wean itself off" China on issues like trade and technology.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/keir-starmer-ex-rights-lawyer-musician-set-to-take-uk-labour-back-to-power-6036578]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Keir Starmer: Ex-Rights Lawyer, Musician Set To Take Labour Back To Power]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/keir-starmer-ex-rights-lawyer-musician-set-to-take-uk-labour-back-to-power-6036578]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 05 Jul 2024 03:47:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[UK Labour leader Keir Starmer is an ex-human rights lawyer and public prosecutor who will have to focus his relentless work ethic and methodical mind to fixing the country.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>UK Labour leader Keir Starmer is an ex-human rights lawyer and public prosecutor who will have to focus his relentless work ethic and methodical mind to fixing the country.</p>

<p>If exit polls are confirmed, at 61, Starmer will be the oldest person to become British prime minister in almost half a century -- and comes just nine years since he was first elected to parliament.</p>

<p>The married father-of-two is unlike most modern politicians: he had a long and distinguished career before becoming an MP and his views are rooted in pragmatism rather than ideology.</p>

<p>"We must return politics to service," Starmer said repeatedly during the campaign, promising to put "country first, party second" following 14 chaotic years of Conservative rule under five different prime ministers.</p>

<p>That mantra chimes with supporters' lauding of him as a managerial safe pair of hands who will approach life in Downing Street the same way he did his legal career: seriously and forensically.</p>

<p>Detractors, though, label him an uninspiring opportunist who regularly shifts position on an issue and who has failed to spell out a clear and defining vision for the country.</p>

<p>Football-mad Starmer, a devoted Arsenal fan, has struggled to shed his public image as buttoned-up and boring and only recently started to appear more at ease in the public spotlight.</p>

<p>Supporters admit that he fails to ooze the charisma of more flashy predecessors like Boris Johnson, but say that therein lies his appeal: a reassuring and strait-laced presence following the turbulent, self-serving years of Tory rule.</p>

<p>With his grey quiff and black-rimmed glasses -- Starmer, named after Labour's founding father Keir Hardie -- is also the centre-left party's most working-class leader in decades.</p>

<p>"My dad was a toolmaker, my mum was a nurse," he tells voters often, countering depictions by opponents that he is the epitome of a smug, liberal, London elite.</p>

<p>Starmer's purging of left-wingers from his party highlights a ruthless side that has propelled him to Britain's highest political office, but he is said to be funny in private and loyal to his friends.</p>

<p>He has pledged to maintain his habit of not working after 6:00 pm on a Friday to spend time with his wife Victoria, who works as an occupational therapist in the National Health Service, and their two teenage children, who he does not name in public.</p>

<p>"There's something extraordinary in him still being quite normal," Starmer's biographer Tom Baldwin wrote in the Guardian.</p>

<p><strong>Top Lawyer</strong></p>

<p>Born on September 2, 1962, Keir Rodney Starmer was raised in a cramped, pebble-dashed semi-detached house on the outskirts of London by a seriously ill mother and an emotionally distant father.</p>

<p>He had three siblings, one of whom had learning difficulties. His parents were animal lovers who rescued donkeys.</p>

<p>A talented musician, Starmer had violin lessons at school with Norman Cook, the former Housemartins bassist who became DJ Fatboy Slim.</p>

<p>After legal studies at the universities of Leeds and Oxford, Starmer turned his attention to leftist causes, defending trade unions, anti-McDonald's activists, and death row inmates abroad.</p>

<p>He is friends with human rights lawyer Amal Clooney from their time together at the same legal practice and once recounted a boozy lunch he had with her and her Hollywood actor husband George.</p>

<p>In 2003, he began moving towards the establishment, shocking colleagues and friends, first with a job ensuring police in Northern Ireland complied with human rights legislation.</p>

<p>Five years later, he was appointed director of public prosecutions (DPP) for England and Wales when Labour's Gordon Brown was prime minister.</p>

<p>Between 2008 and 2013, he oversaw the prosecution of MPs for abusing their expenses, journalists for phone-hacking, and young rioters involved in unrest across England.</p>

<p>He was knighted by Queen Elizabeth II, but rarely uses the prefix "Sir", and in 2015 was elected as a member of parliament, representing a seat in left-leaning north London.</p>

<p>Just weeks before he was elected, his mother died of a rare disease of the joints that had left her unable to walk for many years.</p>

<p><strong>Rebellion</strong></p>

<p>Just a year after becoming an MP, Starmer joined a rebellion by Labour lawmakers over radical left-winger Jeremy Corbyn's perceived lack of leadership during the EU referendum campaign.</p>

<p>It failed, and later that year he rejoined the top team as Labour's Brexit spokesman, where he remained until succeeding Corbyn after he took the party to its worst defeat since 1935 in the last election five years ago.</p>

<p>Starmer moved the party back to the more electable centre ground, purging Corbyn and rooting out anti-Semitism.</p>

<p>Dominic Grieve, who as Conservative attorney-general worked closely with Starmer as DPP, said he "inspires loyalty because he comes across as being so transparently decent and rational".</p>

<p>"These are quite important features even if you disagree with a policy. And he comes across as man of moderation," he told The Times.</p>

<p>Nevertheless, the left accuses him of betrayal for dropping a number of pledges he made during his successful leadership campaign, including the scrapping of university tuition fees.</p>

<p>But his successful strategic repositioning of Labour is indicative of a constant throughout his life: a drive to succeed.</p>

<p>"If you're born without privilege, you don't have time for messing around," Starmer once said.</p>

<p>"You don't walk around problems without fixing them, and you don't surrender to the instincts of organisations that won't face up to change."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/68ukip18_keir-starmer-wife-reuters_625x300_05_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The married father-of-two, Keir Starmer is unlike most modern politicians]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-elections-what-does-uks-labour-want-to-do-6036572]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What Does UK's Labour Want To Do?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-elections-what-does-uks-labour-want-to-do-6036572]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 05 Jul 2024 03:43:00 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Britain's Labour party, predicted to win Thursday's election, is promising a "decade of national renewal" and with a record landslide that gives the party a free reign to implement its programme.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Britain's Labour party, predicted to win Thursday's election, is promising a "decade of national renewal" and with a record landslide that gives the party a free reign to implement its programme. &nbsp;</p>

<p>Here are its policies on key issues:</p>

<p>- <strong>Economy </strong>-</p>

<p>Labour has vowed to follow the UK fiscal rules and ruled out increasing income tax, National Insurance welfare contributions and VAT sales tax -- although senior figures have not ruled out other tax rises -- limiting its scope for boosting public spending.</p>

<p>It hopes to plug the gap through improved growth, the elimination of the tax breaks for non-domiciled UK residents, reducing tax avoidance and the imposition of VAT on private school fees.</p>

<p>It also intends to use a windfall tax on energy companies and borrowing to fund its "green prosperity plan".</p>

<p>- <strong>Healthcare </strong>-</p>

<p>Often the highest priority for UK voters, the country's free-at-point-of-use National Health Service (NHS) is currently buckling under the strain of tight budgets, a 7.5-million person waiting list that ballooned during Covid, staff shortages and strikes.</p>

<p>Labour says it will deliver two million more NHS appointments a year to clear the backlog by paying staff extra to work evenings and weekends and using spare capacity in private healthcare providers.</p>

<p>It also promises to double the number of MRI and CT scanners in the NHS.</p>

<p>- <strong>Immigration </strong>-</p>

<p>Labour leader Keir Starmer has promised to deploy special investigators to "smash" people-smuggling gangs behind irregular immigration into the UK, process asylum claims more quickly to clear the current backlog and to return failed applicants to safe countries.</p>

<p>He has also pledged to ditch the Conservative plan to send asylum seekers to Rwanda.</p>

<p>However, Tory leader Rishi Sunak raised doubts during a debate with Starmer about whether he would be able to convince the Afghan Taliban or Iranian leaders to take back failed asylum seekers from their countries.</p>

<p>- <strong>Energy </strong>-</p>

<p>In order to insulate the UK against shocks to the international energy market, as seen during Russia's invasion of Ukraine, and to meet climate targets, Labour plans to set up "Great British Energy", a new publicly-owned energy company.</p>

<p>"A Labour government will invest in homegrown clean power, cut bills, create jobs, and give us independence from dictators like (Russian President Vladimir) Putin, paid for in part by a proper windfall tax on oil and gas giants," the party says.</p>

<p><strong>- Education -</strong></p>

<p>Labour says it will make private schools pay VAT on fees and use the proceeds to "improve standards in stretched state schools with more teachers" and help "break down barriers to opportunity."</p>

<p><strong>- Environment -</strong></p>

<p>Starmer has set the target of decarbonising the UK's electricity grid by 2030 and said his party will not approve any new oil or gas projects in the North Sea.</p>

<p>Pollution of rivers and seas has been a prominent issue recently, and Labour has promised to block bonuses for water bosses if their companies harm the environment.</p>

<p>- <strong>Transport </strong>-</p>

<p>The UK's rail system is a constant source of complaints, and Labour says it will create an "arm's length public body –- Great British Railways" tasked with improving railway infrastructure and services.</p>

<p><strong>- Workers' rights -</strong></p>

<p>Labour will change the way the minimum wage is calculated by taking into account the cost of living.</p>

<p>It has also pledged to make flexible working "the default" and ban "zero-hour contracts", under which employers are not obliged to provide any minimum working hours and the worker is not obliged to accept any work offered.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-04/an24fi44_uk-labour-leader-keir-starmer-twitter_625x300_30_April_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Labour has vowed to follow the UK fiscal rules and ruled out increasing income tax.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-army-officer-killed-in-hezbollah-rocket-attack-6036492]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israeli Army Officer Killed In Hezbollah Rocket Attack]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-army-officer-killed-in-hezbollah-rocket-attack-6036492]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 05 Jul 2024 03:16:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An Israeli army officer was killed in Hezbollah rocket fire on Thursday, the Israeli military said in a press statement.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An Israeli army officer was killed in Hezbollah rocket fire on Thursday, the Israeli military said in a press statement.</p>

<p>The officer was identified as Itay Galea, 38, a deputy company commander in the 8679th Unit of the Israeli army's 679th Armored Brigade, Xinhua news agency reported.</p>

<p>He was killed when a rocket hit the Israeli-annexed Golan Heights during Hezbollah's massive attacks against Israel.</p>

<p>Hezbollah launched about 200 rockets, missiles, and drones toward northern Israel in retaliation for Israel's recent targeted killing of its senior military leader Mohammad Naameh Nasser in southwestern Lebanon's Tyre city.</p>

<p>Galea, a reservist officer, fought in the Gaza Strip before being sent to northern Israel as part of Israel's preparation for a possible full-fledged war with Hezbollah.</p>

<p>His death marked the 18th fatality among Israeli troops from Hezbollah attacks since the beginning of the cross-border fighting between the Lebanese armed group and Israel in early October last year.</p>

<p>Tensions along the Lebanon-Israel border escalated on October 8, 2023, following a barrage of rockets launched by Hezbollah toward Israel in solidarity with the attack by its ally Hamas on Israel the day before.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2015-06/israeli-annexed-golan-heights_650x400_51434534711.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The officer killed when a rocket hit the Israeli-annexed Golan Heights during Hezbollah's attacks.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-elections-uks-labour-to-win-massive-election-majority-exit-poll-shows-6036401]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Huge Win For Labour, Historic Loss For Rishi Sunak's Party: Exit Polls]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-elections-uks-labour-to-win-massive-election-majority-exit-poll-shows-6036401]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 05 Jul 2024 02:42:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Keir Starmer will be Britain's next prime minister with his Labour Party set to win a massive majority in a parliamentary election, an exit poll on Thursday indicated, while Rishi Sunak's Conservatives are forecast to suffer historic losses.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Keir Starmer will be Britain's next prime minister with his Labour Party set to win a massive majority in a parliamentary election, an exit poll on Thursday indicated, while Rishi Sunak's Conservatives are forecast to suffer historic losses.</p>

<p>The poll showed Labour would win 410 seats in the 650-seat parliament, ending 14 years of Conservative-led government.</p>

<p>Sunak's party were forecast to only take 131 seats, down from 346 when parliament was dissolved, as voters punish the Conservatives for a cost-of-living crisis and years of instability and in-fighting which has seen five different prime ministers since 2016.</p>

<p>In the last six national elections, only one exit poll has got the outcome wrong - in 2015 when the poll predicted a hung parliament when in fact the Conservatives won a majority. Official results will follow over the next few hours.</p>

<p>Sunak stunned Westminster and many in his own party by calling the election earlier than he needed to in May with the Conservatives trailing Labour by some 20 points in opinion polls.</p>

<p>He had hoped that the gap would narrow as had traditionally been the case in British elections, but the deficit has failed to budge in a fairly disastrous campaign.</p>

<p>It started badly with him getting drenched by rain outside Downing Street as he announced the vote, before aides and Conservative candidates became caught up in a gambling scandal over suspicious bets placed on the date of the election.</p>

<p>Sunak's early departure from D-Day commemorative events in France to do a TV interview angered veterans, and even those within his own party said it raised questions about his political acumen.</p>

<p>While polls have suggested that there is no great enthusiasm for Labour leader Starmer, his simple message that it was time for change appears to have resonated with voters.</p>

<p>Unlike in France where Marine Le Pen's far-right National Rally party made historic gains in an election last Sunday, the disenchanted British public appears to have instead moved to the centre-left.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/urbuhg98_keir-starmer_625x300_04_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Keir Starmer will be Britain's next PM with his Labour Party set to win a massive majority.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-sees-significant-opening-in-israel-hamas-hostage-talks-official-6036135]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Sees "Significant Opening" In Israel-Hamas Hostage Talks: Official]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-sees-significant-opening-in-israel-hamas-hostage-talks-official-6036135]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 05 Jul 2024 01:11:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United States believes Israel and Hamas have a "pretty significant opening" to reach an agreement on a ceasefire in Gaza and the release of hostages held there, a senior US official said Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United States believes Israel and Hamas have a "pretty significant opening" to reach an agreement on a ceasefire in Gaza and the release of hostages held there, a senior US official said Thursday.</p>

<p>The official, who spoke on condition of anonymity, said the Palestinian operative group's latest response "moves the process forward and may provide the basis for closing the deal," while stressing it does not mean an agreement was likely in the coming days, and that "significant work" remained on implementation steps.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/fmar0mb8_gaza-war_625x300_01_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US believes Israel and Hamas have a "significant opening" to reach an agreement on a ceasefire in Gaza.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistan-to-host-sco-meeting-in-october-2024-foreign-office-6036009]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Pakistan To Host SCO Meeting In October 2024: Foreign Office]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistan-to-host-sco-meeting-in-october-2024-foreign-office-6036009]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 05 Jul 2024 00:30:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Pakistan on Thursday said it would host the SCO Heads of Government meeting in October and invite all heads of government of the member states of the grouping.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pakistan on Thursday said it would host the SCO Heads of Government meeting in October and invite all heads of government of the member states of the grouping.</p>

<p>Foreign Office spokesperson Mumtaz Zahra Baloch said at the weekly press briefing that Pakistan as the rotating Chairmanship of the SCO Council of Heads of Government (CHG) would host the SCO Heads of Governments Meeting in October this year.</p>

<p>When asked if Pakistan would extend an invitation to Prime Minister Narendra Modi to visit and attend the Summit in Pakistan.</p>

<p>Baloch replied, "The chairmanship belongs to Pakistan, so in our capacity as the chair, we will be extending invitations to all Heads of Government of SCO member states." "This conference will take place in person and we hope and expect that all members of SCO will be represented at the Heads of Governments Meeting being held in October," she said.</p>

<p>She said the October summit will be preceded by a Ministerial meeting and several rounds of Senior Officials meetings, focusing on the financial, economic, socio-cultural and humanitarian cooperation among the SCO member states.</p>

<p>Baloch also said that Pakistan would not become a part of any bloc in international politics as it believed in having good ties with all countries.</p>

<p>"I would first like to clarify that Pakistan has repeatedly said that we are not part of any bloc. We do not believe in bloc politics. We believe in good relations with all countries on the basis of mutual respect, mutual confidence and non-interference in each other's domestic affairs," she said.</p>

<p>She said Pakistan categorically rejects the baseless assertions made about Pakistan in the recent report on religious freedom released by the US Department of State and as a matter of principle, Pakistan opposes such unilateral reports that make observations on the internal affairs of sovereign states.</p>

<p>"We believe that International Religious Freedom cannot be viewed from the lens of any single country's social and legal perspective," it said.</p>

<p>It said unilateral reports assessing other countries' human rights situations are not free from political bias and present an incomplete and distorted picture and the methodology adopted in preparing these reports and the mandate and expertise of its authors are not transparent.</p>

<p>"We strongly believe that each State itself has the primary responsibility to promote and protect the religious rights and freedoms of its nationals," she said, adding that Pakistani citizens are entitled to the freedom of religion and belief under the law and as enshrined in Pakistan's constitution.</p>

<p>She said that during the visit of Prime Minister Shehbaz Sharif to Tajikistan this week, the two sides signed the Pakistan-Tajikistan Strategic Partnership Agreement, which would be based on five pillars of bilateral cooperation, including political, trade and investment, energy and connectivity, security and defence, and people-to-people contacts.</p>

<p>It will include structured high-level dialogue at the leadership and Foreign Ministers' level.</p>

<p>She termed the UN group report on Imran Khan as unwarranted and said, "I would like to underline that a report on any particular case is unwarranted when it lacks objectivity and is based on an incomplete and inaccurate understanding of Pakistan's legal and judicial system".</p>

<p>The report said that cases against Khan were politically motivated.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/2kucele_india-at-sco_625x300_04_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Pakistan on Thursday said it would host the SCO Heads of Government meeting in October.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>