<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Fri, 04 Oct 2024 03:01:13 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-modi-chairs-urgent-top-level-security-meet-on-widening-west-asia-crisis-6710175]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[PM Modi Chairs Urgent Top-Level Security Meet On Widening West Asia Crisis]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-modi-chairs-urgent-top-level-security-meet-on-widening-west-asia-crisis-6710175]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 04 Oct 2024 01:27:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Narendra Modi called an urgent meeting of the government's topmost decision-making body - the Cabinet Committee on Security over the crisis in West Asia.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi called an urgent meeting of the government's topmost decision-making body - the Cabinet Committee on Security over the crisis in West Asia.</p>

<p>The committee comprising the Prime Minister, the Home Minister, the Defence Minister, the Foreign Minister, the Finance Minister and the National Security Adviser, discussed in detail the fresh hostilities in the Middle East and the sharp escalation after Iran's ballistic missile attack on Israel.</p>

<p>Describing the recent developments in West Asia as "deeply concerning", the highest committee in the country delved upon various issues arising from the ongoing and widening crisis.</p>

<p>Among several key issues, they discussed the impact on trade, navigation, and supply chains - especially the supply of oil, petroleum, and its products.</p>

<p>India has urged all parties involved in the conflict to address all issues urgently, and through diplomacy and dialogue. New Delhi has also said that the ongoing conflict "must not take a wider regional dimension."</p>

<h2><strong>IMPACT ON MARITIME TRADE AND SUPPLY CHAINS</strong></h2>

<p>A conflict doesn't just affect those who are party to it, but has a fallout that impacts the rest of the region and even the world. With the sharp escalation between Iran and Israel, India is bracing for wider trade disruptions across the key Red Sea and Gulf of Aden routes.</p>

<p>The conflict can lead to significantly higher cargo freight tariffs as Lebanon's Iran-backed Hezbollah militants have close ties with the Houthi rebels in Yemen, who are responsible for most attacks on merchant ships and vessels carrying cargo via the Red Sea and Gulf of Aden routes.</p>

<p>The Red Sea crisis began in October last year, when Iran-backed Houthi militia disrupted global trade in the area. For India alone, it affected petroleum exports which dropped 37.56 per cent to $5.96 billion in August this year, down from $9.54 billion in the same month last year.</p>

<p>The Red Sea route followed by the Suez Canal accounts for 50 per cent of India's exports - worth Rs 18 lakh crore, and 30 per cent of imports, worth Rs 17 lakh crore, as per data from 2023.</p>

<p>India's overall merchandise trade (exports and imports combined) in FY23 was Rs 94 lakh crore, with 68 per cent (in value terms) and 95 per cent (in volume terms) shipped by sea.</p>

<p>India also trades heavily with the Gulf nations. As per the latest government data, the Gulf Cooperation Council or GCC now contributes 15 per cent of India's total trade, and sectors like energy, defence, security, and health are growing rapidly in the region. The bilateral trade between India and the Gulf Cooperation Council countries reached $162 billion last year.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/305fcd14_pm-modi-cabinet-committee-on-security-meet-ani_625x300_04_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[PM Modi chaired a meet of the Cabinet Committee on Security to discuss the West Asia crisis.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/g7-voices-deep-concern-over-deteriorating-situation-in-mideast-6710832]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[G7 Voices "Deep Concern" Over Deteriorating Situation In Mideast]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/g7-voices-deep-concern-over-deteriorating-situation-in-mideast-6710832]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 04 Oct 2024 01:12:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Leaders of the G7 countries on Thursday voiced concern over the "deteriorating situation" in the Middle East while warning against further "uncontrollable escalation" in the region.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Leaders of the G7 countries on Thursday voiced concern over the "deteriorating situation" in the Middle East while warning against further "uncontrollable escalation" in the region.</p>

<p>G7 leaders "express deep concern over the deteriorating situation in the Middle East and condemn in the strongest terms Iran's direct military attack against Israel," they said in a statement, warning that the "dangerous cycle of attacks and retaliation risks fuelling uncontrollable escalation... which is in no one's interest".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/8rlnkq38_israel-lebanon_625x300_03_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[G7 countries have warned against further "uncontrollable escalation" in the Middle East.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-causes-nearly-90-drop-in-gaza-gdp-imf-6710443]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel-Hamas War Causes Nearly 90% Drop In Gaza GDP: IMF]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-causes-nearly-90-drop-in-gaza-gdp-imf-6710443]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 03 Oct 2024 23:33:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A year of conflict between Israel and Hamas has resulted in a "devastating impact on the economy" in the occupied West Bank and Gaza, the IMF said Thursday, including a nearly 90 percent drop in Gaza's GDP.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A year of conflict between Israel and Hamas has resulted in a "devastating impact on the economy" in the occupied West Bank and Gaza, the IMF said Thursday, including a nearly 90 percent drop in Gaza's GDP.</p>

<p>"Preliminary official estimates indicate an 86 percent decline in GDP in the first half of 2024" in Gaza, said International Monetary Fund communications chief Julie Kozack.</p>

<p>She added that Gaza's "civilian population faces dire socioeconomic conditions, a humanitarian crisis and insufficient aid delivery."</p>

<p>In the West Bank, "already grim prospects have further deteriorated, and preliminary official data indicate a 25 percent decline in GDP in the first half of 2024," Kozack told reporters at a regular briefing.</p>

<p>Israel has been at war in Gaza since Hamas's October 7 resulted in the deaths of 1,205 people in the country, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli figures that include hostages killed in captivity.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory offensive in Gaza has killed at least 41,788 people, the majority of them civilians, according to figures provided by the Hamas-run territory's health ministry. The UN has described the figures as reliable.</p>

<p><strong>Israeli economy also hit</strong></p>

<p>Israel's economy has also been battered by the war, with three main ratings agencies downgrading its debt.</p>

<p>After shrinking by 21 percent in the fourth quarter of 2023, Israeli GDP rebounded by 14 percent in the first three months this year, official data showed.</p>

<p>But growth turned sluggish in the second quarter at 0.7 percent.</p>

<p>Kozack also noted that "in Lebanon, the recent intensification of the conflict is exacerbating the country's already fragile macroeconomic and social situation."</p>

<p>"We're closely monitoring the situation, and this is a situation of great concern and very high uncertainty," she added.</p>

<p>Hezbollah, an ally of Hamas, began exchanging cross-border fire from Lebanon with Israel after Hamas's October 7 attack. But the conflict has escalated after Israel announced this week that its troops had started "ground raids" into parts of southern Lebanon, after days of heavy bombardment of areas across the country where the group holds sway.</p>

<p>The bombing has killed more than 1,000 people, according to Lebanon's health ministry, and forced hundreds of thousands to flee their homes.</p>

<p>Hezbollah-backer Iran launched around 200 rockets in a direct missile attack on Israel on Tuesday, prompting Netanyahu to warn that Tehran would pay.</p>

<p>Iran said it was in retaliation for the killing of Hassan Nasrallah, the leader of Hezbollah, in a massive bombing in south Beirut.</p>

<p>US President Joe Biden said he was discussing possible Israeli strikes on Iranian oil facilities, in comments that sent oil prices spiking Thursday just a month before the US presidential election.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/45959ij8_gaza-afp_625x300_25_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel's retaliatory offensive in Gaza has killed at least 41,788 people.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-middle-east-conflict-means-for-global-economy-6710173]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explainer: What Middle East Conflict Means For Global Economy]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-middle-east-conflict-means-for-global-economy-6710173]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 03 Oct 2024 22:46:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Rising tensions in the Middle East add new uncertainties for the global economy even as policymakers start to congratulate themselves on having steered it out of a bout of high inflation without triggering recession.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Rising tensions in the Middle East add new uncertainties for the global economy even as policymakers start to congratulate themselves on having steered it out of a bout of high inflation without triggering a recession.</p>

<p>Israel, which has been fighting with Hamas in Gaza for almost a year, has sent its troops into southern Lebanon after two weeks of intense airstrikes, escalating tensions in a conflict that risks drawing in the United States and Iran.</p>

<p>The following sketches what we know about how this could play out on the world economy in the weeks ahead.</p>

<p><strong>WHAT IMPACT, IF ANY, HAS BEEN FELT SO FAR?</strong></p>

<p>Very little beyond the immediate region, with the main effects limited to financial markets as investors hedge their portfolios with safe-haven assets. The US dollar has been a beneficiary since Iran's ballistic missile attack on Israel: the dollar index, which measures the US currency against the euro, yen and four other top currencies, is trading around three-week peaks.</p>

<p>Oil prices rose around 2% on Thursday on concerns a wider conflict could disrupt crude oil flows from the region - for example if Israel chose to target Iranian oil infrastructure which in turn could trigger retaliation from Iran.</p>

<p>But it is not clear that this will translate into the kind of sustained, sharper rises that motorists start to notice at the fuel pump. Analysts point out that the United States has high levels of crude oil inventories while OPEC-producing nations have enough spare capacity to smooth out the impact of disruptions, at least in the short term.</p>

<p><strong>HOW ARE ECONOMIC POLICYMAKERS REACTING?</strong></p>

<p>As always, central bankers stress that their job is to look beyond unpredictable, one-off shocks to the economy and instead focus on the deeper, underlying trends. But they cannot afford to totally ignore geopolitical events either.</p>

<p>Bank of England Governor Andrew Bailey told The Guardian newspaper that the bank could move more aggressively to cut interest rates if inflation pressures continue to weaken - suggesting central bankers for now did not see the Middle East conflict as a major threat to their attempts to temper inflation. Bailey said there seemed to be a commitment to keep oil markets stable but he also said the conflict could yet push up oil prices if things keep escalating.</p>

<p>Sweden's Riksbank Deputy Governor Per Jansson delivered a similar message, saying the effects of the Middle East conflict were not yet enough to warrant scratching economic forecasts.</p>

<p>The International Monetary Fund said on Thursday an escalation of the conflict in the Middle East could have significant economic ramifications for the region and the global economy, but commodity prices remain below the highs of the past year. It was too early to predict specific impacts on the global economy, IMF spokesperson Julie Kozack said.</p>

<p><strong>WHEN WILL ANY IMPACT BECOME MORE EVIDENT?</strong></p>

<p>For context, Brent crude futures are currently around $75 a barrel, well below their $84 level at the time of Hamas' Oct. 7 strike on Israel nearly a year ago and far off the $130 highs reached after Russia's invasion of Ukraine in February 2023.</p>

<p>Europe would be exposed to rising oil prices because, unlike the United States, it has no major domestic oil production. But even there, policymakers estimate a durable 10% rise in prices would be needed to push up inflation by just 0.1 percentage point.</p>

<p>The economic impacts of an all-out war that led to wider attacks on energy infrastructure throughout the Middle East and Gulf regions plus further disruptions to trade routes through the Red Sea, would be more tangible.</p>

<p>Oxford Economics estimated such a scenario would spike oil prices up to $130 and knock 0.4 percentage points off global output growth next year, which the International Monetary Fund currently sees at around 3.3%.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/01ddgl88_gaza-reuters_625x300_03_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel has been fighting with Hamas in Gaza for almost a year.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-strikes-hezbollah-intelligence-headquarters-in-beirut-6709703]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Strikes Hezbollah Intelligence Headquarters In Beirut]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-strikes-hezbollah-intelligence-headquarters-in-beirut-6709703]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 03 Oct 2024 21:38:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel's military said Thursday it had hit Hezbollah's intelligence headquarters in the Lebanese capital, as troops battled militants near the border and warplanes bombarded their strongholds around the country.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel's military said Thursday it had hit Hezbollah's intelligence headquarters in the Lebanese capital, as troops battled militants near the border and warplanes bombarded their strongholds around the country.</p>

<p>Israel announced this week that its troops had started "ground raids" into parts of southern Lebanon, a stronghold of Hezbollah, after days of heavy bombardment of areas across the country where the group holds sway.</p>

<p>The bombing has killed more than 1,000 people, according to Lebanon's health ministry, and forced hundreds of thousands to flee their homes in a country already mired in economic and political crisis.</p>

<p>Israel, at war in Gaza since Hamas's October 7 attack, says it shifted its focus to secure its northern border and ensure the safe return of more than 60,000 people displaced by Hezbollah attacks over the past year.</p>

<p>On the Gaza front, the Israeli military said a strike three months ago killed three senior Hamas leaders, including Rahwi Mushtaha, the head of the militant movement's government in the war-ravaged Palestinian territory.</p>

<p>In Lebanon, the Israeli military said it hit "targets belonging to Hezbollah's intelligence headquarters in Beirut".</p>

<p>Lebanon's state-run National News Agency reported three air strikes on Beirut's southern suburbs, with a source close to Hezbollah telling AFP the target was an evacuated building that housed the group's media relations office.</p>

<p>Israel told Lebanese people to evacuate more than 20 villages and the city of Nabatiyeh.</p>

<p>"For your own safety, you must evacuate your homes immediately and head north of the Awali River. Save your lives," army spokesman Avichay Adraee said on X.</p>

<p><strong>Central Beirut strike</strong></p>

<p>Hezbollah said it fought off a bid by Israeli troops to advance at Fatima's Gate on the border.</p>

<p>It also said it set off two explosive devices against advancing Israeli forces as it kept up its cross-border rocket fire.</p>

<p>The military said an overnight strike killed 15 Hezbollah fighters in Bint Jbeil, an area heavily damaged during Israel's last war with the militant group in 2006.</p>

<p>Later the Lebanese army said one of its soldiers was killed when "the Israeli enemy targeted an army post in the Bint Jbeil area" -- the third death among its troops in the current escalation -- prompting retaliatory fire.</p>

<p>A Lebanese military official said it was the army's first response to Israeli fire since last October.</p>

<p>Israel earlier carried out a deadly air raid in downtown Beirut, hitting an emergency services rescue facility run by Hezbollah, killing seven workers, the service said.</p>

<p>Hassan Ammar, 82, who had been staying in the high-rise building whose walls were partly blown out by the strike after he fled south Lebanon, said: "We are peaceful civilians in our homes."</p>

<p>Israel has yet to comment on the strike, but said it had hit about 200 Hezbollah targets "in Lebanese territory".</p>

<p>According to Lebanon's Health Minister Firass Abiad, more than 40 rescuers and firefighters have been killed by Israeli fire in three days.</p>

<p><strong>Iran missile attack</strong></p>

<p>The latest strikes came after Hezbollah-backer Iran launched its second direct missile attack on Israel, prompting Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu to warn that Tehran would pay.</p>

<p>As Israel weighs retaliation for the Iranian missile strike, President Joe Biden said the United States was "fully supportive" of the ally but ruled out supporting a strike on Iran's nuclear sites.</p>

<p>Iran, which arms and funds Lebanon's Hezbollah, said it would step up its response if Israel counterattacked.</p>

<p>Israel's ground operations and strikes follow the killing in a massive bombing in south Beirut of Hezbollah's chief Hassan Nasrallah and other commanders.</p>

<p>Israel intercepted most of the 200 missiles launched by Iran. In the Israel-occupied West Bank, a Palestinian was killed by shrapnel.</p>

<p>Israeli Defence Minister Yoav Gallant warned that "those who attack the state of Israel, pay a heavy price", while Iranian President Masoud Pezeshkian warned of a "stronger" response.</p>

<p>Iran's Revolutionary Guards said its missiles were fired in retaliation for Nasrallah's killing alongside that of a general in the Guards' Quds force, as well as for the killing in July of Hamas leader Ismail Haniyeh in Tehran.</p>

<p>A day after its military said it was launching ground operations in south Lebanon, Israel on Wednesday reported the first death of a soldier in the Israel-Hezbollah war, a toll that later rose to eight dead.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said it had deployed a second division to support the fighting.</p>

<p>Lebanon's health ministry said 46 people were killed and 85 others injured by Israeli strikes over the previous 24 hours.</p>

<p><strong>'Sickening cycle'</strong></p>

<p>The impact of the war was also felt in Syria, where the Syrian Observatory for Human Right monitor said an Israeli strike in Damascus killed four people, including Hassan Jaafar al-Qasir, Nasrallah's son-in-law.</p>

<p>Iranian media said a Revolutionary Guards military "adviser" in Syria, Majid Divani, succumbed Thursday to wounds sustained in an Israeli strike on Damascus earlier this week.</p>

<p>In Israel's commercial hub Tel Aviv, Liron Yori, 22, said he was worried about "where the war's going and I don't feel comfortable with it".</p>

<p>The fighting comes with many Israelis celebrating Rosh Hashanah, the Jewish new year, on Thursday.</p>

<p>UN chief Antonio Guterres called for an end to the "sickening cycle of escalation" in the Middle East and the G7 group of wealthy nations said a diplomatic solution was "still possible".</p>

<p>Months of similar calls and mediation efforts have so far failed to bring a Gaza truce.</p>

<p>Hezbollah began strikes on Israeli troops a day after Hamas staged its October 7 attack on Israel, which resulted in the deaths of 1,205 people in Israel, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli official figures that include hostages killed in captivity.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory offensive in Gaza has killed at least 41,788 people, the majority of them civilians, according to figures provided by the Hamas-run territory's health ministry. The UN has described the figures as reliable.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/nd26tj0o_beirut-reuters_625x300_03_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel bombing has killed more than 1,000 people, according to Lebanon. (FILE)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-played-quiet-but-important-role-in-chagos-islands-resolution-sources-6709483]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India Played Quiet But Important Role In Chagos Islands Resolution: Sources]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-played-quiet-but-important-role-in-chagos-islands-resolution-sources-6709483]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 03 Oct 2024 21:03:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India has played a quiet but important background role in UK's move habd over sovereignty of the Chagos Islands to Mauritius. Sources said India had firmly and consistently supported the need to do away with the last vestiges of colonisation".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India has played a quiet but important background role in UK's move hand over sovereignty of&nbsp; Chagos Islands to Mauritius. Sources said India had firmly and consistently supported the need to do away with the last vestiges of colonisation".&nbsp;</p>

<p>New Delhi's role had got a mention in the joint statement of the UK and Mauritius. &nbsp;</p>

<p>"In reaching today's political agreement, we have enjoyed the full support and assistance of our close partners, the United States of America and the Republic of India," the joint statement read.&nbsp;</p>

<p>India, sources said, consistently encouraged both sides to negotiate -- "with an open mind and a view to achieving mutually beneficial outcomes".&nbsp;</p>

<p>It is believed that the final outcome "is a win for all sides involved and will reinforce long term security in the Indian Ocean region," sources said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In its message welcoming the agreement, New Delhi said, "India has consistently supported Mauritius's claim for sovereignty over Chagos, in line with its principled stand on decolonization and support for the sovereignty and territorial integrity of nations, as well as its longstanding and close partnership with Mauritius'.</p>

<p>The UK has been under pressure for decades to hand over Chagos. In February 2019, the International Court of Justice had declared British control of the Chagos Islands illegal. &nbsp;Three months later, the United Nations overwhelmingly backed a resolution demanding that the UK relinquish control of Chagos Islands.</p>

<p>UK, though, had resisted, citing the Diego Garcia base, a key installation used to help US operations across the Indian Ocean and Gulf regions.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Its move today came after two years of negotiation, which, both nations said, were conducted in a respectful manner as equal sovereign states. The political agreement is subject to the finalisation of a treaty and supporting legal instruments, which both sides have committed to complete as quickly as possible.</p>

<p>Over the last decade, New Delhi has kept a firm focus on its maritime strategy in the Indian Ocean with an eye to counter China's growing influence. Special attention is being paid to Mauritius, which holds the key to the south-west Indian Ocean and is also the entry point to the Atlantic Ocean.&nbsp;</p>

<p>India is also cultivating other nations at key points in the Indian Ocean -- the Persian Gulf, Malacca Strait and southern Africa.&nbsp;Efforts are also being made to expand ties on various fronts with Madagascar, Mozambique and Seychelles.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/37qvd13_chagos-islands-reuters-650_625x300_05_September_18.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ndtv-exclusive-jamaican-pm-on-why-global-south-wants-india-to-represent-it-6709348]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[NDTV Exclusive: Jamaican PM On Why Global South Wants India To Represent It]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ndtv-exclusive-jamaican-pm-on-why-global-south-wants-india-to-represent-it-6709348]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 03 Oct 2024 20:47:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India has become the voice of the Global South in a strategic and robust way, and the world saw that in the most-recent G20 Summit which happened in New Delhi, said Jamaican Prime Minister Andrew Holness in an exclusive interview to NDTV.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India has become the voice of the Global South in a strategic and robust way, and the world saw that in the most-recent G20 Summit which happened in New Delhi, said Jamaican Prime Minister Andrew Holness in an exclusive interview to NDTV.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Holness, who is in India to strengthen ties between the two nations, held a bilateral meeting with Prime Minister Narendra Modi on October 1, during which India and Jamaica signed four agreements, including one on the possible roll-out of UPI payment systems in the Caribbean country.</p>

<p>The two leaders also discussed greater cooperation in energy, defence, and climate change, among several key issues. Jamaica has also strongly backed India's bid for a permanent seat at the UN Security Council and has called for urgent reforms in this regard.</p>

<p>Speaking exclusively to NDTV, the Jamaican prime minister praised India's global role, especially as the voice of the Global South. He praised PM Modi for his role, saying "India has become the voice of the Global South in a strategic and robust way, and the world saw that in the most-recent G20 Summit which happened in New Delhi. The theme - One Earth, One People - resonated with all. I feel India, and Prime Minister Modi in particular, has played that role. It is important that a large country like India, with significant resources can represent the Global South."</p>

<p>He also recalled how India helped during the COVID-19 pandemic. "Prime Minister Modi was one of the first world leaders to reach out to assist with vaccines," Prime Minister Holness said.</p>

<h2><strong>DIGITAL ECONOMY</strong></h2>

<p>Praising India's efforts to make the economy a digital one, Prime Minister Holness said, ""India has created the roadmap for developing countries and nations from the Global South to follow its path to step into the world of digitalisation, and how to create digital societies"</p>

<p>He went on to say that Jamaica is interested in India's UPI payments system, saying, "People who have benefited most from the Aadhaar and UPI platforms are those who are poor as these have facilitated seamless, effective and efficient transfer of funds to the weaker sections of society."</p>

<h3><strong>SECURITY AND DEFENCE</strong></h3>

<p>The two leaders, had on Monday, discussed the security framework between India and Jamaica. "We have engaged with India on support for security and defence, particularly in training of our defence officers," he said.</p>

<p>"But more than training, we have looked to build on technology. In today's global environment, it is important to be ahead of the curve on technology and security - both for the economy and for the society, and India is a leader in the sphere of technology," he said.</p>

<h3><strong>CLIMATE CHANGE</strong></h3>

<p>The Jamaican PM said that his country has already been working with India to combat climate change. "India has been leading efforts in developing global solar energy technology, and then making it available to developing countries. We are also part of the International Solar Alliance, which is led by India.</p>

<h3><strong>INDIANS IN JAMAICA</strong></h3>

<p>Praising the Indian community in Jamaica, Prime Minister Holness said, "The Indian diaspora has been in Jamaica for centuries. The first Indians arrived in Jamaica in 1845. Since then the Indians have integrated into Jamaica. You can see Indians in all spheres of life in Jamaican society - in business, commerce, education, healthcare - in almost every aspect, and they have contributed very significantly to society."</p>

<p>In his concluding remarks, the prime minister said, "India and Jamaica have a lot in common. Our relationship has a long history, we have the Commonwealth, we have the diaspora connection, we have sport, especially cricket, we have a common legislative system, we are both strong democracies, but India has significantly created a pathway for development - in technology, in pharma, in agriculture - all that can be beneficial to smaller countries. And the beauty of our relationship is that India is willing to share all this... after all, that is the essence of the global fraternity."</p>

<p>In his media statement, PM Modi had said that India has always been a reliable partner in Jamaica's development journey and it is ready to share its expertise with that country in areas such as digital public infrastructure, small industries, biofuel, innovation, health, education and agriculture.</p>

<p>PM Modi also said that the India-Jamaica partnership is characterised by the four Cs -- Culture, Cricket, Commonwealth, and CARICOM.</p>

<p>The CARICOM (Caribbean Community) is a grouping of 20 island nations which are home to approximately 16 million people.</p>

<p>"India and Jamaica may be separated by vast oceans, but our minds, our cultures and our histories are deeply intertwined," PM Modi had said with Prime Minister Holness by his side.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/pi8ec01_pm-modi-jamaican-pm-andrew-holness-pti_625x300_03_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Prime Minister Narendra Modi and his Jamaican counterpart Andrew Holness held bilateral talks.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-israel-conflict-discussing-possible-israel-strikes-on-iran-oil-facilities-says-biden-6709272]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Discussing" Possible Israel Strikes On Iran Oil Facilities, Says Biden]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-israel-conflict-discussing-possible-israel-strikes-on-iran-oil-facilities-says-biden-6709272]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 03 Oct 2024 20:38:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Biden told reporters at the White House however that he was not expecting Israel to launch any retaliation for Tehran's missile barrage on Israel before Thursday at least.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden said he was discussing possible Israeli strikes on Iranian oil facilities, in comments that sent oil prices spiking Thursday just a month before the US presidential election. Biden told reporters at the White House however that he was not expecting Israel to launch any retaliation for Tehran's missile barrage on Israel before Thursday at least.</p>

<p>When asked by a reporter if he supported Israel striking Iran's oil facilities, Biden said "we're discussing that. I think that would be a little... anyway."</p>

<p>Oil prices jumped five percent over concerns about the Middle East after Biden spoke.</p>

<p>A rise in oil prices could be hugely damaging for Biden's Vice President Kamala Harris as the Democrat confronts Republican former president Donald Trump in a November 5 election where the cost of living is a major issue.</p>

<p>Biden said he did not expect any immediate action from Israel -- even if Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu has recently paid little heed to calls for restraint as he targets the Iran-allied Hezbollah militia in Lebanon.</p>

<p>"First of all, we don't 'allow' Israel, we advise Israel. And there is nothing going to happen today," Biden told reporters when asked if he would allow Israel to retaliate against Iran.</p>

<p>Biden said on Wednesday that he would not back Israel attacking Iranian nuclear sites.</p>

<p>Iran launched around 200 rockets in a direct missile attack on Israel on Tuesday, prompting Netanyahu to warn that Tehran would pay.</p>

<p>Iran said it was in retaliation for the killing of Hassan Nasrallah, the leader of Hezbollah.</p>

<p>Hezbollah has been launching rockets at Israel since shortly after the October 7, 2023 attacks on Israel by Iran's Palestinian ally Hamas, and Israel's crushing retaliatory offensive in Gaza.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/o30es1hg_joe-biden-afp_625x300_25_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Biden was asked if he supported Israel striking Iran's oil facilities. (FILE)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mps-can-cross-vote-on-major-issues-rules-pakistan-supreme-court-6709068]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[MPs Can Cross Vote On Major Issues, Rules Pakistan Supreme Court]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mps-can-cross-vote-on-major-issues-rules-pakistan-supreme-court-6709068]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 03 Oct 2024 20:08:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Pakistan's Supreme Court ruled on Thursday that lawmakers can vote separately from their parties on major issues, allowing parliamentary horse-trading as the government tries to rally support for constitutional reform.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pakistan's Supreme Court ruled on Thursday that lawmakers can vote separately from their parties on major issues, allowing parliamentary horse-trading as the government tries to rally support for constitutional reform.</p>

<p>Elections in February were marred by allegations of rigging that favoured Prime Minister Shehbaz Sharif, who heads a shaky coalition lacking the two-thirds majority needed to change the constitution.</p>

<p>He is reportedly planning to give the executive more power over the judiciary, where dozens of cases are playing out against jailed opposition leader Imran Khan.</p>

<p>Thursday's ruling allows his government to court individual MPs for their votes and pressure lawmakers loyal to Khan's Pakistan Tehreek-e-Insaf (PTI) party for their support.</p>

<p>"This has cleared the way for them for the constitutional amendment," political analyst Zahid Hussain told AFP. "This is also being used by the ruling party to weaken PTI."</p>

<p>A 2022 Supreme Court decision said MPs crossing the aisle would have their ballots discounted on major votes including constitutional amendments, no-confidence votes and the election of prime ministers.</p>

<p>However, Thursday's ruling "unanimously" backtracked that ruling, Chief Justice Qazi Faez Isa said in court, adding that a detailed verdict would be released later.</p>

<p>Opposition parties say the amendments proposed by Sharif's government would create a new court to rule on the constitution, with a head judge picked by the prime minister.</p>

<p>The Supreme Court and other Pakistani tribunals would be beholden to the new court's rulings.</p>

<p>"Not only would this constitutional amendment weaken the judiciary but also democracy and the constitution itself," said PTI lawyer Ali Zafar.</p>

<p>Khan was barred from contesting February's election and sidelined in jail on charges he says are politically motivated.</p>

<p>Candidates loyal to the former international cricket star became the biggest bloc in parliament after that election but fell short of the majority needed to rule.</p>

<p>Sharif's Pakistan Muslim League Nawaz (PML-N) party sealed a deal to rule with other parties also considered close to the powerful military establishment.</p>

<p>However, PTI has been a vocal opposition force, holding regular street protests and needling the government in parliament.</p>

<p>Khan has seen his cases, many alleging corruption, ping-pong through different courts, one of which has openly alleged intimidation by state intelligence agencies.</p>

<p>The 71-year-old has been jailed for more than a year and PTI has called for fresh protests in the capital Islamabad on Friday.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/b85qm20g_pakistan-supreme-court-reuters_625x300_21_July_18.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A 2022 top court decision said MPs crossing the aisle would have their ballots discounted]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-fire-killed-over-40-rescuers-firefighters-in-3-days-lebanon-6708801]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israeli Fire Killed Over 40 Rescuers, Firefighters In 3 Days: Lebanon]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-fire-killed-over-40-rescuers-firefighters-in-3-days-lebanon-6708801]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 03 Oct 2024 19:28:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Lebanon's health minister said Thursday more than 40 rescuers and firefighters were killed by Israeli fire in three days, with 97 killed overall since Hezbollah and Israel began clashing last October.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lebanon's health minister said Thursday more than 40 rescuers and firefighters were killed by Israeli fire in three days, with 97 killed overall since Hezbollah and Israel began clashing last October.<br />
Firass Abiad told reporters that in three days 40 people "among those working in ambulances and fire trucks" were killed.</p>

<p>He said 97 "paramedics and firefighters" had been killed and 188 wounded since fighting began.</p>

<p>The toll includes rescuers in organisations affiliated with Hezbollah or other Lebanese parties.</p>

<p>Since the clashes began, 1,974 people have been killed by Israeli fire, including 127 children, he said, adding that more than 9,350 have been wounded.</p>

<p>After nearly a year of low-intensity cross-border fighting, Israel has shifted the focus of its operation from Gaza to Lebanon, where heavy bombing has forced hundreds of thousands to flee.</p>

<p>This week, Israel announced that its troops had started ground raids into parts of southern Lebanon, a stronghold of Hezbollah.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/776tnli_beirut-attack_625x300_03_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Ninety-seven have been killed since Hezbollah and Israel began clashing last October.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-may-have-had-role-in-israeli-embassy-attacks-swedish-security-service-6708243]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iran May Have Had Role In Israeli Embassy Attacks: Swedish Security Service]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-may-have-had-role-in-israeli-embassy-attacks-swedish-security-service-6708243]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 03 Oct 2024 18:13:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Swedish intelligence agency Sapo said Thursday that Iran may have been involved in explosions and gunfire around Israeli embassies in Sweden and Denmark this week.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Swedish intelligence agency Sapo said Thursday that Iran may have been involved in explosions and gunfire around Israeli embassies in Sweden and Denmark this week.</p>

<p>In Denmark, police said they arrested three Swedish nationals on Wednesday after two blasts, likely caused by hand grenades, close to the Israeli embassy in Copenhagen.</p>

<p>On Tuesday, the Israeli embassy in Stockholm was targeted in a shooting, according to Swedish police.</p>

<p>Asked about reports of links to Iran, Fredrik Hallstrom, head of operations at the Sapo agency, told a press conference that "there are some things that could point in that direction."</p>

<p>"In part due to the choice of targets and modus operandi, but that is an assumption rather than pure knowledge," Hallstrom said.</p>

<p>In May, Sapo said that Iran was recruiting members of Swedish criminal gangs to commit "acts of violence" against Israeli and other interests in Sweden - a claim Iran denied.</p>

<p>Swedish broadcaster SVT on Wednesday reported that it had received information that the two latest embassy attacks had been ordered by the Swedish criminal network Foxtrot -- at the behest of Iran.</p>

<p>A Danish court on Thursday remanded two of the arrested Swedes -- aged 16 and 19 -- in custody for 27 days.</p>

<p>Copenhagen police said that the third Swede, arrested near the crime scene, had been released.</p>

<p>Since the outbreak of the Israel-Hamas war in October 2023, several incidents apparently targeting Israeli interests in Sweden have been reported.</p>

<p>In February, police found a grenade on the grounds of the Israeli embassy compound, which the ambassador said was an attempted attack.</p>

<p>In May, gunshots were fired outside the Israeli embassy, which prompted the country to boost security measures around Israeli interests and Jewish community institutions.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/3damnj8o_israels-copenhagen-embassy-reuters_625x300_03_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Two blasts occurred close to the Israeli embassy in Copenhagen.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-historic-move-uk-gives-up-sovereignty-of-chagos-islands-to-mauritius-keeps-military-base-in-diego-garcia-6708242]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[In Historic Move, UK Gives Up Sovereignty Of Chagos Islands To Mauritius]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-historic-move-uk-gives-up-sovereignty-of-chagos-islands-to-mauritius-keeps-military-base-in-diego-garcia-6708242]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 03 Oct 2024 18:13:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Britain today said it will give up sovereignty of the Chagos Islands to Mauritius, but will keep its strategic joint military base with the US in Diego Garcia.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Britain today said it will give up sovereignty of the Chagos Islands to Mauritius, but will keep its strategic joint military base with the US in Diego Garcia.</p>

<p>"Following two years of negotiation, this is a seminal moment in our relationship and a demonstration of our enduring commitment to the peaceful resolution of disputes and the rule of law," the UK and Mauritius said in a joint statement today.</p>

<p>Negotiations have been conducted in a constructive and respectful manner, as equal sovereign states, on the basis of international law, and with the intention of resolving all outstanding issues between the United Kingdom and Mauritius concerning the Chagos Archipelago, including those relating to its former inhabitants, they said in the statement.</p>

<p>The political agreement is subject to the finalisation of a treaty and supporting legal instruments, which both sides have committed to complete as quickly as possible. Under the terms of this treaty, the UK will agree that Mauritius is sovereign over the Chagos Archipelago, including Diego Garcia.</p>

<p>"In resolving all outstanding issues between the United Kingdom and Mauritius, the treaty will open a new chapter in our shared history, one which will continue to be based on mutual respect and trust as close Commonwealth partners committed to the security and prosperity of the Indian Ocean Region. In reaching today's political agreement, we have enjoyed the full support and assistance of our close partners, the United States of America and the Republic of India," the joint statement said.</p>

<p>Britain has been under pressure for decades to hand over the Indian Ocean islands but has resisted because of the Diego Garcia base, a key installation used to help US operations across the Indian Ocean and Gulf regions.</p>

<p>"For the first time in more than 50 years, the status of the base will be undisputed and legally secure," the Foreign Commonwealth and Development Office (FCDO) said.</p>

<p>US President Joe Biden hailed the continuation of the Diego Garcia base on the largest island in the chain and was used during the wars in Afghanistan and Iraq.</p>

<p>"I applaud the historic agreement and conclusion of the negotiations," President Biden said in a White House statement, adding that the site "plays a vital role in national, regional, and global security".</p>

<p>Britain decided in 1965 to separate the islands from its then colony of Mauritius and set up a military base there, which it leased to the US. In doing so, it evicted thousands of Chagos islanders who have since mounted a series of legal claims for compensation in the British courts.</p>

<p>Mauritius has claimed the archipelago -- renamed British Indian Ocean Territory -- since its independence in 1968. Mauritius Foreign Minister called the announcement of the accord "a day to remember" and a "seminal moment" in his country's relationship with Britain.</p>

<p>International calls for Britain to hand over one of its last remaining overseas territories have grown in recent years.</p>

<p>In 2019, the International Court of Justice asked Britain to hand over the remote islands. The same year, the UN General Assembly also voted for Britain to withdraw.</p>

<p><strong>With inputs from AFP</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/ju76m2ao_diego-garcia_625x300_03_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Negotiations have been conducted in a constructive and respectful manner]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indonesian-women-trapped-in-temporary-pleasure-marriages-with-tourists-for-money-6708241]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Indonesian Women Trapped In  'Pleasure Marriages' With Tourists For Money]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indonesian-women-trapped-in-temporary-pleasure-marriages-with-tourists-for-money-6708241]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 03 Oct 2024 18:13:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Young women from poor backgrounds in Indonesia are entering into short-term marriages with male tourists, primarily from the Middle East, in exchange for money.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A disturbing practice in Indonesian villages has sparked widespread condemnation online. According to the<em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/article/3279641/short-term-us500-pleasure-marriage-practice-among-poor-rural-indonesia-women-condemned" rel="nofollow, noindex"> South China Morning Post</a></em>, young women from impoverished backgrounds are entering into short-term marriages with male tourists, primarily from the Middle East, in exchange for money. This phenomenon is prevalent in Puncak, a popular destination in West Indonesia, that attracts&nbsp;Arab tourists. Several visitors are exploiting local women through temporary marriages arranged by agencies in the mountain resort of Kota Bunga.</p>

<p>The arrangement involves the agencies introducing tourists to local women. Once both parties agree, they hold a quick, informal wedding ceremony, after which the man pays a bride price to the woman. In return, the woman provides sexual and domestic services during the tourist's stay. When the tourist departs, the marriage is dissolved.</p>

<p>According to a report by the <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.latimes.com/world-nation/story/2024-09-11/indonesia-divorce-village-contract-marriage-sex-tourism">Los Angeles Times</a></em>, this&nbsp;controversial practice known as "pleasure marriages" has emerged as a lucrative industry, bolstering tourism and the local economy.&nbsp;Initially, family members or acquaintances facilitated introductions between tourists and local women. However, the growth of agencies specialising in these arrangements has institutionalised the practice.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Cahaya, a young Indonesian woman, shared her harrowing experience as a temporary wife. She told the <em>LA Times</em> that she has been married over 15 times to Middle Eastern tourists. Her first husband, a 50-year-old Saudi Arabian man, paid a bride price of $850 (Rs 71,412), but after agents and officials took their share, she received only half.&nbsp;Five days after the wedding, the man flew back home and they were ''divorced''. Cahaya revealed that she earns between $300 and $500 per marriage, which barely covers her rent and supports her ailing grandparents.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Another woman, Nisa, broke free from this cycle after at least 20 temporary marriages. She met an Indonesian immigration officer, married him, and started a new life with two sons. Nisa vowed never to return to her past.</p>

<p>These temporary marriages, also known as nikah mut'ah are rooted in Shia Islam culture. However, the majority of scholars called such marriages ''unacceptable''. These temporary arrangements are also not recognised by Indonesian law, as they undermine the fundamental purpose of marriage.</p>

<p>This practice raises serious concerns about the exploitation of vulnerable women, sex tourism, and the lack of protection for women's rights. Critics and people on the internet slammed the practice, arguing that it perpetuates human trafficking, abuse, and exploitation, taking advantage of poverty-stricken communities.</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/gj2pi0no_marriage_625x300_03_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The arrangement involves the agencies introducing tourists to local women.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-becomes-1st-person-to-touch-200-million-followers-on-x-6707934]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk Becomes 1st Person To Touch 200 Million Followers On X]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-becomes-1st-person-to-touch-200-million-followers-on-x-6707934]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 03 Oct 2024 17:37:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Tech billionaire Elon Musk on Thursday became the first person to reach 200 million followers on X social media platform, which he acquired in October 2022 for a whopping $44 billion.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Tech billionaire Elon Musk on Thursday became the first person to reach 200 million followers on X social media platform, which he acquired in October 2022 for a whopping $44 billion.</p>

<p>The X owner is currently followed by former US President Barack Obama at 131.9 million followers, and famous footballer Cristiano Ronaldo at 113.2 million followers (as of October 3).</p>

<p>Popular singer Justin Bieber is at the fourth position with 110.3 million followers and Rihanna is in the fifth spot with 108.4 million followers.</p>

<p>Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi recently crossed the 100 million mark in the world -- which was hailed by Musk -- and has 102.4 million followers as of now.</p>

<p>Musk recently said that X now has more than 600 million monthly active users (MAUs), and around 300 million daily active users (DAUs).</p>

<p>Reports surfaced recently, claiming that most of Musk's followers are fake and the count is bloated by millions of new, inactive accounts. However, there has been no official confirmation about the claim.</p>

<p>According to the Tesla and SpaceX owner, X social media platform has become a group chat for Earth, with maximum traffic coming from all over the world. X is the group chat for Earth, Musk had posted.</p>

<p>The tech billionaire aims to make it an everything app where people can post movies and TV shows and also make digital payments. Musk also claimed that X usage in the US has reached an all-time high.</p>

<p>Earlier this week, global investment firm Fidelity cut the value of its holding in Musk-run X (formerly Twitter) by a massive 78.7 per cent, which implies that the X social media platform is likely valued at just $9.4 billion.</p>

<p>According to the asset manager, X is now valued at less than a quarter of its $44 billion purchase price (at August end), reports TechCrunch which cited its filings. X, Fidelity or Musk did not comment on the report based on regulatory disclosures.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/9r47i6pc_elon-musk-ians_625x300_14_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/israel-and-iran-wanted-a-zero-sum-game-now-both-are-losing-6707808]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: Israel And Iran Are Now Stuck In Their Own Zero-Sum Game]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/israel-and-iran-wanted-a-zero-sum-game-now-both-are-losing-6707808]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 03 Oct 2024 17:21:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The heart of the matter is that Iran - along with its proxies and Israel - has taken a maximalist position on the negotiating table. This makes it far more difficult to arrive at a negotiated settlement.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/crgv337o_israel_625x300_03_October_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>The last two weeks have seen the Middle East teetering on a knife's edge. While tensions have been high since the Hamas attacks last October, the developments in the previous two weeks have been particularly concerning. Tensions began to rise on September 17 when the pagers used by Hezbollah members exploded all of a sudden, followed by similar explosions of other communication devices.</p>

<p>These events took place at a time when Israel shifted its attention towards its northern border with Lebanon. Since then, tensions have mounted with the killing of Hassan Nasrallah and other top Hezbollah commanders. Iran's airstrikes directly targeting Israel mark a dangerous point of escalation.<br />
As the threat of a larger regional war looms, is there a way out of this crisis? Negotiations for a ceasefire have been taking place for the past several months. Despite the efforts, we are nowhere close to a negotiated settlement. The heart of the matter is that Iran - along with its proxies and Israel - has taken a maximalist position on the negotiating table. This makes it far more difficult to arrive at a negotiated settlement.</p>

<h2><strong>Hezbollah Can't Take A U-Turn</strong></h2>

<p>Hezbollah entered the conflict almost immediately after the October 7 attacks last year. The group has aimed to put pressure on Israel by opening up another front alongside Gaza. It has linked negotiations with Israel to the ongoing situation there. Any peace settlement along Israel's northern frontiers will be dependent on a similar settlement in Gaza. Hezbollah and its leadership have pushed themselves into a corner by taking such a maximalist position on the issue. The Israeli leadership knows this and has steadily pushed the Hezbollah up an escalator ladder. From Hezbollah's point of view, any negotiation or compromise would mean a U-turn unless it is part of a larger settlement involving Gaza.</p>

<h2><strong>Iran In A Bind</strong></h2>

<p>Iran is also in a very delicate position. Like Hezbollah, the Iranian state has also linked negotiations with Israel to the ongoing situation in Gaza. More importantly, the developments over the last two weeks have significantly weakened Iran's larger strategic and security position. Militarily, Iran cannot match up to Israel. Hence, a conventional war against Israel is not in Iranian interests. Over the years, Iran has tried to overcome this challenge by building a network of proxies like Hamas in Gaza, Hezbollah in Lebanon and the Houthis in Yemen. While Hamas has been weakened significantly since the October 7 attacks, the last two weeks have also seen the Hezbollah being dealt a major blow. The 'axis of resistance' Iran had carefully built over the past several years has weakened substantially.</p>

<p>This puts the Iranian state in a precarious position. Though it would like to avoid escalation, it has little choice. The killing of Ismail Haniyeh on Iranian soil and the successful operation to take out Hassan Nasrallah came as major blows to Iranian prestige. Therefore, as many predicted, the regime had little choice but to launch a direct attack on Israel. With a weakened network of proxies, the Iranian regime would be cautious when approaching negotiations.</p>

<h2><strong>Why Israel Is Willing To Go Further</strong></h2>

<p>Israel has shown a greater willingness to escalate the conflict. Over the last two weeks, it has almost entirely taken out Hezbollah's top leadership and launched a ground operation in Lebanon. There are two factors why the Israeli state is taking a more maximalist stance. Firstly, Netanyahu's political future is precarious. Before the Hamas attack on October 7, there were clear indications of Netanyahu's falling popular support. From January to October last year, there were widespread protests against his government's proposed judicial reforms. These protests subsided only after the Hamas attacks.</p>

<p>Netanyahu faces an uncertain future once the conflict comes to an end. Continued conflict and further escalation would benefit him as they would preserve his authority. His popularity ratings have slowly risen as the war has dragged on. Therefore, from Netanyahu's perspective, there is little incentive to actively negotiate.</p>

<p>Secondly, over the last two weeks, Israel has gained the upper hand. With the Hezbollah and Hamas severely weakened, escalation would force Iran to get directly involved. This is in Israel's interests. Recent statements by former Prime Minister Naftali Bennett underscored Israel's stance. With Iran's proxies severely weakened, he views this as the ideal opportunity to change the Middle East's power balance. Given these realities, Israel is not likely to make a major compromise on the negotiating table.</p>

<h2><strong>Negotiation Is Difficult, But Possible</strong></h2>

<p>With all sides taking a maximalist position, does this mean a negotiated settlement is impossible? Not really. While it may be difficult, it is within the realm of possibility. The key will be to find off-ramps for the various parties involved. The US, in particular, will have a crucial role to play. In April this year, when Iran launched a similar attack on Israel, the US played a decisive role in convincing Israel to tone down its retaliation. Can the Biden administration pull off something similar? That would then offer a good starting point to begin the negotiations. The next few days are going to be crucial for the region. If further escalation is averted, bringing all parties to the negotiating table is possible.</p>

<p><em>(The author is Assistant Professor of International Studies, FLAME University)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/d8ho5jdg_israel_625x300_03_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-israeli-strikes-hit-south-beirut-lebanon-state-media-6707774]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Enemy Aircraft Launched 3 Strikes": Fresh Israel Raids In South Beirut]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-israeli-strikes-hit-south-beirut-lebanon-state-media-6707774]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 03 Oct 2024 17:18:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Lebanon's state-run media said three Israeli air strikes hit Hezbollah's south Beirut stronghold on Thursday, the latest raids following a night of intense bombardment.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lebanon's state-run media said three Israeli air strikes hit Hezbollah's south Beirut stronghold on Thursday, the latest raids following a night of intense bombardment.</p>

<p>"Enemy aircraft launched three strikes on (Beirut's) southern suburbs," the official National News Agency (NNA) reported.</p>

<p>A source close to the group told AFP the strike "targeted a building housing Hezbollah's media relations office," which had already been "evacuated".</p>

<p>This week, Israel announced that its troops had started "ground raids" into parts of southern Lebanon, a stronghold of Hezbollah, after days of heavy bombardment of areas across the country where the militant group holds sway.</p>

<p>After nearly a year of low-intensity cross-border fighting, Israel has shifted the focus of its operation from Gaza to Lebanon, where heavy bombing has killed more than 1,000 people and forced hundreds of thousands to flee.</p>

<p>Last week, Israel killed Hezbollah leader Hassan Nasrallah in the group's southern Beirut bastion, a densely packed residential area before residents fled the violence.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/msqeclr_beirut-reuters_625x300_29_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The latest raids following a night of intense bombardment. (FILE)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gaza-and-a-ceasefire-slip-out-of-focus-as-lebanon-conflict-rages-6707519]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[As Lebanon Conflict Rages, Gaza And A Ceasefire Slip Out Of Focus]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gaza-and-a-ceasefire-slip-out-of-focus-as-lebanon-conflict-rages-6707519]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 03 Oct 2024 16:41:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Palestinians fear the crisis in Lebanon is diverting the world's attention from Gaza, where Israeli strikes killed dozens more people this week, and diminishing already dim prospects for a ceasefire a year into a war that has shattered the enclave.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Palestinians fear the crisis in Lebanon is diverting the world's attention from Gaza, where Israeli strikes killed dozens more people this week, and diminishing already dim prospects for a ceasefire a year into a war that has shattered the enclave.</p>

<p>An escalation in the conflict between Israel and Iran-backed militant group Hezbollah over the past two weeks has led to clashes between Israeli and Hezbollah forces inside Lebanon and fueled fears of a wider regional war.</p>

<p>Both Israel and its Hamas foes in Gaza say the Lebanon conflict could help end the Gaza conflict, but some analysts, officials from mediating countries, and Gazans, are sceptical.</p>

<p>"The focus is on Lebanon, which means the war in Gaza isn't ending anytime soon," Hussam Ali, a 45-year-old Gaza City resident who said his family had been displaced seven times since the conflict between Israel and Hamas began on Oct. 7 last year, told Reuters via a chat app.</p>

<p>When Iran launched ballistic missiles at Israel late on Tuesday, provoking an Israeli promise of a "painful" response, some Gazans welcomed the salvo visible in the skies overhead as a sign Tehran was fighting for their cause.</p>

<p>Sami Abu Zuhri, a senior Hamas official, said prospects for a Gaza ceasefire deal, which would see the release of Israeli hostages held in Gaza and Palestinians jailed by Israel, were distant before the escalation in Lebanon. A regional conflagration could lead to pressure on Israel to strike a deal in Gaza, he said.</p>

<p>But with attention swinging to Lebanon, the war in Gaza risked being prolonged, said Ashraf Abouelhoul, managing editor of state-owned newspaper Al-Ahram in Egypt, which has helped to mediate months of ceasefire negotiations.</p>

<p>"The most dangerous thing isn't that the media attention is going somewhere else, it is the fact that no one in the world is now talking about a deal or a ceasefire, and that frees Israel's hand to continue its military offensive and plans in Gaza," he said.</p>

<p><strong>STALLED TALKS</strong></p>

<p>Inside Gaza there has been no sign of a let-up in Israel's offensive against Hamas. On Thursday, local medics reported at least 99 Palestinian deaths in the past 24 hours.</p>

<p>Egypt, which has been alarmed by the Israeli offensive on the other side of its border with Gaza and has lost billions of dollars in Suez Canal revenues during the war, is frustrated that its mediation efforts have failed to secure a truce.</p>

<p>US State Department spokesman Matthew Miller told reporters that the US remained focused on securing a ceasefire though Hamas had for weeks "refused to engage".</p>

<p>Hamas officials and Western diplomats said in August that negotiations had stalled due to new Israeli demands to keep troops in Gaza.</p>

<p>"Whereas Israel has been saying since Oct. 7 that military force and putting pressure on Hamas and Hezbollah will help to bring the hostages home we have seen that the exact opposite is true," said Nomi Bar-Yaacov, an expert on Middle East diplomacy at London-based think-tank Chatham House.</p>

<p>Israel's escalated campaign against Hezbollah "is putting the ceasefire in Gaza on the back burner, given that the focus is now on trying to dismantle as much of Hezbollah's military arsenal as possible," she said.</p>

<p>An official briefed on the Gaza ceasefire talks told Reuters nothing would happen until after the US presidential election on Nov. 5, "because nobody can effectively pressure (Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin) Netanyahu, which is the key impediment to a Gaza ceasefire deal".</p>

<p>The official said that during UN General Assembly meetings last week Hezbollah wanted a proposal for a 21-day ceasefire with Israel to be linked to a ceasefire deal in Gaza, but Israel rejected this and the plan was dropped. Top Israeli officials publicly dismissed the idea of a quick ceasefire with Hezbollah.</p>

<p>Israel's killing of Hezbollah leader Hassan Nasrallah last week complicated chances for mediation, two Egyptian security sources said. Egypt's efforts became limited to containing any further escalation, the sources said.</p>

<p><strong>ROCKETS</strong></p>

<p>Hezbollah began firing rockets into Israel at the start of the Gaza war in support of Hamas, causing the evacuation of tens of thousands of residents whom Israel says need to return home.</p>

<p>In Lebanon, nearly 1,900 people have been killed and more than 9,000 wounded in Lebanon in nearly a year of cross-border fighting, with most of the deaths occurring in the past two weeks, according to Lebanese government statistics.</p>

<p>More than a million Lebanese have been forced to flee their homes.</p>

<p>The casualty figures are still a fraction of those in Gaza, where the health ministry says at least 41,788 Palestinians have been killed and 96,794 wounded since Oct. 7 last year.</p>

<p>The Gaza war began after Hamas led a shock incursion into Israel, killing about 1,200 people and taking more than 250 hostage, according to Israeli tallies.</p>

<p>"We feel for the people of Lebanon and we don't want them to go through the devastation and starvation we are enduring," said Ghada, a 50-year-old mother of five living in a tent in the central Gaza city of Deir Al-Balah, where a million people are sheltering.</p>

<p>"I am afraid the world has become less interested in what happens to us here."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/k8ri1jd8_gaza-reuters_625x300_03_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/massive-sinkhole-in-lahore-swallows-3-vehicles-causes-traffic-disruptions-6707460]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Massive Sinkhole In Lahore Swallows 3 Vehicles, Causes Traffic Disruptions]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/massive-sinkhole-in-lahore-swallows-3-vehicles-causes-traffic-disruptions-6707460]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 03 Oct 2024 16:34:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Pictures and videos of the incident have gone viral on social media, showing locals helping the trapped commuters.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A massive sinkhole suddenly appeared on a main road in Johar Town, Lahore, swallowing three vehicles - a car and two motorcycles - and causing major traffic disruptions. Two people, who were trapped inside the car when the sinkhole suddenly formed, sustained injuries but were rescued with the help of nearby residents, <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.geo.tv/latest/566765-watch-massive-lahore-sinkhole-swallows-three-vehicles">Geo News</a></em> reported. They were taken to a hospital. According to the Lahore Development Authority (LDA), the sinkhole was caused by an underground sewer line leakage, which weakened the road over time.</p>

<p>Pictures and<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://x.com/ShirazHassan/status/1840764018845245451/video/1"> videos </a>of the incident have gone viral on social media, showing locals helping the trapped commuters.&nbsp;</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="cy">Sinkhole near Johar town, Lahore. <a href="https://t.co/2yVGB5dKlX">pic.twitter.com/2yVGB5dKlX</a></p>
 Basit Alvi (@bpk69) <a href="https://twitter.com/bpk69/status/1840809891466002665?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 30, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The incident prompted swift action from the Chief Traffic Officer (CTO) of Lahore, who diverted traffic from the affected area, leading to increased congestion on alternative routes. A traffic response unit was also deployed to mitigate the situation.</p>

<p>This is not an isolated incident, as Johar Town has experienced multiple sinkholes in recent months, causing injuries and damage. Notably, the area's infrastructure has been severely impacted by record-breaking rains in August, damaging drainage systems and roads, particularly in Khayaban-i-Firdausi. Residents and commuters are urging authorities to address the recurring infrastructure issues and improve road safety.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The road has become extremely dangerous for motorists, as sinkholes can emerge at any time, putting lives at risk. Look at this incident  the car fell in, injuring the driver and his friend, a witness told&nbsp;<em><a href="https://www.dawn.com/news/1862231/three-injured-as-car-bike-fall-into-sinkhole" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Dawn</a>.</em></p>

<p>A sinkhole is a depression or hole in the ground that forms when a layer of soil or rock is removed or collapses, often suddenly and without warning. This phenomenon can occur due to various natural or human-induced reasons, including karst terrain, groundwater, weathering, and earthquakes, as well as mining, drilling, construction, and water leakage. Sinkholes can vary greatly in size, from small depressions to massive craters, and can extend hundreds of feet in depth, posing significant risks to structures, infrastructure, and human life.</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/q2a15ut_-sinkhole-in-lahore_625x300_03_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[This is not an isolated incident as Johar Town has experienced multiple sinkholes in recent months]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-teen-arrested-for-filming-women-minors-in-mall-restroom-using-hidden-camera-6707005]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Teen Arrested For Filming Women In Mall Restroom Using Hidden Camera]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-teen-arrested-for-filming-women-minors-in-mall-restroom-using-hidden-camera-6707005]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 03 Oct 2024 15:39:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Andy Cardenas, the teenager, has been charged with invasion of privacy for placing a hidden camera in a mall restroom]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A US teenager has been arrested on charges of using a hidden camera in a mall toilet to record numerous women and at least four minors. The incident occurred at the Newport Centre Mall in Jersey City, where officials reported that the 18-year-old, Andy Cardenas, now faced a charge of invasion of privacy.</p>

<p>On Friday, August 9, 2024, an adult female discovered a black device while using the family restroom located on the first floor of JC Penney, the Hudson County prosecutor's office said in a press release.</p>

<p>Upon discovering the concealed device, she promptly handed it to the authorities, leading to an investigation by the Hudson County prosecutor's office.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">PRESS RELEASE: Man Charged After Recording Device Found in Mall Restroom <a href="https://t.co/KnWuarPLvP">pic.twitter.com/KnWuarPLvP</a></p>
 ProsecutorSuarezHCPO (@HCPOProsecutor) <a href="https://twitter.com/HCPOProsecutor/status/1841539307128992169?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 2, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>According to a report by a <a href="https://www.nj.com/hudson/2024/10/dozens-of-women-and-4-girls-filmed-by-hidden-camera-inside-bathroom-at-nj-mall-teen-is-arrested.html">local news outlet</a>, authorities reviewed the footage obtained through a communications data warrant and discovered approximately 35 videos of adult women who were exposed using the restroom, approximately four videos of female minors who were exposed using the restroom, and one video of a male and woman in the restroom together engaging in sexual acts, as stated in Cardenas' criminal complaint.</p>

<p>Crucially, the footage also captured a male figure  later identified as Cardenas  setting up the hidden camera inside the JC Penney toilet. This led to his identification and arrest.</p>

<p>Authorities are still piecing together the timeline of the suspect's activities, as the footage lacks any dates or timestamps. They are also uncertain about the locations where all the videos were filmed. To identify more potential victims, the prosecutor's office has released images of four unrecognised restrooms.</p>

<p>The Hudson County prosecutor's office said, Multiple electronic/digital files were recovered from the recording device, which contained images from several unidentified restrooms. The Special Victims Unit is seeking the public's help identifying the location of the restrooms in the attached photos. It is not yet known how long the recording device was being utilised.<br />
<br />
Cardenas was arrested on October 1 and released on a summons pending his first court appearance, which is tentatively scheduled for October 22, stated the press release.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/8qhrb7t8_us-teen-_625x300_03_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Andy Cardenas, 18, was arrested and charged with one count of invasion of privacy]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-gaza-israeli-man-who-lost-wife-son-in-october-7-attack-pain-doesnt-subside-6706986]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Pain Doesn't Subside": Israeli Man Who Lost Wife, Son In October 7 Attack]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-gaza-israeli-man-who-lost-wife-son-in-october-7-attack-pain-doesnt-subside-6706986]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 03 Oct 2024 15:36:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Avida Bachar runs his hands across the steel surface of a door that is pierced with bullet holes and is still stained by his son Carmel's]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Avida Bachar runs his hands across the steel surface of a door that is pierced with bullet holes and is still stained by his son Carmel's blood, nearly a year after the 15-year-old was killed during Hamas' October 7 attack on southern Israel.</p>

<p>Bachar also lost his wife Dana that day, when the operatives stormed through their home at Kibbutz Be'eri, setting fire to houses and killing or kidnapping men, women and children. In all, the kibbutz, a tight-knit community just three miles (five km) from Gaza, lost about a tenth of its roughly 1,000 residents.</p>

<p>Bachar's family, like most others on the kibbutz, took shelter in the safe room when Hamas started firing rockets from Gaza into Israel that morning.</p>

<p>But kibbutz safe rooms were built to protect residents against rockets - not a ground assault by dozens of heavily armed men who shot through the steel door, threw grenades through the window and set Bachar's home ablaze.</p>

<p>"I miss them endlessly," 51-year-old Bachar said of his wife and son. "(The pain) doesn't fade or subside. It's strong, all the time."</p>

<p>But Bachar, who lost a leg in the attack, remains hopeful that Kibbutz Be'eri can still heal in time. He is sustained in his optimism by his daughter Hadar, now 14, who was wounded in the attack.</p>

<p>"Hadar is okay. Hadar is 10 times stronger than me. Kids see the here and now. I imagine Hadar getting married in a few years without her mother by her side and I fall apart," he added.</p>

<p>Bachar returned to Be'eri after a six-month hospitalisation and is now busy overseeing the jojoba harvest and getting used to his prosthetic leg. "In two weeks we start to harvest the avocado," he said, donning an 'I Love Be'eri' T-shirt.</p>

<p><strong>SAFE HAVEN</strong></p>

<p>Be'eri was established in 1946 with the aim of creating a collective, egalitarian farming community. Its main source of income these days is its print shop, which was back up and running just weeks after the Hamas attack.</p>

<p>In the aftermath of Oct. 7, most of its surviving residents were evacuated to a hotel by the Dead Sea. A few have now gone back to live on the kibbutz, where many houses still stand damaged by the grenades and gunfire, ransacked, or burnt.</p>

<p>"This place will flourish again and we will recover with it. If I fast-forward three or four years ahead, I have no doubt we will be in a better place," said Bachar.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, his daughter Hadar is staying with her aunt, until Bachar can join her, at the temporary residence being built for the community in Hatzerim, a kibbutz in the Negev desert, around 18 miles (29 km) away.</p>

<p>Close to 70% of Kibbutz Be'eri's surviving population, mostly families, have moved to Hatzerim since the start of the school year in September, said Iftah Celniker, Be'eri's community director.</p>

<p>Keeping the community together while uprooted has been their main challenge, said Celniker. But the ties between the kibbutz members remain strong while the houses in Be'eri are being torn down and rebuilt.</p>

<p>It could take many months before they all go back to Be'eri. "It will take time not only to build Be'eri but to build the confidence of it being a safe haven," said Celniker.</p>

<p>Hamas operatives killed 1,200 people and took some 250 hostages in their Oct. 7 rampage, according to Israeli tallies, prompting an Israeli military offensive in which Gaza health officials say more than 41,000 Palestinians have been killed.</p>

<p><strong>'OUR PLACE TO FIGHT FOR'</strong></p>

<p>Anger still smoulders among Be'eri residents towards the Israeli army for failing to protect their kibbutz and towards the government, which many say is not doing enough to bring back the 101 hostages still held in Gaza, at least half of whom are believed to be still alive. The operatives took 10 hostages from Be'eri, of whom at least three are thought to be still alive.</p>

<p>One of the killed hostages from Be'eri is Carmel Gat, 40, whose body was found in a Hamas tunnel in southern Gaza with five other hostages. The gunmen killed the six people when they spotted Israeli soldiers in the vicinity, authorities said.</p>

<p>Gat had survived in captivity until the end of August. Hostages who had been with her and were released during a brief November truce said she had helped them get through their time in captivity with yoga and meditation.</p>

<p>Gat's mother Kinneret was killed by Hamas on Oct. 7 in the kibbutz. Her sister-in-law was kidnapped and released in November.</p>

<p>A banner with a photo of a smiling Carmel hangs over the wreckage of the family home at Be'eri, as her younger brother Or sifts through the family belongings in the ravaged house.</p>

<p>Outside, a pomegranate hangs off a tree with no one to pick it. The fruit is a traditional food of the Jewish new year which begins on Thursday. Despite his family's ordeal, Or can still see a future in which he one day raises a family in Be'eri.</p>

<p>"Our safety will never be the same again but this is the place for all of our life, for the happiest moments and the horrible moments - this is our place to live in, our place to fight for," Or Gat said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/l6ut6kf8_avida-bachar-reuters_625x300_03_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Avida Bachar was injured following a deadly attack by Hamas gunmen from Gaza.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>