<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Dec 2024 07:59:48 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/human-rights-day-2024-know-date-history-theme-and-significance-7212592]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Human Rights Day 2024: Know Date, History, Theme And Significance]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/human-rights-day-2024-know-date-history-theme-and-significance-7212592]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Dec 2024 07:58:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Human Rights Day 2024: The UN  has decided to dedicate the theme of Human Rights Day this year to "Our Rights, Our Future, Right Now".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Human Rights Day 2024:</strong> Human Rights Day is celebrated every year on December 10 to commemorate the adoption of the Universal Declaration of Human Rights (UDHR) by the United Nations General Assembly (UNGA) in 1948. The day is intended to celebrate and promote rights that protect against abuses, violations and other harms, ensuring everyone can live in dignity and respect -- irrespective of their race, gender, religion, nationality or any other factor. As per the UN, "upholding human rights is not only about addressing present injustices, it's about reshaping unjust societies and empowering marginalised groups".</p>

<h3><strong>Theme for Human Rights Day 2024</strong></h3>

<p>This year's theme for Human Rights Day is: "Our Rights, Our Future, Right Now" which reinforces how human rights affect people everywhere, every day.</p>

<p>"Human rights have a tangible positive impact and offer practical solutions. By embracing the full power of human rights as the path to the future we want, the world can become more peaceful and equal," the UN said announcing the theme.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/india-says-us-report-on-alleged-human-rights-abuses-reflects-deep-biases-very-poor-understanding-of-india-5520822" rel="noindex, nofollow"><strong>Also Read | "Poor Understanding": India Trashes US Report On Alleged Rights Abuse</strong></a></p>

<h3><strong>History and significance</strong></h3>

<p>Human rights are protected by international and national laws and treaties globally. The mission to protect human rights around the world has been tasked to a 47-member grouping known as the Human Rights Council.</p>

<p>These UN member-states are empowered to prevent inequality, abuses and discrimination, protect the most vulnerable, and punish the perpetrators of human rights violations.</p>

<h3><strong>Why are human rights necessary?</strong></h3>

<p>Human rights are necessary and their defence even more so to prevent harm befalling any marginalised individual or group. They have a preventative, protective as well as a transformative role to play in civil society.</p>

<h3><strong>India reaffirms its commitment</strong></h3>

<p>On the eve of Human Rights Day, the National Human Rights Commission (NHRC) Acting Chairperson, Vijaya Bharathi Sayani said India remained committed to upholding the human rights of every individual.</p>

<p>"This significant day, observed every year on 10th December since 1950, commemorates the adoption of the Universal Declaration of Human Rights (UDHR) by the United Nations in 1948. For India, this day holds special significance, as Indian representatives made a pivotal contribution to the drafting of this landmark document, which embodies humanity's shared commitment to dignity, justice, and equality," said Mr Sayani.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/dacu54cg_human_625x300_10_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Human Rights Day is celebrated every year on December 10.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-luigi-mangione-man-behind-unitedhealthcare-ceos-murder-7212585]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Who Is Luigi Mangione, Man Behind UnitedHealthCare CEO's Murder]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-luigi-mangione-man-behind-unitedhealthcare-ceos-murder-7212585]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Dec 2024 07:52:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Luigi Mangione was detained in Altoona, Pennsylvania on Monday after he was found with a gun without a license, a silencer, and fake ID cards.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Luigi Mangione, a 26-year-old former Ivy League student has been <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/26-year-old-man-arrested-over-unitedhealthcare-ceos-murder-police-7211564" target="_blank">arrested as a suspect</a> in UnitedHealthcare CEO Brian Thompson's murder. Mangione was detained in Altoona, Pennsylvania on Monday after he was found with a gun without a license, a silencer, and fake ID cards.</p>

<p>Brian Thompson, 50, was shot in the chest in New York, last week on December 4. He was shot outside the hotel New York Hilton Midtown on West 54th Street. He was in town to attend his company's annual investor conference when he was shot at least twice - once in the back and once in the right calf. He was taken to the hospital but declared dead.</p>

<h3><strong>Here's what we know about Luigi Mangione:</strong></h3>

<ol>
	<li>Luigi Mangione, arrested by the New York Police as a "strong person of interest" is an Ivy League graduate software engineer.</li>
	<li>Mangione comes from a famous Baltimore family. He is the grandson of Nicholas Mangione, a famed Baltimore real-estate developer and Mary C Mangione, a philanthropist, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://edition.cnn.com/us/live-news/brian-thompson-unitedhealthcare-death-investigation-12-9-24/index.html" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">reported CNN</a>.</li>
	<li><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/luigi-mangione/" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">Mangione's LinkedIn profile</a> suggests he has a bachelor's and master of science engineering from the University of Pennsylvania. <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2024/dec/09/unitedhealthcare-ceo-shooting-suspect-arrested" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">The Guardian</a> confirmed it with a university spokesperson and found the information true.</li>
	<li>The social media profile also states that he has been employed at TrueCar for the past four years. However, in a statement, TrueCar, Inc told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2024/dec/09/unitedhealthcare-ceo-shooting-suspect-arrested" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">The Guardian</a> that Mangione has not been with the company since 2023. "While we generally don't comment on personnel matters, we can confirm that Luigi Mangione has not been an employee of our company since 2023," they said.</li>
	<li>Mangione is registered to vote at his family's address in Cockeysville, Maryland, a Baltimore suburb, reported CNN, basis the state's voter registration lookup website.</li>
</ol>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/rbg97kpg_luigi-mangione_625x300_10_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Luigi Mangione, a suspect in UnitedHealthcare CEO's murder.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-criminology-student-kills-woman-to-know-what-it-feels-like-7212430]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK Criminology Student Kills Woman To "Know What It Feels Like"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-criminology-student-kills-woman-to-know-what-it-feels-like-7212430]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Dec 2024 07:11:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[On the night of the stabbings, the two women were sitting on the sand where they had lit a fire and were watching the full moon.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A criminology student in the UK has been accused of killing a woman while injuring another as he wanted to "know what it would be like to take a life", according to the prosecutors.&nbsp;Nasen Saadi, 20, killed Amie Gray, 34, and seriously injured 38-year-old Leanne Miles on Durley Chine Beach in Bournemouth in&nbsp;May, earlier this year.&nbsp;Saadi started his pursuit to kill someone in April as he looked for a place for the attack. After researching beaches in the south of England, he settled on Bournemouth, according to a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/ceqlnpg0gr1o" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>BBC </em></a>report.</p>

<p>"He seems to have wanted to know what it would be like to take life, &nbsp;perhaps he wanted to know what it would be like to make women feel afraid, perhaps he thought it would make him feel powerful, make him interesting to others," Sarah Jones KC, the prosecutor told the jury at the Winchester Crown Court.</p>

<p>On the night of the stabbings, the two women were sitting on the sand where they had lit a fire and were watching the full moon. Both were chatting and sharing stories when Saadi, 20, 'hovering at the edges of the promenade" stepped up and executed the knife attack on the two unsuspecting women.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/man-jailed-for-10-years-over-womans-death-at-slapping-therapy-workshop-in-uk-7198153" rel="noindex, nofollow"><strong>Also Read | Man Jailed For 10 Years Over Woman's Death At 'Slapping Therapy' Workshop In UK</strong></a></p>

<h3><strong>Fascinated by true crime</strong></h3>

<p>Ms Gray suffered 10 thrusts from the knife, including one to her heart and succumbed to the injuries on the beach. Ms Miles suffered about 20 wounds but managed to survive.</p>

<p>"In an act horrifying in its savagery and in its randomness he stabbed them both multiple times, chasing after them as they tried to escape or divert him from the other and continued his attack," Ms Jones said.</p>

<p>"He left them on the sand to bleed to death while he moved away and tried to disappear back into the shadows, away from the glare of the streetlights or the moonlight and back into anonymity. He got rid of his weapon. He changed his clothes and shoes and got rid of them," the barrister added.</p>

<p>Saddi told the police he was fascinated by true crime and was in Bournemouth at the time of the attacks but denied any involvement. He left the area the next day and was arrested on May 28 with the police finding knives in his bedside drawer and hidden between a wall and wardrobe.</p>

<p>Despite the overwhelming evidence against him, Saadi has pleaded not guilty to murder and attempted murder as the trial continues.</p>

<p><br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/72d23nag_crime-generic_625x300_09_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Despite the overwhelming evidence, Saadi has pleaded not guilty.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-nominates-indian-american-harmeet-dhillon-for-top-civil-rights-post-7212336]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Nominates Indian-American Harmeet Dhillon For Top Civil Rights Post]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-nominates-indian-american-harmeet-dhillon-for-top-civil-rights-post-7212336]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Dec 2024 06:59:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President-elect Donald Trump on Monday nominated Indian-American Harmeet K Dhillon as Assistant Attorney General for Civil Rights at the Department of Justice.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President-elect Donald Trump on Monday nominated Indian-American Harmeet K Dhillon as Assistant Attorney General for Civil Rights at the Department of Justice.</p>

<p>“I am pleased to nominate Harmeet K. Dhillon as Assistant Attorney General for Civil Rights at the US Department of Justice,” Trump announced on Truth Social, a social media platform owned by him.</p>

<p>“Throughout her career, Harmeet has stood up consistently to protect our cherished civil liberties, including taking on big tech for censoring our free speech, representing Christians who were prevented from praying together during COVID, and suing corporations who use woke policies to discriminate against their workers,” he said.</p>

<p>“Harmeet is one of the top election lawyers in the country, fighting to ensure that all, and ONLY, legal votes are counted. She is a graduate of Dartmouth College and the University of Virginia Law School, and clerked in the US Fourth Circuit Court of Appeals,” Trump said.</p>

<p>“Harmeet is a respected member of the Sikh religious community. In her new role at the DOJ, Harmeet will be a tireless defender of our constitutional rights, and will enforce our civil rights and election laws FAIRLY and FIRMLY,” said the President-elect.</p>

<p>Dhillon was subject to racial attack after she recited Ardas at the Republican National Convention in July this year. Last year she unsuccessfully ran for the position of Republican National Committee chairmanship.</p>

<p>Chandigarh-born Dhillon, 54, moved to the United States when she was a child along with her parents. In 2016, she was the first Indian-American to appear on the stage of the GOP Convention in Cleveland.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/hosrh6ko_harmeet-k-dhillon_625x300_10_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Harmeet K. Dhillon  is one of the top election lawyers in the country.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/all-about-anoushka-kale-the-british-indian-student-elected-president-of-prestigious-cambridge-union-7212372]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[All About The British Indian Student Elected President Of Cambridge Union]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/all-about-anoushka-kale-the-british-indian-student-elected-president-of-prestigious-cambridge-union-7212372]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Dec 2024 06:58:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Anoushka Kale has been elected president of the University of Cambridge's renowned Cambridge Union Society for the Easter term following an uncontested race.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Anoushka Kale has been elected president of the University of Cambridge's renowned Cambridge Union Society for the Easter term following an uncontested race. The 20-year-old British Indian student will reportedly become the first female Union president since last Easter term. She is the fourth candidate in five elections to become president unopposed.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Ms Kale is reading English Literature at Sidney Sussex College at Cambridge University. She is among the few South Asian heritage female members to take on the prestigious role. As the serving Debates Officer of the society, she ran on a platform of strengthening ties with cultural societies of the university such as the India Society.</p>

<p>The president-elect won 126 votes to be elected uncontested for the next 2025 Easter term, with 25 members balloting to re-open nominations. Her campaign centred around improving "diversity and access" at the Union. She has promised to strengthen "ties with cultural and access-based societies" and reduce access ticket costs, according to a report by Variety.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Ms Kale's pledges find root in the Cambridge Union's decision to increase their membership fees earlier this year amid financial pressures and increasing "upkeep costs" of its Grade-II listed heritage building.</p>

<p>After her victory, Ms Kale told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.varsity.co.uk/news/28700" rel="No Follow, No Index" target="_blank">Varsity</a>, "I am absolutely delighted and honoured to have been elected as President of the Cambridge Union Society for Easter 2025 and grateful for the membership's support,"</p>

<p>"For my term, I will seek to expand diversity and access at the Union through greater collaboration with cultural groups, like the university's India Society. I am also especially passionate about continuing to host international speakers and global debate motions, as I did as Debates Officer of the society," she added.</p>

<p>She further said that she's looking forward to delivering on her manifesto promises, "particularly on expanding diversity through society collaborations and reduced access tickets for the summer garden party."</p>

<p>"A key component of my platform was delivering more for members, which I will prioritise throughout the term with a members' motion and debate dinner ballots. Bringing new faces onto committees and increasing membership engagement is crucial to making our elections more contested again, which I pledge to push for," she added</p>

<h2><strong>About Cambridge Union Society</strong></h2>

<p>Cambridge Union Society is one of the world's oldest debating societies founded in 1815, known for its commitment to free speech.</p>

<p>Former presidents and officers of the Cambridge Union Society have included celebrated English economist and philosopher John Maynard Keynes, novelist Robert Harris and, in recent years, British Indian peer and founder of Cobra Beer Karan Bilimoria.</p>

<p>Like the Oxford University's Oxford Union Society, the Cambridge Union has a long tradition of hosting prominent figures from all areas of public life in its chamber, from US presidents Theodore Roosevelt and Ronald Reagan and UK Prime Ministers Winston Churchill, Margaret Thatcher and John Major, to Stephen Hawking, Bill Gates and the Dalai Lama.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/r93okv78_anoushka-kale_625x300_09_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Anoushka Kale is reading English Literature at Sidney Sussex College at Cambridge University]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-warplanes-launch-over-100-strikes-on-syria-army-targets-report-7212124]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israeli Warplanes Launch Over 100 Strikes On Syria Army Targets: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-warplanes-launch-over-100-strikes-on-syria-army-targets-report-7212124]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Dec 2024 05:37:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel conducted more than 100 air strikes on military targets in Syria on Monday including a research centre Western countries suspected of having links to chemical weapons production in Damascus, a war monitor said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel conducted more than 100 air strikes on military targets in Syria on Monday including a research centre Western countries suspected of having links to chemical weapons production in Damascus, a war monitor said.</p>

<p>"Israeli warplanes launched over 100 strikes in Syria today, including on the Barzah scientific research centre," Rami Abdel Rahman who heads the Syrian Observatory for Human Rights told AFP, reporting "increased Israeli strikes to destroy the former regime's military capabilities".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-10/6e8i71v_missile-generic_650x400_17_October_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-army-in-golan-buffer-zone-violation-of-1974-syria-agreement-un-7212119]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israeli Army In Golan Buffer Zone Violation Of 1974 Syria Agreement: UN]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-army-in-golan-buffer-zone-violation-of-1974-syria-agreement-un-7212119]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Dec 2024 05:32:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli troops that have moved into the buffer zone on the edge of the Israeli-annexed Golan Heights "constitute a violation" of the 1974 disengagement agreement between Israel and Syria, a UN spokesman said Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli troops that have moved into the buffer zone on the edge of the Israeli-annexed Golan Heights "constitute a violation" of the 1974 disengagement agreement between Israel and Syria, a UN spokesman said Monday.</p>

<p>The UN peacekeeping force deployed in the Golan Heights, known as UNDOF, "informed the Israeli counterparts that these actions would constitute a violation of the 1974 disengagement agreement," said Stephane Dujarric, spokesman for Secretary-General Antonio Guterres.</p>

<p>Stephane Dujarric said that the Israeli forces that entered the zone were still present in at least three locations.</p>

<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu announced on Sunday he had ordered the army to "seize" the demilitarized zone in the Syrian-controlled part of the Golan Heights after rebels swept Syrian president Bashar al-Assad from power.</p>

<p>Most of the Golan Heights plateau has been occupied since 1967 by Israel, which later annexed it in a move not recognized by most of the international community.</p>

<p>In 1974 a buffer zone was established to separate the Israeli-held and Syrian territories, with UN peacekeepers stationed there.</p>

<p>Amid the downfall of Assad, Israel announced a troop deployment to the Golan Heights citing "the possible entry of armed individuals into the buffer zone."</p>

<p>Israeli forces "will continue to operate as long as necessary in order to preserve the buffer zone and defend Israel," it added.</p>

<p>Israeli troops "have entered the area of separation and have been moving within that area where they remain in at least three locations throughout the area of separation," Dujarric said.</p>

<p>"There should be no military forces or activities in the area of separation. And Israel and Syria must continue to uphold the terms of that 1974 agreement, and preserve stability in the Golan," he said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/0ljbd8tg_united-nations_625x300_09_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/netanyahu-to-testify-in-corruption-trial-for-1st-time-amid-israel-hamas-war-7212093]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Netanyahu To Testify In Corruption Trial For 1st Time Amid Israel Hamas War]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/netanyahu-to-testify-in-corruption-trial-for-1st-time-amid-israel-hamas-war-7212093]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Dec 2024 05:26:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu of Israel is set to take the stand on Tuesday for the first time in his long-running corruption trial under a court order that is likely to force him to juggle between the courtroom and war room for weeks.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu of Israel is set to take the stand on Tuesday for the first time in his long-running corruption trial under a court order that is likely to force him to juggle between the courtroom and war room for weeks.</p>

<p>Israel has been waging war against the Palestinian group Hamas in Gaza for more than a year, during which Netanyahu had been granted a delay for the start of his court appearances. But on Thursday, the judges ruled that he must start testifying.</p>

<p>Charged with bribery, fraud and breach of trust, Netanyahu will testify three times a week, the court said, despite the Gaza war and possible new threats posed by wider turmoil in the Middle East, including in neighbouring Syria.</p>

<p>Netanyahu was indicted in 2019 in three cases involving gifts from millionaire friends and for allegedly seeking regulatory favours for media tycoons in return for favourable coverage. He denies any wrongdoing.</p>

<p>In the run-up to his court date, Netanyahu revived familiar pre-war rhetoric against law enforcement, describing investigations against him as a witch hunt. He denies the charges and has pleaded not guilty.</p>

<p>"The real threat to democracy in Israel is not posed by the public's elected representatives, but by some among the law enforcement authorities who refuse to accept the voters' choice and are trying to carry out a coup with rabid political investigations that are unacceptable in any democracy," he said in a statement on Thursday.</p>

<p>At a Monday night press conference Netanyahu said he had waited eight years to be able to tell his story and expressed outrage at the way witnesses had been treated during investigations.</p>

<p>Before the war, Netanyahu's legal troubles bitterly divided Israelis and shook Israeli politics through five rounds of elections. His government's bid last year to curb the powers of the judiciary further polarised Israelis.</p>

<p>The shock Hamas attack on Israel on Oct. 7, 2023, and the ensuing Gaza war swept Netanyahu's trial off the public agenda as Israelis came together in grief and trauma. But as the war dragged on, political unity crumbled.</p>

<p>In recent weeks, while fighting abated on one front after Israel reached a ceasefire with Hamas' Lebanese ally Hezbollah, members of Netanyahu's cabinet, including his justice and police ministers, have clashed with the judiciary.</p>

<p>In power almost consecutively since 2009, Netanyahu, 75, is Israel's longest serving leader and its first sitting prime minister to be charged with a crime.</p>

<p>His domestic legal battles were compounded last month when the International Criminal Court (ICC) issued an arrest warrant for him and his former defence chief Yoav Gallant along with a Hamas leader, for alleged war crimes in the Gaza conflict.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ekg2ef7_benjamin-netanyahu-reuters_625x300_24_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Benjamin Netanyahu was indicted in 2019 in three cases. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/26-year-old-man-arrested-over-unitedhealthcare-ceos-murder-police-7211564]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ex-Ivy League Student, 26, Arrested For UnitedHealthcare CEO's Murder]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/26-year-old-man-arrested-over-unitedhealthcare-ceos-murder-police-7211564]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Dec 2024 02:14:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 26-year-old man was arrested Monday after the targeted killing of a top health insurance executive on the streets of New York, police said, crediting a McDonald's employee in Pennsylvania who spotted a suspicious-looking customer.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 26-year-old man was arrested Monday over the targeted killing of a health insurance executive on the streets of New York, with investigators charging him with possession of fake IDs and a gun.</p>

<p>Investigators continued to interrogate Luigi Mangione in connection with last week's brazen murder, which triggered a nationwide manhunt and global headlines.</p>

<p>He arrived at a Pennsylvania court wearing a dark sweatshirt after 6:00 pm (2300 GMT) Monday and was led inside by Altoona police flanked by NYPD detectives where he was arraigned, broadcasters showed.</p>

<p>Mangione is next due to appear in court on December 23.</p>

<p>Pennsylvania Governor Josh Shapiro said that murder charges in New York state would follow, telling a media briefing "we do not kill people in cold blood to resolve policy differences or express a viewpoint."</p>

<p>Police have not confirmed reports the words "delay" and "deny" -- language used by insurers to reject claims -- were written on casings found at the scene, hinting at a possible political motive for the crime.</p>

<p>Mangione was apprehended by officers following a tip from staff at an Altoona McDonald's branch, where he was found wearing a mask and a beanie while using a laptop, and gave officers a fake ID, charging documents show.</p>

<p>They then searched him and found what police called a "ghost gun" capable of firing 9MM rounds and equipped with a suppressor that could have been made on a 3D printer.</p>

<p>When officers asked if he had been to New York recently, Mangione "became quiet and started to shake," according to the criminal complaint.</p>

<p>One of the fake IDs found was that used to check in to a Manhattan hostel ahead of the attack, discovered alongside a document that spoke to Mangione's "motivation and mindset," New York police said.</p>

<p>Mangione was born and raised in Maryland, studied at the Ivy League University of Pennsylvania, and had been living in Hawaii ahead of the killing.</p>

<p>"He matches the description of the identification we've been looking for. He's also in possession of several items that we believe will connect him to this incident," said New York mayor Eric Adams.</p>

<p>Police told reporters that Mangione possessed material that suggested he had "ill-will towards corporate America."</p>

<p>Mangione's LinkedIn profile showed he worked as a data engineer at TrueCar, a California-based online auto marketplace that said he left their employment in 2023.</p>

<p><strong>Fled by bike</strong></p>

<p>In last Wednesday's shooting, the gunman walked up behind Brian Thompson, a senior executive at UnitedHealthcare -- one of the country's largest medical insurers -- and shot him dead in front of bystanders.</p>

<p>The attack was captured by a surveillance camera and the footage seen by millions around the world as interest in the manhunt and mystery over the killer's motives built to a frenzy.</p>

<p>Thompson, 50, was attending an investor conference in the Midtown business district.</p>

<p>Detectives said the suspect fled the crime scene on foot before riding a bike to Central Park and later boarding a bus from a terminal in the north of the city connecting New York to surrounding states and beyond.</p>

<p>Video footage shows Thompson on the sidewalk outside the New York Hilton Midtown when a man in a hooded top, his lower face covered, approaches from behind and fires several shots at the father-of-two, who crumples to the ground.</p>

<p>An image released of the suspect was obtained from a youth hostel where the gunman apparently stayed before the hit, with media reporting he had lowered his mask to flirt with a receptionist.</p>

<p>A photo on what appeared to be one of Mangione's social media accounts includes an X-ray of an apparently injured spine, though no explicit political affiliation has emerged.</p>

<p>The highly profitable US medical insurance system is the source of deep frustration and anger among many Americans due to its steep costs and limited coverage, and Thompson's death was greeted with an absence of sympathy by some.</p>

<p>A Facebook post mourning his loss, shared by UnitedHealth Group, racked up more than 71,000 laugh emojis within two days before the counter was disabled.</p>

<p>Mangione must now be extradited from Pennsylvania to New York to face murder charges, police said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/scn21b3o_unitedhealthcare-ceo-killer_625x300_06_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Accused also had fake IDs similar to those used by the killer, say police (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-will-attack-us-again-if-we-end-war-now-says-israeli-pm-netanyahu-7211534]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hamas Will Attack Us Again If We End War Now, Says Israeli PM Netanyahu]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-will-attack-us-again-if-we-end-war-now-says-israeli-pm-netanyahu-7211534]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Dec 2024 02:05:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said Monday he would not stop the war in Gaza "now", with renewed efforts towards a ceasefire underway.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said Monday he would not stop the war in Gaza "now", with renewed efforts towards a ceasefire underway.</p>

<p>Speaking at a press conference in Jerusalem 14 months into the war against Hamas Palestinian operatives, he said "if we end the war now, Hamas will return, recover, rebuild and attack us again -- and that is what we do not want to go back to".</p>

<p>Netanyahu reiterated that he had set the goal of "the annihilation of Hamas, the elimination of its military and administrative capabilities" to prevent future attacks but said that the objective was not yet complete.</p>

<p>US Secretary of State Antony Blinken said on October 23 that Israel had "managed to dismantle Hamas's military capacity" and eliminated its senior leadership. With those successes, he said, it was time to "get the hostages home and bring the war to an end with an understanding of what will follow."</p>

<p>In recent days, there had been signs that months of failed ceasefire and hostage release negotiations might be revived and achieve a breakthrough.</p>

<p>Qatar, a main mediator, said on Saturday there was new "momentum" for negotiations created by the election of Donald Trump in the United States.</p>

<p>A source close to the Hamas delegation said at the same time that Turkey as well as Egypt and Qatar had been "making commendable efforts to stop the war," and a new round of talks could begin soon.</p>

<p>On Sunday, the prime minister met with the families of hostages held in Gaza and said that Israel's wars on Hezbollah and Hamas would facilitate negotiations for their release.</p>

<p>Protesters, including relatives of the hostages, have repeatedly called for a deal to free the captives and accused him of prolonging the war.</p>

<p>The war in Gaza was sparked by Hamas's October 7, 2023 attack which resulted in the deaths of 1,208 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on official data.</p>

<p>During the attack, operatives also kidnapped 251 hostages, 96 of whom remain in Gaza, including 34 who the military says are dead.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory offensive in Gaza has killed at least 44,758 people, mostly civilians, according to data from the Hamas-run health ministry that is considered reliable by the UN.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/c803ouj8_netanyahu-reuters_625x300_28_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel's retaliatory offensive in Gaza has killed at least 44,758 people, says Hamas (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-pm-says-occupied-golan-heights-will-remain-israeli-for-eternity-7211486]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israeli PM Says Occupied Golan Heights Will Remain Israeli "For Eternity"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-pm-says-occupied-golan-heights-will-remain-israeli-for-eternity-7211486]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Dec 2024 01:58:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said Monday that the Golan Heights, occupied by Israel for almost 60 years, would remain Israeli "for eternity".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said Monday that the Golan Heights, occupied by Israel for almost 60 years, would remain Israeli "for eternity".</p>

<p>Speaking at a press conference in Jerusalem,Benjamin Netanyahu thanked US President-elect Donald Trump for recognising Israel's 1981 annexation of the territory during his first term and said "the Golan will be part of the State of Israel for eternity"</p>

<p>.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/jdpp60fk_benjamin-netanyahu-afp_625x300_22_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Golan Heights has been occupied by Israel for almost 60 years. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-police-detain-man-in-connection-with-unitedhealth-ceos-murder-reports-7211128]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Police Detain Man In Connection With UnitedHealth CEO's Murder: Reports]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-police-detain-man-in-connection-with-unitedhealth-ceos-murder-reports-7211128]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Authorities on Monday detained a man in central Pennsylvania in connection with last week's murder of UnitedHealthcare CEO Brian Thompson after finding him in possession of a gun, a silencer and false identification cards similar the killer.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Authorities on Monday detained a man in central Pennsylvania in connection with last week's murder of UnitedHealthcare CEO Brian Thompson after finding him in possession of a gun, a silencer and false identification cards similar to those used by the killer, several media outlets reported.</p>

<p>Investigators received a tip about the man after he was spotted at a McDonald's in Altoona by someone who thought he looked like the suspected killer, CNN reported, citing unnamed officials.</p>

<p>The man being questioned had a handwritten "manifesto" criticizing healthcare companies for prioritizing profits over care, the New York Times reported, citing a law enforcement official.</p>

<p>One of the false cards found on the man also matched the ID used by the suspect to check into a hostel in Manhattan before the shooting, the Times reported.</p>

<p>The man has been arrested on local charges, possibly in connection with presenting a false ID to police, and New York detectives are headed to Altoona, according to the Times.</p>

<p>Neither the New York City Police Department nor the Altoona Police Department responded to a request for comment.</p>

<p>Thompson, 50, was gunned down outside a Manhattan hotel early on Wednesday morning by a masked man who appeared to wait for his arrival before shooting the executive from behind.</p>

<p>Police have not publicly identified a motive but have said Thompson appeared to be deliberately targeted.</p>

<p>The words "deny," "defend" and "depose" were carved into shell casings found at the scene, several news outlets have reported. The words evoke the title of a book critical of the insurance industry published in 2010 titled "Delay, Deny, Defend: Why Insurance Companies Don't Pay Claims and What You Can Do About It."</p>

<p>The suspect, who has not been identified by police, ran from the scene and then rode a bike into Central Park. Surveillance video captured him exiting the park and taking a taxi to a bus station in northern Manhattan, where police believe he used a bus to flee the city.</p>

<p>Thompson, a father of two, had been CEO of UnitedHealth Group's insurance unit since April 2021, part of a 20-year career with the company. He had been in New York to attend the company's annual investor conference.</p>

<p>A UnitedHealth spokesperson declined to comment on the latest reports.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/scn21b3o_unitedhealthcare-ceo-killer_625x300_06_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[One of the false cards found on the man also matched the ID used by the suspect. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-sanctions-syrian-leader-bashar-al-assads-father-in-law-7211085]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Sanctions Syrian Leader Bashar Al Assad's Father-In-Law]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-sanctions-syrian-leader-bashar-al-assads-father-in-law-7211085]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Dec 2024 23:56:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The US unveiled sanctions Monday against Bashar al-Assad's father-in-law, a day after the former Syrian president reportedly fled to Russia as rebels took over the capital Damascus.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The US unveiled sanctions Monday against Bashar al-Assad's father-in-law, a day after the former Syrian president reportedly fled to Russia as rebels took over the capital Damascus.</p>

<p>Assad's abrupt departure brought to a spectacular end five decades of brutal rule by his clan over a country ravaged by one of the deadliest wars of the century.</p>

<p>He oversaw a crackdown on a pro-democracy movement that erupted in 2011, sparking a civil war that killed 500,000 people and forced half the country to flee their homes.</p>

<p>The Treasury Department announced in a statement that Fawaz al-Akhras was being designated for providing "support and facilitation to Bashar al-Assad related to financial matters, sanctions evasion and attempts by Bashar al-Assad to achieve international political engagement."</p>

<p>Akhras was born in the Syrian city of Homs in September 1946, and is a dual Syrian and UK national, according to the Treasury's list of sanctioned individuals.</p>

<p>He trained as a cardiologist, and practised medicine in London, where his daughter Asma -- who is married to the toppled former president -- was born.</p>

<p>Akhras, whose registered address is an unassuming house in west London, was previously sanctioned by the US in 2020 along with Asma, his wife Sahar, and several other family members.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/osuo314g_fawaz-alakhras_625x300_09_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Fawaz al-Akhras was being designated for providing "support and facilitation to Bashar al-Assad. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mexico-study-suggest-extreme-heat-greater-risk-for-young-people-7211014]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Mexico Study Suggest Extreme Heat Greater Risk For Young People]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mexico-study-suggest-extreme-heat-greater-risk-for-young-people-7211014]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Dec 2024 23:46:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Extreme heat poses a greater risk to younger populations than the elderly, according to a new analysis which revealed that 75 per cent of heat-related deaths in Mexico from 1998-2019 occurred among those aged under 35 years.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Extreme heat poses a greater risk to younger populations than the elderly, according to a new analysis which revealed that 75 per cent of heat-related deaths in Mexico from 1998-2019 occurred among those aged under 35 years.</p>

<p>Researchers, including those from Columbia University, US, said the findings challenge the conventional belief that the elderly population are especially vulnerable to extreme heat on its head.</p>

<p>"It's a surprise. The young are physiologically the most robust people in the population. I would love to know why this is so," co-author Jeffrey Shrader of the Center for Environmental Economics and Policy, Columbia University's Climate School, said.</p>

<p>Published in the journal Science Advances, the team analysed excess deaths -- the number of deaths more or less than the average -- with 'wet-bulb' temperatures, a metric that combines heat and humidity or humid-heat to measure their intensified effects.</p>

<p>They found that over the two decades, the country suffered about 3,300 deaths a year related to heat, with nearly a third occurring in people aged 18-35 years. Children aged under five years, especially infants, too were found to be highly vulnerable.</p>

<p>However, people aged 50 years and above, usually considered at high risk in a warmer future, suffered the least levels of heat-related death. Instead, people in the age group died predominantly from modest cold, the team found.</p>

<p>They explained that while Mexico is mainly tropical and subtropical, there are many climate zones, including high-elevation areas, that can get relatively chilly.</p>

<p>The authors said, younger people are predominantly vulnerable to heat, with 35 years old accounting for 75 per cent of recent heat-related deaths and 87 per cent of heat-related lost life years.</p>

<p>Those 50 and older account for 96 per cent of cold-related deaths and 80 per cent of cold-related lost life years, the authors wrote.</p>

<p>According to researchers several factors are at work, for instance young adults are more likely to be engaged in outdoor labour, such as farming and construction activities, and thus could be more exposed to dehydration and heat stroke.</p>

<p>The same could go for indoor manufacturing in spaces lacking air conditioning, they said.</p>

<p>"These are the more junior people, low on the totem pole, who probably do the lion's share of hard work, with inflexible work arrangements," Shrader said.</p>

<p>Young adults are also more likely to participate in strenuous outdoor sports, the researchers said.</p>

<p>They cited a previous study by Mexican researchers which has shown that death certificates of working-age men were more likely to list extreme weather as a cause than those of other groups.</p>

<p>"We project, as the climate warms, heat-related deaths are going to go up, and the young will suffer the most," co-lead author, R. Daniel Bressler, a PhD candidate at Columbia University's Sustainable Development program, said.</p>

<p>Mexico was chosen for the analysis as the country collects highly granular geographical data on both mortality and daily temperatures, the team said.</p>

<p>They added that despite attention given to global warming and its dangers, extensive research has revealed that cold, not heat, is currently the world's number one cause of temperature-related mortality, including in Mexico.</p>

<p>However, heat-related deaths have been climbing in proportion since at least 2000, a trend that is expected to continue, the authors said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-07/q6mas5ug_heat-generic_625x300_27_July_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The authors said, younger people are predominantly vulnerable to heat. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/assads-fall-an-opportunity-to-rid-syria-of-chemical-weapons-7210946]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Assad's Fall An Opportunity To Rid Syria Of Chemical Weapons]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/assads-fall-an-opportunity-to-rid-syria-of-chemical-weapons-7210946]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Dec 2024 23:32:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The downfall of Syria's Bashar al-Assad, found to have used chemical weapons against his own people on multiple occasions during the civil war, creates an opportunity to rid the country of banned munitions, diplomatic sources said on Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The downfall of Syria's Bashar al-Assad, found to have used chemical weapons against his own people on multiple occasions during the civil war, creates an opportunity to rid the country of banned munitions, diplomatic sources said on Monday.</p>

<p>The Organisation for the Prohibition of Chemical Weapons (OPCW) said it was following the situation in Syria with "special attention" to chemical weapons-related sites and had reminded Syria, through its embassy, of its continued obligation to declare and destroy all banned chemical weapons.</p>

<p>A team at OPCW has spent more than a decade trying to clarify what types of chemical weapons Syria still possesses, but has made little progress due to obstruction by Assad's government, it said.</p>

<p>"To date, this work has continued, and the Syrian declaration of its chemical weapons programme still cannot be considered as accurate and complete," the OPCW statement said.</p>

<p>A diplomatic source said Assad's government had been "playing cat and mouse with us for years" and that "we are convinced that they still had an ongoing programme."</p>

<p>"It costs millions and millions of dollars without making any progress," said the source, speaking on condition of anonymity. "So it really is a great opportunity now to get rid of (chemical weapons) for good. This is the moment."</p>

<p>Security guarantees will need to be arranged before any deployment by OPCW inspectors. That would require contacting new power brokers in Syria, possibly rebel forces in the alliance that toppled Assad, such as Hayat Tahrir al-Sham, a former al Qaeda affiliate labelled a terrorist group by some governments.</p>

<p>Past missions have not been free of risk. Members of a United Nations-OPCW mission to Syria were hit by explosives and AK-47 fire while trying to reach the site of a chemical attack in the northern town of Kafr Zita in May 2014.</p>

<p>Assad's government and its Russian allies always denied using chemical weapons against opponents in the civil war, which erupted in March 2011.</p>

<p>Three different investigations - a joint UN-OPCW mechanism, the OPCW's Investigation and Identification team, and a UN war crimes investigation - concluded that Syrian government forces used the nerve agent sarin and chlorine barrel bombs in attacks during the civil war that killed or injured thousands.</p>

<p>A French court issued an arrest warrant for Assad which was upheld on appeal over the use of banned chemical weapons against civilians.</p>

<p><strong>EVIDENCE</strong></p>

<p>Syria declared 1,300 tons of banned chemical weapons after joining the OPCW in 2013. The weapons were destroyed by the international community, but weapons inspectors have since found evidence of an ongoing programme that violated the 1997 Chemical Weapons Convention overseen by the OPCW.</p>

<p>The OPCW has conducted 28 rounds of consultations with Assad's government since 2013, but a list of unexplained inconsistencies has only grown.</p>

<p>A recent assessment said 19 outstanding issues included "potentially undeclared full-scale development and production of chemical weapons at two declared chemical weapons-related facilities," OPCW chief Fernando Arias said in November.</p>

<p>"The facilities were previously declared as having never been in operation," he said. But inspectors found evidence contradicting that claim, sources said.</p>

<p>Among thousands of victims of suspected chemical weapons attack were more than 1,000 killed in a sarin gas attack on Aug. 21, 2013 in the Damascus suburb Ghouta, and around 100 killed in an April 4, 2017 gas attack on the Khan Sheikhoun in northern Syria. The systematic use of chlorine barrel bombs has killed and injured hundreds more, the OPCW has found.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-07/jr7baoio_organisation-for-the-prohibition-of-chemical-weapons_625x300_08_July_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The OPCW has conducted 28 rounds of consultations with Assad's government since 2013. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ins-tushil-russia-ukraine-come-together-despite-war-to-deliver-navy-ship-to-india-7210940]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India's Russia-Made Warship Comes With Ukrainian Engines. How It Happened]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ins-tushil-russia-ukraine-come-together-despite-war-to-deliver-navy-ship-to-india-7210940]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Dec 2024 23:31:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Despite the years-long war between Russia and Ukraine, Moscow and Kiev worked separately for a common cause - to manufacture an Indian Navy warship, which was handed over to New Delhi on Monday when Defence Minister Rajnath Singh arrived in Moscow.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Despite the years-long war between Russia and Ukraine, Moscow and Kiev worked separately for a common cause - to manufacture an Indian Navy warship, which was handed over to New Delhi on Monday when Defence Minister Rajnath Singh arrived in Moscow for a top-level visit.</p>

<p>The frigate - INS Tushil - is one of two naval ships for which India placed an order with Russia in 2016. It is a Krivak III-class warship, which is an advanced stealth missile frigate. India currently operates six such warships - all manufactured in Russia.</p>

<p>Besides the two that is being made in Russia, two more similar ships have been ordered to be manufactured in India and will likely be manufactured at the Goa Shipyard.</p>

<p>What is interesting is that the primary engines - the gas turbines of these frigates - is manufactured in Ukraine. A Russian warship with a Ukrainian engine, made for India - which shares close ties with both countries.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/u4eqkrd8_ins-tushil-ceremony_625x300_09_December_24.jpeg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>A majority of the ships in the Indian navy fleet use gas turbines made by the Ukrainian company Zorya-Mashproekt - which is a recognised globally as a leader in marine gas turbine production.</p>

<p>What is unique however, is that this order has been delivered while the war is on between Russia and Ukraine, and it is significant to note that both countries have delivered the order in spite of the conflict. However, there was a bit of a challenge involved - India had to physically procure these engines from Ukraine and have them delivered to Russia before they could be installed on this warship, so it has been somewhat delayed.</p>

<h2><strong>ALL ABOUT THE INS TUSHIL</strong></h2>

<p>INS Tushil is the Indian Navy's latest multi-role, stealth-guided missile frigate. The name 'Tushil' means a 'protector shield' and its crest represents the 'Abhedya Kavacham' (Impenetrable Shield). It has a motto - 'Nirbhay, Abhedya aur Balsheel' (Fearless, Indomitable, and Resolute). The ship stands as a symbol of the Indian Navy's undying commitment to safeguarding the nation's maritime frontiers.</p>

<p>The INS Tushil is an advanced Russian Krivak III-class warship under 'Project 11356'.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/bpnt3vr8_ins-tushil_625x300_09_December_24.jpeg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Project 11356 is the code name for the Talwar-class frigates, which are a class of stealth, guided-missile frigates designed and built by Russia for the Indian Navy. The design for the Talwar Class frigates have been developed as an advanced version of the Admiral Grigorovich-class frigates that Russia uses. So far, six such ships have been built and delivered by Russia to India between 1999 and 2013.</p>

<p>The six Krivak class warships that are already in service are 3 Talwar Class ships built at Baltiysky shipyard in St. Petersburg, and three Teg Class ships constructed at the Yantar shipyard in Kaliningrad.</p>

<p>'INS Tushil' will be the seventh in the series, and the first of the two upgraded, advanced warships for which the Indian government and the Indian Navy had signed a contract with Russia's JSC Rosoboronexport, in October 2016.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/hp6vc2b_ins-tushil_625x300_09_December_24.jpeg?im=FitAndFill,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>The construction of the 125-metre-long warship, weighing 3,900 tonnes, was under constant monitoring by experts of India's Warship Overseeing Team stationed permanently in Russia's Kaliningrad throughout its construction. The warship is fitted with advanced Indian missiles, details of which are not revealed by the Indian Navy.</p>

<p>The warship has undergone a series of sea trials, factory sea trials, and state committee trials starting January 2024, during which it clocked an impressive speed of more than 30 knots (55 kmph). It is now being delivered to India in a combat-ready condition.</p>

<p>Russia is delivering the warship to India at Kaliningrad on Monday, and Defence Minister Rajnath Singh along with Indian Navy Chief Admiral Dinesh K Tripathi will be commissioning it.</p>

<p>Upon commissioning, INS Tushil will join the 'Sword Arm' of the Indian Navy, the Western Fleet, under the Western Naval Command.</p>

<h2><strong>THE CHINA CHALLENGE</strong></h2>

<p>While the first of the two warships have been delivered on Monday, the delivery date for the second ship might take a while. The warship is an important addition to the Indian Navy which is faced with the challenge of the fast-growing Chinese Navy in the Indian Ocean.</p>

<p>The Chinese Navy is the fastest-growing navy in the world, and according to some reports the Chinese Navy might have already outnumbered the US Navy to become the largest naval fleet globally. Nowhere is this felt more significantly that the Indian Ocean.</p>

<p>While India has the geographical advantage over China in the Indian Ocean and its strategic location close to key choke points leading to it, China has the advantage in terms of number of vessels in the naval fleet.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/bpnt3vr8_ins-tushil_625x300_09_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[INS Tushil will join 'Sword Arm' of Indian Navy, the Western Fleet, under Western Naval Command.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/british-indian-student-anoushka-kale-elected-president-of-historic-cambridge-union-7210898]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[British Indian Student Elected President Of Historic Cambridge Union]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/british-indian-student-anoushka-kale-elected-president-of-historic-cambridge-union-7210898]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Dec 2024 23:27:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A British Indian student, Anoushka Kale, has been elected president of the University of Cambridge's historic Cambridge Union Society, among the world's oldest debating societies which prides itself as a defender of free speech since 1815.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A British Indian student has been elected president of the University of Cambridge's historic Cambridge Union Society, among the world's oldest debating societies which prides itself as a defender of free speech since 1815.</p>

<p>Anoushka Kale won 126 votes to be elected uncontested for the next Easter 2025 term in an election held recently. As the serving debate officer of the society, Ms Kale ran on a platform of strengthening ties with cultural societies of the university such as the India Society.</p>

<p>"I am absolutely delighted and honoured to have been elected as President of the Cambridge Union Society for Easter 2025 and grateful for the membership's support," said Ms Kale.</p>

<p>"For my term, I will seek to expand diversity and access at the Union through greater collaboration with cultural groups, like the university's India Society. I am also especially passionate about continuing to host international speakers and global debate motions, as I did as Debates Officer of the society," she said.</p>

<p>Former presidents and officers of the Cambridge Union Society have included celebrated English economist and philosopher John Maynard Keynes, novelist Robert Harris and, in recent years, British Indian peer and founder of Cobra Beer Karan Bilimoria.</p>

<p>Like the Oxford University's Oxford Union Society, the Cambridge Union has a long tradition of hosting prominent figures from all areas of public life in its chamber, from US presidents Theodore Roosevelt and Ronald Reagan and UK Prime Ministers Winston Churchill, Margaret Thatcher and John Major, to Stephen Hawking, Bill Gates and the Dalai Lama.</p>

<p>Anoushka Kale, a 20-year-old student who is reading English Literature at Sidney Sussex College at Cambridge University, is among the few South Asian heritage female members to take on the prestigious role.</p>

<p>"I'm looking forward to delivering on my manifesto promises, particularly on expanding diversity through society collaborations and reduced access tickets for the summer garden party," she added.</p>

<p>It follows the Cambridge Union's decision to increase prices amid financial pressures and increasing "upkeep costs" of its Grade-II listed heritage building.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/r93okv78_anoushka-kale_625x300_09_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Cambridge Union has a tradition of hosting prominent figures from all areas of public life.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-korean-president-banned-from-leaving-country-7210873]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[South Korean President Banned From Leaving Country]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-korean-president-banned-from-leaving-country-7210873]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Dec 2024 23:22:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[South Korea's President Yoon Suk Yeol was banned Monday from travelling abroad, the justice ministry said, less than a week after he plunged the country into chaos by briefly imposing martial law.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>South Korea's President Yoon Suk Yeol was banned Monday from travelling abroad, the justice ministry said, less than a week after he plunged the country into chaos by briefly imposing martial law.</p>

<p>Yoon sent special forces and helicopters to parliament on the night of December 3 before lawmakers forced him to rescind the order by rejecting his decree.</p>

<p>The unpopular leader narrowly survived an impeachment motion in parliament on Saturday even as huge crowds braved freezing temperatures to call for his ouster.</p>

<p>Despite remaining in office, a clutch of investigations has been closing in on Yoon and his close allies, including a probe for alleged insurrection.</p>

<p>The ministry of justice confirmed on Monday that Yoon had become the first sitting South Korean president to be banned from leaving the country.</p>

<p>A lawmaker was asked at a parliamentary hearing on Monday whether Yoon had been banned from leaving the country. "Yes, that's right," Bae Sang-up, an immigration services commissioner at the ministry, replied.</p>

<p>Also under travel bans for their roles in last week's events are former defence minister Kim Yong-hyun -- currently in detention -- and ex-interior minister Lee Sang-min.</p>

<p>General Park An-su, the officer in charge of the martial law operation, and defence counterintelligence commander Yeo In-hyung are also barred from leaving the country.</p>

<p>Investigators hauled Park in for further questioning on Monday, and Yonhap news agency reported late Monday that prosecutors had asked for a warrant for Kim's formal arrest.</p>

<p><strong>'Second coup'&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p>The impeachment push failed to pass after members of Yoon's own People Power Party (PPP) walked out of parliament, depriving it of the necessary two-thirds majority.</p>

<p>The PPP says that in exchange, the 63-year-old Yoon has agreed to hand power to the prime minister and party chief, prompting howls of protest from the opposition.</p>

<p>"This is an unlawful, unconstitutional act of a second insurrection and a second coup," Democratic Party floor leader Park Chan-dae said on Monday.</p>

<p>Under South Korea's constitution, the president remains head of government and commander in chief of the army unless he or she is incapacitated, resigns or steps down.</p>

<p>In such a case, power would then be handed to the prime minister on an interim basis until elections could be held.</p>

<p>Claiming that Yoon can remain in office but has delegated his powers to the prime minister and leader of his ruling PPP -- who is not an elected official -- is "a blatant constitutional violation with no legal basis", Park said.</p>

<p>"Their attitude of placing themselves above the constitution mirrors that of insurrectionist Yoon Suk Yeol," he said.</p>

<p><strong>Power vacuum?</strong></p>

<p>The defence ministry confirmed on Monday that the embattled Yoon remained at the head of the country's security apparatus, despite the apparent power vacuum in a country that remains technically at war with nuclear-armed North Korea.</p>

<p>"Legally, (control of military forces) currently lies with the commander in chief," defence ministry spokesperson Jeon Ha-kyou said.</p>

<p>Yoon has apologised for "anxiety and inconvenience" caused by his declaration of martial law but has not stepped down, saying instead he would entrust decisions about his fate to his party.</p>

<p>He also said he would accept all political and legal responsibility for the martial law fiasco.</p>

<p>There is no constitutional basis supporting the ruling party's claim that Yoon can stay in office but hand over his power to unelected party officials, said Kim Hae-won, a constitutional law professor at Pusan National University Law School.</p>

<p>"It seems to resemble an unconstitutional soft coup," he told AFP.</p>

<p>"If there are issues with the president, there are ways laid out in the constitution such as suspending the president from his duties, and then move on to proceedings set out in the constitution, such as impeachment," he said.</p>

<p>The opposition has already said they would try again to impeach Yoon, with leader Lee Jae-myung saying another vote would be held on Saturday.</p>

<p>Huge crowds are expected to gather again outside the National Assembly building.</p>

<p>Yoon's approval rating hit 11 percent, a historic low for the unpopular president, according to a new Gallup poll commissioned by local media.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/rs525hi8_yoon-suk-yeol_625x300_09_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The unpopular leader narrowly survived an impeachment motion in parliament on Saturday. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/cop16-report-warns-over-75-of-global-land-permanently-drier-7210830]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[COP16 Report Warns Over 75% Of Global Land "Permanently Drier"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/cop16-report-warns-over-75-of-global-land-permanently-drier-7210830]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Dec 2024 23:16:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Just over 75 percent of the world's land has been left "permanently drier" over the previous three decades, a UN-backed report coinciding with COP16 talks on desertification in Saudi Arabia said on Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Just over 75 percent of the world's land has been left "permanently drier" over the previous three decades, a UN-backed report coinciding with COP16 talks on desertification in Saudi Arabia said on Monday.</p>

<p>Dry land now covers around 40 percent of the Earth's land mass, excluding Antarctica, the United Nations Convention to Combat Desertification (UNCCD) study found, cautioning the shift could affect up to five billion people by 2100.</p>

<p>"Some 77.6 percent of Earth's land experienced drier conditions during the three decades leading up to 2020 compared to the previous 30-year period," the report said.</p>

<p>It indicates an "existential threat" posed by the seemingly irreversible trends and showed that dry land -- regions where agriculture is difficult -- increased by 4.3 million square kilometres (1.7 million square miles) between 1990 and 2020, an area a third the size of India.</p>

<p>The warning comes during a 12-day meeting in Riyadh, which began last week, for the 16th session of the Conference of the Parties (COP16) under the UNCCD and seeks to protect and restore land and respond to drought amid ongoing climate change.</p>

<p>Aridity, a chronic shortage of water, now extends over 40.6 percent of the Earth's land mass, again excluding Antarctica, compared with 37.5 percent 30 years ago, the report warns.</p>

<p>It also cautions the areas most affected include the nations bordering the Mediterranean, southern Africa, southern Australia and certain regions of Asia and Latin America.</p>

<p>"Unlike droughts -- temporary periods of low rainfall -- aridity represents a permanent, unrelenting transformation," said Ibrahim Thiaw, UNCCD Executive Secretary.</p>

<p>"The drier climates now affecting vast lands across the globe will not return to how they were and this change is redefining life on Earth," he added.</p>

<p>The changes are largely attributed to global warming caused by greenhouse gas emissions, which alter rainfall and increase evaporation, the report said.</p>

<p>"For the first time, a UN scientific body is warning that burning fossil fuels is causing permanent drying across much of the world," lead UNCCD Chief Scientist Barron Orr said.</p>

<p>He added this could have "potentially catastrophic impacts affecting access to water that could push people and nature even closer to disastrous tipping points".</p>

<p>The effects of the chronic water shortages include soil degradation, ecosystem collapse, food insecurity and forced migration, according to the scientists.</p>

<p>Already, 2.3 billion people live in expanding dry areas, according to the report, with projections showing a "worst-case scenario" of five billion people living in the conditions as the planet continues to warm.</p>

<p>To counter this trend, the scientists urged members to "integrate aridity metrics into existing drought monitoring systems", improve soil and water management, and "build resilience in vulnerable communities".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/pk9n5i9g_cop16_625x300_03_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The warning comes during a 12-day meeting in Riyadh. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/assads-exit-shatters-irans-influence-but-risks-islamists-rise-in-syria-7210282]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Assad's Exit Shatters Iran's Influence But Risks Islamists' Rise In Syria]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/assads-exit-shatters-irans-influence-but-risks-islamists-rise-in-syria-7210282]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Dec 2024 21:49:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The ouster of Syrian President Bashar al-Assad, after rebel forces swept into Damascus this weekend, shattered Iran's network of influence in the Middle East but Israel, the United States and Arab powers must now deal with the risk of instability.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The ouster of Syrian President Bashar al-Assad, after rebel forces swept into Damascus this weekend, shattered Iran's network of influence in the Middle East but Israel, the United States and Arab powers must now deal with the risk of instability and extremism from the mosaic of forces that replaces him.</p>

<p>Chief among the rebel forces that ended 50 years of brutal dynastic rule by Assad and his father was Hayat Tahrir al-Sham (HTS), a Sunni Muslim group previously affiliated with Al Qaeda that is designated as a terrorist organization by the US and the UN.</p>

<p>Western and Arab nations fear that the HTS-led rebel coalition may seek to replace Assad's regime with a hardline Islamist government, or one less able or inclined to prevent the resurgence of radical forces, three diplomats and three analysts told Reuters.</p>

<p>"There is strong fear inside and outside the region of the power vacuum that Assad's sudden collapse may cause," said Abdelaziz al-Sager, director of the Gulf Research Center, a think tank focused on the Middle East. He cited the civil wars that followed the toppling of Iraqi president Saddam Hussein in 2003 and Libyan dictator Muammar Gaddafi in 2011.</p>

<p>One senior Western diplomat in the region, who spoke on condition of anonymity, told Reuters that - with the rebel forces fragmented - there was no plan for how to rule Syria, a complex nation divided into various sects and ethnic groups, each with its own regional power base.</p>

<p>The senior diplomat expressed fears that lawlessness in Syria could allow the flourishing of extremist groups like Islamic State (IS), which in 2014 swept through large swathes of Syria and Iraq and established an Islamic Caliphate before it was driven out by a US-led coalition by 2019.</p>

<p>US President Joe Biden on Sunday welcomed Assad's toppling and said he should be "held accountable" for his despotic rule but he warned that his departure was a moment of "risk and uncertainty". US forces on Sunday conducted dozens of strikes within Syria against IS to prevent it reasserting itself.</p>

<p>The speed of Assad's ouster, just two weeks since the rebel offensive began, took many in the White House by surprise. A senior US official said Washington was now seeking ways to communicate with all the rebel groups, not just HTS.</p>

<p>So far, Washington had mostly thrown its support behind Syrian Kurdish groups, such as the Syrian Democratic Forces (SDF), whose areas of control are in northeast Syria. These groups, however, are in conflict with one of the main victorious rebels factions, the Syrian National Army (SNA), backed by regional power broker, Turkey, which opposes Kurdish influence.</p>

<p>Assad's allies, Tehran and Moscow, who propped up his rule for 13 years with military support, men and airpower, also face far-reaching implications from his precipitous downfall.</p>

<p>Moscow - which has given Assad and his family asylum - has two major military bases in Syria, its main footprint in the Middle East. Its naval base in Tartous on the Mediterranean has been a staging post to fly military contractors in and out of Africa.</p>

<p>For Tehran, its alliance with Assad - a member of the minority Alawite sect, an offshoot of Shi'ite Islam - was a cornerstone of its powerbase in a predominantly Sunni region wary of Shi'ite Iran.</p>

<p>Assad's departure shattered a pivotal axis of influence, eroding Tehran's ability to project power and sustain its network of militia groups across the Middle East, particularly to its ally Hezbollah in Lebanon. A senior Iranian official told Reuters on Monday it had opened a direct line of communication with the rebels in an attempt to "prevent a hostile trajectory".</p>

<p>Israel's year-long military campaign has already severely weakened the military power of Hezbollah and Palestinian group Hamas in Gaza.</p>

<p>Assad offered Iran a vital conduit for arms shipments to rebuild Hezbollah. Jonathan Panikoff, a former US deputy national intelligence officer for the Middle East, said his ouster could make it more difficult for Hezbollah to rearm, increasing the prospects that a ceasefire with Israel agreed last month would hold.</p>

<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu hailed the ousting of Assad as an "historic day" that followed the blows delivered by Israel against Iran and Hezbollah. He said he had ordered Israeli forces to seize areas along the bordering buffer zone to ensure Israel's security.</p>

<p>Israeli forces carried out air strikes against suspected chemical weapons and missile sites on Monday to prevent them from falling into the hands of hostile actors, the foreign minister said.</p>

<p>Carmit Valensi, a senior researcher at the Institute for National Security Studies (INSS), a think tank for Israeli security policy based in Tel Aviv, said that - despite the risk of a prolonged period of chaos and violence in Syria - Assad's fall could benefit Israel.</p>

<p>"Despite concerns over the rise of extremist elements near the border and the lack of a clear authority in charge, the military capabilities of the rebels, in their various forms, aren't comparable to those of Iran and its proxies," she said.</p>

<p>CALLS FOR NEW CONSTITUTION, ELECTIONS</p>

<p>Marwan al-Muasher, vice president for studies at the US-based Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, said Assad's exit could provide an opportunity for Syrians to establish an inclusive political governance through an orderly transition that avoided a power vacuum that would allow extremist groups to gain ascendancy.</p>

<p>Hadi Al-Bahra, the head of Syria's main opposition abroad, told Reuters on the sidelines of the Doha Forum on Sunday that Syria should have an 18-month transition period to establish "a safe, neutral, and quiet environment" for free elections.</p>

<p>Al-Bahra, President of the Syrian National Coalition, said Syria should draft a constitution within six months, on which the first election would be a referendum. He said the opposition had asked state employees to report to work until the power transition, and assured them that they would not be harmed.</p>

<p>But Syria's political opposition has little influence on the ground in Damascus, where armed groups hold sway, and many Syria watchers remain skeptic.</p>

<p>HTS' leader, Abu Mohammed al-Golani, addressed huge crowds at the medieval Umayyad Mosque in central Damascus on Sunday, promising a new chapter for the region and that Syria would become "a beacon for the Islamic nation".</p>

<p>There are, however, questions about whether Golani's form of strict Islamist ideology would be accepted throughout Syria, a country where a moderate and liberal form of Islam prevails and with a mixed Christian, Alawite, Druze and Kurdish population.</p>

<p>Both Western and Middle Eastern officials expressed concern about the unity of Syria, with key territories, including those along borders with Iraq and Turkey, under the control of different sects and ethnic groups: these divisions, which were entrenched by a bloody 2011 uprising, present a growing threat to national stability.</p>

<p>The analysts and diplomats who spoke to Reuters warned of the risk of a free-for-all conflict - akin to the wake of the toppling of Gaddafi in Libya or Saddam in Iraq - in which armed groups from different Islamist, ethnic and ideological shades fight for supremacy over territory. Such a failed state in Syria would have a major impact on neighbors Lebanon, Turkey, Iraq and Jordan, they said.</p>

<p>RIVALRY AMONG REBELS</p>

<p>Syria's opposition comprises a broad spectrum from moderate groups such as the SNA to jihadi elements within the HTS, each with its own vision for Syria's future, ranging from secular democracy to Islamic governance.</p>

<p>"Each one of these rebel group is vying for supremacy; each one wants to be in charge. Each one thinks they can be Bashar al-Assad, and each one has allegiance to a foreign party funding his group," said al-Sager. "They will clash unless there is an effort by the UN and some regional countries with influence to unify them."</p>

<p>Turkish-backed forces dominate in the north, while US-aligned Kurdish groups, such as the Syrian Democratic Forces (SDF), hold sway in northeastern Syria.</p>

<p>In a sign of the tensions between the groups, the Turkey-backed SNA seized swathes of territory, including the city of Tel Refaat, from US-backed Kurdish forces at the start of the recent offensive. On Sunday, a Turkish security source said the rebels entered the northern city of Manbij after pushing the Kurds back again.</p>

<p>Still, some analysts say that an orderly transition is possible, arguing that well-established government institutions in Damascus remain capable of carrying out duties.</p>

<p>They also point to the rebels' experience of governing in enclaves across Syria that they have managed in some cases for more than a decade. The rebel alliance, led by HTS, made a point of offering clemency for members of the security forces when it seized Aleppo, Syria's second-largest city, late last month and promised the sizeable minority populations that it would preserve their way of life.</p>

<p>But Hassan Hassan, an expert on Islamist groups in the Middle East based in Washington, said that concerns persisted among these minority groups now that the rebels had captured Damascus.</p>

<p>"There is uncertainty about what will happen next, particularly about religious influence and how (Islamic) laws may evolve," he said.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/hnlpk09g_bashar-al-assad_625x300_09_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Western and Arab nations fear that the HTS-led rebel coalition may seek to replace Assad's regime.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>