<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Sun, 30 Jun 2024 13:54:44 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/2024s-first-hurricane-beryl-bears-down-on-caribbean-6002024]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[2024's First Hurricane, 'Beryl', Bears Down On Caribbean]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/2024s-first-hurricane-beryl-bears-down-on-caribbean-6002024]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 30 Jun 2024 13:30:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Much of the southeast Caribbean was on alert Sunday as Beryl strengthened into the first hurricane of the 2024 Atlantic season, with forecasters warning it will swiftly become a major storm.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Much of the southeast Caribbean was on alert Sunday as Beryl strengthened into the first hurricane of the 2024 Atlantic season, with forecasters warning it will swiftly become a major storm.</p>

<p>The US National Hurricane Center (NHC) said Beryl -- currently churning in the Atlantic Ocean about 530 miles (850 kilometers) east of Barbados -- was expected to bring "life-threatening winds and storm surge" when it reached the Windward Islands early Monday.</p>

<p>Warning the storm was "getting stronger", the NHC forecast it would become a "dangerous major hurricane" by the time it hit Caribbean communities.</p>

<p>Barbados, St Lucia, St Vincent and the Grenadines, and Grenada were all under hurricane warnings, while tropical storm warnings or watches were in effect for Martinique, Tobago and Dominica, the NHC said in its latest advisory.</p>

<p>Cars were seen lined up at gas stations in the Barbadian capital Bridgetown, while supermarkets and grocery stores were crowded with shoppers buying food, water and other supplies. Some households were already boarding up their properties.</p>

<p>A major hurricane is considered a Category 3 or higher on the Saffir-Simpson scale, with winds of at least 111 miles per hour (179 kilometers per hour).</p>

<p>Such a powerful storm forming this early in the Atlantic hurricane season -- which runs from early June to late November -- is extremely rare, experts said.</p>

<p>"Only five major (Category 3+) hurricanes have been recorded in the Atlantic before the first week of July. Beryl would be the sixth and earliest this far east in the tropical Atlantic," hurricane expert Michael Lowry posted on social media platform X.</p>

<p>The NHC said that as of 2:00 am (0600 GMT) Sunday, Beryl's maximum sustained winds had increased to nearly 90 mph with higher gusts.</p>

<p>"Hurricane conditions are expected in the hurricane warning area beginning early on Monday," it said, warning of heavy rain, flooding and storm surge that could raise water levels as much as seven feet (2.1 meters) above normal.</p>

<p>"Devastating wind damage is expected where the eyewall of Beryl moves through portions of the Windward Islands," the NHC said, indicating wind speeds in some locations could be 30 percent stronger than those listed in their advisory.</p>

<p>The Saffir-Simpson wind scale designates Category 1 hurricanes as having wind speeds of at least 74 mph, up to Category 5 storms with winds of 157 mph or higher.</p>

<p>The US National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration said in late May that it expects this year to be an "extraordinary" hurricane season with up to seven storms of Category 3 or higher.</p>

<p>The agency cited warm Atlantic ocean temperatures and conditions related to the weather phenomenon La Nina in the Pacific for the expected increase in storms.</p>

<p>Extreme weather events including hurricanes have become more frequent and more devastating in recent years as a result of climate change.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/c94abq2o_cyclone-beryl-afp-_625x300_30_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A major hurricane is considered a Category 3 or higher.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/secrets-of-elizabeth-is-spy-network-revealed-in-428-year-old-dossier-6001605]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Secret Dossier Reveals Queen Elizabeth I's Network Of Spies: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/secrets-of-elizabeth-is-spy-network-revealed-in-428-year-old-dossier-6001605]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 30 Jun 2024 12:03:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A document titled "The Names of the Intelligencers" has now disclosed the hidden network of spies of England and Ireland's former Queen Elizabeth I.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">A document titled "The Names of the Intelligencers" has now disclosed the hidden network of spies of England and Ireland's former Queen Elizabeth I.</p>

<p dir="ltr">The single sheet of paper has been lying undisturbed in the National Archives for over a century, as per a <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/article/2024/jun/29/uncovered-428-year-old-secret-dossier-reveals-elizabeth-is-network-of-spies ">Guardian</a> report.</p>

<p dir="ltr">The report also mentioned that this paper is part of a 428-year-old&nbsp;secret dossier that once belonged to Robert Cecil, the spymaster for Queen Elizabeth. Cecil is also the man who discovered the Gunpowder Plot in 1605. Putting this document together with the dossier shows how Cecil used a secret spy network to watch European kings and queens for England.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Historian Stephen Alford, who is also a professor of early modern British history at the University of Leeds, found the list nearly 15 years ago. He believes it was England's “first properly organised secret service”. Alford has been working to reconstruct Cecil's files on each spy ever since he found the document.</p>

<p dir="ltr">“There were lots of names listed – some I recognised, people in or close to the privy council of Elizabeth I, and lots I didn't know. Eventually, I realised that the numbers next to their names were folio numbers and that this was really a contents page. That was a lightbulb moment,” said Mr Alford as per the report.</p>

<p dir="ltr">The list of spies had been placed in a “miscellaneous” folder by Victorian archivists. As per Mr Alford's beliefs, Cecil began to write the document in 1596.&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">Mr Alford thinks that he is “probably the first scholar” to take an interest in this document. He also said, “The Victorians had a habit, where if they came across papers that didn't make sense to them, that were a little mysterious and couldn't be filed away in a neat and tidy way, they would scratch their heads and then stick them in a miscellaneous folder and ignore them. And that's where historians now find really interesting stuff.”&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">Mr Alford searched through old archives for relevant papers marked with small numbers matching the index. Many papers were damaged from poor storage in the Tower of London, often by rats and mice leaving stains and even bite marks. Despite these challenges, the documents survived.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Before Mr Alford's research, scholars believed Cecil had only a few scattered spies. However, he discovered Cecil had a well-organised network of over 20 spies in cities like Lisbon, Calais, Brussels, Seville, Rome, Amsterdam, Scotland, Sweden, and other places. Mr Alford said, “He (Cecil) chose merchants because they travel, can read and write, speak European languages and have networks of their own.”</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/ujrt0tv_elizabeth_625x300_30_June_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The report also mentioned that this paper is part of a 428-year-oldsecret dossier]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/if-donald-trump-becomes-us-president-melania-trump-will-not-be-on-first-lady-duty-24-7-report-6001087]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Melania Trump's Deal With Donald Trump If He Becomes President]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/if-donald-trump-becomes-us-president-melania-trump-will-not-be-on-first-lady-duty-24-7-report-6001087]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 30 Jun 2024 10:25:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump, the Republican nominee for the US Presidential poll, has been busy with the 2024 US Election Campaign. But if the 78-year-old becomes the President, he might not see his wife Melania Trump much in action.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump, the Republican nominee for the US Presidential poll, has been busy with the 2024 US Election Campaign. But if the 78-year-old becomes the President, he might not see his wife Melania Trump much in action.</p>

<p>Melania Trump has made a deal with the former US President, reported <a href="https://pagesix.com/2024/06/28/gossip/melania-trump-has-deal-with-donald-to-not-be-24-7-first-lady-if-he-wins-presidency/">Page Six.</a></p>

<p>“Melania has made a deal with her husband that if he wins the presidency she will not have to be on first lady duty 24/7,” a source was quoted as saying.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The report added that the former First Lady has made the deal as she wants to spend more time with her son Barron Trump. The 18-year-old will reportedly move to a University soon in New York City, and Melania Trump wants to help him adjust to the new life.</p>

<p>“She's a hands-on mother, and is already planning to spend part of every month — and potentially every week — in NYC,” the source added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The source continued, “Barron has never been completely on his own before — and with the added stress of him being both a freshman in college and potentially the son of a president in a predominantly Democratic city, [Melania] wants to be close… The added attention he'll get if his father is president worries Melania who is also concerned about the reaction at his school over Barron's ever-present Secret Service [detail].”</p>

<p dir="ltr">Melania Trump has been “&nbsp;an extremely protective mother” and she “even pushed back on the idea that Barron would serve as a Republican delegate to the [Republican National Convention] from Florida,” the report added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Donald Trump and Joe Biden are polling neck and neck ahead of the November 5 vote as they attempt to woo any Americans still fine-tuning their decision.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-11/ccijet1o_donald-trump-melania-trump_625x300_04_November_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-israeli-driver-enters-palestine-territory-his-car-is-set-on-fire-6001042]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Video: Israeli Driver Enters Palestine Territory, His Car Is Set On Fire]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-israeli-driver-enters-palestine-territory-his-car-is-set-on-fire-6001042]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 30 Jun 2024 09:54:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An Israeli citizen mistakenly entered the Palestinian town of Qalandiya, situated between Jerusalem and Ramallah, in West Bank and was soon met with aggression from local residents, leading to a violent confrontation.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An Israeli citizen mistakenly entered the Palestinian town of Qalandiya, situated between Jerusalem and Ramallah, in West Bank and was soon met with aggression from local residents, leading to a violent confrontation.</p>

<p>Videos circulating on social media show a mob of Palestinians chasing the Israeli vehicle, hurling stones at it. The driver attempted to flee but ultimately lost control, crashing into a concrete divider near a military checkpoint, a <em>Times of Israel </em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.timesofisrael.com/liveblog-june-30-2024/">report </a>said. The man reportedly suffered minor injuries before being rescued and transported to Jerusalem's Shaare Zedek hospital.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="rtl" lang="iw">היהודי הגיע פצוע למחסום קלנדיה, לאחר שנזרקו אבנים לרכבו, והתנגש בבטונדות של המעבר. כוחות מגב משטרה ומד״א הוקפצו לאירוע.<br />
המשך לקלנדייה <a href="https://t.co/IpGOuCn7Ig">pic.twitter.com/IpGOuCn7Ig</a></p>
— כל החדשות בזמן אמת ? (@Saher95755738) <a href="https://twitter.com/Saher95755738/status/1807154606952022510?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 29, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>Other footage revealed that the vehicle was set ablaze by the Palestinian attackers.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="ro">The car of the Jew who accidentally entered Qalandia was set on fire. רכבו של היהודי שנכנס בטעות לקלנדיה, הוצת. <a href="https://t.co/PAZkT3z9cY">pic.twitter.com/PAZkT3z9cY</a></p>
— Rat Bastard (@RRespawned) <a href="https://twitter.com/RRespawned/status/1807168647070163241?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 29, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>This incident comes amid a backdrop of escalating violence in the West Bank, an area under Israeli occupation since 1967. Last week, the Israeli military reported the death of a soldier and serious injury to another during an operation in Jenin, a city known for its militant presence. The Israeli army frequently conducts raids in Jenin and its adjacent refugee camp as part of its ongoing security operations.</p>

<p>The West Bank has seen a significant surge in violence, especially following the outbreak of the Israel-Hamas war in Gaza on October 7. Palestinian officials report that at least 553 Palestinians have been killed by Israeli forces or settlers in the West Bank since the conflict began. Meanwhile, attacks by Palestinians have resulted in the deaths of at least 15 Israelis, including soldiers, in the same period, according to news agency AFP.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/rlm82u78_israel-car-fire-_625x300_30_June_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Other footage revealed that the vehicle was set ablaze by the Palestinian attackers.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/amid-cancer-battle-buckingham-palace-releases-new-portrait-of-king-charles-6000967]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Amid Cancer Battle, Buckingham Palace Releases New Portrait Of King Charles]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/amid-cancer-battle-buckingham-palace-releases-new-portrait-of-king-charles-6000967]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 30 Jun 2024 09:39:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[King Charles is adorned in the Field Marshal's uniform, the highest rank in the British Army.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A new portrait of King Charles in military attire has been unveiled in honour of Armed Forces Day. The photograph, captured in Windsor Castle's Grand Corridor, depicts the monarch seated in his Field Marshal's ceremonial dress adorned with medals, sword, and decorations.</p>

<p>The release of this image coincides with Queen Camilla's tribute to armed forces members, whom she described in a video message as a source of inspiration, reassurance, and pride.</p>

<p>Armed Forces Day, observed on the final Saturday in June, pays homage to veterans, military personnel, and service families, a tradition established in the UK in the late 2000s, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cv2gle48845o"><em>BBC </em></a>reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Photographed last November by Hugo Burnand, known for his royal photography including the King's 2023 coronation portraits, King Charles is adorned in the Field Marshal's uniform, the highest rank in the British Army. As monarch, he serves as ceremonial head of the armed forces.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/C8ynxFDsAGa/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C8ynxFDsAGa/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C8ynxFDsAGa/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C8ynxFDsAGa/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by The Royal Family (@theroyalfamily)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p></p>

<p>During his recent attendance at D-Day commemorations in Normandy, France, King Charles donned a tan version of the Field Marshal's uniform.</p>

<p>In her video message from Clarence House, Queen Camilla praised the 'incredible bravery' of military personnel who initiated Europe's liberation from Nazi Germany in 1944.</p>

<p>She said that 80 years on, the "same spirit and those same qualities remain much in evidence throughout our Armed Forces", who "undertake your duties in the face of a multitude of challenges and dangers".</p>

<p>The Queen added: "In so doing, you not only protect these Isles, but also defend liberties way beyond these shores.</p>

<p>"Your determination, unrelenting efforts and selfless loyalty to each other and to the United Kingdom are as enduring as our gratitude."</p>

<p>The patron of the British Forces Broadcasting Service charity, responsible for the video, extended gratitude to the families of servicemen and women who maintain home life while their loved ones serve abroad.</p>

<p>Reflecting on her father Major Bruce Shand's service in North Africa and Dunkirk during World War Two, where he earned the Military Cross, the Queen remarked, 'As the daughter of an Army officer, I understand the profound impact military life has on families. You too are heroes.'"</p>

<p>"In times of war and in times of peace, whether seen or unseen, our armed forces support and strengthen our nation. You are a source of inspiration, reassurance and pride - and I salute you all."<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/eikffodg_king-charles_625x300_30_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The release of this image coincides with Queen Camilla's tribute to armed forces members]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-elections-2024-a-look-at-rishi-sunaks-india-connection-5995752]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK Elections 2024: Rishi Sunak's India Connection In 10 Points]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-elections-2024-a-look-at-rishi-sunaks-india-connection-5995752]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 30 Jun 2024 08:53:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Rishi Sunak scripted history on October 25, 2022, when he became the first Indian-origin Prime Minister of the United Kingdom.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Rishi Sunak scripted history on October 25, 2022, when he became the first Indian-origin Prime Minister of the United Kingdom. In the upcoming July 4 elections, Mr Sunak's Conservative Party is facing a major challenge from the Opposition Labour Party, led by Keir Starmer.<br />
<br />
<strong>Ahead of the crucial polls, here's a look at the 10 points about Rishi Sunak's connection with India:</strong><br />
<br />
1. Rishi Sunak was born on May 12, 1980, in Southampton, Hampshire. His parents -- Yashvir Sunak and Usha Sunak -- are of Indian descent. While his father was a National Health Service general practitioner, his mother, Usha, ran a chemist shop. Both of them migrated from East Africa to the UK during the 1960s.<br />
<br />
2. For his studies, Mr Sunak went to Winchester College and studied Politics, Philosophy and Economics at Oxford University. Further, he was also a Fulbright Scholar at Stanford University in the US, where he studied for his MBA.<br />
<br />
3. Rishi Sunak is married to Akshata Murty, the daughter of Infosys chief Narayana Murthy and Sudha Murty, who is a Rajya Sabha MP. Together, Rishi and Akshata have two daughters - Krishna and Anoushka.<br />
<br />
4.&nbsp; He has served as a Member of Parliament from Richmond (Yorks) since 2015. He earlier became the first UK parliamentarian to take oath as an MP on the Bhagavad Gita in the Parliament.<br />
<br />
5. Being a Hindu, he has often been vocal about his heritage and how his family reminded him about their values and culture.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
6. He celebrated Diwali with his wife and family at 10 Downing Street and even hosted a reception last year for the Indian diaspora, parliamentarians, entrepreneurs and Bollywood celebrities.<br />
<br />
7. Before becoming the UK Prime Minister, Rishi Sunak would often visit Bengaluru with his wife and two children to meet his in-laws.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
8. While he was campaigning for the PM's post in 2022, Mr Sunak was criticised for his lavish house, expensive suits, and shoes. However, he later said that the Bhagavad Gita often rescues him during stressful situations, besides reminding him to be dutiful.<br />
<br />
9. Like most Indians, Sunak, too, likes to play cricket to stay fit. In April this year, he surprised netizens by joining the country's cricket team for a net session.<br />
<br />
10. Besides being a part of politics, Mr Sunak has had a successful business career as well. He co-founded a firm, while working with companies from Silicon Valley to Bengaluru, according to reports. In May, it was reported that the personal wealth of Rishi Sunak and his wife rose by 122 million pounds last year and reached 651 million pounds.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/3srb65a8_rishi-sunak-reuters_625x300_20_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Rishi Sunak often visits Bengaluru with his wife and two children to meet his in-laws.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/2024-uk-election-rishi-sunak-vs-keir-starmer-predictions-5995496]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Rishi Sunak vs Keir Starmer, Who Will Win The 2024 UK Elections?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/2024-uk-election-rishi-sunak-vs-keir-starmer-predictions-5995496]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 30 Jun 2024 08:42:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United Kingdom is preparing to go to polls on July 4, with odds heavily favouring the Labour Party leader Keir Starmer while Prime Minister Rishi Sunak is trying hard to keep his Conservative Party in power, the voter fatigue.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United Kingdom is preparing to go to polls on July 4, with odds heavily favouring the Labour Party leader Keir Starmer. While Prime Minister Rishi Sunak is trying hard to keep his Conservative Party in power, the voter fatigue -- stemming from the 14-year Tory rule -- is visible in predicted numbers.<br />
<br />
Keir Starmer is projected to win a historic mandate in the upcoming general election. In contrast, the Conservatives may see their lowest numbers in nearly two centuries.&nbsp;The Liberal Democrats, too, are likely to achieve their best-ever performance.<br />
<br />
<b>YouGov predictions</b><br />
<br />
The Labour Party could secure between 422 and 456 seats, one of the largest majorities in British political history, according to recent polling and analysis by <a href="http://https://yougov.co.uk/politics/articles/49606-first-yougov-mrp-of-2024-general-election-shows-labour-on-track-to-beat-1997-landslide ">YouGov</a>.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
Conservatives, though, face a challenging future, with predictions ranging from 72 to 140 seats, a significant decline from their current figures.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
Betting odds strongly favour Keir Starmer as the next Prime Minister, with odds for Rishi Sunak significantly lower.<br />
<br />
<b>Ipsos predictions</b><br />
<br />
The Labour Party is on course for a historic victory with 453 seats. However, a crushing defeat stares in the face of Conservatives, who are likely to get 115 seats, according to Ipsos's inaugural MRP model of the campaign. Should this come to fruition, Mr Starmer's party will return to power after 14 years.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
The Liberal Democrats are predicted to win 38 seats, the Scottish National Party 15, and the Greens and Reform UK three each.<br />
<br />
<b>How accurate the predictions are</b><br />
<br />
The accuracy of MRP (multilevel regression and poststratification) polls, which combine polling data with census-type information, has improved over recent years but remains subject to variability and uncertainty. However, tactical voting, undecided voters, and changes in public opinion may influence final numbers.<br />
<br />
The pollsters themselves acknowledge the limitations of their models and the potential for error. Patrick English, director of political analytics for YouGov, notes that polling is an inexact science, and Chris Hanretty, a professor of politics at Royal Holloway, University of London, stated that models can only work with the data available and cannot capture all the complexities of human behaviour, according to <a href="http://https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2024/apr/05/how-accurate-are-mrp-polls-predicting-huge-tory-losses-in-next-general-election ">The Guardian</a>.<br />
<br />
<b>Public reception to certain policies</b><br />
<br />
Policies that have connected with the British public include pledges from both Labour and the Conservatives not to increase National Insurance, VAT or income tax. The Conservative triple lock on pensions has also received strong support, with 73% of respondents in favour. Labour's plans to introduce VAT on private schools and create a publicly owned renewable energy provider have also been well-received, with 61% and 74% support respectively.<br />
<br />
Some policies have also faced opposition. The Conservative national service pledge has been unpopular, with 52% of respondents against it. Labour's plan to lower the voting age to 16 has also been met with resistance, with 60% of respondents opposed.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
Will the odds hold, or will there be a twist in the tale on election day? Only time will tell.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/u4pllgd8_rishi-sunak-and-keir-starmer_625x300_04_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Betting odds strongly favour Keir Starmer as the next Prime Minister.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/warren-buffett-changes-his-will-reveals-what-will-happen-to-his-money-after-death-6000626]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Warren Buffett Reveals What Will Happen To His Money After Death]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/warren-buffett-changes-his-will-reveals-what-will-happen-to-his-money-after-death-6000626]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 30 Jun 2024 08:05:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Berkshire Hathaway announced on Friday that Mr Buffett is converting around 9,000 Class A shares into over 13 million Class B shares.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Warren Buffett has revised the plans for his considerable fortune after his death. Mr Buffett, 93, the chairman of Berkshire Hathaway, revealed to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.wsj.com/finance/warren-buffett-gives-us-a-preview-of-his-will-419ad46d"><em>Wall Street Journal </em></a>that he has reworked his will and will not continue donations to the Bill &amp; Melinda Gates Foundation posthumously. Instead, he will allocate his wealth to a new charitable trust managed by his three children.</p>

<p>"The Gates Foundation has no money coming after my death," Mr Buffett told the Journal.</p>

<p>Mr Buffett mentioned that he has altered his will multiple times, with the latest changes motivated by his confidence in his children's values and ability to distribute his wealth appropriately. Each of his children has a philanthropic organisation.</p>

<p>"I feel very, very good about the values of my three children, and I have 100% trust in how they will carry things out," Buffett said.</p>

<p>Previously, Mr Buffett had stated that over 99% of his estate was designated for philanthropic use by the Bill &amp; Melinda Gates Foundation and the four family-related charities: the Susan Thompson Buffett Foundation, Sherwood Foundation, Howard G. Buffett Foundation, and NoVo Foundation.</p>

<p>For now, Mr Buffett seems to be continuing his donations to the Gates Foundation during his lifetime.</p>

<p>Berkshire Hathaway announced on Friday that Mr Buffett is converting around 9,000 Class A shares into over 13 million Class B shares. Approximately 9.3 million shares will be allocated to the Bill &amp; Melinda Gates Foundation Trust, with the remainder distributed among the four Buffett family charities.</p>

<p>"Warren Buffett has been exceedingly generous to the Gates Foundation through more than 18 years of contributions and advice," Mark Suzman, the foundation's chief executive, stated to CNN. "We are deeply grateful for his most recent gift and contributions totalling approximately $43 billion to our work." (Melinda announced in May that she would leave the organization, with her last day being June 7, though the foundation has not yet changed its name.)</p>

<p>Last year, Mr Buffett donated about $870 million to his family's four charities, and around $750 million to them in 2022.</p>

<p>Following these newly announced donations, Mr Buffett owns 207,963 Berkshire Hathaway Class A shares and 2,586 Class B shares, with the total value of these shares being roughly $128 billion.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2019-02/8t9tcl7o_warren-buffett-reuters_625x300_26_February_19.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mr Buffett mentioned that he has altered his will multiple times]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/18-killed-42-injured-in-series-of-suicide-attacks-in-nigeria-6000356]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[18 Killed, 42 Injured In Series Of Suicide Attacks In Nigeria]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/18-killed-42-injured-in-series-of-suicide-attacks-in-nigeria-6000356]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 30 Jun 2024 06:31:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[At least 18 people were killed and 19 seriously wounded in a string of suicide attacks in northeastern Nigeria on Saturday, emergency services said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At least 18 people were killed and 19 seriously wounded in a string of suicide attacks in northeastern Nigeria on Saturday, emergency services said.</p>

<p>In one of three blasts in the town of Gwoza, a female attacker with a baby strapped to her back detonated explosives in the middle of a wedding ceremony, according to a police spokesman.</p>

<p>The other attacks in the border town across from Cameroon targeted a hospital and a funeral for victims of the earlier wedding blast, authorities said.</p>

<p>At least 18 people were killed and 42 others injured in the attacks, according to the Borno State Emergency Management Agency (SEMA).</p>

<p>"So far, 18 deaths comprising children, men, females and pregnant women" have been reported, said Barkindo Saidu, the head of the agency, in a report seen by AFP.</p>

<p>Nineteen "seriously injured" people were taken to the regional capital Maiduguri, while 23 others were awaiting evacuation, Saidu said in the report.</p>

<p>A member of a militia assisting the military in Gwoza said two of his comrades and a soldier were also killed in another attack on a security post, though authorities did not immediately confirm this toll.</p>

<p>Boko Haram militants seized Gwoza in 2014 when the group took over swathes of territory in northern Borno.</p>

<p>The town was taken back by the Nigerian military with help from Chadian forces in 2015 but the group has since continued to launch attacks from mountains near the town.</p>

<p>Boko Haram has carried out raids, killing men and kidnapping women who venture outside the town in search of firewood and acacia fruits.</p>

<p>The violence has killed more than 40,000 people and displaced around two million in Nigeria's northeast.</p>

<p>The conflict has spread to neighbouring Niger, Cameroon and Chad, prompting the formation of a regional military coalition to fight the militants.</p>

<p><br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-06/7l09kf1_nigeria-police-reuters-650_625x300_05_June_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Nineteen "seriously injured" people were taken to the regional capital Maiduguri.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russian-strike-on-ukraine-town-kills-7-zelensky-asks-allies-for-more-weapons-6000019]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russian Strike On Ukraine Kills 7, Zelensky Asks Allies For More Weapons]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russian-strike-on-ukraine-town-kills-7-zelensky-asks-allies-for-more-weapons-6000019]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 30 Jun 2024 04:36:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Russian strike on the south Ukrainian town of Vilniansk killed at least seven people, Kyiv said, in an attack that came hours after Russia said a Ukrainian drone killed five people on its border village.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Russian strike on the south Ukrainian town of Vilniansk killed at least seven people, Kyiv said, in an attack that came hours after Russia said a Ukrainian drone killed five people on its border village.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Both countries said two children were killed in each attack, in a deadly day in the more than two-year war.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Kyiv also said four people were killed in eastern frontline villages in the Donetsk region.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky warned the death toll in Vilniansk -- near the regional hub of Zaporizhzhia -- may increase.</p>

<p>"Seven people, including two children, have been killed by a Russian missile strike in the Zaporizhzhia region," Zelensky said on social media.&nbsp;</p>

<p>He called for his Western allies to speed-up weapons deliveries, saying: "Any delay in decisions in this war means the loss of human lives."&nbsp;</p>

<p>Ukraine's Internal Minister, Igor Klimenko, said 18 people -- including four children -- were wounded in Vilniansk.&nbsp;</p>

<p>He posted images of a local burnt out low-rise building and blackened cars.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The head of the Zaporizhzhia region, Ivan Fedorov, earlier said a "critical infrastructure facility, a shop and residential buildings were damaged" in the strike.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Vilniansk lies 29 kilometres (18 miles) north-east of the city of Zaporizhzhia, the main regional city which is under Ukrainian control.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Russia's attack on Vilniansk came hours after Moscow said a Ukrainian drone on a house in a Russian border village killed five people, including two children.&nbsp;</p>

<h3>Five dead in Russian village</h3>

<p>Moscow said the drone hit a house in the village of Gorodishche, a tiny village in Russia's Kursk region, just a few metres from the border with Ukraine.</p>

<p>"To our great grief, five people were killed ... including two small children. Another two members of the family are in a serious condition," Kursk governor Alexei Smirnov said in a post on Telegram.</p>

<p>The attack was with a "copter"-style drone, he added, a small device that can be fitted to carry grenades or other explosives that are dropped over targets.</p>

<p>Both sides have used drones, including larger self-detonating craft with ranges of up to hundreds of kilometres, extensively throughout the conflict which began in February 2022.</p>

<p>Ukraine has stepped up its attacks on Russian territory this year, targeting both energy sites that it says fuel Russia's military, as well as towns and villages just across the border.</p>

<p>Fighting in Ukraine has intensified in several directions as Russia has launched offensives from several directions, taking advantage of Kyiv being on the back foot militarily.&nbsp;</p>

<h3>Four dead in eastern Ukraine</h3>

<p>Kyiv's army said Saturday Moscow was attacking from several directions and that "the total number of hostile attacks along the entire frontline has now risen to 90."&nbsp;</p>

<p>Ukrainian officials reported deadly attacks on Saturday morning that killed four people in eastern villages.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"In (the village of) Zarichne, Russians killed three people," Vadym Filashkin, the head of the Donetsk region, said on social media.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The office of Ukraine's General Prosecutor later said another person, a resident of the eastern village of New York "also sustained fatal injuries."&nbsp;</p>

<p>New York has been intensely attacked since mid-June as Russian forces push towards the city of Toretsk, further north.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In the central city of Dnipro, police said they found a woman who was killed in an attack a day earlier that also wounded 13 people.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Police identified a woman killed in a missile attack on Dnipro city. She is a 76-year-old resident of a destroyed apartment block," Ukraine's National Police said in a statement.&nbsp;</p>

<p>It said the number of wounded in the attack rose to 13, "including an infant and a pregnant woman."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/o0h6lir8_russia-ukraine_625x300_30_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rishi-sunak-wife-akshata-murty-offer-prayers-at-london-temple-ahead-of-uk-polls-5999964]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Rishi Sunak, Wife Offer Prayers At London Temple Ahead Of UK Elections]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rishi-sunak-wife-akshata-murty-offer-prayers-at-london-temple-ahead-of-uk-polls-5999964]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 30 Jun 2024 04:18:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[British Prime Minister Rishi Sunak and wife Akshata Murty on the last weekend of the general election campaign prayed at London's iconic BAPS Swaminarayan Mandir, popularly known as Neasden Temple.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>British Prime Minister Rishi Sunak and wife Akshata Murty on the last weekend of the general election campaign prayed at London's iconic BAPS Swaminarayan Mandir, popularly known as Neasden Temple.</p>

<p>The couple was greeted with loud cheers as its convoy drove into the grand temple grounds on Saturday evening and went on to perform puja guided by the priests.</p>

<p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">It was a pleasure to welcome <a href="https://twitter.com/RishiSunak?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@RishiSunak</a> and Akshata Murty to <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/NeasdenTemple?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#NeasdenTemple</a> today. <a href="https://t.co/EEOC9SXccE">pic.twitter.com/EEOC9SXccE</a></p>&mdash; Neasden Temple (@NeasdenTemple) <a href="https://twitter.com/NeasdenTemple/status/1807162600725032972?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 29, 2024</a></blockquote></p>

<p>After a tour of the grand temple complex and interaction with volunteers and community leaders, cricket fan Sunak began his address to the congregation with a reference to India's winning the T20 World Cup before speaking about the inspiration he draws from his faith.</p>

<p>"I am Hindu and like all of you, I draw inspiration and comfort from my faith," he said.</p>

<p>"I was proud to be sworn in as a member of parliament on the 'Bhagavad Gita'. Our faith teaches us to do our duty and not fret about the outcome as long as one does it faithfully.</p>

<p>"That is what I was brought up to believe by my wonderful and loving parents and that is how I live my life; and that is what I want to pass on to my daughters as they grow up. It is dharma which guides me in my approach to public service," he said.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/emhabhas_rishi-sunak-akshata-murty_625x300_30_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The couple was greeted with loud cheers as its convoy drove into the grand temple grounds .]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nothing-new-no-real-progress-hamas-official-on-ceasefire-deal-with-israel-5999907]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Nothing New, No Real Progress": Hamas Official On Gaza Ceasefire Deal]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nothing-new-no-real-progress-hamas-official-on-ceasefire-deal-with-israel-5999907]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 30 Jun 2024 03:56:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A senior Palestinian Hamas official said Saturday in Beirut that negotiations for an agreement with Israel on a Gaza ceasefire and hostage release deal had not made any progress.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A senior Palestinian Hamas official said Saturday in Beirut that negotiations for an agreement with Israel on a Gaza ceasefire and hostage release deal had not made any progress.</p>

<p>A plan presented last month by US President Joe Biden, which he said was proposed by Israel, included a six-week truce accompanied by an Israeli withdrawal from densely populated areas and the release of some hostages in exchange for Palestinian prisoners held in Israel.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to US news site Axios, "three sources with direct knowledge" said Washington had presented a "new language for parts of" the proposed deal.</p>

<p>On Saturday, Osama Hamdan, a Hamas official based in Lebanon, confirmed that the Islamist movement had received the latest proposal on June 24, but that it included "nothing new".</p>

<p>"We can say that there is no real progress in the negotiations to stop the (Israeli) aggression so far", he said at a press conference.</p>

<p>The plan presented by Biden has so far failed to result in a deal, with both sides sticking to their demands.</p>

<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu has said he will continue the war until Hamas is totally defeated and all hostages are freed.</p>

<p>Hamas insists on a permanent ceasefire and a complete withdrawal of Israeli forces from the Gaza Strip.</p>

<p>Hamdan said the proposals were "merely a waste of time and provide additional time for the occupation (Israel) to practise genocide".</p>

<p>He also said Hamas was being pressured to accept Israel's deal "as it is without modification".</p>

<p>The war started with Hamas's October 7 attack on southern Israel which resulted in the deaths of 1,195 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli figures.</p>

<p>The militants also seized hostages, 116 of whom remain in Gaza although the army says 42 are dead.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory offensive has killed at least 37,834 people, also mostly civilians, according to data from the health ministry in Hamas-run Gaza.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/bdgi79g8_israel-airstrike-on-gaza-reuters_625x300_25_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Benjamin Netanyahu has said he will continue the war until Hamas is totally defeated.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/40-killed-over-200-injured-in-israeli-attacks-on-gaza-in-24-hours-5999905]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[40 Killed, Over 200 Injured In Israeli Attacks On Gaza In 24 Hours]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/40-killed-over-200-injured-in-israeli-attacks-on-gaza-in-24-hours-5999905]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 30 Jun 2024 03:54:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[At least 40 Palestinians were killed and 224 others injured in Israeli attacks across the besieged Gaza Strip over the past 24 hours, according to health authorities controlled by Hamas.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At least 40 Palestinians were killed and 224 others injured in Israeli attacks across the besieged Gaza Strip over the past 24 hours, according to health authorities controlled by Hamas.</p>

<p>The latest casualties bring the total Palestinian death count to 37,834, with 86,858 injuries reported since the outbreak of the Palestinian-Israeli conflict in October 2023, the health authorities said on Saturday.</p>

<p>Officials added that rescue teams faced significant obstacles in reaching areas targeted by attacks due to fuel shortages and intense clashes between Israeli forces and Palestinian armed factions, particularly in the city of Rafah in southern Gaza and the Shujaeya neighbourhood in eastern Gaza City, Xinhua news agency reported.</p>

<p>Avichay Adraee, an Israeli military spokesperson, said in a press statement on Saturday that the Israeli forces are continuing the attack on "terrorist" targets in the Shujaeya area, fighting simultaneously above and below ground.</p>

<p>During the past hours, the forces eliminated many "saboteurs" in clashes, and the troops found a weapons depot inside a school complex in the area, he added.</p>

<p>In Rafah, the Israeli forces eliminated several "saboteurs" and destroyed many "terrorist" infrastructure, including tunnel openings, according to Adraee.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the United Nations Relief and Works Agency for Palestine Refugees in the Near East highlighted on social media platform X that hundreds of thousands of Gazans continue to endure severe shortages of shelter, food, medicine, and clean water, exacerbated by restricted access through border crossings.</p>

<p>A temporary floating aid pier operated by the US, anchored off the coast of Gaza to facilitate humanitarian deliveries, has been removed due to adverse weather conditions, the Pentagon announced on Friday. This marks the third interruption since mid-May.</p>

<p>"Temporarily relocating the pier will prevent potential structural damage that could be caused by the heightened sea state," said Sabrina Singh, Deputy Pentagon Press Secretary, during a briefing on Friday.</p>

<p>The pier is not an end-all solution to getting aid into Gaza, Singh said, adding that land routes are the most effective delivery method.</p>

<p>Israel launched a large-scale offensive against Hamas in the Gaza Strip to retaliate against a Hamas rampage through the southern Israeli border on October 7, 2023, during which about 1,200 people were killed and around 250 were taken hostage.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/tvebgnig_gaza_625x300_30_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/man-attacks-israeli-embassy-in-serbia-with-crossbow-shot-dead-by-cops-5999850]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Man Attacks Israeli Embassy In Serbia With Crossbow, Shot Dead By Cops]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/man-attacks-israeli-embassy-in-serbia-with-crossbow-shot-dead-by-cops-5999850]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 30 Jun 2024 03:35:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Serbian police officer on Saturday killed a man who shot him in the neck with a crossbow in front of the Israeli embassy in Belgrade, in what the prime minister called a "terrorist act".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Serbian police officer on Saturday killed a man who shot him in the neck with a crossbow in front of the Israeli embassy in Belgrade, in what the prime minister called a "terrorist act".</p>

<p>Police identified the assailant as being a "convert" to Islam, who was born in 1999 in the town of Mladenovac, some 50 kilometres from Belgrade.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The attack happened around 11:00 am (0900 GMT) on Saturday in the Serbian capital, when the attacker shot the officer who was on duty outside the Israeli embassy.</p>

<p>The policeman in self-defence opened fire from his gun at the attacker "who died as a result of his injuries", said Interior Minister Ivica Dacic.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Authorities said some arrests had been made for "preventive reasons" and a number of people known to the security services were suspected of being linked to the attack.</p>

<p>The arrested included a man from Belgrade who was already held two years ago for being the administrator of several militant internet sites that called for "jihad", or holy war, but was released from custody, Dacic said.</p>

<p>"It is suspected that he directly participated in the logistical support and organisation of this terrorist act."</p>

<p>Police also said they were carrying out searches in a number of locations.</p>

<p>"There are several more persons that we are looking for, certainly for one who is on the territory of Serbia," President Aleksandar Vucic told reporters after visiting the wounded officer.</p>

<p>The attacker and his associates were tracked by the authorities before Saturday's attack but there was not enough evidence to arrest them, he added.</p>

<p>The 34-year-old officer, who underwent surgery in hospital, was in his guard booth when the attack happened.</p>

<p>According to authorities, the assailant had moved to live in Novi Pazar, which is a historical and political centre of the Bosniak Muslim minority in Serbia, and a centre of Islam in the country.</p>

<p>Dacic told reporters that there were early indications connecting the attack with people suspected of being linked to the Wahhabi movement -- an ultra-conservative branch of Islam that dominates in Saudi Arabia.</p>

<p>He said that overall security had been stepped up in Belgrade while special prosecutors had taken over the case.</p>

<h2>'Terrorist act'</h2>

<p>Serbian Prime Minister Milos Vucevic strongly condemned what he labelled a "heinous terrorist act".</p>

<p>The prime minister said his country would firmly respond to the threat of terrorism and stressed Serbian citizens could "feel safe".</p>

<p>"The embassy is closed and no employee of the embassy was injured," in an "attempted terrorist attack" in its vicinity, an Israeli foreign ministry statement said. The circumstances are still being investigated, it added.</p>

<p>Later on Saturday, Israel's Foreign Minister Israel Katz on X thanked Serbian authorities for their "strong support and cooperation following the attempted terror act on the Embassy of Israel in Belgrade today".</p>

<p>"Terrorism cannot be tolerated!"</p>

<p>Israeli ambassador to Serbia Yahel Vilan on X voiced his gratitude to the wounded officer, "who courageously prevented the attack".</p>

<p>"I am convinced that the investigation by the competent authorities of this shameful attack will identify all responsible persons and further contribute to the preservation of Serbia as a safe country."</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Serbia's top Islamic cleric Senad Halitovic strongly condemned the attack and wished the wounded officer a quick recovery.</p>

<p>"Such crimes are against all religious teachings, especially the teachings of Islam. Today's crime is the work of a mindless individual," he said in a statement.</p>

<p>The Balkan nation has continued arms sales to Israel after the war in Gaza started with Hamas's October 7 attack on southern Israel, which claimed 1,195 lives, mostly of civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli figures.</p>

<p>The militants also seized hostages, 116 of whom remain in Gaza although the army says 42 are dead.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory offensive has killed at least 37,834 people, also mostly civilians, according to data from the health ministry in Hamas-run Gaza.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-12/0htt5beg_india-police-generic_625x300_23_December_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-minister-says-iran-deserves-to-be-destroyed-for-war-threat-5999579]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Minister Says Iran "Deserves To Be Destroyed" For War Threat]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-minister-says-iran-deserves-to-be-destroyed-for-war-threat-5999579]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 30 Jun 2024 02:05:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli Foreign Minister Israel Katz said on Saturday that Iran's message of an "obliterating war" made it worthy of destruction.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli Foreign Minister Israel Katz said on Saturday that Iran's message of an "obliterating war" made it worthy of destruction.</p>

<p>⁠"A regime that threatens destruction deserves to be destroyed," Katz said in a post on X. He also said Israel will act with full force against Iran-backed Hezbollah if it does not stop firing at Israel from Lebanon and move away from the border.</p>

<p>Iran's UN mission said on Friday that if Israel embarks on a "full-scale military aggression" in Lebanon, "an obliterating war will ensue."</p>

<p>The Iranian mission also said in the post on X, formerly known as Twitter, that in such an event "all options, incl. the full involvement of all resistance fronts, are on the table."</p>

<p>Hezbollah has been exchanging fire with Israel since October, in parallel with the Gaza war. Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu and Defence Minister Yoav Gallant said this week they prefer a diplomatic path to resolving the situation.</p>

<p>Though Katz is a member of Israel's security cabinet, war policy has largely been led by Netanyahu and a small circle of ministers that includes Gallant, who visited Washington this week for talks on Gaza and Lebanon.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/b81i2gm8_israel-katz-x_625x300_16_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-warns-israel-of-obliterating-war-if-lebanon-attacked-5998738]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iran Warns Israel Of "Obliterating" War If Lebanon Attacked]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-warns-israel-of-obliterating-war-if-lebanon-attacked-5998738]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 29 Jun 2024 22:53:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iran on Saturday warned that "all Resistance Fronts", a grouping of Iran and its regional allies, would confront Israel if it attacks Lebanon.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Iran on Saturday warned that "all Resistance Fronts", a grouping of Iran and its regional allies, would confront Israel if it attacks Lebanon.</p>

<p>The comment from Iran's mission to New York comes with fears of a wider regional war involving Israel and Lebanon's Iran-backed Hezbollah movement. The two sides have engaged in near-daily exchanges of fire since the war in Gaza began.</p>

<p>Such exchanges have escalated this month, alongside bellicose rhetoric from both sides. Israel's military said plans for a Lebanon offensive had been "approved and validated", prompting Hezbollah to respond that none of Israel would be spared in a full-blown conflict.</p>

<p>In a post on social media platform X, the Iranian mission said it "deems as psychological warfare the Zionist regime's propaganda about intending to attack Lebanon".</p>

<p>But, it added, "should it embark on full-scale military aggression, an obliterating war will ensue. All options, incl. the full involvement of all Resistance Fronts, are on the table."</p>

<p>The war in Gaza began in October when Hamas Palestinian operatives attacked southern Israel.</p>

<p>Iran, which backs Hamas, has praised the attack as a success but has denied any involvement.</p>

<p>Alongside Hezbollah's attacks on northern Israel, Iran-backed rebels in Yemen have repeatedly struck commercial ships in the Red Sea area in what they say are acts of solidarity with the Palestinians.</p>

<p>Iran also backs other groups in the region.</p>

<p>The Islamic republic has not recognised Israel since the 1979 revolution that toppled Iran's United States-backed shah.</p>

<p>Fears of regional war also soared in April, after an air strike that levelled Iran's consulate in Damascus and killed seven Revolutionary Guards, two of them generals.</p>

<p>Iran hit back with an unprecedented drone and missile attack on Israel on April 13-14.</p>

<p>Iran's state media later reported explosions in the central province of Isfahan as US media quoted American officials saying Israel had carried out retaliatory strikes on its arch-rival.</p>

<p>Tehran downplayed the reported Israeli raid.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/5husnh3_israel-lebanon_625x300_27_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The war in Gaza began in October when Hamas operatives attacked Israel. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/5-isis-bombs-found-hidden-in-iconic-iraq-mosque-un-agency-5998694]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[5 ISIS Bombs Found Hidden In Iconic Iraq Mosque: UN Agency]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/5-isis-bombs-found-hidden-in-iconic-iraq-mosque-un-agency-5998694]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 29 Jun 2024 22:47:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A United Nations agency said it has discovered five bombs in a wall of Mosul's iconic Al-Nuri mosque, planted years ago by Islamic State group jihadists, during restoration work in the northern Iraqi city.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A United Nations agency said it has discovered five bombs in a wall of Mosul's iconic Al-Nuri mosque, planted years ago by Islamic State group jihadists, during restoration work in the northern Iraqi city.</p>

<p>Five "large-scale explosive devices, designed to trigger a massive destruction of the site," were found in the southern wall of the prayer hall on Tuesday by the UNESCO team working at the site, a representative for the agency told AFP late Friday.</p>

<p>Mosul's Al-Nuri mosque and the adjacent leaning minaret nicknamed Al-Hadba or the "hunchback", which dates from the 12th century, were destroyed during the battle to retake the city from IS.</p>

<p>Iraq's army accused IS, which occupied Mosul for three years, of planting explosives at the site and blowing it up.</p>

<p>UNESCO, the UN cultural agency, has been working to restore the mosque and other architectural heritage sites in the city, much of it reduced to rubble in the battle to retake it in 2017.</p>

<p>"The Iraqi armed forces immediately secured the area and the situation is now fully under control," UNESCO added.</p>

<p>One bomb was removed, but four other 1.5-kilogram (3.3-pound) devices "remain connected to each other" and are expected to be cleared in the coming days, it said.</p>

<p><strong>'Complex manufacturing'</strong></p>

<p>"These explosive devices were hidden inside a wall, which was specially rebuilt around them: it explains why they could not be discovered when the site was cleared by Iraqi forces" in 2020, the agency said.</p>

<p>Iraqi General Tahseen al-Khafaji, spokesperson for the Joint Operations Command of various Iraqi forces, confirmed the discovery of "several explosive devices from ISIS jihadists in Al-Nuri mosque."</p>

<p>He said provincial deminers requested help from the Defence Ministry in Baghdad to defuse the remaining munitions because of their "complex manufacturing".</p>

<p>Construction work has been suspended at the site until the bombs are removed.</p>

<p>It was from Al-Nuri mosque that Abu Bakr Al-Baghdadi, the then-leader of IS, proclaimed the establishment of the group's "caliphate" in July 2014.</p>

<p>The jihadists took over large swathes of territory in Iraq and neighbouring Syria, which they ruled with brutality.</p>

<p>Iraqi forces backed by a US-led coalition drove IS out of Mosul in 2017.</p>

<p>The Al-Nuri mosque derives its name from Nureddine al-Zinki, the unifier of Syria who also reigned for a time over Mosul and ordered its construction in 1172.</p>

<p>It was destroyed and rebuilt in 1942 in a renovation project, with only the ancient minaret remaining from the original structure.</p>

<p>The current restoration of Al-Nuri, largely funded by the United Arab Emirates, is still expected to be completed in December 2024.</p>

<p>This, said UNESCO, will finally erase "the stigma" of IS occupation.</p>

<p>The minaret -- which will be reconstructed at a slant upon the request of locals -- is being rebuilt with 45,000 of the original bricks saved from the rubble, only a third of the original structure.</p>

<p>The bomb scare was not the first surprise discovery at Al-Nuri. In January 2022, restoration teams unearthed an underground prayer room from the original 12th century building.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/bvm7vdi_al-nuri-mosque_625x300_29_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Iraq's army accused IS of planting explosives at the site and blowing it up.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/2-priests-among-prisoners-exchanged-between-ukraine-russia-5998634]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[2 Priests Among Prisoners Exchanged Between Ukraine, Russia]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/2-priests-among-prisoners-exchanged-between-ukraine-russia-5998634]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 29 Jun 2024 22:37:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ukraine and Russia said Saturday that priests were among the dozens of captured soldiers and civilians they had exchanged earlier this week.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ukraine and Russia said Saturday that priests were among the dozens of captured soldiers and civilians they had exchanged earlier this week.</p>

<p>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky said two Ukrainian Greek Catholic priests taken captive in Moscow-occupied Berdiansk were handed back to Ukraine thanks to the mediation of the Vatican.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Russia said a high-ranking Ukrainian Orthodox cleric was handed over to Moscow along with two other priests.</p>

<p>Churches have been heavily affected by the war, with Kyiv's Orthodox church breaking ties with Moscow and Ukraine regularly accusing clerics of treason.</p>

<p>Moscow and Kyiv exchanged 90 POWs and some civilians each earlier this week.</p>

<p>Speaking at an event in Kyiv, Zelensky named the two released Ukrainian Greek Catholic priests as Bogdan Geleta and Ivan Levytskyi, and said they had been preaching in Berdiansk.</p>

<p>Bediansk, on the Azov Sea, fell to Russian forces in the first days of their February 2022 invasion. The priests had been held by the Russians since 16 November 2022, Zelensky added.</p>

<p>He said they were freed "thanks to the efforts of our team and the mediation of the Vatican, for which I am especially grateful."</p>

<p>Pope Francis earlier this year expressed hopes for a "general" prisoner exchange between the two countries.</p>

<p>Metropolitan Ionafan, the Ukrainian Orthodox cleric handed over to Moscow, had been convicted in August 2023 of justifying the Russian invasion and was facing five years in prison.</p>

<p>Moscow's ombudsman Tatiana Moskalkova said Ionafan was received by the head of the Russian Orthodox Church, Patriarch Kirill in Moscow.</p>

<p>She said two other Orthodox priests who had remained with Moscow's patriarchy when the church split were also handed over to Russia in the course of the exchange.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/ggql5n4g_ukrainian-priests-_625x300_29_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Moscow and Kyiv exchanged 90 POWs and some civilians each earlier this week.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uks-hannibal-the-cannibal-locked-in-fortress-cell-behind-17-doors-report-5997415]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA['Hannibal The Cannibal' Locked In Fortress Cell Behind 17 Doors: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uks-hannibal-the-cannibal-locked-in-fortress-cell-behind-17-doors-report-5997415]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 29 Jun 2024 18:50:00 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Robert Maudsley, dubbed "Hannibal the Cannibal," has been held in solitary confinement at Wakefield Prison for 45 years due to his extreme danger, locked behind 17 steel doors resembling conditions akin to Hannibal Lecter.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Robert Maudsley, 70, has been held in solitary confinement at Wakefield Prison for the past 45 years due to the extreme danger he poses to other inmates, according to a report by <em>the Manchester Evening News.</em> Originally sentenced for murder, Maudsley went on to kill three more people while incarcerated.</p>

<p>New details about Maudsley's extreme confinement are emerging from the book <em>"Inside Wakefield Prison: Life Behind Bars in the Monster Mansion"</em> by authors Jonathan Levi and Emma French. The book describes conditions mirroring those of the fictional serial killer Hannibal Lecter, with Maudsley reportedly kept in a specially designed transparent cell.</p>

<p>The writers detail: "Today, in Wakefield Prison, Maudsley is kept in confinement for twenty-three hours of the day. Everything in his cell is made of cardboard, and you have to go through 17 steel doors to get to it."</p>

<p>As per the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.manchestereveningnews.co.uk/news/greater-manchester-news/uks-most-dangerous-prisoner-locked-29432901">news outlet,</a> his confinement closely mirrors Hannibal Lecter, played by Anthony Hopkins in the film Silence of the Lambs, which has led to Maudsley being dubbed "Hannibal the Cannibal." The authors spoke to a prison insider named Pete, who gave more insights about the infamous "strongbox" in which he resides.</p>

<p>Pete remarked on Maudsley's harsh reality, asserting: "The sad thing is, if he were living with someone else, he'd kill somebody else. It'd have been more humane to just put him down."</p>

<p>As per the news report, he was unequivocal in his belief that Maudsley would kill again if released. Levi and French delved into the myth of the "Perspex Cell," noting that "every contributor tells a different story".</p>

<p>"Pete, for example, described the box in the following terms: 'Metal with thick Perspex around them that looked out into the middle, and there was a metal door with thick Perspex on it and then an outer cell door," they said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/tqk6vi0o_robert-maudsley_625x300_29_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Robert Maudsley, known as "Hannibal the Cannibal," has been held in extreme solitary confinement.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-how-new-uk-prime-minister-will-be-elected-5997220]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: How New UK Prime Minister Will Be Elected]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-how-new-uk-prime-minister-will-be-elected-5997220]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 29 Jun 2024 18:10:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The upcoming general elections will shape the composition of the House of Commons, ultimately determining the Prime Minister of the United Kingdom.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In May 2024, to everyone's shock, UK Prime Minister Rishi Sunak announced snap polls for July 4. Now, that means electing the members to the House of Commons, which will then determine the next Prime Minister of the United Kingdom. The Conservative Party, in power for 14 years, is facing a formidable challenge from the Labour Party.<br />
<br />
The Prime Minister of the United Kingdom is the head of government, responsible for advising the sovereign on the exercise of the royal prerogative, chairing the Cabinet and selecting its ministers.<br />
<br />
<strong>How a new PM is elected</strong></p>

<ul>
	<li>The UK holds a general election to choose Members of Parliament to represent their constituencies.</li>
	<li>The political party with the majority of seats in the House of Commons typically forms the government.</li>
	<li>The leader of the party with the most seats becomes the Prime Minister.</li>
	<li>The monarch (currently King Charles III) formally appoints the Prime Minister, usually the party leader with the most seats.</li>
	<li>The PM must maintain the confidence of the House of Commons, meaning they must command the support of a majority of MPs.</li>
	<li>If the PM loses the confidence of the House or their party loses a general election, they may resign or be replaced by a new PM.</li>
	<li>The office of the prime minister is not established by any statute or constitutional document but exists by a long-established convention.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Responsibilities of the Prime Minister</strong><br />
The Prime Minister of the United Kingdom leads the government and the Cabinet, heading a major political party and typically controlling a majority in the House of Commons. This position wields significant legislative and executive powers.<br />
<br />
The Prime Minister holds various responsibilities, including serving as First Lord of the Treasury, Minister for the Civil Service, Minister for National Security and Minister for the Union. The Prime Minister's official residence and office is 10 Downing Street in London.<br />
<br />
The Prime Minister's key responsibilities include guiding law-making in the House of Commons, appointing and managing Cabinet members and ministers and coordinating government departments and the Civil Service. The PM also represents the UK at home and abroad, serving as public face and voice of His Majesty's Government.<br />
<br />
The Prime Minister also advises the sovereign, playing a central and influential role in the UK government. It includes appointing judges, officials and ecclesiastical leaders as well as conferring honours and peerages.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
So far, fifty-seven people have served as UK Prime Minister, with Robert Walpole being the first (1721) and longest-serving (over 20 years), while Liz Truss was the shortest-serving (seven weeks).&nbsp;<br />
<br />
<strong>Polling day&nbsp;</strong><br />
<br />
On July 4, voters will vote in person at polling stations from 7 am to 10 pm, or by post beforehand.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
Photo ID will be required for in-person voting, a first for a UK general election. Once polls close at 10 pm, an exit poll will be announced, based on a survey of voters in around 150 constituencies across England, Scotland and Wales.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/3o59eluo_rishi-sunak_625x300_07_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The PM must maintain the confidence of the House of Commons (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>