<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Sep 2024 17:57:15 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gen-z-rejects-9-5-jobs-76-aim-to-be-their-own-boss-poll-6533790]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Gen Z Rejects 9-5 Jobs, 76% Aim To Be Their Own Boss: Poll]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gen-z-rejects-9-5-jobs-76-aim-to-be-their-own-boss-poll-6533790]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Sep 2024 17:57:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A recent poll reveals that 76% of Generation Z, compared to 57% of millennials and lower percentages of Gen X and baby boomers, prefer entrepreneurship over traditional 9-5 jobs.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Confident and digitally savvy, Gen Z is set to outshine millennials with their entrepreneurial spirit. A new poll highlights a growing trend of young people choosing to start their own businesses rather than work for others.</p>

<p>The research by<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.santander.co.uk/about-santander/media-centre/press-releases/santander-shortlists-100-uk-start-ups-for-its-2024"> Santander UK </a>revealed that three quarters of Gen Z are seeking to "be their own boss" and are not planning to work a nine-to-five job for the rest of their career. 77 percent are confident in their ability to launch and run a successful business, and 39 percent back themselves to do so from their smartphone.</p>

<p>Half of those polled said that Gen Z and Millennials have an advantage when it comes to starting a business because they grew up in the digital age. In comparison, Gen X and Boomers say there were fewer opportunities to start a business in their younger years (34%) as there was more pressure to follow a traditional education and career path.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Gen Z is proving to be the most entrepreneurial generation yet, and it's no coincidence. Unlike previous generations, they've grown up fully immersed in the digital age, where information, tools, and global connections are just a click away. &nbsp;This constant exposure has fostered a mindset that values innovation and agility. &nbsp;With a deep understanding of digital landscapes, they're not just prepared to start their own ventures - they're uniquely positioned to outpace previous generations in turning ideas into reality," said Sam Jones, Dragon's Den star and &nbsp;founder of Gener8.</p>

<p>"It's clear that digital-savvy Gen Z have a fantastic entrepreneurial spirit, but the qualities you need to succeed on your own aren't bound by age - entrepreneurship is driven by passion, curiosity, and the desire to create something meaningful. Some develop these attributes early on, often sparked by a need to solve a problem. While others may discover a business drive later in life, perhaps after spotting a gap in the market," said Mike Regnier, CEO, Santander UK.</p>

<p>The survey of 2,000 adults found that while Gen Z and millennials may be perceived as the most entrepreneurial, age is not a barrier to success.</p>

<p>This year, Santander saw more than 850 businesses apply for the awards, with Gen Z making up two-thirds of those that applied. The 100 that have been shortlisted cover a range of industries, including healthcare, sustainability, AI, and tech.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/ma022ev8_social-media-influencer_625x300_10_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Of those surveyed, 39% of Gen Z believe they can start a business via smartphone.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/g20-or-cop29-west-will-keep-choosing-politics-over-climate-6533701]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: G20 Or COP29, West Will Keep Choosing Politics Over Climate]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/g20-or-cop29-west-will-keep-choosing-politics-over-climate-6533701]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Sep 2024 17:42:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[While US ambivalence on international commitments for climate change is known, the Europeans, who project themselves as champions of climate action, are now prevaricating too.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/00f2d6kg_climate_625x300_10_September_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Come November and climate activists get excited as the annual United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC) Conference of Parties (COP) takes place. This year, the COP (29th edition) will be held in Baku, Azerbaijan, from November 11 to November 22. The month will also see the G20 Summit on November 18-19 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. With the G20 also focussed on sustainable development and climate change, there is every reason for expectations to be raised.</p>

<p>In 2021, the G20 met in Italy just before the Glasgow COP, and it would be fair to surmise that the G7 pressure within the G20 for "Net Zero by 2050" saw both China and India also sign on to the Net Zero pledge, albeit for 2060 and 2070, respectively.</p>

<h2><strong>NCGQ: The Next 'Big' Goal</strong></h2>

<p>Among Brazil's overarching G20 priorities is "energy transitions and sustainable development". They have already established the G20 Task Force on Global Mobilization against Climate Change. Furthermore, they will host the COP in 2025, where the updated (target date for submission is early 2025) Nationally Determined Contributions (NDCs), the voluntary goals on climate action taken by all countries, will be subject to a global stocktake.</p>

<p>The big-ticket item at Baku is a New Collective Quantified Goal (NCQG) on climate financing. At the Copenhagen COP in 2009, developed countries agreed to provide $100 billion a year for climate action to developing countries. A decade and a half later, and after stretching the data by all sorts of inclusions, the OECD has now declared that the developing countries met their target in 2022. Voila!</p>

<p>At its COP in Paris in 2015, the UNFCCC had agreed that a new and collective - not individual country commitments - quantified financing goal would be established. In the decade since, several key matters remain stalled, including the elusive number for the NCQG that developing countries want to know and are calling for. India has called for $1 trillion a year, and the Azeris have proposed &nbsp;$6 trillion till 2030.</p>

<h2><strong>Developed Nations Won't Assume Full Responsibility</strong></h2>

<p>Additionally, there are other critical unresolved issues, including who would contribute to this. Developed countries are unlikely to agree that it is their responsibility alone, putting China - rightly - on the mat, but also pressuring large developing countries like India to come on board the contributing side.</p>

<p>Presidential elections will be held in the US on November 5, and at this stage, former President Donald Trump stands an even chance of coming back. In 2016, soon after becoming President, he pulled the US out of the 2015 Paris Agreement on climate change. This despite Paris meeting the key US condition of jettisoning the cardinal UNFCCC principle of common and differentiated responsibilities and asking all countries to put forth NDCs. Years earlier, the US had not ratified the Kyoto Protocol on quantified emissions reductions by developed countries.</p>

<p>While US ambivalence on international commitments for climate change is known, the Europeans, who project themselves as champions of climate action, are now prevaricating too, with cutbacks on their domestic action and trade moves, all to penalise developing countries over their exports to the European Union (EU) for exceeding predetermined carbon limits in the products. The stress on their economies and energy security resulting from the Ukraine-Russia conflict are the articulated reasons for the European pullback on climate. But their thrust joins the US in the shirking of historical and capacity responsibilities and trying to shift the burden for climate action onto large developing countries.</p>

<h2><strong>Politics And Climate Can't Be Divorced</strong></h2>

<p>The G20 meeting is a summit and is expected to be attended by member countries at the level of heads of state or governments. But no matter its economic focus, it is intertwined with politics, as evidenced by references to the Russia-Ukraine conflict being the make or break of its declarations at Bali and New Delhi. Russian President Vladimir Putin didn't attend the G20 summits in Bali and New Delhi, but the Brazilians have been public in their urging of his presence at Rio. They are similarly pursuing President Xi of China.</p>

<p>The Brazilians have ace diplomats, but squaring their national, hemispheric and global interests could be a tall order. Indeed, with Ukraine being central to his administration's concern, could Rio see President Biden excuse himself? In any case, with US elections scheduled for November 5, Biden will either way be a "caretaker" till January 2025.</p>

<p>At Copenhagen, former US President Barack Obama had demurred on $30 billion per year till 2030 as the short-term financing goal, stating that budgets were Congress's domain. The world then got the expression "approaching" $30 billion. The US team at Baku would have an even better way out. In such circumstances, it is understandable that countries may not reveal their climate hands this fall. Will politics trump climate? Only November will tell, but the key date is neither COP nor the G20 Summit.</p>

<p><em>[The author is a former Indian ambassador to the European Union and a Distinguished Fellow, The Energy and Resources Institute (TERI)]&nbsp;</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/agc6ebco_climate_625x300_10_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/lotions-sunscreens-linked-to-hormonal-disruptions-in-children-study-finds-6533234]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Lotions, Sunscreens Linked To Hormonal Disruptions In Children, Study Finds]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/lotions-sunscreens-linked-to-hormonal-disruptions-in-children-study-finds-6533234]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Sep 2024 16:49:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A new study links personal care products like lotions and hair conditioners to elevated levels of endocrine-disrupting chemicals called phthalates in young children.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A recent study found a worrying correlation between the use of personal care products including lotions, hair oils, hair conditioners, ointments, and sunscreen, and higher levels of phthalates in young children, according to the new study by George Mason University College of Public Health.</p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://ehp.niehs.nih.gov/doi/10.1289/EHP13937">the study</a>, depending on the children's racial and ethnic origin, different quantities of these chemicals-known for their endocrine-disrupting qualities-were identified. Phthalates are frequently utilised in plastics to improve their flexibility and durability; they are also found in a lot of personal hygiene products.</p>

<p>Researchers are concerned about possible effects on children's development during important growth phases since these chemicals mimic, inhibit, or interact with the body's natural hormones.</p>

<p>"This is the first study to suggest that different skin care products used by young children may differentially increase exposure to endocrine-disrupting phthalates and phthalate replacements in young children," <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://publichealth.gmu.edu/news/2024-09/new-study-finds-associations-between-use-skin-care-products-and-exposure-potential">said the primary investigator of the study, Michael S Bloom</a>, professor in the Department of Global and Community Health at George Mason University's College of Public Health.</p>

<p>The study collected medical data from 630 children between the ages of four and eight from 10 different sites across the United States, including a clinical examination and a urinalysis. The child's parent or guardian was also asked to complete a survey within 24 hours prior to the child's examination, which included questions regarding the child's sociodemographic information (race/ethnic identity, sex assigned at birth, etc.). It also asked parents to list all the skin care products, including lotions, soaps, shampoos, oils, and cosmetics, that were applied to the child's skin in the 24 hours prior to their examination, with as much specificity as possible regarding the product type and brand or generic name.</p>

<p>"We found associations between recent use of different skin care products and higher concentrations of phthalate and phthalate-replacement compounds," said Bloom. "There were different relationships between the use of skin care products and the endocrine-disrupting chemicals in children depending on their racial and ethnic identities and their sex assigned at birth. We also found that distinct patterns of using multiple skin care products were predictive of higher concentrations of phthalates and phthalate replacements."</p>

<p>"The results can inform policies to address the use of endocrine-disrupting chemicals in skin care products that may be used on children and to help advise parents' decisions about using products to limit their children's exposure to potential developmental toxicants," said Bloom.</p>

<p>The research emphasizes raising public awareness of the possible dangers associated with kids' regular exposure to these chemicals, especially in the early years when hormonal balance is crucial for healthy development.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/jqos0g78_lotions-sunscreens_625x300_10_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The research also reveals that exposure varies among different racial and ethnic groups.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-no-longer-exists-as-a-military-formation-israel-defence-minister-6532886]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hamas No Longer Exists As A Military Formation: Israel Defence Minister]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-no-longer-exists-as-a-military-formation-israel-defence-minister-6532886]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Sep 2024 16:07:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli Defence Minister Yoav Gallant offered his support for a hostage release agreement in the first phase of a Gaza truce deal, saying it would give Israel a "strategic opportunity" to address other security challenges.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli Defence Minister Yoav Gallant offered his support for a hostage release agreement in the first phase of a Gaza truce deal, saying it would give Israel a "strategic opportunity" to address other security challenges.</p>

<p>Bringing the hostages home is "the right thing to do", Gallant told foreign journalists.</p>

<p>"Achieving an agreement is also a strategic opportunity that gives us a high chance to change the security situation on all fronts," he said.</p>

<p>Israel, which has been at war with Palestinian militants in Gaza since Hamas's October 7 attack, is also engaged in near-daily clashes with Lebanon's Hezbollah movement on its northern border with Lebanon.</p>

<p>Urging the international community to keep up the pressure on Hamas to reach an agreement, Gallant said he firmly supported the first stage of a three-phase ceasefire deal announced by US President Joe Biden on May 31, hoping to build on it for an eventual end to the war.</p>

<p>"Israel should achieve an agreement that will bring about a pause for six weeks and bring back hostages," Gallant told journalists at a sit-down on Monday at his office. His remarks were released for publication on Tuesday.</p>

<p>Gallant also said Hamas's military capabilities had been severely damaged after more than 11 months of war and that it no longer existed as a military formation in Gaza.</p>

<p>"Hamas as a military formation no longer exists. Hamas is engaged in guerrilla warfare and we are still fighting Hamas terrorists and pursuing Hamas leadership," he said.</p>

<p>His comments came as mediators from the United States, Qatar and Egypt struggle to reach an agreement between Israel and Hamas to end the war in Gaza, which has killed nearly 41,000 people.</p>

<p>The widespread destruction has produced a dire humanitarian situation in the besieged territory, underscored by the recent confirmation of its first polio case in 25 years.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/j16pmol_hamas-reuters-_625x300_11_June_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hamas is engaged in guerrilla warfare, Israeli Defence Minister Yoav Gallant said. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/video-remote-surgery-conducted-9-000-km-away-using-game-controller-6532741]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Video: Remote Surgery Conducted 9,000 KM Away Using Game Controller]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/video-remote-surgery-conducted-9-000-km-away-using-game-controller-6532741]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Sep 2024 15:48:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Researchers from ETH Zurich and CU Medicine successfully performed a teleoperated magnetic endoscopy on a swine model, with a remote specialist in Zurich using a video game controller.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Researchers from the Swiss Federal Institute of Technology Zurich (ETH Zurich), Switzerland, and the Chinese University of Hong Kong (CUHK) Faculty of Medicine (CU Medicine) have successfully completed a teleoperated magnetic endoscopy surgery, marking a significant achievement in medical science. Using a remote-controlled device, a biopsy of the stomach wall was taken during the surgery on a swine model.</p>

<p>A clinician who was physically present in the operating room in Hong Kong and a remote specialist who was stationed 9,300 kilometres distant in Zurich, Switzerland, both participated in the process. Advanced technology was used by both experts to control the procedure; the distant expert used a game controller from an operator console in Zurich.</p>

<p><strong>Watch the video here:</strong></p>

<p><iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="315" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Qy0F4xYLgOY?si=5HsQZCou0vAenHnF" title="YouTube video player" width="560"></iframe></p>

<p>This study demonstrates how this cutting-edge technology may be able to provide speciality surgical treatment in remote areas, particularly when access to local expertise may be limited. The research findings were released by <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/aisy.202400522"><em>Advanced Intelligent Systems, </em></a>which is a peer-reviewed open access scientific journal.</p>

<p>“Teleoperated endoscopy offers not only remote surgical training and mentoring but also immediate diagnostic and surgical care in remote areas, particularly when local expertise is lacking. A remote expert can even instruct trained nurses to perform the procedures. Millions of patients worldwide will be able to be diagnosed and treated for gastrointestinal cancer in a timely manner as endoscopic technology becomes more accessible," <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.med.cuhk.edu.hk/press-releases/cuhk-and-eth-zurich-successfully-conduct-world-s-first-in-vivo-teleoperated-magnetic-endoscopy-using-an-animal-model-over-a-distance-of-9-300-km-between-zurich-and-hong-kong#:~:text=Featured%20is%20Dr%20Shannon%20Chan,live%20on%20the%20computer%20screen.">said Dr Shannon Melissa Chan</a>, Assistant Professor in the Department of Surgery at CU Medicine.</p>

<p>“In the next step of our research, we will be performing tele-endoscopy on a human stomach. In addition to endoscopic procedures, such as cancer screening, there is a lot of potential for this technology. This includes its application to other areas of the gastrointestinal tract, to the neurovascular system, and in foetal surgery,” <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.med.cuhk.edu.hk/press-releases/cuhk-and-eth-zurich-successfully-conduct-world-s-first-in-vivo-teleoperated-magnetic-endoscopy-using-an-animal-model-over-a-distance-of-9-300-km-between-zurich-and-hong-kong#:~:text=Featured%20is%20Dr%20Shannon%20Chan,live%20on%20the%20computer%20screen.">said Professor Dr Bradley Nelson</a>, Director of the Multi-Scale Robotics Lab, Head of the Institute of Robotics and Intelligent Systems, ETH Zurich.</p>

<p>A magnetic endoscope, controlled by an external magnetic field, was successfully tested on a sedated pig by a Zurich surgeon using a video game controller. Other tests have used a similar game controller. The endoscope made a U-turn and took a stomach biopsy, with low latency under 300 milliseconds. This experiment suggests that remote surgeries, potentially even for astronauts, could soon be feasible, particularly benefiting patients in remote areas.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/6lnelgso_dr-shannon-chan_625x300_10_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Dr Shannon Chan in Hong Kong, remotely operating the endoscopic system in Switzerland.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/thousands-plead-for-help-as-death-count-in-typhoon-hit-vietnam-rises-to-82-6532721]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Thousands Plead For Help As Death Count In Typhoon-hit Vietnam Rises To 82]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/thousands-plead-for-help-as-death-count-in-typhoon-hit-vietnam-rises-to-82-6532721]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Sep 2024 15:44:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Thousands of people were stranded on rooftops and posted desperate pleas for help on social media Tuesday after severe flooding in parts of typhoon-hit Vietnam, as the death count climbed to 82.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Thousands of people were stranded on rooftops and posted desperate pleas for help on social media Tuesday after severe flooding in parts of typhoon-hit Vietnam, as the death count climbed to 82.</p>

<p>Typhoon Yagi struck Saturday bringing winds in excess of 149 kilometres (92 miles) per hour and a deluge of rain that has caused flooding not seen in decades, according to locals.</p>

<p>Some communities in Hanoi along the swollen and fast-moving Red River were inundated, with people forced to evacuate in boats and authorities warning more flooding was expected to hit the capital later Tuesday.</p>

<p>Phan Thi Tuyet, 50, who lives close to the river, said she had never experienced such high water.</p>

<p>"I have lost everything, all gone," she told AFP, clutching her two dogs.</p>

<p>"I had to come to higher ground to save our lives. We could not bring any of the furniture with us. Everything is under water now."</p>

<p>The storm downed bridges, tore roofs off buildings, damaged factories and triggered widespread flooding and landslides, leaving 64 people still missing.</p>

<p>Hanoi authorities said more than 25,000 trees in the city had been uprooted in the storm. Huge trunks blocked key roads in the city centre, creating large traffic jams.</p>

<p>The north of the country -- densely populated and a major manufacturing hub for global tech firms including Samsung -- was badly hit, with floodwaters in the city of Yen Bai at record levels, meteorologists said.</p>

<p>Authorities have issued flood and landslide warnings for 401 communes across 18 northern provinces.</p>

<p>One-storey homes in parts of Thai Nguyen and Yen Bai cities were almost completely submerged in the early hours of Tuesday, with residents waiting on the roofs for help.</p>

<p>Rescuers were trying to reach residential areas to retrieve old people and children. On social media, relatives of those stuck in floodwater posted desperate pleas for help and supplies in the early hours of the morning.</p>

<p>Crops including bananas, guavas and corn -- which are usually sold in nearby markets -- were all flooded.</p>

<h3><strong>Bridge collapsed</strong></h3>

<p>As well as the dead and missing, flooding and landslides have also injured at least 752 people, officials at the ministry of agriculture said Tuesday.</p>

<p>Authorities stopped heavy vehicles crossing a major bridge over the Red River in central Hanoi on Tuesday and suspended a train line across Long Bien bridge as the water level rose.</p>

<p>The action followed the dramatic collapse of a bridge higher up the river in northern Phu Tho province on Monday.</p>

<p>Pictures showed half of the 375-metre Phong Chau bridge gone.</p>

<p>Five people who were crossing the bridge at the time have been rescued, but eight others were still missing Tuesday, authorities said.</p>

<p>The storm has also caused power blackouts and major disruptions to factories in the country's north, which is a major production centre for a number of global tech firms.</p>

<p>Susumu Yoshida from the Japan Chamber of Commerce and Industry told AFP more than 80 Japanese companies had suffered some kind of damage from the typhoon, including to factory buildings, machinery, raw materials and products.</p>

<p>Some had suspended or partially suspended production, and would not resume operations until the end of the week, he said.</p>

<p>At least 24 people were killed as Yagi tore through southern China and the Philippines before hitting Vietnam.</p>

<p>Typhoons in the region are forming closer to the coast, intensifying more rapidly, and staying over land longer due to climate change, according to a study published in July.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/dcsjgt1o_typhoon-yagi_625x300_10_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The storm downed bridges, tore roofs off buildings, damaged factories]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chinese-company-to-lose-rs-35-crore-after-washing-machine-pricing-error-6532652]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Chinese Company To Lose Rs 35 Crore After Washing Machine Pricing Error]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chinese-company-to-lose-rs-35-crore-after-washing-machine-pricing-error-6532652]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Sep 2024 15:36:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The incident happened on the evening of August 28, when Little Swan's online shop received over 40,000 orders in just 20 minutes, after customers noticed exceptionally low prices on washing machines.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Chinese small business, Little Swan Dongshan Franchise Shop, is facing a potential loss of 30 million yuan (approximately Rs 35 crore) due to a pricing error. According to the <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3277651/china-shop-loses-us42-million-20-minutes-after-washing-machine-pricing-error" rel="nofollow, noindex">South China Morning Post</a></em>, an employee mistakenly labelled some washing machines with incorrect prices, sparking a surge in sales. The company, which operates both online and offline in Jixi county, Anhui province, has apologised for the mistake and is requesting customers to cancel their orders.</p>

<p>The incident happened on the evening of August 28, when Little Swan's online shop received over 40,000 orders in just 20 minutes, after customers noticed exceptionally low prices on washing machines. The company, a well-known domestic brand, attributed the chaos to a single employee's mistake. The error resulted in a massive surge in orders, putting the company at risk of a significant financial loss.</p>

<p>If the shop had fulfilled the orders, it would have lost 30 million yuan, as the total value of the products was 70 million yuan, but customers only paid 40 million yuan. A customer, surnamed Wang, said she discovered the drastically reduced prices on social media on August 28 and purchased three washing machines online. She bought two machines normally priced at 1,699 yuan (US$240) each for just 299 yuan, and a third machine normally priced at 2,499 yuan for 439 yuan. After seeing the store's apology and request to cancel orders, Ms Wang promptly cancelled her purchases.</p>

<p data-qa="Component-Component" datatype="p">The company acknowledged that, ''Due to the misunderstanding, we made a significant mistake. We recognise that this issue has caused confusion among the public and has seriously disrupted the market. We feel deeply guilty and upset.''</p>

<p data-qa="Component-Component" datatype="p">The Little Swan Dongshan Franchise Shop, a small business with only six employees, has struggled to make a profit in recent years due to the economic downturn.&nbsp;Following the incident, the company issued a public apology and requested customers to cancel their orders.</p>

<p data-qa="Component-Component" datatype="p">''Tens of thousands of orders and tens of millions of yuan are astronomical figures for us. We feel sincerely sorry for all the affected customers. We humbly beg you to understand our difficulties and to agree to withdraw orders. We will refund you as fast as we can,'' said a statement from the company.</p>

<p data-qa="Component-Component" datatype="p">The local market supervision authority has launched an investigation into the incident. According to Zhao Liangshan, a lawyer from Shaanxi Hengda Law Firm, if the company intentionally mispriced the products to attract attention or boost sales, they are legally required to fulfill the orders. However, if the incorrect pricing was genuinely an error, the company can petition the court to cancel the purchase contracts, allowing them to refund customers without having to deliver the goods.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/a5c1omf_washing-machine_625x300_10_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The company has apologised for the mistake and is requesting customers to cancel their orders.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ahead-of-trump-debate-kamala-harris-border-abortion-policies-in-spotlight-6532627]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ahead Of Trump Debate, Kamala Harris' Border, Abortion Policies In Spotlight]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ahead-of-trump-debate-kamala-harris-border-abortion-policies-in-spotlight-6532627]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Sep 2024 15:31:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kamala Harris has unveiled a few centrist-leaning policies, abandoned some past positions and left much else vague as she gears up for a critical US presidential debate with Donald Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kamala Harris has unveiled a few centrist-leaning policies, abandoned some past positions and left much else vague as she gears up for a critical US presidential debate with Donald Trump.</p>

<p>The Democratic vice president unveiled a list of policies on her website on the eve of the clash, with Republicans accusing her of "flip-flopping" on key issues.</p>

<p>Here is where the White House hopeful stands in five key areas:</p>

<h2>'Opportunity economy'</h2>

<p>Harris has stressed her commitment to the United States' middle class, citing her own background of being raised by a single mother in California, and said she wants to create an "opportunity economy."</p>

<p>One of her most concrete policies so far is a child tax credit of $6,000 for families of newborn children. She has also promised tax cuts for 100 million Americans while raising taxes on the richest, and to bring down housing prices.</p>

<p>Tax is one of the few policy areas where she has broken with President Joe Biden. In a nod to moderate voters, she wants a 28 percent tax on capital gains, less than the 39.6 percent proposed by Biden.</p>

<p>Harris has also promised to end taxes on tips paid to service industry workers -- weeks after Trump announced a similar policy.</p>

<p>She has said she will take on "price gouging" by corporations to tackle high prices -- one of her main weak spots against Republican Trump -- but her plans on that front remain vague.</p>

<h2>Environmental flip-flops</h2>

<p>Harris has not set out a detailed environmental policy except on one key area: fracking.</p>

<p>She has vowed not to ban the practice, which uses high-pressure water to extract oil and gas -- despite previously saying that she was opposed to it.</p>

<p>In her first and only on-screen interview since becoming the Democratic candidate, she told CNN that her "values have not changed" even if her position had.</p>

<p>Harris has, according to the Axios news site, also backtracked on her opposition to plastic straws.</p>

<p>As vice president, she has strongly backed Biden's green energy transition under the so-called "Inflation Reduction Act."</p>

<h2>Border 'consequences'</h2>

<p>Illegal migration over the US-Mexican border is one of the most sensitive issues in the campaign.</p>

<p>Harris said in her CNN interview there would be "consequences" for people crossing illegally.</p>

<p>She supported Biden's bid to toughen migration policy and has backed investing in the border "wall" that Trump called for -- despite her criticizing it in the past.</p>

<p>Biden's proposals, however, have never made it through a divided Congress, with Republicans blocking them to cause Democrats political damage.</p>

<h2>Firm on abortion</h2>

<p>Harris's position on abortion, another key election issue, is not in doubt.</p>

<p>She has repeatedly criticized Trump for bragging that he enabled the US Supreme Court to overturn the federal right to terminate pregnancies.</p>

<p>Harris has said that if elected she would push to enshrine protections for abortion in US law.</p>

<h2>Gaza quagmire</h2>

<p>Harris has been more vocal than Biden on the issue of civilians killed by Israel in the war in Gaza, leading to speculation that she might take a tougher line with the US ally.</p>

<p>But during her CNN interview she said she would not halt arms deliveries to Israel, despite calls among Democrats and Arab American voters to do so, and pledged to help Israel defend itself.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/425dmocs_kamala-harris-reuters_625x300_30_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/eu-top-court-triumphs-in-crackdown-on-apples-tax-deal-googles-practices-6532561]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[EU Top Court Triumphs In Crackdown On Apple's Tax Deal, Google's Practices]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/eu-top-court-triumphs-in-crackdown-on-apples-tax-deal-googles-practices-6532561]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Sep 2024 15:23:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The EU's top court on Tuesday delivered two major victories in the bloc's battle against tech giants by ruling against Apple and Google in separate legal sagas with billions of euros at play.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The EU's top court on Tuesday delivered two major victories in the bloc's battle against tech giants by ruling against Apple and Google in separate legal sagas with billions of euros at play.</p>

<p>The decisions give a boost to the bloc's outgoing competition chief, Margrethe Vestager, who had suffered a series of setbacks in EU courts against her decisions.</p>

<p>Concluding a long-running legal battle, the European Court of Justice ruled that the iPhone maker must pay 13 billion euros ($14.3 billion) in back-taxes to Ireland.</p>

<p>"The Court of Justice gives final judgment in the matter and confirms the European Commission's 2016 decision: Ireland granted Apple unlawful aid which Ireland is required to recover," the court said in a statement.</p>

<p>Minutes later, the court also upheld a 2.4-billion-euro fine against Google, one of a string of high-profile EU competition cases targeting the tech giant.</p>

<p>The court dismissed an appeal by Google and its parent company Alphabet against the fine, slapped on the search engine in 2017 for abusing its dominant position by favouring its own comparison shopping service.</p>

<p>Apple and Google said they were "disappointed" by the decisions.</p>

<h3><strong>Sweetheart tax arrangements</strong></h3>

<p>One of the most bitter legal battles between the European Commission and big tech, the Apple case dates back to 2016 when the EU's executive arm claimed Ireland allowed the iPhone maker to avoid billions of euros in taxes.</p>

<p>By the commission's calculations, Dublin allowed Apple to pay a tax rate of one percent of its European profits in 2003 which then dropped to 0.005 percent by 2014.</p>

<p>It was one of several investigations over the previous decade into sweetheart tax arrangements between major companies and several EU countries.</p>

<p>But Apple on Tuesday said there was no "special deal"</p>

<p>"We always pay all the taxes we owe wherever we operate and there has never been a special deal," the company said in a statement.</p>

<p>"The European Commission is trying to retroactively change the rules and ignore that, as required by international tax law, our income was already subject to taxes in the US," it added.</p>

<p>The decision is a blow for Apple as the iPhone maker had gained the upper hand in the Ireland case in 2020, when the EU's General Court annulled the order for it to pay the taxes owed.</p>

<p>Following an appeal by Brussels, the legal adviser of the higher European Court of Justice in November last year recommended scrapping that decision, saying it was peppered with legal errors.</p>

<p>But the top court, which could have sent the case back to the lower court, decided to rule that Apple should pay the back-taxes.</p>

<p>The decisions will offer relief for Brussels which has faced difficulty defending its tax enforcement moves in recent years, with previous cases lost against Amazon and Starbucks.</p>

<p>"This ruling exposes EU tax havens' love affair with multinationals. It delivers long-overdue justice after over a decade of Ireland standing by and allowing Apple to dodge taxes," said Chiara Putaturo at EU tax expert at anti-poverty organisation.</p>

<h3><strong>Google's vice tightening</strong></h3>

<p>The EU fine against Google was one of several record penalties imposed for violating EU competition rules, totalling around eight billion euros between 2017 and 2019.</p>

<p>"We are disappointed with the decision of the court," Google said. "We made changes back in 2017 to comply with the European Commission's decision."</p>

<p>Google faces yet another test next week when the top EU court will decide on the smallest of those fines, worth around 1.49 billion euros.</p>

<p>Legal headaches for Google are mounting across the Atlantic as well.</p>

<p>A trial began on Monday in the United States where the government accuses Google of dominating online advertising and stifling competition.</p>

<p>It comes after a US judge ruled last month that Google maintained a monopoly with its search engine.</p>

<p>Google's so-called ad tech -- the system that decides which online adverts people see and how much they cost -- is an area of particular concern for regulators worldwide.</p>

<p>Brussels in a preliminary finding last year accused Google of abusing its dominance of the online ad market and recommended the US company sell part of its ad services to ensure fair competition. Google had the right to respond and the probe remains open.</p>

<p>Separately, Britain's competition watchdog on Friday concluded Google employs "anti-competitive practices" with regards to online advertising after a two-year investigation.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/51f7esdg_apple-logo_625x300_10_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Apple and Google said they were "disappointed" by the decisions.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/spacex-launches-4-member-civilian-crew-polaris-dawn-mission-for-first-privately-funded-spacewalk-6532475]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[SpaceX Launches 4-Member Civilian Crew For First Privately-funded Spacewalk]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/spacex-launches-4-member-civilian-crew-polaris-dawn-mission-for-first-privately-funded-spacewalk-6532475]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Sep 2024 15:11:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[SpaceX launched its daring Polaris Dawn mission on Tuesday, a multiday orbital expedition carrying a four-member civilian crew for the first spacewalk by non-professional astronauts.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>SpaceX launched its daring Polaris Dawn mission on Tuesday, a multiday orbital expedition carrying a four-member civilian crew for the first spacewalk by non-professional astronauts.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Watch live as Falcon 9 launches the <a href="https://twitter.com/PolarisProgram?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@PolarisProgram</a>'s Polaris Dawn crew on a multi-day mission orbiting Earth <a href="https://t.co/u1KqQx5AFr">https://t.co/u1KqQx5AFr</a></p>
— SpaceX (@SpaceX) <a href="https://twitter.com/SpaceX/status/1833358277805039800?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 10, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>"Liftoff of Polaris Dawn!" SpaceX said on X, alongside a photo of the rocket as it took off.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/97jehl5o_spacex_625x300_10_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/south-korea-summit-announces-blueprint-for-using-ai-in-the-military-6532240]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[South Korea Summit Announces 'Blueprint' For Using AI In The Military]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/south-korea-summit-announces-blueprint-for-using-ai-in-the-military-6532240]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Sep 2024 14:42:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Among the details added in the document was the need to prevent AI from being used to proliferate weapons of mass destruction (WMD)]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A global summit in South Korea on Tuesday announced a "blueprint for action" to govern responsible use of artificial intelligence (AI) in the military, with more practical guidelines than a similar document last year, but still legally non-binding.</p>

<p>It was not immediately clear how many of the 96 nations that sent government representatives to the summit, including the United States and China, are endorsing the document.</p>

<p>The Responsible AI in the Military Domain (REAIM) summit in Seoul, the second of its kind, follows one held in Amsterdam last year. At that time, around 60 nations endorsed a modest "call to action" without legal commitment.</p>

<p>Government representatives speaking at a roundtable on Tuesday said this year's "blueprint" was more action-oriented.</p>

<p>This is in keeping with advances in discussions about AI risk, and developments in military use of AI such as Ukraine's rollout of AI-enabled drones.</p>

<p>"We are making further concrete steps," Netherlands Defence Minister Ruben Brekelmans told Reuters. "Last year...was more about creating shared understanding, now we are getting more towards action."</p>

<p>This includes laying out what kind of risk assessments should be made, important conditions such as human control, and how confidence-building measures can be taken in order to manage those risks, he said.</p>

<p>Among the details added in the document was the need to prevent AI from being used to proliferate weapons of mass destruction (WMD) by actors including terrorist groups, and the importance of maintaining human control and involvement in nuclear weapons employment.</p>

<p>South Korean officials said the document covers much of the same ground as principles laid out elsewhere, such as the U.S. government's declaration on responsible use of AI in the military launched last year.</p>

<p>But the Seoul summit - co-hosted by the Netherlands, Singapore, Kenya and the United Kingdom - aims to ensure ongoing multi-stakeholder discussions not dominated by a single nation or entity.</p>

<p>The venue and timing for the next summit is still being discussed, officials said.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/rtdo9p8g_ai-korea-defense-summit_625x300_10_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The conference was held in Amsterdam last year, where 60 nations endorsed a modest "call to action"]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/vietnam-typhoon-yagi-video-phong-chau-bridge-collapses-vehicles-plunge-into-river-6531982]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Video: Bridge Collapses In Typhoon-Hit Vietnam, Vehicles Plunge Into River]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/vietnam-typhoon-yagi-video-phong-chau-bridge-collapses-vehicles-plunge-into-river-6531982]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Sep 2024 14:28:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A bridge in northern Vietnam's Phu Tho province collapsed on Monday morning as the region faced the devastating impact of typhoon Yagi.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">A bridge in northern Vietnam's Phu Tho province collapsed on Monday morning as the region faced the devastating impact of typhoon Yagi. At least 10 vehicles, including motorbikes and cars, plunged into the Red River after the collapse of the 375-metre-long Phong Chau Bridge, local media reported.&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">WARNING - disturbing footage.<br />
In Vietnam, at least 13 people fell into the Hồng (Red) River after part of Phong Châu Bridge in Phú Thọ was swept away by floodwaters. About 10 vehicles and two motorbikes fell in. Rescue efforts are hindered by fast currents following Typhoon… <a href="https://t.co/TUZSnL5EIe">pic.twitter.com/TUZSnL5EIe</a></p>
— Volcaholic ? (@volcaholic1) <a href="https://twitter.com/volcaholic1/status/1833075237623132300?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 9, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p dir="ltr">Authorities have confirmed that 13 people are missing following the incident, though Deputy Prime Minister&nbsp;Ho Duc Phoc&nbsp;has said it is unclear if there have been any casualties. Rescue operations are ongoing, with part of the bridge still standing. Efforts are being made to construct a pontoon bridge to restore access to the area.&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr"><strong>Read |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/apophis-asteroid-isros-newest-headache-how-to-ward-off-egyptian-god-of-chaos-6530873">Large Asteroid Hurtles Towards Earth, ISRO Warns Of "Worst Case Scenario"</a></p>

<p dir="ltr">The bridge collapse comes as Vietnam continues to reel from the effects of typhoon Yagi, the most powerful storm to hit the region in decades. The storm, which made landfall on Saturday, has killed at least 64, with severe flooding and landslides causing widespread damage in northern provinces.</p>

<p dir="ltr">In addition to the bridge collapse, a passenger bus carrying 20 people was swept away by a landslide in Cao Bang province. Rescue teams have also been hampered by blocked roads and ongoing heavy rains.&nbsp;</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/c2jce6kg_vietnam-bridge-afp_625x300_10_September_24.jpeg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p dir="ltr">Prime Minister Pham Minh Chinh has announced emergency aid packages and instructed the military to prioritise rescue and recovery efforts. Typhoon Yagi has also caused significant disruption to northern Vietnam's industrial hubs, with numerous factories experiencing power outages and severe damage.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Millions of households and businesses lost power, and telecommunications were cut off in many areas. Over 5.7 million customers were left without electricity, with more than 75 per cent of power restored by Monday.</p>

<p dir="ltr"><strong>Read |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/samsung-takes-jab-at-apples-iphone-16-let-us-know-when-it-folds-6531622">Samsung Takes Jab At Apple's iPhone 16: "Let Us Know When It Folds"</a></p>

<p dir="ltr">Industrial zones in Haiphong, a city with a population of two million, suffered extensive damage. Roofs of factories were torn off, and workers struggled to salvage equipment as heavy rains flooded production plants. Factories of South Korean conglomerate LG Electronics in Haiphong experienced significant damage, although no casualties were reported among employees.&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">The Vietnam Meteorological Agency has warned of continued risks of flooding and landslides, with rainfall in northern regions ranging between 208 and 433 mm in the past 48 hours.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/2t4cvlrg_vietnam-bridge-afp_625x300_10_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Authorities have confirmed that 13 people are missing following the bridge collapse.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-south-korea-school-students-teachers-battle-deepfake-porn-crisis-6531842]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[In South Korea, School Students, Teachers Battle Deepfake Porn Crisis]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-south-korea-school-students-teachers-battle-deepfake-porn-crisis-6531842]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Sep 2024 13:56:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[After South Korean authorities uncovered a sprawling network of AI deepfake porn Telegram chatrooms targeting schools and universities, teenage activist Bang Seo-yoon began collecting testimony of abuse from victims.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After South Korean authorities uncovered a sprawling network of AI deepfake porn Telegram chatrooms targeting schools and universities, teenage activist Bang Seo-yoon began collecting testimony of abuse from victims.</p>

<p>Many of the cases she documented followed the same pattern: schoolboys steal innocuous selfies from private Instagram accounts and create explicit images to share in the chat rooms, specifically to humiliate female classmates -- or even teachers.</p>

<p>Super-wired South Korea, with the world's fastest average internet speeds, has long battled sexual cyber violence, but experts say a toxic combination of Telegram, AI tech, and lax laws has supercharged the issue -- and it is tearing through the country's schools.</p>

<p>"It's not just the harm caused by the deepfake itself, but the spread of those videos among acquaintances that is even more humiliating and painful," Bang, 18, told AFP.</p>

<p>She has received thousands of reports from devastated victims since authorities in August found the first such Telegram chatrooms, typically set up within a school or university to prey on female students and staff.</p>

<p>Most perpetrators are teens, police say.</p>

<p>Deepfake prevalence is increasing exponentially globally, industry data shows, up 500 percent on year in 2023, cybersecurity startup Security Hero estimates, with 99 percent of victims women -- typically famous singers and actresses.</p>

<p>But while celebrities have powerful backers to protect them -- the K-pop agency behind girlband NewJeans recently took legal action against deepfake porn -- many ordinary victims are struggling to get justice, activists say.</p>

<h2>'Live in fear'</h2>

<p>Prosecution rates are woeful: between 2021 and July this year, 793 deepfake crimes were reported but only 16 people were arrested and prosecuted, according to police data obtained by a lawmaker.</p>

<p>After news of the chat rooms spread, complaints surged, with 118 cases reported in just five days in late August, and seven people arrested amid a police crackdown.</p>

<p>But six out of seven alleged perpetrators were teenagers, police say, which complicates prosecutions as South Korean courts rarely issue arrest warrants for minors.</p>

<p>The chatrooms, multiple of which AFP attempted to join before being removed by moderators, have lewd names such as "the lonely masturbator" and rules requiring members to post photos of women they wish to see "punished".</p>

<p>Victims find themselves "sexually insulted and mocked by their classmates in online spaces", Kang Myeong-suk, head of victim support at the Women's Human Rights Institute of Korea told AFP.</p>

<p>"But the perpetrators often face no consequences," she said, adding that victims now "live in fear of where their manipulated images might be distributed by those around them".</p>

<p>"Some online comments say the victims should 'get over it' as these deepfake images are not even real," Kang said.</p>

<p>"But just because manipulated images aren't real doesn't mean the pain the victims endure is any less genuine."</p>

<h2>Victim blaming</h2>

<p>While overall crime rates in South Korea are generally low, the country has long suffered from an epidemic of spy-cam crimes, which led to major protests in 2018 inspired by the global #MeToo movement, eventually forcing lawmakers to strengthen laws.</p>

<p>Even so "the penalties issued are often trivial, like fines or probation, which are disproportionate to the gravity of the offenses", professor Yoon Kim Ji-young told AFP.</p>

<p>There have also been Telegram porn scandals before, most notably in 2020 when a group blackmailing women and girls to make sexual content for paid chatrooms was uncovered. The ringleader was jailed.</p>

<p>But things have not improved.</p>

<p>President Yoon Suk Yeol's dismissive views on feminism -- which he has blamed for the country's low birthrate -- have signalled to men it is "okay to be hostile or discriminatory towards women", Yoon Kim said.</p>

<p>South Korean police blame low prosecution rates on Telegram, which is famed for its reluctance to cooperate with authorities. Its founder was recently arrested in France for failing to curb illegal content on the app.</p>

<p>But one victim of a 2021 deepfake porn incident told AFP that this was no excuse -- many victims manage to identify their attackers themselves simply by determined sleuthing.</p>

<p>The victim, who requested anonymity, said it had been a "huge trauma" to bring her assailant to justice after she was attacked in 2021 with a barrage of Telegram messages containing deepfake images showing her being sexually assaulted.</p>

<p>Her attacker was a fellow student at the prestigious Seoul National University, who she had rarely interacted with but always thought was "gentle".</p>

<p>"It was hard to accept," she said, adding police required her to collect all the evidence herself, then she had to lobby hard for a trial, which is now ongoing.</p>

<p>"The world I thought I knew completely collapsed," she said in a letter she plans to submit to the court on September 26.</p>

<p>"No one should be treated as an object or used as a means to compensate for the inferiority complexes of individuals like the defendant, simply because they are women."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/euug6la8_south-korea-deepfake_625x300_10_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/lockheed-martin-tata-to-expand-c-130j-super-hercules-opportunities-in-india-6531832]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Lockheed Martin, Tata To Expand C-130J Super Hercules Opportunities In India]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/lockheed-martin-tata-to-expand-c-130j-super-hercules-opportunities-in-india-6531832]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Sep 2024 13:52:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US Defence major Lockheed Martin and Tata Advanced Systems Ltd on Tuesday announced a teaming agreement to expand on their engagement through the C-130J Super Hercules tactical airlifter project.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US Defence major Lockheed Martin and Tata Advanced Systems Ltd on Tuesday announced a teaming agreement to expand on their engagement through the C-130J Super Hercules tactical airlifter project.</p>

<p>The announcement, being seen as a significant step in enhancing India's defence and aerospace capabilities, came weeks after Defence Minister Rajnath Singh travelled to the US during which both sides vowed to further boost overall defence ties.</p>

<p>This agreement provides a framework for collaboration on future potential business opportunities that include establishing a Maintenance, Repair and Overhaul (MRO) facility in India to support the Indian Air Force's (IAF) existing fleet of 12 C-130Js as well as other global Super Hercules fleets.</p>

<p>The pact will also provide for expanding C-130J manufacturing and assembly in India to produce aircraft for the IAF's Medium Transport Aircraft (MTA) programme, subject to US and Indian government approvals, the Tata Advanced Systems said.</p>

<p>The IAF is actively seeking to acquire up to 80 medium transport aircraft and issued a request for information (RFI) or initial tender last year. Lockheed Martin responded to the RFI as the C-130J-30 Super Hercules is ideally suited to meet the requirements.</p>

<p>Lockheed Martin will continue to build C-130Js for the US government and other global operators at the existing Super Hercules production facility in Marietta, Georgia in the US.</p>

<p>Lockheed Martin will establish additional production and assembly capacity in India, if awarded the MTA contract.</p>

<p>"Collaborating with Lockheed Martin on the C-130J platform proposition for IAF's MTA project is a milestone for Tata Advanced Systems," Sukaran Singh, Chief Executive Officer and Managing Director of Tata Advanced Systems, said.</p>

<p>"The current announcement is also significant as it marks the entry of Tata Advanced Systems into the defence MRO space in India for large aircraft platforms," he said.</p>

<p>Mr Singh said the pact will also help in having a deeper relationship between the two companies adding to the aerostructure work by Tata Advanced Systems for Lockheed Martin platforms.</p>

<p>The C-130J Super Hercules is a tactical airlift aircraft providing a unique mix of versatility and performance to complete any mission.</p>

<p>It is the current variant of the C-130 Hercules and is the airlifter of choice for 26 operators in 22 nations.</p>

<p>The IAF operates a fleet of 12 C-130Js.</p>

<p>"The C-130J is known as the world's workhorse, not just for its large global presence, but also for its international supply chain partners, including the single source provider of empennages -- Tata Lockheed Martin Aerostructures Limited in Hyderabad," Rod McLean, Vice President and General Manager of the Air Mobility and Maritime Missions line of business at Lockheed Martin, said.</p>

<p>"This teaming agreement between Lockheed Martin and Tata Advanced Systems further demonstrates Lockheed Martin's commitment to a self-reliant India and the degree of confidence that exists in our relationships with our partners in India and the Indian industry at large," he said.</p>

<p>Lockheed Martin and Tata Advanced Systems Ltd have a long-standing partnership through the Tata Lockheed Martin Aerostructures Ltd (TLMAL) joint venture.</p>

<p>Established in 2010, TLMAL focuses on complementing India's "Make in India" objectives and has the distinction of being the single global source of C-130J empennage assemblies included on all new Super Hercules aircraft produced in the US.</p>

<p>To date, TLMAL has manufactured more than 220 C-130J empennages, the Tata Advance Systems said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-10/spdeejb8_-c130j-super-hercules-aircraft_625x300_02_October_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The IAF operates a fleet of 12 C-130Js]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/rahul-gandhi-in-us-says-will-think-of-scrapping-of-reservations-when-india-is-fair-6531550]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Will Think Of Scrapping Of Reservations When India Is Fair": Rahul Gandhi]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/rahul-gandhi-in-us-says-will-think-of-scrapping-of-reservations-when-india-is-fair-6531550]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Sep 2024 13:43:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Congress leader Rahul Gandhi raised the caste census issue during his US visit and said that the party will call for the scrapping of reservations only when "India is a fair place".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Congress leader Rahul Gandhi raised the caste census issue during his US visit and said that the party will call for the scrapping of reservations only when "India is a fair place".</p>

<p>During an interaction with the students and the faculty of Georgetown University in Washington DC, Mr Gandhi said, "The elephant in the room is that 90 per cent of India -- OBCs, Dalits and Adivasis don't play the game...Caste census is a simple exercise to know how the lower castes, backward castes and Dalits are integrated into the system...Out of the top 200 businesses in India, there is almost no ownership of 90 per cent of the population of India. In the highest courts of the country, there is almost no participation of 90 per cent of India. In media, there is zero participation of lower castes, OBCs, Dalits..."</p>

<p>"...We want to understand what their social and financial position looks like...We also want to look at the Indian institutions to have a sense of India's participation in these institutions.."</p>

<p>The Congress MP emphasised the need for the caste census, which he said has three components -- institutional survey, socio-economic survey, and census.</p>

<p>"Caste Census is a simple way of saying: we got independence in 1947, let's see how the lower castes, backward castes, and Dalits have integrated into the system. What is their actual participation? ... A socio-economic survey is to understand the socio-economic position of these castes and the poor...We also want to understand and examine India's institutions -- media, healthcare, education -- the ownership, the structure that delivers these services, and India's participation in these institutions," Gandhi said.</p>

<p>When a student asked him whether there were other better ways to strengthen institutions at the grassroots level than caste-based reservation, the Congress leader presented her with numbers of the participation of various castes in the governance. He said..."Let's look at the numbers .. if you look at the Indian government... there are 78 bureaucrats who run the govt.. secretaries to the GOI .. they make financial decisions .. if you add up Dalits, OBCs, and tribals they come to 73 per cent.. Out of 78 people, there is one tribal...there are three Dalits, three OBCs and a minority .. 90 per cent of India has less than one per cent...."</p>

<p>He further said, "We will think of scrapping of reservations when India is a fair place and India is not a fair place ... that way it is a problem.. because there are many people who come from the upper castes who say look what have we done wrong .. why we are being punished.. and so then you think of increasing dramatically the supply of some of these things, you think of decentralisation power, you think of involving many more in the governance..."</p>

<p>The Congress leader accused the Indian government of not having adequate representation of the bureaucrats in the government.</p>

<p>Making a strong pitch for the caste census in the US, Rahul Gandhi said, " The caste census is now an unstoppable idea. The critical question of whether 90 per cent of our population is meaningfully represented in India's institutional structure -- economy, government, education -- demands an answer. At its core, this is an issue of fairness and justice. Anything less than a comprehensive caste census along with an economic and institutional survey is unacceptable."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/epcuqhdg_rahul-gandhi-twitter-ani_625x300_10_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Rahul Gandhi said caste census is now an unstoppable idea.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukraine-launches-140-drones-at-russia-overnight-1-killed-near-moscow-6531650]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ukraine Launches 140 Drones At Russia Overnight, 1 Killed Near Moscow]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukraine-launches-140-drones-at-russia-overnight-1-killed-near-moscow-6531650]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Sep 2024 13:28:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ukraine unleashed more than 140 drones on Russia overnight, officials said Tuesday, killing a woman near Moscow, grounding flights and setting off air defences in several parts of the country.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ukraine unleashed more than 140 drones on Russia overnight, officials said Tuesday, killing a woman near Moscow, grounding flights and setting off air defences in several parts of the country.</p>

<p>Russia's ministry of defence said in a statement it had shot down 144 Ukrainian drones overnight -- "72 UAVs over Bryansk region, 20 over Moscow region, 14 over Kursk region, 13 over Tula region", and 25 more over five other parts of the country.</p>

<p>Moscow regional governor Andrey Vorobyov said in a Telegram post that a 46-year-old woman had been killed and several people wounded in the strikes.</p>

<p>But an earlier statement in which he reported the death of a 9-year-old child was still "not confirmed", he added.</p>

<p>As a result of the attack, four airports servicing Moscow -- including major hubs Domodedovo and Sheremetyevo -- had cancelled or delayed flights on Tuesday morning, according to state media.</p>

<p>In Bryansk, which borders Ukraine, "the enemy carried out a massive terrorist attack", regional Governor Aleksandr Bogomaz said on Telegram, adding "there were no casualties or damage, all attacks were repelled".</p>

<p>Ukraine and Russia routinely carry out nighttime drone attacks on each other's territory.</p>

<h2>Advances in east</h2>

<p>The latest wave of drones came as Moscow continued to claim incremental gains in Ukraine's east more than 30 months into its offensive, and as Kyiv's forces pressed their incursion into Russia's region of Kursk.</p>

<p>Russia on Monday said its forces had captured another Ukrainian village, Memryk, seen as a stepping stone to the Kyiv-held logistics hub of Pokrovsk some 20 kilometres (12 miles) away.</p>

<p>Pokrovsk lies on the intersection of a key road that supplies Ukrainian troops and towns across the eastern front and has long been a target for Moscow's army.</p>

<p>Kyiv had launched its Kursk offensive on August 6 aiming to force Russia to redeploy troops pressing forward in the east, but Moscow has appeared to intensify its attacks there.</p>

<p>Moscow has also kept up its own aerial attacks on Ukraine in recent weeks, including on key energy infrastructure ahead of winter.</p>

<p>Three Russian drones were shot down above Ukraine's Sumy overnight, the regional military administration said early Tuesday, while air defences were also activated around Kyiv.</p>

<p>The military administration in the capital later said there were "no consequences after the Russian UAV attack".</p>

<p>United Nations human rights chief Volker Turk condemned Russian attacks on Ukraine's energy facilities on Monday.</p>

<p>Ukraine's population was enduring "ongoing attacks by the Russian Federation striking civilian facilities like hospitals, schools and supermarkets, and repeated waves of targeting of energy infrastructure", Turk told the UN Human Rights Council.</p>

<p>"I fear for Ukrainians this coming winter," he said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/5apj0mi_ukraine-drone-attack_625x300_10_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Ukraine and Russia routinely carry out nighttime drone attacks on each other's territory.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/samsung-takes-jab-at-apples-iphone-16-let-us-know-when-it-folds-6531622]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Samsung Takes Jab At Apple's iPhone 16: "Let Us Know When It Folds"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/samsung-takes-jab-at-apples-iphone-16-let-us-know-when-it-folds-6531622]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Sep 2024 13:26:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Samsung is back at its favourite pastime online, taking a jibe at its rival Apple. This time the target is Apple's newly released iPhone 16.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">Samsung is back at its favourite pastime online, taking a jibe at its rival Apple. This time the target is Apple's newly released iPhone 16.&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">At Apple's grand event in Cupertino, California, the tech giant launched its latest iPhone 16 series. The much-anticipated launch showcased four new models – the iPhone 16, iPhone 16 Plus, iPhone 16 Pro and iPhone 16 Pro Max – along with new Apple Watch models and updated AirPods. However, as the world tuned in to Apple's latest innovations, their long-standing rival, Samsung, had something cheeky to say.</p>

<p dir="ltr">On their official X account, Samsung poked fun at Apple by reposting a 2022 upload that read, “Let us know when it folds.” This jab was aimed at Apple's continued absence from the foldable phone market, a segment where Samsung has made significant strides with its Galaxy Z Fold5. “Still waiting......” read the post.&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Still waiting...... <a href="https://t.co/s6SFaLTk3b">https://t.co/s6SFaLTk3b</a></p>
— Samsung Mobile US (@SamsungMobileUS) <a href="https://twitter.com/SamsungMobileUS/status/1833222647334789442?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 9, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p dir="ltr">People commented with fun reactions. “It can easily fold...once,” said a user.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">It can easily fold...<br />
<br />
...once.</p>
— TechWhirl Ultimate (@TechWhirlUlt) <a href="https://twitter.com/TechWhirlUlt/status/1833223053897048185?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 9, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p dir="ltr">Another wrote, “My favorite thing about Apple users is how Android is always ~10 years ahead but when they finally get the upgrades they try to rub it in everyone's faces.”</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">My favorite thing about Apple users is how Android is always ~10 years ahead but when they finally get the upgrades they try to rub it in everyone's faces</p>
— 4KT WHO YOU HATE (@royal_bobby24) <a href="https://twitter.com/royal_bobby24/status/1833278102463451249?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 9, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p dir="ltr">“It might be able to fold, question is will it be usable after?” read another comment.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">It might be able to fold, question is will it be usable after?</p>
— Zollz (@zollz) <a href="https://twitter.com/zollz/status/1833241361954512915?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 9, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p dir="ltr">A few said that Apple had “stopped innovating years ago.”</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">They stopped innovating years ago ????‍♂️</p>
— Nicholas Irvine (@_NicholasIrvine) <a href="https://twitter.com/_NicholasIrvine/status/1833234689899073816?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 9, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p dir="ltr">Meanwhile, Samsung didn't stop at foldable phones. In another tweet, the Korean tech giant wrote, "You know... we may have set your AI expectations too high." This tweet was a dig at Apple's new ‘Apple Intelligence', an AI feature introduced with the iPhone 16 series.&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">You know... we may have set your AI expectations too high. ????</p>
— Samsung Mobile US (@SamsungMobileUS) <a href="https://twitter.com/SamsungMobileUS/status/1833218967768330348?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 9, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p dir="ltr">This isn't the first time Samsung has taken a swipe at Apple. Earlier, the tech giant mocked Apple's iPad Pro ad. The ad from Apple stirred controversy after showing a hydraulic press crushing various artistic tools, which many interpreted as a metaphor for creativity being suppressed by technology.&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">In response, Samsung released a 43-second spot titled ‘Creativity Cannot Be Crushed'. The ad opened with a woman walking through the ruins left behind by Apple's hydraulic press, finding a tattered guitar and playing it while reading music notes on a Galaxy Tab S9 Ultra. Samsung's message: “We would never crush creativity.”&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/kg8d7tdg_iphone-16_625x300_10_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/apple-iphone-16-launch-met-with-hilarious-memes-online-6531222]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Same Product, Different Year": Internet Reacts To Apple iPhone 16 Launch]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/apple-iphone-16-launch-met-with-hilarious-memes-online-6531222]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Sep 2024 13:13:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Apple officially launched the highly anticipated iPhone 16 series at the Glowtime Event 2024, held at its Cupertino Park headquarters in California on Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Apple officially launched the highly anticipated iPhone 16 series at the Glowtime Event 2024, held at its Cupertino Park headquarters in California on Monday. The new phone was met with a flurry of memes and jokes on social media, with users noting the similarities between the iPhone 16 and its predecessors.</p>

<p>Many pointed out that the main change in the design was merely the repositioning of the camera, with some even recycling memes from previous years to show how little had changed.</p>

<p>Reacting to the new iPhone 16, a user wrote on X, "<em>19-20 ka Hi to Farak Hai&nbsp;(</em>There's just a slight difference)."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="hi">19-20 ka Hi to Farak Hai ????<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/iPhone16?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#iPhone16</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/iPhone16pro?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#iPhone16pro</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/iPhone%E5%A3%81%E7%B4%99?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#iPhone壁紙</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/meme?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#meme</a> <a href="https://t.co/VzqmU2H4Iy">pic.twitter.com/VzqmU2H4Iy</a></p>
— Anand Joshi (@theiconicanand) <a href="https://twitter.com/theiconicanand/status/1790644292521971974?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">May 15, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>"Apple launches iPhone 16 and the meme continues," quipped another, reacting to the new iPhone by posting a picture of the famous Spiderman meme, where multiple Spidermen point at each other in confusion.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="pt">Apple lança o iPhone 16 e o meme continua <a href="https://t.co/wtY9ljTqs0">pic.twitter.com/wtY9ljTqs0</a></p>
— Fante ???? (@manicacagoiano) <a href="https://twitter.com/manicacagoiano/status/1833275240509555182?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 9, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>This user joked, "Apple just keeps making the same products over and over again thinking their customers will keep buying them.</p>

<p>-Sent from my new iPhone 16 Pro Max."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Apple just keeps making the same products over and over again thinking their customers will keep buying them.<br />
<br />
-Sent from my new iPhone 16 Pro Max</p>
— Douglas A. Boneparth (@dougboneparth) <a href="https://twitter.com/dougboneparth/status/1833168548341879050?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 9, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>This "honest review" of the iPhone 16 featured the Japanese flag.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Honest review of <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/iPhone16?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#iPhone16</a>. <a href="https://t.co/NpH4NbiqnN">pic.twitter.com/NpH4NbiqnN</a></p>
— Akdas (@Akdas_Hayat) <a href="https://twitter.com/Akdas_Hayat/status/1833224198233506289?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 9, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Take a look at some other memes:</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">iphone 15 owners upgrading to the iphone 16 <a href="https://t.co/auDI6G4NxX">pic.twitter.com/auDI6G4NxX</a></p>
— ian bremmer (@ianbremmer) <a href="https://twitter.com/ianbremmer/status/1833233723866612017?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 9, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">apple announcing the iphone 16 <a href="https://t.co/Nptaxm4xIl">pic.twitter.com/Nptaxm4xIl</a></p>
— leon (@skyferrori) <a href="https://twitter.com/skyferrori/status/1833197577275380012?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 9, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">iPhone 15 iPhone 16 <a href="https://t.co/E0UiISysoL">pic.twitter.com/E0UiISysoL</a></p>
— Morning Brew ☕️ (@MorningBrew) <a href="https://twitter.com/MorningBrew/status/1833199925615550528?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 9, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="qme"><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/iPhone?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#iPhone</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/iPhone16?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#iPhone16</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/meme?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#meme</a> <a href="https://t.co/D8pQkMtCqJ">pic.twitter.com/D8pQkMtCqJ</a></p>
— Jamjam (@Damjam_jam) <a href="https://twitter.com/Damjam_jam/status/1833203036191395989?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 9, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Despite the impression that the new iPhones resemble their predecessors, the iPhone 16 series boasts a number of innovative features and updates.</p>

<p>Each model has a different screen size: 6.1 inches for the iPhone 16, 6.3 inches for the iPhone 16 Pro, 6.7 inches for the iPhone 16 Plus, and 6.9 inches for the iPhone 16 Pro Max.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The new A18 chip powers all models, with enhanced performance in the Pro and Pro Max versions. The iPhone 16 Pro and Pro Max have improved cameras with a new 48 MP ultra-wide-angle lens and 5x optical zoom.</p>

<p>The new iPhones have an enlarged action button and a new capture button for easier photo-taking. They also support Apple Intelligence, with exclusive features coming soon. The iPhone 16 series has improved battery life, with the Pro Max having the largest battery ever in an iPhone.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/rqtp0h0g_iphone-16-meme-_625x300_10_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nobel-peace-laureate-malala-yousafzai-unveils-new-documentary-at-toronto-film-festival-6531505]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Nobel Laureate Malala Yousafzai Unveils New Documentary At Toronto Festival]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nobel-peace-laureate-malala-yousafzai-unveils-new-documentary-at-toronto-film-festival-6531505]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Sep 2024 13:06:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Nobel peace laureate Malala Yousafzai, who unveiled her first documentary with Apple TV+ at the Toronto film festival, said Monday that its inspiring story of elderly South Korean women sea divers dovetails perfectly with her own activism.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Nobel peace laureate Malala Yousafzai, who unveiled her first documentary with Apple TV+ at the Toronto film festival, said Monday that its inspiring story of elderly South Korean women sea divers dovetails perfectly with her own activism.</p>

<p>"The Last of the Sea Women" tells the compelling story of the matriarchal haenyeo community, whose members support themselves by fishing off South Korea's Jeju island, using only wetsuits, masks, flippers, baskets and hooks.</p>

<p>The traditional community, inscribed on UNESCO's intangible cultural heritage list in 2016, has existed for centuries, but is at risk as many of the women are now in their 60s, 70s or even 80s.</p>

<p>"I was looking for stories of women... I wanted stories of their resilience. And when I heard about this project from Sue, I was like, 'This is exactly what I'm looking for'," Yousafzai told AFP in an interview with Korean-American director Sue Kim.</p>

<p>"When I look at the stories of the haenyeo, it inspires me about the possibilities and the capabilities that women have in their bodies, in their minds," said the 27-year-old Pakistani activist, who is one of the film's producers.</p>

<p>"They have inspired me in so many ways, in their activism and how they are cooperating with nature, how they have built the community."</p>

<h2>'Total badasses'</h2>

<p>In the 1960s, 30,000 women plucked everything from abalone to octopus from the sea to support their families. Today, that number has dwindled to 4,000.</p>

<p>The film shows the women speaking candidly about their difficult jobs, which involves holding their breath underwater for up to two minutes, and includes beautiful under-sea images of them at work.</p>

<p>It explores how the haenyeo are attempting to breathe new life into their culture through training and social media outreach, and how they work together to prevent overfishing.</p>

<p>It also examines the threat they believe is posed by the release into the Pacific Ocean of wastewater from Japan's stricken Fukushima nuclear power plant.</p>

<p>"I met them first when I was a child, and I was so struck by them, because they cut such a confident, bold figure," Kim, making her feature directorial debut, told AFP.</p>

<p>"They're total badasses. They're so physically agile and adept and strong, and they're advocating for the environment, and they're caring about the next generation."</p>

<p>As a teenager, Yousafzai survived a 2012 assassination attempt by the Taliban over her campaigning for education rights for girls. She was co-awarded the Nobel Peace Prize in 2014 at age 17.</p>

<p>She signed a deal with Apple TV+ in 2021 to produce content focused on women and girls and has started her own production company.</p>

<p>"Storytelling has been part of my activism, and I believe that we need to create platforms and opportunities for girls and women to reflect on the world as they see it," Yousafzai said.</p>

<p>"I hope to continue to work with these incredible female directors and storytellers to bring more stories to the screen."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/lc614nt8_malala_625x300_10_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/dubai-princess-who-dumped-husband-in-insta-post-launches-perfume-line-called-divorce-6531431]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Dubai Princess Launches 'Divorce' Perfume Months After Dumping Husband]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/dubai-princess-who-dumped-husband-in-insta-post-launches-perfume-line-called-divorce-6531431]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Sep 2024 12:57:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The fragrance, released under her brand Mahra M1, is a direct reference to her recent high-profile divorce.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sheikha Mahra Al Maktoum, the daughter of Dubai's ruler, has sparked controversy with the launch of her new perfume line, "Divorce." The fragrance, released under her brand Mahra M1, is a direct reference to her recent high-profile divorce.</p>

<p>In a social media post, the 30-year-old princess shared a teaser of the perfume, featuring a black bottle engraved with the word 'Divorce.' The accompanying video, filled with imagery of broken glass and a black panther, further emphasized the theme of separation.</p>

<p><strong>See the viral post here:</strong></p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/C_tjZBDTIrs/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C_tjZBDTIrs/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C_tjZBDTIrs/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C_tjZBDTIrs/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by @mahraxm1</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p></p>

<p>Reacting to the perfume line, a user wrote, "Do you see how Mahra is moving accordingly? Very demure, very quietly, very princessey, she is not like most of you throwing tantrums or making videos online, no, she is very classy, very reserved, very standing on business."</p>

<p>Another user wrote, "When women are done dealing with you, they are done."</p>

<p>"So creative! Your ex is burning in pain lol," the third user commented.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The launch comes just weeks after Sheikha Mahra publicly divorced her husband on Instagram, using the Islamic practice of triple talaq. Her decision to announce the divorce on social media, especially so soon after the birth of their child, has garnered significant attention worldwide.</p>

<p>"Dear Husband," the Dubai princess began. "As you are occupied with other companions, I hereby declare our divorce. I divorce you, I divorce you, and I divorce you. Take care. Your ex-wife."&nbsp;</p>

<p>Shaikha Mahra is the daughter of the Vice President and Prime Minister of the United Arab Emirates and the Ruler of Dubai. She is an advocate for women's empowerment and local designers in the UAE. She holds a degree in International Relations from a university in the UK and also has a college degree from the Mohammed bin Rashid Government Administration.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/f8dkd14g_sheikha-mahra-al-maktoum_625x300_10_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The 30-year-old princess shared a teaser of the perfume]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>