<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 04:37:04 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/lebanon-says-child-among-4-killed-as-israel-strikes-near-beirut-hospital-6843174]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Lebanon Says Child Among 4 Killed As Israel Strikes Near Beirut Hospital]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/lebanon-says-child-among-4-killed-as-israel-strikes-near-beirut-hospital-6843174]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 04:19:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Lebanon said four people including a child were killed Monday in Israeli air strikes near the country's biggest public hospital close to south Beirut, with state media reporting over a dozen raids.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lebanon said four people including a child were killed Monday in Israeli air strikes near the country's biggest public hospital close to south Beirut, with state media reporting over a dozen raids.</p>

<p>"The Israeli enemy strike near the Hariri Hospital killed, in a preliminary toll, four people, including a child, and injured 24," the health ministry said, adding it had caused "significant damage to the hospital".</p>

<p>In a separate statement, the ministry said the strike hit the entrance to the hospital, "which is still operating and receives a large number of patients".</p>

<p>It denied claims by the Israeli army that Hezbollah had stored half a billion dollars under the Sahel hospital in south Beirut.</p>

<p>Lebanon's National News Agency reported at least three Israeli strikes on the Ouzai district of south Beirut.</p>

<p>While most districts of Beirut's southern suburbs had been emptied for almost a month, the densely-packed residential area of Ouzai was still filled with people because it had never been targeted before.</p>

<p><strong>- 'No room for escape' -</strong></p>

<p>The NNA reported more than a dozen strikes on various south Beirut districts including Haret Hreik, just south of Ouzai, and Hadath.</p>

<p>Hezbollah-affiliated rescuers told AFP they were looking for survivors amid the devastation in Ouzai, adding that the evacuation order, then the strike, caused "panic among residents" who "started to run in the streets".</p>

<p>"They did not leave any room for people to escape. The strike came closely after the warning," one said.</p>

<p>A Lebanese security official told AFP that the country's national airline had to switch landing strips after Israeli strikes near Beirut's only international airport hit close to the main runway.</p>

<p>"Middle East Airlines switched the runway it was using because the main runway is close to the site of the Ouzai strike," the official said, requesting anonymity to discuss sensitive matters.</p>

<p>AFPTV footage showed plumes of smoke rising from Beirut's southern suburbs, with AFP correspondents also hearing several loud bangs before the strikes.</p>

<p>The footage also showed two strikes that caused a huge fire, with black smoke surrounding dissipating orange flames.</p>

<p>Just prior to the strikes, the Israeli military called on residents to leave parts of southern Beirut, in their latest such appeal.</p>

<p>Military spokesman Avichay Adraee posted the new call on social media indicating several locations to be evacuated, including an area close to Beirut airport.</p>

<p>"You are located near facilities and interests affiliated with Hezbollah that the IDF will work against in the near future," he wrote.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/vjsmbq1g_lebanon-airstrikes-afp_625x300_01_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[At least 24 people also injured in Israeli strike near southern Beirut hospital on Monday.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korea-sending-troops-to-ukraine-would-be-dangerous-move-us-6843063]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[North Korea Sending Troops To Ukraine Would Be "Dangerous" Move: US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korea-sending-troops-to-ukraine-would-be-dangerous-move-us-6843063]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 03:33:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United States on Monday said it would be a dangerous development for North Korea to send troops to support Russia in Ukraine, as Seoul has asserted.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United States on Monday said it would be a dangerous development for North Korea to send troops to support Russia in Ukraine, as Seoul has asserted.<br />
<br />
"We have seen reports the DPRK has sent forces and is preparing to send additional soldiers to Ukraine to fight alongside Russia," Robert Wood, US ambassador to the United Nations, told the Security Council.</p>

<p>"If true, this marks a dangerous and highly concerning development and an obvious deepening of the DPRK-Russia military relationship," Wood said, using the acronym for the North's official name.</p>

<p>"We are consulting with our allies and partners on the implications of such a dramatic move," he added.</p>

<p>Seoul's spy agency said on Friday that North Korea had decided to send a "large-scale" troop deployment to support Moscow's war in Ukraine, with 1,500 special forces already in Russia's Far East and undergoing training.</p>

<p>The agency estimated the North could send around 12,000 soldiers in total.</p>

<p>The US State Department is "not yet at a point where we're able to confirm those reports and whether they are accurate," deputy spokesman Vedant Patel said Monday.</p>

<p>France's UN envoy Nicolas de Riviere told the UN Security Council that the deployment of North Korean soldiers would constitute a further escalation.</p>

<p>He added that Pyongyang's "increasing support for the Russian war effort is very worrying."</p>

<p>The United States and its allies have already voiced concern about North Korea providing weapons to Russia, which invaded Ukraine in February 2022.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2016-09/north-korea-army-reuters_650x400_71474875874.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The agency estimated the North could send around 12,000 soldiers in total to support Russia in war.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-to-form-doha-based-ruling-committee-instead-of-appointing-new-chief-6842331]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[No New Chief, Hamas To Be Led By Ruling Committee: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-to-form-doha-based-ruling-committee-instead-of-appointing-new-chief-6842331]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:07:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Two Hamas sources said the Palestinian militant group was moving towards appointing a Doha-based ruling committee rather than a single successor to its chief Yahya Sinwar, who was killed by Israeli troops last week.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Two Hamas sources said the Palestinian operator group was moving towards appointing a Doha-based ruling committee rather than a single successor to its chief Yahya Sinwar, who was killed by Israeli troops last week.</p>

<p>"The Hamas leadership's approach is not to appoint a successor to the late chief, the martyr Yahya Sinwar, until their next elections" scheduled for March "if conditions permit", a well-informed source from the group told AFP.</p>

<p>A five-member committee that was formed in August following the assassination of political chief Ismail Haniyeh in Tehran "will take over the leadership of the group", the source added.</p>

<p>The committee was formed to facilitate decision-making in view of the difficulty of communicating with Sinwar in Gaza before his death.</p>

<p>Sinwar was named the Gaza chief of the terrorist group in 2017, before rising to become the overall leader of Hamas after Haniyeh was assassinated in July.</p>

<p>The source said the committee is made up of representatives of the two Palestinian territories and the community, namely Khalil al-Hayya for Gaza, Zaher Jabarin for the West Bank and Khaled Meshaal for Palestinians abroad.</p>

<p>It also includes the head of Hamas's Shura advisory council Mohammed Darwish and the secretary of the political bureau, who is never identified for security reasons.</p>

<p>All current members of the committee are based in Qatar.</p>

<p>According to the source, the committee is tasked with "governing the movement during the war and exceptional circumstances, as well as its future plans".</p>

<p>He added that it is authorised to "make strategic decisions".</p>

<p>Another source from the group said that the Hamas leadership discussed a proposal that was made "internally" to appoint a political chief without announcing their name.</p>

<p>But, the source added, the leaders preferred to rule through the committee.</p>

<p>Sinwar was killed by Israeli troops in southern Gaza on Wednesday, more than a year into the devastating war in the territory sparked by Hamas's October 7 attack.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/gk9jnhcg_hamas_625x300_19_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hamas Chief was killed by Israeli troops in southern Gaza on Wednesday. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-strikes-hezbollah-bunker-containing-millions-in-cash-and-gold-6842285]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Strikes Hezbollah Bunker Containing "Millions" In Cash, Gold]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-strikes-hezbollah-bunker-containing-millions-in-cash-and-gold-6842285]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 23:58:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Israeli army on Monday said it hit a Hezbollah bunker holding tens of millions of dollars worth of cash and gold during strikes aimed at the group's financial network.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Israeli army on Monday said it hit a Hezbollah bunker holding tens of millions of dollars worth of cash and gold during strikes aimed at the group's financial network.</p>

<p>"The Israeli Air Force carried out a series of precise strikes on these Hezbollah financial strongholds," said military spokesman Rear Admiral Daniel Hagari. "One of our main targets last night was an underground vault with millions of dollars in cash and gold. The money was being used to finance Hezbollah's attacks on Israel."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2016-09/israel-air-force_650x400_51472816126.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel air force's main target was underground vaults with cash and gold. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-to-limit-some-trade-transactions-to-block-data-access-by-russia-china-6842137]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US To Limit Some Trade Transactions To Block Data Access By Russia, China]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-to-limit-some-trade-transactions-to-block-data-access-by-russia-china-6842137]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 23:31:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The US Justice Department on Monday proposed new rules to protect federal government data or Americans' bulk personal data from getting into the hands of countries like China, Iran and Russia by placing new limits on certain business transactions.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The US Justice Department on Monday proposed new rules to protect federal government data or Americans' bulk personal data from getting into the hands of countries like China, Iran and Russia by placing new limits on certain business transactions.</p>

<p>The proposal, which was previewed in March, implements an executive order issued earlier this year by President Joe Biden which aims to keep foreign adversaries from using accessible American financial and genomic data and health data for cyber attacks, espionage and blackmail.</p>

<p>In addition to China, Russia and Iran, the rule would also apply to Venezuela, Cuba and North Korea.</p>

<p>Washington has been trying to stem the flow of American personal data to China, part of a years-long struggle over trade and technology.</p>

<p>In 2018, a US panel that reviews foreign investments for potential national security threats rejected a plan by China's Ant Financial to acquire U.S. money transfer company MoneyGram International, because of concerns over safety of data that can be used to identify US citizens.</p>

<p>The officials said transactions will be banned with data brokers who know the information will end up in "countries of concern", as will the transfer of any data on US government personnel.</p>

<p>Monday's proposal for the first time gave more specific details about the types and amounts of data that cannot be transferred, including human genomic data on over 100 Americans or personal health or financial data on over 10,000 people.</p>

<p>The proposal would also bar the transfer of precise geolocation data on over 1,000 US devices.</p>

<p>The rule would allow the Justice Department to enforce compliance both through criminal and civil penalties.</p>

<p>US officials told reporters on Monday that Chinese apps such as TikTok could run afoul of the proposal if they transferred sensitive data from US users to a Chinese parent company.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/9q90snc_us-justice-department_625x300_21_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Washington has been trying to stem the flow of American personal data to China. (Representation)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/helicopter-crash-in-houston-kills-4-including-child-destroys-radio-tower-6841978]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Helicopter Crash In Houston Kills 4, Including Child, Destroys Radio Tower]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/helicopter-crash-in-houston-kills-4-including-child-destroys-radio-tower-6841978]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 23:08:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A helicopter crash has killed four passengers, including a child, in the southern US city of Houston, authorities said, with the accident also destroying a radio transmission tower.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A helicopter crash has killed four passengers, including a child, in the southern US city of Houston, authorities said, with the accident also destroying a radio transmission tower.</p>

<p>The private aircraft "either struck a cable or actually struck at the tower", Houston police chief Noe Diaz told reporters.</p>

<p>No one on the ground was injured in the crash on Sunday, he added, and investigations to determine the cause of the accident were ongoing.</p>

<p>Television footage showed burning debris on the ground after the crash, and other videos -- apparently from CCTV cameras -- appeared to show the helicopter approaching the tower and then bursting into flame.</p>

<p>John Whitmire, the city's mayor, said the crash took place near a residential area and close to a highly flammable tank of butane.</p>

<p>"We are fortunate that it wasn't worse," he said.</p>

<p>Whitmire said firefighters had responded to the sound of a loud explosion, with a "fireball" visible in the air.</p>

<p>The helicopter had taken off from an airfield less than 18 miles (30 kilometers) from the crash site, according to authorities.</p>

<p>Houston, located in the state of Texas, is the fourth-largest city in the United States, with a population of 2.3 million.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/0ve05k4g_houston-helicopter-crash_625x300_21_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The crash took place near a residential area and close to a highly flammable tank of butane.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ndtv-world-summit-2024-why-switch-to-electric-vehicles-makes-sense-charge-zone-ceo-kartikey-hariyani-explains-6841922]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Why Switch To Electric Vehicles 'Makes Sense'? Charge Zone CEO Explains]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ndtv-world-summit-2024-why-switch-to-electric-vehicles-makes-sense-charge-zone-ceo-kartikey-hariyani-explains-6841922]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 22:59:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kartikey Hariyani, the founder and CEO of Electric vehicle (EV) charging network Charge Zone, while speaking at NDTV World Summit 2024, explained why switching to EV makes Sense.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kartikey Hariyani, the founder and CEO of Electric vehicle (EV) charging network Charge Zone, while speaking at <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/na-chain-na-araam-pm-modi-at-ndtv-world-summit-on-hard-work-6836565">NDTV World Summit 2024</a>, explained why switching to EV makes Sense.</p>

<p>"In India, the purpose of an EV or a car is for personal mobility. 80 percent of the mobility requirement of an Indian consumer is less than 51 k a day. So, with this stat, EV becomes a natural choice for adoption but it also (poses) a question whether the cost makes sense. Then as an individual consumer, you will say I don't need an EV or the payback is not really attractive," he said.</p>

<p>Mr Hariyani, however, insisted that "there is good news around".</p>

<p>"Two developments have happened in the industry so far. In the last two quarters, the cost of the battery has come down by half. The second good news is some of the OEMs (original equipment manufacturers) have initiated battery as a service which means battery and charging will effectively becomes your fuelling system. So, what you are going to buy will be a car without the battery cost, it means (it would be) equivalent to the cost of a petrol car," he said.</p>

<p>Mr Hariyani stressed that one has to think through carefully in terms of how the recharging networks will be planned.</p>

<p>"For each of the EV segments, the industry players have started investing into this. Six years ago, standards got built into this. Later on, local ecosystem played a big part. Localisation did happen in terms of semiconductors as well as power electronics. Today we are ready with the chargers, localised both for three wheelers and four wheelers," he said.</p>

<p>He also said that even though fast-charging is a key for adoption of EVs but it's not just about cars but also buses and trucks.</p>

<p>"For a charging company like us, when we started off in 2019, there were green sprouts around electric cars coming into the market, then electric buses started coming. And today we see the launch of electric trucks. As a priority, I will enable inter-city mobility. In other words, charging infra on highways is our priority number one. We have electrified 33,000 kms of highways in India. Fast-charging is a cornerstone. But, if I invest into fast-charging only for cars, I won't be able to make money even in my whole life time. Inter-city buses and inter-city trucks are going to be the biggest enablers," he added.</p>

<p>Earlier in the day, Prime Minister Narendra Modi emphasised the importance of clean energy for a better future, stating that "clean energy is the need of the hour".</p>

<p>At COP26, India committed to reducing projected carbon emissions by 1 billion tonnes by 2030 and achieving net-zero emissions by 2070. These commitments necessitate a rapid transition to renewables.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/m12gafl_kartikey-hariyani_625x300_21_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kartikey Hariyani said that "there is good news around" as far as prices of EVs were concerned.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-sued-for-defamation-over-false-comment-in-presidential-debate-6841905]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump Sued For Defamation Over False Comment In Presidential Debate]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-sued-for-defamation-over-false-comment-in-presidential-debate-6841905]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 22:55:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The "Central Park Five," five men who were falsely convicted of rape in a notorious 1989 New York case, launched a defamation lawsuit Monday against former US president Donald Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The "Central Park Five," five men who were falsely convicted of rape in a notorious 1989 New York case, launched a defamation lawsuit Monday against former US president Donald Trump.</p>

<p>The lawsuit, filed in a federal court in Pennsylvania, accuses the Republican White House candidate of making "false and defamatory" comments during the September 10 presidential debate with Vice President Kamala Harris in Philadelphia.</p>

<p>The five Black and Hispanic men -- Yusef Salaam, Raymond Santana, Kevin Richardson, Antron Brown and Korey Wise -- were teenagers when they were convicted of the rape and assault of a female jogger in Central Park.</p>

<p>They were eventually exonerated and their convictions were vacated in 2002. They received $41 million in a 2014 settlement with New York City.</p>

<p>Trump, during the presidential debate, "falsely stated that Plaintiffs killed an individual and pled guilty to the crime," the lawsuit said. "These statements are demonstrably false.</p>

<p>"Plaintiffs never pled guilty to any crime and were subsequently cleared of all wrongdoing."</p>

<p>The lawsuit also recalled that Trump, 11 days after the Central Park attack, published a full-page advertisement in four New York City newspapers calling to "bring back the death penalty."</p>

<p>Trump made comments about the "Central Park Five" after Harris mentioned the ad during the debate.</p>

<p>"A lot of people including Mayor Bloomberg agreed with me on the Central Park Five," Trump said, apparently confusing former New York mayor Michael Bloomberg with former New York mayor Ed Koch, who was the mayor at the time.</p>

<p>"They admitted -- they said, they pled guilty," Trump said. "And I said, well, if they pled guilty they badly hurt a person, killed a person ultimately.</p>

<p>"And if they pled guilty -- then they pled we're not guilty."</p>

<p>The "Central Park Five" are seeking a jury trial and unspecified damages.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/bdehpaas_donald-trump_625x300_17_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump made comments about the "Central Park Five" over mention of the ad during the debate. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/william-dalrymple-on-why-it-is-a-surprise-that-india-dominated-asia-for-1-000-years-6841825]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[William Dalrymple On Why It Is A "Surprise That India Dominated Asia For 1,000 Years"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/william-dalrymple-on-why-it-is-a-surprise-that-india-dominated-asia-for-1-000-years-6841825]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 22:40:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Archeology and solid scholarship show that India lay at the heart of ancient world, argued historian William Dalrymple, underscoring that the myth of the Silk road has made India seem more peripheral than it actually was.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Archeology and solid scholarship show that India lay at the heart of ancient world, argued historian William Dalrymple, underscoring that the myth of the Silk road has made India seem more peripheral than it actually was.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"This map which people continue to reproduce in book after book of what is said to be the silk road. We are told that the principal trade east-west in ancient times was this single line which ran from the Mediterranean to the South China sea. Even its modern edition called the maritime silk road which runs down from Guangzhou through the Malacca Strait bypasses India. The line just dots around the peninsula," said the historian speaking at NDTV World Summit on Monday.</p>

<p>"It is the contention in the book that I have just written - The Golden Road - that this is an entirely false premise. Memorised from this map and rooted takes. Compare it with the actual shape of roman trade with India which is revealed by new map put out by Oxford University this year," said Mr Dalrymple.</p>

<p>He detailed India's waxing soft power influence on the culture, education, religion and civilisations of the rest of the world from 250 BC-1200 AD.</p>

<p>"This is not about the Indian century, it's about the Indian millennium stretching from around 250 BC TO 1200 AD when India was the centre of the world," he said speaking at the Summit whose theme was 'The India Century'.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Look at this extraordinary image that just turned up in an archeological excavation in Egypt. You can see very clearly it is the Buddha's head. What's surprising is the marble is carved from in what is now Turkey. It was found in a temple on the shore of Red sea. It seems extraordinary that a Buddha would turn up in Egypt but it should not be so when you consider that just as Buddha's head is found in Egypt, 6,000 miles to the west of India so Angkor Wat to 5,000 miles to the east of India is entirely an Indian planned project. In the galleries of Angkor Wat, you see the battle of Kurukshetra, the battle of Lanka, images of Krishna and his gopis inspired by stories first told in the area here around Delhi. Why is this not better known. Why is it a surprise that India dominated Asia for as much as a 1,000 years," asked the historian.</p>

<p>Answering his own question, the historian said the blame lay partly in colonialism.</p>

<p>"Partly, the story is clearly about colonialism about the way that Macaulay and others like him said that a single shelf of good English books is worth entire native literature of India and Arabia," he said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The historian pointed out Rome and India were the main trading partners of each other in ancient India and not China. He added that romans knew every coast on the west coast of India and couldn't get enough of Indian products, underlining the importance of the country.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Here is a map of Roman coin hordes discovered by archeologists. None are found east of the Pamirs of the Oxus. Not a single Roman coin horde has ever been found in China. But there is a notable concentration of roman gold all around the coasts of India. India is dotted with Roman coin hordes. India and Rome were the principal trading partner of each other in the early millennia BC," he said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Very Indian looking deities and apsaras seen floating over the Buddhist temples of China tell the story of Indian art having more and more influence, said the historian.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Indian ideas were soon being transmitted through Afghanistan, through Bamiyan to China, where by 2nd and 3rd century we find the Budhha taking on the physiognomy of China. Originally Buddhism is just the religion brought by traders into China, but by the 5th and 6th century we find Gupta sculptures being copied by Chinese all over Ghangzuo and beginning to head eastwards into the heartlands of China," said the historian.</p>

<p>The historian described Nalanda University as the Oxbridge of ancient India which attracted students from all over, including Korea and Japan. &nbsp;</p>

<p>"Nalanda - the oxbridge, the Ivy League, the NASA of ancient Asia - was visited not just by monks from China but monks from Nepal, Korea and Japan. Its library had science, mathematics, astronomy, everything was gathered in this extraordinary space. Look at the plan of different monasteries and university buildings in Nalanda, it is the same as we find in Oxbridge," he said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Sanskrit emerged as the language of diplomacy and culture, spanning from Kandahar to Bali, he said, adding that the Palava script formed the base for various Southeast Asian scripts such as Khmer and Thai.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/ptidpedg_william-dalrymple_625x300_21_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[William Dalrymple at NDTV World Summit]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/not-a-birkin-internet-reacts-to-israels-claim-of-yahya-sinwars-wifes-rs-26-lakh-hermes-bag-6841700]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Internet Reacts To Israel's Claim Of Yahya Sinwar's Wife's Rs 26 Lakh Bag]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/not-a-birkin-internet-reacts-to-israels-claim-of-yahya-sinwars-wifes-rs-26-lakh-hermes-bag-6841700]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 22:24:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In the clip, Sinwar's wife is seen holding a bag, which Israel claimed to be worth $32,000 (around Rs 26.90 lakh).]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Days after Yahya Sinwar was killed in an Israeli operation in southern Gaza, a video has surfaced showing the Hamas leader, along with his wife and children, moving through a tunnel the night before the October 7 attack on Israel last year.</p>

<p>The CCTV footage, released by the Israel Defense Forces (IDF), captures Sinwar and his group carrying various supplies, including pillows, mattresses, a television, and several bags, into the tunnel.</p>

<p>In the clip, Sinwar's wife is seen holding a bag, which Israel claimed to be worth $32,000 (around Rs 26.90 lakh).</p>

<p>"Sinwar's wife was caught on camera sneaking into the tunnels the night before October 7, clutching a $32,000 Hermes Birkin bag! While Gazans faced hardships under Hamas, Sinwar and his family shamelessly lived in luxury, indulging while sending others to fight," Israel stated.</p>

<p>Lieutenant Colonel Avichay Adraee, the IDF's Arabic language spokesperson, reiterated this claim, highlighting the contrast between the opulent lifestyle of Sinwar's family and the poverty experienced by most residents of Gaza, who "struggle to afford basic necessities."</p>

<p>However, internet users were quick to criticize these claims. Many on X pointed out that the bag was not a "Birkin," accusing Israel of spreading false information.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">They are not stupid, they know that's not a Birkin, but they're pandering to an audience of evil, delusional beings who are willing to believe anything Israel says so they can continue their support without feelings of guilt bc the ppl they're murdering somehow deserve it. <a href="https://t.co/GZXsm1hx9O">https://t.co/GZXsm1hx9O</a></p>
— Rebecca Sevilla (@rebeccasev7) <a href="https://twitter.com/rebeccasev7/status/1848038997437694034?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 20, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>A user wrote, "They are not stupid, they know that's not a Birkin, but they're pandering to an audience of evil, delusional beings who are willing to believe anything Israel says so they can continue their support without feelings of guilt bc the ppl they're murdering somehow deserve it."</p>

<p>Another user commented, "Even someone with zero fashion sense knows this bag ain't no Hermes, not even close. How's the official Israel account gonna mess that up? Y'all are embarrassing yourselves out here."</p>

<p>"Haha such a lame propaganda to come up with, The oceans of the world are gonna dry up but your lies are never ending," the third user remarked.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Desperately clutching at straws. It's not a Birkin. And it's hilarious to see this coming from an official state account. You're neck and neck with old Katzy for the weirdest official account propaganda posts prize," the fourth user commented.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Isn't it embarrassing when an official account representing a state posts desperate propaganda? The world is laughing at you," the fifth user wrote.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/4l1eba3_yahya-sinwars-wife_625x300_21_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Internet users were quick to criticize these claims.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-election-2024-important-dates-6841651]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Important Dates In US Presidential Election 2024]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-election-2024-important-dates-6841651]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 22:17:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Republican former President Donald Trump and Vice President Kamala Harris, a Democrat, will face each other in the November 5 US presidential election.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Republican former President Donald Trump and Vice President Kamala Harris, a Democrat, will face each other in the November 5 US presidential election.</p>

<p>Here is a timeline of events related to the election between now and Inauguration Day in January.</p>

<p>- November 5: Election Day</p>

<p>- Later in November: It could take days for the election result to be known, especially if it is close and mail-in ballots are a factor.</p>

<p>- November 26: Trump, the first sitting or former US president to be convicted of a crime, is due to be sentenced in a Manhattan hush money case where he was found guilty of falsifying documents to cover up a payment to silence a porn star. Trump has denied wrongdoing. Sentencing was originally due to take place on September 18.</p>

<p>- December 17: Electors, who together form the Electoral College, meet in their respective states and the District of Columbia to select the president and vice president.</p>

<p>- December 25: The electoral votes must be received by this date by the president of the Senate - a role held by the vice president, currently Harris - and the archivist.</p>

<p>2025</p>

<p>- January 6: The vice president presides over the Electoral College vote count at a joint session of Congress, announces the results and declares who has been elected.</p>

<p>Ahead of the count on January 6, 2021, then-President Trump lambasted his vice president, Mike Pence, for refusing to try to prevent Congress from certifying President Joe Biden's victory over Trump. On that day, the US Capitol was attacked by Trump supporters trying to stop the count. Biden's win was certified early the next day.</p>

<p>Congress has since passed the Electoral Count Reform and Presidential Transition Improvement Act of 2022, which requires approval of one-fifth of the House and Senate to consider a challenge to a state's results - a much higher bar than existed before, when at least one member each in the Senate and House of Representatives could together trigger a challenge.</p>

<p>- January 20: The inauguration of the election winner and their vice president takes place. At this ceremony, the victor and the vice president are officially sworn into office.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/at6bqpl_us-election-generic-reuters_625x300_16_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[It could take days for the election result to be known. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-everything-you-need-to-know-about-the-us-presidential-candidates-6841626]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Everything You Need To Know About The US Presidential Candidates]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-everything-you-need-to-know-about-the-us-presidential-candidates-6841626]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 22:10:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Republican former President Donald Trump will face Vice President Kamala Harris in the November 5 US presidential election after Democratic President Joe Biden ended his reelection bid.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Republican former President Donald Trump will face Vice President Kamala Harris in the November 5 US presidential election after Democratic President Joe Biden ended his reelection bid.</p>

<p>Several third-party hopefuls are also running. Here are the candidates.</p>

<p><strong>DEMOCRATIC PARTY</strong></p>

<p><strong>KAMALA HARRIS</strong></p>

<p>Harris, 60, won the Democratic Party's nomination after Biden ended his reelection bid, allowing Democrats to present a renewed American vision in contrast to Trump's agenda as they seek to revive their coalition of young voters, people of color and suburban women.</p>

<p>A former US senator, California attorney general and San Francisco prosecutor, Harris became the first woman and person of color to serve as vice president after Biden selected her as his 2020 running mate. She would become the first woman to serve as president in the nation's 248-year history if she wins.</p>

<p>Opinion polls show Harris is in a close race against Trump. She leads the former president nationally 45% to 42%, according to a October 23-27 Reuters/Ipsos poll.</p>

<p>Other surveys show Harris and her running mate, Minnesota Governor Tim Walz, in tight races among the seven battleground states that could decide the election: Wisconsin, Pennsylvania, Georgia, Arizona, North Carolina, Michigan and Nevada.</p>

<p>Harris has made reproductive rights and personal freedoms a rallying cry and backs a national law codifying access to safe abortion.</p>

<p>Her economic plans include tax cuts for most Americans, price gouging bans, more affordable housing and a new child tax credit as well as efforts to boost domestic manufacturing. She proposed increasing the corporate tax rate to 28% from 21% and ending taxes on tips.</p>

<p>She has promised tougher immigration and fentanyl controls at the border. Her climate and energy positions are similar to those held by Biden, who made fighting climate change a top priority.</p>

<p>Harris has been seen as tech-friendly even as she took on alleged anticompetition and privacy issues, and she has sought to reassure donors that she backs capitalism.</p>

<p>On foreign policy, Harris is expected to stick largely to Biden's playbook on key issues such as Ukraine, China and Iran. She has also pressured Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu for a Gaza ceasefire deal but has also taken a hard line against Hamas, saying the terrorist group must be "eliminated", and remains committed to the US policy of arming Israel.</p>

<p>Key labor groups, including the Service Employees International Union, the United Auto Workers and the American Federation of Teachers, endorsed her. Former US military officials, company executives and numerous former top Republican officials have also backed her.</p>

<p><strong>REPUBLICAN PARTY</strong></p>

<p><strong>DONALD TRUMP</strong></p>

<p>Trump, 78, secured the Republican nomination in July to make his third consecutive run for the White House after losing his 2020 reelection bid.</p>

<p>Trump continues to repeat his false claim that Democrats stole the 2020 election as he campaigns amid unprecedented legal challenges, including a fresh US indictment over efforts to subvert his loss to Biden.</p>

<p>In office from 2017 to 2021, he has cast his indictments in four criminal cases as a political attack, vowing "retribution" against perceived enemies and embracing increasingly dystopian rhetoric. He has also made ominous comments about "the enemy within" the United States and threatened to deploy the military domestically.</p>

<p>Trump became the first former US president to be convicted of a crime in May, in New York City. He was also the first president to be impeached twice. He denies any wrongdoing.</p>

<p>Trump, who chose US Senator JD Vance of Ohio as his running mate, has refused to commit to accepting the 2024 results or to rule out possible political violence, while he and Republicans lay the groundwork to contest a potential loss. He promised to pardon supporters imprisoned for the January 6, 2021, attack on the US Capitol and threatened to prosecute election officials, donors, Google and others if he wins.</p>

<p>He said he would not run again if he loses.</p>

<p>Trump is the oldest US presidential nominee and would become the nation's second oldest president. He faced two assassination attempts, one at a Pennsylvania campaign rally in July and another one in September near one of his Florida golf courses.</p>

<p>Trump-friendly think tanks' sweeping "Project 2025" policy agenda would target the Justice Department's independence, among other plans. Trump has sought to distance himself from the project despite his former aides' and Vance's involvement. He also wants the power to replace federal civil service workers with loyalists.</p>

<p>On foreign policy, Trump has vowed to fundamentally alter the US relationship with NATO and to resolve the Ukraine war with possible peace talks that might require Kyiv to cede territory. He has said Hamas must be "crushed" and vowed to be tougher on Iran, but has given few details or policy proposals.</p>

<p>Trump has made immigration a top issue, promising mass deportations, including legal Haitian immigrants given Temporary Protected Status in Springfield, Ohio. He would end birthright citizenship and expand a travel ban on people from certain countries.</p>

<p>He takes credit for the US Supreme Court ruling overturning Roe v. Wade protections, saying abortion laws should be left to the states. Trump said he does not support banning birth control.</p>

<p>On the economy, Trump would impose sweeping tariffs on imported goods and on specific companies and countries. He pledged to end taxes on tips and overtime, to lower corporate tax rates and to open federal lands to foreign companies and housing. He has also vowed to undo much of Biden's climate change work.</p>

<p>Trump has faced criticism, including from some Republicans, for personal attacks against Harris, including over her race and gender.</p>

<p>Trump appointed former Democrat Robert F. Kennedy Jr. to his transition team and said he would tap billionaire supporter Elon Musk to address government efficiency.</p>

<p>The National Fraternal Order of Police and other police groups have also backed his election bid.</p>

<p><strong>THIRD PARTIES And INDEPENDENTS</strong></p>

<p><strong>LIBERTARIAN PARTY</strong></p>

<p>CHASE OLIVER</p>

<p>While the Libertarian Party invited Trump to its convention, it ultimately selected Oliver, 39. Oliver ran for a Georgia state Senate seat in 2022 and garnered 2% of the vote.</p>

<p><strong>GREEN PARTY</strong></p>

<p>JILL STEIN</p>

<p>Stein, 74, a physician who ran under the Green Party in 2016, is running again in 2024.</p>

<p>She launched her current campaign accusing Democrats of betraying their promises "for working people, youth and the climate again and again - while Republicans don't even make such promises in the first place."</p>

<p><strong>INDEPENDENT</strong></p>

<p>CORNEL WEST</p>

<p>The political activist, philosopher and academic is making a bid to attract more progressive, Democratic-leaning voters.</p>

<p>West, 71, initially ran as a Green Party candidate but in October said people "want good policies over partisan politics" and declared himself an independent. He has promised to end poverty and guarantee housing.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/b64vd7go_donald-trump-kamala-harris_625x300_22_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Republican presidential nominee and former US President Donald Trump. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ndtv-world-summit-time-for-global-system-to-change-what-indias-former-un-ambassador-syed-akbaruddin-siad-6841473]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Time For Global System To Change: What India's Former UN Ambassador Siad]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ndtv-world-summit-time-for-global-system-to-change-what-indias-former-un-ambassador-syed-akbaruddin-siad-6841473]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 21:49:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Speaking about India's need to be treated as equals, Syed Akbaruddin said that, "This aspiration for being treated equally in a changing world is just an extension of our independence movement."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Speaking about India's right to be treated as equals, in a session titled 'Geo-Political Disruptions: Emerging Powers vs Existing Powers', former permanent representative at the UN Syed Akbaruddin at the NDTV World Summit on Monday said that, "This aspiration for being treated equally in a changing world is just an extension of our independence movement."</p>

<p>He said that since India has gained political independence and is economically self-sufficient, the world needs to treat India equally at a table where the latter's voice is not heard.</p>

<p>He cited the example of a smartphone updating its software with the click of one button. He said that, "We are not saying the international system needs to be that fast, but it's time for the international system to change."</p>

<p>In response to that, Dr Philipp Ackermann, Ambassador of Germany to India &amp; Bhutan, said that India has gained a high level on the international stage and should not be asking questions of equal footing. He added, "The American president comes, the German Chancellor comes, they seek the Prime Minister's wisdom and ideas. India is being treated as an equal partner already."</p>

<p>As a footnote, Mr Ackermann also further stated that, even though the P5 says that the Security Council needs to be bigger, nobody has the intention to see it actuate, "they are very comfortable in their little club of 5", he said. "India, Germany, Brazil, and Japan belong to this table. We have to keep fighting."</p>

<p>Addressing what role India needs to play in climate change, Mr. Akbaruddin said that the climate transition is a difficult and complex one for India and that developed nations need to be more understanding of the needs of developing countries. Continuing on the topic of resetting the existing order, he said, "We have seen lone rangers do well sometimes but the big issues of the time require partnerships."&nbsp;</p>

<p>He was of the opinion that the challenges will be in climate, artificial intelligence, space and more, which are by definition transboundary and states will have to work to find solutions for that and that will come through partnerships and not lone rangers.</p>

<p>India has long advocated for the reform of the UN Security Council, arguing that its current structure is outdated and doesn't represent the world's current political landscape. India believes that the Council should be expanded to include more permanent and non-permanent members. Delhi has emphasized its own right to a permanent seat on the Council.</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/51voi39s_geo-political-disruptions-discussion-ndtv-world-summit_625x300_21_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/germanys-3-year-old-laurent-schwarz-mini-picasso-gains-global-art-fame-6841108]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Germany's 3 Year Old "Mini Picasso" Gains Global Art Fame]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/germanys-3-year-old-laurent-schwarz-mini-picasso-gains-global-art-fame-6841108]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 20:58:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Three-year-old Laurent Schwarz may still be wearing nappies but his paintings have earned him social media fame and the nickname of Germany's "mini-Picasso".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Three-year-old Laurent Schwarz may still be wearing nappies but his paintings have earned him social media fame and the nickname of Germany's "mini-Picasso".</p>

<p>In a studio his parents have set up at their home in the Bavarian town of Neubeuern, the toddler has been busy creating splashy artworks, often several times bigger than he is.</p>

<p>When he is not playing with his dinosaur toys, he likes to liberally apply acrylic paint to canvas with brushes, rollers or just his fingers to create riotously abstract pieces.</p>

<p>His parents said his works have attracted the eye of art lovers and galleries and fetched high prices. They insisted it was Laurent's artistic passion that has fuelled the art world hype, media interest and his very early brush with fame.</p>

<p>His 33-year-old mother Lisa Schwarz told AFP that the family discovered Laurent's love for painting on a family holiday last year, at a hotel which had a studio.</p>

<p>"When we got home, Laurent just wanted to paint -- paint, paint, paint, the whole time," she said.</p>

<p>She and her husband Philipp bought him some canvases, brushes and paint, and it was not long before family and friends were clamouring to see the prodigy's work.</p>

<p>They set up an Instagram account to share images of his work more easily and said they were soon bowled over by the response.</p>

<p>"Within four weeks we had got 10,000 followers," said Lisa, with enquiries from galleries following soon after, and interest from newspapers in Germany and abroad which quickly dubbed him the "mini-Picasso".</p>

<p>The Instagram account now has 90,000 followers and at a sale of Laurent's work in September buyers from around the world showed interest, according to his parents.</p>

<p>They said some works have sold for hundreds of thousands of euros, but declined to divulge details on sales and buyers.</p>

<p><strong>'Always painting'</strong></p>

<p>Laurent is not the first child artist to capture the public's imagination.</p>

<p>In 2022 for example, 10-year-old American Andres Valencia sold his Picasso-influenced works for several hundred thousand dollars.</p>

<p>In the late 1990s, Romanian-American artist Alexandra Nechita also drew comparisons with the Spanish master at the tender age of 12.</p>

<p>Laurent's parents said they are still surprised at the reaction to their son's work.</p>

<p>While at the moment "almost everything has been sold", Laurent "is always painting new ones," said Philipp, 43.</p>

<p>"There are pictures that we don't sell, for example his first work or ones that he particularly likes," he explained.</p>

<p>Laurent's parents said they are keeping the money paid for his work in an account in his name which he will be able to access when he is an adult.</p>

<p>"He can study painting, buy a car, play an instrument, play football... It's up to him to choose," said Philipp, 43.</p>

<p>"The important thing for us is that he's happy."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/7cggs1c_laurent-schwarz_625x300_21_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Three-year-old Laurent Schwarz's work have sold for hundreds of thousands of dollars.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/car-explodes-in-syrias-damascus-damages-hotel-and-vehicles-6841045]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[2 Killed After Israeli Strike on "Civilian Car" In Damascus: Syria]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/car-explodes-in-syrias-damascus-damages-hotel-and-vehicles-6841045]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 20:47:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Syria's defence ministry said two civilians were killed in an Israeli strike on a vehicle on Monday afternoon in the Mazzeh district of Damascus, home to embassies and security headquarters.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Syria's defence ministry said two civilians were killed in an Israeli strike on a vehicle on Monday afternoon in the Mazzeh district of Damascus, home to embassies and security headquarters.</p>

<p>The Mazzeh neighbourhood, where United Nations offices are also based, has been the target of other recent strikes blamed on Israel.</p>

<p>"At approximately 17:05 pm (1417 GMT), the Israeli enemy launched an air strike targeting a civilian car" in Mazzeh, "killing two civilians and injuring three," the ministry said in a statement.</p>

<p>It added that the attack caused "material damage to private property" nearby.</p>

<p>The official SANA news agency had earlier reported "a car explosion in one of the neighbourhoods" of Mazzeh, where an AFP correspondent said a hotel was damaged and vehicles incinerated following the blast near Syria's Information Ministry.</p>

<p>Ambulances rushed to the site of the explosion where crowds gathered around the mangled four-wheel drive which was reduced to scraps of metal, the correspondent said.</p>

<p>In early April Iran blamed Israel for an air strike on the Iranian consular annex in Mazzeh that killed seven Revolutionary Guards and several other people. Iran later that month retaliated with its first ever direct missile and drone strike against Israel.</p>

<p>Earlier this month, the Syrian government said seven civilians were killed in an Israeli air strike on a residential and commercial building in Mazzeh.</p>

<p>The Syrian Observatory for Human Rights war monitor gave a higher toll of nine killed, five of them civilians including a child. It said the attack targeted a building used by Iran's Revolutionary Guards and Lebanon's Hezbollah.</p>

<p>Israeli authorities rarely comment on individual strikes in Syria but have repeatedly said they will not allow arch-enemy Iran to expand its presence.</p>

<p>Iran and Lebanon's Hezbollah have been among the Syrian government's most important allies in the country's civil war that began in 2011.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/dtm9l538_damascus-car-explosion_625x300_21_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The car was reduced to scraps of metal.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/reuven-azar-israel-hamas-hezbollah-ndtv-world-summit-right-and-duty-to-retaliate-says-israeli-envoy-on-irans-attack-6840842]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Right And Duty To Retaliate": Israeli Envoy To India On Iran's Attack]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/reuven-azar-israel-hamas-hezbollah-ndtv-world-summit-right-and-duty-to-retaliate-says-israeli-envoy-on-irans-attack-6840842]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 20:18:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel has a right and duty to retaliate after Iran fired at least 180 missiles at it on October 1, the country's Ambassador to India, Reuven Azar, has said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel has a right and duty to retaliate after Iran fired at least 180 missiles at it on October 1, the country's Ambassador to India, Reuven Azar, has said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In an interview during the NDTV World Summit on Monday, Mr Azar said Israel is keen on peace and stability in the region but it cannot have a situation where Iran is free to attack whenever it likes.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Mr Azar also said that, as a rising power, India has a substantial role to play in the Middle East and its importance will only increase every year.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Asked about reports stating that Israel could respond to the Iranian attack before elections are held in the US - which is its most important ally -&nbsp; on November 5, the ambassador said, "The US elections are not a factor. What is a factor is that we have not only a right but a duty to retaliate. Imagine a situation in which a country like Iran is capable of threatening any country in the region without any repercussions... this is completely unacceptable."</p>

<p>Mr Azar said Israel wants to promote stability in the region and it is doing that with its peace agreements with Jordan and Egypt, the Abraham Accords with the UAE, Bahrain, Morocco and Sudan, and dialogue with Saudi Arabia.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"We have proved after the attack by Iran that we are capable of defending the skies of the Middle East from the Iranian threat, but we cannot be in a situation in which the Iranians feel free to attack us at any point. This is why the security building block has to be complemented by our retaliation," he said.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>'Neutralised Missile Threat'</strong></p>

<p>On the killing of leaders like Hamas chief Yahya Sinwar and the fact that the outfit has regrouped in the past, Mr Azar said the situation is very different now.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"What we have managed to achieve in the Gaza Strip right now is that we have defeated the terrorist army of Hamas in a way that they cannot pose a missile threat to Israel. We have destroyed their missile factories. We have sealed the border between the Gaza Strip and the Sinai, so it will be much more difficult to re-arm," he said.</p>

<p>The ambassador admitted that they have not been able to bring back all the hostages from the October 7, 2023, attack and remove Hamas from government. The latter, he said, is being worked on by finding a way to distribute assistance to the population in Gaza so that Hamas cannot hold them hostage.</p>

<p>The balance, the ambassador claimed, is changing in Israel's favour in its conflicts with Hamas and Hezbollah.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Indian Century</strong></p>

<p>Asked about India's role in West Asia and in ending the conflicts, Mr Azar said the country will contribute a lot to the region and the world.</p>

<p>"India is a rising power. I was looking at the data and I saw that in the next year, when India grows by seven per cent, it will grow by $260 billion... our (Israel's) economy is $600 billion. So what India has to contribute to the world is huge. It is going to be a powerhouse, a manufacturing hub, and it needs to be connected to the world. It has a lot to offer to countries in West Asia. I have seen how India is increasing its links with the UAE," he noted.</p>

<p>The envoy added, "When all this infrastructure of connectivity is set, we are going to see an incredible role of India in our region. It won't be just about merchandise, it will be about manufacturing... We depend on the goodwill of India, on the investments of India, on our cooperation with India and that role is going to increase every year."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/1qec30h_reuven-azar_625x300_21_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mr Azar also said India has a substantial role to play in the Middle East.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/truly-historic-egypt-certified-malaria-free-by-who-after-100-year-effort-6840771]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Truly Historic": Egypt Certified Malaria-Free By WHO After 100-Year Effort]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/truly-historic-egypt-certified-malaria-free-by-who-after-100-year-effort-6840771]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 20:09:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In the 1940s, malaria cases in Egypt surged to over three million due to population displacement during World War II.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Egypt has officially been declared malaria-free, with the World Health Organization (WHO) hailing the achievement as "truly historic" after nearly a century of dedicated efforts to eradicate the disease, the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cm2yl8pjgn2o" rel="nofollow, noindex"><em>BBC </em></a>reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Malaria is as old as Egyptian civilization itself, but the disease that plagued the pharaohs now belongs to its history," said WHO Director-General Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus.</p>

<p>Egypt began its fight against the mosquito-borne infectious disease almost 100 years ago. Certification is awarded when a country can prove it has interrupted the transmission of malaria for at least three consecutive years. Malaria still claims the lives of at least 600,000 people annually, the vast majority of whom are in Africa.</p>

<p>In its statement, the WHO commended "the Egyptian government and people" for their successful efforts to "end a disease that has been present in the country since ancient times."</p>

<p>Egypt is now the third country in the WHO's Eastern Mediterranean Region to receive this certification, following the United Arab Emirates and Morocco. Globally, a total of 44 countries and one territory have reached this milestone.</p>

<p>The WHO emphasized that this certification marks "the beginning of a new phase," urging Egypt to remain vigilant in order to maintain its malaria-free status.</p>

<p>For certification, a country must demonstrate its ability to prevent the re-establishment of malaria transmission. The WHO highlighted that Egypt's initial attempts to reduce human-mosquito contact began in the 1920s by restricting rice cultivation and other agricultural crops near residential areas.</p>

<p>Malaria, caused by a parasite transmitted through mosquito bites, has seen progress in control efforts, with vaccines now being deployed in some regions. However, monitoring the disease and preventing mosquito bites remain the most effective preventive measures.</p>

<p>"Receiving the malaria elimination certificate today is not the end of the journey but the beginning of a new phase," said Egypt's Health Minister, Khaled Abdel Ghaffar. "We must now work tirelessly and vigilantly to sustain our achievement through maintaining the highest standards for surveillance, diagnosis, and treatment."</p>

<p>In the 1940s, malaria cases in Egypt surged to over three million due to population displacement during World War II. The construction of the Aswan Dam in the 1960s also increased malaria risks by creating mosquito breeding grounds through standing water. However, by 2001, Egypt had brought malaria "firmly under control," according to the WHO.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Nigeria continues to bear the highest malaria burden, accounting for more than a quarter of all malaria deaths globally, followed by the Democratic Republic of Congo, Uganda, and Mozambique.<br />
&nbsp;</p>

<p><br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/k7qbgqbg_mosquito-_625x300_21_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Egypt is now the third country in the WHO's Eastern Mediterranean Region]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israels-ben-gurion-airport-reopens-after-halt-over-suspicious-object-6840751]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Airport Reopens After Brief Halt Over "Suspicious Object"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israels-ben-gurion-airport-reopens-after-halt-over-suspicious-object-6840751]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 20:01:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel's airport authority on Monday resumed operations at the country's main airport, Ben Gurion, after briefly closing its airspace.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel's airport authority on Monday resumed operations at the country's main airport, Ben Gurion, after briefly closing its airspace.</p>

<p>Local media reported a "suspicious object" being spotted near the facility that led to its closure for about 30 minutes.</p>

<p>"The airport is open for landings and departures," the airport authority said in a statement.</p>

<p>The Israeli army later said in a statement that five drones had been intercepted "in the area of the Mediterranean Sea" and stressed that there were no security risks to the airport.</p>

<p>"The UAVs were intercepted prior to crossing into Israeli territory," it said.</p>

<p>"In addition, it should be emphasised that there is no concern for a security incident in the area of Ben Gurion Airport," which is near the commercial centre of Tel Aviv.</p>

<p>The temporary suspension of the airport's operations came weeks after Israel's airspace was briefly closed when Iran targeted the country with around 200 missiles.</p>

<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu later vowed to make Iran "pay" for its "big mistake", while Tehran in turn warned of a "decisive and regretful" response to an Israeli attack.</p>

<p>Israel is at war with Iran-backed Hezbollah, which has previously claimed rocket fire towards Tel Aviv from Lebanon.</p>

<p>Another Iran-backed group, the Huthi rebels of Yemen, in early October claimed a drone attack on Tel Aviv, after saying they had fired a missile at Ben Gurion Airport. The latter attack led to Israeli air strikes on Yemen.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-10/joahkg8g_israel-airport-afp_625x300_11_October_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Operations halted as "suspicious object" spotted at Israel's airport. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-palestine-conflict-explained-how-does-aid-enter-gaza-6840620]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: How Does Aid Enter Gaza?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-palestine-conflict-explained-how-does-aid-enter-gaza-6840620]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 19:41:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel has announced steps to boost aid deliveries to Gaza, but UN figures show a huge drop in supplies getting through to the war-battered territory and humanitarian workers doubt much is reaching those who need it most.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel has announced steps to boost aid deliveries to Gaza, but UN figures show a huge drop in supplies getting through to the war-battered territory and humanitarian workers doubt much is reaching those who need it most.</p>

<p>Aid workers and experts told AFP that there were still many obstacles to getting desperately needed supplies to Palestinians in the besieged Gaza Strip's north, where intense Israeli military operations since early October have left hundreds dead.</p>

<p>Not only are there disputes over the actual volume of aid being allowed in, but agencies are often unable to reach people under constant bombardment, meaning it does not always make it where the dire humanitarian needs are greatest.</p>

<p><strong>How does aid enter Gaza?&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p>Most trucks carrying humanitarian supplies enter through the Kerem Shalom crossing on the border between Israel and the southern Gaza Strip.</p>

<p>The shipments are inspected by the Israeli military for security reasons, a process cited by humanitarian groups as the main factor behind the slow delivery of aid.</p>

<p>Israel, which imposed a siege on the Hamas-ruled territory in the early stages of the war last year, often blames the inability of relief organisations to handle and distribute large quantities of aid.</p>

<p>Once the aid enters Gaza, deliveries are subject to coordination with COGAT, an Israeli defence ministry agency that oversees civilian affairs in the Palestinian territories.</p>

<p>Many aid groups regularly report difficulties in communicating and coordinating with COGAT.</p>

<p>The distribution of aid is further complicated by shortages of fuel for trucks, war-damaged roads and looting, as well as fighting in densely populated areas and the repeated displacement of much of Gaza's 2.4 million people.</p>

<p>Several humanitarian officials told AFP on condition of anonymity that almost half of the aid that enters Gaza is being looted, especially basic supplies.</p>

<p>According to the United Nations, 396 trucks have entered Gaza so far in October, far below previous months.</p>

<p>In September 3,003 trucks got through, following 3,096 in August and 4,681 in July, according to UN figures which Israel's COGAT regularly disputes.</p>

<p>Some foreign countries have opted for dropping aid from the air. COGAT said 81 packages were parachuted into the narrow coastal territory on Saturday.</p>

<p>But this effort as well as a short-lived maritime aid corridor have not been able to meet the increasing needs of Gazans after more than a year of war.</p>

<p><strong>What has Israel said?</strong></p>

<p>A joint statement issued Tuesday by the military and COGAT said Israel "remains committed to facilitating humanitarian aid".</p>

<p>It came as the United States, Israel's top arms provider, has warned it may suspend some of its military assistance if Israel does not quickly improve humanitarian access to Gaza.</p>

<p>The Israeli statement highlighted patient transfers between hospitals in Gaza and the delivery of 68,650 litres of fuel to medical facilities across the territory -- many of which have been put out of service during the war.</p>

<p>The military has also announced that 30 World Food Programme trucks were recently able to bring flour directly to northern Gaza, not via the southern Kerem Shalom crossing.</p>

<p>Tania Hary, head of Israeli rights group Gisha which monitors access into Gaza, said that "Israel has come under (diplomatic) pressure to allow more aid in, especially to the north".</p>

<p>She told AFP that only a ceasefire would enable humanitarian operations on the required scale.</p>

<p>"But short of that, genuine action and cooperation by the Israeli authorities could ensure the safe and free movement of aid," Hary said, but cautioned that she had seen no "genuine will" from the Israeli authorities throughout the war.</p>

<p><strong>What's the impact on the ground?</strong></p>

<p>Juliette Touma, spokeswoman for the UN agency for Palestinian refugees UNRWA, said there has been "no major change".</p>

<p>"What has come in is very, very little and is by far not enough in the face of the needs," Touma told AFP.</p>

<p>A displaced resident of the northern Jabalia area, a focus of the recent fighting, said the area "is being wiped out".</p>

<p>"If we don't die from the bombing and gunfire, we will die of hunger," said 42-year-old Umm Firas Shamiyah, demanding aid be sent to the north.</p>

<p>Sarah Davies, spokeswoman for the International Committee of the Red Cross, said that even if aid deliveries are boosted, the fighting makes it "very difficult to effectively distribute things to all those who need it".</p>

<p>A humanitarian worker whose group has a large presence on the ground said that some crucial items are banned by Israel.</p>

<p>"We're having great difficulty bringing in oxygen concentrates, generators and reconstruction equipment because the Israeli authorities consider them to be dual-purpose items that have both military and medical uses," he said.</p>

<p>"Some clinics are even running out of paracetamol," the common painkiller, the aid worker added.</p>

<p>"October has been catastrophic."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/sst8lb88_gaza-afp_625x300_19_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[According to the UN, 396 trucks have entered Gaza so far in October, far below previous months. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-woman-jailed-for-fatally-poisoning-boyfriend-over-false-30-million-inheritance-6840453]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Woman Jailed For Poisoning Boyfriend Over False $30 Million Inheritance]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-woman-jailed-for-fatally-poisoning-boyfriend-over-false-30-million-inheritance-6840453]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 19:21:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[State District Judge Richard Hagar sentenced Kenoyer to 25 years in prison last Wednesday after she pleaded guilty in May.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A North Dakota woman, Ina Thea Kenoyer, 48, has been sentenced to 25 years in prison for poisoning her boyfriend, Steven Riley Jr., 51, after mistakenly believing he had inherited $30 million and planned to break up with her. Riley died last year from ethylene glycol poisoning, a toxic substance commonly found in antifreeze, the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/10/20/us-news/woman-sentenced-to-25-years-for-poisoning-boyfriend-when-thinking-she-inherited-30-million/" rel="nofollow, noindex"><em>New York Post </em></a>reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>During the court hearing in Minot, Stephanie Gonzalez, Riley's sister, confronted Kenoyer, telling her she was fortunate to receive such a lenient sentence, as reported by <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.kxnet.com/video/ina-kenoyer-sentencing/10137085/" rel="nofollow, noindex"><em>KXMB</em></a>. "As so many other families of victims often feel, the punishment should fit the crime," Gonzalez said to Kenoyer. "But lucky for you, the Department of Corrections doesn't serve antifreeze in your iced tea."</p>

<p>State District Judge Richard Hagar sentenced Kenoyer to 25 years in prison last Wednesday after she pleaded guilty in May. In addition to her prison term, Kenoyer received 10 years of supervised probation and was ordered to pay $3,455 in restitution to Riley's family, according to court records.</p>

<p>However, it appears there was never any inheritance at all. Officials revealed that Kenoyer poisoned Riley just hours after discovering an email he had received, claiming he would inherit $30 million.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Ryan Riley, the victim's 21-year-old son, later told The Post that both his father and Kenoyer had fallen victim to an online scam, and no such inheritance actually existed.</p>

<p>On September 3, 2023, while meeting with the supposed estate lawyer, Riley began to feel unwell. Paramedics were called to his home the next day, where they found him unresponsive. He was pronounced dead on September 5.</p>

<p>Kenoyer initially told police that Riley had been drinking heavily and suffered from heat stroke in the days leading up to his death, according to the affidavit. She also claimed that she planned to split Riley's alleged inheritance with his son, asserting that she was entitled to a share as his common-law wife. However, North Dakota does not recognize common-law marriages.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/qk4mhsj8_ina-thea-kenoyer_625x300_21_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kenoyer initially told police that Riley had been drinking heavily]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>