<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Fri, 23 Aug 2024 14:38:47 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/humpback-whale-freed-from-entanglement-after-22-hour-rescue-in-sydney-6400155]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Humpback Whale Freed From Entanglement After 22-Hour Rescue In Sydney]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/humpback-whale-freed-from-entanglement-after-22-hour-rescue-in-sydney-6400155]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 23 Aug 2024 14:12:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A juvenile humpback whale was freed Friday after it was entangled in ropes and buoys in the harbour of Australia's largest city for 22 hours.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A juvenile humpback whale was freed Friday after it was entangled in ropes and buoys in the harbour of Australia's largest city for 22 hours.</p>

<p>Rescuers in Sydney received a call on Thursday afternoon that the whale had become entangled and raced under fading light to save it.</p>

<p>By dawn, rescuers followed the whale in an inflatable boat and used specialised equipment to hold the whale in place while they cut the debris away.</p>

<p>The whale was freed shortly before midday on Friday, and swam off to the open ocean after its 22-hour ordeal.</p>

<p>Jessica Fox, from the Organisation for the Rescue and Research of Cetaceans in Australia, told AFP that efforts to save the whale were "incredible".</p>

<p>"It is not uncommon for a whale to enter Sydney Heads -- they pop their heads in time to time, but to have one entangled in Sydney Harbour is extremely rare."</p>

<p>For decades, humpback whale populations were hunted to the brink of extinction -- at one stage there were only an estimated 1,500 of the animals left in Australian waters.</p>

<p>But they are a rare conservation success story after global protections were afforded to the whales in 1965.</p>

<p>Humpback whale numbers now exceed 40,000 -- a number close to pre-whaling levels -- and the marine animal has since been removed from Australia's threatened species list.</p>

<p>"With so many more whales in the ocean and more humans in the ocean, there is going to be greater potential for conflict," Fox said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/ktst96go_australia-whale_625x300_23_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Humpback whales are a rare conservation success story after global protections were afforded in 1965.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-gaza-mother-separated-from-triplets-by-war-fears-will-die-without-them-6399708]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Gaza Mother Separated From Triplets By War Fears "Will Die Without Them"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-gaza-mother-separated-from-triplets-by-war-fears-will-die-without-them-6399708]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 23 Aug 2024 13:45:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[As their first birthday approaches, the triplets Gaza-native Hanane Bayouk gave birth to in Jerusalem before the war have seen their mother just once, and she fears she will "die without them".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As their first birthday approaches, the triplets Gaza-native Hanane Bayouk gave birth to in Jerusalem before the war have seen their mother just once, and she fears she will "die without them".</p>

<p>The 26-year-old had to return to the Palestinian territory alone after giving birth to Najoua, Nour and Najmeh on August 24, 2023, because her Israeli travel permit had expired.</p>

<p>Bayouk received a permit to exit Gaza and give birth in annexed east Jerusalem's Al-Maqased hospital after seven years of painful IVF procedures.</p>

<p>She caught a glimpse of her children in their incubators, "barely an hour and a half", before driving back to Gaza after her permit "expired and the hospital told me to leave".</p>

<p>Bayouk was supposed to return in early October after her daughters had spent several weeks in incubators, which were in short supply in hospitals in Gaza even before the<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/10-key-moments-in-israel-hamas-war-6240607" target="_blank"> Israel-Hamas war</a> erupted last October.</p>

<h3><strong>Far from the war</strong></h3>

<p>Two days after she applied for a new exit permit on October 5, Hamas commandos blasted through the Erez terminal, the only entry point from Gaza into Israel.</p>

<p>Once in Israel, the operatives carried out an unprecedented attack that left 1,198 people dead, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli official figures.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory military campaign has killed <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/video/gaza-death-count-climbs-to-40-000-as-ceasefire-talks-continue-in-qatar-826405" target="_blank">40,265</a> Palestinians in Gaza, according to the Hamas-run territory's health ministry, which does not give details of civilian and operative deaths. The UN rights office says most of the dead have been women or children.</p>

<p>Like Bayouk, Heba Idriss found herself surrounded by war and unable to return to Jerusalem to get her only daughter, Saida, born prematurely at the Maqased two months earlier.</p>

<p>The 27-year-old had hoped to bring her newborn back to her husband Saleh at their home in Shujaiya, in the northern Gaza Strip.</p>

<p>Instead, the couple has been displaced nine times by <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-airstrikes-target-gaza-ahead-of-ceasefire-talks-6336678" target="_blank">Israeli air strikes</a> or evacuation orders and her husband Saleh has only seen pictures of Saida.</p>

<p>"I want to see my daughter, I suffer so much from being separated from her", she said in tears.</p>

<p>Hanane Bayouk too has been forced from her home and now lives in a displacement persons' camp in the south, sharing a tent with seven of her in-laws.</p>

<p>"It drives me crazy. It took me so long to get pregnant, and now I'm crying all the time," she told AFP on one of the rare days she was able to get through on Gaza's struggling phone network.</p>

<p>"Sometimes, I think I'd like for my daughters to return to Gaza before I die because I have never kissed them, but then I get a hold of myself and tell myself it's better for them to be safe far from the war," she said.</p>

<p>Back at the Maqased, neonatal intensive care unit director Hatem Khammach says that in normal times, there would not have been space to keep Nour, Najmeh, and Najoua for so long.</p>

<h3><strong>I cry every time</strong></h3>

<p>But the number of births at the hospital has fallen sharply as Israel has stopped issuing travel permits to mothers from Gaza and slashed the number given to mothers from the occupied West Bank.</p>

<p>With more checkpoints closed more often, even those with a permit struggle to access specialist treatment in Jerusalem.</p>

<p>"Before the war, we had seven or eight Gaza babies in our department, which can host 30 at a time," Khammach said.</p>

<p>Since October, none have come, "and many sick people from the West Bank can't reach us".</p>

<p>But the hospital's<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/un-warns-of-unacceptable-rising-violence-against-human-aid-workers-6368664" target="_blank"> health workers </a>keep busy, like those who call Bayouk to let her speak on the phone to her three daughters.</p>

<p>"My husband can't do it. I do it and I cry every time we hang up. I'm afraid my daughters will grow up without knowing me," Bayouk said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/0m20cid8_gaza-triplets_625x300_23_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hanane Bayouk had to return to Palestinian territory after giving birth as her Israeli permit had expired]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/andrew-tate-placed-under-house-arrest-latest-case-against-him-explained-6399718]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: Why Andrew Tate Has Been Placed Under House Arrest]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/andrew-tate-placed-under-house-arrest-latest-case-against-him-explained-6399718]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 23 Aug 2024 13:05:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Andrew Tate, who has often courted criticism for his misogynistic views, appeared in court alongside his brother Tristan, who, too, was placed under special judicial control.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Controversial social media influencer Andrew Tate has been once again placed under house arrest in Romania as authorities investigate new allegations of sex trafficking, including exploiting minors. Andrew Tate, who has often courted criticism for his misogynistic views, appeared in court alongside his brother Tristan, who, too, was placed under special judicial control. Prosecutors sought a 30-day custody to investigate the allegations involving 35 victims.</p>

<h3><strong>The Case Against Andrew Tate</strong></h3>

<p>The case against <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/andrew-tate-case-romanian-prosecutors-ask-court-to-extend-andrew-tates-detention-6395035" target="_blank">Andrew Tate</a> involves new allegations of sex trafficking and grooming, being investigated by Romania's anti-organised crime agency, DIICOT.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The allegations include sex with a minor, with Tate accused of having sexual relations with a 15-year-old girl. Additionally, Tate and his brother Tristan are accused of trafficking underage persons, grooming and exploiting "vulnerable" individuals, including minors, for online pornographic content.</p>

<p>One suspect, who remains unnamed, is accused of forcing a 17-year-old girl to perform sexual acts for online content and keeping the $1.5M profit. The man allegedly had sexual relations with another girl who was 15.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to DIICOT, the brothers made some $2.8M through sexual exploitation. Prosecutors further accuse the brothers of money laundering, alleging they bought luxury cars and registered them in other people's names to hide the proceeds of their alleged illicit activity. The investigators have seized luxury items and cash and impounded 16 cars.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The two brothers have also allegedly attempted to intimidate victims and witnesses.&nbsp;</p>

<p>DIICOT revealed that six people, including both Romanians and foreigners, have been detained in total.&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>What Andrew Tate Said</strong></h3>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/misogynist-influencer-andrew-tates-romania-house-raided-over-rape-charges-6384609" target="_blank">Andrew Tate</a> has vehemently denied these allegations, calling the case a "stitch-up" and "absolutely disgusting". He claimed that thirty girls have stated that he and his brother have done nothing wrong and that two of the accusers are mothers of his children who have never been to Romania.</p>

<p>When questioned by a reporter about the allegations of sex with a minor and trafficking underage persons, Tate refused to respond and walked away.</p>

<p>The Tate brothers have faced similar allegations in the past, with previous charges of human trafficking and rape. They were released from house arrest a year ago but were told not to leave Romania.</p>

<p>Despite the mounting allegations, the brothers have consistently denied any wrongdoing and deny the formal charges against them. The new allegations are separate from the previous charges, and the investigation is ongoing.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/4b2pabh8_andrew-tate_625x300_23_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Andrew Tate has vehemently denied these allegations]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-thai-politician-under-investigation-after-slapping-woman-reporter-for-asking-question-6399652]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Video: Thai Politician Slaps Woman Reporter For Asking Question]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-thai-politician-under-investigation-after-slapping-woman-reporter-for-asking-question-6399652]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 23 Aug 2024 12:57:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Thailand's parliament has said that it will investigate veteran politician and former army chief Prawit Wongsuwon after he was filmed slapping a journalist as she tried to ask him questions.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Thailand's parliament has said that it will investigate veteran politician and former army chief Prawit Wongsuwon after he was filmed slapping a journalist as she tried to ask him questions. According to the <em>BBC</em>, Mr Wongsuwon, the Palang Pracharath Party (PPRP) leader, struck a ThaiPBS reporter on the head after she asked him a question about the new prime minister Paetongtarn Shinawatra. The incident took place on Friday and it prompted the reporter to file a formal complaint against the senior politician, following which the Thai parliament said it would investigate the case.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In a video shared on X (formerly Twitter), the senior politician, 79, was seen hitting Duangthip Yiamphop several times around the head as he left a building, demanding, "What are you asking? What? What?" Sharing the clip, a user wrote, "A politician is surrounded by journalists while walking down a corridor when one of them asks him a question. Instead of answering it, he raises his hand and slaps her in the head several times before climbing into his vehicle and driving away."&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Take a look at the video below:&nbsp;</strong></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">A politician is surrounded by journalists while walking down a corridor when one of them asks him a question.<br />
■ Instead of answering it, he raises his hand and slaps her in the head several times before climbing into his vehicle and driving away.<br />
■ Videos of this interaction in… <a href="https://t.co/WjYw7CZtWa">pic.twitter.com/WjYw7CZtWa</a></p>
— Stephen Mutoro (@smutoro) <a href="https://twitter.com/smutoro/status/1826264745755783513?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 21, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Mr Wongsuwon was Thailand's army chief in the early 2000s. According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/article/2024/aug/22/senior-thai-politician-who-slapped-reporter-to-be-investigated" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>The Guardian</em></a>, he was one of the architects of the 2014 coup that ousted the then PM, Yingluck Shinawatra. He then went on to serve as deputy prime minister under the military-backed government that ruled until last year.&nbsp;</p>

<p>After the incident started gaining traction on social media, a PPRP party spokesman said that the 79-year-old knew the journalist well and had apologised, saying he was "teasing her as someone who he is close to" and that he "did not have any bad intention".&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/star-of-my-life-all-about-kamala-harris-mother-shyamala-gopalan-6398652">"Star Of My Life": All About Kamala Harris' Mother, Shyamala Gopalan</a></strong></p>

<p>However, the Thai parliament said it would investigate the slapping after the reporter made a formal complaint. The Thai Journalists Association also condemned Mr Wongsuwon for using "violence against a journalist". It said it "considers his actions to be threatening and harassing toward the rights and freedom of the press".</p>

<p>Separately, Thai PBS has demanded that Mr Wongsuwon "take responsibility for his alleged attempts to intimidate a reporter". Noppadol Srihatai, the executive editor of ThaiPBS, said that the politician's actions "threaten journalism". "He was seen hurting a reporter and we cannot accept it. As a public organisation, we must protect journalists' rights so that media work won't be affected in the future," Mr Srihatai said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/fio4e7s_prawit-wongsuwon_625x300_23_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The incident took place on Friday.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/right-to-disconnect-act-employees-will-have-right-to-ignore-their-bosses-outside-working-hours-6399565]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[In This Country, You Have The Right To Ignore Your Bosses After Hours]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/right-to-disconnect-act-employees-will-have-right-to-ignore-their-bosses-outside-working-hours-6399565]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 23 Aug 2024 12:42:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Australians can ignore their bosses outside of work hours, according to a new law brought to tackle work-related mental health issues.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Australians can ignore their bosses outside of work hours, according to a new law brought to tackle work-related mental health issues. The Fair Work Amendment (Right to Disconnect) Act, which amends the Fair Work Act 2009, moved through parliament earlier this year and will be implemented from August 26.</p>

<p>The <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-these-countries-companies-cant-disturb-staff-after-office-hours-5017694" target="_blank">"Right to Disconnect"&nbsp;</a><span style="box-sizing: border-box; margin: 0px; padding: 0px;"><a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-these-countries-companies-cant-disturb-staff-after-office-hours-5017694" target="_blank">Act</a>&nbsp;protects</span>&nbsp;employees who refuse to monitor, read, or respond to any contact from their employers outside work hours. It, however, allows circumstances where an employee's right to refuse is "unreasonable", depending on their role, the reason for the contact, and how it is made, among other factors.</p>

<p>According to the law, some factors must be considered when determining whether an employee's refusal is unreasonable:</p>

<ul>
	<li>The reason for the contact.</li>
	<li>How the contact is made and how disruptive it is to the employee.</li>
	<li>Whether the employee is compensated or paid extra for being available to be contacted to perform work within a specific period, or working additional hours outside their ordinary hours of work.</li>
	<li>The nature of the employee's role and level of responsibility.</li>
	<li>The employee's personal circumstances, including family or caring responsibilities.</li>
</ul>

<p>The <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/the-latest-country-to-give-right-to-ignore-calls-emails-after-hours-5016616" target="_blank">law</a>&nbsp;has drawn criticism from employer groups who call it rushed and flawed.</p>

<p>Similar laws giving employees <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/webstories/feature/countries-where-companies-cant-disturb-staff-after-work-hours-13243" target="_blank">a right to switch off their devices</a> are already in place in France, Belgium, Italy, Argentina, Chile, Luxembourg, Mexico, Philippines, Russia, Slovakia, Spain, Ontario, and Ireland. &nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/u010fcrg_office_625x300_23_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Representational Image]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/when-will-sunita-williams-come-back-to-earth-nasa-shares-big-update-6399519]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[When Will Sunita Williams Come Back To Earth? Nasa Shares Big Update]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/when-will-sunita-williams-come-back-to-earth-nasa-shares-big-update-6399519]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 23 Aug 2024 12:37:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Astronauts Sunita Williams and Butchwilmore have been stuck in space since June 6 and are hoping to make their way back to Earth soon, but NASA says they may have to spend the next few days in uncertainty too.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Astronauts Sunita Williams and Butchwilmore have been stuck in space since June 6 and are hoping to make their way back to Earth soon, but Nasa says they may have to spend the next few days in uncertainty too.</p>

<p>NASA is expected to take a final decision on Saturday to bring Sunita Williams back to Earth on Boeing's Starliner spacecraft or on SpaceX's Dragon capsule, the US space agency said.</p>

<p>"NASA's decision on whether to return Starliner to Earth with astronauts aboard is expected no earlier than August 24 (Saturday) at the conclusion of an agency-level review," the space agency said in a statement.</p>

<p>What began as an eight-day sojourn on the International Space Station (ISS) has extended to more than two months in space for Williams and Willmore -- the duo who became the first to ride the much-delayed Starliner.</p>

<p>As Starliner approached the orbiting lab, the spacecraft experienced a series of technical issues such as the failure of several thrusters and helium leaks in the propulsion system.</p>

<p>While engineers were able to bring four of the five malfunctioning thrusters back online (there are 28 thrusters on Starliner), it still raises a concern about “a successful de-orbit” to Earth.</p>

<p>Although Boeing proclaimed the safety of Starliner, NASA officials have disagreed.</p>

<p>If the US space agency deems Starliner unfit to travel on Saturday, it would undock uncrewed from the orbiting lab.</p>

<p>Williams and Wilmore will return onboard a SpaceX Dragon capsule in February 2025, as NASA has delayed the launch of the SpaceX Crew-9 mission to the ISS to September 24.</p>

<p>After many setbacks for years, Boeing launched its first flight on June 5.</p>

<p>Together with SpaceX, the company signed a contract in 2014 with NASA's Commercial Crew Programme to fly operational missions to and from the space station.</p>

<p>In 2019, its debut uncrewed orbital flight mission did not go as planned. The mission was completed in 2022.</p>

<p>SpaceX's Dragon capsules have been launching astronauts to space on its Falcon 9 rockets since 2020. It has so far aced about 12 flights to the Space Station.</p>

<p>While Boeing has poured over $1.5 billion into its Starliner programme, NASA has paid the aerospace giant about $4.2 billion over the years.</p>

<p>Both Boeing's Starliner and SpaceX's Dragon were aimed to ferry astronauts and cargo for NASA missions to low Earth orbit, the Moon, Mars, and beyond.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/gpei299g_sunita-williams_625x300_23_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/meet-maya-harris-the-sister-of-us-vice-president-kamala-harris-6399041]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Who is Maya Harris, Sister Of US Vice President Kamala Harris]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/meet-maya-harris-the-sister-of-us-vice-president-kamala-harris-6399041]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 23 Aug 2024 12:03:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Maya Harris was the campaign chairperson during Kamala Harris' first presidential campaign in 2020.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US Vice President Kamala Harris has accepted the Democratic Party nomination for the US Presidential elections. On the fourth and final night of the Democratic National Convention (DNC) in Chicago, her sister <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-kamala-harris-in-her-biggest-speech-yet-remembers-mother-dr-shyamala-gopalan-harris-6398395">Maya Harris</a> addressed the attendees and spoke at length about her relationship with the US Vice-President and their late mother, Shyamala Gopalan Harris.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Noting their mother would be proud to see Kamala Harris as the Democratic Party nominee, Maya said that she raised them to "believe that we could be and do anything, and we believed her".</p>

<p>"She knew that we could be the authors of our own story," she said, adding that her elder sister has been "fighting for each of us to have that freedom."&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Who is Maya Harris?</strong></p>

<p>Maya, the younger sister of the US vice president, has remained a major part of her life and professional career over the decades.</p>

<p>When Kamala and Maya's parents -- Donald Harris and Shyamala Gopalan -- parted ways, the two sisters decided to live with their mother. At the time, they were just 12 and nine years old.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/shyamala-gopalan-harris-all-about-kamala-harris-mother-who-grew-up-in-india-and-moved-to-us-6398700"><strong>Also Read: All About Kamala Harris' Mother, Who Grew Up In India And Moved To US</strong></a></p>

<p>Maya later attended the Stanford Law School before working as a civil litigator. Then she became an adjunct law professor and Dean of Lincoln Law School of San Jose.</p>

<p>In her career, Maya has majorly focused on policy and civil rights, besides racial and gender justice. She was also a visiting scholar at Harvard Law School and a senior fellow at the Center for American Progress.</p>

<p>She was also the vice president of democracy, rights and justice at the Ford Foundation and executive director of the ACLU of Northern California.</p>

<p><strong>Involvement in presidential campaigns</strong></p>

<p>In 2020, Maya was the campaign chairperson during Kamala Harris' first presidential campaign.</p>

<p>Before that, she even worked as the senior policy advisor to Hillary Clinton during her presidential run in 2016. At the time, she used to lead the group of policy experts, besides developing Clinton's domestic policy.</p>

<p><strong>Family</strong></p>

<p>Maya welcomed her only child, daughter Meena, when she was a teenager.</p>

<p>Interestingly when Meena was just four, she played a matchmaker and introduced her mother to Tony West, who later became her husband.</p>

<p>In an interview with Stanford Lawyer in 2010, she said that Meena played a game of hide-and-seek with West on the campus of the university while they were just students. The two started dating after graduation.</p>

<p>Maya has two granddaughters -- Amara and Leela -- and often posts photographs with them on social media.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/p6ps02po_maya-harris-afp_625x300_23_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[In her career, Maya Harris has majorly focused on policy and civil rights.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-slams-kamala-harris-speech-trying-to-gaslight-america-6399161]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Trying To Gaslight America": Donald Trump On Kamala Harris' Speech]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-slams-kamala-harris-speech-trying-to-gaslight-america-6399161]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 23 Aug 2024 11:35:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[As Kamala Harris spoke, Donald Trump posted about 37 times on his Truth Social platform, launching a series of critical comments against her. ]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former US President Donald Trump went all guns blazing in his response to Vice President Kamala Harris' Democratic nomination acceptance speech on Thursday.</p>

<p>Harris took the stage on the fourth day of the Democratic National Convention in Chicago, promising to be a president for all Americans.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In her speech, she talked about her commitment to serving all Americans and upholding the country's core principles. "You can always trust me to put country above party and self. To hold sacred America's fundamental principles from the rule of law to free and fair elections, to the peaceful transfer of power," she told supporters.</p>

<p>As she spoke, Trump posted about 37 times on his Truth Social platform, launching into a tirade against her.&nbsp;</p>

<p>His first post, as her speech began, read: "WATCH KAMALA TRY TO GASLIGHT AMERICA..." &nbsp;</p>

<p><iframe allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" class="truthsocial-embed truthsocial-video" src="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/113009224720203152/embed" style="max-width: 100%; border: 0" width="600"></iframe><script src="https://truthsocial.com/embed.js" async="async"></script></p>

<p>Throughout her address, Harris discussed a range of topics, including her stance on national security, immigration and Trump's influence on the Supreme Court. She also blamed the Republican nominee for the failure of a bipartisan border bill earlier in the year. The Vice-President called it the "strongest border bill in decades," and accused him of playing politics with national security.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In response, Trump posted, "Why didn't she do something about the things of which she complains?"</p>

<p>Referring to her vice-presidential tenure, the former president added, "She said, 'Chart a new way forward,' but she's had three and a half years, and has done nothing but HARM!"</p>

<p>Trump accused Harris of incompetence, weakness, and radicalism. He claimed she wanted to grant citizenship to undocumented immigrants, adding she supported violent rioters during the protests in Minnesota.&nbsp;</p>

<p><iframe allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" class="truthsocial-embed" src="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/113009066397212800/embed" style="max-width: 100%; border: 0" width="600"></iframe><script src="https://truthsocial.com/embed.js" async="async"></script></p>

<p>"She stands for Incompetence and Weakness - Our Country is being laughed at all over the World!," Trump wrote on his social media platform.</p>

<p><iframe allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" class="truthsocial-embed" src="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/113009133460070875/embed" style="max-width: 100%; border: 0" width="600"></iframe><script src="https://truthsocial.com/embed.js" async="async"></script></p>

<p>In another post, the former president called her a "Radical Marxist." "She just called to give all Illegals CITIZENSHIP, SAY GOODBYE TO THE U.S.A.! SHE IS A RADICAL MARXIST!"</p>

<p><iframe allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" class="truthsocial-embed" src="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/113009120925667027/embed" style="max-width: 100%; border: 0" width="600"></iframe><script src="https://truthsocial.com/embed.js" async="async"></script></p>

<p>He also took issue with her remarks on the rule of law, pointing out her role as "Border Czar" and accusing her of allowing millions of undocumented immigrants into the country, many of whom he described as "criminals".&nbsp;</p>

<p><iframe allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" class="truthsocial-embed" src="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/113009055608083509/embed" style="max-width: 100%; border: 0" width="600"></iframe><script src="https://truthsocial.com/embed.js" async="async"></script></p>

<p>Kamala Harris also used her speech to address the overturning of Roe v Wade, which ended federal protections for abortion in 2022. She pointed to Trump's role in appointing three conservative justices to the Supreme Court, which she said directly led to the landmark decision's reversal.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Trump responded on Truth Social, arguing both Democrats and Republicans wanted Roe v Wade overturned to return the decision to the states and that the people are now voting on the issue, as it was "supposed to be."</p>

<p><iframe allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" class="truthsocial-embed" src="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/113009103940625194/embed" style="max-width: 100%; border: 0" width="600"></iframe><script src="https://truthsocial.com/embed.js" async="async"></script></p>

<p>Earlier in the day, Trump claimed Harris "became the Nominee without receiving one Vote, stealing the Nomination from Crooked Joe Biden, who earned it by getting 14 Million Votes."&nbsp;</p>

<p>This comes just weeks before the Trump vs Harris presidential debate on September 10.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/06lu95io_kamala-harris-donald-trump-afp_625x300_03_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-kamala-harris-grandnieces-tutorial-on-pronouncing-leaders-name-6399146]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Video: Kamala Harris' Grandnieces' Tutorial On Pronouncing Leader's Name]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-kamala-harris-grandnieces-tutorial-on-pronouncing-leaders-name-6399146]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 23 Aug 2024 11:31:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ahead of Kamala Harris' historic speech on the final night of the Democratic National Convention, her grandnieces took the stage to give an unusual tutorial to the crowd.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ahead of Kamala Harris' historic speech on the final night of the Democratic National Convention, her grandnieces took the stage to give an unusual tutorial to the crowd. Introduced by actor Kerry Washington, the two girls offered to help the crowd learn how to properly pronounce the US vice president's name.</p>

<p>"It's come to my attention that there are some folks who struggle — or pretend to struggle — with the proper pronunciation of our future president's name. Confusion is understandable. Disrespect is not. So tonight we are going to help everyone get it right," the actor said before the two children walked on to a cheering crowd.</p>

<p>Eight-year-old Amara and six-year-old Leela, daughters of Harris' niece Meena Harris, were wearing a pink pantsuit and a blue dress.</p>

<p>"First you say ‘comma' like the comma in a sentence," Amara said. "Then you say ‘la' like la-la-la-la-la," added Leela.</p>

<p>Then it was the crowd's turn to practice. "Comma! La!, Comma! La!, Kama La" they roared.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Amara and Leela Ajagu — the daughters of Kamala Harris' niece, Meena Harris — joined actress Kerry Washington on stage to teach people — hint, hint — how to pronounce their “auntie's” name, “Kamala.” <a href="https://t.co/MLmaOd2BG4">pic.twitter.com/MLmaOd2BG4</a></p>
— Andreas Sandre (@andreas212nyc) <a href="https://twitter.com/andreas212nyc/status/1826806449634148388?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 23, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>The girls' mother and Harris' niece also took the stage talking about growing up with her. “I grew up in Oakland, California in a house full of extraordinary women my mom, my grandma and my auntie who showed me the meaning of service, helping her sister, a 17 year old single mom fighting for justice for the American people and still cooking Sunday family dinner. She guided me. Now she's guiding my own children and I know she'll guide our country forward," she said.</p>

<p>In the past, several leaders have stumbled while pronouncing the Indian-origin leader's name.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Most prominently, her now rival and Republican candidate Donald Trump has prided himself on mispronouncing her name, often using it as a way to dismiss her as competition. &nbsp;</p>

<p>When asked why, Trump said he had heard Harris' first name said "about seven different ways."</p>

<p>"Don't worry about it, it doesn't matter what I say. I couldn't care less," he said.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/5sqqovh8_kamala-harris-grandnieces_625x300_23_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-kamala-harris-on-gaza-war-what-kamala-harris-said-on-gaza-war-6399111]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Now Is The Time To...": What Kamala Harris Said On Gaza War]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-kamala-harris-on-gaza-war-what-kamala-harris-said-on-gaza-war-6399111]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 23 Aug 2024 11:29:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Vice President Kamala Harris, accepting the Democratic presidential nomination, pledged to broker a ceasefire in the Gaza conflict and solidify support for Ukraine, while criticizing her Republican opponent Donald Trump's stance.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Vice President Kamala Harris, accepting the Democratic presidential nomination, pledged to broker a ceasefire in the Gaza conflict and solidify support for Ukraine, while criticizing her Republican opponent Donald Trump's stance.</p>

<p>On the final, and most anticipated, night of the four-day Chicago convention, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-message-for-america-as-she-accepts-presidential-nomination-6398145">Harris, 59, promised</a> to chart a "New Way Forward" as she and Trump, 78, enter the final 11 weeks of the razor-close campaign.</p>

<p>"Now is the time to get a hostage deal and a ceasefire deal done," <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-kamala-harris-in-her-biggest-speech-yet-remembers-mother-dr-shyamala-gopalan-harris-6398395">Kamala Harris</a> told her supporters at the Democratic National Convention as she accepted the party's presidential nomination.</p>

<p>"And let me be clear, I will always stand up for Israel's right to defend itself and I will always ensure Israel has the ability to defend itself," she said</p>

<p>"What has happened in Gaza over the past 10 months is devastating. So many innocent lives lost, desperate hungry people fleeing for safety over and over again. The scale of suffering is heartbreaking," she added.</p>

<p>"President Biden and I are working to end this war such that Israel is secure, the hostages are released, the suffering in Gaza ends and the Palestinian people can realize their right to dignity, security, freedom and self-determination."</p>

<p><strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-message-for-america-as-she-accepts-presidential-nomination-6398145">Also Read: Kamala Harris' Donald Trump Warning As She Accepts Presidential Nomination</a></strong></p>

<p>The speech laid out some broad policy principles, foreign and domestic, but left unsaid specific details which in weeks to come she could be pressured to provide.</p>

<p>After days of protests from Palestinian supporters who were disappointed at not getting a speaking spot at the convention, Harris delivered a pledge to secure Israel, bring the hostages home from Gaza and end the war in the Palestinian enclave.</p>

<p>Attacking Trump for his frequent denigration of NATO and Ukraine, she said that "as president I will stand strong with Ukraine and our NATO allies."</p>

<p>Ms Harris called out Trump's public praise for Russian President Vladimir Putin and North Korea's Kim Jong Un, saying "I will not cozy up to tyrants and dictators."</p>

<p>Tyrants are "rooting for Trump, because you know, they know he is easy to manipulate with flattery and favors. They know Trump won't hold autocrats accountable because he wants to be an autocrat himself," she said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/4ph9j3d_gaza-reuters_625x300_15_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US Presidential Elections: Kamala Harris pledged to broker a ceasefire in the Gaza conflict.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/5-key-takeaways-from-the-democratic-national-convention-6399099]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Five Key Takeaways From The Democratic National Convention]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/5-key-takeaways-from-the-democratic-national-convention-6399099]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 23 Aug 2024 11:26:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[It was Kamala Harris's big night Thursday but she wasn't the only US Democrat to knock it out of the park during a week of rousing speeches, celebrity cameos and lashings of hope and joy.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It was Kamala Harris's big night Thursday but she wasn't the only US Democrat to knock it out of the park during a week of rousing speeches, celebrity cameos and lashings of hope and joy.</p>

<h2><strong>Here are some takeaways from the Democratic National Convention in Chicago.</strong></h2>

<h3><strong>Star-studded convention</strong></h3>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/let-us-choose-joy-oprah-winfrey-urges-us-voters-in-chicago-6396583" target="_blank">Oprah Winfrey </a>stole the show, exhorting voters to "choose joy" and Stevie Wonder took the convention to "Higher Ground."</p>

<p>John Legend lit up the United Center with a tribute to Prince, while comic actress Mindy Kaling shared stories of cooking lessons from the vice president.</p>

<p>And there was comedy with a serious message from Saturday Night Live star Kenan Thompson, who brought a giant book on stage to represent the radical Trump-linked Project 2025 governing agenda.</p>

<p>There was feverish speculation over a potential appearance by global superstar Beyonce, but it didn't pan out.</p>

<h3><strong>Family affair</strong></h3>

<p>On the biggest stage of their careers, political leaders often look to dewy-eyed family moments that, if seen as genuine, can humanize them and make them relatable to voters.</p>

<p>Minnesota Governor Tim Walz's 17-year-old son Gus touched a nation as he wiped away joyous tears, pointed to his father accepting the vice presidential nomination and sobbed: "That's my dad!"</p>

<p>Second Gentleman Doug Emhoff provided another indelible memory, referring to Harris as "my wiiiiife" as he recounted the goofy, endearing story of their romance.</p>

<p>And President Joe Biden's daughter Ashley was a highlight of the opening night as she paid tribute to "the O.G. Girl Dad."</p>

<h3><strong>Obamas sizzle</strong></h3>

<p>Barack and Michelle Obama -- the undisputed power couple of Democratic politics -- partied like it was 2008 as they gave the convention a shot of star power on Day Two.</p>

<p>The 44th president got the night's biggest laugh as he <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/barack-obama-michelle-obama-donald-trump-obamas-back-kamala-harris-as-president-shred-donald-trump-for-his-lies-6382885" target="_blank">goaded Donald Trump </a>over the Republican's "obsession with crowd sizes."</p>

<p>But he was upstaged by the former first lady -- by far the country's most popular Democrat -- who spoke of the "contagious power of hope" in the most cheered speech of the week.</p>

<p>The party made use of a deep bench of luminaries, including former president Bill Clinton, whose raspy speech was more than twice the allotted time but included some memorable applause lines.</p>

<h3><strong>Gaza fizzles</strong></h3>

<p>There were <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/democrats-cheer-joe-biden-and-kamala-harris-in-chicago-convention-amid-protester-march-6368883" target="_blank">protests across Chicago</a> against the administration's handling of the Israel-Hamas war, and particularly over the decision not to allow a Palestinian American to speak from the main stage.</p>

<p>The largest protest Thursday featured several thousand marchers, but was still much smaller than the demonstrations of tens of thousands predicted by organizers, and was not the fly in the ointment that the Democrats had feared.</p>

<p>Protests were largely peaceful, although several demonstrators were arrested when they broke through a security fence earlier in the week around the United Center where the main program was staged.</p>

<p>Although the activists were largely pro-Palestinian, they were joined by others marching against a variety of progressive causes, from reproductive rights to migrant welfare.</p>

<h3><strong>Bye bye Biden</strong></h3>

<p>The president gave an emotional keynote speech to open a conference that he thought just weeks ago he would be headlining.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-to-pass-torch-to-kamala-harris-at-democratic-convention-10-points-6373095" target="_blank">Biden</a> took to the stage, dabbing his eyes, and spoke at length about his achievements while making a case for Harris that was criticized for lacking the pizzazz of the Obama endorsements.</p>

<p>Flanked by First Lady Jill Biden and Harris, the veteran Democrat's final bow marked at long last the passing of the torch for a politician who has been in the public eye for more than half a century.</p>

<p>"Democracy has prevailed. Democracy has delivered. And now democracy must be preserved," he declared, to one of many standing ovations from the rapt audience.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/qp4pb238_kamala-harris-afp-_625x300_23_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[There were protests across Chicago against the administration's handling of the Israel-Hamas war (File).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-is-our-auntie-all-about-us-vice-presidents-nieces-and-nephews-6399047]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Our Auntie": All About Kamala Harris' Nieces And Nephews]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-is-our-auntie-all-about-us-vice-presidents-nieces-and-nephews-6399047]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 23 Aug 2024 11:20:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US Vice President Kamala Harris' godson, niece and nephew - Alexander Hudlin, Arden Emhoff and Jasper Emhoff - participated in the Democratic National Convention (DNC) on Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US Vice President Kamala Harris' godson, niece and nephew - &nbsp;Alexander Hudlin, Arden Emhoff and Jasper Emhoff&nbsp;- participated in the Democratic National Convention (DNC) on Wednesday. The three gave a speech about their "auntie", following a speech by former House Speaker Nancy Pelosi at the United Center in Chicago. They shared some stories about their relationship with her growing up. "Kamala Harris is our auntie," Jasper said, while Arden continued, "She'll be a president who cares for all of us."</p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://people.com/all-about-kamala-harris-nieces-nephews-8700253" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>People</em></a>, Kamala Harris has one sister, Maya Harris, who is the mother of Meena Harris. The vice president is also an aunt to nieces and nephews on her husband Doug Emhoff's side, including his brother Andrew Emhoff's daughter Arden and son Jasper. Mr Emhoff also has a sister, Jackie, who has children as well. In addition to being an aunt, Ms Harris is also a great-aunt to Ms Meena's daughters, Amara and Leela.</p>

<h3><strong>Now, as Kamala Harris' nieces and nephews take centre stage at the DNC, here's everything to know about them</strong></h3>

<h2>Meena Harris&nbsp;</h2>

<p>Meena Harris, daughter of Kamala Harris' sister Maya, has been open about growing up in an all-women household from her mother and aunt to her grandmother, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/star-of-my-life-all-about-kamala-harris-mother-shyamala-gopalan-6398652">Shyamala Gopalan</a>. According to the outlet, she described what it was like having "incredible women of colour running around" and how they inspired her to be ambitious.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"They were all in service and had a purpose. I appreciate that even more as an adult just how informative that was for me and I think about how I'm raising my own children, not only how I can carry that legacy forward but also that my kids in many good ways are growing up in a different environment," Meena Harris said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.newsweek.com/kamala-harris-family-tree-dnc-2024-emhoff-1943293" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>Newsweek</em></a>, the 39-year-old is the founder and CEO of Phenomenal, a consumer and media company. She is also a lawyer and author and has worked on her aunt's 2022 presidential campaign.&nbsp;</p>

<h2>Jasper Emhoff</h2>

<p>Jasper Emhoff is the son of Doug Emhoff's brother, Andy. Emhoff has a sister as well. He grew up in Santa Cruz, California. Like is cousin, he is also building an impressive career for himself after graduating from the University of California, Berkeley, in 2023 with a degree in computer science.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Since graduating, Jasper started working as a machine learning engineer at Stealth Startup, People reported.&nbsp;</p>

<h2>Arden Emhoff&nbsp;</h2>

<p>Arden Emhoff is Jasper's sister. She made a rare public appearance on Wednesday when she spoke in favour of her aunty at the DNC. Arden shared how "even as a kid, Auntie made me feel that I was seen, that my words are important, that I am important and loved".&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-message-for-america-as-she-accepts-presidential-nomination-6398145">Kamala Harris' Donald Trump Warning As She Accepts Presidential Nomination</a></strong></p>

<p>"I know she will value others perspectives no matter their age or background," Arden said. "Let's win this thing."</p>

<h2>Kamala Harris' great-nieces</h2>

<p>The vice president is a great-aunt to Ms Meena's daughters, Amara and Leela. The two little girls made headlines for dressing up like the vice president, including donning fur coats to Ms Harris' inauguration in 2021. Leela also twinned with her aunt at this year's DNC as well. She reportedly wore a tan suit inspired by Kamala Harris' bespoke tan wood suit.&nbsp;<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/kg7basfg_kamala-harris_625x300_23_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Meena Harris is daughter of Kamala Harris' sister Maya.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/shyamala-gopalan-harris-all-about-kamala-harris-mother-who-grew-up-in-india-and-moved-to-us-6398700]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[All About Kamala Harris' Mother, Who Grew Up In India And Moved To US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/shyamala-gopalan-harris-all-about-kamala-harris-mother-who-grew-up-in-india-and-moved-to-us-6398700]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 23 Aug 2024 10:16:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kamala Harris accepted the Democratic presidential nomination in Chicago today and remembered her Indian-origin mother Shyamala Gopalan Harris before a rapturous crowd.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kamala Harris accepted the Democratic presidential nomination in Chicago today and remembered her Indian-origin mother Shyamala Gopalan Harris before a rapturous crowd. Taking center stage on the last day of the Democratic Party convention, she said her mother was only 19 when she crossed the world alone, travelling from India to California with an "unshakeable dream to be the scientist who would cure breast cancer".</p>

<p>"My mother Shyamala Harris had one of her own. I miss her every day -- especially now. And I know she's looking down tonight, and smiling," she told the gathering in Chicago.</p>

<p>"... It was mostly my mother who raised us. Before she could finally afford to buy a home, she rented a small apartment in the East Bay. In the Bay, you either live in the hills or the flatlands. We lived in the flats -- a beautiful working-class neighbourhood of firefighters, nurses, and construction workers, all of whom tended their lawns with pride," Ms Harris added.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-kamala-harris-in-her-biggest-speech-yet-remembers-mother-dr-shyamala-gopalan-harris-6398395" target="_blank">Shyamala Gopalan Harris</a> was a breast cancer specialist who emigrated from Tamil Nadu in 1960 to pursue a doctorate in endocrinology at the University of California Berkeley.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-when-my-mother-shyamala-gopalan-harris-came-from-india-she-didnt-imagine-2322213" target="_blank">ALSO READ | "When My Mother Came From India, She Didn't Imagine...": Kamala Harris</a></strong><br />
<br />
"When she finished school, she was supposed to return home to a traditional arranged marriage, but as fate would have it, she met my father, Donald Harris, a student from Jamaica. They fell in love and got married, and that act of self-determination made my sister, Maya, and me," Ms Harris said in her speech.</p>

<p>Kamala's sister, Maya Harris, also spoke at the Chicago event and recalled how their mother moved to the US from India to pursue a better life and encouraged her daughters to be "the authors of our own stories."</p>

<p>"Mommy's journey, and the opportunity that she wanted for Kamala and me - that's a distinctly American story," she said.</p>

<p><strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-kamala-harris-learnt-from-her-mother-dont-complain-do-something-2278643" target="_blank">ALSO READ | "Don't Complain, Do Something": What Kamala Harris Learnt From Her Mother</a></strong><br />
<br />
She also mentioned that if their late mother was here, she would say how proud she was of her daughter. Then, "without missing a beat, she'd say, "That's enough. You've got work to do."</p>

<h3><strong>Kamala Harris' India Connection</strong></h3>

<p>Kamala Harris, 59, was born in Oakland, California in 1964 to Afro-Jamaican Donald Harris, who came to the US to study economics, and Shyamala Gopalan.</p>

<p>Her parents met at the University of California, a hub of student activism while participating in the civil rights movement.</p>

<p>Donald Harris is a professor emeritus at Stanford University, while Shyamala Gopalan&nbsp;died of cancer on February 11, 2009, a year before Kamala was elected as California's attorney general.</p>

<p>After the couple divorced, Shyamala&nbsp;Gopalan raised Kamala and her younger sister Maya.</p>

<p>She took them on trips to India and often expressed affection or frustration in Tamil, Kamala wrote in her 2019 book, "The Truths We Hold."</p>

<p>Kamala Harris has often spoken about her India connection and the influence of her maternal grandfather, PV Gopalan.</p>

<p>PV Gopalan left Thulasendrapuram, a village in Tamil Nadu decades ago, but residents say the family has maintained close links and has regularly donated to the temple's upkeep.</p>

<p>Earlier today, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/vivek-ramaswamy-says-kamala-harris-is-cog-in-wheel-and-puppet-6397740" target="_blank">Kamala Harris</a> formally accepted the Democratic Party's 2024 presidential nomination to fight against her Republican rival Donald Trump. Ms Harris emerged as the Democratic candidate after President Joe Biden, 81, was forced to quit the race for the White House last month. If successful, she will become the first woman elected US president.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/jau5lu9g_shyamala-gopalan-harris_625x300_23_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kamala Harris' mother Shyamala Gopalan was a breast cancer specialist]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/unlikely-journeys-kamala-harris-reflects-on-her-indian-roots-in-dnc-speech-6398691]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[In Kamala Harris' Democratic Convention Speech, A Mention Of India]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/unlikely-journeys-kamala-harris-reflects-on-her-indian-roots-in-dnc-speech-6398691]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 23 Aug 2024 10:12:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kamala Harris took to the stage, not just as a candidate for the highest office in the land but as a proud daughter of immigrants as well. ]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On the fourth night of the Democratic National Convention (DNC), US Vice President Kamala Harris accepted her party's nomination for the President of the United States. Amid the cheers and applause, Harris not only laid out her vision for America but also touched upon a deeply personal narrative - one that connects her to her South Asian roots through her mother, Shyamala Gopalan.</p>

<p>Kamala Harris' candidature came after President Joe Biden announced his decision to drop out of the presidential race and endorsed the VP as the party's nominee last month.&nbsp;</p>

<p>On Thursday, the room erupted into applause as she began her speech, surrounded by supporters holding 'Kamala' placards in blue. In her address to the nation at the DNC, Harris began by acknowledging the journey that brought her to this historic moment. "The journey has been unexpected, but I am no stranger to unlikely journeys," she began. &nbsp;</p>

<p>Kamala Harris's mother, Shyamala Gopalan, who died in 2009, played an instrumental role in shaping the Vice President's identity and values. Harris spoke fondly of her mother, recalling the courage and determination that led a 19-year-old Shyamala to leave India for the US. "My mother was 19 when she crossed the world alone, travelling from India to California with an unshakable dream to be the scientist who would cure breast cancer," Harris shared, her voice filled with pride.</p>

<p><iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="315" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/nKNW_KHYrbY?si=XFeJYMnzoz0Xjwwz" title="YouTube video player" width="560"></iframe></p>

<p>Shyamala Gopalan's journey was supposed to be temporary - she was expected to return to India after completing her studies, where an arranged marriage awaited her. However, destiny had plans, revealed the Democratic nominee.&nbsp;</p>

<p>While studying at the University of California, Berkeley, Shyamala Gopalan met Donald Harris, a Jamaican student. "They fell in love and got married, and that act of self-determination made my sister Maya and me," Harris told the audience.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Harris also reminisced about her childhood, filled with memories of frequent moves due to her parents' careers. "Growing up, we moved a lot. I will always remember that big Mayflower truck, packed with all our belongings, ready to go to Illinois, to Wisconsin, and wherever our parents' jobs took us," she said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"My early memories of our parents together are very joyful ones. A home filled with laughter and music, coal train, and miles," Harris recalled. Her father's influence, particularly in her formative years, was also a significant theme in her speech. "In my earliest years, he taught me to be fearless," she said, reflecting on the words of encouragement he often gave her: "Run, Kamala, run. Don't be afraid, don't let anything stop you."&nbsp;</p>

<p>Shayamala Goapalan's father, a civil servant, was a supporter of India's struggle for independence from British rule - a spirit of activism that Shyamala carried with her to the United States. In Berkeley, she became involved in the Civil Rights Movement.</p>

<p>Shyamala earned her doctorate by the age of 25 and later became a renowned breast cancer researcher.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Today, when Kamala Harris stood before the nation, she wasn't just a candidate for the highest office in the land but a proud daughter of immigrants as well. "On behalf of my mother and everyone who has ever set out on their own unlikely journey... I accept your nomination for president of the United States of America," Harris declared as the room erupted into applause.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/gs5frbgs_kamala-harris_625x300_23_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/star-of-my-life-all-about-kamala-harris-mother-shyamala-gopalan-6398652]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Star Of My Life": All About Kamala Harris' Mother, Shyamala Gopalan]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/star-of-my-life-all-about-kamala-harris-mother-shyamala-gopalan-6398652]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 23 Aug 2024 10:08:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[When US Vice President Kamala Harris talks about her South Asian identity, it's usually in the context of her mother, Shyamala Gopalan. The same was true on Thursday during Ms Harris' speech on the fourth night of the DNC.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When US Vice President Kamala Harris talks about her South Asian identity, it's usually in the context of her mother, Shyamala Gopalan. The same was true on Thursday during Ms Harris' speech on the fourth night of the Democratic National Convention (DNC). "My mother was 19 when she crossed the world alone, travelling from India to California with an unshakable dream," Ms Harris said during her speech. "She taught us to never complain about injustice, but to do something about it," she added.&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>Now, as Kamala Harris secured the 2024 Democratic presidential nomination, here's everything to know about her mother, Dr Shyamala Gopalan Harris.</strong></h3>

<p>Shyamala Gopalan, a breast cancer researcher, died in 2009 at the age of 70 of colon cancer. She was born and raised in Chennai (then called Madras). According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/politics/elections/2024/08/22/kamala-harriss-mother-shyamala-gopalan/74774514007/" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>USA Today</em></a>, she was born to a civil servant father and a homemaker mother, and she was the eldest of four. &nbsp;</p>

<p>At just 19, soon after she graduated from the University of Delhi, Ms Gopalan defied cultural norms by pursuing a PhD in nutrition and endocrinology at the University of California, Berkeley. Her decision to move to the United States was a bold one, especially for a young woman from a conservative Tamil Brahmin community.&nbsp;</p>

<p>After moving to the US, Ms Gopalan almost immediately gravitated to the Black community and found a common cause in the Civil Rights Movement. At one such meeting in 1962, she met Donald Harris, a student from Jamaica who was pursuing a doctorate in economics. The two got married a year later, in 1963.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In 1964, at age 25, Ms Gopalan earned her doctorate and gave birth to Kamala Harris. Two years later, she gave birth to Maya Harris, who is now a civil rights champion. But the marriage didn't last and the couple divorced in 1971.</p>

<p>Ms Gopalan raised her two daughters in the highly diverse working community in the Berkeley Flats neighbourhood, as per <em>USA Today</em>. During her DNC speech, Ms Harris said that despite her mother's success, her life as a new immigrant was often marred by racism.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"My mother was a brilliant 5-foot-tall brown woman with an accent," she said. "As the eldest child, I saw how the world would sometimes treat her. But my mother never lost her cool."</p>

<p>Ms Gopalan went on to become a distinguished breast cancer researcher. Her work took her all over the world, doing research in France and Canada.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-kamala-harris-in-her-biggest-speech-yet-remembers-mother-dr-shyamala-gopalan-harris-6398395">Kamala Harris, In Her Biggest Speech Yet, Remembers "Trailblazer" Mother</a></strong></p>

<p>According to her obituary published in the <em>San Francisco Chronicle</em>, she began her career conducting research at the school's zoology department and its cancer research lab. She published numerous notable research papers and spent time at many of the top research institutions in the US and around the world.</p>

<p>Ms Gopalan worked at the University of Illinois, the University of Wisconsin and abroad in France and Italy. She spent 16 years at McGill University's Lady Davis Institute for Medical Research at the Jewish General Hospital in Canada. During the last decade of her work, she returned to UC Berkeley to conduct research within the Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory.</p>

<p>Ms Gopalan received numerous honours for her work as a research scientist. Notably, her discovery related to the hormone-responsiveness of breast tissue led to many subsequent advances, according to Breast Cancer Action.</p>

<p>Notably, since becoming vice president, Kamala Harris has continued talking about the advice she got from her mother. In her 2019 memoir, 'The Truths We Hold', Ms Harris also wrote, "Mommy, you are the star of this book because you are the reason for everything. There is no title or honour on earth I'll treasure more than to say I am Shyamala Gopalan Harris' daughter."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/2ul261o8_kamala-harris-mother-_625x300_23_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Shyamala Gopalan died in 2009 at the age of 70.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/instagram-tiktok-stars-get-vip-treatment-at-kamala-harris-democrat-event-6398612]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Instagram, TikTok Stars Get VIP Treatment At Kamala Harris' Democrat Event]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/instagram-tiktok-stars-get-vip-treatment-at-kamala-harris-democrat-event-6398612]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 23 Aug 2024 09:59:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Kamala Harris campaign rolled out the blue carpet for social media influencers at the Democratic National Convention this week, hoping that they can help get out the vote to beat Donald Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Kamala Harris campaign rolled out the blue carpet for social media influencers at the Democratic National Convention this week, hoping that they can help get out the vote to beat Donald Trump.</p>

<p>Stars of Instagram and TikTok were feted with free drinks, yacht parties and full VIP access, among other special treatment that was not given to the traditional press at the political convention -- which felt more like a festival, at times -- in Chicago.</p>

<p>"People have to realize that a lot of these creators have larger audiences than CNN, The New York Times, Univision, Telemundo, ABC," said Benjamin Zamora, a former journalist who left the news media to work as an influencer online, where he has 6.3 million followers across platforms.</p>

<p>He spoke on the floor of Chicago's United Center, where rooms have been set aside to pamper influencers with spreads of wine and prime-rib sandwiches.</p>

<p>It was a far cry from what was available for the mainstream press, but for Zamora, the difference in treatment makes sense.</p>

<p>"The Democratic National Convention sees content creators as allies; that's not the case for the press," he said.</p>

<p>The accreditation of more than 200 influencers is a new development at this convention, part of a strategy to broaden Harris's electoral base.</p>

<p>The treatment given to influencers contrasts with the fact that Harris has not given an interview or press conference to the mainstream press since President Joe Biden stepped aside and the party endorsed her nomination.</p>

<p>At least five influencers made the convention's select list of speakers, including Uruguay's Carlos Eduardo Espina, who took the podium Wednesday.</p>

<p>"It's really incredible that they gave us that opportunity," he told AFP.</p>

<p>"We see Bill Clinton, Joe Biden, and we think 'Wow, we don't deserve to be in the same space as them,'" he added.</p>

<p>"But we do. We have a lot to offer," said the 25-year-old, who has more than 11 million followers on social networks.</p>

<p>In the arena, influencers -- with cameras, lights and microphones in hand -- are freer to roam than many press teams, and have a reserved area on the blue carpet for interviews.</p>

<p>The reserved space for the traditional media sits outside the stadium, with few luxuries other than water, powerful air conditioning and Wi-Fi.</p>

<h2>All in for Harris</h2>

<p>The work is different, explained 12-year-old influencer Knowa, who argued with Republican activists Charlie Kirk and Mike Lindell in a recent video that went viral.</p>

<p>Despite his young age, Knowa speaks with a self-confidence that many may not reach in a lifetime, and with an undeniable charisma.</p>

<p>For Knowa, the DNC is not the biggest event of his short career, even though it has seen him sitting alongside US Senator Bernie Sanders and former Georgia state legislator Stacey Abrams.</p>

<p>"No, I would say the White House... that was pretty big as well," he said.</p>

<p>The young campaigner and social media star is all in for Harris, having met her five times.</p>

<p>The young influencer is homeschooled and has few other hobbies, dedicating all his time to the cause.</p>

<p>"The first thing I do when I wake up, I Google Kamala Harris. That's it," he told AFP.</p>

<p>Not all influencers at the convention are focused on politics, however.</p>

<p>Beauty, entertainment, lifestyle -- influencers covering all walks of life are adapting their brands to the convention.</p>

<p>Blair Imani, with 642,000 followers on Instagram, promotes one-and-a-half-minute videos on a diversity of topics on her "Smarter in Seconds" channel.</p>

<p>At the convention, Imani interviewed popular Michigan Governor Gretchen Whitmer.</p>

<p>"They've given us access, they've been so hospitable," said Imani.</p>

<p>"I know they're accommodating some content creators with hotel accommodations, because a lot of us are independent creators... They've gone above and beyond," she said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/oh6fpq7g_influencers-dnc_625x300_23_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-narendra-modi-to-visit-ukraine-today-meet-president-volodymyr-zelensky-amid-war-with-russia-6398463]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Live Updates: PM Modi In Ukraine, Will Meet President Zelensky]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-narendra-modi-to-visit-ukraine-today-meet-president-volodymyr-zelensky-amid-war-with-russia-6398463]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 23 Aug 2024 09:23:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[PM Modi Ukraine Visit: PM Narendra Modi is in Ukraine for his much-anticipated trip after wrapping up his two-day visit to Poland this morning.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>PM Narendra Modi is in Ukraine for his much-anticipated trip after wrapping up his two-day visit to Poland this morning. He is scheduled to meet the Ukrainian PM Volodymyr Zelenskyy, upon whose invite he is visiting the conflict-hit nation-state.</p>

<p>PM Modi's Ukraine visit comes nearly six weeks after he visited Russia to discuss the conflict-ridden situation amid Russia Ukraine. This is also the first visit by an Indian PM to Ukraine.</p>

<p>The Official Spokesperson of the Ministry of External Affairs, Randhir Jaiswal posted on the social media platform X (formerly, Twitter) that PM Modi's visit to Poland after four decades will widen and deepen India-Poland relations.</p>

<p>The UN secretary-general's office said that they hope that the Indian PM's visit to Ukraine might bring up the possibility of putting an end to the war.</p>

<p>Although India has yet to condemn the Russian invasion of Ukraine, PM Modi's statement said, "As a friend and partner, we hope for an early return of peace and stability in the region."</p>

<p>"I look forward to the opportunity to build upon earlier conversations with President Zelenskyy on strengthening bilateral cooperation and share perspectives on peaceful resolution of the ongoing Ukraine conflict. I am confident that the visit will serve as a natural continuation of extensive contacts with the two countries and help create the foundation for stronger and more vibrant relations in the years ahead," it further added.</p>

<p>The Ukrainian PM congratulated PM Modi on his election victory earlier this year.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>Here are the live updates of PM Modi's visit to Ukraine:&nbsp;</strong></h2>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/rhjsunco_modi-zelensky-_625x300_23_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[PM Narendra Modi will meet Ukrainian PM Volodymyr Zelenskyy today.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-kamala-harris-in-her-biggest-speech-yet-remembers-mother-dr-shyamala-gopalan-harris-6398395]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Miss Her Every Day": Kamala Harris Invokes Mother In Her Biggest Speech]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-kamala-harris-in-her-biggest-speech-yet-remembers-mother-dr-shyamala-gopalan-harris-6398395]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 23 Aug 2024 09:10:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Demoratic presidential candidate Kamala Harris started her speech at the party's big national convention with a special mention to her Indian-origin mother, Dr Shyamala Gopalan Harris. Not just that, Kamala's sister Maya Harris shared their family's]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Democratic presidential candidate Kamala Harris started her speech at the party's big national convention with a special mention to her Indian-origin mother, Dr Shyamala Gopalan Harris. Not just that, Kamala's sister Maya Harris shared their family's story with the convention audience.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-message-for-america-as-she-accepts-presidential-nomination-6398145">Kamala Harris</a> said that her mother was 19 when she crossed the seven seas alone, traveling from India to California "with an unshakable dream to be the scientist who would cure breast cancer."</p>

<p>"I miss her every day, and especially right now - and I know she's looking down, smiling," Ms Harris said.</p>

<p>"When she finished school, she was supposed to return home to a traditional arranged marriage, but as fate would have it, she met my father, Donald Harris, a student from Jamaica. They fell in love and got married, and that act of self-determination made my sister, Maya, and me," <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-polls-2024-national-democratic-convention-day-4-live-kamala-harris-to-give-biggest-speech-of-career-on-final-day-of-dnc-6397465">Ms Harris added</a>.</p>

<p><strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/indians-abroad/kamala-harris-credits-superhero-mother-for-motivating-her-political-career-1976118">Also Read:&nbsp;Kamala Harris Credits Mother For Motivating Her Political Career</a></strong></p>

<p>Kamala's sister, Maya Harris recalled how their mother moved to the US from India to pursue a better life and encouraged her daughters to be "the authors of our own stories."</p>

<p>"Mommy's journey, and the opportunity that she wanted for Kamala and me - that's a distinctly American story," she said.</p>

<p>She also mentioned that if their late mother was here, she would say how proud she was of her daughter. Then, "without missing a beat, she'd say, 'That's enough. You've got work to do.'"</p>

<p><strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-on-mother-shyamala-gopalan-her-words-guided-me-pushing-me-to-action-2293100">Also Read:&nbsp;"Her Words Guided Me Pushing Me To Action": Kamala Harris On Mother</a></strong></p>

<p>Dr Shyamala Gopalan Harris, a biomedical scientist died in 2009, a year before Kamala Harris was elected as California's attorney general.</p>

<p>Kamala Harris made the history by becoming the first woman, the first Black person and the first Indian-American to become US Vice President.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-08/ll85els8_kamala-harris-mother-sister_625x300_12_August_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kamala Harris and her sister Maya Harris with their mother Dr Shyamala Gopalan Harris.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-message-for-america-as-she-accepts-presidential-nomination-6398145]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris' Donald Trump Warning As She Accepts Presidential Nomination]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-message-for-america-as-she-accepts-presidential-nomination-6398145]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 23 Aug 2024 08:15:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Vice President Kamala Harris today formally accepted the Democratic Party's 2024 presidential nomination to fight against her Republican rival Donald Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US Vice President Kamala Harris today formally accepted the Democratic Party's 2024 presidential nomination to fight against her Republican rival Donald Trump. Ms&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-hindus-in-us-form-group-to-rally-support-for-kamala-harris-6397682" target="_blank">Harris</a>, who is of Indian origin, emerged as the Democratic candidate after President <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pro-palestine-democrats-welcome-joe-bidens-exit-but-side-eye-kamala-harris-6384605" target="_blank">Joe Biden</a>, 81, was forced to quit the race for the White House last month. If successful, she will become the first woman elected US president.</p>

<p>"On behalf of every American, regardless of party, race, gender, or the language your grandmother speaks, on behalf of everyone whose story could only be written in the greatest nation on earth, I accept your nomination for President of the United States of America," she said as the gathering at Chicago's United Center erupted into cheers on the last day of the four-day <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-polls-2024-national-democratic-convention-day-4-live-kamala-harris-to-give-biggest-speech-of-career-on-final-day-of-dnc-6397465" target="_blank">Democratic National Convention</a>.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Vice President Harris: On behalf of everyone whose story could only be written in the greatest nation on earth, I accept your nomination for President of the United States of America <a href="https://t.co/I8sXLSHOox">pic.twitter.com/I8sXLSHOox</a></p>
— Kamala HQ (@KamalaHQ) <a href="https://twitter.com/KamalaHQ/status/1826814475745317230?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 23, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>During her acceptance speech, the 59-year-old vowed to be the "president who unites" Americans and pledged to "fight for America's future".</p>

<p>"With this election, our nation has a precious and fleeting opportunity to move past the bitterness, cynicism, and divisive battles of the past. A chance to chart a New Way Forward, not as members of any one party or faction but as Americans," she said.</p>

<h3><strong>Kamala Harris Jabs Donald Trump</strong></h3>

<p>Kamala Harris&nbsp;slammed her rival <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/michelle-obama-democratic-convention-chicago-kamala-harris-barack-obama-donald-trump-my-girl-is-ready-michelle-obamas-powerful-warning-6384150" target="_blank">Donald Trump</a>&nbsp;and accused him of planning to "pull our country back".</p>

<p>"This election is one of the most important in the life of our nation. Just imagine Donald Trump with no guardrails. How he would use the immense powers of the presidency of the United States, not to improve your life, but to serve the only client he has ever had… himself," she said.</p>

<p>“In many ways, Donald Trump is an unserious man, but the consequences of putting Donald Trump back in the White House are extremely serious,” she warned.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Vice President Harris: This election is one of the most important in the life of our nation. Just imagine Donald Trump with no guardrails. How he would use the immense powers of the presidency of the United States, not to improve your life, but to serve the only client he has… <a href="https://t.co/bOr5AN7pLR">pic.twitter.com/bOr5AN7pLR</a></p>
— Kamala HQ (@KamalaHQ) <a href="https://twitter.com/KamalaHQ/status/1826816985998536800?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 23, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>She also spoke about the “chaos and calamity” of Mr Trump's years in the Oval Office and also pointed to him questioning election results in 2020 when he lost his reelection bid.</p>

<p>“Donald Trump tried to throw away your votes. When he failed, he sent an armed mob to the United States Capitol where they assaulted law enforcement officers. When politicians in his own party begged him to call off the mob and send help, he did the opposite. He fanned the flames,” Ms Harris said.</p>

<h3><strong>Kamala Harris Praises Joe Biden</strong></h3>

<p>Kamala Harris also thanked her boss, Joe Biden, and said that his character is "inspiring".</p>

<p>"Joe, I am filled with gratitude. Your record is extraordinary as history will show. Your character is inspiring," she said.it," she said.</p>

<p>Mr Biden, who gave an emotional farewell speech to the convention on Monday, said he and First Lady Jill Biden had called Ms Harris to wish her luck.</p>

<p>"I am proud to watch my partner Kamala Harris accept our nomination for president. She will be an outstanding president because she is fighting for our future," he said on X.</p>

<p>He also said that Ms Harris and her running mate, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/vp-pick-tim-walz-praises-kamala-harris-at-democratic-convention-6391895" target="_blank">Tim Walz</a>, will "inspire a generation and lead us into the future".</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Jill and I just spoke to <a href="https://twitter.com/KamalaHarris?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@KamalaHarris</a> — we can't wait to watch her accept this historic nomination.<br />
<br />
Kamala and Tim will inspire a generation and lead us into the future. <a href="https://t.co/guKuTevT8F">pic.twitter.com/guKuTevT8F</a></p>
— Joe Biden (@JoeBiden) <a href="https://twitter.com/JoeBiden/status/1826789597600256189?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 23, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<h3><strong>Kamala Harris On Her Family</strong></h3>

<p>Kamala Harris also remembered her "tough and courageous" mother, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-kamala-harris-in-her-biggest-speech-yet-remembers-mother-dr-shyamala-gopalan-harris-6398395#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">Shyamala Gopalan</a>, saying she misses her every day, especially when she is on the verge of breaking the highest glass ceiling in the United States.</p>

<p>She said her mother was 19 when she crossed the world alone, travelling from India to California with an unshakeable dream to be the scientist who would cure breast cancer.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Vice President Harris: My mother taught Maya and me to never complain about injustice, but do something about it. She also taught us to never do anything half-assed <a href="https://t.co/rzpox2qOOH">pic.twitter.com/rzpox2qOOH</a></p>
— Kamala HQ (@KamalaHQ) <a href="https://twitter.com/KamalaHQ/status/1826813929571410270?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 23, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>"... It was mostly my mother who raised us. Before she could finally afford to buy a home, she rented a small apartment in the East Bay. In the Bay, you either live in the hills or the flatlands. We lived in the flats -- a beautiful working-class neighbourhood of firefighters, nurses, and construction workers, all of whom tended their lawns with pride," Ms Harris said.</p>

<p>She also spoke about her Jamaican father, Donald Jasper Harris, and said he always taught her to be “fearless”.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/qdana4vc_kamala-harris_650x400_23_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kamala Harris accepted the Democratic Party's 2024 presidential nomination during an event in Chicago]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-hindus-in-us-form-group-to-rally-support-for-kamala-harris-6397682]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hindus In US Form Group To Rally Support For Kamala Harris]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-hindus-in-us-form-group-to-rally-support-for-kamala-harris-6397682]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 23 Aug 2024 08:00:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Some Hindus in the US have come together to create "Hindus For Kamala Harris", a support group for the Democratic presidential nominee, saying she would be good for India, America and the world.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Some Hindus in the US have come together to create “Hindus For Kamala Harris”, a support group for the Democratic presidential nominee, saying she would be good for India, America and the world.</p>

<p>The group has been created “to support Kamala Devi Harris to become the 47th President of the United States of America”, its founding members said.</p>

<p>On Thursday, Harris, 59, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-polls-2024-national-democratic-convention-day-4-live-kamala-harris-to-give-biggest-speech-of-career-on-final-day-of-dnc-6397465">formally accepted</a> the nomination of the Democratic Party to be its presidential nominee.</p>

<p>“We must help her win. This is the best outcome for America, India and the World! The alternative Trump is a disaster!' one of the members of the group said.</p>

<p>“There is a simple path to victory. Without rejecting the other side, promote Harris candidacy because of what it stands for and the solution it will provide," another member said, adding that the candidacy has a unique momentum to win.</p>

<p>The group is urging Hindus to vote in the elections, display signs of support near their house, and make donations in support of the Harris campaign.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/4i5380b_kamala-harris-_625x300_20_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The group is urging Hindus to vote in the elections.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>