<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Wed, 11 Sep 2024 18:56:03 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-a-bag-of-cheetos-unleashed-chaos-in-a-fragile-us-cave-ecosystem-6541709]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How A Bag Of Cheetos Unleashed Chaos In A Fragile US Cave Ecosystem]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-a-bag-of-cheetos-unleashed-chaos-in-a-fragile-us-cave-ecosystem-6541709]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 11 Sep 2024 18:16:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A recent incident at Carlsbad Caverns National Park, where a visitor dropped a half-empty bag of Cheetos, highlights the damaging effects of littering on fragile ecosystems.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We generally overlook the negative impact human beings create by the trash that we leave behind after outdoor events and activities. No matter if it is a plain, a riverside, a desert, or a hilltop, it seems travellers have left behind plastic waste in all natural locations. Littering is emerging as a huge problem that is threatening these locations for their fragile ecology and aesthetic value.</p>

<p>Last week at Carlsbad Caverns National Park, one visitor tossed away an open bag of Cheetos. It served as a snack for the mould of the cave. One of the most visited places in New Mexico, the park welcomed almost 400,000 visitors last year.</p>

<p>In response, park rangers painstakingly removed mould and microbial growth along the path leading to the Big Room-the biggest cave chamber by volume in North America-for 20 minutes. And all this was because of the bag of Cheetos dropped by the careless visitor.</p>

<p>The National Park's social media account now shared a statement regarding the incident, explaining that we affect the world around us in subtle ways, whether it be purposeful or not.</p>

<p>The post reads, "To the owner of the snack bag, the impact is likely incidental. But to the ecosystem of the cave, it had a huge impact."</p>

<p><iframe allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="true" frameborder="0" height="737" scrolling="no" src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/post.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2FCarlsbadCavernsNPS%2Fposts%2Fpfbid02gVZQZQfmnJ3RzfcGD1z1tkJwgTzJZh3xh6XRMYfmv47mN6rzM66G41WcjHUWdEmil&amp;show_text=true&amp;width=500" style="border:none;overflow:hidden" width="500"></iframe></p>

<p>"The processed corn, softened by the humidity of the cave, formed the perfect environment to host microbial life and fungi. Cave crickets, mites, spiders, and flies soon organise into a temporary food web, dispersing the nutrients to the surrounding caves and formations. Moulds spread higher up the nearby surfaces, fruit, die, and stink. And the cycle continues."</p>

<p>"Rangers spent twenty minutes carefully removing the foreign debris and moulds from the cave surfaces. Some members of this fleeting ecosystem are cave dwellers, but many of the microbial life and moulds are not. At the scale of human perspective, a spilt snack bag may seem trivial, but to the life of the cave, it can be world-changing. Great or small, we all leave an impact wherever we go. Let us all leave the world a better place than we found it."</p>

<p>This eye-opening incident is a reminder that our reliance on convenience comes at a significant cost to the planet, and mindful travel is more important than ever.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/uc1mama8_carlsbad-caverns-national-park_625x300_11_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Carlsbad Caverns National Park is one of New Mexicos biggest tourist attractions.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-man-gets-23-teeth-extracted-and-12-implants-placed-in-one-day-dies-of-heart-attack-6541684]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[China Man Gets 23 Teeth Extracted In One Day, Dies Of Heart Attack]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-man-gets-23-teeth-extracted-and-12-implants-placed-in-one-day-dies-of-heart-attack-6541684]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 11 Sep 2024 18:11:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The procedure involved extracting 23 teeth and inserting 12 implants in a single day using the "immediate restoration" method.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A recent case in eastern China has raised concerns about dental procedure safety. According to the <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3277773/china-father-dies-heart-attack-after-having-23-teeth-extracted-12-implants-placed-1-day" rel="nofollow, noindex">South China Morning Post</a></em>, a man surnamed Huang, underwent an extensive dental procedure on August 14 at Yongkang Deway Dental Hospital in Jinhua, Zhejiang province. The procedure involved extracting 23 teeth and inserting 12 implants in a single day using the "immediate restoration" method.&nbsp;Two weeks later, he suffered a sudden heart attack and died on August 28. The case was brought to light through an online post by his daughter Shu on September 2.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Huang revealed that her father, whose age has not been disclosed, experienced persistent pain following the treatment. ''I never thought my dad would pass so quickly. He did not even get the chance to drive the new car we bought him,'' stated his daughter.</p>

<p>In response to the incident, an official from the Yongkang Municipal Health Bureau stated on September 3 that the cause of death is still being investigated, citing the 13-day gap between the dental procedure and the man's death.&nbsp;</p>

<p data-qa="Component-Component" datatype="p">Three days later, a&nbsp;clinic staff member told <em>SCMP</em> ''We will not be responding to this matter now as it has been handed over to our lawyer. If there are any updates, we will issue a statement; however, the investigation is ongoing.''</p>

<p data-qa="Component-Component" datatype="p">According to Xiang Guolin, director of the Dental Medicine Centre at the Hospital of Universal Love in Wuhan, there are no established official guidelines for the maximum number of teeth that can be extracted in a single procedure. However, in general practice, the limit is typically considered to be around 10 teeth.&nbsp;</p>

<p>''Extracting 23 teeth is quite a lot. It requires a clinic and dentist with sufficient qualifications and experience. It's also essential to consider the patient's physical capacity to handle such an extensive procedure,'' he said.</p>

<p>Many social media users expressed shock and disbelief upon learning about the case. One person questioned the decision to extract 23 teeth in a single day, sharing their own experience of being refused by a dentist when requesting the removal of two wisdom teeth simultaneously.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Another user wrote, ''I'm a dentist, and I never extract more than three teeth at one time unless they're very loose. The doctor must have lost his mind. It sounds more like a human experiment than a dental procedure.''</p>

<p data-qa="Component-Component" datatype="p"></p>

<p data-qa="Component-Component" datatype="p"></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/ktfk2s4g_dentist_625x300_11_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The case was brought to light through an online post by his daughter Shu on September 2.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/married-colleagues-in-china-fired-for-kissing-in-office-sue-company-6541169]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Married Colleagues In China, Fired For Kissing In Office, Sue Company]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/married-colleagues-in-china-fired-for-kissing-in-office-sue-company-6541169]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 11 Sep 2024 17:07:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The employees have now filed a lawsuit against their former employer, alleging wrongful termination.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Two employees in China were terminated from their jobs after they were caught having an extramarital affair and kissing each other openly at work. The employees have now filed a lawsuit against their former employer, alleging wrongful termination. According to the <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/article/3277304/china-colleagues-both-married-others-fired-kissing-office-sue-company">South China Morning Post,</a></em> the man, known as Liu, and the woman, identified as Chen, were both employed in the same department of a pharmaceutical company in Sichuan province, southwestern China.&nbsp;Their relationship became public knowledge after Liu's wife shared their chat records with the company's chat group and management in March 2020.</p>

<p>The records included messages such as “I love you” and “I want to look at you all the time.'' Following this, Liu requested leave to address personal matters, and Chen's husband confronted the couple at the workplace. Despite warnings, the romantic relationship between Liu and Chen continued, and they were again seen kissing at work.</p>

<p>In October 2020, a coworker confronted Chen about the behaviour, leading to a disagreement. The incident prompted seven colleagues to submit a joint letter to the general manager, expressing concerns about the situation. As a result, the company terminated Liu and Chen's employment, citing violations of the employee handbook and company rules.</p>

<p>Liu and Chen have each filed separate lawsuits against their former employer. Chen is seeking compensation of 26,000 yuan (approximately Rs 3 lakh), while Liu, who held a more senior position, is seeking over 230,000 yuan (approximately Rs 27 lakh) in damages.</p>

<p>The company defended its decision to terminate their employment, referencing its employee handbook, which permits termination for behaviour deemed unethical. The&nbsp;handbook clearly states it has ''the right to break the labour relationship with employees who are morally corrupt, tarnish the company's reputation and have a negative influence on the company.''</p>

<p>The court ultimately ruled in favour of the company, dismissing the lawsuits filed by Liu and Chen.</p>

<p>On social media, the incident has generated widespread discussion, with many users criticising the employees' behavior. One user wrote, ''Obviously they did not work hard enough if they had the energy to find colleagues attractive.'</p>

<p data-qa="Component-Component" datatype="p">Another commented, ''Shame on them to even sue the company.''</p>

<p></p>

<p></p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/5he6jk58_china_625x300_11_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The court ruled in favour of the company and dismissed the lawsuits.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/carnival-cruise-ship-hits-ice-in-alaska-passengers-call-it-a-titanic-moment-6540670]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Cruise Ship Hits Ice in Alaska, Passengers Call It A "Titanic Moment"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/carnival-cruise-ship-hits-ice-in-alaska-passengers-call-it-a-titanic-moment-6540670]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 11 Sep 2024 16:05:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The hull of the Carnival Spirit was assessed and no damages were found after the incident.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a dramatic moment, a Carnival cruise ship made contact with a chunk of ice in Alaska's Tracy Arm Fjord last Thursday but emerged unscathed. Despite one passenger likening the incident to a "Titanic moment," a thorough inspection of the hull revealed no damage, according to a statement from Carnival Cruise Line. ''The ship was struck with an errant piece of drifting ice last Thursday while sailing in Tracy Arm Fjord, Alaska,'' the company operating the cruise said in a statement to&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.foxbusiness.com/lifestyle/social-media-users-get-dramatic-carnival-cruise-ship-hits-ice-alaska-titanic-moment"><em>Fox Business</em>.</a></p>

<p>The Carnival Spirit sustained no damage after striking ice in Alaska and completed its 7-day voyage as scheduled, without any delays. Carnival said, "The vessel&nbsp;continued on its cruise and there has been no impact to operations."&nbsp;</p>

<p>However, the incident drew a dramatic comparison to the Titanic moment from one passenger.&nbsp;"If we die, it was damn well worth it. It's a Titanic moment," passenger Cassandra Goskie said in a video she posted in a private Carnival VIFP Club Members Facebook group. In the video, she is heard saying, ''Oh, we are hitting it,'' as the ship makes contact with the ice.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Another passenger shared pictures on X and wrote, ''From April Futrell “Good evening James! We are on the carnival spirit and hit an iceberg just outside of Sitka and Tracy arm fjord! Here's some pictures! We are safe and after assessing for damage we are back on track headed to Skagway!''</p>

<p>One image captures a tugboat trailing behind the Carnival Spirit as it navigates through icy waters, gliding smoothly over the partially submerged ice.</p>

<p><strong>See the pictures here:</strong></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">From April Futrell “Good evening James! We are on the carnival spirit and hit an iceberg just outside of Sitka and Tracy arm fjord! Here's some pictures! We are safe and after assessing for damage we are back on track headed to Skagway!” <a href="https://t.co/KIUkrlLtx9">pic.twitter.com/KIUkrlLtx9</a></p>
— James Spann (@spann) <a href="https://twitter.com/spann/status/1831890843105706446?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 6, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The Carnival Spirit is expected to arrive in Seattle on September 24, marking the end of its 14-day round-trip Alaska cruise that began on September 10.&nbsp;</p>

<p></p>

<aside></aside>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/dlfv89r_cruise-ship_625x300_11_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Carnival Spirit is expected to arrive in Seattle on September 24]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/japan-penguin-found-safe-2-weeks-after-escape-keeper-calls-it-a-miracle-6540134]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Japan Penguin Found Safe 2 Weeks After Escape, Keeper Calls It "A Miracle"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/japan-penguin-found-safe-2-weeks-after-escape-keeper-calls-it-a-miracle-6540134]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 11 Sep 2024 14:54:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A fugitive penguin in Japan has been found safe and sound two weeks after escaping into the sea and paddling for miles, in what her keeper called a "miracle".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A fugitive penguin in Japan has been found safe and sound two weeks after escaping into the sea and paddling for miles, in what her keeper called a "miracle".</p>

<p>Pen-chan, a female Cape penguin born and raised in captivity who had never swum in the open sea before or fended for herself, absconded from an event in the central Aichi region on August 25.</p>

<p>Feeling "desperate", keeper Ryosuke Imai said that a team began scouring the area immediately but a huge typhoon dumping record rains across Japan hampered the search.</p>

<p>Given Pen-chan's lack of swimming and unproven survival skills in the wild, the team thought she would not get very far or survive longer than a week.</p>

<p>But amazingly on September 8, Imai received information that the flightless bird had been seen happily bobbing in the water at a beach 30 miles (45 kilometres) away.</p>

<p>"I thought she would look exhausted, but she was swimming as usual," Imai told AFP after the animal was recaptured.</p>

<p>"It was beyond my surprise... It's a miracle," he said.</p>

<p>He said that six-year-old Pen-chan must have been eating fish and crabs that she caught itself.</p>

<p>"I think she got there by stopping at various places for a break, but it's still unbelievable," Imai said.</p>

<p>"She lost her weight slightly, but she's doing great."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/bpuj7cm8_japan-miracle-penguin-_625x300_11_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Pen-chan, a female Cape penguin, was raised in captivity and had never swum in the open sea before.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/india-pakistan-peace-is-possible-only-if-pak-army-takes-a-back-seat-6540120]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: India-Pak Peace Is Possible - Only If Pak Army Takes A Back Seat]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/india-pakistan-peace-is-possible-only-if-pak-army-takes-a-back-seat-6540120]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 11 Sep 2024 14:52:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[If India and Pakistan have tepid bilateral relations today, it is because the Pakistan army appears reluctant to allow civilian governments to build a warm relationship with India.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/6m9q4578_pakistan_625x300_11_September_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Following the controversial February general election, it seems Pakistan is going through a period where a nominal civilian government led by Prime Minister Shehbaz Sharif is working under the strict control of the army. But while the military exerts its influence behind the scenes without accountability, the government, involved in the day-to-day running of the country, is still answerable to its people.&nbsp;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
The Pakistan military has directly ruled the country for over half of its existence, with generals such as Ayub Khan, Yahya Khan, Zia-ul-Haq and Pervez Musharraf holding power for 43 years in total. For the remaining years, when the military was not in power, it maintained significant influence over political parties and indirectly controlled elected governments. Today, it is one of the most powerful, feared and unpopular institutions in Pakistan.</p>

<p>It may seem hard to explain how an army that was so badly humiliated on the battlefield, lost one big chunk of the country and was made to surrender en masse to its arch-rival in 1971, went on to become the country's main power centre. But, there is an explanation: the Pakistan army owes a lot to the US and China, both of which helped in rebuilding it. It also got a new fillip under General Zia, who began to Islamise the country and the armed forces. It got a boost when nuclear tests were conducted, and another shot in the arm when the Soviet Union invaded Afghanistan in 1979. The US poured arms and money into Pakistan and bolstered the army's capabilities, supplying its air force with F16 fighter jets. Following 9/11, the Pakistan army even joined the US-led global war on terror. For years, America paid the Pakistan army $2 billion a year for being at the forefront of the global war on terrorism and supporting its operations and logistics in Afghanistan.</p>

<h2><strong>A Vice-Like Grip</strong></h2>

<p>In practice, much of Pakistan's security issues and foreign affairs are reported to be shaped not in the capital Islamabad but at the General Headquarters in Rawalpindi, where the Chief of Army Staff (COAS) plays the role of a kingmaker. The military has significant economic interests, with control over large sectors of real estate, agriculture, corporations and industry.</p>

<p>Pakistan's current political turmoil was triggered when Imran Khan, who came to power with the army's support, later began to defy its authority. Many believe that if India and Pakistan have tepid bilateral relations today, it is because the Pakistan army appears reluctant to allow civilian governments to build a warm relationship with India.</p>

<p>But the considered view in the West is that the military is the main institution that holds Pakistan together. A few foreign policy think tank people I have interacted with in recent weeks are of the opinion that for all its faults, the Pakistan army is the one institution that can take on the forces endangering the country's future. They argue that the West needs a disciplined institution like the Pakistan military that can safeguard the big nuclear stockpile that Islamabad has amassed. They urge the military to mend relations with India and hope that it will respond positively because a disintegrated Pakistan, the argument goes, will create havoc in the region, which will severely affect India too.</p>

<h2><strong>Democratic Rule Is In Everyone's Interest</strong></h2>

<p>I, however, think this is a myopic view. The West should try to help strengthen political parties and push for the protection of the autonomy of national institutions. The restoration of true democracy should be everyone's objective. It will be easier for any country, more particularly a democratic India, to deal with an elected civilian government, with no direct or indirect interference by the Pakistani army. Former prime ministers Nawaz Sharif and Benazir Bhutto felt immense pressure from the army when they tried to initiate dialogues with India. During the two full-scale wars between India and Pakistan in 1965 and 1971, the country was ruled by the military.</p>

<p>The Kargil War in 1999 is widely seen as an attempt by the Pakistan army to undermine the civilian government's efforts to establish peace with India. The war highlighted the tensions between Pakistan's civilian and military leadership and the army's willingness to pursue its own agenda, even if it meant undermining the country's democratic institutions.</p>

<h2><strong>The Root Cause Of Terrorism In India&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p>The public view in India, meanwhile, is that the root cause of terrorism here is the Pakistan army. The Indian government has largely been sceptical of a dialogue with Pakistan, which it accuses of exporting terrorism to its territories. It is, therefore, callous for the West to disregard the fact that over the past four decades, India has been at the receiving end of terrorism, which, India believes, is being perpetuated by Pakistan. India has shared evidence too with its Western allies and even with Pakistan, which reveals how the Inter-Services Intelligence (ISI) of Pakistan's army plans and trains young boys to commit acts of terrorism in India. Pakistan, expectedly, has always denied the allegations.</p>

<p>But the denial carries little weight. On May 16, 2011, David Coleman Headley, one of the main planners of the Mumbai terror attack, appeared in a federal court in Chicago and revealed how two ISI officers were present during the planning and training stages of the attack. I was present in the courtroom when he narrated this. In his long testimony, he gave graphic details of what instructions he got from the ISI men and which places in Mumbai he was told to target. In fact, the 10 heavily armed terrorists who attacked Mumbai had come from Pakistan. This is a well-known fact that none should dispute.</p>

<h2><strong>Terror Camps And Training&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p>I have met scores of militants during my long years in reporting, who have shared with me details of their training routines in camps in and around Muzaffarabad. I have met a few journalists from Pakistan who have visited these camps, organised by authorities and Islamist outfits.</p>

<p>The civilian governments in Pakistan have largely not been averse to being friends with India. The people, too, admire the progress India has made. The two countries have had a history of Track-II diplomacy.&nbsp;</p>

<p>However, the Pakistan army's obsession with Kashmir and its desire for parity with India has led to hostilities and has hindered regional peace and stability. And thus, peaceful negotiations to normalise bilateral relations can be successful only if the army's influence is weakened.</p>

<p>India will have to take some steps too to achieve this non-combatant objective - something that will ultimately contribute to overall peace and stability in the Indian subcontinent. India will have to support Pakistan's civilian leadership and democratic forces that seek to reduce the army's influence over the country's politics. This will include taking a stand against the Pakistan Army's human rights abuses in Kashmir and Balochistan and restructuring ties with countries like Iran and Afghanistan, which share concerns about Pakistan's military and its adventurism. India could also do more to invest in strategic communications to counter the Pakistan army's propaganda and disinformation campaigns. By pursuing these strategies, India can create an environment that undermines the Pakistan army's dominance and creates space for more constructive engagement between the two countries.</p>

<h2><strong>Weakening The Pak Army</strong></h2>

<p>These strategies are not new. During the 1971 Bangladesh Liberation War, India supported Mukti Bahini to weaken the Pakistani military's control over East Pakistan (now Bangladesh). Several big powers adopt these strategies. The US has conducted cyber operations and supported opposition groups to weaken the Revolutionary Guards's influence in Iran, while Israel has taken similar actions against both the Iranian Revolutionary Guard and Lebanon's Hezbollah. Again, during the Cold War, the US engaged in a strategy of economic pressure, diplomatic isolation and ideological competition to weaken the Soviet military.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Saudi Arabia's military is an example of how things can go horribly wrong if done in haste. Its military operations and support for opposition groups with a view to weakening the Houthi rebels' control over Yemen have not yielded any success at all. &nbsp;</p>

<p>India will thus have to pursue these strategies tactfully, without seeming to be interfering in Pakistan's internal affairs. Kashmir will always remain an issue for the two countries, &nbsp;but it's possible to agree to work on other bilateral issues to first normalise relations. If there is political will on both sides of the border and the Pakistan army takes a backseat, peace may not be so unachievable.</p>

<p><em>(Syed Zubair Ahmed is a London-based senior Indian journalist with three decades of experience with the Western media)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/rg1r6j2o_pakistan_625x300_11_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-makes-surprise-spin-room-visit-after-debate-with-harris-6540009]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Makes Surprise 'Spin Room' Visit After Debate With Harris]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-makes-surprise-spin-room-visit-after-debate-with-harris-6540009]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 11 Sep 2024 14:40:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Minutes after being hustled by Kamala Harris during their US presidential debate on Tuesday, Donald Trump appeared in front of reporters to get the last word.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Minutes after being hustled by Kamala Harris during their US presidential debate on Tuesday, Donald Trump appeared in front of reporters to get the last word.&nbsp;</p>

<p>As the debate drew to a close, cries of surprise went up at the entrance to the press room.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Trump had made an unexpected entrance to the "spin room," where the candidates' spokespeople and supporters usually hurry to distribute talking points to journalists.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Cameras and microphones in hand, dozens of reporters crowded behind thin ribbons to get as close as possible to the former president.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"What about black voters?" a reporter asked, managing to stand out from the crowd. "I love them. They love me," the Republican billionaire declared.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Others tried to get his opinion on the 90-minute debate, during which 59-year-old Democratic candidate Harris had launched a relentless attack.</p>

<h3><strong>'Not seen that in years'&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>"I thought it was a great debate," Trump said.</p>

<p>"I thought it was my best performance, actually, but I don't even view it as a performance," he added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Our country is in decline. We're a nation in decline. And I thought that when we got that out, she was unable to defend it."&nbsp;</p>

<p>Trump walked around the room, trailed by reporters, and after fielding a few questions, he finally disappeared behind black curtains.</p>

<p>"The fact that he showed up in the media filing centre and spin room at the end, we haven't seen that in years," said Aaron Kall, director of debates at the University of Michigan.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"He wants to try to change the subject to something as quickly as possible."&nbsp;</p>

<p>Both Trump and Harris will be back on the campaign trail on Wednesday, with less than two months left before the election.&nbsp;</p>

<p>They will take part in separate ceremonies to honour the victims of the September 11, 2001, attacks.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/j5slvajo_donald-trump-in-spin-room-afp_625x300_11_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump appeared before reporters to get the last word after the debate with Kamala Harris.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/palestine-takes-seat-among-un-member-states-at-79th-general-assembly-session-6539868]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Palestine Takes Seat Among UN Member States At 79th General Assembly Session]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/palestine-takes-seat-among-un-member-states-at-79th-general-assembly-session-6539868]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 11 Sep 2024 14:16:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The 79th session of the UN General Assembly kicked off in New York with the presence of the representatives of Palestine, who have been given a seat in the General Assembly Hall next to the UN member states.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The 79th session of the UN General Assembly kicked off in New York with the presence of the representatives of Palestine, who have been given a seat in the General Assembly Hall next to the UN member states.</p>

<p>Palestine is not a full member of the 193-member UN body.</p>

<p>The Palestinian Authority's envoy to the United Nations, Riyad Mansour, took his place on Tuesday afternoon at a table marked "State of Palestine" between Sri Lanka and Sudan.</p>

<p>Palestine's Permanent Mission to the UN posted a clip on social media on the intervention by the Ambassador of Egypt and the President of the General Assembly confirming the new seating of the State of Palestine.</p>

<p>The representative of Egypt raised a point of order to ask the President to confirm that the necessary arrangements have been made "This is not merely a procedural matter. This is a historic moment for us," said Egyptian Ambassador Osama Mahmoud Abdelkhalek Mahmoud.</p>

<p>The UNGA President replied: "I have been informed that all arrangements have been made to have Palestine seated where it is supposed to sit."</p>

<p>Israel has denounced the move. The representative of Israel said that the Assembly's decision in this matter is motivated by political favouritism, underscoring that UN membership and associated privileges are specifically reserved for sovereign States.</p>

<p>On May 10, this year a resolution was adopted to recognise the reconsideration of Palestine's UN membership in the UN Security Council and the granting of additional rights to Palestine, which holds observer status.</p>

<p>The resolution called for arrangements to allow Palestine to participate in General Assembly sessions, UN meetings and conferences, specifying that this would be done "on an exceptional basis and without setting a precedent."</p>

<p>The resolution had won a resounding majority of 143 votes in favour, including by India.</p>

<p>Notably, India has always reiterated its stand for a two-state solution in the Israel-Palestine conflict. While, New Delhi has condemned any terrorist attack, including the October 7 attack by Hamas, it has also called for a homeland for Palestinians.</p>

<p>"We have supported a negotiated two-state solution, towards the establishment of a sovereign, independent and viable state of Palestine within secure and recognised borders, living side by side in peace with Israel," the Ministry of External Affairs reiterated in the Parliament in February.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Philemon Yang, the former Prime Minister of Cameroon who was elected president of the 79th General Assembly in June took over from his predecessor, Dennis Francis.</p>

<p>"I will urge the assembly to intensify its determination, to prioritize the resolution of conflicts, including the intractable ones in the Gaza Strip, Haiti and Ukraine," Yang said.</p>

<p>"Human rights will remain at the core of our General Assembly," the new UNGA President said</p>

<p>Secretary-General Antonio Guterres congratulated Yang and pointed out that the 79th session was opening amid the backdrop of a "world in trouble" but said, "The good news is that we can do something about it."</p>

<p>He said that last year was very "tumultuous," with poverty, inequality and injustice as well as conflict and violence persisting. Guterres also recalled that last year was "the hottest" year on record, saying "This session also closes at a time of growing hope and inspiration in what we can achieve if we work as one."</p>

<p>He emphasized that many tasks lie ahead for member states in the 79th session.</p>

<p>"This is the place where solutions are made. And we need solutions across the board. "In confronting the challenges before us, the United Nations General Assembly remains an indispensable tool and a vital pathway towards a peaceful and just future for all people," the UN Secretary-General said</p>

<p>He emphasised solutions for bringing Sustainable Development Goals back to life, ending poverty and inequality, solutions to spur economic progress and job-creation for all, bridging the political divides and end conflicts, to ending the climate catastrophe. He also called for solutions to summon the financing that developing countries need to invest in the future of their people and to ensure that groundbreaking tech like artificial intelligence is a boon, not a barrier, to human progress and equality</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the landmark "Summit of the Future" which brings together world leaders together in New York will take place at UN Headquarters on September 22-23, just before the annual high-level debate of the General Assembly.</p>

<p>This year's General Debate, from September 24 to September 30, boasts the theme "Leaving no one behind: Acting together for the advancement of peace, sustainable development and human dignity for present and future generations."</p>

<p>It will aim to secure a negotiated "Pact for the Future" designed to boost global cooperation to tackle current challenges effectively for future generations.</p>

<p>There will also be high-level meetings on topics as wide-ranging as the elimination of nuclear weapons; addressing the threat posed by rising sea levels; and strengthening global health systems against antimicrobial resistance.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/vi5f75kg_palestine_625x300_22_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Palestine is not a full member of the 193-member UN body (representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistan-jolted-by-5-7-magnitude-earthquake-tremors-felt-in-india-6539768]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Pakistan Jolted By 5.7 Magnitude Earthquake, Tremors Felt In India]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistan-jolted-by-5-7-magnitude-earthquake-tremors-felt-in-india-6539768]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 11 Sep 2024 14:02:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 5.7 magnitude earthquake jolted parts of Pakistan, including the capital Islamabad, on Wednesday, according to the country's meteorological department.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 5.7 magnitude earthquake jolted parts of Pakistan, including the capital Islamabad, on Wednesday, according to the country's meteorological department.</p>

<p>The earthquake was felt in several parts of the Punjab and Khyber Pakhtunkhwa provinces as well as the federal capital.</p>

<p>It originated at 12:28 pm Pakistan Standard Time (PST) and was recorded at magnitude 5.7 on the Richter's scale, according to the Pakistan Meteorological Department.</p>

<p>The epicentre was situated near the Dera Ghazi Khan region in the southwestern part of the Punjab province at a depth of 10 kilometres, Geo News reported, citing the Met Department.</p>

<p>The United States Geological Survey however stated that the extent of the quake was recorded at magnitude 5.4, affecting India, Pakistan, and Afghanistan.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, India's National Center for Seismology said the earthquake of magnitude 5.8 struck Pakistan at 12:58 pm. &nbsp; In 2005, a magnitude 7.6 quake killed thousands of people in Pakistan and Kashmir.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2016-10/earthquake-generic_650x400_41477031172.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The earthquake was felt in many parts of the Punjab and Khyber Pakhtunkhwa provinces (representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-president-visits-iraq-on-first-foreign-trip-amid-political-turmoil-6539717]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iran President Visits Iraq On First Foreign Trip Amid Political Turmoil]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-president-visits-iraq-on-first-foreign-trip-amid-political-turmoil-6539717]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 11 Sep 2024 13:56:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iran's new president, Masoud Pezeshkian, began a visit to Iraq on Wednesday, aiming to deepen already close ties with the neighbouring country on his first trip abroad since taking office.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Iran's new president, Masoud Pezeshkian, began a visit to Iraq on Wednesday, aiming to deepen already close ties with the neighbouring country on his first trip abroad since taking office.</p>

<p>The three-day trip comes amid turmoil in the Middle East sparked by the war in Gaza, which has drawn in Iran-backed armed groups around the region and complicated Iraq's relations with the United States.</p>

<p>"Prime Minister Mohammed Shia al-Sudani welcomes the president of the Islamic Republic of Iran, Masoud Pezeshkian," the Iraqi premier's office said in a brief statement alongside a picture of the two men shaking hands on the tarmac at Baghdad airport.</p>

<p>Pezeshkian has vowed to make relations with neighbouring countries a priority as he seeks to ease Iran's international isolation and mitigate the impact of US-led sanctions on its economy.</p>

<p>His visit comes after Western powers on Tuesday announced fresh sanctions on Iran for supplying Russia with short-range missiles for use against Ukraine.</p>

<p>Iranian foreign ministry spokesman Nasser Kanani warned Britain, France and Germany that they "will face the appropriate and proportionate action" for the "hostile" move.</p>

<p>Hours before Pezeshkian's arrival, an explosion rocked a base at the airport used by a US-led anti-jihadist coalition, Iraqi security officials said.</p>

<p>A spokesperson for the Iranian-backed Hezbollah Brigades in Iraq said Tuesday night's "attack" aimed to "disrupt the Iranian president's visit".</p>

<p>Ties between Iran and Iraq, both Shiite-majority countries, have grown closer since the US-led invasion of 2003 toppled the Sunni-dominated regime of Iraqi dictator Saddam Hussein.</p>

<p>"Iraq is one of our friends, brothers and Muslim countries," Pezeshkian said before leaving Iran, according to footage aired on Iranian state television.</p>

<p>"And for this reason, we will go to this country as the first trip," he added.</p>

<p>Pezeshkian, who took office in July after an early election following the death of his predecessor Ebrahim Raisi in a helicopter crash, has previously linked shoring up ties to sanctions pressure.</p>

<p>"Relations with neighbouring countries... can neutralise a significant amount of pressure of the sanctions," he said last month.</p>

<p>Iran has suffered years of crippling Western sanctions, especially after its arch-foe the United States, under then-president Donald Trump, unilaterally abandoned a landmark nuclear deal between the Islamic Republic and major powers in 2018.</p>

<p>Pezeshkian has made the top diplomat who negotiated the 2015 deal, Mohammad Javad Zarif, his vice president for strategic affairs as part of his bid for a more open Iran.</p>

<h3><strong>Key trade partners</strong></h3>

<p>Iran has become one of Iraq's leading trade partners and wields considerable political influence in Baghdad, where its Iraqi allies dominate parliament and the current government.</p>

<p>Every year, millions of Iranian pilgrims travel to Iraq's Shiite holy cities of Najaf and Karbala, and Pezeshkian will also visit the shrines there during his visit.</p>

<p>Non-oil trade between Iran and Iraq stood at nearly $5 billion over the five months from March 2024, Iranian media reported.</p>

<p>Iran also exports millions of cubic metres of gas a day to Iraq to fuel its power plants, under a regularly renewed waiver from US sanctions.</p>

<p>Iraq is billions of dollars in arrears on its payments for the imports, which cover 30 percent of its electricity needs.</p>

<p>Political scientist Ali al-Baidar said expanding trade ties was a major goal of Pezeshkian's visit.</p>

<p>"Iran needs the Iraqi market for its exports, just as it needs Iraq's energy imports," the Iraqi analyst said.</p>

<h3><strong>US troop drawdown&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Washington still has around 2,500 troops in Iraq and 900 in neighbouring Syria as part of an international coalition against the Islamic State jihadist group.</p>

<p>Last winter, US-led coalition forces in both Iraq and Syria were targeted dozens of times with drones and rocket fire as violence related to the Israel-Hamas war in Gaza has drawn in Iran-backed armed groups across the Middle East.</p>

<p>The barrage of attacks triggered retaliatory US air strikes in both countries.</p>

<p>On Sunday, Iraqi Defence Minister Thabet al-Abbassi told pan-Arab television channel Al-Hadath that the US-led coalition would pull out of most of Iraq by September 2025 and the Kurdish autonomous region by September 2026.</p>

<p>Despite months of talks, the target dates have yet to be agreed between Baghdad and Washington.</p>

<p>Pezeshkian will also travel to the Kurdish regional capital Arbil for talks with Kurdish officials, Iran's official IRNA news agency said.</p>

<p>In March last year, Tehran signed a security agreement with the federal government in Baghdad after launching air strikes against bases of Iranian Kurdish rebel groups in the autonomous region.</p>

<p>They have since agreed to disarm the rebels and remove them from border areas.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/is7lb2vo_iran-presidents-visit-to-iraq-reuters_625x300_11_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Iran President's visit comes after Western powers on Tuesday announced fresh sanctions on Iran.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-vs-kamala-harris-debate-sparks-meme-fest-online-6538915]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Trump Is Cooked": Internet Reacts To Crucial US Presidential Debate]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-vs-kamala-harris-debate-sparks-meme-fest-online-6538915]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 11 Sep 2024 13:47:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former US President Donald Trump and Vice President Kamala Harris on Tuesday faced off in their first presidential debate, sparking an immediate wave of reactions online.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">Former US President Donald Trump and Vice President Kamala Harris on Tuesday faced off in their first presidential debate, sparking an immediate wave of reactions online. Hosted by ABC News, the 90-minute debate covered topics such as the economy, abortion rights, the Israel-Gaza and Russia-Ukraine conflicts, and immigration laws. Both Trump and Harris took aim at each other's policies with sharp retorts, making it one of the most intense debates of the election season.&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">Trump accused the Biden administration of mishandling the economy and criticised their foreign policy. Kamala Harris fired back, defending the administration's achievements and attacking Trump's controversial immigration reforms and handling of foreign affairs during his presidency.&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">As the debate wrapped up, social media platforms exploded with memes, highlighting key moments.&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">A user wrote on X (formerly Twitter), “Americans watching the debate rеalizing we are in the late stage of an еmpіre,” with a GIF of Homelander, a character from the popular TV show&nbsp;<em>The Boys</em>, watching hopelessly in a room full of people.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">americans watching the debate rеalizing we are in the late stage of an еmpіre <a href="https://t.co/TZgT7oyYJm">pic.twitter.com/TZgT7oyYJm</a></p>
— kira ???? (@kirawontmiss) <a href="https://twitter.com/kirawontmiss/status/1833696550872027239?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 11, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p dir="ltr">Another wrote, “Oh Kamala clocking that orange man in this debate,” followed by a clip of American rapper Nicki Minaj applauding.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">oh kamala clocking that orange man in this debate <a href="https://t.co/ugEC3KRQLV">pic.twitter.com/ugEC3KRQLV</a></p>
— ALV ???? (@AriLuxeVibez) <a href="https://twitter.com/AriLuxeVibez/status/1833676063093686677?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 11, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p dir="ltr">A viral collage claimed to capture the contrast between Trump and Harris during the debate, showing the former with a confused scowl and Harris with a confident smile. "Debate summed up,” the caption read.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Debate summed up <a href="https://t.co/wKCOuaFONX">pic.twitter.com/wKCOuaFONX</a></p>
— Secular Talk???? (@KyleKulinski) <a href="https://twitter.com/KyleKulinski/status/1833698668492558459?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 11, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p dir="ltr">“Republicans coming up with the cat and dog eating story two days before the debate,” a post read.&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">republicans coming up with the cat and dog eating story two days before the debate <a href="https://t.co/5UDUQgCOOr">pic.twitter.com/5UDUQgCOOr</a></p>
— brandon* (@brndxix) <a href="https://twitter.com/brndxix/status/1833679911455687147?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 11, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p dir="ltr">This hilarious post said "‘take a shot every time Trump lies or deflects a question'," accompanied by a clip of a drunk man tumbling down the stairs with a glass of alcohol in hand.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">“Take a shot everytime trump lies or deflects a question”<br />
<br />
Me by the first break <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Debate2024?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Debate2024</a> <a href="https://t.co/3Yc1qw8gnX">pic.twitter.com/3Yc1qw8gnX</a></p>
— emily :) (@Ewobbuffet) <a href="https://twitter.com/Ewobbuffet/status/1833643759612887521?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 10, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p dir="ltr">“Trump is cooked,” read a reaction.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Trump is cooked ???????? <a href="https://t.co/4EBjMBmXOl">pic.twitter.com/4EBjMBmXOl</a></p>
— juju ???? (@ayeejuju) <a href="https://twitter.com/ayeejuju/status/1833681234008195573?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 11, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p dir="ltr">Check out other memes here:</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">the presidential debate: <a href="https://t.co/u1RDxkVmo1">pic.twitter.com/u1RDxkVmo1</a></p>
— ໊ (@buffys) <a href="https://twitter.com/buffys/status/1833669271114715405?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 11, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Trump: “She wants to take everybody's guns!”<br />
<br />
Kamala: <a href="https://t.co/nsjooEKddO">pic.twitter.com/nsjooEKddO</a></p>
— Josiah Johnson (@KingJosiah54) <a href="https://twitter.com/KingJosiah54/status/1833695339368624304?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 11, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">pets watchin the presidential debate <a href="https://t.co/ka0H7kkiQ9">pic.twitter.com/ka0H7kkiQ9</a></p>
— Devin Walker (@Devin_Walker2) <a href="https://twitter.com/Devin_Walker2/status/1833682184982450179?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 11, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Fact checkers after only 9 minutes of the <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/PresidentialDebate?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#PresidentialDebate</a> <a href="https://t.co/Rq896PLMby">pic.twitter.com/Rq896PLMby</a></p>
— Thor: NIGnarok (@hosienation) <a href="https://twitter.com/hosienation/status/1833674633578525130?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 11, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p dir="ltr">Not long after the debate ended, Democratic candidate Kamala Harris challenged Donald Trump to a second face-off. The Harris campaign issued an email, talking about her performance and criticising Trump's responses. Trump responded, saying Harris wants another debate because she didn't do well, and he would “think about that.”</p>

<p dir="ltr">Meanwhile, the vice presidential debate between Democratic candidate Tim Walz and Republican candidate JD Vance is scheduled for October 1.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/7tirvqog_trump_625x300_11_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/japan-might-have-driverless-bullet-trains-from-mid-2030s-6539480]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Japan Might Have Driverless Bullet Trains By Mid-2030s]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/japan-might-have-driverless-bullet-trains-from-mid-2030s-6539480]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 11 Sep 2024 13:22:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Shinkansen bullet trains could be whizzing around Japan without drivers from the mid-2030s, one of its main rail operators said, motivated in part by the country's demographic crisis.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Shinkansen bullet trains could be whizzing around Japan without drivers from the mid-2030s, one of its main rail operators said, motivated in part by the country's demographic crisis.</p>

<p>East Japan Railway (JR East) will first introduce trains where many of the driver's tasks are automated -- but they will remain in the cab -- on parts of one route from 2028, the firm said Tuesday.</p>

<p>The following year, the company hopes to trial driverless trains on a short stretch of out-of-service track before rolling them out between Tokyo and Niigata on the Joetsu Shinkansen line in the mid-2030s.</p>

<p>"Through realising driverless driving and transforming railway management to an efficient and sustainable system, we will adapt to changes in the social environment such as declining population and reforms in ways of how workers work," a company statement said.</p>

<p>The main drive behind the plan, however, "is the need to constantly innovate railway technology, and that could in turn help address the labour shortage and other issues", a JR East spokesman told AFP on Wednesday.</p>

<p>The Shinkansen's maximum speed on the Joetsu route is 275 kilometres (170 miles) per hour, but on other lines, they can run at 300 km/h or faster.</p>

<p>Japan, whose shrinking population is the world's second oldest, is already facing worker shortages across many sectors of the economy.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2019-05/6dk5jp6o_shinkansen-bullet-train-afp_625x300_18_May_19.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Shinkansen's maximum speed is 275 kilometres (170 miles) per hour (file).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-threatens-action-against-western-sanctions-over-arms-supply-to-russia-6539336]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iran Threatens Action Against Western Sanctions Over Arms Supply To Russia]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-threatens-action-against-western-sanctions-over-arms-supply-to-russia-6539336]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 11 Sep 2024 13:05:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iran has vowed to respond to fresh sanctions imposed by Britain, France and Germany over what they said was its supply of short-range missiles to Russia for use in Ukraine.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Iran has vowed to respond to fresh sanctions imposed by Britain, France and Germany over what they said was its supply of short-range missiles to Russia for use in Ukraine.</p>

<p>"This action of the three European countries is the continuation of the hostile policy of the West and economic terrorism against the people of Iran, which will face the appropriate and proportionate action of the Islamic Republic of Iran," foreign ministry spokesman Nasser Kanani said in a statement late Tuesday.</p>

<p>The three governments had announced they would take steps to cancel air services agreements with Iran and "work towards imposing sanctions on Iran Air".</p>

<p>"In addition, we will pursue the designations of significant entities and individuals involved with Iran's ballistic missile programme and the transfer of ballistic missiles and other weapons to Russia," they added.</p>

<p>Iran again denied it had delivered any weapons to Russia for use in the Ukraine war.</p>

<p>"Any claim that the Islamic Republic of Iran has sold ballistic missiles to the Russian Federation is completely baseless and false," Kanani said.</p>

<p>Earlier, US Secretary of State Antony Blinken said Russia had received shipments of ballistic missiles from Iran and "will likely use them within weeks in Ukraine".</p>

<p>He added that dozens of Russian military personnel have received training in Iran on using the Fath-360 missile, which has a range of 120 kilometres (75 miles).</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/q61vg93g_iran-military-reuters_625x300_13_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Iran denied delivering any weapons to Russia for use in the Ukraine war (file).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-backs-donald-trump-claims-he-will-get-things-done-as-us-president-6539324]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["I Don't Think Hosts Were Fair To...": Musk After Trump-Harris Debate]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-backs-donald-trump-claims-he-will-get-things-done-as-us-president-6539324]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 11 Sep 2024 13:03:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Elon Musk is endorsing Donald Trump in the 2024 US elections.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">Billionaire Elon Musk today spoke on the first presidential debate between Republican nominee Donald Trump and Democrat Kamala Harris and said that while Harris "exceeded expectations", Trump would be "more effective in getting things done".</p>

<p dir="ltr">On his social media platform X, Musk wrote, "While I don't think the debate hosts were fair to [Donald Trump], [Kamala Harris] exceeded most people's expectations tonight."</p>

<p dir="ltr">"When it comes to getting things done, not just saying nice-sounding words, I strongly believe that Trump will do a far better job," he added.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Elon Musk also took a jab at the Biden administration, suggesting that Vice President Harris is "basically in charge already" due to Biden's frequent absences.</p>

<p dir="ltr">“If Kamala can do great things, why hasn't she?,” he said, adding that Biden "rarely shows up for work, so she's basically in charge already".</p>

<p dir="ltr">“Do you want current trends to continue for 4 more years or do you want change?”</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">While I don't think the debate hosts were fair to <a href="https://twitter.com/realDonaldTrump?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@realDonaldTrump</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/KamalaHarris?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@KamalaHarris</a> exceeded most people's expectations tonight.<br />
<br />
That said, when it comes to getting things done, not just saying nice-sounding words, I strongly believe that Trump will do a far better job.<br />
<br />
After…</p>
— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1833743479773818939?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 11, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p dir="ltr">In a separate post, he said "we will never reach Mars if Kamala wins".</p>

<p>"Unless there is significant government reform, laws and regulations will keep getting worse every year until every great endeavor, from high-speed rail between our cities to making life multiplanetary, is effectively illegal. Trump supports a government efficiency commission to allow great things to be done, Kamala does not," he wrote.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Unless there is significant government reform, laws &amp; regulations will keep getting worse every year until every great endeavor, from high-speed rail between our cities to making life multiplanetary, is effectively illegal.<br />
<br />
Trump supports a government efficiency commission to…</p>
— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1833755778924351663?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 11, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Elon Musk has endorsed Trump, and in return, the former President has pledged to set up a government commission that could give the tech billionaire significant responsibilities in auditing federal spending and regulations. This move strengthens their pre-election alliance, with Mr Musk potentially leading the commission if Trump wins a second term.</p>

<p dir="ltr">The first presidential debate saw both Trump and Harris clash on key issues like the economy, abortion and foreign policy. In the 90-minute session, Trump criticised the Biden administration's handling of the economy and foreign policy, while Harris defended their achievements and attacked Trump's controversial immigration reforms and past foreign policy decisions.&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">Following the debate, singer <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/backing-kamala-harris-taylor-swift-calls-herself-childless-cat-lady-6538227 ">Taylor Swift</a> made headlines by endorsing Kamala Harris. She embraced the "Childless Cat Lady" label, a term used by Trump's running mate JD Vance to disparage women without children. The singer declared she was voting for Harris because she is a "steady-handed, gifted leader" who fights for Ms Swift's believed causes.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">In response to Taylor Swift's endorsement, Mr Musk, who is backing Trump, made a comment on X, <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fine-taylor-you-win-elon-musk-after-taylor-swift-backs-kamala-harris-6538352#pfrom=home-ndtv_topstories \">offering to give the singer a child</a>&nbsp;and protect her cats. “Fine Taylor … you win … I will give you a child and guard your cats with my life,” the billionaire wrote.&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">Tuesday's debate saw Kamala Harris launch scathing attacks on Donald Trump, calling him a "convicted felon", "friend of dictators" and accusing him of using "race to divide the American people". Trump accused her of borrowing campaign ideas from Joe Biden and labelling her a "Marxist".</p>

<p dir="ltr">After the first presidential debate, the Democratic candidate swiftly challenged Donald Trump to a second face-off.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/uqplijs8_musk-trump-harris-_625x300_11_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/rahul-gandhi-meeting-us-lawmaker-ilhan-omar-she-introduced-anti-india-resolutions-says-bjp-6539327]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[BJP Attacks Rahul Gandhi For Meeting "Anti-India" US Lawmaker Ilhan Omar]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/rahul-gandhi-meeting-us-lawmaker-ilhan-omar-she-introduced-anti-india-resolutions-says-bjp-6539327]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 11 Sep 2024 13:01:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[BJP leaders have severely criticized Congress leader and Lok Sabha LoP Rahul Gandhi following his meeting with US Congresswoman Ilhan Omar in the United States.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>BJP leaders have severely criticized Congress leader and Lok Sabha Leader of Opposition Rahul Gandhi following his meeting with US Congresswoman Ilhan Omar in the United States. BJP IT Cell head Amit Malviya accused the Congress of working against the country.</p>

<p>"India's Leader of Opposition Rahul Gandhi meets Ilhan Omar in the USA, a Pakistan-sponsored anti-India voice, a radical Islamist, and an advocate of independent Kashmir. Even Pakistani leaders would be more circumspect about being seen with such rabid elements. Congress is now openly working against India," Amit Malviya said in a post on X.</p>

<p>Another BJP spokesperson Shehzad Poonawalla also criticised Rahul Gandhi.<br />
<br />
"After spewing venom against Sikhs and running down India on foreign soil, now Rahul Gandhi meets and engages with anti-India Ilhan Omar - 1) Ilhan had introduced anti-India resolutions in US Congress 2) She has been against abrogation of Art 370 3) She violated India's sovereignty &amp; visited PoK on a trip sponsored by Pakistan 4) She met Imran Khan &amp; other such elements to discuss "Islamophobia" in India 5) She has been instrumental in peddling hatred against Hindus Why did Rahul Gandhi have to meet her? Why is he engaging with the most radical anti-India elements on every foreign trip? In BJP virodh - desh virodh is ok?," he posted on X.</p>

<p>Party spokesperson Pradeep Bhandari said, "Rahul Gandhi's meeting with Pro Pakistan Ilhan Omar in the United States of America has made it clear that - He endorses Pak apologists - He endorses Anti India elements Congress Party chooses to compromise with India's national security."</p>

<p>Congress leader Rahul Gandhi, on a three-day visit to the United States, engaged with the Indian community, students, and US lawmakers. His trip began with meetings at the Rayburn House Office Building, hosted by Congressman Bradley James Sherman. Among the attendees were US Congress members Jonathan Jackson, Ro Khanna, Raja Krishnamoorthi, Barbara Lee, Shri Thanedar, Jesus G. "Chuy" Garcia, Ilhan Omar, Hank Johnson, and Jan Schakowsky.</p>

<p>Sources told ANI that Mr Gandhi also met US diplomat Donald Lu and Congresswoman Pramila Jayapal. He also met Lu, Assistant Secretary of State for South and Central Asia, on September 9 in Washington DC, ahead of Lu's visit to India and Bangladesh. He also interacted with Pramila Jayapal and officials from the US House Foreign Affairs Committee.</p>

<p>Mr Gandhi's visit to the US is his first since becoming the Leader of the Opposition in the Lok Sabha. Following his arrival, Mr Gandhi said he is looking forward to engaging in meaningful discussions that will strengthen the bond between India and the US. In a Facebook post, he described his visit to Dallas as a great start.</p>

<p>"My interaction with students and faculty at the University of Texas was dynamic and engaging, with thoughtful discussions on politics, production, skill-respect in India, and the vital role of youth and women in shaping the future of our nations," he said. He also spoke about the importance of the Indian community and their role in bridging the two countries.</p>

<p>Chairperson of the Indian Overseas Congress, Sam Pitroda, had already outlined the visit's activities, mentioning a full day in Dallas with events including the student discussion, a large community event with nearly 4,000 attendees, and a community dinner. Pitroda also noted upcoming meetings on Capitol Hill, at the National Press Club, with think tanks, and other engagements.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/2dfiiue_rahul-gandhi-ilhan-omar_625x300_11_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Rahul Gandhi met Ilhan Omar in the United States (On extreme right)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/the-us-media-verdict-on-high-stakes-donald-trump-kamala-harris-debate-2024-6539064]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[The US Media Verdict On High-Stakes Donald Trump-Kamala Harris Debate]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/the-us-media-verdict-on-high-stakes-donald-trump-kamala-harris-debate-2024-6539064]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 11 Sep 2024 12:23:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US media gave the edge to Democratic Presidential nominee Kamala Harris in her heated debate with her Republican rival Donald Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US media gave the edge to Democratic Presidential nominee Kamala Harris in her heated debate with her Republican rival Donald Trump. In sharp contrast to President Joe Biden's performance during his July debate, Harris was visibly confident and focused at the prime-time debate held in Philadelphia.</p>

<p>ABC News, which hosted the debate, focused on the falsehoods and conspiracies that Trump resorted to in a desperate attempt to outshine Harris. He was put on the defensive early in the debate as Harris didn't waste time in attacking Trump, it said.</p>

<p><strong>Check highlights of the debate <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-debate-live-donald-trump-and-kamala-harris-to-face-off-in-1st-televised-debate-6537144">here</a></strong></p>

<p>Politico declared Harris the winner of the debate - and said it wasn't even a close victory. She repeatedly baited him and knocked him off balance, it said.</p>

<p>The New York Times said Harris "owned much of the night" as she used her skills as prosecutor to put Trump on the defensive.</p>

<p>Vice President Harris was expected to defend the Biden administration before her rival Trump, but NYT pointed out the Republican was left defending his own record as President rather than picking on hers.</p>

<p><b>Read |&nbsp;</b><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/harris-trump-face-off-for-first-time-in-key-us-presidential-debate-6537401">Trump Vows To End Russia-Ukraine War. "Putin Would Eat You," Says Harris</a></p>

<p>Trump looked "miserable", resorting to crowd sizes and conspiracies - which captured his difficult night, the NYT said. Harris was well prepared in leading him astray, it added.</p>

<p>Washington Post said Trump often strayed from facts and resorted to debunked theories about the 2020 presidential polls that he lost and immigration.</p>

<p>Harris called out Trump's "same old tired playbook, a bunch of lies, grievances and name-calling", declaring the Republican has no plan for the people and is more interested in defending himself.</p>

<p>The Post said Harris was able to deliver her case against Trump in a way that Biden struggled to do in July. She was ready with retorts to most of Trump's charges, it added.</p>

<p><strong>Read |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-debate-kamala-harris-donald-trump-how-tables-turned-between-biden-vs-trump-and-harris-vs-trump-6538351">How Tables Turned Between Biden vs Trump And Harris vs Trump</a></p>

<p>CNN said Trump took every bait that Harris used to throw him off his game. The Vice President was well prepared and her every retort was designed to enrage Trump, who was often out of control, it said.</p>

<p>Trump nearly choked on Harris' baits, it reported, pointing out that he went on a bizarre spell insisting that migrants eat Americans' pets.</p>

<p>Fox News tried a balancing act, but focused on Trump having to spar with the ABC News' debate moderators for fact-checking him.</p>

<p>Trump and Harris faced off in their first televised debate on Tuesday.</p>

<p>Trump was initially leading in national polls, but the entry of Harris changed the game. Latest polls suggest the two leaders are neck and neck with the Democrat maintaining a marginal lead over her Republican rival.</p>

<p>If Harris wins the November polls, she will become the first woman president of the US.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/28h27408_trump-harris-debate-2024_625x300_11_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-says-he-doesnt-care-about-kamala-harris-racial-identity-6539001]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump Says He Doesnt Care About Kamala Harris' Racial Identity]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-says-he-doesnt-care-about-kamala-harris-racial-identity-6539001]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 11 Sep 2024 12:15:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former President Donald Trump said he does not care how Vice-President Kamala Harris identified racially. Harris' mother was from India and her father was from Jamaica. She identified both as black and Indian American.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former President Donald Trump said he does not care how Vice-President Kamala Harris identified racially. Harris' mother was from India and her father was from Jamaica. She identified both as black and Indian American.</p>

<p>"I don't, and I don't care," Trump said at the presidential debate when he was referencing the earlier statement. "I don't care what she is. I don't care if you make a big deal out of something. I couldn't care less. Whatever she wants to be is okay with me."</p>

<p>When the moderators pushed back, reminding him of his earlier statement, he said, "So I don't know. I don't know. I mean, all I can say is, I read where she was not black that she put out, and I'll say that. And then I read that she was black, and that's okay. Either one was okay with me. That's up to her."</p>

<p>In July, Trump said at a black journalists' conference, "I didn't know she was black until a number of years ago when she happened to turn black and now she wants to be known as black. So, I don't know, is she Indian or is she black?" Trump said.</p>

<p>Asked to respond to Trump's new position on the issue, Harris said, "I think it's a tragedy that we have someone who wants to be President who has consistently, over the course of his career, attempted to use race to divide the American people. You know, I do believe that the vast majority of us know that we have so much more in common than what separates us, and we don't want this kind of approach that is just constantly trying to divide us, especially by race."</p>

<p>"And let's remember how Donald Trump started. He owned land, he owned buildings, and he was investigated because he refused to rent property to black families. Let's remember this is the same individual who took out a full-page ad in the New York Times calling for the execution of five young black and Latino boys who were innocent. The Central Park Five took out a full-page ad calling for their execution."&nbsp;</p>

<p>"This is the same individual who spread birth lies about the first black President of the United States. And I think the American people want better than that. Want better than this. Want someone who understands as I do. I travel to our country. We see in each other, a friend. We see each other, a neighbour. We don't want a leader who is constantly trying to have Americans point their fingers at each other," she added.</p>

<p>Trump hit back, saying, "This is the most divisive President in the history of our country. There's never been anything like it. They're destroying our country, and they come up with things like what she just said, going back many, many years when a lot of people, including Mayor Bloomberg, agreed with me on the Central Park Five, they admitted, they said they pleaded guilty. And I said, well, if they plead guilty, they badly hurt a person, killed a person, ultimately. And if they plead guilty, then they plead we're not guilty ...I built one of the greatest economies in the history of the world, and I'm going to build it again."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/vsu6q5ig_trump-harris_625x300_11_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Former President Donald Trump said he does not care about Vice-President Kamala Harris' race.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/elon-musk-xai-tesla-musks-ai-side-gig-should-keep-its-distance-from-tesla-6538753]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Musks AI Side Gig Should Keep Its Distance From Tesla]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/elon-musk-xai-tesla-musks-ai-side-gig-should-keep-its-distance-from-tesla-6538753]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 11 Sep 2024 11:37:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[If Tesla were to now actually invest billions in xAI, and/or share revenue with it, the potential conflict of interest could hardly be clearer.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The all-in view of Tesla Inc. was summed up in a line from a report this summer by one of the more all-in analysts covering the company: "The car is to Tesla what the video game chip is to Nvidia. The car is to Tesla what selling books is to Amazon." Morgan Stanley's Adam Jonas was arguing that Tesla is morphing from a maker of electric vehicles to an artificial intelligence and robotics powerhouse. On this reading, a Tesla isn't just a box-on-wheels with a battery but an AI-delivery vehicle. Chief Executive Elon Musk also touts this thesis, declaring with typical bravado: "If somebody doesn't believe Tesla is going to solve autonomy, I think they should not be an investor in the company."</p>

<p>An asterisk on that statement might be in order. This weekend, the Wall Street Journal reported that xAI, Musk's artificial intelligence side gig to his social media side gig, X, has floated the possibility of licensing its models to aid Tesla's autonomous driving ambitions in exchange for a revenue-sharing deal. Musk dismissed the story over the course of several tweets, including calling it "nonsense."</p>

<p>On the other hand, only five months ago, Musk accused Reuters of "lying" when it reported that Tesla had scrapped plans for a sub-$30,000 EV model, only for the company to soon after announce a pivot from a very cheap EV toward robotaxis. Plus, Musk has already polled that body of impartial sages known as his followers as to whether Tesla should invest $5 billion in xAI (the majority answered in the affirmative).</p>

<p>That flapping sound you hear is the wind blowing through a resplendence of red flags.</p>

<p>Musk has a habit of treating his various separate companies as parts of a unified whole. The most egregious example was Tesla's acquisition of SolarCity Corp. in 2016, whereby the EV company bought a spiraling rooftop solar business that was chaired by Musk, owed him (and Space X) money and was run by his cousin. Even Jonas later characterized that deal as a "controlled detonation." When Musk first bought Twitter Inc., which became X, he brought in engineers from Tesla to review its code. A few months ago, he redirected thousands of Nvidia Corp. chips destined for Tesla to xAI, explaining it away as a logistical hiccup.</p>

<p>If Tesla were to now actually invest billions in xAI, and/or share revenue with it, the potential conflict of interest could hardly be clearer. X has struggled as a business since Musk's takeover, with advertising revenue under pressure and Fidelity, one of the co-investors, marking down the value of its stake enormously. Musk has indicated that the shareholders of X would own 25% of xAI, though it isn't clear if that would be individually or collectively through X itself. Either way, any infusion of cash or revenue potential from Tesla would be useful not only to xAI but to the broader X project.</p>

<p>Such a deal would also make a mockery of Tesla's justification for awarding a gigantic options package to Musk and then pushing for its reinstatement after a Delaware court struck it down. Chairwoman Robyn Denholm exhorted shareholders to vote yes by arguing, in part, that it would keep Musk's roving eye focused on Tesla: "We want those ideas, that energy and that time to be at Tesla, for the benefit of you, our owners," she wrote. This followed Musk's unsubtle threat to take his AI vision elsewhere if he didn't get a bigger stake in Tesla (after he had sold off a chunk during the takeover of Twitter).</p>

<p>If Tesla were to end up investing in, or contracting with, another Musk-controlled venture that literally has AI in its name, that rather suggests at least some of his AI ideas went elsewhere, options or no. Beyond the conflicts and governance-trolling, though, there's a more fundamental problem here.</p>

<p>Jonas, like similarly bullish analysts, ascribes only a fraction of his Tesla valuation to the making and selling of EVs, even though this accounts for the vast majority of the company's revenue and profit. The only way to remotely justify the almost $700 billion market cap is to believe that Tesla isn't a mere automaker but instead an AI pioneer.</p>

<p>Yet if that is the case, if Tesla is going to "solve autonomy," why would it consider outsourcing core AI functions or feel the need to invest billions of dollars into a startup launched only last year? Automakers do partner with other companies for certain technologies. But Musk has been saying for years that Tesla is already on the cusp of cracking vehicle autonomy under its own steam. Putting money, or revenue, into xAI undercuts that narrative and would divert some of the promised value away from Tesla's shareholders to Musk's own ventures.</p>

<p>Perhaps these are mere proposals and polls that stay just that. Still, there was another line in that Jonas report that sticks, telling investors to prepare for the company's new strategy "to more conspicuously connect Tesla with Elon's other controlled enterprises such as SpaceX/Starlink, X and xAI." Autonomy is, after all, about just doing what you want.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/0n3cgu_elon-musk-bloomberg_625x300_11_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Musk has a tendency to see his companies as part of a unified whole]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/weight-loss-drug-safe-effective-for-children-under-12-shows-new-study-6538733]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Weight Loss Drug Safe, Effective For Children Under 12, Shows New Study]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/weight-loss-drug-safe-effective-for-children-under-12-shows-new-study-6538733]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 11 Sep 2024 11:31:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A weight loss drug has been found to be broadly safe and effective for children under 12 with obesity, according to a small study on Wednesday that was cautiously welcomed by outside experts.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A weight loss drug has been found to be broadly safe and effective for children under 12 with obesity, according to a small study on Wednesday that was cautiously welcomed by outside experts.</p>

<p>A new class of weight loss drugs called GLP-1 agonists have become hugely popular across the world in the last couple of years, sparking stock shortages and widespread off-label use despite steep prices.</p>

<p>But little research has been conducted on how these new drugs work on young children.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Obesity in children and adolescents has quadrupled since 1990, according to the World Health Organization. Yet there are no regularly prescribed drugs which treat obesity in children.</p>

<p>The study looked at an older GLP-1 agonist called liraglutide, sold under the brand name Saxenda by Danish pharmaceutical giant Novo Nordisk, which also makes the blockbuster semaglutide drugs Ozempic and Wegovy.</p>

<p>The US-based phase 3 trial, which was funded by Novo Nordisk, was the first to investigate liraglutide's effect on under-12s.</p>

<p>It involved 82 children aged six to 12 with obesity, some of whom were randomly assigned a daily injection of liraglutide, while others received a placebo. The children were also encouraged to exercise and eat healthily.</p>

<p>After a little over a year, 46 per cent of the children receiving the drug saw their body mass index (BMI) shrink by at least five per cent, according to the study.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Only nine per cent of the placebo group had such a reduction in BMI, which also takes into account height and was used because children at these ages grow quickly.</p>

<p>Some children taking the drug also reported side effects such as vomiting and nausea, which was in line with those experienced by adults, the researchers said.</p>

<p>Lead study author Claudia Fox of the University of Minnesota said that kids living with obesity are currently told to just "try harder with diet and exercise".</p>

<p>But these findings raise hopes that a drug could one day help these children "live healthier, more productive lives," she said in a statement.&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>Stunted growth fear&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Stephen Burgess, a statistician at the University of Cambridge not involved in the research, said the study showed that drugs could "help change the trajectory of weight gain in young children".</p>

<p>"While receiving weight loss injections is clearly not the ideal solution to childhood obesity, reductions in body mass index for trial participants were sustained even beyond the duration of the treatment course," he told AFP.</p>

<p>Simon Cork, a researcher at the UK's Anglia Ruskin University, said that "the evidence that liraglutide is both safe and effective in children is positive".</p>

<p>But one concern about children taking weight loss drugs such as GLP-1 agonists which work by suppressing appetite is that this could risk stunting growth, he warned.</p>

<p>The new study showed no evidence this had occurred.</p>

<p>But Cork said that "further studies over longer time periods will need to be undertaken to ensure that appetite suppression in these children does not have unforeseen negative consequences later in their development".</p>

<p>The study was presented at the European Association for the Study of Diabetes being held in Madrid and was also published in the New England Journal of Medicine.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2018-10/q0seobkg_childhood-obesity-_625x300_10_October_18.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Obesity in children and adolescents has quadrupled since 1990, according to the World Health Organization]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/energy-drinks-and-caffeine-craze-comes-at-a-cost-for-impoverished-afghans-6538615]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Energy Drinks And Caffeine Craze Comes At A Cost For Impoverished Afghans]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/energy-drinks-and-caffeine-craze-comes-at-a-cost-for-impoverished-afghans-6538615]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 11 Sep 2024 11:15:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A production line in a warehouse in western Afghanistan churns out 24 energy drinks every second, feeding a thirst for the tonic used to mask life's hardships and lift wilting spirits.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A production line in a warehouse in western Afghanistan churns out 24 energy drinks every second, feeding a thirst for the tonic used to mask life's hardships and lift wilting spirits.</p>

<p>The Taliban government has purged many signs of Western influence but a stimulant drink craze that arrived with US soldiers remains, and has even sprouted a thriving domestic industry.</p>

<p>Alcohol is outlawed in Afghanistan but caffeine-rich energy drinks are consumed by all, from secret police to children, and advertised on billboards more than even Taliban state propaganda.</p>

<p>Many homegrown brand names evoke the bygone war: "Commando", "Attack", and "Predator".</p>

<p>"It's obvious that there are more struggles and hardships of life among the youth here," said Milad Ghaznavi at a Herat city supermarket aisle that boasted 40 varieties of the beverage.</p>

<p>"Energy drinks have become kind of a habit and a craving for people," Ghaznavi told AFP.</p>

<p>"They consume anything that comforts them," said the 19-year-old, who claimed he had been "addicted" but gave them up for health reasons.</p>

<h3><strong>'We drink energy'&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Energy drinks, which are high in caffeine and sugar and often more available than drinking water at roadside kiosks, are seen by many Afghans as a way to supplement an insufficient diet.</p>

<p>Nearly 90 per cent of people in poverty-stricken Afghanistan are consuming inadequate food, according to the World Food Programme (WFP).</p>

<p>Most recent data from March reveals 86 per cent of households are relying on less-preferred and cheaper food, with more than a third reducing meals and more than half reducing portions.</p>

<p>Gulzar, a labourer, fuels his 14-hour work days with four cans of "Hit".</p>

<p>"We work here, we sweat, so when we are tired we drink energy," said the 40-year-old, who goes by one name.</p>

<p>"If you don't drink you are tired, you have a headache, you are weary."</p>

<p>But drinking that many energy drinks comes with a cost.</p>

<h3><strong>Health impacts&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Gulzar's diet contains over 100 grams of sugar -- twice the intake the World Health Organization recommends -- as well as a caffeine hit equivalent to six espressos, which he compares to a smoking habit.</p>

<p>Excessive caffeine consumption can cause high blood pressure, heart palpitations, anxiety and insomnia, according to the US Food and Drug Administration.&nbsp;</p>

<p>But Gulzar says he has no choice.</p>

<p>"Afghanistan is below impoverished," he said. "If we had the means we wouldn't use this."</p>

<p>Local brands cost only around 30 Afghani ($0.40) while imported Red Bull or Monster, two of the most popular global names, are unaffordable to most.</p>

<p>The poorest Afghans, who rely on dwindling foreign aid, are unable to buy energy drinks and instead subsist on bread with caffeinated green tea.</p>

<h3><strong>&nbsp;'Business is good'</strong>&nbsp;</h3>

<p>Energy drinks were invented in Japan in 1962 but exploded in popularity during the 2000s into a global sector worth nearly $40 billion this year, according to research firm Future Market Insights.</p>

<p>In the industrial hub of western Herat, the Pamir Cola company says it produces over a million cans daily.</p>

<p>Still, Pamir Cola says it is a minor player in an industry it estimates produces two cans a day for each of Afghanistan's 40 million citizens.</p>

<p>The figure is impossible to verify because of the drought of data on Afghan commerce.</p>

<p>Workers at the company funnel sugar and citric acid into the bowels of a machine pumping out product every moment the electricity is on.</p>

<p>Pamir Cola says it manufactures to EU standards in a largely unregulated Afghan market left to its own devices.</p>

<p>While Red Bull affiliates with glamorous extreme sports and Monster with motorsports, Zahir Shah Bahaduri, who runs Pamir Cola with his two brothers, is under no illusions.</p>

<p>"For the people of Afghanistan who do hard labour duties and don't have good food, the best way for them is to drink energy drinks," said the 45-year-old.</p>

<p>"I think business is good and will probably get better."</p>

<p>By the side of a Kabul highway, enterprising vendors stack energy drinks high as the traffic roars past.</p>

<p>"It removes their tiredness," said 36-year-old Ahmad Gulab, who sometimes sells to customers by the crate. "It's their joy in life."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/0e897bog_afghanistan-energy-drink-craze-afp-_625x300_11_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[By the side of a Kabul highway, enterprising vendors stack energy drinks high as the traffic roars past.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>