<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Sun, 24 Nov 2024 13:27:39 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jay-bhattacharya-born-in-kolkata-emerges-as-trumps-top-pick-to-head-us-health-agency-7093578]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Jay Bhattacharya Emerges As Trump's Top Pick To Head US Health Agency]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jay-bhattacharya-born-in-kolkata-emerges-as-trumps-top-pick-to-head-us-health-agency-7093578]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 24 Nov 2024 13:23:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Jay Bhattacharya, a Stanford University-trained physician and economist, has reportedly emerged as the presumptive favourite of President-elect Donald Trump's transition team for the post of next director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH).]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Jay Bhattacharya, a Stanford University-trained physician and economist, has reportedly emerged as the presumptive favourite of President-elect Donald Trump's transition team for the post of next director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH), a nearly USD 50 billion agency that oversees the nation's biomedical research.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Stanford-trained physician and economist met this week with Robert F. Kennedy Jr.-- who has been appointed by Mr Trump to lead the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS)-- United States' top health agency which oversees NIH and other health agencies, the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/health/2024/11/23/bhattacharya-nih-director-trump-candidate/" rel="No Follow, No Index" target="_blank">Washington Post</a> reported citing three people.</p>

<p>As per the report, Dr Bhattacharya impressed Kennedy with his ideas to overhaul NIH by shifting the agency's focus toward funding more innovative research. He also reportedly recommended reducing the influence of some of its longest-serving career officials, among other ideas. NIH awards funding grants to researchers, oversees clinical trials on its Maryland campus, and supports a variety of efforts to develop drugs and therapeutics.</p>

<p>Mr Trump's transition team has yet to make any official statement regarding the developments being reported. The decision of who will lead NIH will not be final until the President-elect himself announces it, as Mr Trump is known to sometimes rebuff his advisers' recommendations. The President-elect's transition team has, reportedly, also looked at other candidates to lead NIA.</p>

<h2><strong>Who Is Jay Bhattacharya?</strong></h2>

<p>Born in Kolkata, India, in 1968, Jayanta "Jay" Bhattacharya is a Professor of Health Policy at Stanford University and a research associate at the National Bureau of Economics Research. He holds an MD and PhD in economics -- both earned at Stanford University -- and also directs Stanford's Center for Demography and Economics of Health and Aging.&nbsp;</p>

<p>As per Stanford's official website, Dr Bhattacharya's research focuses on the health and well-being of vulnerable populations, with a particular emphasis on the role of government programs, biomedical innovation, and economics. His recent research focuses on the epidemiology of COVID-19 as well as an evaluation of policy responses to the epidemic.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The economist's broader research interests encompass the implications of population ageing for future population health and medical spending in developed countries, the measurement of physician performance tied to physician payment by insurers, and the role played by biomedical innovation on health. He has published 135 articles in top peer-reviewed scientific journals in medicine, economics, health policy, epidemiology, statistics, law, and public health among other fields.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Dr Bhattacharya was a prominent critic of the federal government's COVID-19 response, co-writing an October 2020 open letter known as the Great Barrington Declaration that called for rolling back coronavirus-related shutdowns while keeping "focused protections" for vulnerable populations, such as older Americans. At the time, the proposal won support from Republican politicians and some Americans eager to resume daily life, but it was criticized as being unethical and infeasible by Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus, the director-general of the World Health Organization.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/uiepa8pg_jay-bhattacharya-twitter_625x300_24_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Jay Bhattacharya was a prominent critic of the federal government's COVID-19 response]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/worlds-thinnest-spaghetti-that-cant-be-clicked-by-camera-created-by-scientists-7093479]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[World's Thinnest Spaghetti That Can't Be Clicked By Camera Created]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/worlds-thinnest-spaghetti-that-cant-be-clicked-by-camera-created-by-scientists-7093479]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 24 Nov 2024 13:01:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The spaghetti nanofibres can be used as next-generation bandaging or carbonised supercapacitor electrodes.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A team of UK chemists at the University College London (UCL), have created the world's thinnest spaghetti, believed to be 200 times thinner than a human hair and narrower than some wavelengths of light. The study, published in <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://pubs.rsc.org/en/content/articlelanding/2024/na/d4na00601a" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>Nanoscale Advances</em></a>, states that the new brand of pasta smashed the previous record for the thinnest pasta <em>lunga </em>by approximately a thousand times. Since each individual strand was too narrow to be clearly captured by any form of visible light camera or microscope, the researchers used a "scanning electron microscope, scanning the mat with a focused beam of electrons and creating an image based on the pattern of electrons that are deflected".</p>

<p>The 'near-invisible' pasta is not intended to be a new food as it will overcook in under a second. It has been created because extremely fine strands in it, called nanofibres, could have significant medical uses.</p>

<p>The team achieved the desired result by using a technique called 'electrospinning' to create the nanofibres, with diameters of 372 nanometres (billionths of a metre), from a flour mixture. They used flour and formic acid rather than water as the formic acid breaks up the helices (giant stacks of spirals) that make up starch.</p>

<p>Additionally, they had to warm up the mixture for several hours before slowly cooling it back down to make sure it was the right consistency.</p>

<p>"To make spaghetti, you push a mixture of water and flour through metal holes. In our study, we did the same except we pulled our flour mixture through with an electrical charge. It's literally spaghetti but much smaller," said co-author Dr. Adam Clancy.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/food/6-irresistibly-healthy-pasta-recipes-you-must-try-4627069"><strong>Also Read | 6 Irresistibly Healthy Pasta Recipes You Must Try</strong></a></p>

<h3><strong>Uses of nanofibres</strong></h3>

<p>The formed nanofibres are hydrophilic, and can be used as a cheaper, greener replacement for starch in biodegradable, biosourced nanofiber applications, such as next-generation bandaging, or carbonised supercapacitor electrodes.</p>

<p>"Nanofibers, such as those made of starch, show potential for use in wound dressings as they are very porous. In addition, nanofibers are being explored for use as a scaffold to regrow tissue, as they mimic the extra-cellular matrix – a network of proteins and other molecules that cells build to support themselves," said co-author Professor Gareth Williams.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ili7cleo_pasta_625x300_24_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The world's thinnest spaghetti was only captured using an electron microscope.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/a-look-back-at-trump-ag-nominee-pam-bondi-legal-battle-over-a-dog-7093308]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Pam Bondi, Donald Trump Pick For Top Lawyer, Got Sued For "Stealing" A Dog]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/a-look-back-at-trump-ag-nominee-pam-bondi-legal-battle-over-a-dog-7093308]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 24 Nov 2024 12:54:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President-elect Donald Trump's attorney general nominee, Pam Bondi, was once at the centre of a legal dispute over a dog named Tank, whose story continues to draw attention.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President-elect Donald Trump's attorney general nominee, Pam Bondi, was once at the centre of a legal dispute over a dog named Tank, whose story continues to draw attention. The saga began in 2005 when Tank, a St. Bernard, was separated from his Louisiana owners, Steve and Dorreen Couture, during Hurricane Katrina. Tank was later taken to the Pinellas Humane Society in Florida, where Ms Bondi, a prominent animal rights advocate, adopted him and renamed him Noah.</p>

<p>Ms Bondi, who served as Florida's attorney general, was known for her active support of animal rights, even promoting causes like the 2018 Florida ballot measure to ban dog racing. But her involvement with Tank stirred controversy, especially when the dog's original owners tracked him down in 2006.</p>

<p>Ms Bondi argued that Tank had been seriously neglected by the Coutures, citing medical issues like heartworms that had severely affected the dog's health. “He was dying from heartworms. They had filled his heart,” she told <a href="https://www.ocala.com/story/news/2006/05/22/family-fights-to-get-back-dogs-katrina-forced-them-to-give-up/31159332007/ " rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">The St. Petersburg Times</a>. “I took a dog who was a walking skeleton. That's what was wrong with him before the hurricane.”</p>

<p>The Coutures denied these allegations, claiming that the heartworm condition was long-standing, and sought to reclaim their pet. In response, Ms Bondi insisted that she was providing a better environment for Tank. “If I thought I was sending him to a stable environment, where he would be cared for, as hard as it would be, I'd put him in my car and drive him back myself,” she said.</p>

<p>The dispute escalated into a legal battle, which lasted for 16 months and became widely covered by major news outlets.</p>

<p>The case ultimately settled before trial, with the details of the agreement remaining private. Ms Bondi eventually returned Tank to the Coutures, along with supplies of food and medication, but their relationship quickly soured.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Doreen Couture was frustrated with the situation, particularly Ms Bondi's promises. “It was a burden, it really was,” she told The St. Petersburg Times in 2010. “Financially, emotionally, it was a really rough time.” She further criticised Ms Bondi, saying, “Why should I? She stole my dog… She has no compassion at all.”</p>

<p>Despite the settlement, Ms Bondi's reputation regarding the incident remained largely unaffected. In her successful 2010 campaign for Florida attorney general, she declared that the matter had been resolved and claimed she was widely supported by animal rights activists.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/k4b0pc3o_pam-bondi-st-bernard-_625x300_24_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The case ultimately settled before trial.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/too-little-too-late-india-rejects-300-billion-cop29-climate-deal-7093183]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Too Little, Too Late": India Rejects $300 Billion COP29 Climate Deal]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/too-little-too-late-india-rejects-300-billion-cop29-climate-deal-7093183]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 24 Nov 2024 12:10:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India has rejected the new USD 300 billion climate finance deal for the Global South, which has been agreed upon and adopted at the United Nations COP29 Summit in Azerbaijan's capital Baku.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India has rejected the new &nbsp;USD 300 billion climate finance deal for the Global South, which has been agreed upon and adopted at the United Nations COP29 Summit in Azerbaijan's capital Baku. India raised the objection after the financial package had been adopted, saying that it was too little and too late.</p>

<p>Chandni Raina, the representative of the Indian delegation, expressed her disappointment over the outcome and said, "We are disappointed in the outcome which clearly brings out the unwillingness of the developed country parties to fulfil their responsibilities."</p>

<p>Department of Economic Affairs adviser, Raise, while addressing the closing plenary session of the summit, said that the delegation was not allowed to speak before the adoption of the deal.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"I regret to say that this document is nothing more than an optical illusion. This, in our opinion, will not address the enormity of the challenge we all face. Therefore, we oppose the adoption of this document," she said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"USD 300 billion does not address the needs and priorities of developing countries. It is incompatible with the principle of CBDR (Common but Differentiated Responsibilities) and equity, regardless of the battle with the impact of climate change," Raina added.</p>

<p>The Indian negotiator added, "We are very unhappy, disappointed with the process, and object to the adoption of this agenda."</p>

<p>Supporting India, Nigeria said the USD 300 billion climate finance package was a "joke". Malawi and Bolivia also lent support to India.</p>

<h2><strong>About The Deal</strong></h2>

<p>The agreement would provide USD 300 billion annually by 2035, boosting rich countries' previous commitment to provide USD 100 billion per year in climate finance by 2020. That earlier goal was met two years late, in 2022, and expires in 2025. The deal also lays the groundwork for next year's climate summit, to be held in the Amazon rainforest of Brazil, where countries are meant to map out the next decade of climate action.</p>

<p>The summit cut to the heart of the debate over the financial responsibility of industrialized countries - whose historic use of fossil fuels has caused the bulk of greenhouse gas emissions - to compensate others for worsening damage from climate change.</p>

<p>It also laid bare divisions between wealthy governments constrained by tight domestic budgets and developing nations reeling from the costs of storms, floods and droughts.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Negotiations had been due to finish on Friday but ran into overtime as representatives from nearly 200 countries struggled to reach consensus. Talks were interrupted on Saturday as some developing countries and island nations walked away in frustration.</p>

<p>United Nations climate chief Simon Stiell acknowledged the difficult negotiations that led to the agreement but hailed the outcome as an insurance policy for humanity against global warming.</p>

<p>"It has been a difficult journey, but we've delivered a deal...This deal will keep the clean energy boom growing and protect billions of lives," Stiell said.</p>

<p>"But like any insurance policy - it only works - if the premiums are paid in full, and on time."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/r8blid5o_cop20-reuters_625x300_24_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Supporting India, Nigeria said the USD 300 billion climate finance package was a "joke".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-to-release-remaining-files-on-jfks-assassination-he-says-7093010]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump To Release Remaining Files On JFK's Assassination? He Says...]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-to-release-remaining-files-on-jfks-assassination-he-says-7093010]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 24 Nov 2024 11:36:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former US President John F Kennedy was shot dead in 1963 while riding in a convertible car.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump had vowed to release the remaining classified documents related to the 1963 assassination of former US President John F Kennedy during his 2016 US presidential campaign. While he initially delayed the release after taking office, as President-elect once again in 2024, Trump has reiterated his commitment to fulfilling this promise, as per a <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/stephenpastis/2024/11/22/will-trump-release-the-remaining-files-on-jfks-assassination-heres-what-hes-said/ " rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">Forbes</a> report.</p>

<p>The release of government-archived files on JFK's assassination has been a subject of public interest for decades. While most of the millions of archival materials have been made available to the public – around 99 per cent – thousands remain classified or partially redacted.</p>

<p>Over the years, Robert F. Kennedy Jr., who is now nominated to serve in Trump's cabinet, has been vocal about the release of these files. In a tweet marking the 61st anniversary of his uncle's assassination, Kennedy Jr. quoted JFK, saying, "the very word ‘secrecy' is repugnant in a free and open society," alongside a black-and-white photo of the two men. It remains unclear, however, whether he was directly referencing the withheld documents in his post.</p>

<p>In 2017, Trump first expressed his desire to release the complete archives, pledging "great transparency" and hoping to make nearly all of the records public. However, the release was delayed due to national security concerns, as outlined in a White House memo. Trump's stance on the issue resurfaced during his 2024 campaign, where he confirmed plans to open the files "immediately" upon being re-elected.</p>

<p>In an October 2024 interview with comedian Joe Rogan, Trump shared the reasons behind his previous delay, saying that he was persuaded by "good people," including former Secretary of State Mike Pompeo, to hold off for national security reasons. He also mentioned that while he had agreed to postpone the release, he believed the remaining files could soon be made public. Trump said, “I think it's going to be just fine to open” the rest of the documents.</p>

<p>Before that, during a June appearance on the “All In” podcast, Trump further discussed his knowledge of the files, indicating that he had some understanding of their contents. Although the CIA did not directly request the delay, Trump speculated that the agency "was probably behind" the request and might prefer the records remain unreleased.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>The Assassination Of John F Kennedy</strong></p>

<p>Former US President John F. Kennedy was assassinated on November 22, 1963, in Dallas, Texas, during a motorcade through the city. He was shot while riding in a convertible car with his wife, Jacqueline, Texas Governor John Connolly, and Connolly's wife, Nellie. Kennedy was struck by two bullets, one in the upper back and the fatal shot in the head, while travelling through Dealey Plaza. The shots were fired from the Texas School Book Depository, a building that overlooked the motorcade route. Lee Harvey Oswald, a former Marine, was arrested shortly after the shooting and charged with the murder. He was shot and killed by nightclub owner Jack Ruby two days later, before he could stand trial.</p>

<p>The unresolved questions surrounding the assassination, particularly the circumstances of Oswald's shooting while in police custody, have fuelled many conspiracy theories over the years.&nbsp;</p>

<p>As of today, more than 3,000 records remain unreleased or redacted. Information such as names, addresses, and other sensitive details are blacked out in an effort to protect individuals connected to the investigation. In 1992, the President John F. Kennedy Assassination Records Collection Act led to the creation of a complete collection of over five million records, which was stored at the National Archives and Records Administration. The Act required these documents to be released by 2017, with the exception of information that could jeopardise national security.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ncepoq1g_donald-trump_625x300_20_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[File photo]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/im-heartbroken-us-woman-mother-of-two-places-children-for-adoption-due-to-financial-struggles-7092910]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Woman Places Children For Adoption Due To Financial Struggles]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/im-heartbroken-us-woman-mother-of-two-places-children-for-adoption-due-to-financial-struggles-7092910]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 24 Nov 2024 11:12:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[After trying to care for Adriana for about six weeks, Martin realized she couldn't manage alone.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hannah Martin, a 32-year-old from Waymart, Pennsylvania, shared the emotional story of her decision to place both of her children for adoption, describing it as a deeply painful yet necessary choice. She reflected on the experience as "traumatic" and "heartbreaking," but also "heartwarming" because it allowed her to give her children a chance at a better life, according to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.themirror.com/lifestyle/parenting/i-forced-put-2-kids-806824" rel="noindex,nofollow"><em>Mirror</em></a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Now a stay-at-home mom to a 15-year-old son, an 8-year-old daughter, and a 6-year-old son, Martin recounted how, in 2011 at just 19 years old, she had to put her daughter Adriana up for adoption due to financial struggles. Discovering her pregnancy had initially left her "excited but scared," as she had conceived after a casual encounter with her brother's friend. Despite being on birth control, she became pregnant, and the baby's father denied responsibility and refused to provide support.</p>

<p>After trying to care for Adriana for about six weeks, Martin realized she couldn't manage alone. "I couldn't do it," she admitted to The Mirror. "The father refused to help me. He said it wasn't his child." Feeling overwhelmed, she sought someone to adopt Adriana and connected with Maria, a lawyer from Miami, who became a source of immense support. "Maria was like another mother to me," Martin shared. "She helped me through everything-therapy and reassurance that I was doing the right thing."</p>

<p>When faced with a similar situation with her son Tyler, Martin again turned to Maria, who helped her find a loving home for him. However, these decisions have continued to weigh heavily on her. She revealed that she hasn't had contact with either child since the adoption and isn't sure if they even know about her.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Reflecting on the experience, Martin acknowledged the toll it took on her mental health, saying, "It was very hard. I went through a bad time because I have depression. If I could change things, I would have kept them, but I was young, struggling, and didn't know how to access the resources that could have helped us."</p>

<p><br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ejihijgo_mother_625x300_24_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Martin acknowledged the toll it took on her mental health]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pete-hegseth-nomination-as-defence-secretary-rekindles-scrutiny-of-2006-killings-in-iraq-7092770]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[18 Years On, A War Crime Investigation Haunts Trumps Defence Secretary Pick]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pete-hegseth-nomination-as-defence-secretary-rekindles-scrutiny-of-2006-killings-in-iraq-7092770]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 24 Nov 2024 10:44:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Eighteen years ago, an operation targeting suspected al-Qaeda militants in Iraq took a dark turn when US soldiers killed three detainees under suspicious circumstances. At the centre of renewed scrutiny is Pete Hegseth.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Eighteen years ago, an operation targeting suspected al-Qaeda terrorists in Iraq took a dark turn when US soldiers killed three detainees under suspicious circumstances. At the centre of renewed scrutiny is Pete Hegseth, a former platoon leader in the brigade involved, now US President-elect Donald Trump's nominee for Secretary of Defence.</p>

<p>The events of May 9, 2006, during Operation Iron Triangle, remain one of the most infamous examples of misconduct from the Iraq War. US Army soldiers reported killing three detainees, claiming they broke free of their restraints and attacked them. But a subsequent investigation uncovered a darker truth: the detainees had been deliberately released and shot as they fled. This led to court-martial, convictions, and a reprimand for Col. Michael Steele, the brigade commander, whose leadership and command culture were scrutinised.</p>

<p>Pete Hegseth, then a 26-year-old lieutenant in the Army National Guard, joined the 101st Airborne Division's 3rd Brigade Combat Team in 2005, ahead of its deployment to Iraq. Although he was not directly involved in the killings, his deployment with the unit exposed him to the fallout of military misconduct and its impact on the soldiers involved.</p>

<p>“Every single person that was involved in that has had an indelible mark left on them,” Col. Steele said in an interview years later, as per <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/national-security/2024/11/23/pete-hegseth-army-iraq-war-crimes/ " rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">The Washington Post</a>.</p>

<p>Interviews with Hegseth's peers paint a picture of a young officer navigating an intensely aggressive operational environment. The brigade, particularly Charlie Company – labelled “Kill Company” – earned notoriety for its combative tactics. The unit kept a tally of confirmed kills, including civilians, on a whiteboard, signalling a culture that, according to some accounts, blurred ethical lines.</p>

<p>Hegseth himself expressed discomfort with these tactics. In a 2009 interview with The New Yorker, he recalled challenging orders to enter buildings “hot,” or with weapons drawn, fearing civilian casualties. Yet, he also defended the need for aggressiveness, given the insurgency's intensity.</p>

<p>The operation targeted an al-Qaeda training hub on Lake Tharthar, believed to house associates of Abu Musab al-Zarqawi, the al-Qaeda leader in Iraq. Initial reports described a chaotic firefight, but investigations revealed that three detainees, captured during the raid, were executed.</p>

<p>Cpl. William Hunsaker and Pfc. Corey Clagett admitted to killing the detainees under orders from Staff Sgt. Raymond Girouard. Another soldier, Spec. Juston Graber, carried out what he described as a “mercy killing” of a detainee. The investigation uncovered a systematic effort to cover up the crimes, leading to convictions and prison sentences for those involved.</p>

<p>While Hegseth had already been reassigned to governance duties at the time of the killings, his association with the unit exposed him to the long shadow of the incident. Former colleagues describe a fractured morale, as many soldiers felt the Army had unfairly scapegoated the brigade.</p>

<p>In the years since, Pete Hegseth has become an outspoken advocate for US troops accused of war crimes, arguing that restrictive rules of engagement put soldiers in untenable positions. His defence of high-profile cases, such as that of Navy SEAL Edward Gallagher, aligns with his criticism of what he perceives as the military's failure to protect its rank-and-file soldiers.</p>

<p>As a media personality on Fox &amp; Friends Weekend, Hegseth gained the attention of President-elect Trump, who sought his advice on cases involving troops accused of misconduct. Trump's 2019 pardons of soldiers convicted or accused of war crimes reflected Hegseth's influence and populist appeal.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/s80c8g9_pete-hegseth-afp_625x300_17_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Operation 'Iron Triangle' targeted an al-Qaeda training hub on Lake Tharthar.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/brooke-rollins-donald-trumps-loyalist-set-to-be-us-agriculture-secretary-7092581]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Who Is Brooke Rollins, Trump's Loyalist Set To Be US Agriculture Secretary]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/brooke-rollins-donald-trumps-loyalist-set-to-be-us-agriculture-secretary-7092581]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 24 Nov 2024 10:05:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Brooke Rollins currently serves as the CEO of the America First Policy Institute, a non-profit think tank often referred to as Trump's "White House in waiting."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President-elect Donald Trump has tapped policy advocate <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-picks-brooke-rollins-his-loyalist-as-us-agriculture-secretary-7091849 ">Brooke Rollins as his choice for agriculture secretary</a>, making the final selection for his incoming cabinet ahead of his return to the White House in January.</p>

<p>Ms Rollins, 52, currently serves as the CEO of the America First Policy Institute, a non-profit think tank often referred to as Trump's "White House in waiting."</p>

<p>Known for her unwavering loyalty to Trump's agenda during his first term, Ms Rollins has played a major role in shaping policies that align with the "America First" vision.</p>

<p><strong>Here are some facts about Brooke Rollins:</strong></p>

<ul>
	<li aria-level="1"><a href="http://https://americafirstpolicy.com/team/brookerollins " rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">Brooke Rollins</a> is from Glen Rose, Texas, now living in Fort Worth, Texas, with her husband, Mark, and their four children.</li>
	<li aria-level="1">She graduated with honours in Agricultural Development from the Texas A&amp;M University. The 52-year-old made history as the first female student body president at University. She earned her Juris Doctor with honours from the University of Texas School of Law.</li>
	<li aria-level="1">Ms Rollins worked as a litigation attorney in Dallas and clerked for a federal judge in Texas.</li>
	<li aria-level="1">She was the Director of the Domestic Policy Council and Assistant to the President for Strategic Initiatives in the Trump White House. She also held the role of Director of the Office of American Innovation during Trump's first term.</li>
	<li aria-level="1">Brooke Rollins is the CEO and President of the America First Policy Institute, a think tank championing Trump's agenda.</li>
	<li aria-level="1">She is the Policy Director for Texas Governor Rick Perry. She also led the Texas Public Policy Foundation (TPPF) for 15 years, transforming it into a nationally influential think tank.</li>
</ul>

<p>If confirmed by the Senate, Brooke Rollins will lead a sprawling US Department of Agriculture, a vital agency with far-reaching impacts on American citizens and businesses.</p>

<p>The department employs around 100,000 people and manages diverse areas, including farm programs, research and trade, food safety, animal and plant health, and forest management. It also administers the Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Programme (SNAP), supporting over 40 million recipients nationwide.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ft56l5v_brooke-rollins-_625x300_24_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Brooke Rollins is known for her loyalty to Trump's agenda during his first term]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-neil-degrasse-tyson-clash-again-over-mars-colonisation-it-doesnt-happen-7092491]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk, Neil deGrasse Tyson Clash Again Over Mars Colonisation]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-neil-degrasse-tyson-clash-again-over-mars-colonisation-it-doesnt-happen-7092491]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 24 Nov 2024 09:50:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[After the video clip of Neil deGrasse Tyson's monologue went viral, the Tesla CEO took to X and issued a response]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Elon Musk and Neil de Grasse Tyson have clashed once again with the latter claiming that the billionaire will not be able to fund his quest to set up civilisation on Mars. Speaking to American talk show host, Bill Maher, Mr Tyson commented on the feasibility of travelling to Mars, adding that the investors would never agree to the idea as it had no return on investment. For a long time, Mr Musk has posited that Mars colonisation is the only way for humanity to survive while Mr Tyson wants humankind to focus on immediate challenges present on Earth instead of expending resources in outer space.</p>

<p>During the interview, Mr Maher asked Mr Tyson how long would it take for the SpaceX boss to "realistically send humans to Mars".</p>

<p>"How badly would we have to rat f**k Earth before it's worse than a place that's 200 below zero with no air and no water with six months to reach it?!" quizzed Mr Maher.</p>

<p>To which, Mr Tyson, who hosted the TV series Cosmos, developed by Carl Sagan, replied: "My read of the history of space exploration is such that we do big, expensive things only when it's geopolitically expedient, such as we feel threatened by an enemy."</p>

<p>"And so for him to just say, let's go to Mars because it's the next thing to do. What is that venture capitalist meeting look like? 'So, Elon, what do you want to do?' 'I want to go to Mars?' 'How much will it cost?' '$1 trillion.' 'Is it safe?' 'No. People will probably die.' 'What's the return on the investment?' 'Nothing.' That's a five-minute meeting. And it doesn't happen," he added.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Wow, they really don't get it.<br />
<br />
Mars is critical to the long-term survival of consciousness.<br />
<br />
Also, I'm not going to ask any venture capitalists for money. I realize that it makes no sense as an investment. That's why I'm gathering resources. <a href="https://t.co/XVCpHKlusD">https://t.co/XVCpHKlusD</a></p>
— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1860322925783445956?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 23, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jensen-huang-elon-musk-richest-ever-but-this-asian-billionaire-was-2024s-top-earner-7084906"><strong>Also Read | Elon Musk Richest Ever, But This Asian Billionaire Was 2024's Top Earner</strong></a></p>

<h3><strong>Musk responds</strong></h3>

<p>After the video of Mr Tyson's monologue went viral, the Tesla CEO took to X (formerly Twitter) and issued a response.</p>

<p>"Wow, they really don't get it. Mars is critical to the long-term survival of consciousness. Also, I'm not going to ask any venture capitalists for money. I realise that it makes no sense as an investment. That's why I'm gathering resources," wrote Mr Musk, adding the 'slapping forehead in disbelief' emoji.</p>

<p>In a separate post, Mr Musk added even if he failed at creating a Mars colony that can grow without continuous support from Earth, "the absurdly ambitious nature of the goal nonetheless results in the creation of alien-level technology that is crushingly better than competitors who merely aim for Earth orbit".</p>

<p>Mr Musk's SpaceX is hoping to use the Starship's reusability factor to build a colony on Mars. In September, the company announced that it would be launching its first uncrewed mission to Mars in the next two years.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/no4ki4d8_neil-degrasse-tyson-elon-musk_625x300_24_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Elon Musk (R) and Neil deGrasse Tyson (L).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musks-praise-for-indian-elections-with-a-potshot-at-california-7092386]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk Praises India's Vote Counting Process, Takes Jibe At US Elections]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musks-praise-for-indian-elections-with-a-potshot-at-california-7092386]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 24 Nov 2024 09:29:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Elon Musk on Sunday praised the efficiency of India's vote-counting process and slammed the prolonged delays in parts of the United States, particularly California.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Elon Musk on Sunday praised the efficiency of India's vote-counting process and slammed the prolonged delays in parts of the United States, particularly California. In a post on X (formerly Twitter), Mr Musk applauded India's ability to count 640 million votes in just one day after the 2024 Lok Sabha elections, contrasting it with the sluggish vote tallying in California for the US presidential elections, which remains unfinished nearly 20 days after voting began on November 5.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Responding to a post that carried a screenshot of a media report titled 'How India counted 640 million votes in a day', the Tesla and SpaceX chief wrote, "India counted 640 million votes in 1 day. California is still counting votes"</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">India counted 640 million votes in 1 day.<br />
<br />
California is still counting votes ?‍♂️ <a href="https://t.co/ai8JmWxas6">https://t.co/ai8JmWxas6</a></p>
— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1860476995370455296?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 24, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>India conducted its Lok Sabha elections earlier this year, involving over 900 million eligible voters. Of these, a record-breaking 642 million people cast their votes. Despite the sheer scale, results were declared within a single day of counting.</p>

<h2><strong>How India Counted The Votes</strong></h2>

<p>Through Electronic Voting Machines (EVMs): Used since 2000, these devices ensure rapid and accurate counting.</p>

<p>Voter Verifiable Paper Audit Trail (VVPAT): Introduced to enhance transparency, the VVPAT system produces a paper slip for every vote cast, allowing for verification if needed.</p>

<p>Additionally, India's 543 parliamentary constituencies conduct counting simultaneously, overseen by the Election Commission of India (ECI). &nbsp;According to Supreme Court guidelines, postal ballots are processed and counted before EVM votes are unsealed. Under the supervision of Returning Officers, votes are tallied in centralised locations, and results are declared after each round.<br />
Even during state elections in Maharashtra and Jharkhand last week, India managed to count nearly 90 million votes in just a few hours. Maharashtra alone, with a population four times that of California, delivered results with remarkable efficiency.</p>

<h2><strong>Why The Delay In California&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p>Vote counting in the United States - particularly in states like California - often stretches over weeks. California, the most populous US state, reported delays in its November 5 presidential election, with more than 300,000 ballots still uncounted weeks later. This has drawn criticism not only from Mr Musk but also from voters and analysts who question the system's efficiency.</p>

<p>California conducts most of its elections by mail. Processing these ballots involves multiple steps like Signature verification on ballot envelopes, opening and sorting ballots before they can be tallied, etc.<br />
Unlike India's centralised oversight by the ECI, the US relies on state and local election offices, each with its own laws and resources.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/h7fd0c4_elon-musk-india-_625x300_24_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Vote counting in the United States - particularly in states like California - often stretches over weeks.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trudeau-attends-taylor-swift-concert-amid-montreal-violence-faces-backlash-7092220]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Anti-Israel Riots Rage In Montreal. Trudeau Spotted At Taylor Swift Concert]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trudeau-attends-taylor-swift-concert-amid-montreal-violence-faces-backlash-7092220]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 24 Nov 2024 08:42:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A video of Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau attending a Taylor Swift concert amid the ongoing violence in Montreal has drawn massive outrage on social media.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A video of Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau attending a Taylor Swift concert amid the ongoing violence in Montreal has drawn massive outrage on social media. Trudeau, who represents the Papineau district in Montreal, reportedly attended Taylor Swift's Eras Tour concert in Toronto with his family on Friday.</p>

<p>A viral video posted on X (formerly Twitter) shows the politician dancing and singing in the audience. In another video, he can be seen distributing friendship bracelets among the people.</p>

<p>However, this did not sit well with the internet users as the timing of him attending the concert coincided with the Montreal violence.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Trudeau at a Taylor Swift concert while Montreal burns," one user wrote.&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Trudeau at a Taylor Swift concert while Montreal burns.<a href="https://t.co/biFD1CEva0">pic.twitter.com/biFD1CEva0</a></p>
— Defiant World (@DefiantWorld) <a href="https://twitter.com/DefiantWorld/status/1860332476507521367?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 23, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Another said, "Justin Trudeau exchanging friendship bracelets at the Taylor Swift concert last night - AFTER we all learned Montreal was burning to the ground."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Justin Trudeau exchanging friendship bracelets at the Taylor Swift concert last night ? — AFTER we all learned Montreal was burning to the ground. <a href="https://t.co/vSMXSgFKs4">pic.twitter.com/vSMXSgFKs4</a></p>
— dahlia kurtz ✡︎ דליה קורץ (@DahliaKurtz) <a href="https://twitter.com/DahliaKurtz/status/1860347216566669575?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 23, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Some people also drew parallels between Trudeau and Roman Emperor Nero - who was known for his cruelty and debauchery.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"According to ancient tradition, the degenerate Emperor Nero got on stage and recited poetry while Rome burned. Here's Trudeau dancing at tonight's Taylor Swift concert after doubling the debt to $1.2 trillion and creating a housing crisis by opening Canada's borders," a user said.</p>

<p>However, the internet also seemed to be divided as some people came in support of Trudeau.</p>

<p>"Ya know, all it looks like, is that he's being a goofy Dad with his daughter, at a concert. Nothing nefarious going on here. And I don't even like the guy, not one bit," one user said.</p>

<p>Montreal's streets were engulfed in violent chaos as anti-Israeli protests escalated on November 22 - at a time when the &nbsp;North Atlantic Treaty Organisation (NATO) was holding its parliamentary assembly in the Quebec metropolis. The protesters were denouncing the trans-Atlantic alliance.</p>

<p>The tensions escalated when the demonstrators burned an effigy of Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu on the streets. The protestors, around 800 people, also set ablaze vehicles, smashed windows of nearby shops, and set off smoke bombs, reported news agency AFP. Following this, the police had to use chemical irritants and truncheons to disperse the crowd.</p>

<p>The Montreal police have reportedly arrested three people so far.&nbsp;</p>

<p>On Saturday, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/justin-trudeau-calls-his-officials-criminals-media-wrong-over-leaks-fake-report-on-indian-leadership-7087186">Justin Trudeau</a> condemned the violence in Montreal, saying that there "must be consequences and rioters should be held accountable".</p>

<p>"What we saw on the streets of Montreal last night was appalling. Acts of antisemitism, intimidation, and violence must be condemned wherever we see them. The RCMP are in communication with local police. There must be consequences, and rioters held accountable," he wrote in a post on X.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/isa03oh_justin-trudeau-taylor-swift_625x300_24_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A video shows Justin Trudeau dancing and singing in the audience.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/15-year-old-boy-may-be-tried-as-adult-for-fatally-stabbing-teen-cheerleader-in-us-7092189]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Boy, 15, May Be Tried As Adult For Fatally Stabbing Teen Cheerleader In US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/15-year-old-boy-may-be-tried-as-adult-for-fatally-stabbing-teen-cheerleader-in-us-7092189]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 24 Nov 2024 08:39:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The 15-year-old suspect was arrested shortly after the incident and charged with second-degree murder]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 13-year-old cheerleader, Savannah Copeland, was allegedly stabbed to death by a 15-year-old boy using a pocket knife and left near a dirt road. Prosecutors are seeking to have the suspect tried as an adult, according to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.foxnews.com/us/teen-suspect-arrested-after-cheerleader-found-dead-woods" rel="noindex,nofollow"><em>Fox News</em></a>.</p>

<p>The incident reportedly occurred around midnight on October 22, when Savannah met the 15-year-old. He allegedly attacked her before fleeing the scene, as detailed in a petition released by Knox County court on October 24. The nature of their relationship or how they knew each other remains unclear.</p>

<p>Michael Copeland, Savannah's father, told <em>8WVLT </em>that his daughter had been missing in Powell for several hours. Using her cellphone information, he tracked her location and discovered her body.</p>

<p>The 15-year-old suspect was arrested shortly after the incident and charged with second-degree murder, according to the Knox County Sheriff's Office. Despite the suspect's age, a judge allowed his name to be released two days later and scheduled a hearing for January 14 to determine if he will face trial as an adult, as reported by 6 News. Fox News Digital has chosen not to identify the suspect until a decision is made.</p>

<p>Savannah's name was not included in the sheriff's office's statement but was confirmed by her family through a GoFundMe page, an online obituary, her cheerleading team, and various news outlets.</p>

<p>"I think it was a lack of compassion and a lack of empathy that drove the hand that took my daughter's life," the victim's father told <em>8 WVLT.</em>&nbsp;</p>

<p>Copeland, a cheerleader with Powell Mac Cheerleading, was a talented student who also excelled in karate and gymnastics, her family wrote in her obituary. Her father told 8WVLT the teen had "spunkiness, eagerness and ... a go-getter attitude."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/pf37rpj8_savannah-copeland_625x300_24_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The incident reportedly occurred around midnight on October 22]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ndtv-exclusive-un-official-calls-for-survivor-centred-anti-violence-laws-7092153]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[NDTV Exclusive: UN Official Calls For Survivor-Centred Anti-Violence Laws]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ndtv-exclusive-un-official-calls-for-survivor-centred-anti-violence-laws-7092153]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 24 Nov 2024 08:29:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Melissa Alvarado, Regional Programme Manager for Ending Violence Against Women at UN Women, emphasised the importance of a survivor-centric approach when drafting laws and regulations to combat violence against women.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In an exclusive interview with NDTV, Melissa Alvarado, Regional Programme Manager for Ending Violence Against Women at UN Women, emphasised the importance of a survivor-centric approach when drafting laws and regulations to combat violence against women. Ms Alvarado stressed that the voices of survivors must be central in the formulation of policies aimed at curbing gender-based violence.</p>

<p>"Survivors may not be experts on the broader legalities of violence, but they are experts in their own experiences," Ms Alvarado said. "We must listen carefully to them and shape our laws and practices based on their lived experiences."</p>

<p>She also highlighted the need for a robust feedback loop to evaluate the effectiveness of laws and policies. According to Ms Alvarado, survivor input is crucial to refining and improving legal frameworks that are meant to protect women from violence.</p>

<h2><strong>Identifying At-Risk Women</strong></h2>

<p>Ms Alvarado underscored the importance of identifying women at risk before they become victims of violence. She noted that many victims fail to reach out to existing support systems, such as hotlines and healthcare centres, either due to fear, stigma, or lack of awareness. "Laws and regulations should be designed not only for those who report violence but also for those who don't," she said, stressing the need for preventative measures that reach vulnerable women before situations escalate.</p>

<p>A key focus, Ms Alvarado explained, should be preventing severe forms of violence, including domestic abuse that leads to murder or rape. Early identification of high-risk situations, she argued, is essential for preventing these tragic outcomes.</p>

<p>There are 1,583 legislative measures across 193 countries to address violence against women, UN data says.</p>

<h2><strong>The Impact Of Conflict And Crises On Women</strong></h2>

<p>Ms Alvarado also discussed the heightened vulnerability of women in conflict zones or during crises, noting that they are often disproportionately affected by violence in such circumstances. She emphasized the importance of integrating women's voices into crisis planning and response efforts, as well as building social protection systems that specifically address the risks women face in times of crisis.</p>

<p>"We need to ensure that, as we prepare for the next climate disaster or other emergencies, we are including women, women's rights organizations, disability rights groups, and LGBTQ+ activists in crisis preparedness and planning," Ms Alvarado said.</p>

<p>UN Women data shows that 70% of women in conflict, war, and humanitarian crisis, experience gender-based violence.</p>

<h2><strong>Addressing Workplace Violence</strong></h2>

<p>Ms Alvarado also called on businesses to adopt a "zero-tolerance" policy for workplace violence against women. Companies, she argued, have a crucial role to play in creating safe environments for female employees and customers alike.</p>

<p>In addition to enforcing zero-tolerance policies, Ms Alvarado suggested that companies provide training for employees to recognise signs of violence and extend support to customers who may be experiencing abuse.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/h4u4teeo_melissa-alvarado-_625x300_24_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[There are 1,583 legislative measures across 193 countries to address violence against women.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mcdonalds-launches-new-mcvalue-menu-to-bring-back-customers-heres-what-it-includes-7092105]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[McDonald's Launches Affordable 'McValue' Menu To Bring Back Customers]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mcdonalds-launches-new-mcvalue-menu-to-bring-back-customers-heres-what-it-includes-7092105]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 24 Nov 2024 08:11:00 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[McDonald's global sales at outlets open at least a year fell by 1.5 per cent between July and September -- the biggest decline in four years.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>McDonald's has announced it will be launching a new "McValue" menu, starting next year, to provide more savings to consumers. The fast-food franchise giant is hoping the move would bring more customers as soaring inflation pushes them to cheaper dining alternatives. The McValue platform will be available in restaurants in the US, beginning January 7 and will include McDonald's $5 meal deal, which the company launched in June, in addition to a new 'Buy One, Add One at $1' feature.</p>

<p>"When it comes to value, we know there's no one-size-fits-all. We've worked closely with our franchisees to create a new platform that will let our customers define value on their own terms," said Joe Erlinger, president of McDonald's USA.</p>

<p>"From deals on their personal go-to order to universal favorites like the $5 Meal Deal, we're excited to give fans more ways to save every time they visit one of our restaurants," added Mr Erlinger.</p>

<h3><strong>What does the Buy One, Add One for $1 menu include?</strong></h3>

<p>Customers will be allowed to customise their own deals, mixing and matching their favourite items. On buying a full-priced menu item from the McValue menu, they can add another item of their choice for $1.</p>

<p>The McValue breakfast menu includes:</p>

<ul>
	<li>Sausage McMuffin</li>
	<li>Sausage Biscuit</li>
	<li>Sausage Burrito</li>
	<li>Hash Browns</li>
</ul>

<p>Meanwhile, the McValue lunch/dinner menu includes:</p>

<ul>
	<li>6-pc. Chicken McNuggets</li>
	<li>Double Cheeseburger</li>
	<li>McChicken</li>
	<li>Small Fries</li>
</ul>

<p>Cory Watson, McDonald's Owner/Operator and National Value Chair for 2025, said the company knew about the challenges and was willing to listen to its customers.</p>

<p>"No matter the city or the state, they're telling us how important it is for them to find their favourite meals at affordable prices. And we couldn't agree more. That's why we're committed to continuing to serve up great local deals," said Mr Watson.</p>

<p>As for the launch of the McValue menu in the international market, no update has been provided by the company.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/man-60-shot-dead-by-77-year-old-in-paris-mcdonalds-7082021" rel="noindex, nofollow"><strong>Also Read | Man, 60, Shot Dead By 77-Year-Old In Paris McDonald's</strong></a></p>

<h3><strong>Slowing growth</strong></h3>

<p>In October, McDonald's posted another big drop in sales globally as demand continued to slow. McDonald's global sales at outlets open at least a year fell by 1.5 per cent between July and September -- the biggest decline in four years.</p>

<p>The international markets were down by 2.1 per cent, driven by France and the UK while net profits fell by three per cent to $2.3 billion. Weaker consumer spending in China, and the continued impact of the conflicts in the Middle East, led to a 3.5 per cent drop in sales in its licensed business, in which restaurants are run by local partners.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/6a0q9h7g_mcdonalds-pexels_625x300_13_April_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[McDonald's has been undergoing a slow growth period.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-cops-injured-in-shooting-near-israeli-embassy-in-jordan-gunman-shot-dead-7092067]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[3 Cops Injured In Shooting Near Israeli Embassy In Jordan, Gunman Shot Dead]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-cops-injured-in-shooting-near-israeli-embassy-in-jordan-gunman-shot-dead-7092067]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 24 Nov 2024 08:03:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A gunman was dead and three policemen injured after a shooting near the Israeli embassy in neighbouring Jordan, a security source and state media said on Sunday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A gunman was dead and three policemen injured after a shooting near the Israeli embassy in neighbouring Jordan, a security source and state media said on Sunday.</p>

<p>Police shot a gunman who had fired at a police patrol in the Rabiah neighbourhood of Amman, state news agency Petra reported, citing public security, adding investigations were ongoing.</p>

<p>Jordanian police had earlier cordoned off an area near the heavily policed embassy after gunshots were heard, witnesses said. Two witnesses said police and ambulances rushed to the Rabiah neighbourhood, where the embassy is located.</p>

<p>The area is a flashpoint for frequent demonstrations against Israel. The kingdom has witnessed some of the biggest peaceful rallies across the region as anti-Israel sentiment runs high over the war in Gaza.</p>

<p>Police had called on residents to stay in their homes as security personnel searched for the culprits, a security source said.</p>

<p>Many of Jordan's 12 million citizens are of Palestinian origin, they or their parents having been expelled or fled to Jordan in the fighting that accompanied the creation of Israel in 1948. Many have family ties on the Israeli side of the Jordan River.</p>

<p>Jordan's peace treaty with Israel is unpopular among many citizens who see normalisation of relations as betraying the rights of their Palestinian compatriots.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/iubsfbo8_police-generic_625x300_22_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Representational Image]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/katy-perry-wins-trademark-case-against-australian-designer-katie-perry-7092039]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Katy Perry Wins Trademark Case Against Australian Designer Katie Perry]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/katy-perry-wins-trademark-case-against-australian-designer-katie-perry-7092039]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 24 Nov 2024 07:59:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The judges determined that Perry had used her name as a trademark for five years before Taylor began her clothing business.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pop star Katy Perry won an appeal on Friday in a trademark case brought by Australian fashion designer Katie Taylor, who markets her clothing under the name Katie Perry,&nbsp;<em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/entertainment/music/2024/11/22/katy-perry-trademark-lawsuit-win/76493815007/" rel="noindex,nofollow">USA Today</a> </em>reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>A panel of three judges overturned a 2023 ruling that had sided with Taylor, allowing Katy Perry (born Katheryn Hudson) to continue using her stage name to sell merchandise in Australia despite Taylor's trademark claim.</p>

<p>The judges determined that Perry had used her name as a trademark for five years before Taylor began her clothing business and already had an "international reputation in music and entertainment, if not more broadly." As a result, Perry was deemed entitled to use her stage name in Australia.</p>

<p>The court also cancelled Taylor's trademark registration, according to USA Today.</p>

<p>"This case is unfortunate in that two enterprising women in different countries independently adopted their name as a trademark, unaware of each other's existence," the judges wrote in their decision. They also noted that Taylor had, at times, appeared to associate herself with Perry, raising the risk of consumer confusion or deception.</p>

<p>However, little confusion resulted, and the court found. Since Perry offered both women rights to the trademarked name in 2009, which Taylor rejected, the judges ruled that Taylor's own trademark license would need to be cancelled. "In that sense, (Taylor) has brought this result on herself. Unfortunately, it is no longer possible to return to the time of peaceful co-existence," they wrote.</p>

<p>Disappointed with the decision, Taylor told<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2024/nov/22/katy-perry-appeal-legal-case-sydney-fashion-label-katie-perry" rel="noindex,nofollow"><em> The Guardian</em></a>, "This case proves a trademark isn't worth the paper it's printed on."</p>

<p>She went on to say: "My fashion label has been a dream of mine since I was 11 years old and now that dream that I have worked so hard for, since 2006, has been taken away."</p>

<p>"I have lost everything, including my trademark. As you can imagine I'm devastated," she told <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/11/21/entertainment/katy-perry-wins-trademark-battle-with-australian-designer-over-name/" rel="noindex,nofollow">The New York Post.</a></em></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/brdsbe6o_katy-perry_625x300_24_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The court also cancelled Taylor's trademark registration]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/salary-of-prisoners-in-uk-more-than-jail-guards-and-teachers-report-7091910]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Salary Of Prisoners In UK More Than Jail Guards And Teachers: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/salary-of-prisoners-in-uk-more-than-jail-guards-and-teachers-report-7091910]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 24 Nov 2024 07:15:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The highest-paid inmate in the UK received a net pay of $46,005 last year, which means their gross salary was about $57,640.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prisoners in British jails are earning more than the officers that guard them as well as secondary teachers, biochemists, psychotherapists and midwives, according to a report in <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/2024/11/23/britain-best-paid-inmates-earn-more-than-prison-officers/" rel="nofollow, noindex"><em>The Telegraph</em></a>. Inmates in some of the low-security, open prisons are allowed to venture outside for work, as long as they return to the jail confines by the end of the day. The move is part of a concerted effort to rehabilitate the prisoners and prepare them for a life back in society. However, the pay difference between the inmates and those belonging to the civil society has raised questions regarding income disparity in the UK.</p>

<p>The highest-paid inmate in the UK received a net pay of $46,005 (Rs 38,84,491) last year, which means their gross salary was about $57,640 (Rs 48,66,907). The data by the Home Office showed that nine other inmates had net earnings of more than $28,694 (Rs 24,22,814), which means the average working prisoner was being paid just under $25,061 (Rs 21,16,057) per year. Meanwhile, the average salary of a prison guard is $35,085 (Rs 29,62,446), while fresh recruits are paid approximately $30,073 (Rs 25,39,252) per year.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-may-soon-bring-assisted-dying-law-lawmaker-explains-its-safeguards-7004474" rel="noindex, nofollow"><strong>Also read | UK May Soon Bring 'Assisted Dying' Law. Lawmaker Explains Its Safeguards</strong></a></p>

<p>As per the Ministry of Justice, there were two other high-paid prisoners who netted more than $37,591 (Rs 31,74,044) after deductions last year and another seven who put between $28,694 (Rs 24,22,814) and $37,591 (Rs 31,74,044) into private bank accounts. Although the prisoners do a variety of jobs, the high-earning individuals engage in one of the most lucrative jobs -- driving lorries.</p>

<p>“Some offenders, towards the end of their sentence, receive a release on temporary licence. This sees them spend some of their day in the community, often working, before returning to prison," a prison service spokesman was quoted as saying by the publication.</p>

<p>“If they are working, their earnings are subject to tax, court fines and a levy of up to 40 per cent, which funds a charity for victims," they added.</p>

<p>Despite the deductions, the prisoners were ahead of midwives who had an average take-home pay of $45,889 (Rs 38,74,696) while biochemists ($45,844, Rs 38,74,274 ), psychotherapists ($45,864, Rs 38,72,585) and chartered surveyors ($43,908, Rs 37,07,428) also netted less than them.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/4oggmfjg_prison_625x300_24_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Prisoners in the UK are earning significantly more than officers guarding them.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jensen-huang-elon-musk-richest-ever-but-this-asian-billionaire-was-2024s-top-earner-7084906]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk Richest Ever, But This Asian Billionaire Was 2024's Top Earner]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jensen-huang-elon-musk-richest-ever-but-this-asian-billionaire-was-2024s-top-earner-7084906]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 24 Nov 2024 07:02:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Tesla CEO Elon Musk might be the richest person in history, but he was way behind Nvidia CEO Jensen Huang on the 2024 list of top earners.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Tesla CEO Elon Musk might be the richest person in history, but he was way behind Nvidia CEO Jensen Huang on the 2024 list of top earners. Mr Huang's annual earnings skyrocketed from $21.1 billion in 2023 to $77 billion in 2024, according to <a href="https://www.forbes.com/profile/jensen-huang/?listuri=rtb " rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">Forbes</a>. This was nearly four-fold of Mr Musk's <a href="http://https://www.forbes.com/profile/elon-musk/?list=rtb/ " rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">$15 billion increase</a> in annual earnings from $180 billion in 2023 to $195 billion in 2024.</p>

<p>The massive boost took Mr Huang's net worth to $123.8 billion, placing him ninth on the Forbes Real-Time Billionaire List.</p>

<p>Tesla's soaring shares pushed Mr Musk's net worth to $334.3 billion this year.</p>

<h3><strong>Who is&nbsp;Jensen Huang</strong></h3>

<p>Born in Taiwan and raised in the US from the age of nine, Mr Huang's academic journey led him from Oregon State University to Stanford University, where he specialised in electrical engineering. As co-founder and CEO of Nvidia since 1993, Mr Huang has been the visionary behind the company's rise as a leader in AI technology.</p>

<p>Nvidia's shares hit a record high this year, contributing significantly to Huang's fortune. His 3.5 per cent equity stake in the $3.5 trillion company now accounts for nearly all of his wealth, valued at $122.2 billion. Even after selling $713 million worth of Nvidia stock earlier this year, Mr Huang remains the company's largest shareholder.</p>

<p>Nvidia holds an 80 per cent market share in AI accelerators, crucial for cutting-edge AI applications used by tech giants like Amazon, Google, Meta, Microsoft, and even Tesla. The company's graphics processing units (GPUs), initially popular in gaming, have become essential for AI models like OpenAI's ChatGPT. Demand for Nvidia's products is so intense that Mr Huang described it as “insane,” with customers reportedly becoming “really emotional” over availability, <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/dereksaul/2024/10/21/nvidia-ceo-jensen-huang-vaults-into-worlds-10-richest-for-first-time-ever/" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">Forbes</a> reported.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/0v3tkg5g_jensen-huang_625x300_24_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Jensen Huang has been the visionary behind Nvidia's rise as a leader in AI technology.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-picks-brooke-rollins-his-loyalist-as-us-agriculture-secretary-7091849]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Picks Brooke Rollins, His Loyalist, As US Agriculture Secretary]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-picks-brooke-rollins-his-loyalist-as-us-agriculture-secretary-7091849]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 24 Nov 2024 06:53:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump on Saturday announced his pick for agriculture secretary -- the final top post in his incoming cabinet -- as policy advocate Brooke Rollins, a loyalist from his first term.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump on Saturday announced his pick for agriculture secretary -- the final top post in his incoming cabinet -- as policy advocate Brooke Rollins, a loyalist from his first term.</p>

<p>Ahead of his return to power in January, the Republican has moved swiftly to name the inner circle who will lead key government agencies, with his picks ranging from TV hosts to US senators and governors.</p>

<p>Rollins, 52, is the CEO of the America First Policy Institute, a non-profit organization dedicated to promoting Trump's agenda, often described as his "White House in waiting."</p>

<p>Several other Trump nominees have close ties to the group.</p>

<p>With his agriculture pick Saturday, Trump has now chosen someone for all of the top cabinet posts.</p>

<p>Some lower-level positions have yet to be announced, such as the heads of the Small Business Administration and Office of Science and Technology.</p>

<p>Rollins, if confirmed by the Senate, would command a sprawling agency that has major implications for American citizens and corporations.</p>

<p>It employs some 100,000 people and oversees farm programs, research and trade, food safety, animal and plant health, and the nation's forests.</p>

<p>It also manages the nation's food assistance program, which has over 40 million recipients.</p>

<p>Trump hailed his nominee's "commitment to support the American Farmer, defense of American Food Self-Sufficiency, and the restoration of Agriculture-dependent American Small Towns."</p>

<p>Rollins temporarily led Trump's Domestic Policy Council during his first term.</p>

<p>As a more traditional conservative, there is potential for her to butt heads with Robert F. Kennedy Jr., Trump's pick for health secretary who has been a vocal opponent to the corporate agriculture industry.</p>

<p>He has pledged to improve American nutrition by cracking down on ultra-processed foods and toxic chemicals.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, concern has mounted over the Trump team's apparent refusal to sign key transition agreements as required by US law.</p>

<p>Senator Elizabeth Warren wrote a letter Thursday to the General Services Administration seeking information on the status of the agreements.</p>

<p>"President-elect Trump is undermining his administration's ability to manage urgent national security threats, health and safety threats, and serious conflicts of interest starting on day one of his presidency," wrote Warren.&nbsp;</p>

<p>She noted in particular that failure to sign the documents means "the FBI cannot begin critical background checks of candidates for high-level national security roles," including those Trump has picked for his cabinet and other top positions.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/unts6p78_brooke-rollins_625x300_24_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Rollins temporarily led Trump's Domestic Policy Council during his first term.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-s-sinkholes-popular-tourist-destination-but-at-what-environmental-cost-7085411]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[In China, These Giant Sinkholes Are Tourist Spots. But Experts Flag Risks]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-s-sinkholes-popular-tourist-destination-but-at-what-environmental-cost-7085411]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 24 Nov 2024 06:47:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[China's massive sinkholes, particularly those in Guangxi province, have gained massive popularity among tourists, drawing visitors eager to explore their ancient ecosystems.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>China's massive sinkholes, particularly those in Guangxi province, have gained massive popularity among tourists, drawing visitors eager to explore their ancient ecosystems. But while these natural wonders offer a unique glimpse into Earth's past, experts warn the influx of tourists may threaten the fragile habitats hidden within these sinkholes.</p>

<p>Ranging from 100 to 300 metres in depth, these sinkholes — locally known as “tiankeng” or “heavenly pits” — have long been shrouded in myth. Ancient local beliefs held that the mist rising from the depths was caused by demons and ghosts, adding an air of mystery to the already dangerous terrain. But now, these sites have become increasingly accessible, with guided tours and even extreme sports activities like abseiling attracting tourists from across the country.</p>

<p>Rui, a tourist from Shanghai, expressed her excitement at exploring one such sinkhole. She told <a href="http://https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c8697gqwyx6o" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">BBC</a>, “I've never done this kind of thing before. It's very cool. It will be the first time but not the last time.”</p>

<p>Fei Ge, a tour guide in his 50s, who, according to the BBC report, was one of the first explorers of these sinkholes, recalls the legends surrounding the pits. “We thought that if humans went into the sinkholes, demons would bring strong winds and heavy rain. We thought ghosts brought the mist and fog,” he said.</p>

<p>His curiosity led him to become one of the earliest explorers of these sites, eventually introducing scientists to the area. Their discoveries were groundbreaking, having identified rare and previously unknown species of plants and animals, including orchids, white cave fish and several types of spiders and snails.</p>

<p>China is home to around two-thirds of the world's more than 300 sinkholes, and Guangxi alone has over 30. These sinkholes are formed in limestone-rich regions where underground rivers gradually erode the rock, creating vast caverns that eventually collapse, leaving deep holes behind. These pits are isolated from the outside world, allowing ecosystems to thrive, largely untouched by human activity.</p>

<p>Dr Lina Shen, a sinkhole researcher, highlighted the importance of preserving these unique habitats. “We should better protect such habitats. Sinkholes are paradises for many rare and endangered plant species.” Dr Shen suggested that measures such as “hot air balloons, drones for aerial photography, and appropriate pathways for observation from a distance” could help minimise human impact on these delicate sites while allowing people to “closely yet remotely view sinkholes.”</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/i8v7f4vo_china-sinkholes-_625x300_23_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[China is home to around two-thirds of the world's more than 300 sinkholes.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>