<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Sep 2024 08:03:33 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/apollo-quiboloy-how-filipino-pastor-on-fbis-most-wanted-list-was-arrested-by-2-000-cops-6522145]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How Filipino Pastor On FBI's Most Wanted List Was Arrested By 2,000 Cops]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/apollo-quiboloy-how-filipino-pastor-on-fbis-most-wanted-list-was-arrested-by-2-000-cops-6522145]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Sep 2024 07:47:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Followers of Apollo Quiboloy, who was wanted on charges of child and sexual abuse, had blocked the gate of the compound to prevent shield-carrying police from arresting him.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Influential pastor Apollo Quiboloy, the self-proclaimed "owner of the universe" and "appointed son of god" who was wanted in the US for child sex trafficking, was arrested in the Philippines on Sunday.</p>

<p>Over 2,000 police were deployed for more than two weeks to search a 74-acre compound in the southern city of Davao owned by his church - the Kingdom of Jesus Christ (KOJC) - on suspicion that he was hiding there in a bunker.</p>

<p>Quiboloy's followers had blocked the gate of the compound to prevent shield-carrying police from enforcing a court order to arrest him. Police also used helicopters to circle over a cathedral, a college, and a stadium with 75,000 seats.</p>

<p>Days before Quiboloy's arrest, the police reportedly recorded the warmth and heartbeat of a human body, deep in the earth, using thermal imaging and radar technology.</p>

<h3><strong>Apollo Quiboloy Is Accused Of Sex Crimes</strong></h3>

<p>Apollo Quiboloy, a longtime friend of former Philippines president Rodrigo Duterte, is wanted on charges of child and sexual abuse and related allegations of human trafficking. He also figures on the FBI's "most wanted" list on charges of sex trafficking.</p>

<p>Quiboloy was charged by the US Justice Department in 2021 with sex trafficking of girls and women between the ages of 12 and 25 to work as personal assistants, or "pastorals", who were allegedly required to have sex with him.</p>

<p>He is also sought by authorities for bulk cash smuggling and a scheme that brought church members to the United States using fraudulently obtained visas. They were then forced to solicit donations for a bogus charity, raising funds that were instead used to finance church operations and the lavish lifestyles of its leaders.</p>

<p>The evangelist preacher, who is followed by millions of people in the Philippines, has denied wrongdoing.</p>

<p><em>(With agency inputs)</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/q18i4ef8_apollo-quiboloy_625x300_09_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Apollo Quiboloy is followed by millions of people in the Philippines]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/rahul-gandhi-in-us-says-india-has-to-think-about-the-act-of-production-6521998]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["India Has To Think About The Act Of Production": Rahul Gandhi In US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/rahul-gandhi-in-us-says-india-has-to-think-about-the-act-of-production-6521998]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Sep 2024 07:12:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India, the US and other countries in the West are facing the problem of unemployment while China isn't as it is dominating global production, Leader of Opposition in the Lok Sabha Rahul Gandhi said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India, the US and other countries in the West are facing the problem of unemployment while China isn't as it is dominating global production, Leader of Opposition in the Lok Sabha Rahul Gandhi said, underscoring the need to focus on manufacturing in India.</p>

<p>During an interaction with students at the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/rahul-gandhi-on-ai-during-interaction-in-texas-if-youre-positioned-properly-its-an-opportunit-6521837">University of Texas in Dallas</a> on Sunday, Mr Gandhi said there is no shortage of skills in India and the country could compete with China if it starts aligning itself for production.</p>

<p>He also stressed the need to encourage vocational training to bridge the gap between the business system and the education system and flagged the "ideological capture" of the latter.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/rahul-gandhi-on-ai-during-interaction-in-texas-if-youre-positioned-properly-its-an-opportunit-6521837"><strong>Read: "If You're Positioned Properly, It's An Opportunity": Rahul Gandhi On AI</strong></a></p>

<p>Mr Gandhi is on a four-day unofficial trip to the US during which he will interact with the members of the Indian diaspora and youths with stops in Dallas, Texas and Washington DC. He also plans to meet lawmakers and senior officials of the US government during his visit to Washington DC beginning Monday.</p>

<p>He arrived in Dallas on Saturday night and was welcomed by dozens of members of the Indian-American community led by senior Congress leader Sam Pitroda and president of Indian National Overseas Congress, USA, Mohinder Gilzian.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bharat-jodo-yatra-introduced-the-idea-of-love-in-politics-rahul-gandhi-in-us-6521554"><strong>Read: "Bharat Jodo Yatra Introduced The Idea Of Love In Politics": Rahul Gandhi In US</strong></a></p>

<p>"The West has an employment problem. India has an employment problem... But many countries in the world don't have an employment problem. China certainly doesn't have an employment problem. Vietnam doesn't have an employment problem," Mr Gandhi said.</p>

<p>"If you look at the United States in the 1940s, 50s and 60s, they were the centre of global production. Anything that was made, (be it) cars, washing machines (or) TVs, all was made in the United States. Production moved from the United States. It went to Korea and it went to Japan. Eventually, it went to China. If you look today, China is dominating global production," he said.</p>

<p>The West, America, Europe and India have "given up on the idea of production" and they've handed it to China.</p>

<p>"The act of production creates jobs. What we do, what the Americans do, what the West does, is we organise consumption... India has to think about the act of production and organising production..."</p>

<p>"It's not acceptable that India simply says, okay, manufacturing, what you call manufacturing or production is going to be the preserve of the Chinese. It's going to be the preserve of the Vietnamese. It's going to be the preserve of Bangladesh," Mr Gandhi said.</p>

<p>He underlined the need to encourage manufacturing.</p>

<p>"Until we do that, we will face high levels of unemployment. And frankly, it's not sustainable. So, you're going to see that if we carry on down this path of forgetting about manufacturing, you're going to see massive social problems coming in India and in the United States and Europe. The polarisation of our politics is because of this..." he added.</p>

<p>According to the leader of opposition, there is no shortage of skills in India.</p>

<p>"Many people say that India has a problem with skills. I don't think India has a problem with skills. I think... India does not have respect for people who possess skills," he said.</p>

<p>Mr Gandhi said there is a need to link the education system with the business system through vocational training.</p>

<p>"Bridging that gap or linking these two systems, skills and education, through vocational training is fundamental. I think currently the huge problem with the education system is the ideological capture, where ideology is being fed through it...," he said.</p>

<p>He said he is convinced that India can take on China if it starts aligning itself for production and starts respecting skills.</p>

<p>"I'm absolutely convinced of it. States like Tamil Nadu have already shown it. It's not that Indian states have not done it. Pune has shown it. Maharashtra has shown it. So, it is being done but it's not being done at the scale and with the coordination that it needs to be done," Mr Gandhi said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/g5tltqpg_rahul-gandhi-texas-ani_625x300_09_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Rahul Gandhi said India can take on China if it starts aligning itself for production.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/apple-ai-to-star-at-iphone-16-series-launch-all-eyes-on-glowtime-event-6522021]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Apple AI To Star At iPhone 16 Series Launch? All Eyes On "Glowtime" Event]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/apple-ai-to-star-at-iphone-16-series-launch-all-eyes-on-glowtime-event-6522021]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Sep 2024 07:07:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Apple has a lot riding on what would be the iPhone 16 and will hope that customers will be enticed to buy the latest models, attracted by new AI powers.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Apple is expected to release its latest line of iPhones on Monday that will feature generative AI capabilities as the tech behemoth looks to bolster sales of its iconic device. The company founded by Steve Jobs has disclosed little about what it plans to show off during a launch event, titled "Glowtime," at its headquarters in the Silicon Valley city of Cupertino.</p>

<p>It is the time of year, though, when Apple typically updates its iPhone lineup.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/ahead-of-apples-big-launch-first-indian-ad-for-apple-goes-viral-6516353">Apple</a> has a lot riding on what would be the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.gadgets360.com/mobiles/news/iphone-16-series-a18-apple-arm-v9-chipset-financial-times-report-6513432">iPhone 16</a> and will hope that customers will be enticed to buy the latest models, attracted by new AI powers.</p>

<p>With $39 billion in sales last quarter, the iPhone counts for roughly 60 percent of Apple's revenue, and remains the main entryway to the company's services, such as the App Store or Apple TV, which are becoming a growing part of its business.&nbsp;</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/all-about-iphone-16-series-set-to-launch-on-september-9-6489624">Apple</a> is only just coming out of a long sales slump as users increasingly stick with older models longer.</p>

<p>"The iPhone 16 will be one of the most significant iPhone introductions, not because of what's on the outside but because of what's inside -- namely, Apple Intelligence," said Forrester principal analyst Dipanjan Chatterjee.</p>

<p><strong>ALSO READ | <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/tim-cook-explains-why-apple-manufactures-iphones-in-china-elon-musk-reacts-6510900">Tim Cook Explains Why Apple Manufactures iPhones In China. Elon Musk Reacts</a></strong><br />
<br />
"Apple Intelligence" is a new suite of software features for all devices that was announced in June at the company's annual developers conference, where it also announced a partnership with ChatGPT-maker OpenAI.</p>

<p>In the short-term, these include AI-infused image editing, translation, and small, creative touches in messaging, but not more ambitious breakthroughs promised by other AI players, such as OpenAI or Google.</p>

<h3><strong>'Super-powered Siri'</strong></h3>

<p>Apple also said its digital assistant Siri will get an AI upgrade and now will appear as a pulsating light on the edge of a home screen.</p>

<p>"Siri will be a big part of the conversation," Creative Strategies analyst Carolina Milanesi said of Monday's event.</p>

<p>Launched more than 12 years ago, Siri has come to be seen as a dated feature, overtaken by a new generation of assistants such as GPT-4o, OpenAI's latest offering.</p>

<p>Apple watchers predict Apple will introduce iPhone 16 models with custom chips that can power these AI features, including the Siri upgrade.</p>

<p>By adding AI capabilities, Apple is looking to "shake that expectation" that iPhone launches are &nbsp;"just steady improvements in hardware and software," &nbsp;said Techsponential analyst Avi Greengart.</p>

<p>Longer term, Apple could dramatically change the iPhone experience with a "super-powered Siri" working across all the apps, Greengart said.</p>

<h3><strong>Pixel power</strong></h3>

<p>Apple's announcement closely follows Google, which last month unveiled AI-infused Pixel 9 smartphones, its challenge to the iPhone.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Pixels account for a tiny sliver of the global smartphone market dominated by Samsung and Apple, but Google argued its new line is a chance to answer what -- after all the hype -- AI can actually do for customers.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"There have been so many promises, so many 'coming soons,' and not enough real world helpfulness when it comes to AI - which is why today we're getting real," Google senior vice president of devices Rick Osterloh said at the company's campus in Mountain View, California.</p>

<p>Samsung has also showcased AI across a range of its consumer electronic products as it looks to extend its leadership in global smartphone sales.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/ao3hf2jg_apple_625x300_09_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Apple said its digital assistant Siri will get an AI upgrade (Representative)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/imran-khans-party-issued-warning-for-defying-rules-clashes-with-police-6521361]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Imran Khan's Party Issued Warning For Defying Rules, Clashes With Police]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/imran-khans-party-issued-warning-for-defying-rules-clashes-with-police-6521361]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Sep 2024 06:44:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Imran Khan's party, Pakistan Tehreek-E-Insaf, was issued a warning by the local administration to adhere to the rally's NOC guidelines, which mandated them to vacate the venue by 7pm, ARY News reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Imran Khan's party, Pakistan Tehreek-E-Insaf, was issued a warning by the local administration to adhere to the rally's NOC guidelines, which mandated them to vacate the venue by 7pm, ARY News reported.</p>

<p>In the Sangjani Rally on Sunday, the district magistrate issued several reminders to vacate the venue. But the rally exceeded the permit time, which made the police and the administration take action against them, as per ARY News report.</p>

<p>The participants arriving from a different route clashed with the police as the PTI workers threw stones, leading the police to respond with tear gas at Choongi No 26 area, ARY News stated.</p>

<p>A police spokesperson told ARY News that participants deviated from the designated rally route and attacked law enforcement. Several officers, including SSP Safe City Shoaib Khan, were injured in the incident as stone pelting continued.</p>

<p>Pakistan's interior Minister, Mohsin Naqvi, took notice of the situation and sought a report from Inspector General Islamabad and instructed to provide the best medical treatment of injured police officers. In a telephonic conversation with injured SSP Shoaib Khan, Mohsin Naqvi inquired about his health and emphasized the need for top-quality treatment for all injured officers involved in the incident.</p>

<p>PTI alleged that shots were fired at its members by the police during the rally in Islamabad on Sunday, which was being held demanding the release of party founder and incarcerated former Prime Minister Imran Khan.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Pakistan Tehreek-e-Insaf shared a video where they shared visuals from the rally and stated, "You can jail a man, but not his ideas," referring to PTI's incarcerated leader and founder Imran Khan.</p>

<p>The party's official account also shared pictures of protests at Pakistani Embassy in Norway demanding the release of Imran Khan.</p>

<p>The post stated, "Protest in front of the Pakistani Embassy in Oslo Norway to show solidarity with Imran Khan and his fight for justice and democracy."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/qchdb0u_pakistan-tehreekeinsaf-party-rally-islamabad-afp_625x300_09_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The participants arriving from a different route clashed with the police]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/rahul-gandhi-on-ai-during-interaction-in-texas-if-youre-positioned-properly-its-an-opportunit-6521837]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["If You're Positioned Properly, It's An Opportunity": Rahul Gandhi On AI]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/rahul-gandhi-on-ai-during-interaction-in-texas-if-youre-positioned-properly-its-an-opportunit-6521837]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Sep 2024 06:38:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Congress leader Rahul Gandhi said on Monday that the Artificial Intelligence (AI) can be a good opportunity if one is positioned properly.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Congress leader Rahul Gandhi said on Monday that the Artificial Intelligence (AI) can be a good opportunity if one is positioned properly.</p>

<p>The Leader of the Opposition in Lok Sabha, while interacting with the students at the University of Texas at Dallas, spoke about the fears that AI is going to take jobs away.</p>

<p>He said that every new technology takes away some jobs and generates new ones.</p>

<p>"Everytime you get a new technology, the argument is made that it's going to take jobs away. When computers first came [it was feared that] it's going to take jobs away. When calculators first came [it was feared that] it's going to take jobs away. ATMs came [it was feared that] it's going to take jobs away. What happens is- it does take jobs away from some people and then transfers them to other people. I'm not of the view that jobs will vanish, but different types of jobs will be created and different types of systems will benefit more or less," Mr Gandhi said.</p>

<p>Elaborating his view, the Congress leader said, "I think, for example, the IT industry in India is going to have a real big serious problem because of AI. But I don't really think that Bajaj- making scooters is going to have such a big problem. It's going to take away some jobs, it's going to add some jobs and if you're positioned properly, it's an opportunity and if you positioned badly, you're in trouble."</p>

<p>"I remember Mr [Atal Bihari] Vajpayee gave a speech that Indians don't need computers. And somebody else gave a speech that Indians don't need English. [But] Computers created millions of jobs in India. So it depends how flexible you are and how well you're looking at the future," he added.</p>

<p>Rahul Gandhi arrived in Dallas, Texas, on Sunday for his three-day US visit. The Congress MP was welcomed at the airport by Sam Pitroda, Chairman of the Indian Overseas Congress, and members of the Indian diaspora.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/sqjsf20o_rahul-gandhi-texas-ani_625x300_09_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Rahul Gandhi said if you positioned badly, you're in trouble.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-strikes-in-central-syria-kill-7-says-war-monitor-6521899]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israeli Strikes In Central Syria Kill 7, Says War Monitor]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-strikes-in-central-syria-kill-7-says-war-monitor-6521899]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Sep 2024 06:29:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli strikes in central Syria killed at least seven people late Sunday, including three civilians, a war monitor reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli strikes in central Syria killed at least seven people late Sunday, including three civilians, a war monitor reported.</p>

<p>Since the start of the civil war in Syria in 2011, Israel has carried out hundreds of strikes there, targeting pro-Iranian groups in particular.</p>

<p>"The number of dead in the Israeli strikes on the Masyaf region stands at seven, namely three civilians, including a man and his son who were in a car, and four unidentified soldiers," said the Britain-based Syrian Observatory for Human Rights, which has a vast network of sources inside the country.</p>

<p>The attack also wounded at least 15 others and destroyed military facilities in the area, the Observatory said.</p>

<p>"Thirteen violent explosions rang out in the zone housing scientific research centres in Masyaf where pro-Iranian groups and weapons development experts are present," the group said in an earlier statement.</p>

<p>The Syrian state news agency Sana had previously reported five killed and 19 wounded near Masyaf, citing a medical source.</p>

<p>"Around 11:20 pm (2020 GMT) on Sunday, the Israeli enemy carried out an air attack from the northwest of Lebanon targeting a number of military sites in the central region," Sana reported, citing a military source.</p>

<p>"Our air defence shot down some missiles."</p>

<p>Israeli air raids in Syria have intensified since the October 7 Hamas attack on Israel that sparked the war in Gaza.</p>

<p>Israeli authorities rarely comment on individual strikes in Syria, but have repeatedly said they will not allow arch-enemy Iran to expand its presence there.</p>

<p>At the end of August, three pro-Iranian fighters were killed in the central region of Homs in strikes attributed to Israel, the Observatory said.</p>

<p>A few days later, the Israeli military said it had killed an unspecified number of fighters belonging to Hamas ally Islamic Jihad in a strike in Syria near the Lebanese border.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-10/6e8i71v_missile-generic_650x400_17_October_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-russia-send-greetings-to-kim-jong-un-on-north-koreas-founding-anniversary-6521724]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[China, Russia Send Greetings To Kim Jong On N Korea's Founding Anniversary]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-russia-send-greetings-to-kim-jong-un-on-north-koreas-founding-anniversary-6521724]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Sep 2024 05:29:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Chinese President Xi Jinping and Russian President Vladimir Putin sent greetings to North Korean leader Kim Jong Un on the occasion of North Korea's founding anniversary, state media KCNA said on Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Chinese President Xi Jinping and Russian President Vladimir Putin sent greetings to North Korean leader Kim Jong Un on the occasion of North Korea's founding anniversary, state media KCNA said on Monday.</p>

<p>"I am sure that the comprehensive strategic partnership between Russia and the DPRK will be strengthened in a planned way thanks to our joint efforts," Putin said, according to KCNA.</p>

<p>DPRK is short for the Democratic People's Republic of Korea, the North's official name.</p>

<p>Xi called for deeper strategic communication and cooperation with North Korea in his message, KCNA said.</p>

<p>Last year, Kim marked the country's founding day on Sept 9 with a parade of paramilitary groups and diplomatic exchanges in which he vowed to deepen ties with China and Russia.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/qnmnpi2o_kim-jong-un-afp-_625x300_16_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-house-republican-report-blasts-biden-over-chaotic-afghan-withdrawal-6521723]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US House Republican Report Blasts Biden Over Chaotic Afghan Withdrawal]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-house-republican-report-blasts-biden-over-chaotic-afghan-withdrawal-6521723]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Sep 2024 05:25:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[U.S. House of Representatives Republicans will release a long-awaited report on Monday blasting Democratic President Joe Biden's administration for failures surrounding the chaotic and deadly U.S. withdrawal from Afghanistan in August 2021.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>U.S. House of Representatives Republicans will release a long-awaited report on Monday blasting Democratic President Joe Biden's administration for failures surrounding the chaotic and deadly U.S. withdrawal from Afghanistan in August 2021.</p>

<p>The report contends that the administration made its decision to evacuate noncombatants far too late, formally ordering it only on Aug. 16, failed to communicate between departments in Washington and among officials in Afghanistan, and botched the paperwork for the departure of Afghan civilians eligible to leave the country.</p>

<p>It is the result of a three-year investigation led by Representative Michael McCaul, Republican chair of the House Foreign Affairs Committee.</p>

<p>"America's credibility on the world stage was severely damaged after we abandoned Afghan allies to Taliban reprisal killings - the people of Afghanistan we had promised to protect," the report said. "And the moral injury to America's veterans and those still serving remains a stain on this administration's legacy."</p>

<p>The withdrawal has become intensely politicized ahead of the Nov. 5 U.S. presidential election. Last month, the Republican nominee, former President Donald Trump, shot video for his campaign at Arlington National Cemetery where he appeared at a ceremony honoring troops killed in the evacuation.</p>

<p>Trump has also attacked Biden and Vice President Kamala Harris over the exit from Afghanistan during campaign appearances, blaming them personally for the deaths at Kabul airport's Abbey Gate. On Aug. 26, 2021, as U.S. forces were trying to help Americans and Afghans flee as the Islamist Taliban movement took control of the country, a suicide attack at the Abbey Gate entrance to Kabul's airport killed 13 Americans, compounding the U.S. sense of defeat after two decades of war.</p>

<p>Harris is the Democratic presidential nominee.</p>

<p>Democrats have insisted that some blame for the messy end of the war - less than seven months into Biden's presidency - should be laid at the feet of Trump, who began the withdrawal process by signing a deal with the Taliban in 2020.</p>

<p>"When former President Trump took office, there were approximately 14,000 American troops in Afghanistan. Days before leaving office, the former President ordered a further reduction to 2,500," Representative Gregory Meeks, the top Democrat on the Foreign Affairs panel, said in a letter to committee Democrats about the investigation.</p>

<p>Republican committee aides dismissed that contention as partisan politics, saying Biden could have ignored Trump's agreement or enforced it, accusing officials who served during Biden's presidency of allowing the Taliban to disregard its commitments.</p>

<p>Some 800,000 U.S. servicemembers served in Afghanistan following the U.S.-led invasion triggered by the Sept. 11, 2001, attack on the U.S. by Afghanistan-based al Qaeda.</p>

<p>During the war, 2,238 U.S. servicemembers died and nearly 21,000 were wounded. Independent estimates put the number of Afghan security forces and civilians killed at more than 100,000.</p>

<p>McCaul has subpoenaed Secretary of State Antony Blinken three times in connection with the Afghanistan investigation, most recently last week, saying that he wants him to testify in person.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/vj7m4c84_joe-biden-afp-joe-biden-white-house-afp_625x300_06_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bharat-jodo-yatra-introduced-the-idea-of-love-in-politics-rahul-gandhi-in-us-6521554]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Bharat Jodo Yatra Introduced The Idea Of Love In Politics": Rahul Gandhi]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bharat-jodo-yatra-introduced-the-idea-of-love-in-politics-rahul-gandhi-in-us-6521554]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Sep 2024 04:24:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Rahul Gandhi, the Leader of the Opposition in Lok Sabha, while interacting with the students at the University of Texas, Dallas in the US, said that Bharat Jodo Yatra introduced the idea of love in politics.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Rahul Gandhi, the Leader of the Opposition in Lok Sabha, while interacting with the students at the University of Texas, Dallas in the US, said that Bharat Jodo Yatra introduced the idea of love in politics.</p>

<p>Elaborating the reasons for conducting the Bharat Jodo Yatra, Rahul Gandhi said, "The reason [behind conducting Bharat Jodo Yatra] is that all avenues of communication in India were shut. No matter what we did, it was all shut. We spoke in parliament. That's not televised. We go to the media, they don't pick up what we say. We even go with documents to the legal system, nothing happens. So all our avenues were shut. And for a long time we literally couldn't understand how to communicate. And then suddenly we hit upon the idea... what better way to go directly than to literally go walking across the country? And so that's what we did..."</p>

<p>"But it went surprisingly easy. And it fundamentally changed the way I think about my work... It completely changed how I view politics, how I view our people, how I communicate, how I listen. To me, the most powerful thing that happened organically, was that we introduced certainly for the first time in India, possibly for the first time in many countries, the idea of 'love' in politics. And this is strange... because... [in] the political discourse in most countries, you will never find the word 'love'... You'll find hatred, anger, unfairness, corruption... and the Bharat Jodo Yatra actually introduced that idea into the Indian political system, and it has amazed me how that idea has worked," he said.</p>

<p>The Congress leader also said that India has to think about the act of production and organising production.</p>

<p>"India has to think about the act of production and organising production. It's not acceptable that India simply says, manufacturing or production is going to be the reserve of the Chinese... or Vietnamese... or Bangladeshis. Bangladesh completely outcompetes us in textiles, regardless of the problems they're facing right now... We have to reimagine how to produce in a democratic environment. Until we do that, we will face high levels of unemployment. And frankly, it's not sustainable. So... if we carry on down this path... you're going to see massive social problems coming in India and in the United States and in Europe. The polarization of our politics is because of this," he said.</p>

<p>Talking about issues faced by the youth due to unemployment, the Raebareli MP said that the act of production creates jobs. But India organises consumption, which is the reason of worry.</p>

<p>"If you look at the United States in the 1940s, 50s and 60s, they were the center of global production. Anything that was made- cars, washing machines, TVs- all made in the United States. Production moved from the United States... [then] to Korea, [from there] it went to Japan. Eventually it went to China... China is dominating global production. [In] India, the phones... furniture... clothes, [most are] made in China. That's a fact. The West, America, Europe, India have given up on the idea of production and they've handed it to China. The act of production creates jobs. What we do, Americans do, the west does, is organize consumption. Uber, Foxconn, Mahindra, Bajaj organize production. These are the guys who create the jobs..."</p>

<p>Mr Gandhi added that not all countries have an employment problem.<br />
"Let's be clear. Not everywhere on the planet has an employment problem. The west... [and] India has an employment problem. But there are many countries in the world that don't have an employment problem. China... [and] Vietnam doesn't have an employment problem. So there are places on the planet that are not struggling with unemployment. There's a reason," he said.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/1hho8df8_raga_625x300_09_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/drought-sinks-longest-polish-river-to-record-low-level-6521499]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Drought Sinks Longest Polish River To Record-low Level]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/drought-sinks-longest-polish-river-to-record-low-level-6521499]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Sep 2024 04:04:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Poland's longest river, the Vistula, on Sunday hit a record-low water level in the capital because of drought, the national weather agency said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Poland's longest river, the Vistula, on Sunday hit a record-low water level in the capital because of drought, the national weather agency said.</p>

<p>Its level at one Warsaw measuring station fell to 25 centimetres (10 inches), beating the last record by a centimetre, according to the IMGW weather institute.</p>

<p>"It's worse than in 2015 -- and the water continues to fall!" the institute added on X, formerly Twitter.</p>

<p>Most of Poland's rivers are suffering from drought, IMGW hydrologist Grzegorz Walijewski told AFP last week.</p>

<p>"We've been dealing with hydrological drought in Poland for a while. Since 2015 there's been permanent drought," he said.</p>

<p>He said climate change was to blame, as milder winters with less snow alongside fewer days of rain and higher temperatures push down water levels.</p>

<p>The Vistula, which is the EU member's longest river at more than 1,000 kilometres (621 miles), splits the country in half and deposits in the Baltic Sea.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/u5mvmemg_drought-generic-_625x300_16_May_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/thousands-defy-roadblocks-in-rally-for-pakistan-ex-pm-imran-khan-6521389]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Thousands Defy Roadblocks In Rally For Pakistan Ex PM Imran Khan]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/thousands-defy-roadblocks-in-rally-for-pakistan-ex-pm-imran-khan-6521389]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Sep 2024 03:23:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Thousands of supporters of Pakistan's former prime minister Imran Khan gathered in Islamabad on Sunday despite authorities' attempts to block the protesters' main routes into the capital, AFP journalists noted.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Thousands of supporters of Pakistan's former prime minister Imran Khan gathered in Islamabad on Sunday despite authorities' attempts to block the protesters' main routes into the capital, AFP journalists noted.</p>

<p>The demonstration, led by Khan's Pakistan Tehreek-e-Insaf (PTI) party, is the largest in Islamabad since the retired international cricketer was jailed last year on several charges, some of them still before the courts.</p>

<p>The rally's "size and popularity ensure (PTI's) mobilization capabilities remain intact despite relentless attempts to curb it," said Michael Kugelman, Pakistan specialist at the Wilson Center, a US-based think tank.</p>

<p>Protesters on Sunday cleared containers used by Pakistani authorities to block major roads into Islamabad ahead of the demonstration.</p>

<p>"They closed the city with containers. But despite this, thousands are here. They cannot stop this motivation and emotions the people have right now," Humayun Mohmand, a PTI senator, told AFP.</p>

<p>In jail since August 2023, Khan insists along with his party that the charges against him are designed to prevent him from returning to office.</p>

<p>Backed by the military, which wields enormous influence, he rose to power in 2018 by standing against widespread corruption embedded in the country's revolving door of dynastic politics.</p>

<p>But he was ousted in 2022 after falling out with the military establishment.</p>

<p>That furthered a sense of helplessness and frustration among many Pakistanis who want the generals to stay out of politics in a country that has been ruled by the military on and off for much of its history, and where a civilian prime minister has never served a full term.</p>

<p>Khan's first arrest, on corruption charges in May 2023, sparked nationwide demonstrations by supporters expressing anger at the army. In response, the army orchestrated a massive crackdown on the PTI.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/7pt9hf3g_imran-khan-rally_625x300_09_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Protesters on Sunday cleared containers used by Pakistani authorities to block major roads]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukraine-attacks-oil-storage-depot-in-russian-border-region-reservoirs-catch-fire-6521363]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ukraine Attacks Oil Storage Depot In Russian Border Region]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukraine-attacks-oil-storage-depot-in-russian-border-region-reservoirs-catch-fire-6521363]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Sep 2024 03:17:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The governor of Russia's southern Belgorod region said on Sunday Ukrainian forces attacked a fuel depot, triggering a series of fires after Moscow and Kyiv accused each other of launching overnight attacks on border regions.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The governor of Russia's southern Belgorod region said on Sunday Ukrainian forces attacked a fuel depot, triggering a series of fires after Moscow and Kyiv accused each other of launching overnight attacks on border regions.</p>

<p>"The Ukrainian military, aided by lethal drones, attacked a fuel storage site in Volokonovsky district," Vyacheslav Gladkov wrote on Telegram, referring to an area near the border.</p>

<p>"Several reservoirs caught fire in an explosion. Firefighting crews are putting out the blaze."</p>

<p>Gladkov also reported drone attacks on three other localities. There were no casualties reported in the incidents.</p>

<p>In the overnight air attacks, Ukrainian officials said two people died and four were injured in Sumy region. Gladkov reported three civilians were injured in Belgorod.</p>

<p>Two children were among those injured in Sumy, the military administration of the northeastern Ukrainian region said on Sunday on Telegram. Several homes and cars were damaged.</p>

<p>In Belgorod region, three civilians, including two children, were injured. Gladkov said two residential buildings were destroyed and more than 15 buildings in total were damaged.</p>

<p>The Russian defence ministry said it had destroyed one drone over Belgorod region and another over Kursk region, where Ukrainian forces launched a cross-border incursion last month. It said two drones were intercepted over Belgorod overnight.</p>

<p>Reuters could not independently verify the reports.</p>

<p>Border regions on both sides have been subject to frequent attacks. Both Moscow and Kyiv deny targeting civilians, saying the attacks are aimed at destroying each other's infrastructure critical to war efforts.</p>

<p>Thousands of civilians have died in the war, which Russia started with a full-scale invasion on Ukraine in February 2022. Millions of Ukrainians have also been displaced, while their cities and villages have become piles of rubble</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/dihogkno_russia-ukraine_625x300_09_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/another-fire-breaks-out-at-kenyan-school-third-incident-in-2-days-6521360]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Another Fire Breaks Out At Kenyan School, Third Incident In 2 Days]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/another-fire-breaks-out-at-kenyan-school-third-incident-in-2-days-6521360]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Sep 2024 03:12:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A blaze destroyed a dormitory at a Kenyan school on Sunday, police said, the third such incident in just days.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A blaze destroyed a dormitory at a Kenyan school on Sunday, police said, the third such incident in just days.</p>

<p>A dorm at Njia Boys High School in the central county of Meru caught fire as students were having supper and no casualties were reported, a police statement said.</p>

<p>The building housing about 150 students "completely burnt down, the inferno consuming everything, and property of unknown value was destroyed", it said.</p>

<p>Last Thursday, 21 boys perished when flames engulfed their dormitory at the Hillside Endarasha Academy in Nyeri county as they were sleeping.</p>

<p>And on Saturday, another fire erupted at a girls' high school in Isiolo county, also in the centre of the country.</p>

<p>A local official said there were several injuries, but police said no one was hurt.</p>

<p>Last week's deadly inferno has thrown the spotlight on safety at Kenya's schools, with President William Ruto vowing that those responsible would be brought to justice.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-05/c590rf94_fire-generic_625x300_17_May_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Last week's deadly inferno has thrown the spotlight on safety at Kenya's schools (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/21-killed-67-injured-in-market-shelling-in-sudan-report-6521334]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[21 Killed, 67 Injured In Market Shelling In Sudan: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/21-killed-67-injured-in-market-shelling-in-sudan-report-6521334]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Sep 2024 03:08:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Shelling at a market in Sennar in southeast Sudan killed 21 people and wounded another 67 on Sunday, a medical source told AFP, blaming paramilitaries for the attack.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Shelling at a market in Sennar in southeast Sudan killed 21 people and wounded another 67 on Sunday, a medical source told AFP, blaming paramilitaries for the attack.</p>

<p>The Sudan Doctors Network, which was set up after the start of the war in April 2023, reported a similar death count, but said the number of wounded was more than 70. It blamed the paramilitary Rapid Support Forces (RSF) for the shelling.</p>

<p>The RSF, led by Mohamed Hamdan Daglo, is fighting the Sudanese army under the country's de facto ruler Abdel Fattah al-Burhan.</p>

<p>The government has in the past accused the RSF of systematically targeting civilians and civilian institutions.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-04/870oehpg_sudan-clashes-reuters_625x300_18_April_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The government has in the past accused the RSF of systematically targeting civilians (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/golden-eagle-attacks-norwegian-toddler-killed-by-gamekeeper-report-6521042]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Golden Eagle Attacks Norwegian Toddler, Killed By Gamekeeper: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/golden-eagle-attacks-norwegian-toddler-killed-by-gamekeeper-report-6521042]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Sep 2024 01:25:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A golden eagle attacked a toddler in Norway on Sunday, with her mother and a neighbour fighting the bird off repeatedly until a game warden killed it, Norwegian media reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A golden eagle attacked a toddler in Norway on Sunday, with her mother and a neighbour fighting the bird off repeatedly until a game warden killed it, Norwegian media reported.</p>

<p>The 20-month-old girl, who was playing on her family's farm in Trondelag in central Norway when the eagle swooped down on her, required stitches to the back of her head and had scratches from the eagle's talons on her face, her father told public broadcaster NRK.</p>

<p>"The eagle came out of nowhere and grabbed our youngest daughter," said the father, whose name was not disclosed.</p>

<p>"Her mother jumped up and grabbed hold of the eagle, but had to fight to get it to let go. A neighbour also had to help her and our little girl," he said.</p>

<p>Gamekeeper Per Kare Vinterdal, who killed the eagle, told NRK the bird saw the little girl as "prey".</p>

<p>He said the mother and neighbour managed to get the eagle off the girl "but it kept coming back" even though "the neighbour chased it away with a stick".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/svphobi_eagle-generic_625x300_26_June_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Gamekeeper Per Kare Vinterdal killed the eagle (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kolkata-doctor-rape-murder-rg-kar-hospital-protests-across-25-countries-over-130-cities-over-kolkata-rape-murder-case-6520789]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Protests Held Across 25 Countries Over Kolkata Doctor's Rape-Murder]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kolkata-doctor-rape-murder-rg-kar-hospital-protests-across-25-countries-over-130-cities-over-kolkata-rape-murder-case-6520789]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:03:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Thousands of diaspora Indians were protesting in more than 130 cities across 25 countries on Sunday, organisers said, to demand justice after last month's rape and murder of a trainee doctor at a hospital in the city of Kolkata.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Thousands of members of the Indian community were protesting in more than 130 cities across 25 countries on Sunday, organisers said, to demand justice after last month's rape and murder of a trainee doctor at a hospital in the city of Kolkata.</p>

<p>The protests started in large and small groups across Japan, Australia, Taiwan and Singapore, before spreading to cities in several European countries. Sixty were planned in the US.</p>

<p>They added to ongoing protests around India after the August 9 killing of the 31-year-old postgraduate student of chest medicine.</p>

<p>A suspect has been arrested along with the former principal of RG Kar Medical College where the doctor was studying.</p>

<p>At one of the protests in the Swedish capital Stockholm, scores of mainly black-clad women gathered in Sergels Torg square to sing songs in Bengali and hold signs, demanding accountability for the crime and safety for Indian women.</p>

<p>"The news of this heinous crime committed on a young trainee doctor while on duty numbed and shocked each of us at the sheer ruthlessness, brutality and disregard of human life," said Dipti Jain, an organiser of the global protests.</p>

<p>Ms Jain, now a British citizen and alumni of the Calcutta National Medical College and Hospital, had last month organised a female doctors protest in the UK.</p>

<p>The Supreme Court has listed the next hearing of the trainee's case for Monday.</p>

<p>Although tougher laws were introduced after the 2012 gruesome gang rape and murder of a 23-year-old student on a moving bus in New Delhi, activists say the Kolkata case shows how women continue to suffer from sexual violence.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/7aathulg_worldwide-protests-kolkata-horror_625x300_09_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sixty protests were planned in the US]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/national-grandparents-day-kamala-harris-recalls-long-walks-with-her-grandfather-and-what-they-discussed-6520786]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris Recalls Walks With Her Grandfather,  And What They Discussed]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/national-grandparents-day-kamala-harris-recalls-long-walks-with-her-grandfather-and-what-they-discussed-6520786]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:01:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Indian-origin Democratic presidential candidate Kamala Harris on Sunday, recalling her fond memories with her grandparents in India, wished National Grandparents Day to all the grandparents who help shape and inspire the next generation.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Indian-origin Democratic presidential candidate Kamala Harris on Sunday, recalling her fond memories with her grandparents in India, wished National Grandparents Day to all the grandparents who help shape and inspire the next generation.</p>

<p>"As a young girl visiting my grandparents in India, my grandfather took me on his morning walks, where he would discuss the importance of fighting for equality and fighting corruption. He was a retired civil servant who had been part of the movement to win India's independence," Ms Harris said in a post on X.</p>

<p>"My grandmother travelled across India-bullhorn in hand-to speak with women about accessing birth control," the incumbent vice-president said.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">As a young girl visiting my grandparents in India, my grandfather took me on his morning walks, where he would discuss the importance of fighting for equality and fighting corruption. He was a retired civil servant who had been part of the movement to win India's independence. <a href="https://t.co/vOpgtsomQN">pic.twitter.com/vOpgtsomQN</a></p>
 Kamala Harris (@KamalaHarris) <a href="https://twitter.com/KamalaHarris/status/1832805919781974438?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 8, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The Democrat added that her grandparents' "commitment to public service and fight for a better future" lived in her today.</p>

<p>"Happy National Grandparents Day to all the grandparents who help shape and inspire the next generation," Kamala Harris, who is contesting against former president Donald Trump, said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/7crakfag_kamala-harris-childhood_625x300_09_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kamala Harris is contesting against former president Donald Trump]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-debate-donald-trump-kamala-harris-tied-in-latest-polls-ahead-of-televised-presidential-debate-6520668]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump, Harris Tied In Latest Polls Ahead Of Televised Presidential Debate]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-debate-donald-trump-kamala-harris-tied-in-latest-polls-ahead-of-televised-presidential-debate-6520668]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Sep 2024 23:38:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The US presidential race remains neck-and-neck according to polls released Sunday, two days before Kamala Harris and Donald Trump hold their first -- and potentially only -- televised debate.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The US presidential race remains neck-and-neck according to polls released Sunday, two days before Kamala Harris and Donald Trump hold their first -- and potentially only -- televised debate.</p>

<p>The latest polling confirms that Trump retains locked-in support from about half of voters, despite the Republican's historic status as a convicted felon and his role in instigating the unprecedented attempt to overturn his 2020 loss to Joe Biden.</p>

<p>Harris, who only jumped into the race after President Biden abruptly quit in July, has rapidly transformed herself from a little-noticed vice president into a serious contender. However, the polls show she has not made a major breakthrough, leaving the race a toss-up.</p>

<p>A New York Times/Siena poll found that 78-year-old Trump is leading Harris nationally by 48 to 47 percent, well within the margin of error.</p>

<p>US presidential elections are decided by tallying the results of state-by-state contests, rather than an overall national popular vote, meaning that a tiny handful of swing states typically decide the balance.</p>

<p>The poll found Harris, 59, narrowly ahead in Wisconsin, Michigan and Pennsylvania and tied in four other swing states -- Nevada, Georgia, North Carolina and Arizona.</p>

<p>A CBS News/YouGov poll put Harris ahead by one percentage point in Michigan and Wisconsin and tied in Pennsylvania.</p>

<p>The election is already chaotic, with 81-year-old Biden dropping out amid concerns over his age, Trump narrowly surviving an assassin's bullet at a rally, and fears mounting that Trump will again refuse to concede if he loses in November.</p>

<p>However, the latest numbers confirm that each candidate retains a remarkably stable base of loyalists, almost evenly splitting the country.</p>

<p>One game changer could be Tuesday's ABC News debate, the only one scheduled between the two.</p>

<p>Trump will be under pressure to rein in his characteristic use of insults and intimidation as he stands next to a mixed-race candidate vying to become the first female president in US history.</p>

<p>Harris will need to use the huge viewership to connect with Americans in a way that she was unable to as vice president and has had little time to accomplish in her super-condensed campaign run.</p>

<p>With Trump now the oldest presidential nominee in US history, she is pitching an optimistic, forward-looking message in contrast to Trump's apocalyptic claims that the country faces terminal decline without him in the White House.</p>

<p><strong>Sexist taunts</strong></p>

<p>At the same time, Harris will have to solve the conundrum of how to debate Trump, who habitually makes false statements on nearly every topic and loves to get under his opponents' skin. Biden, in his only debate against Trump before dropping his candidacy, found himself entirely unable to cope.</p>

<p>Already, Trump has been subjecting Harris in his speeches to racist and sexist taunts, deliberately mispronouncing her name and calling her "crazy" and a "Marxist."</p>

<p>"It will take almost superhuman focus and discipline to deal with Donald Trump in a debate," Harris supporter and current transportation secretary Pete Buttigieg told CNN.</p>

<p>The Harris campaign announced it would "barnstorm battleground states" after the debate, beginning in North Carolina, then Pennsylvania.</p>

<p>Trump held a rally in Wisconsin on Saturday where he appealed to his mostly white, working class base with a dark speech claiming that he is struggling against a "rogue regime" where Democrats "imported murderers, child predators and serial rapists from all over the planet."</p>

<p>On his Truth Social platform, he warned that once back in the White House he would impose "long prison sentences" on all those he said were planning "cheating" in November.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ugf3uu1g_trump-harris-_625x300_22_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Latest numbers confirm that each candidate retains a remarkably stable base of loyalists. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-we-are-afraid-israeli-strike-kills-gaza-civil-emergency-service-director-6520591]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["We Are Afraid": Israeli Strike Kills Gaza Civil Emergency Service Director]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-we-are-afraid-israeli-strike-kills-gaza-civil-emergency-service-director-6520591]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Sep 2024 23:20:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An Israeli airstrike on a house in Jabalia on Sunday killed Mohammad Morsi, deputy director of the Gaza Civil Emergency Service in the northern areas of the Gaza Strip, and four of his family, health officials said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An Israeli airstrike on a house in Jabalia on Sunday killed Mohammad Morsi, deputy director of the Gaza Civil Emergency Service in the northern areas of the Gaza Strip, and four of his family, health officials said.</p>

<p>The Civil Emergency Service said in a statement that Morsi's death raised to 83 the number of its members killed by Israeli fire since Oct. 7.</p>

<p>There was no immediate Israeli comment on Morsi's death.</p>

<p>Residents said Israeli forces had also blown up several houses in the Zeitoun suburb of Gaza City 5 km from Jabalia. Medical teams said they were unable to answer desperate calls by some of the residents who had reported being trapped inside their houses, some wounded.</p>

<p>"We hear constant bombing in Zeitoun, we know they are blowing up houses there, we don't sleep because of the sounds of explosions, the roaring of tanks sound close and the drones don't stop circling," said one resident of Gaza City, who lives around 1 km away.</p>

<p>"The occupation is wiping out Zeitoun, we are afraid about the people trapped in there," he told Reuters via a chat app, refusing to be named.</p>

<p>Later on Sunday, the Gaza health ministry said Israeli military strikes across the enclave killed at least 15 people.</p>

<p>Residents of central and southern Gaza areas reported interruption in internet and communication services, which the Palestinian Telecommunication Company said was because of "the ongoing (Israeli) aggression."</p>

<p>Palestinians say internet and communication outages, the first in months, impact the ability of medical staffers to dispatch ambulances to bombed areas and make it difficult for people to check on their relatives or report attacks.</p>

<p>Israel and Hamas continued to blame one another for the failure of mediators, including Qatar, Egypt and the U.S., to broker a ceasefire. The U.S. is preparing to present a new proposal, but the prospects of a breakthrough appear dim as gaps between the sides' positions remain large.</p>

<p>Meanwhile on Sunday the United Nations, in collaboration with local health authorities, extended by a day a campaign to vaccinate children in the southern Gaza Strip against polio before it moves on Monday to the north.</p>

<p>The campaign aims to vaccinate 640,000 children in Gaza after its first polio case in around 25 years. Limited pauses in the fighting have allowed the campaign to proceed.</p>

<p>U.N. officials said they were making progress, having reached more than half of the children needing the drops in the first two stages in the southern and central Gaza Strip. A second round of vaccination will be required four weeks after the first.</p>

<p>The latest bloodshed in the decades-old Israeli-Palestinian conflict was triggered on Oct. 7 when the Hamas group attacked Israel, killing 1,200 and taking about 250 hostages, according to Israeli tallies.</p>

<p>Israel's subsequent assault on Gaza has killed more than 40,900 Palestinians, according to the local health ministry, while also displacing nearly the entire population of 2.3 million, causing a hunger crisis and leading to genocide allegations at the World Court, which Israel denies.</p>

<p>The Palestinian health ministry does not distinguish between combatants and non-combatants in its casualty reports, but health officials say that most of the fatalities have been civilians.</p>

<p>Israel, which has lost 340 soldiers in Gaza, says at least a third of the Palestinian dead are fighters.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/h828s4n8_gaza-reuters-_625x300_04_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel says at least a third of the Palestinian dead are fighters. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/48-killed-after-fuel-truck-explodes-in-nigeria-after-collision-with-vehicle-6520563]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[48 Killed After Fuel Truck Explodes In Nigeria After Collision With Vehicle]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/48-killed-after-fuel-truck-explodes-in-nigeria-after-collision-with-vehicle-6520563]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Sep 2024 23:15:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[At least 48 people were killed on Sunday in a fuel tanker truck explosion following a collision with another vehicle in north-central Nigeria, the state's disaster management agency said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At least 48 people were killed on Sunday in a fuel tanker truck explosion following a collision with another vehicle in north-central Nigeria, the state's disaster management agency said.</p>

<p>The State Emergency Management Agency in north-central Niger state said the fuel truck collided with a truck carrying travellers and cattle. Several other vehicles were also caught up in the accident, it said.</p>

<p>The agency's spokesperson Hussaini Ibrahim put the death count at 48 and officials were still trying to clear the scene of the incident.</p>

<p>Nigeria's state-owned firm NNPC Ltd last week hiked the price of gasoline by at least 39%, the second major increase in more than a year but shortages have continued, forcing motorists to queue for hours in the country's major cities and towns.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-02/rr7gtng_blast-generic-fire-generic-unsplash_625x300_27_February_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Nigeria's state-owned firm last week hiked the price of gasoline by at least 39% (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>