<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 01:02:06 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/once-bursting-with-life-beirut-now-lies-in-ruins-6834474]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Once Bursting With Life, Beirut Now Lies In Ruins]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/once-bursting-with-life-beirut-now-lies-in-ruins-6834474]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 20 Oct 2024 23:55:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Just a month ago, south Beirut's bustling streets were packed with traffic, families strolling about and youths in cafes, but now silence dominates the abandoned Hezbollah bastion, interrupted only by the sound of Israeli bombs.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Just a month ago, south Beirut's bustling streets were packed with traffic, families strolling about and youths in cafes, but now silence dominates the abandoned Hezbollah bastion, interrupted only by the sound of Israeli bombs.</p>

<p>Escalating Israeli attacks since late September, after nearly a year of low-intensity cross-border exchanges, have reduced much of the Lebanese capital's once densely-packed southern suburbs to rubble and sent many of its residents fleeing.</p>

<p>Braving the smell of rotting flesh that reeks from razed buildings, a few young men stood guard, dressed in black civilian clothes and occasionally driving around the ruins on their motorbikes.</p>

<p>They observed the odd car and the handful of displaced residents who come on foot, hastily checking on their apartment or collecting some belongings before heading back to safety.</p>

<p>"The young people told me not to stay too long because drones were constantly flying over and could strike at any time," said 32-year-old Mohammed, on a brief visit home to get more clothes.</p>

<p>Giving his first name only for security concerns, he said he first left on September 27, days into Israel's intense air campaign on Lebanon.</p>

<p>That day, massive Israeli strikes killed Hezbollah's elusive leader Hassan Nasrallah in the heart of the Iran-backed group's south Beirut stronghold, toppling several apartment buildings and spreading fear of even greater violence.</p>

<p>"We left in a hurry and thought we would never see our house again," said Mohammed, adding that his neighbours had also fled.</p>

<p>The building was still standing, but many others have been damaged or destroyed.</p>

<p><strong>Attacks on infrastructure</strong></p>

<p>Cracks snaked down nearby buildings as torn-off asphalt and burst pipes leaked sewage and tap water.</p>

<p>Generators that long made up for daily power cuts after five years of economic crisis had also been blown to bits.</p>

<p>"About 320 buildings were destroyed in Beirut and its suburbs" in less than a month of war, Mona Fawaz of the Beirut Urban Lab told AFP.</p>

<p>The devastation has surpassed the damage caused by Israel's last war with Hezbollah in 2006, said Fawaz, who records cases of "urbicide", the destruction of cities in conflict, focusing now on Lebanon and the Gaza Strip.</p>

<p>She accused Israel of "deliberate targeting of what allows life to continue," including vital infrastructure unrelated to Hezbollah.</p>

<p>Hezbollah had completely rebuilt Beirut's south based on the existing urban plans from before the 2006 war, which had displaced about 100,000 people from the area.</p>

<p>During that 33-day war, "surveys list 1,332 severely damaged multi-storey apartment buildings, of which 281 were completely razed to the ground" in an area of about 20 square kilometres (eight square miles), said Fawaz.</p>

<p>The Burj al-Barajneh neighbourhood, unscathed in 2006, has been heavily damaged in the bombardment this time around.</p>

<p><strong>Childhood memories</strong></p>

<p>Once again, families from south Beirut are forced to seek refuge elsewhere in the country or abroad.</p>

<p>Many live in rented apartments or with relatives, while others are crammed in schools-turned-shelters.</p>

<p>Hassan, 37, grew up in the Mraijeh district of Beirut's south, where Israeli jets targeted Hashem Safieddine, widely seen as Nasrallah's most likely successor.</p>

<p>Despite the bloodshed, he said Mraijeh will always remind him of his "friends, the games we used to play as children, the smell of freshly-baked bread in the morning, neighbours chatting and Ramadan festivities".</p>

<p>The supermarket he used to shop at is in ruins, with nearby shops, schools and buildings also reduced to rubble.</p>

<p>Hassan, who also asked to be identified by first name only, was told his favourite record store was no more.</p>

<p>As the war shows no signs of abating, greater losses are all but certain.</p>

<p>"We are afraid to return after the war only to discover how many of our friends have died, like in 2006," said Hassan with a sigh.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/oisd6ts_beirut-reuters_625x300_20_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[As the war shows no signs of abating, greater losses are all but certain.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/justin-trudeau-wrecked-canada-india-ties-says-indian-envoy-6834429]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Justin Trudeau Wrecked Canada-India Ties, Says Indian Envoy]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/justin-trudeau-wrecked-canada-india-ties-says-indian-envoy-6834429]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 20 Oct 2024 23:41:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Indian envoy to Canada Sanjay Kumar Verma - now withdrawn by New Delhi -- has accused Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau of wrecking bilateral ties with India and reiterated that Ottawa's allegations are politically motivated. O]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Indian envoy to Canada Sanjay Kumar Verma - now withdrawn by New Delhi -- has accused Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau of wrecking bilateral ties with India and reiterated that Ottawa's allegations are politically motivated. Ottawa has accused Mr Verma of having links to the murder of Khalistani separatist Hardeep Singh Nijjar.</p>

<p>India's response to the allegations was to withdraw the diplomats. It was followed by Canadian government's move to formally expel them. India reiterated by ordering out six Canadian diplomats.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In an interview to CTV aired on Sunday, Mr Verma said, "On the basis of intelligence, if you want to destroy a relationship, be my guest. And that's what he did".</p>

<p>Justin Trudeau had specifically tied the Indian diplomats to the murder of Nijjar that took place last year in British Columbia.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Asked whether he had had anything to do with Nijjar's murder, Mr Verma said: "Nothing at all. No evidence was presented. (This is) politically motivated."</p>

<p>"On what basis do they want to question me... If you are a defendant, for example, which I am not, then evidence would be shared and that happens even if you are caught for a petty crime. If I'm going for an interrogation I need to know what I am interrogated for. I need to know what evidence you have so I go prepared," Mr Verma told the Canadian network when asked about India's refusal to join the so-called ongoing investigations.</p>

<p>Ties between the two nations - on a downward spiral since September last year -- have nosedived after the series of fresh allegations.</p>

<p>The Foreign Ministry has slammed Ottawa for its allegations against Mr Verma -- one of the country's senior-most diplomats who has served in Japan, Sudan, Italy, Turkey, Vietnam and China.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The allegations, India said, were "ludicrous" and deserved to be treated with contempt. New Delhi said it has "no faith in the current Canadian Government's commitment to ensure their security".</p>

<p><br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/oftq3iv_pm-modi-justin-trudeau-modi-trudeau-ani_625x300_11_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-now-60-questions-78-year-old-donald-trumps-fitness-to-be-us-president-6834417]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris, Now 60, Questions 78-Year-Old Trump's Fitness To Be President]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-now-60-questions-78-year-old-donald-trumps-fitness-to-be-us-president-6834417]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 20 Oct 2024 23:40:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kamala Harris turned 60 on Sunday in the final stretch of a knife-edge election battle with 78-year-old Donald Trump, as she urged a Black congregation in Georgia to embrace compassionate values while others "spread hate, sow fear and cause chaos."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kamala Harris turned 60 on Sunday in the final stretch of a knife-edge election battle with 78-year-old Donald Trump, as she urged a Black congregation in Georgia to embrace compassionate values while others "spread hate, sow fear and cause chaos."</p>

<p>Harris, speaking at a Baptist megachurch near Atlanta, did not mention Trump by name but the crowd -- after spontaneously serenading her with "Happy Birthday" -- nodded knowingly to her allusions to her Republican rival.</p>

<p>Georgia is one of the key states that are expected to decide the November 5 election. Both candidates were planning events later Sunday in another of those states, Pennsylvania, which both sides see as a must-win.</p>

<p>With just over two weeks before Election Day, the Democratic vice president and the Republican billionaire are in a fierce race.</p>

<p>Harris, addressing the enthusiastic Black churchgoers -- normally a strongly Democratic demographic -- delivered a temperate speech, telling the tale of the Good Samaritan but also using it to exhort the crowd to vote and "shine the light in moments of darkness."</p>

<p>Indeed, Trump is using increasingly angry and dark language in the campaign.</p>

<p>He has likened undocumented migrants to animals, threatened revenge against his perceived enemies, praised autocrats like Vladimir Putin of Russia and described America as a ruined nation only he can fix.</p>

<p>"Where we go from here is up to us as Americans and as people of faith," Harris said. "What kind of country do we want to live in -- a country of chaos, fear and hate, or a country of freedom, compassion and justice?"</p>

<p>In other events, Harris has increasingly raised questions about Trump's fitness to be president.</p>

<p>"Now he's ducking debates and canceling interviews because of exhaustion," Harris told a rally Saturday in Atlanta, mocking his rambling, off-script speeches.</p>

<p>The former president himself has surprised attendees at his rallies with sometimes bizarre references, including a ribald allusion Saturday to the anatomy of a famous golfer.</p>

<p>But Trump's age and spontaneous remarks have not appeared to be a deal-breaker for voters, as polls show a close battle ahead.</p>

<p><strong>'Across the finish line'</strong></p>

<p>Harris had also sought to goad Trump with a report on October 12 that described her "excellent health", but the ex-president's campaign insisted he, too, is "in perfect and excellent health to be Commander-in-Chief".</p>

<p>The Republican running for a second go in the White House countered Harris's accusations with a marathon speech in Pennsylvania on Saturday, a day after saying she "doesn't have the energy of a rabbit."</p>

<p>Both candidates are spending their final campaign days in pivotal states, but so are their surrogates.</p>

<p>Tesla and SpaceX boss Elon Musk has personally hit the campaign trail in Pennsylvania, holding a series of events in the must-win state.</p>

<p>Speaking in the southeastern city of Harrisburg, he announced he would start to randomly distribute cash awards -- $1 million each day until the November 5 vote -- to a registered voter in the state who signed his organization's petition.</p>

<p>Harris deployed surrogates in the form of pop stars Lizzo and Usher to make her case to voters.</p>

<p>Lizzo drew cheers when telling a Detroit rally that America was more than ready for its first woman president, dropping a reference to her own hit song: "It's about damn time!"</p>

<p>One of Atlanta's major stars, Usher, told voters there that "I'm counting on you" to get Harris's "campaign across the finish line" in Georgia.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/ou6o95ig_kamala-harris-donald-trump_625x300_20_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Harris has increasingly raised questions about Trump's fitness to be president (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-should-be-on-un-security-council-permanently-russias-top-diplomat-sergey-lavrov-6834363]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India Should Be On UN Security Council Permanently: Russia's Top Diplomat]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-should-be-on-un-security-council-permanently-russias-top-diplomat-sergey-lavrov-6834363]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 20 Oct 2024 23:29:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russia's top diplomat has said that his country believes that India, Brazil and African countries should be represented in the UN Security Council on a permanent basis, state-owned TASS news agency reported on Sunday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russia's top diplomat has said that his country believes that India, Brazil and African countries should be represented in the UN Security Council on a permanent basis to ensure the representativeness of the global majority, state-owned TASS news agency reported on Sunday.</p>

<p>"Countries such as India, Brazil, as well as representatives of Africa should have been on a permanent basis in the Security Council for a long time. This is necessary to ensure representativeness, representation of the global majority," Russian Foreign Minister Sergey Lavrov told aif.ru. in an interview, TASS reported.</p>

<p>India has been at the forefront of years-long efforts calling for reform of the Security Council, including expansion in both its permanent and non-permanent categories, saying the 15-nation Council, founded in 1945, is not fit for purpose in the 21st Century and does not reflect contemporary geo-political realities. Delhi has underscored that it deserves a permanent seat at the horse-shoe table.</p>

<p>Last month, British Prime Minister Keir Starmer joined US President Joe Biden and French President Emmanuel Macron in backing India's bid for a permanent seat on the United Nations Security Council (UNSC).</p>

<p>India last sat at the UN high table as a non-permanent member in 2021-22. There has been a growing demand to increase the number of permanent members to reflect the contemporary global reality.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-11/ccd2a8hg_sergey-lavrov-afp_625x300_16_November_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[India last sat at the UN high table as a non-permanent member in 2021-22 (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/indias-digital-revolution-an-example-for-world-nobel-laureate-paul-romer-6834252]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India's Digital Revolution An Example For World: Nobel Laureate Paul Romer]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/indias-digital-revolution-an-example-for-world-nobel-laureate-paul-romer-6834252]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 20 Oct 2024 23:05:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Nobel Laureate Professor Paul Michael Romer on Sunday hailed India's digital revolution as one of the most inspiring and interesting success stories and said that it has set a new benchmark for world powers.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Nobel Laureate Professor Paul Michael Romer on Sunday hailed India's digital revolution as one of the most inspiring and interesting success stories and said that it has set a new benchmark for world powers.</p>

<p>Prof Paul Michael Romer, also the former Chief Economist of World Bank, is currently in India and will be one of the lead speakers at the two-day NDTV World Summit, starting from October 21.</p>

<p>Professor Paul, sharing his views on India's digital prowess, pointed out a unique aspect of India's digital transformation and said that the South Asian nations can benefit heavily by emulating it.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Watch: Professor Paul Michael Romer says, "Well, this is what makes the digital revolution in India so interesting, is that it's been used by the government to actually provide benefits to all members of society. It hasn't just created benefits for the lucky few, and this I think… <a href="https://t.co/BPZCwjeZXH">pic.twitter.com/BPZCwjeZXH</a></p>
— IANS (@ians_india) <a href="https://twitter.com/ians_india/status/1847971584146817391?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 20, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>He said that India's digital revolution not only made the lives of people easier and simpler, but it has also emerged as an example for the rest of the world.</p>

<p>Ahead of his participation in the discourse at NDTV platform, the Nobel Laureate lauded Prime Minister Narendra Modi-led government for successfully leading the digital penetration into masses and pushing it to every nook and corner of the country.</p>

<p>"Digital revolution here is very interesting because it is being used by the government to provide benefits to all members of society. This is very different from most countries of the world, where the target is only a lucky few beneficiaries. India's story is unique because it is providing benefits to all," he said.</p>

<p>When questioned on how India's digital success could become a model for South Asian nations, he said that online services like UPI, DBT, Digilockers and more have shown tremendous success and the Southern nations could emulate it for writing a similar success story for them.</p>

<p>"Other countries, particularly in the South should believe that if India can do it, we can also do it. They can draw inspiration and confidence from India and harbour an ambition to create a success story. They don't need to be dependent on rich countries, rather should initiate work based on their own ground realities," he told the mediapersons.</p>

<p>When questioned about India's astounding success in digitising the economy despite very limited online literacy, he said that he has always been a strong votary of technology as a great enabler.</p>

<p>"In 1980s, I strongly vouched for technology to be a life-changing enabler. Technology can improve the quality of life - and is visible in countries like Singapore, South Korea and more. When China grew faster than any other country, some attributed it to its size. However, in democracy what matters is the country's capacity, its ambition and vision to achieve," he remarked.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/vhv38spo_paul-romer_625x300_20_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Professor Paul lauded PM Modi-led government for successfully leading digital penetration into masses]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/study-reveals-the-science-behind-childrens-short-attention-span-6834157]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Study Reveals The Science Behind Children's Short Attention Span]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/study-reveals-the-science-behind-childrens-short-attention-span-6834157]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 20 Oct 2024 22:49:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A new study reveals that kindergarten-aged children tend to over-explore during tasks, not due to lack of understanding or attention, but possibly due to curiosity or underdeveloped working memory.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The reasons behind young children's frequent struggles with focusing on particular tasks have been clarified by a recent study. It was found by researchers that although children as young as kindergarten are able to comprehend and carry out instructions, their natural tendency is to explore their environment.</p>

<p>The four, five, and six-year-old youngsters in the study showed a tendency to scatter their attention widely, gathering too many details that divert them from their main objective. The researchers claim that this behaviour is caused by their innate curiosity and the constraints of their working memory at this developmental stage rather than a lack of comprehension or attention span.</p>

<p>According to a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://news.osu.edu/why-children-cant-pay-attention-to-the-task-at-hand/"><em>release by the Ohio State University</em></a>, it now appears that kids distribute their attention broadly either out of simple curiosity or because their working memory isn't developed enough to complete a task without "overexploring."</p>

<p>"Children can't seem to stop themselves from gathering more information than they need to complete a task, even when they know exactly what they need," said Vladimir Sloutsky, co-author of the study and professor of psychology at The Ohio State University.</p>

<p>Sloutsky conducted the study, published recently in the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/10.1177/09567976241258146"><em>journal Psychological Science</em></a>, with lead author Qianqian Wan, a doctoral student in psychology at Ohio State.</p>

<p>The findings suggest that while young children may have difficulty focusing on a single task, it is a normal and expected part of their cognitive development. As their brains mature, they will gradually develop better concentration skills and learn to prioritise relevant information.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/41g26ck_kindergarten_625x300_20_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A new study reveals why kindergarten-aged children tend to overexplore.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musks-daily-1-million-payouts-at-trump-rally-draw-legal-scrutiny-6834146]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk's Daily $1 Million Payouts At Trump Rally Draw Legal Scrutiny]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musks-daily-1-million-payouts-at-trump-rally-draw-legal-scrutiny-6834146]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 20 Oct 2024 22:45:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Elon Musk promised on Saturday to give away $1 million each day until November's election to someone who signs his online petition, with the first prize awarded at a PAC event supporting Donald Trump, raising questions about legality of the payments.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Billionaire Elon Musk promised on Saturday to give away $1 million each day until November's election to someone who signs his online petition, with the first prize awarded at a PAC event supporting Republican Donald Trump, raising questions about the legality of the payments.</p>

<p>Musk gave a $1 million check to an attendee of his America PAC event in Harrisburg, Pennsylvania, aimed at rallying supporters behind presidential candidate Trump. The winner was a man named John Dreher, according to event staff.</p>

<p>"By the way, John had no idea. So anyway, you're welcome," the Tesla founder said as he handed Dreher the check.</p>

<p>The money is the latest example of Musk using his extraordinary wealth to influence the tightly-contested presidential race between Trump and his Democratic rival Vice President Kamala Harris.</p>

<p>Musk started America PAC, a political action organization he founded in support of Trump's presidential campaign. The group is helping mobilize and register voters in battleground states, but there are signs it is having trouble meeting its goals.</p>

<p><strong>'DEEPLY CONCERNING'</strong></p>

<p>Pennsylvania Governor Josh Shapiro said on Sunday on NBC's "Meet the Press" that Musk's plan to give money to registered voters in Pennsylvania is "deeply concerning" and "it's something that law enforcement could take a look at."</p>

<p>Questions about the legality of these cash payments abounded on Saturday night, as election law experts pointed to various provisions in federal law that prohibited making cash payments to voters.</p>

<p>It is a federal crime to pay people with the intention of inducing or rewarding them to cast a vote or to get registered, an offense punishable by prison time. The prohibition covers not only monetary expenditures, but also anything of monetary value like liquor or lottery chances, a Justice Department election-crimes manual says.</p>

<p>The Harrisburg event was the third in as many days in Pennsylvania, where Musk is painting November's election in stark terms and encouraging supporters to vote early and get others to do the same.</p>

<p>He said on Saturday that if Harris wins, it will be "the last election."</p>

<p>He also said the two assassination attempts against Trump prove he is ruffling feathers and upending the status quo.</p>

<p>The petition Musk is asking people to sign reads: "The First and Second Amendments guarantee freedom of speech and the right to bear arms. By signing below, I am pledging my support for the First and Second Amendments."</p>

<p>Attendees of Saturday's event had to sign the petition, which allows America PAC to garner contact details for more potential voters that it can work to get to the polls for Trump.</p>

<p>Musk, ranked by Forbes as the world's richest person, so far has supplied at least $75 million to America PAC, according to federal disclosures, making the group a crucial part of Trump's bid to regain the White House.</p>

<p>The entrepreneur behind carmaker Tesla and rocket and satellite venture SpaceX has increasingly supported Republican causes and this year became an outspoken Trump supporter.</p>

<p>Trump in turn has said if elected he would appoint Musk to head a government efficiency commission.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/83r3597g_donald-trumpelon-musk-reuters_625x300_19_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Elon Musk so far has supplied $75 million to America PAC, according to federal disclosures (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/87-killed-in-israels-attack-on-gaza-after-yahya-sinwars-killing-6834084]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[87 Killed In Israel's Attack On Gaza After Yahya Sinwar's Killing]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/87-killed-in-israels-attack-on-gaza-after-yahya-sinwars-killing-6834084]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 20 Oct 2024 22:32:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel said it hit Hezbollah's intelligence headquarters in its latest strikes on the Lebanese capital Beirut on Sunday, while officials in Gaza said rescuers were still recovering people from the rubble after an Israeli strike that killed dozens.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel said it hit Hezbollah's intelligence headquarters in its latest strikes on the Lebanese capital Beirut on Sunday, while officials in Gaza said rescuers were still recovering people from the rubble after an Israeli strike that killed dozens.</p>

<p>At least 87 people were dead or missing following the air strike on Beit Lahiya in northern Gaza late on Saturday, the health ministry in the Palestinian territory said, one of the highest death counts for months from a single attack. Israel said it was investigating reports of the incident.</p>

<p>It marked an intensification of Israel's offensives against Palestinian group Hamas in Gaza and Iran-backed Hezbollah in Lebanon, days after the killing of Hamas leader Yahya Sinwar raised hopes of an opening for ceasefire negotiations to end more than a year of conflict in the Middle East.</p>

<p>With US elections approaching, officials, diplomats and other sources in the region say Israel is seeking through military operations to try to shield its borders and ensure its rivals cannot regroup.</p>

<p>Israel is also preparing to retaliate for an Iranian missile barrage earlier this month, though Washington has pressed it not to strike Iranian energy facilities or nuclear sites.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said he was the subject of an assassination attempt by "Iran's proxy Hezbollah" on Saturday when a drone was directed at his holiday home. In a call with former US President Donald Trump, the prime minister reiterated that Israel would make decisions based on its own interests, according to a statement from Netanyahu's office.</p>

<p>Israel's government has spurned several attempts by the United States, its main ally and military backer, at brokering ceasefires in both Gaza and Lebanon.</p>

<p><strong>EVACUATION ORDERS</strong></p>

<p>In Gaza, the health ministry said rescue operations following the strike in Beit Lahiya were being hindered by communications problems and by ongoing Israeli military operations.</p>

<p>The strike came two weeks into a major assault around Jabalia, just south of Beit Lahiya, where Israel says its troops backed by tanks have been trying to root out remaining Hamas fighters.</p>

<p>Israel said the strike hit a Hamas target, questioning an earlier death count of 73 released by the Hamas media office.</p>

<p>As the fighting has continued, two of the three remaining hospitals in northern Gaza have been hit and patients, medical staff and displaced people injured, according to the United Nations. The UN has been urgently seeking access.</p>

<p>Israel says militants use civilian areas including schools and hospitals for cover, a charge Hamas denies.</p>

<p>Over 5,000 Palestinians left Jabalia via designated routes, Israeli military spokesperson Avichay Adraee said on social media platform X.</p>

<p>Evacuation orders have fuelled fears among many Palestinians that the operation is intended to clear them from northern Gaza to enable Israeli control of the area after the war.</p>

<p>Israel has denied this, saying it is trying to protect civilians and separate them from Hamas fighters.</p>

<p>Palestinians were also shocked by footage appearing to show a group of people in a street in Jabalia being hit by a strike as they approached to rescue someone who had already been hit. Reuters verified the location of the footage, but not the date. Israeli officials had no immediate comment.</p>

<p>The Israeli offensive, triggered by the Oct. 7, 2023 Hamas attack on Israel, has made most of Gaza's 2.3 million people homeless, caused widespread hunger and destroyed hospitals and schools.</p>

<p>"Horrifying scenes unfolding in Gaza, amidst conflict, relentless Israeli strikes &amp; an ever-worsening humanitarian crisis," UN Middle East peace envoy Tor Wennesland posted on X.</p>

<p><strong>BEIRUT STRIKES</strong></p>

<p>In Beirut, Israel said its air force had followed strikes on Saturday with an attack on Hezbollah's intelligence headquarters in the capital as well as an underground weapons workshop.</p>

<p>Fighter jets killed three Hezbollah commanders, the Israeli military said in a statement.</p>

<p>Reuters witnesses saw smoke rising from Beirut's southern suburbs, once a densely populated zone that also housed Hezbollah offices and underground installations.</p>

<p>Hezbollah made no immediate comment on the strikes, but said it had fired missiles at Israeli forces in Lebanon and at a base in northern Israel.</p>

<p>Cross-border fighting between Israel and Hezbollah erupted a year ago when the Iranian-backed group began launching rockets in support of Hamas.</p>

<p>At the start of October, Israel launched a ground assault inside Lebanon in an attempt to stabilise the border region for its citizens who had fled rocket attacks in northern Israel.</p>

<p>On Sunday in southern Lebanon, security and civil defence sources said two aid workers were killed in an Israeli strike on a house being used as a clinic, while the Lebanese military said three of its soldiers were killed in a strike on an army vehicle.</p>

<p>Over the last year, Lebanese officials estimate that more than 2,400 people have been killed and more than 1.2 million people displaced. Fifty-nine people have been killed in northern Israel and the occupied Golan Heights over the same period, say Israeli authorities.</p>

<p>Hamas-led militants killed some 1,200 people and took 250 hostages in the attack that sparked the war, according to Israeli tallies. Israel's military response in Gaza has left more than 42,500 people dead, Palestinian officials say.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/icbt1l1_gaza-reuters_625x300_20_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel-Gaza war has been going on since October 7, 2023 (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/millions-of-cubans-still-without-power-after-3rd-grid-failure-6833795]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Millions Of Cubans Still Without Power After 3rd Grid Failure]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/millions-of-cubans-still-without-power-after-3rd-grid-failure-6833795]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 20 Oct 2024 21:34:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Millions of Cubans awoke on Sunday to find their homes still without power after another partial grid failure overnight, deepening a crisis that has raised questions over the viability of the government's efforts to reestablish electrical service.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Millions of Cubans awoke on Sunday to find their homes still without power after another partial grid failure overnight, deepening a crisis that has raised questions over the viability of the government's efforts to reestablish electrical service.</p>

<p>The country's top electricity official, Lazaro Guerra, confirmed a partial grid collapse in the western provinces of Cuba, which includes Havana, late on Saturday.</p>

<p>Technicians were working to resolve the issue, Guerra said, but did not provide a timeline for when power would be restored to the region.</p>

<p>The capital of nearly two million residents appeared to be entirely without electricity early on Sunday, as many Cubans formed lines for subsidized rations and mulled the situation outside their homes.</p>

<p>State-run digital news outlet CubaDebate reported that the country's largest power plant, Antonio Guiteras, was back online Sunday and would begin contributing to a restoration of service over the course of the day.</p>

<p>A third grid failure late on Saturday marked a major setback in the government's efforts to quickly restore power to exhausted residents already suffering from severe shortages of food, medicine and fuel.</p>

<p>The clock was ticking as Hurricane Oscar bore down on northeastern Cuba early on Sunday, threatening to further complicate the government's plans to restore power.</p>

<p>Cuba's meteorological survey warned of "an extremely dangerous situation" in eastern Cuba. The entire region was largely without electricity or communication ahead of the storm, which packed winds as high as 100 miles per hour (161 kph) by midmorning Sunday.</p>

<p>Cuba's national electrical grid first crashed around midday on Friday after the island's largest power plant shut down, sowing chaos. The grid collapsed again on Saturday morning, state-run media reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>By early evening on Saturday, authorities reported some progress restoring power before announcing another partial grid collapse.</p>

<p>"The process of reestablishing the electrical system continues to be complex," Cuba's energy ministry said on X.</p>

<p><strong>RISING TENSIONS</strong></p>

<p>Reuters reporters witnessed two small protests overnight after a grid failure left Havana in the dark late Saturday, one on the outskirts of the capital in Marianao and the other in the more central Cuatro Caminos. Various videos of protests elsewhere in the capital began to crop up on social media late on Saturday, though Reuters was not able to verify their authenticity.</p>

<p>Internet traffic dropped off sharply in Cuba on Saturday, according to data from internet monitoring group NetBlocks, as vast power outages made it all but impossible for most island residents to charge phones and get online.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Network data show that Cuba remains largely offline as the island experiences a second nationwide power outage," Netblocks said on Saturday.</p>

<p>Even before the grid failures, a dire electricity shortfall on Friday had forced Cuba's Communist-run government to send non-essential state workers home and cancel school as it sought to conserve fuel.</p>

<p>The government has blamed weeks of worsening blackouts - as long as 10 to 20 hours a day across much of the island - on deteriorating infrastructure, fuel shortages and rising demand.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Cuba also blames the US trade embargo, as well as sanctions instituted by then-President Donald Trump, for ongoing difficulties in acquiring fuel and spare parts to operate and maintain its oil-fired plants.</p>

<p>The US has denied any role in the grid failures.</p>

<p>Cuba produces little of its own crude oil. Fuel deliveries to the island have dropped significantly this year as Venezuela, Russia and Mexico, once important suppliers, have reduced their exports to Cuba.</p>

<p>Ally Venezuela slashed by half its deliveries of subsidized fuel to Cuba this year, forcing the island to search for more costly oil on the spot market. &nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/fhttkrmo_cuba-power-outage_625x300_20_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Cuba's national electrical grid first crashed around midday on Friday]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-to-address-backlog-of-modern-slavery-cases-amid-50-million-globally-trapped-6832670]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK To Address Backlog Of Modern Slavery Cases Amid 50 Million Trapped]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-to-address-backlog-of-modern-slavery-cases-amid-50-million-globally-trapped-6832670]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 20 Oct 2024 18:14:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The UK Government has announced the recruitment of 200 additional Home Office staff to address a backlog of 23,300 modern slavery cases inherited from the previous administration.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Government of the United Kingdom has recruited 200 additional Home Office staff to clear a backlog of 23,300 modern slavery cases left by the last government. The cases could be "eliminated" within two years, according to an official statement. This step will be giving thousands of women, men, and children who may have suffered traumatic sexual, physical, and economic abuse the clarity needed to assist with their recovery.</p>

<p>According to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/modern-slavery-victims-to-be-supported-in-fresh-measures#:~:text=For%20the%20first%20time%2C%20the,to%20assist%20with%20their%20recovery.">UK government,</a> currently, many victims face long delays in having their status as a victim of modern slavery confirmed through the national referral mechanism via a conclusive grounds decision. This can lead to prolonged uncertainty and mental health suffering.</p>

<p>"For too long, modern slavery survivors and the harrowing experiences they have lived through have not been given the attention and support they deserve," Minister for Safeguarding, Jess Phillips, said. "This is going to change. The actions I have announced today are a first step towards putting survivors first, eradicating the backlog of modern slavery cases to give victims the clarity and peace of mind they need to move on with their lives."</p>

<p>According to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ilo.org/resource/news/50-million-people-worldwide-modern-slavery-0">International Labour Organisation,</a> an estimated fifty million people were living in modern slavery as of 2021, based on the latest Global Estimates of Modern Slavery. Of this number, 28 million individuals were in forced labour, while 22 million were trapped in forced marriage.</p>

<p>The number of people in modern slavery has risen significantly in the last 10 years. 10 million more people were in modern slavery in 2021 compared to 2016 global estimates. Women and children remain disproportionately vulnerable.</p>

<p>Modern slavery occurs in almost every country in the world and cuts across ethnic, cultural, and religious lines. More than half (52 percent) of all forced labour and a quarter of all forced marriages can be found in upper-middle-income or high-income countries.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/23mproco_modern-slavery_625x300_20_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The average wait for a conclusive decision is more than 500 days.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/maggots-slime-and-disease-worlds-dirtiest-cruise-ships-named-and-shamed-6832109]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Maggots, Slime, And Disease": World's Dirtiest Ships Named And Shamed]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/maggots-slime-and-disease-worlds-dirtiest-cruise-ships-named-and-shamed-6832109]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 20 Oct 2024 16:38:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Center for Disease Control (CDC) has revealed the top 10 filthiest cruise ships of 2024 after health officials randomly inspected 114 different ships.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Centres for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), the national public health agency of the United States, has released a troubling list of the top 10 dirtiest cruise ships of 2024, based on health inspections carried out on 114 vessels.</p>

<p>The <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://wwwn.cdc.gov/inspectionquerytool/inspectionsearch.aspx">results showed unhygienic conditions</a> with sludge, maggots, and other health risks. It was discovered that these ships, which were intended to provide tourists with a relaxing escape, had severe hygiene problems that can cause disease outbreaks.</p>

<p>When making a cruise reservation, the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.cdc.gov/vessel-sanitation/site.html#gen">CDC</a> advises guests to review the health inspection record of the ship. In order to protect travellers' safety and wellbeing and avoid any unpleasant shocks while on vacation, these inspections are crucial.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/viral-video-indian-origin-man-faces-hate-in-canada-told-to-return-to-india-6831667#pfrom=home-ndtv_lateststories"><strong>Also Read: Indian-Origin Man Faces Hate In Canada, Told To 'Return To India'</strong></a></p>

<p>The findings of the CDC's Vessel Sanitation Program, which rates cruise ships on a scale of 0 to 100 for cleanliness in an effort to prevent gastrointestinal illnesses, were released. Of these, 10 ships scored worse than 89. A score of 85 or lower is considered "not satisfactory," according to the organisation.</p>

<p>According to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.cdc.gov/vessel-sanitation/about/index.html"><em>CDC,</em></a> travelling on cruise ships exposes people to new environments and high volumes of people, including other ravelers. This exposure can create the risk for illness from contaminated food or water or, more commonly, through person-to-person contact. The agency helps the cruise ship industry prevent and control gastrointestinal (GI) illnesses on cruise ships.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/uqpe2hb_hanseatic-inspiration_625x300_20_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The CDC urges travelers to check a ship's health inspection history before booking a cruise.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/from-comedian-to-president-of-ukraine-all-about-volodymyr-zelenskyy-6831990]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[From Comedian To President Of Ukraine: All About Volodymyr Zelenskyy]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/from-comedian-to-president-of-ukraine-all-about-volodymyr-zelenskyy-6831990]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 20 Oct 2024 16:22:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ukraine President Volodymyr Zelenskyy is actively seeking support from Western allies for his "Victory Plan," which aims to end the ongoing war with Russia.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ukraine President Volodymyr Zelenskyy is actively seeking support from Western allies for his "Victory Plan," which aims to end the ongoing war with Russia. Central to this plan is Ukraine's desire to become NATO's 33rd member with continued arms shipments for security guarantees. The primary goal is to strengthen the nation and facilitate a diplomatic resolution to the conflict which began with Russia's invasion in 2022.</p>

<p>"Either Ukraine will have nuclear weapons and that will be our protection or we should have some sort of alliance. Apart from NATO, today we do not know any effective alliances," Zelenskyy <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cbwyuBGIIJs">said</a> at the European Council summit in Brussels on Thursday.</p>

<p>In response, Russian President Vladimir Putin issued a stern warning. "Any step in this direction will meet an adequate response," he said, claiming that "under no circumstances" would Russia allow such developments to happen.</p>

<p>Zelenskyy later clarified his remarks during a joint press conference with NATO chief Mark Rutte. "We are not building nuclear weapons. What I meant is that today, there is no stronger security guarantee for us than NATO membership," he said.</p>

<h2><strong>Who Is Volodymyr Zelenskyy?</strong></h2>

<p dir="ltr">Volodymyr Zelenskyy is the 6th President of Ukraine. The 45-year-old transitioned from a comedian and TV star to a politician who would go on to lead the nation in the war against Russia.</p>

<h2 dir="ltr"><strong>Early Life And Education</strong></h2>

<p>Born on January 25, 1978, in Kryvyi Rih, Ukraine, Volodymyr Oleksandrovytch Zelenskyy grew up in a Jewish family. Both his parents - Oleksandr Zelenskyy and Rymma Zelenska - are engineers.</p>

<p>Before starting elementary school, Volodymyr Zelenskyy lived for four years in Erdenet, Mongolia, where his father worked to help build a copper mine. Zelenskyy grew up speaking Russian.</p>

<p>Zelenskyy's early life was marked by a strong interest in comedy and acting. He graduated from the Kyiv National Economic University with a degree in law but pursued a career in entertainment instead.</p>

<h2><strong>Career in entertainment</strong></h2>

<p>Volodymyr Zelenskyy began his career in entertainment as an actor, scriptwriter, and producer for the stand-up comedy team KVARTAL 95 from 1997 to 2003. He then became the executive producer of KVARTAL 95, LLC until 2011, and served as Chief Executive at PJSC Inter TV Station from 2011 to 2012. He returned to KVARTAL 95 from 2013 to 2019, founding the NGO 'The League of Laughter' and producing 10 feature films, winning over 30 awards from Ukraine's National Television Award, <em>Teletriumph</em>.</p>

<p>Zelenskyy also supported the armed forces during the Donbas conflict by providing funds, equipment for soldiers. He gained fame for his role in the 2015 TV series <em>Servant of the People</em>, where he played a high school history teacher who becomes President of Ukraine. The show led to the creation of a political party of the same name in March 2018.</p>

<h2><strong>The Unlikely President&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p dir="ltr">In 2019, Volodymyr Zelenskyy announced his candidacy for the Ukrainian presidency. Despite being a political novice, he won the election with a landslide victory, securing 73 percent of the vote, against incumbent Petro Poroshenko. His campaign focused on anti-corruption, economic reform and Ukrainian nationalism.</p>

<h2 dir="ltr"><strong>Presidency</strong></h2>

<p>Volodymyr Zelenskyy was inaugurated as Ukraine's president on May 20, 2019. He is the first Jewish president of the country. He dissolved the parliament in his inaugural address, calling for early elections, but faced opposition from his coalition partner, the People's Front. On May 28, he restored the former president of Georgia, Mikheil Saakashvili's Ukrainian citizenship.</p>

<p>Zelenskyy's proposals to change the electoral system and reintroduce criminal liability for illegal enrichment were rejected by parliament. However, on September 3, he succeeded in stripping lawmakers of legal immunity, fulfilling a key campaign promise.</p>

<p>He cancelled the annual Kyiv Independence Day Parade in July 2019, redirecting funds to support veterans. In 2020, his party proposed reforms to media laws aimed at reducing oligarchs' influence but faced criticism for potential censorship.</p>

<p>Volodymyr Zelenskyy also focused on updating referendum laws, fulfilling another campaign promise, and introduced a bill to create a public registry of Ukraine's oligarchs, which passed in September 2021 despite concerns about consolidating presidential power.</p>

<h2 dir="ltr"><strong>Zelenskyy's Efforts To End The Donbas Conflict</strong></h2>

<p>The Donbas conflict began in 2014 when Russian-backed separatists seized parts of eastern Ukraine. Resolving this conflict was a key promise of Zelenskyy's campaign.</p>

<p>In June 2019, he appointed former President Leonid Kuchma for peace talks and spoke with Russian President Vladimir Putin to push for EU-mediated discussions and prisoner exchanges.</p>

<p>In October 2019, Volodymyr Zelenskyy proposed a deal to respect elections in Donbas if Russia withdrew troops, but the plan faced backlash from nationalists and critics. The agreement failed to reduce violence as separatists continued their attacks.</p>

<p>By December 2019, Zelenskyy resumed peace talks with Russia through the Normandy Format, with France and Germany as mediators. A ceasefire was declared in July 2020, but despite fewer violations, the conflict remained unresolved.</p>

<h2 dir="ltr"><strong>Controversies</strong></h2>

<p><strong>Trump-Ukraine Scandal:</strong> Volodymyr Zelenskyy found himself at the centre of the 2019 impeachment controversy involving then-US President Donald Trump. In a July 2019 phone call, Trump allegedly pressured Zelenskyy to investigate Joe Biden, a key political rival, in exchange for releasing military aid to Ukraine. Despite being drawn into the scandal, Zelenskyy maintained he faced no pressure from Trump. Trump supporters have alleged that Joe Biden used his influence to stop Ukraine from a criminal investigation that could have implicated Hunter Biden, the US President's son, who worked for an Ukrainian energy company. These were just allegations, though, and there was no evidence of any wrongdoing by Hunter Biden or of any move by Joe Biden to benefit his son.</p>

<p><strong>UIA Flight 752 Crash:</strong> In January 2020, Volodymyr Zelenskyy ended a trip to Oman early after the crash of Flight 752 in Iran. In January 2020, the plane was shot down by Iranian forces, killing all on board. Zelenskyy's administration faced criticism for not acting quickly enough to evacuate Ukrainian citizens from Iran.</p>

<h2 dir="ltr"><strong>Russia-Ukraine War</strong></h2>

<p>Volodymyr Zelenskyy has been at the forefront of Ukraine's resistance against Russia since the invasion began in February 2022. "Ukrainians are not ready to give away their land, to accept that these territories belong to Russia," he told CNN in 2023. "This is our land," he declared.</p>

<p>Zelenskyy has firmly rejected any territorial concessions, maintaining that Ukraine must retain its internationally recognised borders. He has also repeatedly advocated for Ukraine's membership in NATO, seeing it as crucial for long-term security.</p>

<p>Zelenskyy received strong backing from Turkish President Recep Tayyip Erdogan who said, "Without a doubt, Ukraine deserves to be in NATO."</p>

<p>NATO (North Atlantic Treaty Organisation) is a military alliance established in 1949 to provide collective defence against potential security threats. It follows an open-door policy, allowing any country to join if it meets the alliance's principles. It must be noted that any current member can block a new country's entry under NATO's accession rules.</p>

<h2 dir="ltr"><strong>Personal Life</strong></h2>

<p dir="ltr">Volodymyr Zelenskyy has been married to Olena Zelenska since 2003. They have two children together - Oleksandra (2004) and Kyrylo (2013).</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/kb55urb_zelensky-afp_625x300_20_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Volodymyr Zelenskyy is the 6th President of Ukraine.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/viral-video-indian-origin-man-faces-hate-in-canada-told-to-return-to-india-6831667]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Video: Indian-Origin Man Faces Hate In Canada, Told To 'Return To India']]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/viral-video-indian-origin-man-faces-hate-in-canada-told-to-return-to-india-6831667]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 20 Oct 2024 15:15:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Mr Annamalai expressed concerns about rising hate crimes against the Indian community, he also cited a report showing that the Waterloo region has the highest rate of police-reported hate crimes in Canada.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ashwin Annamalai, a Canadian citizen of Indian origin, has expressed concern about a "disturbing rise" in hate crimes against the country's Indian population.Rising worries coincide with the ongoing diplomatic level tensions between India and Canada. Mr Annamalai shared a video on microblogging website X, in which he is seen being the target of a racist outburst from a woman who wrongly assumed he was an Indian national. He described the experience as deeply unsettling, adding that such incidents are becoming increasingly frequent.</p>

<p>"The once welcoming community of Kitchener-Waterloo has seen a disturbing rise in hate, particularly against people of colour. Here's a personal account of what I experienced today: A random woman gave me the finger and spewed hate while I was out for a walk at Erb/Avondale. She wrongly assumed I am Indian and I must leave immediately. When I challenged her very politely, she went about her racist rants... She is also upset that there are black people in the community. She also accuses me of not speaking English and that I need to just leave," he wrote in the caption of the video.</p>

<p><strong>Watch the video here:</strong></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">She WRONGLY assumed I am Indian and I must leave immediately. When I challenge her very politely she went about her racist rants... She also is upset that there are black people in the community. She also accuses me of not speaking English &amp; that I need to just leave.</p>
— Ashwin Annamalai (@ignorantsapient) <a href="https://twitter.com/ignorantsapient/status/1846332817480835401?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 15, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p><br />
Mr Annamalai also shared a link of a news report from Canadian Broadcasting Corporation, which titled as Waterloo region has highest rate of police-reported hate crimes in Canada.</p>

<p>"This is not an isolated incident New data from Statistics Canada reveals that Waterloo region has the highest rate of police-reported hate crimes in Canada," he wrote in the comment thread.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/69e0fhr8_hate-crimes-in-canada_625x300_20_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The woman told Mr Annamalai to 'return to India.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/on-kamala-harriss-60th-birthday-donald-trump-to-visit-mcdonalds-store-to-mock-her-6831513]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[On Harris's 60th Birthday, Trump To Visit McDonald's Store To Mock Her]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/on-kamala-harriss-60th-birthday-donald-trump-to-visit-mcdonalds-store-to-mock-her-6831513]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 20 Oct 2024 14:46:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kamala Harris says she worked at a McDonald's when she was young but Donald Trump says he does not believe her.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Democrat Kamala Harris will kick off her 60th birthday on Sunday with two church visits in Georgia, where she plans to rally early voters, while her Republican rival, Donald Trump, spends time at a McDonald's fast food place in Pennsylvania.</p>

<p>Harris and Trump, who are essentially tied in the race for president in the most competitive states, have sharpened their attacks in recent days, while drumming up support for early votes by mail or in person with just 16 days left until the November 5 election.</p>

<p>After being joined on Saturday in Detroit by hometown rapper Lizzo and in Atlanta by pop icon Usher, Harris will get a birthday boost from another music legend, Stevie Wonder, on Sunday when he drops by one of the churches she plans to visit.</p>

<p>Vice President Harris and former President Trump, 78, are focusing on Pennsylvania, Michigan and a handful of other states likely to decide the election, where both parties have strong support and electoral results have been close in past cycles.</p>

<p>Harris and her running mate, Minnesota Governor Tim Walz, will double down on Sunday on a "Souls to the Polls" initiative aimed at using gospel performances, national and state faith leaders, elected officials and others to mobilize voters.</p>

<p>Harris, who was raised in the teachings of the Black church and sang in a church choir, will attend a service and speak at New Birth Missionary Baptist Church in Stonecrest, Georgia, about 30 miles (50 km) east of Atlanta, the campaign said.</p>

<p>She will also speak at Divine Faith Ministries International in Jonesboro, just south of Atlanta, where she plans to encourage worshippers to exercise their voting rights. Wonder will attend and is slated to perform.</p>

<p>After her events, Harris will record an interview with civil rights leader Al Sharpton that will air Sunday night on MSNBC.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Walz will attend service in Saginaw, Michigan, while his wife, Gwen Walz, will visit a church in Las Vegas.</p>

<p>Harris will need strong results in the majority non-white cities of Detroit and Atlanta and their surrounding suburbs to repeat President Joe Biden's 2020 wins in Michigan and Georgia.</p>

<p>Trump, after escalating personal attacks on Harris on Saturday, told Breitbart News he would work at a McDonald's restaurant in Pennsylvania on Sunday "just for fun" to mock Harris. Trump adviser Jason Miller said Trump would be working in the french fries area of the restaurant.</p>

<p>Harris says she worked at a McDonald's when she was young but Trump says he does not believe her.</p>

<p>Trump also plans a rally in Lancaster, Pennsylvania, in late afternoon.</p>

<p>The former president is seeking to take advantage of what he felt was an improved position for him in opinion polls that show a deadlocked race. Some voters already have mail-in ballots in Pennsylvania, the biggest prize on Election Day among battleground states.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/ou6o95ig_kamala-harris-donald-trump_625x300_20_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Harris and Trump are essentially tied in the race for president in the most competitive states]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hits-hezbollah-intelligence-hq-hamas-in-gaza-after-drone-launched-at-benjamin-netanyahu-home-6831469]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Hits Hezbollah Intelligence HQ After Drone Launched At Netanyahu Home]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hits-hezbollah-intelligence-hq-hamas-in-gaza-after-drone-launched-at-benjamin-netanyahu-home-6831469]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 20 Oct 2024 14:37:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The strikes on Hezbollah's south Beirut stronghold came after Benjamin Netanyahu accused the Iran-backed group of attempting to assassinate him by targeting his residence.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Fighting raged on two fronts Sunday as Israel targeted what it said was a Hezbollah "command centre" in the Lebanese capital, while in Gaza rescuers reported 73 people killed in a single air strike. The strikes on Hezbollah's south Beirut stronghold came after Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu accused the Iran-backed group of attempting to assassinate him by targeting his residence.</p>

<p>It also came as Israelis marked the major week-long Jewish holiday of Sukkot, which last year saw the October 7 Hamas attack that sparked the Gaza war.</p>

<p>Lebanon's official National News Agency (NNA) said Israel's strikes on Beirut hit a residential building in Haret Hreik near a mosque and a hospital.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said it hit a Hezbollah "command centre of Hezbollah's intelligence headquarters" and underground weapons facility in Beirut, and that it also killed three Hezbollah militants in other strikes.</p>

<p>It later said about 70 projectiles fired from Lebanon crossed into Israel within a matter of minutes, and that it intercepted some of them.</p>

<p>Gaza's civil defence agency meanwhile said an Israeli air strike on a residential area killed at least 73 Palestinians in Beit Lahia in the territory's north.</p>

<p>"Our civil defence crews recovered 73 martyrs and a large number of wounded as a result of the Israeli air force targeting a residential area... in Beit Lahia in northern Gaza," said civil defence agency spokesman Mahmud Bassal.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said it struck a "Hamas terror target". It added that the toll figures given by Gaza authorities "do not align" with the information it possessed.</p>

<p>The military pressed its offensives in both Gaza and Lebanon, where it said its forces "struck approximately 175 terror targets".</p>

<p>The military said it continued to operate in northern, central and southern parts of Gaza.</p>

<p>"The troops eliminated dozens of terrorists during close-quarter encounters on the ground and aerial strikes" across Gaza, it said.</p>

<h3><strong>'Grave mistake'</strong></h3>

<p>In southern Lebanon, NNA later said Israeli strikes had targeted dozens of locations, including the city of Nabatiyeh for the third time this week.</p>

<p>The military said it "struck and eliminated over 65 Hezbollah terrorists... and struck dozens of Hezbollah terror targets" in southern Lebanon.</p>

<p>On Saturday, Netanyahu's office said a drone was launched towards his residence in the central town of Caesarea but he and his wife were away and there were no casualties.</p>

<p>"The attempt by Iran's proxy Hezbollah to assassinate me and my wife today was a grave mistake," the prime minister said.</p>

<p>"Anyone who tries to harm Israel's citizens will pay a heavy price," he said in comments directed at Tehran and "its proxies", which include Lebanon's Hezbollah, a group Israel has been at war with since late September.</p>

<p>Since then, the war has killed at least 1,454 people in Lebanon, according to an AFP tally of Lebanese health ministry figures.</p>

<p>The Lebanese group, armed and financed by Iran, did not acknowledge the attack, but late on Saturday Iran's mission to the United Nations said "this action was taken" by Hezbollah.</p>

<p>Hezbollah on Saturday said it launched rocket barrages at Israel's north, where rescuers said one man was killed by shrapnel.</p>

<p>Hamas, Hezbollah and allied Iran-backed groups in the region have vowed to keep fighting after Israeli troops on Wednesday killed the Palestinian movement's leader Yahya Sinwar in Gaza, more than a year into the war triggered by Hamas's October 7, 2023 attack on Israel.</p>

<p>"Hamas is a reality in Palestine that no one can ignore, no one can destroy," Iranian Foreign Minister Abbas Araghchi said.</p>

<p>Israel has vowed to respond to Iran's October 1 attack, in which Tehran said it had fired 200 missiles at its arch-foe in response to the killing of an Iranian general and Hezbollah chief Hassan Nasrallah.</p>

<h3><strong>'Every day a massacre'</strong></h3>

<p>The war was sparked by the unprecedented Hamas attack last year that resulted in the deaths of 1,206 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally of official Israeli figures.</p>

<p>Israel's campaign to crush Hamas and bring back the hostages has killed 42,519 people in Gaza, mostly civilians, according to data from the health ministry in the Hamas-run territory, figures the UN considers reliable.</p>

<p>Israel, vowing to stop Hamas militants from regrouping in northern Gaza, launched a major air and ground assault on October 6, tightening its siege on the war-battered area and sending tens of thousands of people fleeing.</p>

<p>Civil defence spokesman Bassal said "we have recovered more than 400 martyrs from the various targeted areas in the northern Gaza Strip", including Jabalia and its refugee camp, since Israel's operation began.</p>

<p>Contacted by AFP, the Israeli military said it was looking into the civil defence agency's reports from Gaza, including that an overnight air raid on Jabalia killed 33 people.</p>

<p>"More than a year has passed, and every day our blood is shed," displaced Gazan Nasser Shaqura said outside a hospital in Deir el-Balah, where victims of an Israeli air strike were taken.</p>

<p>"Every day, every hour, there is a massacre," he said. "This is what our lives have become."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/dog51fe8_israel-hezbollah_625x300_20_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Lebanon's National News Agency said Israel's strikes on Beirut hit a residential building]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/ex-indian-spy-vikas-yadav-wanted-by-fbi-dismisses-khalistani-terrorist-gurpatwant-singh-pannun-murder-charge-6831387]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ex Indian Spy, Wanted By FBI, Dismisses Terrorist Murder Plot Charge]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/ex-indian-spy-vikas-yadav-wanted-by-fbi-dismisses-khalistani-terrorist-gurpatwant-singh-pannun-murder-charge-6831387]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 20 Oct 2024 14:23:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The US Department of Justice charged Vikash Yadav with leading an unsuccessful plot to murder Khalistani terrorist Gurpatwant Singh Pannun last year.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An Indian ex-official charged by the US with directing a murder-for-hire plot has dismissed the allegations, his family said, expressing shock that Vikash Yadav was wanted by the FBI. Yadav, 39, described the claims as false media reports when he spoke to his cousin, Avinash Yadav, the relative told Reuters on Saturday in their ancestral village about 100 km from Delhi.</p>

<p>The US Department of Justice charged Yadav with leading an unsuccessful plot to murder Khalistani terrorist <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ndtv-explains-gurpatwant-singh-pannun-murder-for-hire-case-ex-spy-vikash-yadav-drug-smuggler-nikhil-gupta-plot-to-kill-khalistani-terrorist-6816220">Gurpatwant Singh Pannun</a> last year. Yadav was an official of the Research and Analysis Wing spy service, according to the indictment unsealed on Thursday.</p>

<p>India, which has said it was investigating the allegations, said Yadav was no longer a government employee, without saying whether he had been an intelligence officer.</p>

<p>"The family has no information" about him working for the spy agency, Yadav's cousin said in the village of Pranpura in Haryana state. "He never mentioned anything about it," despite the two speaking to each other regularly.</p>

<p>"For us he is still working for the CRPF," the federal Central Reserve Police Force, which he joined in 2009, said Avinash Yadav, 28. "He told us he is deputy commandant" and was trained as a paratrooper.</p>

<p>The cousin said he did not know where Yadav was but that he lives with his wife and a daughter who was born last year.</p>

<p>Indian officials have not commented on Yadav's whereabouts. The Washington Post, citing American officials, reported on Thursday that Yadav was still in India and that the US was expected to seek his extradition.</p>

<p>His mother, Sudesh Yadav, 65, said she was still in shock. "What can I say? I do not know whether the U.S. government is telling the truth or not."</p>

<p>"He has been working for the country," she said.</p>

<p>The US accuses Yadav of directing another Indian citizen, Nikhil Gupta, who it alleges paid a hitman paid $15,000, to kill Pannun.</p>

<p>But in Pranpura, Yadav's cousin pointed to the family's modest, single-storey house, saying, "Where will so much money come from? Can you see any Audis and Mercedes lined up outside this house?"</p>

<p>Most of the village's nearly 500 families have traditionally sent young men to join the security forces, locals said.</p>

<p>Yadav's father, who died in 2007, was an officer with India's border force till he died in 2007, and his brother works with the police in Haryana, said Avinash Yadav.</p>

<p>Another cousin, Amit Yadav, 41, said <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ex-indian-spy-charged-in-us-over-alleged-khalistani-terrorist-murder-plot-report-6815072">Vikash Yadav</a> had been a quiet boy interested in books and athletics and was a national-level marksman.</p>

<p>"Only the government of India and Vikash know what has happened," he said, adding that Indian officials should inform them.</p>

<p>If the government "abandons" a paramilitary officer, Amit Yadav said, "then who will work for them?"</p>

<p>Avinash Yadav said: "We want the Indian government to support us, they should inform us what has happened. Otherwise where will we go?"</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/lkpopa6_vikas-yadav_625x300_20_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[India said Vikash Yadav was no longer a government employee]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-zealands-dunedin-airport-enforces-3-minute-limit-on-hugs-6831386]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[At This Airport, Goodbye Hugs Have A 'Time Limit'. CEO Explains Why]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-zealands-dunedin-airport-enforces-3-minute-limit-on-hugs-6831386]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 20 Oct 2024 14:23:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A New Zealand airport has stirred up a debate with its new policy aimed at reducing long farewells in the drop-off area.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A New Zealand airport has stirred up a debate with its new policy aimed at reducing long farewells in the drop-off area. A sign recently installed at the Dunedin airport, located in Momona, directs visitors to limit their goodbyes to just three minutes.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.facebook.com/photo/?fbid=10160658242793002&amp;set=gm.1356326512047955&amp;idorvanity=271625487184735">The sign</a>,&nbsp;which has gone viral on social media, has drawn sharp criticism from some users who deem the time limit "inhumane." However, others have praised it, with a few suggesting that similar measures should be adopted at other airports. Some users on a viral Facebook post expressed outrage at the restriction on hugs, while others were surprised that the airport still offers a free drop-off area, given the increasing charges and penalties.</p>

<p>Dunedin Airport's CEO, Daniel De Bono, addressed the issue in an interview with New Zealand's <a href="https://dunedinairport.co.nz/news/drop-off-faq/">RNZ</a> radio. He described airports as “emotional hotspots” and cited a study indicating that a 20-second hug is sufficient to trigger a release of the “love hormone,” oxytocin. He argued that keeping farewells brief allows more people the chance for their hugs.</p>

<p>The airport's car park, where Mr Bono acknowledged that “our team have seen interesting things go on...over the years,” provides 15 minutes of free parking for those who require a little more time to say their goodbyes. For those requiring more time, the airport has advised using the car park.</p>

<p>Commenting on changing the drop-off zone, Mr Bono said, "We've relocated the drop-off zone to improve traffic flow and safety around the terminal. By shifting it, we reduce congestion and make it easier for passengers to be dropped off safely."</p>

<p>Daniel De Bono addressed concerns about the drop-off zone being too far from check-in, explaining that the distance from the current drop-off area to the main terminal entrance is between 62 and 94 metres. He compared this to the previous temporary drop-off lane, which ranged from 50 to 168 metres, stating that the current location is, on average, 74 metres closer. He also mentioned that there is a covered walkway from the new drop-off area to the terminal, keeping passengers “protected from the elements.”</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/2qhl008g_new-zealand-airport-hug-rule-_625x300_20_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[This sign recently installed at the Dunedin airport, directing visitors to limit their goodbyes.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/israel-has-little-reason-to-end-its-war-on-gaza-even-with-yahya-sinwar-dead-6831240]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: Israel Has Little Reason To End Its War On Gaza - Even With Yahya Sinwar Dead]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/israel-has-little-reason-to-end-its-war-on-gaza-even-with-yahya-sinwar-dead-6831240]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 20 Oct 2024 13:57:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[With US elections just weeks away, Israeli PM Netanyahu understands that he would likely get a free pass, whether Trump becomes President or Kamala Harris.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/q461lp8_gaza_625x300_20_October_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>The death of Hamas chief Yahya Sinwar on Thursday, October 17, by the Israeli Defense Forces (IDF), is a watershed moment in the Israel-Hamas war that has raged on since October 7 last year.&nbsp;</p>

<p>A senior member of Hamas, Sinwar had taken over its leadership following the assassination of Hamas chief Ismail Haniyeh earlier this year in Tehran. Committed to Israel's destruction, he was the mastermind of the brutal Hamas attacks in October last year, which claimed the lives of over 1,200 Israelis, with more than 200 people taken hostage by the Hamas. Since then, Israeli reprisals have killed almost 42,000 Palestinians in the Gaza Strip, according to the Gaza Health Ministry. Meanwhile, Iran's proxy and ally on Israel's northern borders, the Hezbollah, began launching rocket attacks on Israel. In retaliation, since October 1 this year, Israel has been involved in full-scale military operations in Southern Lebanon and Beirut in a bid to create a buffer zone free of the Hezbollah's presence between Israel and Lebanon.</p>

<p>Following Sinwar's death, US President Joe Biden and European leaders have renewed calls for a ceasefire in the Gaza Strip. Biden said Sinwar's death was "an opportunity to seek a path to peace" in Gaza.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>The Two Aspects To Sinwar's Death</strong></h2>

<p>However, a ceasefire has proved elusive since Israel's operations in Gaza. All that has been made possible is a few “humanitarian pauses" to let aid reach the besieged people in Gaza. Israel has resisted all calls for a ceasefire, alleging that any such step would be exploited by the Hamas to regroup and remobilise. Shortly after Sinwar's death, Danny Danon, Israel's ambassador to the United Nations wrote on X: "Yesterday at the UN Security Council, many asked why we are still in Gaza a year after the October 7th atrocities. Today they got the answer. No terrorist is immune to the long arm of the IDF. We will not stop until we bring home all of our hostages and eliminate the Hamas monsters.”</p>

<p>There are two aspects to Sinwar's death. On the one hand, defence experts have pointed out that the pictures of the last moments leading to Sinwar's death show him sitting alone in a room above ground. The scene points to significant damage inflicted by the IDF on the numerous underground tunnels that the Hamas used. With the death of numerous high-profile leaders of both the Hamas and the Hezbollah, the organisations are in disarray. The former, especially, has been heavily dismantled. This factor alone may push its other members to surrender and release the 100-odd Israeli hostages still being held captive in the Strip.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Discussions between the US, Israel, the European Union, and Arab states have also revolved around a plan whereby post-war Gaza would see joint-Arab force.</p>

<h2><strong>The Question Of Hostages</strong></h2>

<p>Israel has turned Gaza into rubble. Even with 42,000 dead in the strip, even after a year of war, it has not been able to achieve one of its major objectives —the release of all hostages. While about 120-odd hostages have been freed—thanks to major back-channel efforts by Qatar, Egypt, and the US—a number of them died in captivity, while about 100-odd hostages are still with the Hamas.</p>

<p>On the other hand, the fact remains that high-profile assassinations like Sinwar's are not something new for the Hamas. Israel has a long history of carrying out such operations, and, if anything, the Hamas has only emerged militarily stronger, inflicting increasingly more brutal attacks on Israelis. The October 7 attacks were a culmination of this history,&nbsp;when Hamas launched multi-pronged strikes on Israel from land, sea, and air, carefully dodging all surveillance and air defence systems.&nbsp;&nbsp;launched multi-pronged strikes on Israel from land, sea, and air, carefully dodging all surveillance and air defence systems.&nbsp;, carefully dodging all surveillance and air defence systems. Many, including those inside Israel, have pointed out that the unprecedented destruction wrought by Israel in Gaza may just be what incentivises others to join the ranks of Hamas and continue its work.</p>

<p>Of course, Hamas has kept up the bravado up too. Sinwar's long-time deputy, Khalil al-Hayya, has said that Sinwar's death “will only increase the strength and resolve of Hamas and our resistance”. What is also interesting is that Fatah, the Hamas's arch-rival and which together with the rest of the Palestinian Liberation Organisation had promised to eschew any violence against Israel, has also officially released a statement mourning the death of "martyr Yahya Sinwar ". Hence, while the world would want nothing more for the hostages to be released and a ceasefire reached, whether it will actually happen remains anyone's guess.</p>

<h2><strong>Netanyahu's Quandary</strong></h2>

<p>Tellingly, Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu has also not committed to any ceasefire. "The war ... is not over yet. And it is difficult, and it exacts heavy prices from us,” Netanyahu said in a video statement after Sinwar's death. He also had a message for the Hamas: “Whoever lays down his weapon and returns our hostages—we will allow him to go on living.”&nbsp;</p>

<p>Indeed, Netanyahu would hope for this to happen. His war on Gaza has not exactly provided him the domestic support he had hoped for, with many in his own country opposing it. As long as the hostages from October 7 remain captive in Gaza, it would be seen as a failure. Besides, with hundreds of IDF soldiers dead and the economy taking an unprecedented hit, the war has taken a great toll on the Israeli people themselves. The conflict has significantly escalated with Israel's air and ground operations in Lebanon, which have killed more than 1,000 people and displaced many Lebanese civilians. After the death of Hezbollah chief Hassan Nasrallah, Iran launched a barrage of missiles directly at Israel, the second time it has done so this year. Israel has vowed to avenge this. And in another symbolic escalation, none other than Netanyahu's house was targeted in a Hezbollah drone strike.</p>

<h2><strong>Harris Or Trump, US Support May Continue</strong></h2>

<p>There is little incentive for Netanyahu's government to agree to a ceasefire now, when the IDF's successes in Lebanon and the deaths of those like Nasrallah and Sinwar are being hailed by the Israeli people as achievements after a year of opposition, which even saw calls for the government to resign.</p>

<p>More importantly, with US elections just weeks away, Netanyahu understands that he would likely get a free pass. No matter what US Vice President and Democrat Presidential candidate Kamala Harris's domestic compulsions may be, overall, there is unlikely to be any major opposition to Israel's wars. And in case Donald Trump and the Republicans form the next government, they are only expected to take a harsher stance against Iran. Marwan al-Muasher, Jordan's former foreign minister and now Vice-President for Studies at the U.S.-based Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, sums it up: "There is no reason for Netanyahu to stop his wars before the American elections."</p>

<p>Increasingly, it seems both Israel and Hamas, led by some unknown-to-us, apocalyptic vision, are fighting to the finish.</p>

<p><em>(Aditi Bhaduri is a journalist and political analyst. She has translated the works of Nicholas Roerich from Russian to English)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/b7mgppk8_israel_625x300_20_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-election-obama-harris-trump-you-would-be-worried-if-barack-obamas-grandpa-jibe-at-donald-trump-6831233]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["You Would Be Worried If...": Barack Obama's 'Grandpa' Jibe At Donald Trump]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-election-obama-harris-trump-you-would-be-worried-if-barack-obamas-grandpa-jibe-at-donald-trump-6831233]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 20 Oct 2024 13:56:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Addressing a public rally to build support for Democrat Presidential candidate Kamala Harris and her running mate Tim Walz, former US President Barack Obama today blasted Donald Trump, saying that the Republican candidate cares only about his ego]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Addressing a public rally to build support for Democrat Presidential candidate Kamala Harris and her running mate Tim Walz, former US President Barack Obama today blasted Donald Trump, saying that the Republican candidate cares only about "his ego, money and status".</p>

<p>"We are ready for President Kamala Harris. That's what we want and the good news is Kamala Harris is ready for the job. This is a leader who has spent her entire life fighting for people who need a champion. Somebody raised in the middle class, worked at McDonald's while she was in college just to pay her expenses, somebody who believes in the values that built this country. And she is as prepared for the job as any nominee for president has ever been," he said at the rally in Nevada, praising the 60-year-old leader who has earlier served as US vice president.</p>

<p>Praising the Democratic vice-president nominee, Obama said, "And in the White House, she (Harris) will have an outstanding partner in Governor Tim Walz of Minnesota. I love that guy. Tim's a veteran. He is a teacher, he is a football coach, he is a hunter. Been a great governor, working with Democrats and Republicans to get stuff done. And I just found out he can take vintage trucks apart and put them back together again. You think Donald Trump can do that?"</p>

<p>The former President then slipped in a reference to Jeeves -- the timeless valet character created by English author PG Wodehouse. "Do you think Donald Trump has ever changed a tyre in his life? If he gets a flat tyre, he calls Jeeves (and says) 'Jeeves, change that tyre'. The point is if you elect Kamala and Tim, they won't be focused on their problems. They are gonna be focused on your problems," he said.&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">.<a href="https://twitter.com/KamalaHarris?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@KamalaHarris</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/Tim_Walz?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Tim_Walz</a> are the leaders we need right now.<br />
<br />
Let's help them get elected: <a href="https://t.co/P9hoDajB1P">https://t.co/P9hoDajB1P</a> <a href="https://t.co/eXnJZPNbbp">pic.twitter.com/eXnJZPNbbp</a></p>
— Barack Obama (@BarackObama) <a href="https://twitter.com/BarackObama/status/1847857485631078629?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 20, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>The former President said the US had been grappling with price rise following the Covid pandemic.&nbsp;"We know this election is going to be tight and it's going to be tight because a lot of Americans are still struggling. As a country, we have been through a lot over these last few years. We had a pandemic that wreaked havoc on businesses and communities and then the disruptions from the pandemic caused price hikes and that put a strain on family budgets... So I get why people are looking to shake things up. It's understandable. What I cannot understand is why anybody would think that Donald Trump will shake things up in a way that is good for people because there is absolutely no evidence that this man thinks about anybody but himself," he said.</p>

<p>"I have said it before and I am gonna say it again, Donald Trump is a 78-year-old billionaire who has not stopped whining about his problem since he rode down that golden escalator nine years ago. He is constantly complaining, and when he is not complaining, he is trying to sell you stuff," he said.</p>

<p>"He is trying to sell you a Trump Bible. He's got his name right next to Matthew and Luke. And I will give you one guess where those bibles are made -- in China. This is Mr Tough Guy on China except when he can make a few bucks... And the reason he is doing it is because all he cares about is his ego, money and his status. He is not thinking about you. He sees power as nothing more than a means to meet his ends. He wants the middle class to pay the price for another huge tax cut, to help mostly him and his country club buddies," he added.</p>

<p>Obama said Trump wants the US to be hopelessly divided between "us and them". "Between 'real Americans' who obviously support him and anybody who doesn't because having people divided and angry and resentful and full of grievance boosts his chances of being elected," he said.</p>

<p>"You would be worried if your grandfather started acting like this. You would call up your brother, cousins and ask, 'have you seen grandpa lately? what do we do?' But this is coming from somebody who wants unchecked power, wants the most powerful office on Earth. We don't need to see what an older, loonier Donald Trump looks like with no guardrails. America is ready to turn the page. We are ready for a better story," Obama said.</p>

<p>The age reference is significant against the backdrop of the Democrats choosing Harris as their candidate after incumbent President Joe Biden, who was under age scrutiny, opted out of the race. The change has tilted the balance in favour of the Democrats.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">When it comes to the economy, Donald Trump plans to give another massive tax cut to billionaires and big corporations.<br />
<br />
We need leaders like <a href="https://twitter.com/KamalaHarris?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@KamalaHarris</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/Tim_Walz?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Tim_Walz</a> who will work to lower costs for Americans and hold corporations accountable. <a href="https://t.co/d89Um8w5lh">https://t.co/d89Um8w5lh</a> <a href="https://t.co/hTCD9vBYeo">pic.twitter.com/hTCD9vBYeo</a></p>
— Barack Obama (@BarackObama) <a href="https://twitter.com/BarackObama/status/1847846978853470646?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 20, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>Obama said Trump plans to give a massive tax cut to billionaires and big corporations. "I remember the economy when he first came into office, the first two years were pretty good. Yeah, it was good because it was my economy," he said to loud cheers.</p>

<p>"Some of you remember what it was like in Nevada when I came into office. The worst financial crisis in history, the housing market collapsed here in Nevada. I spent eight years cleaning up that mess that the Republicans had left me. And then I handed over to Donald Trump, 75 straight months of job growth and all he did with it was give a tax cut to people who didn't need it, drove up the deficit in the process and now he wants to do it all over again."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/dol48qm_obama-afp_625x300_20_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Former US President Barack Obama was addressing a rally in Nevada]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rare-us-constitution-copy-from-1787-fetches-over-11-million-at-auction-6830918]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Rare US Constitution Copy From 1787 Fetches Over $11 Million At Auction]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rare-us-constitution-copy-from-1787-fetches-over-11-million-at-auction-6830918]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 20 Oct 2024 12:56:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A rare copy of the United States Constitution, printed after the 1787 Constitutional Convention, has sold for more than $11 million during a live auction in Asheville, North Carolina, on Thursday evening.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A rare copy of the United States Constitution, printed after the 1787 Constitutional Convention, has sold for more than $11 million during a live auction in Asheville, North Carolina, on Thursday evening.</p>

<p>The auction, conducted by Brunk Auctions, ended with a final bid of $9 million, excluding a 23 per cent buyer's premium and undisclosed taxes. The identity of the buyer remains confidential as of now. The bidding of this rare copy commenced at $1.1 million and escalated fast, reaching the final bid within a period of a brief seven minutes. NBC Los Angeles reported that there were 62 bids in total.</p>

<p>The Constitutional Convention, which took place in Philadelphia from May to September 1787, was a pivotal moment in American history. Initially assembled to amend the Articles of Confederation, the need for a new framework of government due to the loopholes in the existing system was quickly pointed out. This resulted in a new constitution, which established a federal government with checks and balances among its branches. This document thus remains foundational to American democracy, making it all the more historically significant at an auction such as this one.</p>

<p>Nancy Zander, the director of external affairs for Brunk Auctions, described the sale as a "spectacular price" to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/19/us/us-constitution-copy-sold.html?smid=whatsapp-nytimes">The New York Times</a>. "It's really important that important things get strong prices," she said in an interview on Friday.</p>

<p>This copy of the Constitution was discovered two years ago in a filing cabinet at Hayes Farm in Edenton, North Carolina. The farm was owned by Samuel Johnston, the governor of North Carolina from 1787 to 1789. It is one of approximately 100 copies printed back then, with only eight or nine known remaining today.</p>

<p>In addition to the Constitution, other notable items sold at the auction included a painting of George Washington crossing the Delaware River, which fetched over $307,000, and a copy of the Articles of Confederation that sold for more than $1.2 million.</p>

<p>Seth Kaller, a historical document expert involved in the auction, said that while there were hopes for a sale price comparable to a previous record-setting sale in 2021-when another early Constitution copy sold for over $43 million- this outcome was anticipated due to differing market conditions this time. Kaller was also representing one of the bidders in this auction.</p>

<p>The auction was initially set up for September 28 but was postponed due to Hurricane Helene's impact on the neighbouring area. "It was not as celebratory as it would have been had we not had the terrible catastrophe around us," said Ms. Zander "But we were all together, appreciating the moment." &nbsp;Despite limited public attendance due to the storm, bidders allegedly also participated via phone calls.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/jufj2hf_rare-copy-us-constitution-_625x300_20_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[This copy of the Constitution was found 2 years ago in a filing cabinet at Hayes Farm North Carolina.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>