<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Tue, 01 Oct 2024 21:20:07 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/painting-found-by-junk-dealer-turns-out-to-be-an-original-picasso-worth-over-rs-50-crore-6694443]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Painting Found In Cellar Turns Out To Be Original Picasso Worth Rs 50 Crore]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/painting-found-by-junk-dealer-turns-out-to-be-an-original-picasso-worth-over-rs-50-crore-6694443]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 01 Oct 2024 20:55:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[It's believed that the portrait is of Dora Maar, a French photographer and painter who was Picasso's mistress and muse.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A junk dealer's discovery in a Capri cellar has turned out to be an original Picasso portrait. According to a <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2024/oct/01/painting-found-by-junk-dealer-in-cellar-is-original-picasso-experts-claim">Guardian</a></em> report, Luigi Lo Rosso found the painting in 1962, took it home to Pompeii, and hung it in his living room despite his wife's distaste for it. For decades, the painting remained a mystery, until Lo Rosso's son Andrea started researching art history and noticed the distinctive signature in the top left corner.&nbsp;The family then sought the advice of a team of experts, including a well-known art detective, Maurizio Seracini.&nbsp;Cinzia Altieri, a graphologist and member of the Arcadia Foundation's scientific committee, confirmed the painting's distorted style as classic Picasso. The art piece is now valued at 5 million pounds (Rs&nbsp;55,71,18,527).</p>

<p>''After all the other examinations of the painting were done, I was given the job of studying the signature. I worked on it for months, comparing it with some of his original works. There is no doubt that the signature is his. There was no evidence suggesting that it was false,'' Mr Altieri told the <em>Guardian.</em>&nbsp;</p>

<p>It's believed that the portrait is of Dora Maar, a French photographer and painter who was Picasso's mistress and muse.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Lo Ross died, but his son Andrea, who is 60 now, pursued his quest to discover the artist behind the painting.</p>

<p>''My father was from Capri and would collect junk to sell for next to nothing. He found the painting before I was even born and didn't have a clue who Picasso was. He wasn't a very cultured person. I kept telling my father it was similar, but he didn't understand. But as I grew up, I kept wondering,''&nbsp;Andrea Lo Rosso told The <em>Guardian.</em></p>

<p>Mr Rosso also revealed that his family considered disposing of the painting due to his mother's strong dislike. "She found it repulsive and repeatedly urged us to get rid of it," he added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>His quest to validate his father's discovery faced a significant hurdle when the Picasso Foundation in Málaga repeatedly dismissed his claims as false. Despite this setback, experts, including graphologist Cinzia Altieri, have now confirmed the painting's authenticity.</p>

<p>Notably, Picasso frequently visited Capri, where the painting was discovered, and the estimated creation period between 1930 and 1936 aligns with his stylistic evolution. Notably, Picasso created over 14,000 works during his lifetime, leaving room for unknown pieces to emerge.</p>

<p>The painting, now stored in a Milan vault, awaits official recognition from the Picasso Foundation.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/f1asd9c_picasso-painting_625x300_01_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The painting's distorted style is classic Picasso, and Italian experts have confirmed its authenticity.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-how-the-quad-faces-a-big-challenge-by-china-led-unnamed-bloc-6694211]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: How 'The Quad' Faces A Big Challenge By China-Led Unnamed Bloc]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-how-the-quad-faces-a-big-challenge-by-china-led-unnamed-bloc-6694211]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 01 Oct 2024 20:24:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Quad, a strategic security grouping which was formed to maintain peace, stability and freedom of navigation in the Indo-Pacific region, is facing a major challenge from an unofficial, unnamed alliance led by China.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Quad, a strategic security grouping which was formed to maintain peace, stability and freedom of navigation in the Indo-Pacific region, is facing a major challenge from an unofficial, unnamed alliance led by China, especially after the chronology of events in recent months leading up to, and beyond the latest Quad Summit in the United States.</p>

<p>The Quad, short for the Quadrilateral, is a group comprising India, the United States, Japan, and Australia. The grouping was formed with an aim to maintain security and freedom of navigation in the Indian Ocean and the Pacific Ocean. The Quad was first set up in 2007, but ceased to exist in 2008 following the withdrawal of Australia. The group was re-established in 2017 by Prime Minister Narendra Modi, then US President Donald Trump, then Japanese PM Shinzo Abe, and then Australian PM Malcolm Turnbull.</p>

<p>China, which considers the grouping a threat to its expansionist policies in the South China Sea, Indian Ocean and Pacific Ocean regions, is now leading an unofficial, unnamed group to counter the Quad. The group comprises of China, Russia, Iran and North Korea.</p>

<p>Russia, which is facing an isolation from the West, especially United States and most of Europe over the Ukraine war, finds itself in a situation where it is heavily dependant on China, both economically as well as supply of select weaponry. Iran and North Korea too, find itself under heavy US sanctions and find itself in depending significantly on China.</p>

<p>Beijing, which aims to replace the United States as the leading global power, is leading its assertive, aggressive and expansionist policies by leveraging the ally's which are dependant on it.</p>

<h2><strong>Here are the chronology of provocative events led by China to send a message to the Quad:</strong></h2>

<h3><strong>MESSAGE TO THE UNITED STATES</strong></h3>

<p>China launched an intercontinental ballistic missile (ICBM) from its territory deep into the Pacific Ocean on September 25, the first such test since 1980. The launch came days after the annual Quad Leaders' Summit was held in Delaware in the US. The ICBM can reportedly target any location in the US in less than 30 minutes.</p>

<p>Beijing has downplayed the incident calling the test - a first in 44 years - "routine".</p>

<p>China's Ministry of National Defence or MND said, "The People's Liberation Army Rocket Force (PLARF) launched an ICBM carrying a dummy warhead to the high seas in the Pacific Ocean at 08:44 on September 25th, and the missile fell into expected sea areas. This test launch is a routine arrangement in our annual training plan. It is in line with international law and international practice, and is not directed against any country or target."</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/ja1odglo_china-icbm-reuters-_625x300_01_October_24.jpeg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>The missile hit the desired target near the exclusive economic zone of French Polynesia, not far from the Marquesas Islands. China sent its Yuan Wang 5 tracking ship near the landing site to collect data. New Zealand described the ICBM test as an "unwelcome and concerning development". The US Air Force too deployed an RC-135S Cobra Ball aircraft to collect optical and electronic data on the missile and its warhead about halfway along its flight path.</p>

<p>The ICBM's desired target was 12,000km from the launch site. The distance between China's Hainan Island and Los Angeles in the US is just 12,100km. China therefore effectively demonstrated its ability to reach the US with this type of nuclear weapon in under 30 minutes. Beijing's newer DF-41 has an even longer range.</p>

<p>This latest provocative test came at a time of heightened tensions with neighbours like Japan, the Philippines and Taiwan.</p>

<p>Taiwan's Ministry of Foreign Affairs immediately tweeted, "PLA's 1st ICBM launch in 44 years exposes the regime's expansionist ambitions &amp; malign nature. Taiwan vehemently condemns the PRC for its reckless moves destabilising the region &amp; urges China to exercise restraint &amp; cease all actions that undermine global efforts for peace." This was more than a routine test. China was sending a signal, an intimidating one at that, Teipei said.</p>

<p>China has a 2009 agreement with Russia for each side to notify the other of ballistic missile launches, but so far China has rejected all such suggestions for a similar mechanism with the US.</p>

<h3><strong>MESSAGE TO JAPAN</strong></h3>

<p>On September 21 - the day that the Quad Summit was held in the US - China began joint naval exercises in the Sea of Japan. Russia's Pacific Fleet had said, "A joint detachment of warships of the Pacific Fleet and Chinese Navy set out from Vladivostok to conduct the joint Russian-Chinese "Beibu/Interaction - 2024" naval exercise," adding that the naval exercises will include anti-aircraft and anti-submarine weapons.</p>

<p>Two days into the joint naval exercise near Japan, Tokyo protested a major provocation by Moscow, when a Russian patrol aircraft entered Japan's airspace - not once, not twice, but three times. Japan's Defence Minister Minoru Kihara had said, "We confirmed today that a Russian Il-38 patrol aircraft has violated our airspace over our territorial waters north of Rebun Island, Hokkaido, on three occasions."</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Japan had scrambled its F-35 fighter jets to warn the Russian military. (Photo: Lockheed Martin)" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/i1j8rtds_f35-fighter-jet-f-35-lightning-ii-jet_625x300_01_October_24.jpg" title="Japan had scrambled its F-35 fighter jets to warn the Russian military. (Photo: Lockheed Martin)" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><em>Japan had scrambled its F-35 fighter jets to warn the Russian military. (Photo: Lockheed Martin)</em></p>
</div>

<p>Japan had scrambled its F-15 and F-35 fighter jets to warn the Russian military over radio during the first two airspace breaches. Finally the Japanese Air Force jets had to resort to firing flares when the third incursion happened. This even prompted Tokyo to call Moscow through diplomatic channels to ensure such provocation doesn't happen again. The Russian government has not commented on the air incursions.</p>

<p>A similar incident happened a month earlier, in August, when Japan had to fly out its air force jets when Chinese military aircraft entered its airspace. Tokyo had warned Beijing, calling it a "serious violation of our sovereignty."</p>

<p>The China-Russia joint naval drill was also the "largest of its kind for three decades," Vladimir Putin had said.</p>

<p>In the aftermath of these China-backed provocations, Japan, Australia and New Zealand sent a strong message to Beijing as their naval ships passed through the Taiwan Strait. JS Sazanami's, a destroyer of the Japan Maritime Self-Defense Force and a navel vessel each from Australia and New Zealand - the HMAS Sydney (DDG 42) and HMNZS Endeavour (A11) - transited the Strait of Taiwan. This was the first ever that such an incident by Japan, Australia and New Zealand took place.</p>

<p>China reportedly sent five of its naval ships to close proximity of the Australian and New Zealand ships and carried out surveillance activity.</p>

<p>With regard to the incident by Japan, Beijing issued a statement via its foreign office spokesperson, who said, "China's response to Japanese Maritime SDF vessel's passing through the Taiwan Strait: The Taiwan question is a red line that must not be crossed. Japan must honor its commitment and be prudent on this issue, and not create disturbance for China-Japan ties and cross-Strait peace."</p>

<h3><strong>CHALLENGE TO FREEDOM ON NAVIGATION IN INDIAN OCEAN</strong></h3>

<p>China, Russia and Iran have also increased their cooperation and activities in West Asia (Middle East). Last year, Beijing brokered a deal between Saudi Arabia and Iran, highlighting its presence in the Middle East. Both Beijing and Moscow have also condemned the killing of Iran-backed Hezbollah chief Hassan Nasrallah, in a stand against Israel.</p>

<p>Russia and Iran are also reportedly negotiating terms to arming Houthis in Yemen who are targeting merchant shipping vessels in and around the Red Sea and the Gulf of Aden. However, they are not targeting Chinese and Russian ships, reports suggest. With a rise in the number of attacks by Houthis, it poses a massive threat to freedom of navigation in the Indian Ocean.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Flames and smoke rise from an oil tanker which was attacked by Iran-backed Houthis in the Red Sea. (Photo: Reuters)" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/898n5gj8_houthis-target-merchant-ships-in-red-sea-reuters_625x300_01_October_24.jpg" title="Flames and smoke rise from an oil tanker which was attacked by Iran-backed Houthis in the Red Sea. (Photo: Reuters)" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><em>Flames and smoke rise from an oil tanker which was attacked by Iran-backed Houthis in the Red Sea. (Photo: Reuters)</em></p>
</div>

<p>Iran-backed and Yemen-based Houthi terrorists have attacked and hijacked ships in the region for many months, affecting the global trade and maritime operations. These incidents are on the rise amid Israel's ongoing war against Hamas and Hezbollah, both backed by Iran.</p>

<p>According to the US Maritime Administration, Houthis have launched over 50 attacks on shipping, resulting in casualties, vessel seizures, and disruptions to global trade routes. The campaign has forced shipping firms to seek alternative routes, impacting approximately 12 per cent of global trade that traverses the Red Sea.</p>

<h3><strong>THE NORTH KOREA THREAT</strong></h3>

<p>In the last few months, North Korea, which is reportedly backed by Beijing, has fired multiple ballistic missiles at the US, Japan and South Korea.</p>

<p>The projectiles were believed to have fallen into the sea. The development comes in the wake of North Korean leader Kim Jong Un seen inspecting a uranium enrichment facility in mid-September.</p>

<p>The US Indo-Pacific Command in statement said it was aware of Pyongyang's "ballistic missile launches and are consulting closely" with South Korea and Japan, as well as other regional allies and partners.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="(Photo Credit: Reuters)" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/oe9qbqdo_north-korea-missile-launcher-reuters_625x300_01_October_24.jpg" title="(Photo Credit: Reuters)" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><em>(Photo Credit: Reuters)</em></p>
</div>

<p>"The United States condemns these actions and calls on the DPRK to refrain from further unlawful and destabilizing acts. While we have assessed that this event does not pose an immediate threat to US personnel, or territory, or to our allies, we continue to monitor the situation," it said in a statement.</p>

<p>A New York Times report has said that US President Joe Biden had in March this year approved a classified document ordering US forces to prepare for possible coordinated nuclear confrontations with Russia, China and North Korea.</p>

<p>Amid these developments, Japanese Prime Minister Shigeru Ishiba has said that Japan faces its "most severe" regional security situation in the post-WWII era. "The security environment surrounding our country is the most severe since the end of World War II," he said last month in his first speech as prime minister.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2018-01/china-aircraft-carrier-afp_650x400_71516190344.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Recent events suggest that China is leading an unnamed bloc which poses a challenge to the Quad]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-preparing-to-imminently-launch-missile-attack-on-israel-us-official-6693783]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iran Preparing To 'Imminently' Launch Missile Attack On Israel: US Official]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-preparing-to-imminently-launch-missile-attack-on-israel-us-official-6693783]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 01 Oct 2024 19:24:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iran is preparing an imminent ballistic missile attack against Israel, the United States said on Tuesday, warning that any such assault would have "severe" consequences for Tehran.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Iran is preparing an imminent ballistic missile attack against Israel, the United States said on Tuesday, warning that any such assault would have "severe" consequences for Tehran.</p>

<p>The warning came as Israel said it had launched a ground offensive in Lebanon to target the Iran-backed militia Hezbollah, whose leader Hassan Nasrallah was killed in an Israeli air strike last week.</p>

<p>"The United States has indications that Iran is preparing to imminently launch a ballistic missile attack against Israel," a senior White House official told AFP on condition of anonymity.</p>

<p>"We are actively supporting defensive preparations to defend Israel against this attack."</p>

<p>The United States and other western allies stepped in to help defend Israel against a combined Iranian missile and drone attack in April, which Tehran launched in retaliation for an Israeli strike on the Iranian consulate in Damascus.</p>

<p>The US official added: "A direct military attack from Iran against Israel will carry severe consequences for Iran."</p>

<p>Iran has said that Nasrallah's killing would bring about Israel's "destruction," though the foreign ministry said Monday that Tehran would not deploy soldiers to confront Israel.</p>

<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu meanwhile issued a stark warning to Iran on Monday, saying there was "nowhere in the Middle East Israel cannot reach."</p>

<p>Netanyahu also said that a future "when Iran is finally free" would "come a lot sooner than people think".</p>

<p>An attack on Israel by Iran would gravely compound fears of a wider regional conflict that the United States and other world powers have said they want to avoid in the Middle East.</p>

<p>The United States has cautiously backed Israel's move to dismantle Hezbollah's ability to attack northern Israel, even as President Joe Biden has called for a ceasefire.</p>

<p>US Secretary of State Antony Blinken said that Washington was "tracking events in the Middle East very closely."</p>

<p>"The United States is committed to Israel's defense," Blinken said Tuesday morning while meeting his Moroccan counterpart Nasser Bourita at the State Department.</p>

<p>Washington said Monday that it was boosting its forces in the Middle East by a "few thousand" troops, by bringing in new units while extending others that are already there.</p>

<p>It was also deploying more fighter jets, the Pentagon said.</p>

<p>US Defense Secretary Lloyd Austin late Monday offered support to his Israeli counterpart Yoav Gallant for "dismantling attack infrastructure" belonging to Hezbollah along the border with Lebanon.</p>

<p>Hezbollah began low intensity strikes on Israeli troops a day after its Palestinian ally Hamas, which is also backed by Iran, staged its unprecedented attack on Israel on October 7, which triggered Israel's devastating assault on the Gaza Strip.</p>

<p>Cross-border fire from Israel and Hezbollah continued throughout Israel's war in Gaza.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-10/6e8i71v_missile-generic_650x400_17_October_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israeli Defence Minister Yoav Gallant has warned the fight was far from over.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hezbollah-ground-operation-have-been-carrying-out-raids-in-lebanon-for-months-israeli-military-6693462]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Have Been Carrying Out Raids In Lebanon For Months: Israeli Military]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hezbollah-ground-operation-have-been-carrying-out-raids-in-lebanon-for-months-israeli-military-6693462]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 01 Oct 2024 18:44:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli forces have been carrying out raids into southern Lebanon for months, uncovering Hezbollah tunnels and weapon caches under homes and uncovering invasion plans by the group, Israeli military spokesman Daniel Hagari said on Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli forces have been carrying out raids into southern Lebanon for months, uncovering Hezbollah tunnels and weapon caches under homes and uncovering invasion plans by the group, Israeli military spokesman Daniel Hagari said on Tuesday.</p>

<p>Hagari said the details were being declassified, hours after Israel announced a ground operation against the Iran-backed Hezbollah in southern Lebanon.</p>

<p>Dozens of such operations had uncovered detailed plans by Hezbollah to enter Israel and carry out an attack similar to the one led by the Palestinian Hamas in southern Israel on October 7 last year.</p>

<p>"Our soldiers entered Hezbollah's underground infrastructure; exposed Hezbollah's hidden weapons caches and seized and destroyed the weapons including advanced, Iranian-made weapons," Hagari said.</p>

<p>The findings and evidence discovered under homes in villages in southern Lebanon during the raids will be presented to the international community, Hagari said.</p>

<p>Hagari showed videos filmed on troops' body-cameras from what he said were Hezbollah tunnels under three Lebanese villages that lie across the border from three Israeli towns. The forces also found maps marking Israeli communities and army posts, he said.</p>

<p>"The operations that we de-classified tonight are only a small number of dozens of operations that we will reveal going forward, including the destruction of Hezbollah's strategic assets and capabilities," he said.</p>

<p>Hagari said that the ground raids would continue until tens of thousands of uprooted Israelis living near the border are able to return safely to their homes, but that the military's aim was to complete them as fast as they can.</p>

<p>"We're not going to Beirut. We're not going to the cities in southern Lebanon. We are focusing on the area of those villages next to our border," said Hagari.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/aisdake_lebanon-reuters_625x300_01_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Smoke billows in south Lebanon amid ongoing hostilities between Hezbollah and Israeli forces.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nepal-floods-anger-in-nepal-over-relief-delays-as-flood-kills-225-the-damage-is-done-6693086]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["The Damage Is Done": Anger In Nepal Over Relief Delays As Flood Kills 225]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nepal-floods-anger-in-nepal-over-relief-delays-as-flood-kills-225-the-damage-is-done-6693086]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 01 Oct 2024 17:58:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Survivors of the monsoon floods that ravaged Nepal at the weekend criticised the government on Tuesday for inadequate relief efforts during a disaster that killed at least 225 people.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Survivors of the monsoon floods that ravaged Nepal at the weekend criticised the government on Tuesday for inadequate relief efforts during a disaster that killed at least 225 people.</p>

<p>Deadly floods and landslides are common across South Asia during the monsoon season from June to September but experts say climate change is making them worse.</p>

<p>Entire neighbourhoods in the capital Kathmandu were inundated at the weekend, along with villages in remote pockets of the Himalayan country that were still awaiting relief efforts.</p>

<p>"There is no road, so no one has come," Mira KC, who lives in a village in Kavre district to Kathmandu's east, told AFP.</p>

<p>"Even if they do, those who died are dead already and the damage is done. All they will do is offer condolences, what will they do?"</p>

<p>The floods disproportionately hit Kathmandu's poorest residents living in haphazard slums along the banks of the Bagmati river and its tributaries, which run through the city.</p>

<p>Slum resident Man Kumar Rana Magar, 49, told AFP that authorities had provided shelter at a school for him and his neighbours after their homes were inundated.</p>

<p>However, he said they had been forced to leave before they were ready to return to their homes when the school reopened for classes.</p>

<p>"We are so close to the seat of the government. If they cannot take care of the poor this close, what will they do about others?" he said.</p>

<p>At least 225 people were killed in the floods, with another 24 still missing, according to police. More than 4,000 others were rescued.</p>

<p>Nepal's weather bureau said preliminary data showed 240 millimetres (9.4 inches) of rain fell in the 24 hours to Saturday morning, the biggest single-day downpour in more than two decades.</p>

<p><strong>'Precautions ignored'</strong></p>

<p>Experts said authorities did not prepare adequately for the disaster despite forecasts of intense storms.</p>

<p>"Precautions that should have been taken were ignored," climate expert Arun Bhakta Shrestha, of Kathmandu-based think tank International Centre for Integrated Mountain Development, told AFP.</p>

<p>Nepali disaster management expert Man Bahadur Thapa said gaps in coordination and resources had also hindered the rescue process.</p>

<p>"We could have saved a lot more lives if we prepared and built the capacity of our responders," he told AFP.</p>

<p>Prime Minister KP Sharma Oli was visiting the United States during the floods and was roundly criticised on social media for not cutting his trip short when the scale of the disaster became clear.</p>

<p>"At a sensitive time like this we all have to work together realistically, not criticise just for the sake of it," he told reporters on his return to Nepal on Monday.</p>

<p>Monsoon rains bring widespread death and destruction in the form of floods and landslides across South Asia every year.</p>

<p>Experts say climate change has worsened their frequency and intensity.</p>

<p>More than 300 people have been killed in rain-related disasters in Nepal this year.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/1lo7d8oo_nepal_625x300_30_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Entire neighbourhoods in the capital Kathmandu were inundated at the weekend.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/book-excerpts/book-excerpt-boastful-a-glimpse-into-masood-azhars-time-in-jail-in-india-6692943]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Book Excerpt | 'Boastful': How Terrorist Masood Azhar Spent His Time In Jail In India]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/book-excerpts/book-excerpt-boastful-a-glimpse-into-masood-azhars-time-in-jail-in-india-6692943]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 01 Oct 2024 17:40:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Mohananey also said that Masood was aware and boastful about his importance. He apparently claimed that when he landed at Heathrow Airport in London, a massive crowd of followers came to see him, resulting in a two-hour traffic jam.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/fjtaj3ro_masood-azhar_625x300_01_October_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p><em><strong>(The following is an excerpt from the book 'Inside the Terrifying World of Jaish-e-Mohammed' by Abhinav Pandya. The book examines the JeM's origins, ideology, organisational structure, financing, strategies, radicalisation methods and more.)</strong></em></p>

<p>After his arrest, it took the authorities some time to ascertain Masood Azhar's real identity for he was carrying a Portuguese passport. He was interrogated several times by the IB, R&amp;AW and the J&amp;K state police. Later, after five Western backpackers were kidnapped in Kashmir by Al Faran (a splinter group of the HuA) in a bid to release Masood, the FBI also interrogated him. In his interrogations, he displayed a mild and cooperative demeanour.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/86vseou8_masood-azhar_625x300_01_October_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>He gave the impression of a religious scholar and an intellectual. With his long experience in journalism, he was smooth in his interviews with the media too; however, he was not comfortable giving interviews to female journalists. He did not look into their eyes because it was deemed un-Islamic.</p>

<p>Chanchal Singh, the jail superintendent at Kot Bhalwal Jail at the time of Masood's release, said that he was treated like an ordinary terrorist. He was kept in a different cell, separate from HM terrorist Mushtaq Zargar and another Jaish militant Omar Saed Sheikh, his aides, who were also released with him. However, some officers suggest he was addressed as 'Azhar sahab' in the jail. Mostly, the jail staff say, he prayed in his cell and distributed small amulets (<em>taweez</em>) to jail inmates. Sometimes, visitors came to him for spiritual healing - looking for relief from their medical and family issues. It is believed that Masood began sermonising in jail and radicalised some of his fellow inmates.</p>

<h2><strong>When Masood Feigned Ignorance About Another Terrorist</strong></h2>

<p>Avinash Mohananey, a former Intelligence Bureau (IB) official who interrogated Masood, revealed that his initial confessions were about how Deobandi clerics inspired him. He said that Masood was very communicative and forthcoming in sharing knowledge about Pakistan's jihadi groups and their networks, including how they recruited terrorists, their training and the ISI's role. However, he feigned ignorance about Omar Saed Sheikh, who had already led a failed attempt, along with Ilyas Kashmiri, to get Masood released by kidnapping three British and one American national from Delhi in October 1994.</p>

<p>Delhi Police arrested Omar Saed Sheikh while Ilyas Kashmiri escaped, becoming one of the most lethal terrorists, masterminding Musharraf's assassination plot later. Omar Saed Sheikh's growing importance and popularity disturbed Masood's inflated ego. Mohananey says Masood feigned ignorance about Omar Saed Sheikh because he might not have actually known him. However, he might have also done it because of his expertise in the tradecraft of terrorism. He shared many generic things about the jihadi landscape but cleverly hid what mattered. During my own field research in Kashmir, I interviewed many militants and OGWs (overground workers), presently or formerly associated with terrorist groups. I found it a common tendency among them to be liberal in sharing generic information about jihadi organisations' clandestine worlds, which may impress a person who is not an insider. However, they never shared anything substantial about operational details.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>Why He Was Disappointed With Pak Organisation</strong></h2>

<p>Masood was highly disappointed with his organisation in Pakistan for providing him with a misleading picture of the ground realities in Kashmir that led to his arrest. He also severely criticised the returning mujahids, called '<em>ghazis</em>' (victors) in Pakistan, for narrating all kinds of false stories of how Kashmir was on the verge of freedom, and the Indian forces were demoralised and on the back foot. In his interrogations, he said, 'I had imagined an Afghanistan-like situation, where mujahideen groups created a liberated belt, and one could travel to and from Pakistan without much difficulty. On the contrary, I found <em>mujahideens </em>on the continuous run, avoiding security forces.'</p>

<p>Mohananey also said that Masood was aware and boastful about his importance. He apparently claimed that when he landed at Heathrow Airport in London, a massive crowd of followers came to see him, resulting in a two-hour traffic jam. Masood further said that he was too important for Pakistan and that India would not be able to keep him in prison for long. Masood knew that his ability to infuse a highly radical and violent jihadi fervour in Kashmir made him indispensable to the ISI. His ego was hurt when Al Faran, during the second kidnapping attempt (July 1995), demanded the release of HuJI chief Nasrullah Manzoor Langaryal, along with him, in exchange for four foreign nationals. He felt it eroded his stature and importance as Nasrallah was a mere 'foot soldier, a person of low intellect', in his view.</p>

<h2><strong>Why Relations Strained With Sajjad Afghani</strong></h2>

<p>Masood was unfit for a combat role ever since the beginning of his career as a mujahideen. He travelled by plane into India using a Portuguese passport because he could not cross into Kashmir from the snowy and mountainous LoC on foot. His physique stopped him from running away and therefore, he was arrested in Anantnag. Initially, after his arrest, Sajjad Afghani told the police that they had nothing to do with each other. However, Masood, not used to handling physical torture, gave away the identity of his colleague in thirty minutes - right after an army soldier slapped him. He allegedly said, 'My father had never slapped me, but for the first time, an army jawan did so even before asking me any question.' Their relations remained strained the entire time they were jailed together because Masood had revealed Sajjad's identity to the Indian Army.</p>

<p><em>[The author is the founder and CEO of Usanas Foundation, an India-based foreign policy and security think tank. He has authored two books, <strong>Radicalization in India: An Exploration (2019)</strong> and <strong>Terror Financing in Kashmir (2023)</strong>. The views expressed are the author's own. Subheadings and paragraph breaks added by NDTV for readers' ease.]</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal views of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/ellfio8g_masood-azhar_625x300_01_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nigerian-zookeeper-mauled-to-death-by-lion-after-leaving-safety-gate-open-during-feeding-6692506]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Nigerian Zookeeper Killed By Lion After Leaving Gate Open During Feeding]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nigerian-zookeeper-mauled-to-death-by-lion-after-leaving-safety-gate-open-during-feeding-6692506]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 01 Oct 2024 16:57:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A zookeeper in Nigeria was mauled to death by a lion after he failed to secure the locks on its enclosure when he went to feed it.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A zookeeper in Nigeria was mauled to death by a lion after he failed to secure the locks on its enclosure when he went to feed it. According to the <em>BBC</em>, the victim, identified as a 35-year-old man named Babaji Daule, worked at the Presidential Library Wildlife Park, owned by former Nigerian President Olusegun Obasanjo in Abeokuta. He was bitten in the neck on Saturday after agreeing to take guests into the enclosure even though they arrived after hours at the wildlife park.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The zookeeper, apparently, feeling comfortable with the animal, left the safety protection gate open and proceeded to feed the animal. He was mauled by the animal and died on the spot," the park management said in a statement, per the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c3e9zv1ypxko" rel="noindex, nofollow">outlet</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Separately, local police spokesperson Omolola Odutola said that the "lion inflicted serious fatal injuries to the man's neck". He said that the lion was shot dead "to release its grip on the handler".&nbsp;</p>

<p>"It is important to state that this activity fell completely outside the standard feeding routine of the park," the wildlife park stressed in its statement.</p>

<p>The police described the 35-year-old as a trained lion handler. It is not clear if Mr Daule had permission to take the guests into the closure when it was supposed to be closed. Either way, he "carelessly neglected to secure the locks and barricade the lion's enclosure before approaching the cage to feed the animal," Mr Odutola said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"This negligence allowed the lion to escape and attack the handler, resulting in fatal injuries to the handler's neck and eventual death. The wild lion was shot to release its grip on the handler," he added.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/marburg-virus-outbreak-in-rwanda-what-is-it-symptoms-cure-6681999">Explained: What Is Deadly Marburg Virus That Originates From Bats</a></strong></p>

<p>The management of the wildlife park expressed condolences to the deceased's family, and reassured the public of its commitment to ensuring the safety of its employees, visitors, and the animals themselves, the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/09/30/world-news/zookeeper-mauled-to-death-by-lion-while-feeding-it-after-hours/" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>New York Post</em></a> reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Meanwhile, this incident comes less than a year after another zookeeper was attacked and killed by a lion at the Obafemi Awolowo University, in Nigeria. Olabode Olawuyi was a veterinary technologist who had been taking care of the lions since they were born on campus about nine years ago. Tragically, in February, one of the male lions killed the man when he was feeding them. His colleagues tried to save him but by the time they could do anything, one of the lions had already fatally wounded him, the university said in a statement.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-01/6de0tlbo_asiatic-lion-generic-unsplash_625x300_20_January_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The man was bitten in the neck on Saturday. (Representative pic)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-targets-mossad-headquarters-military-base-near-tel-aviv-6692430]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hezbollah Targets Mossad Headquarters, Military Base Near Tel Aviv]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-targets-mossad-headquarters-military-base-near-tel-aviv-6692430]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 01 Oct 2024 16:49:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Lebanese militant group Hezbollah on Tuesday said it had targeted the Israeli military intelligence base of Glilot near Tel Aviv.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lebanese militant group Hezbollah on Tuesday said it had targeted the Israeli military intelligence base of Glilot near Tel Aviv.</p>

<p>The Iran-backed group "launched salvoes of Fadi 4 rockets at the Glilot base of the military intelligence's unit 8200 and the Mossad headquarters located on the outskirts of Tel Aviv," it said in a statement.</p>

<p>After an Israeli strike killed its leader Hassan Nasrallah in the Beirut suburbs on Friday, the group said it had dubbed the operation "at your service Nasrallah".</p>

<p>Nasrallah in late August said his group had launched a large-scale attack on Israel, targeting "the Glilot base -- the main Israeli military intelligence base".</p>

<p>The Israeli army said Hezbollah had failed to strike the installation at the time.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/dg8gh7pg_israel_625x300_01_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hezbollah has dubbed the operation "at your service Nasrallah". (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/naked-trump-statue-that-appeared-in-las-vegas-over-the-weekend-vanishes-mysteriously-6692287]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Naked Trump Statue That Appeared In Las Vegas Vanishes Mysteriously]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/naked-trump-statue-that-appeared-in-las-vegas-over-the-weekend-vanishes-mysteriously-6692287]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 01 Oct 2024 16:34:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The statue, made of foam over rebar and weighing around 6,000 pounds, was designed as a marionette with movable arms.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A massive 43-foot-tall naked statue of Donald Trump suddenly appeared alongside the Las Vegas Strip highway over the weekend, only to vanish just as mysteriously. This gigantic effigy, dubbed "Crooked and Obscene," was strategically placed on a plot of land off a highway in Nevada, about 28 miles away from the Trump International Hotel, the <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/09/30/us-news/pop-up-exhibit-43-foot-naked-nevada-trump-effigy-vanishes-after-roadside-ruckus/">New York Post</a></em> reported. Its location was near the highway connecting Las Vegas to Salt Lake City, but far enough from main traffic points, likely due to its explicit nature.</p>

<p>The statue, made of foam over rebar and weighing around 6,000 pounds, was designed as a marionette with movable arms.&nbsp;The identity of the person or group behind the provocative installation remains unknown, and the only clue is that the landowner is a trust registered in Las Vegas.</p>

<p>A spokesperson for the anonymous artist behind the work said the installation is "43ft tall, 10ft wide… weighs 6,000lbs, and is made of foam over rebar," adding that it intended to "ignite conversations".The statue was due to be removed by Monday night and will be moved to "key swing states," the spokesperson added.</p>

<p>The mysterious artwork has generated significant attention, with mixed reactions on social media ranging from amusement to outrage. Some conservatives condemned the display and accused it of inciting violence against the former president.</p>

<p>The Nevada unit of Trump's Republican party described the pop-up as an ''offensive marionette.'' In a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nevadagop.org/press-release-the-nevada-republican-party-strongly-condemns-the-deplorable-statue-of-president-donald-j-trump/">press release,</a> the party said, ''While families drive through Las Vegas, they are forced to view this offensive marionette, designed intentionally for shock value rather than meaningful dialogue. President Trump and Republicans are focused on delivering results that matter—reducing inflation, securing our borders, creating jobs, and ensuring a brighter future for all Americans. While Democrats, especially Kamala Harris, continue to prioritize shock value over substance. President Trump is the only candidate in this race standing up for working men and women across Nevada.''</p>

<p>Interestingly, this isn't the first time a naked Trump statue has made headlines. In 2016, several similar statues popped up in cities across the US, including New York, San Francisco, and Seattle. A baby blimp of Trump was also floated in London ahead of the 2020 election.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/bj26qs1o_trump-statue_625x300_01_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-lebanon-conflict-hassan-nasrallah-hezbollah-what-we-know-about-israels-ground-offensive-in-lebanon-6692016]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What We Know About Israel's Ground Offensive In Lebanon]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-lebanon-conflict-hassan-nasrallah-hezbollah-what-we-know-about-israels-ground-offensive-in-lebanon-6692016]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 01 Oct 2024 16:02:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel announced Tuesday it had launched a ground offensive targeting Hezbollah in southern Lebanon, days after killing its leader Hassan Nasrallah in an air strike on a bunker in Beirut.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel announced Tuesday it had launched a ground offensive targeting Hezbollah in southern Lebanon, days after killing its leader Hassan Nasrallah in an air strike on a bunker in Beirut.</p>

<p>Here is a rundown of what is known about Israel's ground operation so far.</p>

<p><strong>When did the offensive begin</strong></p>

<p>Late Monday, Israel's military began what it called "limited, localised and targeted raids" against Hezbollah in southern Lebanon's border areas.</p>

<p>Its ground forces are backed by fighter jets and artillery fire.</p>

<p>The military formally announced the start of the ground offensive hours after the United States said Israeli forces were conducting limited operations in Lebanon.</p>

<p>The military did not reveal how many soldiers were involved in the incursion, but said its 98th division - including paratroopers and commando units - was taking part.</p>

<p>The division had been previously deployed in the Gaza Strip, where Israeli forces continue to battle Palestinian militants led by Hamas.</p>

<p>On Monday evening, the military declared three areas along the northern border with Lebanon a "closed military zone", providing the first indication of a possible ground offensive.</p>

<p><strong>What are Israel's targets?</strong></p>

<p>The military said it was acting on "precise intelligence" targeting Hezbollah positions and infrastructure in southern Lebanon.</p>

<p>"These targets are located in villages close to the border and pose an immediate threat to Israeli communities in northern Israel," it said.</p>

<p>The ground assault comes after Israeli air strikes killed several top Hezbollah commanders in recent weeks, including Nasrallah on Friday.</p>

<p>"The elimination of Nasrallah is an important step, but it is not the final one," Defence Minister Yoav Gallant warned on Monday, hours before the offensive was announced.</p>

<p>"We will use all the means that may be required - your forces, other forces, from the air, from the sea, and on land," Gallant told soldiers in the north.</p>

<p><strong>What are Israel's goals?</strong></p>

<p>Since October 8, Hezbollah has been firing rockets from across the border, displacing more than 60,000 residents in northern Israel.</p>

<p>Hezbollah has said it was acting in solidarity with its Islamist ally Hamas in Gaza, following the unprecedented attack on Israel on October 7 that resulted in the deaths of 1,205 people on the Israeli side, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli figures.</p>

<p>The ensuing cross-border clashes have intensified in recent weeks.</p>

<p>While Israel engaged in fierce fighting with Hamas in Gaza, Gallant announced on September 18 that the "centre of gravity" of the war was now pivoting to the north.</p>

<p>"It was now time to ensure that those displaced from the north would be able to return to their homes," he said.</p>

<p>Other officials including Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu have repeatedly vowed to return those displaced back to their homes.</p>

<p>"We will continue to hit Hezbollah... the one who has a missile in his living room and a rocket in his home will not have a home," Netanyahu said in a statement last month.</p>

<p><strong>How has Hezbollah responded?</strong></p>

<p>Since the ground offensive began, Hezbollah has fired several rockets into Israel, with explosions heard in the commercial city of Tel Aviv on Tuesday.</p>

<p>A statement said it had "launched salvoes of Fadi 4 rockets at the Glilot base of the military intelligence's unit 8200 and the Mossad headquarters located on the outskirts of Tel Aviv".</p>

<p>Hezbollah said it also targeted Israeli troop movements in Metula in northern Israel "with artillery shells" and later a "gathering of enemy soldiers" in the same area with rockets.</p>

<p>Israeli troops in northern Israel's Avivim were also targeted, the group added.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/us4rjj2g_lebanon-reuters_625x300_01_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Smoke billows over southern Lebanon following an Israeli strike.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hawaii-sues-homeowner-after-his-beachfront-house-partially-falls-into-the-ocean-6692008]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hawaii Sues Homeowner After His Beachfront House Falls Into The Ocean]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hawaii-sues-homeowner-after-his-beachfront-house-partially-falls-into-the-ocean-6692008]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 01 Oct 2024 16:00:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Department of Land and Natural Resources (DLNR) Office of Conservation and Coastal Lands reported that waves destroyed the Haleiwa home, causing debris to fall onto state land and into the ocean.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The state of Hawaii has filed a lawsuit against a North Shore Oahu homeowner after his luxurious property partially collapsed into the ocean, the&nbsp;<em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/09/30/real-estate/hawaii-sues-homeowner-because-his-house-fell-into-the-ocean-despite-efforts-to-save-it/">New York Post</a> </em>reported. On September 25, 2024, the state filed a complaint for declaratory and injunctive relief against Josh VanEmmerik, seeking to hold them accountable for the damage.&nbsp;A shocking video circulating on social media shows the precarious state of the house, prompting widespread concern. In the footage, a voice can be heard warning onlookers, "Be careful where you're standing. The whole roof is gonna come down right now," highlighting the danger posed by the collapsing structure.&nbsp;Glass, metal and wood can be seen strewn across the sand as the waves pull debris into the sea.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Department of Land and Natural Resources (DLNR) Office of Conservation and Coastal Lands reported that waves destroyed the Haleiwa home, causing debris to fall onto state land and into the ocean. Officers responding to the scene found large parts of the structure on state land and debris washing into the sea.</p>

<p><strong>Watch the video here:</strong></p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DAUXMM7yuvG/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DAUXMM7yuvG/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DAUXMM7yuvG/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DAUXMM7yuvG/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by Father_Daughter_Account (@kevin_makana_emery)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p></p>

<p>''On September 24, 2024, large pieces of cement, wood, glass, electrical components, rebar, geotextile fabric, and other unidentified solid materials cover the State land spanning between the property boundary line and the ocean.&nbsp;&nbsp;An unknown quantity of solid material from the dwelling on Subject Property 2 entered the ocean and was taken away from the location due to the ocean's natural processes,'' the complaint reads.</p>

<p>Notably, VanEmmerik's beachfront property purchase in 2021 for $1 million came with a warning about erosion, which ultimately led to the house collapsing into the ocean. Despite the risks, he remodelled the property and listed it for $2.5 million, later reducing the price to $2 million.&nbsp;</p>

<p>''Private landowners take a risk when they allow structures to be so close to the shoreline. The people of Hawaii are now confronted with the consequences of property owners' failures to take heed of the ocean's warning signs of erosion,'' &nbsp;Deputy Attorney General&nbsp;Danica Swenson told&nbsp;<em><a data-link="native" href="https://www.hawaiinewsnow.com/2024/09/26/state-files-legal-action-against-homeowner-whose-house-partially-collapsed-into-ocean/">Hawaii News Now</a>.</em></p>

<p>This isn't the first time the property owner has faced issues with the state. Last year, they received a $110,000 penalty for "erosion control violations" related to sandbags placed at the residence.</p>

<p>Hawaii's coastal erosion problem has been an ongoing issue, with nearly a third of beachfront homes on O‘ahu's North Shore sitting precariously close to the shoreline. Many locals are frustrated with both VanEmmerik and the state government, accusing them of dragging their feet in addressing the erosion issue.<br />
&nbsp;</p>

<p></p>

<p></p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/0glr9tuo_hawaii-house_625x300_01_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A shocking video circulating on social media shows the precarious state of the house]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-media-chief-says-no-israeli-troops-have-entered-lebanon-6691977]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[No Israeli Troops Have Entered Lebanon, Says Hezbollah Media Chief]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-media-chief-says-no-israeli-troops-have-entered-lebanon-6691977]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 01 Oct 2024 15:59:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The head of Hezbollah's media office, Mohammad Afif, said on Tuesday that no Israeli troops have entered Lebanese territory, and warned that the group's strikes on Tel Aviv hours earlier were "only the beginning".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The head of Hezbollah's media office, Mohammad Afif, said on Tuesday that no Israeli troops have entered Lebanese territory, and warned that the group's strikes on Tel Aviv hours earlier were "only the beginning".</p>

<p>In a written statement to Reuters, Afif said Hezbollah had not engaged in "direct ground clashes" with Israeli troops, but that it would be ready to do so.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/vjsmbq1g_lebanon-airstrikes-afp_625x300_01_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hezbollah warned that the strikes on Tel Aviv were "only the beginning". (FILE)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-indian-american-billionaire-vinod-khoslas-heated-exchange-on-x-6691867]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk, Indian-American Billionaire Vinod Khosla's Heated Exchange On X]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-indian-american-billionaire-vinod-khoslas-heated-exchange-on-x-6691867]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 01 Oct 2024 15:43:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The argument stemmed from Khosla’s criticism of Javier Milei’s policies, much to the dismay of Musk, a vocal admirer of the Argentine leader.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Tesla CEO Elon Musk has targeted Indian-American billionaire Vinod Khosla in a sharp social media exchange. Musk called him “dumb” and disputed Khosla's claims about Argentina's economic state under its new conservative president, Javier Milei. The argument, which quickly went viral, stemmed from Khosla's criticism of Milei's policies, much to the dismay of Musk, a vocal admirer of the Argentinian leader.</p>

<p>Vinod Khosla posted on X, linking President Milei's austerity programme to economic downturns and likening it to former US President Donald Trump's policies. “Argentina's unemployment rate soars to 52% under Mileis dictatorial austerity program. Same will happen under @realDonaldTrump&nbsp; as he slashes spending. His tariffs will simultaneously increase inflation.” Khosla wrote, sharing a Financial Times article about Argentina's worsening poverty rate.</p>

<p>Musk, a strong supporter of Milei's libertarian approach, responded bluntly, calling Khosla “dumb” for what he probably deemed a misleading post.&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">You are dumb</p>
— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1839904894339236261?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 28, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>X's community notes also fact-checked Khosla's claims, pointing out that Argentina's unemployment rate had actually decreased to 7.6 per cent in the second quarter of 2024, down slightly from the previous period's 7.7 per cent – far from the 52 per cent unemployment figure Khosla cited.</p>

<p>The exchange escalated when another commenter questioned how Khosla could make such an outlandish claim, writing, “How did Khosla not think this through? A 52% unemployment rate is just absurd; it should have triggered something in his brain to say this doesn't seem right.”&nbsp;</p>

<p>Musk jumped in with a sarcastic reply, saying, “seriously.”</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Seriously</p>
— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1840180420203200948?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 29, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Vinod Khosla, refusing to back down, responded directly to Musk's post. &nbsp;“Poverty is gross underemployment. Too nuanced for macho brains to understand. My nuance vs. your outright posting of false pics? I get a community comment and yours didn't. I thought you were above this kind of bias at X,” Khosla fired back, accusing Musk of selective bias on the platform he now owns.&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Poverty is gross underemployment. Too nuanced for macho brains to understand. My nuance vs. your outright posting of false pics? I get a community comment and yours didn't. I thought you were above this kind of bias at X. <a href="https://t.co/roEVT9mxVI">https://t.co/roEVT9mxVI</a></p>
— Vinod Khosla (@vkhosla) <a href="https://twitter.com/vkhosla/status/1840505662062899547?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 29, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Meanwhile, a <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/09/27/business/argentina-poverty-rate-increase-50-percent/index.html">CNN report</a> noted that under President Milei, Argentina's poverty rate surged to nearly 53 per cent, the worst level in two decades. The country's economic challenges have left approximately 3.4 million more Argentinians living in poverty in 2024 alone.&nbsp;</p>

<p></p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/8sbhru18_vinod-khosla-elon-musk_625x300_25_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/cruise-on-which-everything-went-wrong-sets-sail-after-4-month-delay-6691369]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Cruise On Which "Everything Went Wrong" Sets Sail After 4-Month Delay]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/cruise-on-which-everything-went-wrong-sets-sail-after-4-month-delay-6691369]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 01 Oct 2024 14:37:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A luxury round-the-world cruise ship beset with technical delays and docked in rainy Belfast since May finally departed from the Northern Irish capital late Monday, prompting celebration among its passengers.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A luxury round-the-world cruise ship beset with technical delays and docked in rainy Belfast since May finally departed from the Northern Irish capital late Monday, prompting celebration among its passengers.</p>

<p>"We are going to have one heck of a time tonight, we are going to party like there's no tomorrow," beaming passenger Joe Martino told AFP before boarding.</p>

<p>The Odyssey residential cruise ship pulled out from Belfast harbour at 2240 GMT as passengers cheered on board.</p>

<p>But even Monday's departure was hit with yet another technical hiccup.</p>

<p>Dozens of passengers were left waiting in Belfast's cruise terminal beyond the scheduled boarding time as a last piece of required paperwork was held up.</p>

<p>After Mike Petersen, head of the US-based firm Villa Vie Residences that owns the Odyssey ship, at last, announced the green light for the ship's exit passengers shrieked with elation and hugged each other.</p>

<p>"The exhilaration of getting on that ship, when it takes off it will be the feeling of a lifetime," said Martino, 61, an actor from Chicago who spent the last four months waiting in Belfast.</p>

<p>Passenger Holly Hennessy, holding her cat named "Captain", said ecstatically: "I've been in Belfast for four months and two days, but hey, who's counting!"&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>'Everything went wrong'&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>The Odyssey was scheduled to set sail from the Northern Irish capital on May 30 on a three-and-a-half-year cruise.</p>

<p>But outfitting, certification processes and engine repairs all took much longer than expected.</p>

<p>"Everything that could go wrong went wrong," Martino said.</p>

<p>The ship had undergone repairs for engine trouble in drydock at Belfast's Harland &amp; Wolff, the famed shipyard where the doomed Titanic was built more than a hundred years ago.</p>

<p>Further delay was caused by the shipbuilder going into financial administration this month.</p>

<p>Passengers are able to either buy or rent long-term cabins on the so-called "residential" cruise ship, with the promise of unlimited voyages around the globe.</p>

<p>During the long wait, passengers could spend all day on board the ship but were not allowed to sleep there, so spent the nights in hotels or rented apartments instead.</p>

<p>Some decided to explore Northern Ireland, while others took the opportunity to travel in Europe or join other cruises while the Odyssey remained stuck.</p>

<p>They then flocked back to Belfast in recent days for the expected departure, which will see the ship head first to Brest, then Bilbao, the Azores, and across the Atlantic towards the Caribbean.</p>

<p>The floating town, which can accommodate around 600 passengers, is due to visit all seven continents with more than 425 stops in 147 destinations planned.</p>

<p>Port stays will last between two to seven days.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/icufdeog_belfast-cruise-afp-_625x300_01_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The ship had undergone repairs for engine trouble in drydock at Belfast's Harland & Wolff.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/school-bus-with-44-students-catches-fire-in-thailand-multiple-feared-dead-6691238]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[School Bus With 44 Students Catches Fire In Thailand, Multiple Feared Dead]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/school-bus-with-44-students-catches-fire-in-thailand-multiple-feared-dead-6691238]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 01 Oct 2024 14:19:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A devastating fire tore through a Thai bus carrying 44 students and teachers on a school trip Tuesday, officials said, with up to 25 feared dead.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A devastating fire tore through a Thai bus carrying 44 students and teachers on a school trip Tuesday, officials said, with up to 25 feared dead.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Paetongtarn Shinawatra said there were fatalities and offered condolences to the victims' families.</p>

<p>Transport minister Suriya Jungrungreangkit said the number of fatalities was not clear but 25 people were unaccounted for after the blaze.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Initial reports said there are 44 on board, 38 students and six teachers. As far as we know now, three teachers and 16 students got out," he told reporters.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"For those still missing, we are not clear yet."</p>

<p>The bus was carrying students from Uthai Thani province when a tyre burst on a highway in a northern Bangkok suburb, sending the vehicle crashing into a barrier, a rescue worker said in footage broadcast on local TV.</p>

<p>The bus was running on compressed gas and the crash ignited its fuel tanks, the rescue worker said.</p>

<p>Video footage from the scene showed flames engulfing the bus as it burned under an overpass, huge clouds of dense black smoke billowing into the sky.</p>

<p>"I have learned of the fire on a bus carrying students from Uthai Thani... resulting in deaths and injuries," Paetongtarn wrote on X, formerly Twitter.</p>

<p>"As a mother, I would like to express my deepest condolences to the families of the injured and deceased."</p>

<p>The blaze has been put out but rescue workers have had to wait for the bus to cool down before searching it for bodies, a rescue worker said.</p>

<p>Thailand has one of the worst road safety records in the world, with unsafe vehicles and poor driving contributing to the high annual death count.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/scpc0qao_thailand-school-fire-afp-_625x300_01_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The bus was running on compressed gas and the crash ignited its fuel tanks, said a rescue worker.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/wikileaks-founder-julian-assange-i-am-free-today-because-i-pleaded-guilty-to-journalism-julian-assange-6690953]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["I Am Free Today Because I Pleaded Guilty To Journalism": Julian Assange]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/wikileaks-founder-julian-assange-i-am-free-today-because-i-pleaded-guilty-to-journalism-julian-assange-6690953]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 01 Oct 2024 13:43:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Wikileaks founder Julian Assange on Tuesday said he was released after years of incarceration only because he had pleaded guilty to doing "journalism", which he described as a pillar of a free society.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Wikileaks founder Julian Assange on Tuesday said he was released after years of incarceration only because he had pleaded guilty to doing "journalism", which he described as a pillar of a free society.</p>

<p>Assange spent most of the last 14 years either holed up in the Ecuadoran embassy in London to avoid arrest or locked up at Belmarsh Prison in the British capital.</p>

<p>He was released from jail in June, after serving a sentence for publishing hundreds of thousands of confidential US government documents.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"I am not free today because the system worked. I am free today after years of incarceration because I pleaded guilty to journalism," Assange told the Council of Europe rights body at its Strasbourg headquarters in his first public comments since his release.</p>

<p>"I eventually chose freedom over unrealisable justice... justice for me is now precluded," Assange said, noting he had been facing a 175-year jail sentence.</p>

<p>Speaking calmly and flanked by his wife Stella who fought for his release, he added: "Journalism is not a crime, it is a pillar of a free and informed society."</p>

<p>"The fundamental issue is simple. Journalists should not be prosecuted for doing their jobs," said Assange.</p>

<p>The trove of confidential documents released by Wikileaks included searingly frank US State Department descriptions of foreign leaders, accounts of extrajudicial killings and intelligence gathering against allies.</p>

<p>Assange argued his case provided an insight into "how powerful intelligence organisations engage in transnational repression" against their foes, adding that this "cannot become the norm here."</p>

<h3><strong>'More impunity, more secrecy'&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>He said that during his incarceration "ground has been lost", regretting that he now sees "more impunity, more secrecy and more retaliation for telling the truth."</p>

<p>"Freedom of expression and all that flows from it is at a dark crossroads," he told the hearing of the legal committee of the Parliamentary Assembly of the Council of Europe (PACE).</p>

<p>"Let us all commit to doing our part to ensure the light of freedom never dims and the pursuit of truth will live on and the voices of many are not silenced by the interests of the few," he said.</p>

<p>Assange's case remains deeply contentious.</p>

<p>Supporters hail him as a champion of free speech and say he was persecuted by authorities and unfairly imprisoned. Detractors see him as a reckless blogger whose uncensored publication of ultra-sensitive documents put lives at risk and jeopardised US security.&nbsp;</p>

<p>US President Joe Biden, who is likely to issue some pardons before leaving office next January, has previously described Assange as a "terrorist".</p>

<p>Assange's timing and his choice of venue have puzzled some observers.</p>

<p>The Council of Europe brings together the 46 signatory states of the European Convention on Human Rights, with little say over Assange's legal fate.</p>

<p>Assange is still campaigning for a US presidential pardon for his conviction under the Espionage Act.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/u9mpnj2g_julian-assange-afp_625x300_01_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Julian Assange's case still remains deeply contentious (File).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-launches-icbm-into-pacific-china-missile-launch-china-launches-missile-deep-into-pacific-ocean-first-such-test-since-1980-6690690]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[China Launches Missile Deep Into Pacific Ocean, First Such Test Since 1980]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-launches-icbm-into-pacific-china-missile-launch-china-launches-missile-deep-into-pacific-ocean-first-such-test-since-1980-6690690]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 01 Oct 2024 13:04:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[China launched an intercontinental ballistic missile (ICBM) from its territory deep into the Pacific Ocean on September 25, the first such test since 1980.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>China launched an intercontinental ballistic missile (ICBM) from its territory deep into the Pacific Ocean on September 25, the first such test since 1980.</p>

<p>Beijing's explanation of this extremely rare event was perfunctory, with the Ministry of National Defence (MND) downplaying this hurling of a strategic weapon far across the Pacific. China's MND described the test thus: "The People's Liberation Army Rocket Force (PLARF) launched an ICBM carrying a dummy warhead to the high seas in the Pacific Ocean at 08:44 on September 25th, and the missile fell into expected sea areas. This test launch is a routine arrangement in our annual training plan. It is in line with international law and international practice, and is not directed against any country or target."</p>

<p>Of course, this ICBM launch was anything but "routine," for China has not conducted such a test for 44 years. So significant was the event that Beijing deemed it necessary to warn select nations in advance, including France and the USA.</p>

<p>Sabrina Singh, Pentagon deputy spokeswoman, acknowledged, "We did receive some advance notification of this ICBM test, and we believe that was a good thing. That was a step in the right direction, and it does lead to preventing any misperception or miscalculation."</p>

<p>Singh added that the USA had pressed China for "a more regular bilateral notification arrangement when it comes to ballistic missiles and space launches". She described this as "a common sense, confidence-building measure".</p>

<p>China has a 2009 agreement with Russia for each side to notify the other of ballistic missile launches, but so far China has rejected all American suggestions for such a mechanism.</p>

<p>Warned in advance, the US Air Force deployed an RC-135S Cobra Ball aircraft--one of only three existing to collect optical and electronic data on the missile and its warhead about halfway along its flight path. The USAF describes the RC-135 as "a national asset uniquely suited to provide America's leaders and defence community with vital information that cannot be obtained by any other source".</p>

<p>The missile splashed down near the exclusive economic zone of French Polynesia, not far from the Marquesas Islands. China had sent its Yuan Wang 5 tracking ship near the landing site to collect data. New Zealand described the ICBM test as an "unwelcome and concerning development". Indeed, nations like Australia, Japan and New Zealand asked China for an explanation.</p>

<p>Importantly, this test came precisely ten years after the DF-31AG achieved its first launch on 25 September 2014. Symbolism and dates are important to the PLA, and at that time the then-new missile used a lofted trajectory to limit its ground range. However, this latest provocative test came at a time of heightened tensions with neighbours like Japan, the Philippines and Taiwan.</p>

<p>Taiwan's Ministry of Foreign Affairs immediately tweeted, "PLA's 1st ICBM launch in 44 years exposes the regime's expansionist ambitions &amp; malign nature. Taiwan vehemently condemns the PRC for its reckless moves destabilising the region &amp; urges China to exercise restraint &amp; cease all actions that undermine global efforts for peace." This was more than a routine test. China was sending a signal, an intimidating one at that.</p>

<p>China launched this missile from a countryside site in the northern part of Hainan Island, a Chinese island sitting north of the South China Sea. The ICBM flew approximately 12,000km. It is most notable that the distance between Hainan Island and Los Angeles on the west coast of the USA is some 12,100km. China therefore effectively demonstrated its ability to reach the USA with this type of nuclear weapon, even though the newer DF-41 has an even longer range.</p>

<p>Decker Eveleth, an analyst at the American research organization CNA, explained further why China lobbed this missile in the direction it did. "Generally, the PLARF tests ICBMs from the interior of the country, out in the northern desert shooting east to west. This is satisfactory for most system tests (many missile tests are actually conducted to test a specific subsystem). The problem is that this forces you to use a lofted trajectory. The distance from the ICBM test site to the target ranges is around 2,000-3,000 kilometres, so China has to fire their ICBMs very high to compensate. That's maybe a quarter of an ICBM's actual range. That means, if the PLARF wanted to test a depressed trajectory, they're going to need to find another place to test their ICBMs--like the Pacific Ocean."</p>

<p>Eveleth also identified one possible reason why the missile was fired from Hainan: "Another reason you'd test like this is to test speed and the competence of your missile crews. Launching a missile is complicated, and there are a variety of tasks that, if you mess it up, that missile is going to miss the target, especially considering the ICBM they launched is almost certainly launched from a mobile launcher. By doing it out at Hainan and launching from a launch location the missile crew may be unfamiliar with, you can identify potential pitfalls in the process."</p>

<p>Eveleth said there is a precedent for this kind of end-to-end test, for China did something similar with a DF-2 in 1966. He said on that occasion the PLA's launch "was conducted partly to test the entire transportation and launch support infrastructure". He suggested it was possibly a "similar deal" on this latest occasion.</p>

<p>This was a complex operation for the PLARF, for it entailed transporting a massive HTF5980A 16x16 transporter-erector-launcher (TEL) plus support vehicles from the Chinese mainland across to Hainan Island. A photo circulating on the internet, and others of the launch itself released by the MND, showed that the missile was launched from an unprepared site. Such a procedure with minimal supporting infrastructure makes it much more difficult for an adversary to identify launch sites.</p>

<p>What kind of missile was it? Most analysts agree it was a DF-31AG, a type that publicly debuted in a parade in Beijing on 1 October 2019. The DF-31AG is externally very similar to the earlier DF-31A, suggesting the two ICBMs are not substantially different.</p>

<p>However, the latter uses a truck-and-trailer launcher unit, whereas the DF-31AG is more mobile on an eight-axle truck chassis. Eveleth published a PLARF order of battle in July 2023, where he described the DF-31AG thus: "It is unclear at this point what precisely the difference between the DF-31A and the DF-31AG is, besides the change in transporter and support equipment. PLA military newspapers mention that the AG has upgraded cabling, reducing the number of necessary cables and allowing for faster data transmission times. But what changes, if any, have been made to the missile itself, are still unknown."</p>

<p>The American researcher added, "The big, big thing they'd want to modernize is the guidance system, which still relies on an antiquated alignment system the US got rid of in the 1990s. As Chinese state media still talk about cable vans and alignment, the AG's guidance system has likely not been modernized. It's possible China is working on a new model that updates the guidance system that removes these problems."</p>

<p>The PLARF's 624 Missile Brigade is stationed in Hainan, but that unit possesses DF- 21D anti-ship ballistic missiles. In fact, the nearest DF-31AG unit to Hainan is 632 Brigade stationed in Shaoyang (27.2532°N, 111.3859°E). This is approximately 800km away from the Hainan launch site.</p>

<p>Eveleth, in his PLARF order of battle from 2023, estimated China had anywhere from 48-56 DF-31AG TELs. He listed the 621 Brigade in Yibin, the aforementioned 632 Brigade, 642 Brigade in Datong, 643 Brigade in Tianshui and the 664 Brigade in Xiangyang as units operating the DF-31AG.</p>

<p>In a report published by the Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists earlier this year, it estimated China had 64 DF-31AGs. The same document calculated that China currently fields a total of 438 nuclear warheads, plus another 62 warheads that have been produced but not operationalized. This assessment corresponds almost identically to the 500 warheads estimated by the Pentagon's 2023 report on China's military capabilities.</p>

<p>The Pentagon predicts the PLARF's nuclear warhead stockpile will reach 1,000 by 2030. Eveleth also predicted in his report that, by 2028, China will own more than 1,000 ballistic missile launchers. Of these, 507 will be nuclear-capable, 342-432 will be conventional missile launchers, and at least 252 dual-capable launchers.</p>

<p>However, Eveleth offered this opinion: "The most concerning change to China's nuclear forces is not actually the numerical expansion in launchers, but their apparent shift from a retaliation plan that imagined firing a salvo of nuclear missiles after an adversary had already completed an attack against the Chinese homeland to a posture of launch on warning (LOW). Under launch on warning, an incoming nuclear attack is detected in flight with satellites and ground-based radar, allowing a state to retaliate before the incoming missiles have struck their targets.</p>

<p>"China's developing LOW capability, combined with solid-fueled missile silos, means that they can quickly launch a nuclear attack at a moment's notice. A LOW posture presents new challenges in ensuring conventional conflicts stay conventional."</p>

<p>Senior Colonel Zhang Xiaogang, a Chinese MND spokesperson, said at a 26 September press conference, "China's nuclear policy is very stable, consistent and predictable. We strictly follow a nuclear policy of 'no first use' of nuclear weapons, and pursue a nuclear strategy of self-defence."</p>

<p>Zhang added, "We've promised not to use or threaten to use nuclear weapons against no-nuclear-weapon states or nuclear-weapon-free zones. China will continue to keep its nuclear capabilities at the minimum level required for national security."</p>

<p>Zhang further noted that "At present, there's a more stable momentum in the overall defence relationship between China and the US. The two militaries maintain high-level strategic communication, policy communication, institutionalised dialogues and exchanges in specialized fields. These engagements could help enhance mutual understanding, avoid miscalculation and manage and control risks."</p>

<p>China may well be hoping to solidify its international status as a global power boasting a world-class military. The USA routinely conducts long-range tests of ICBMs and submarine-launched ballistic missiles, so China is demonstrating that it can do so too.</p>

<p>Indeed, Beijing now seems unapologetic about conducting military activities that mirror American ones. Therefore, perhaps a pertinent question to ask is whether this latest test has set a precedent for beyond-border flight tests and whether China will continue to do the same in the future. In 2019-20, China launched multiple DF-21D and DF-26 missiles into the South China Sea. That episode might have been a portent for an ongoing practice of splashing missiles down in extraterritorial waters.</p>

<p>Another purpose for this test across the Pacific may relate to reassuring the Chinese people and demonstrating to the world of the credibility of the PLARF. The aforementioned Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists report noted, "The readiness of the Chinese nuclear missile force was challenged in early 2024 with the disclosure that a US intelligence assessment had found that corruption within the People's Liberation Army had led to an erosion of confidence in its overall capabilities, particularly when it comes to the Rocket Force."</p>

<p>Remember too that the PLARF was embroiled heavily in a corruption scandal that saw the force's top two leaders removed and prosecuted. The Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists report pointed out that "recent dismissals of top defence officials and widespread corruption might chill the Chinese leadership's willingness to arm missiles with warheads in peacetime."</p>

<p>The PLARF is a strategic force, but Chairman Xi Jinping has been ruing the lack of loyalty amongst its top leadership, and he was angered by the corruption that appears rife in the organisation. By demonstrating the ability to relocate a sophisticated ICBM and its launch apparatus from the mainland by sea, and by firing a missile thousands of kilometres at a distance sufficient to reach the USA, the PLARF has sharply demonstrated to Xi that this force is politically reliable and that it is combat ready.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/ja1odglo_china-icbm-reuters-_625x300_01_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[China has not conducted such a test for 44 years. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-limits-visibility-of-bold-font-posts-on-x-my-eyes-are-bleeding-6690355]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["My Eyes Are Bleeding": Elon Musk Limits Visibility Of Bold Font Posts On X]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-limits-visibility-of-bold-font-posts-on-x-my-eyes-are-bleeding-6690355]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 01 Oct 2024 12:50:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Elon Musk, the owner of X, has advised users of the social media platform to refrain from excessively using bold fonts in their posts.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Elon Musk, the owner of X, has advised users of the social media platform to refrain from excessively using bold fonts in their posts.</p>

<p>He stated that such posts would no longer be displayed prominently in the main timeline.</p>

<p>Musk highlighted that the bold font feature, intended to help users emphasise specific parts of their messages, can detract from the overall appeal of a post when overused.</p>

<p>He expressed his frustration in a post, saying, "You will have to click on post details to see anything in bold. My eyes are bleeding."</p>

<p>The change, effective immediately, means that any text formatted in bold will be hidden from direct view on the main feed.</p>

<p>Users will now need to click on individual posts to see the bold text. This update applies not only to web users but has recently been extended to those using the iOS and Android apps.</p>

<p>Previously, X only allowed bold and italic text formatting for web users, but the feature's expansion to mobile platforms has led to a notable increase in its usage.</p>

<p>This new rule has been announced to remind users about maintaining readability and aesthetic quality in their posts, ensuring that the platform remains user-friendly.</p>

<p>With this new rule, X aims to enhance the visual experience for its users and maintain the integrity of the platform's content.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/do8o3bco_elon-musk-reuters-_625x300_26_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Elon Musk stated that such posts would no longer be displayed prominently in the main timeline.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-man-who-failed-in-spanish-now-runs-a-language-school-in-spain-6689685]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Man Who Failed In Spanish Now Runs A Language School In Spain]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-man-who-failed-in-spanish-now-runs-a-language-school-in-spain-6689685]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 01 Oct 2024 12:44:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 36-year-old California man turned a short-term teaching stint in Spain's Mallorca into a successful new life, despite initially struggling with the language.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 36-year-old California man turned a short-term teaching stint in Spain's Mallorca into a successful new life, despite initially struggling with the language. Ted Purdom, who had difficulty with foreign languages in school, moved to the Balearic islands in 2011 as part of a nine-month programme to teach English. He planned to return to the US after the contract ended. However, what started as a short-term stay in Mallorca turned into a life-changing journey, both personally and professionally.</p>

<p>Mr Purdom, who hails from San Anselmo, California, always struggled with Spanish. “Foreign languages was always my most difficult subject,” he told CNN. “I failed second-year Spanish twice and the third time I was able to pass by the skin of my teeth.”&nbsp;</p>

<p>Despite this, a college exchange programme in Spain brought him to the Balearic Islands in 2009, where he spent three months immersed in Spanish culture. That initial visit left a mark, and a desire to return to Spain led him to apply for a programme that placed American “language coaches” in Spanish schools.&nbsp;</p>

<p>I had no teaching experience when I arrived, Mr Purdom admitted. But what started as a temporary gig grew into a full-time opportunity. “I decided to stay because the job opportunities in the US weren't great in 2013, so I felt another year wouldn't be such a bad idea,” he told CNN.</p>

<p>Over time, Mr Purdom integrated into Mallorcan society, learning not only Spanish but also Mallorquin, a Catalan dialect spoken locally. His language skills flourished, and he married a former student, Lluisa, in 2017. Together, they have a four-year-old daughter and are expecting their second child, as per CNN.</p>

<p>In 2017, Mr Purdom took a bold step, opening The Bridge English Academy in Manacor. “The business has grown, we have close to 200 students, beginning at seven years of age and all the way up to adults,” he explained. His background, he believes, helps him connect with students who struggle with language learning, as he once did. To make students more enthusiastic about a subject that some may not find the most interesting, he said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Mr Purdom plans to expand his academy and has recently purchased the office space next door. He also plans to increase the number of courses and enroll more students.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/4mpj6vrg_school-generic_625x300_04_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Ted Purdom, who hails from California, always struggled with Spanish. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/frank-gardner-disabled-uk-journalist-forced-to-crawl-on-flight-due-to-lack-of-wheelchair-6690472]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Disabled UK Journalist Forced To Crawl On Flight Due To Lack Of Wheelchair]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/frank-gardner-disabled-uk-journalist-forced-to-crawl-on-flight-due-to-lack-of-wheelchair-6690472]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 01 Oct 2024 12:44:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A British journalist, who lost his legs in a 2004 war reporting attack, faced a humiliating and discriminatory experience on a LOT Polish Airlines flight.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A British journalist, who lost his legs in a 2004 war reporting attack, faced a humiliating and discriminatory experience on a LOT Polish Airlines flight. Frank Gardner, returning from Warsaw, needed to use the toilet but was informed by the crew that the airline didn't provide onboard wheelchairs. With no alternative, he was forced to crawl across the cabin floor.</p>

<p>Frank Gardner, a seasoned correspondent for the BBC, shared his experience on X, expressing his frustration over the airline's lack of support for disabled passengers. "Wow. It's 2024 and I've just had to crawl along the floor of this LOT Polish airline to get to the toilet during a flight back from Warsaw as 'we don't have onboard wheelchairs. It's airline policy. If you're disabled and you can't walk, this is just discriminatory," he wrote.</p>

<p>Despite the shocking situation, Frank Gardner acknowledged the efforts of the cabin crew, who, he said, were "helpful and apologetic throughout" the ordeal. "Not their fault, it's the airline. Won't be flying A LOT again until they join the 21st century," he added.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">In fairness to the cabin crew, they were as helpful and apologetic as they could be. Not their fault, it's the airline. Won't be flying LOT again until they join the 21st century.</p>
— Frank Gardner (@FrankRGardner) <a href="https://twitter.com/FrankRGardner/status/1840869494224203872?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 30, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The incident sparked outrage on the internet.</p>

<p>“Good lord, Frank, that's horrendous. At least the crew did their best, but just astonishing that you had to crawl,” a user exclaimed.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">good lord, Frank, that's horrendous. At least the crew did their best, but just astonishing that you had to crawl.</p>
— Kate (@katebevan) <a href="https://twitter.com/katebevan/status/1840878760012218486?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 30, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Another wrote, “Absolutely DISGRACEFUL. So sorry, how can an airline in this day &amp; age can treat a disabled person like that? Beggars beyond belief!”</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Absolutely DISGRACEFUL. So sorry, how can an airline in this day &amp; age can treat a disabled person like that? Beggars beyond belief!</p>
— Snuggles (@Heather12379754) <a href="https://twitter.com/Heather12379754/status/1841001318141321520?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 1, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Someone suggested “getting a lawyer and pursuing them for a discrimination case under EU law.”</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Is that not a case of getting a lawyer and pursuing them for a discrimination case under EU law</p>
— Alan McIntosh (@Advice_Scotland) <a href="https://twitter.com/Advice_Scotland/status/1840890931706315002?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 30, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>“How hard would it be to have a fold up wheelchair? What if you had to evacuate the plane?” a comment read.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">How hard would it be to have a fold up wheelchair? What if you had to evacuate the plane?</p>
— Glyn-Oh behave! ???????????????????????????????????? 'Wabbit' ???? (@GlynisSpencer) <a href="https://twitter.com/GlynisSpencer/status/1840876184357478573?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 30, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Frank Gardner's career has taken him to some of the most dangerous parts of the world. In 2004, while covering a story in Riyadh, Saudi Arabia, he was ambushed by Al-Qaeda gunmen, resulting in the loss of his legs and partial paralysis.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/9u00m6i_disabled-uk-journalist-crawl-twitter_625x300_01_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The man expresded his frustration over the airline's lack of support for disabled passengers.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>