<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Nov 2024 23:59:33 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mob-vandalises-3-hindu-temples-in-bangladeshs-chattogram-7136805]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Mob Vandalises 3 Hindu Temples in Bangladesh's Chattogram]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mob-vandalises-3-hindu-temples-in-bangladeshs-chattogram-7136805]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Nov 2024 23:59:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Three Hindu temples were vandalised by a slogan-shouting mob on Friday in Bangladesh's Chattogram which has witnessed protests and violence since a former ISKCON member was booked under sedition charges.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Three Hindu temples were vandalised by a slogan-shouting mob on Friday in Bangladesh's Chattogram which has witnessed protests and violence since a former ISKCON member was booked under sedition charges.</p>

<p>The attack took place around 2:30 pm in the port city's Harish Chandra Munsef Lane, where the Shantaneshwari Matri Temple, the nearby Shoni Temple, and the Shantaneshwari Kalibari Temple were targeted, news portal BDNews24.com reported.</p>

<p>"A group of several hundred slogan-shouting people threw brickbats at the temples, damaging the Shoni Temple and the gates of the other two temples," the news portal quoted temple authorities as saying.</p>

<p>Kotwali Police Station chief Abdul Karim confirmed the attack, saying that assailants attempted to damage the temples.</p>

<p>Police, however, said the damage to the temples was minimal after the confrontation between the two sides, with both groups throwing brickbats at each other, it added.</p>

<p>Tapan Das, a permanent member of the Shantineshwari Main Temple management committee, told bdnews24.com: "A procession of hundreds arrived after the Juma prayers. They started shouting anti-Hindu and anti-ISKCON slogans." "We did not obstruct the attackers. When the situation worsened, we called the army, who arrived quickly and helped restore order. All the temple gates were closed before noon. The miscreants arrived unprovoked and carried out the attack," BDNews24.com said further quoting him.</p>

<p>Spiritual leader Chinmoy Krishna Das, a former member of International Society of Krishna Consciousness (ISKCON) of Bangladesh, was arrested in connection with a sedition case on Monday and denied bail on Tuesday.</p>

<p>It triggered protests by Hindu community members in various locations in Bangladesh, including in the capital Dhaka and Chattogram.</p>

<p>On October 30, a sedition case was filed against 19 people, including Das, at Chattogram's Kotwali Police Station, accusing them of disrespecting Bangladesh's national flag in Chattogram's New Market area during a rally of the Hindu community.</p>

<p>On Tuesday, New Delhi expressed concern over the leader's arrest and denial of bail, and asked Bangladesh to ensure the safety of Hindus and other minorities.</p>

<p>The week's anti-Hindu incidents have led to a diplomatic row between the two South Asian neighbours.</p>

<p>India on Friday said the interim government in Bangladesh must live up to its responsibility of protecting all minorities as it expressed serious concern over the "surge" of extremist rhetoric and increasing incidents of violence against Hindus as well as attacks on temples.</p>

<p>External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar told Parliament that India has taken serious note of incidents of violence against minorities in Bangladesh and that it is the primary responsibility of Dhaka to protect the life and liberty of all the citizens, including minorities.</p>

<p>On the other hand, Bangladesh on Friday expressed deep concern over the violent protest at the Deputy High Commission in Kolkata and urged New Delhi to ensure the safety of all its diplomatic missions in India.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/jhmfvui8_hindu-temples_625x300_29_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Police baton-charge protesting supporters of Chinmoy Krishna Das Brahmachari in Chittagong on Tuesday.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-the-pink-elephant-test-reveals-about-your-ability-to-control-thoughts-7136783]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What The Pink Elephant Test Reveals About Your Ability To Control Thoughts]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-the-pink-elephant-test-reveals-about-your-ability-to-control-thoughts-7136783]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Nov 2024 23:51:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In a new study, we have found evidence the pink elephant problem is not universal. Some people  including people with aphantasia can block involuntary visual thoughts from their minds.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>Tell a man he shouldn't think of a pink elephant and he can't get that beast out of his mind!</p>
</blockquote>

<p>This <a href="https://www.google.com.au/books/edition/City_in_the_Sky/GvRQAQAAIAAJ?hl=en&amp;gbpv=1&amp;bsq=pink%20elephant&amp;dq=city%20in%20the%20sky&amp;printsec=frontcover">quote</a>, from Curt Siodmak's 1974 novel City in the Sky, describes how hard it can be to suppress our thoughts. “Don't think of a pink elephant” has become a classic example of how difficult it can be to intentionally avoid visualising.</p>

<p>Research <a href="https://psycnet.apa.org/doiLanding?doi=10.1037%2F0022-3514.53.1.5">suggests</a> many of you, having read about a pink elephant, will have imagined seeing one.</p>

<p>However, some people, like us, have aphantasia – we cannot visualise. So we are a little confused at the idea other people can imagine seeing things that aren't there.</p>

<p>In a <a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cortex.2024.10.020">new study</a>, we have found evidence the pink elephant problem is not universal. Some people – including people with aphantasia – can block involuntary visual thoughts from their minds.</p>

<h2>What is aphantasia?</h2>

<p>People with aphantasia cannot voluntarily imagine seeing things in our mind's eye. So if you ask us not to think about a pink elephant, we won't visualise one, because we can't.</p>

<p>Aphantasia is typically described as a deficit. When people first learn they have aphantasia they are often upset, as they realise other people can do things they cannot. It might be nice to imagine seeing the characters described in a book, for example, or to visualise an absent loved one.</p>

<figure class="align-center zoomable"><a href="https://images.theconversation.com/files/633730/original/file-20241122-17-nftvqn.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=1000&amp;fit=clip"><img alt="Drawing of a pink elephant." sizes="(min-width: 1466px) 754px, (max-width: 599px) 100vw, (min-width: 600px) 600px, 237px" src="https://images.theconversation.com/files/633730/original/file-20241122-17-nftvqn.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;fit=clip" srcset="https://images.theconversation.com/files/633730/original/file-20241122-17-nftvqn.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=484&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=1 600w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/633730/original/file-20241122-17-nftvqn.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=30&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=484&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=2 1200w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/633730/original/file-20241122-17-nftvqn.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=15&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=484&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=3 1800w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/633730/original/file-20241122-17-nftvqn.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=608&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=1 754w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/633730/original/file-20241122-17-nftvqn.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=30&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=608&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=2 1508w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/633730/original/file-20241122-17-nftvqn.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=15&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=608&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=3 2262w" /></a>

<figcaption><span class="caption">When people are told not to think of a pink elephant, those with more vivid visual imaginations find it difficult to comply.</span> <span class="attribution"><span class="source">Loren Bouyer</span>, <a class="license" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/">CC BY-SA</a></span></figcaption>
</figure>

<p>However, deficits are often balanced by benefits. There are <a href="https://royalsocietypublishing.org/doi/10.1098/rspb.2021.0267?">suggestions</a> people with aphantasia (or aphantasics, as we're sometimes called) may have a heightened resistance to involuntary intrusive thoughts.</p>

<p>Another way to look at it is that aphantasics are one portion of a natural diversity of human minds, with people having different capacities to visualise. Where aphantasics have no capacity, most people would have an average ability, and a small number of people would have an extremely strong ability to visualise.</p>

<h2>Vivid mental imagery and involuntary visualisations</h2>

<p>In our new study, we looked at links between the intensity of people's visual imaginations and their tendency to visualise, even when they try not to. People with vivid visual imaginations were more likely to have involuntary visualisations, and we could predict these outcomes by measuring brain activity.</p>

<p>Some people might enjoy being able to imagine seeing detailed scenes whenever they wish. However, this seems to come at the cost of not being able to shut down these experiences.</p>

<p>Most people have less vibrant imagery, but they seem to be more able to suppress these thoughts.</p>

<h2>Do aphantasics have peaceful minds?</h2>

<p>Aphantasics are unlikely to have involuntary visualisations. Does that mean they have peaceful minds?</p>

<p>In our study people who reported having weak imagery were less likely to imagine seeing things they were trying not to think about. However, they were more likely to report mind-wandering.</p>

<p>If this describes aphantasics, instead of visualising things we are told not to think about, we may turn our minds to other thoughts, such as what's for dinner. So we would not have more peaceful minds, just a resistance to think about things we are trying to put out of mind.</p>

<h2>If aphantasics do not visualise, do they have daydreams?</h2>

<p>From our own experience, we can confirm at least some aphantasics have minds that wander. But when our minds wander, neither of us imagines seeing things. Our experiences are different.</p>

<p>When Derek's mind wanders he imagines hearing and engaging in purely audio conversations. As daydreaming is typically associated with vision, he did not realise until very recently these imagined conversations could be described as his experience of daydreaming.</p>

<p>Loren cannot visualise <em>or</em> imagine hearing things. She experiences her thoughts as different sensations of texture and imagined feelings of movement – and these are what she experiences when her mind wanders.</p>

<h2>Are aphantasics resistant to trauma from re-living events?</h2>

<p>Perhaps.</p>

<p>While our evidence suggests aphantasics are resistant to involuntary visualisations, more research will be needed to work out if we are resistant to reliving traumas, or if these will simply trigger different types of imagined experience.</p>

<p>What is clear is that Siodmak was wrong. If you tell people they shouldn't think of a pink elephant, some of us will happily put that beast out of our minds, and turn our thoughts to other matters. What's for dinner?<!-- Below is The Conversation's page counter tag. Please DO NOT REMOVE. --><img alt="The Conversation" height="1" referrerpolicy="no-referrer-when-downgrade" src="https://counter.theconversation.com/content/244274/count.gif?distributor=republish-lightbox-basic" style="border: none !important; box-shadow: none !important; margin: 0 !important; max-height: 1px !important; max-width: 1px !important; min-height: 1px !important; min-width: 1px !important; opacity: 0 !important; outline: none !important; padding: 0 !important" width="1" /><!-- End of code. If you don't see any code above, please get new code from the Advanced tab after you click the republish button. The page counter does not collect any personal data. More info: https://theconversation.com/republishing-guidelines --></p>

<p><em><span><strong>(Authors:&nbsp;</strong><a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/derek-arnold-106381">Derek Arnold</a>, Professor, School of Psychology, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/the-university-of-queensland-805">The University of Queensland</a> and <a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/loren-n-bouyer-1521346">Loren N. Bouyer</a>, PhD Student, Neuroscience, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/the-university-of-queensland-805">The University of Queensland</a>)</span></em></p>

<p><em><span><strong>Disclosure Statement</strong>:&nbsp;Derek Arnold receives funding from the Australian Research Council.&nbsp;</span></em><em><span>Loren N. Bouyer does not work for, consult, own shares in or receive funding from any company or organisation that would benefit from this article, and has disclosed no relevant affiliations beyond their academic appointment)</span></em></p>

<p><em>This article is republished from <a href="https://theconversation.com">The Conversation</a> under a Creative Commons license. Read the <a href="https://theconversation.com/the-pink-elephant-test-what-your-visual-imagination-predicts-about-your-ability-to-control-your-thoughts-244274">original article</a>.</em></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/2i8677uo_pink-elephant-istock_625x300_29_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[People with aphantasia may have a heightened resistance to involuntary intrusive thoughts.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/four-year-ban-on-pakistan-state-airline-lifted-by-european-union-7136686]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Four-Year Ban On Pakistan State Airline Lifted By European Union]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/four-year-ban-on-pakistan-state-airline-lifted-by-european-union-7136686]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Nov 2024 23:33:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The European Union's aviation authorities have lifted a four-year ban on Pakistan's beleaguered national airline that was at the centre of a pilot license scandal, officials said Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The European Union's aviation authorities have lifted a four-year ban on Pakistan's beleaguered national airline that was at the centre of a pilot license scandal, officials said Friday.</p>

<p>Pakistan International Airlines was barred from flying to the EU in June 2020, a month after one of its aircraft plunged into a Karachi street, killing nearly 100 people.</p>

<p>The disaster was attributed to human error by the pilots and air traffic control, and was followed by allegations that nearly a third of the licences for its pilots were fake or dubious.</p>

<p>It remains banned from operating in the United States.</p>

<p>"EASA has lifted the suspension of the third country operator authorisation issued to Pakistan International Airlines," the European Union Aviation Safety Agency said in a statement.</p>

<p>"This marks the end of a long process initiated in 2020, based on factual and verifiable evidence that the ability of the Pakistan Civil Aviation Authority (PCAA) to certify and oversee its air operators had degraded below acceptable level."</p>

<p>It added that the EASA "has now re-established sufficient confidence in the PCAA oversight capabilities".</p>

<p>PIA, which employs 7,000 people, has long been accused of being bloated and poorly run -- hobbled by unpaid bills, a poor safety record and regulatory issues.</p>

<p>Pakistan's government has said it is committed to privatising the debt-ridden airline and has been scrambling to find a buyer.</p>

<p>Last month, a deal fell through after a potential buyer reportedly offered a fraction of the asking price.</p>

<p>In 2023 PIA made losses of $270 million according to local media. Its liabilities were nearly $3 billion, about five times the total worth of its assets.</p>

<p>Last year, dozens of flights were cancelled when it could not afford fuel for its planes.</p>

<p>Nadir Shafi Dar, the head of the Pakistan Civil Aviation Authority, confirmed the ban had been lifted.</p>

<p>A PIA spokesperson meanwhile said the airline would "strictly adhere to EASA's regulations and guidelines".</p>

<p>"This milestone has been achieved after four years of relentless efforts by the PIA management," the spokesperson added.</p>

<p>PIA came into being in 1955 when the government nationalised a loss-making commercial airline, and enjoyed rapid growth until the 1990s.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/6op53pqo_european-union-generic_625x300_17_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The European Union's aviation authorities lifted the ban.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-colleges-urge-foreign-students-to-return-to-campus-ahead-of-trumps-swearing-in-7136522]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Colleges Urge Foreign Students To Return Ahead Of Trump's Swearing-In]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-colleges-urge-foreign-students-to-return-to-campus-ahead-of-trumps-swearing-in-7136522]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Nov 2024 23:04:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Several American universities have issued travel advisories for their international students as well as staff and urged them to return to the US before President-elect Donald Trump's inauguration in January next year amid concerns over travel bans.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Several American universities have issued travel advisories for their international students as well as staff and urged them to return to the US before President-elect Donald Trump's inauguration in January next year amid concerns over travel bans that may be enacted by his administration.</p>

<p>Trump will take the oath of office on January 20 and has announced that he will sign several executive orders on issues of economy and immigration on his first day as the 47th President of the United States.</p>

<p>Amid concerns over the disruptions caused by travel bans during his first term as president, several top US universities are issuing travel advisories for their international students and faculty who may be travelling outside the country around Trump's inauguration.</p>

<p>According to data from the US Department of State, Bureau of Educational and Cultural Affairs, and the Institute of International Education, India and China made up over half (54 per cent) of all international students in the United States.</p>

<p>But for the first time since 2009, India became the leading place of origin with 331,602 international students in the United States in 2023/2024, reflecting a 23 per cent increase from the prior year, surpassing China, according to data from the 'Open Doors 2024 Report on International Educational Exchange'.</p>

<p>China was the second leading place of origin, despite a 4 per cent decline to 277,398 students. It remained the top-sending country for undergraduates and non-degree students, sending 87,551 and 5,517, respectively.</p>

<p>Associate Dean and Director at Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT) International Students Office David Elwell in a post following the presidential elections said that with every election, "when there is a change in administration on the federal level there can be changes in policies, regulations, and legislation that impacts higher education as well as immigration and visa status matters".</p>

<p>Elwell urged students to assess their travel plans over the upcoming winter break, noting that new executive orders under Trump may impact travel and visa processing.</p>

<p>In addition, election transitions also impact staffing levels at US Embassies/Consulates abroad, which could impact entry visa processing times.</p>

<p>"Students who would need to apply for a new entry visa at the US Embassy/Consulate abroad to return to the US in their student status should assess the possibility of facing any extensive processing times and have a backup plan if they must travel abroad and wait for a new entry visa to be issued. Any processing delays could impact students' ability to return to the US as planned," Elwell said.</p>

<p>The Office of Global Affairs at the University of Massachusetts, Amherst, in an advisory recommended that its "international community-- including all international students, scholars, faculty and staff under UMass immigration sponsorship" strongly consider returning to the US before the presidential inauguration if they are planning on travelling internationally during the winter holiday break.</p>

<p>While noting that this was not a requirement or mandate from UMass, nor was it based on any current US government policy or recommendation, the university added that "given that a new presidential administration can enact new policies on their first day in office (January 20) and based on previous experience with travel bans that were enacted in the first Trump administration in 2017", the Office of Global Affairs is making this advisory out of an abundance of caution to hopefully prevent any possible travel disruption to members of our international community.</p>

<p>"We are not able to speculate on what a travel ban will look like if enacted, nor can we speculate on what particular countries or regions of the world may or may not be affected." The Wesleyan Argus, the college newspaper of Wesleyan University, said in a report that the university has been "evaluating the potential future impacts" of the Trump administration on international and undocumented students.</p>

<p>"Much uncertainty surrounds the possible changes to American immigration policy that could be enacted by the Trump administration beginning January 20, 2025." The report added that Wesleyan's Office of International Student Affairs (OISA) has been "concerned about sweeping policy changes" that could be implemented soon after Trump's inauguration.</p>

<p>"With the presidential inauguration happening on Monday, January 20, 2025, and uncertainties around President-elect Donald Trump's plans for immigration-related policy, the safest way to avoid difficulty re-entering the country is to be physically present in the US on January 19 and the days thereafter of the spring semester," an email sent on November 18 to international students studying under the F-1 visa read, according to the Wesleyan Argus report.</p>

<p>Within a week of his first term as president, Trump had in January 2017 signed an executive order banning nationals of seven Muslim-majority countries - Iraq, Syria, Iran, Libya, Somalia, Sudan and Yemen - from entering the US for 90 days, causing massive disruptions among communities and outrage and concerns by civil rights organisations.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/6qubbcj_donald-trump_625x300_27_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Several top US universities are issuing travel advisories for their international students.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/crisis-in-gaza-debilitates-as-palestinians-seen-scavenging-in-landfills-7136476]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Crisis In Gaza Deteriorates As Palestinians Seen Scavenging In Landfills]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/crisis-in-gaza-debilitates-as-palestinians-seen-scavenging-in-landfills-7136476]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Nov 2024 22:59:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Palestinians are suffering on an unprecedented scale, with the situation in Gaza City being described as "horrendous" by Ajith Sunghay, head of the UN Human Rights Office in the Palestinian territories.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Gaza Strip has spiralled into chaos, with widespread hunger, looting, and violence, including rising cases of rape in shelters, as public order collapses, according to the United Nations.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Palestinians are suffering on an unprecedented scale, with the situation in Gaza City being described as "horrendous" by Ajith Sunghay, head of the UN Human Rights Office in the Palestinian territories.</p>

<p>Sunghay said the Palestinians are distressed "on a scale that has to be seen to be truly grasped".</p>

<p>The breakdown of public order and safety has exacerbated the situation, with rampant looting and fighting over scarce resources. The UN has warned about the impending anarchy in Gaza, which is now a harsh reality.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The anarchy in Gaza we warned about months ago is here", Sunghay said. Young women, many of whom have been displaced multiple times, have highlighted the lack of safe spaces or privacy in their makeshift tents.</p>

<p>Cases of gender-based violence, rape, abuse of children, and other forms of violence within the community have increased in shelters, according to Sunghay. The situation is dire, with thousands of displaced people sheltering in inhumane conditions, facing severe food shortages and terrible sanitary conditions.</p>

<p>He said for the first time, he saw dozens of women and children now scavenging in giant landfills.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">This is a Horrific Scene<br />
<br />
Palestinians are collecting the remains of spoiled flour that was discarded in a makeshift landfill<br />
<br />
They are gathering the flour to use it as animal feed and for kindling fires <a href="https://t.co/uRjhvSSOdF">pic.twitter.com/uRjhvSSOdF</a></p>
— Ryan Rozbiani (@RyanRozbiani) <a href="https://twitter.com/RyanRozbiani/status/1845539618453942424?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 13, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>The UN is being blocked from delivering aid to the 70,000 people still living in northern Gaza, due to repeated impediments or rejections of humanitarian convoys by the Israeli authorities. The UN is calling for an immediate ceasefire and the release of hostages and those arbitrarily detained.</p>

<p>"And every effort must be made to urgently provide the full quantities of food, medicine and other vital assistance desperately needed in Gaza", UN Human Rights Office spokesman Jeremy Laurence said.</p>

<p>"The killing must end," he added.</p>

<p>The conflict has resulted in the deaths of 1,207 people in Israel, most of whom were civilians, and 44,363 people in Gaza, according to figures from the Hamas-run territory's health ministry. The humanitarian crisis in Gaza is worsening by the day, with the UN urging for immediate action to address the crisis.</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/gmcvm66g_gaza-crisis-unrwa_625x300_29_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hindus-across-bangladesh-being-subjected-to-death-uk-mp-in-house-of-commons-7136414]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hindus Across Bangladesh Being Subjected To Death: UK MP]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hindus-across-bangladesh-being-subjected-to-death-uk-mp-in-house-of-commons-7136414]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Nov 2024 22:45:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[UK member of Parliament Bob Blackman, chair of the All Party Parliamentary Group (APPG) for British Hindus, has raised concerns in the House of Commons over the attacks on Hindus in Bangladesh.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>UK member of Parliament Bob Blackman, chair of the All Party Parliamentary Group (APPG) for British Hindus, has raised concerns in the House of Commons over the attacks on Hindus in Bangladesh.</p>

<p>During a Parliament session on Thursday, the MP for Harrow East in north London condemned the persecution of minorities and the imprisonment of Hindu spiritual leader Chinmoy Krishna Das in Bangladesh.</p>

<p>He pointed out that Das is the spiritual leader of the International Society for Krishna Consciousness (ISKCON), which runs the Bhaktivedanta Manor temple at Elstree in Watford, one of the UK's largest Hindu temples on the outskirts of London.</p>

<p>"[He] is under arrest in Bangladesh and Hindus across Bangladesh are being subjected to death, with their houses and temples being burnt," Blackman told MPs.</p>

<p>"There was today (Thursday) an attempt in Bangladesh's High Court to rule that ISKCON should be banned from the country, which is a direct attack on Hindus. There is now a threat from India to take action and we have a responsibility because we enabled Bangladesh to be free and independent," he said.</p>

<p>The Opposition Conservative Party MP stressed that it "cannot be acceptable that religious minorities are persecuted in this way" and called for freedom of religion to be preserved globally.</p>

<p>"We support freedom of religion or belief everywhere and that includes Bangladesh. I will certainly ask Foreign Office Ministers to look at coming forward with a statement about what is happening to Hindus in Bangladesh," said Lucy Powell in her response on behalf of the UK government as the Leader of the House of Commons.</p>

<p>Blackman's intervention was welcomed by the diaspora group Friends of India Society International (FISI) UK which condemned the numerous attacks on Hindus and other minorities in Bangladesh, including "arson, looting, theft, vandalism, and desecration of temples and deities".</p>

<p>It follows a Ministry of External Affairs (MEA) statement calling on Bangladesh authorities to ensure the "safety and security of Hindus and all minorities, including their right of freedom of peaceful assembly and expression".</p>

<p>The MEA statement said: "We have noted with deep concern the arrest and denial of bail to Shri Chinmoy Krishna Das, the Bangladesh Sammilit Sanatan Jagran Jote spokesperson. This incident follows the multiple attacks on Hindus and other minorities by extremist elements in Bangladesh.</p>

<p>"There are several documented cases of arson and looting of minorities' homes and business establishments as well as theft and vandalism and desecration of deities and temples. It is unfortunate that while the perpetrators of these incidents remain at large, charges should be pressed against a religious leader presenting legitimate demands through peaceful gatherings. We also note with concern the attacks on minorities protesting peacefully against the arrest of Shri Das."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/q2lv04lk_bangladesh-violence-targeting-hindus-ians_625x300_29_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[India has urged Bangladesh to ensure the "safety and security of Hindus and all minorities".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/great-victory-against-israel-hezbollah-chief-7136362]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA['Great Victory' Against Israel: Hezbollah Chief]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/great-victory-against-israel-hezbollah-chief-7136362]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Nov 2024 22:38:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hezbollah chief Naim Qassem on Friday declared a "great victory" against Israel in his first speech since a ceasefire went into effect in Lebanon.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hezbollah chief Naim Qassem on Friday declared a "great victory" against Israel in his first speech since a ceasefire went into effect in Lebanon.</p>

<p>"I have decided to declare... officially and clearly that we are facing a great victory that surpasses that of July 2006," Qassem said, adding: "We won because we prevented the enemy from destroying Hezbollah... (and) from annihilating or weakening the resistance."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/66njgdto_hezbollah-chief_625x300_29_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hezbollah chief Naim Qassem.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-nuclear-ambitions-threaten-all-of-us-uk-foreign-intelligence-chief-7136302]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iran Nuclear Ambitions 'Threaten All Of Us': UK Foreign Intelligence Chief]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-nuclear-ambitions-threaten-all-of-us-uk-foreign-intelligence-chief-7136302]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Nov 2024 22:27:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iran's nuclear ambitions pose a major global security threat even after setbacks dealt to Hamas and Hezbollah, the UK's foreign intelligence chief said Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Iran's nuclear ambitions pose a major global security threat even after setbacks dealt to Hamas and Hezbollah, the UK's foreign intelligence chief said Friday.</p>

<p>"Iran's allied militias across the Middle East have suffered serious blows," Secret Intelligence Service chief Richard Moore said in a speech in Paris. "But the regime's nuclear ambitions continue to threaten all of us."</p>

<p>Moore added that "the Iranian regime maintains its efforts to eliminate dissidents at home and abroad".</p>

<p>Iran was to hold talks with Britain, France and Germany in Geneva on Friday over its nuclear programme, in the context of extreme tension in the Middle East between Iran and its allies, and Israel.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said Thursday that Israel would do "everything" to stop Tehran acquiring a nuclear weapon.</p>

<p>The UN nuclear agency has confirmed that Iran plans to install around 6,000 new centrifuges to enrich uranium, according to a report seen by AFP Friday.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/uooo25h8_iran-nuclear_625x300_29_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Iran was to hold talks with Britain, France and Germany on Friday over its nuclear programme.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukraine-says-russia-returned-more-than-500-soldiers-bodies-7136186]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ukraine Says Russia Returned More Than 500 Soldiers' Bodies]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukraine-says-russia-returned-more-than-500-soldiers-bodies-7136186]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Nov 2024 22:08:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kyiv on Friday said Russian authorities returned over 500 bodies of Ukrainian soldiers killed in combat, with most having died in the eastern Donetsk region.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kyiv on Friday said Russian authorities returned over 500 bodies of Ukrainian soldiers killed in combat, with most having died in the eastern Donetsk region.</p>

<p>Russia and Ukraine have been exchanging bodies and prisoners of war since the first months of the conflict -- with casualties estimated to be high on both sides.</p>

<p>"As a result of repatriation activities, the bodies of 502 fallen defenders were returned to territory controlled by the government of Ukraine," Kyiv's Coordination Headquarters for the Treatment of Prisoners of War said on social media.</p>

<p>The centre said that 397 of the bodies were returned from the embattled Donetsk region, where fighting is most intense.</p>

<p>It said 24 were returned from the eastern Lugansk region and 64 from the southern Zaporizhzhia area, while 17 were handed back from morgues on Russian territory.</p>

<p>"We are grateful for the assistance of the International Committee of the Red Cross," Kyiv's centre said.</p>

<p>It said the bodies will be taken for forensic medical examination and that "together with the expert institutions, the deceased will be identified as soon as possible."</p>

<p>Russia, for its part, does not announce the return of its bodies.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ran0o038_ukraine_625x300_26_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Russia and Ukraine have been exchanging bodies and prisoners of war.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-elon-musk-grooves-to-ymca-as-he-celebrates-thanksgiving-with-donald-trump-7136136]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Video: Musk Grooves To YMCA As He Celebrates Thanksgiving With Trump]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-elon-musk-grooves-to-ymca-as-he-celebrates-thanksgiving-with-donald-trump-7136136]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Nov 2024 21:58:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President-elect Donald Trump and Tesla CEO Elon Musk have been nearly inseparable since the elections earlier this month and their bonhomie was once again at display, during a Thanksgiving dinner in Florida.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President-elect Donald Trump and Tesla CEO Elon Musk have been nearly inseparable since the elections earlier this month and their bonhomie was once again at display, during a Thanksgiving dinner in Florida.</p>

<p>A viral video of the event shows Mr Musk sitting at a table with Mr Trump, incoming First Lady Melania Trump and their son Barron. As Mr Trump taps on Mr Musk's shoulder, the X boss raises his hand and grooves to the 'YMCA' song that can be heard in the background.</p>

<p>Trump then shifts his focus to Barron, encouraging him to join in. Barron, however, simply smiles but remains seated. The event was held at Mar-a-Lago in Florida.</p>

<p>"Hope you had a great Thanksgiving," Mr Musk wrote on X.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">??Hope you had a great Thanksgiving!?? <a href="https://t.co/CQMGaAODKq">https://t.co/CQMGaAODKq</a></p>
— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1862331915337945516?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 29, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Mr Musk, who owns X and rocket company SpaceX, and is chief executive of the electric car company Tesla Inc, also spent time with American actor Sylvester Stallone at the event.</p>

<p>"I was telling @TheSlyStallone that I just watched Demolition Man again and how well it predicted the crazy woke future 30 years ago!" Mr Musk wrote on X, referring to the movie that stars Stallone.</p>

<p>Mr Musk has been using his social media platform X to endorse Mr Trump's cabinet picks and promote his own-preferred candidates.</p>

<p>Mr Musk, who has over 206 million followers on X, posted or reposted about Mr Trump's cabinet picks more than 70 times between November 7 and November 20, a Reuters review found.</p>

<p>In between his constant postings of memes of himself and Trump, the X boss has even embraced a title suggested for his role: "First Buddy".</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/e5cjqnmo_donald-trump-elon-musk_625x300_29_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US President-elect Donald Trump and X boss Elon Musk.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uks-assisted-dying-bill-a-step-closer-to-reality-as-mps-vote-in-favour-7135838]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK's Assisted Dying Bill A Step Closer To Reality As MPs Vote In Favour]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uks-assisted-dying-bill-a-step-closer-to-reality-as-mps-vote-in-favour-7135838]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Nov 2024 21:09:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Terminally Ill Adults (End of Life) Bill can now go through a lengthy process of amendments by the House of Lords before becoming a law - since the bill got 330 votes in favour and 275 against.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On Friday, Members of Parliament of the House of Commons voted in favour of a bill that will grant terminally ill adults in England and Wales with less than six months to live the right to die with medical assistance under proper legislation.</p>

<p>The Terminally Ill Adults (End of Life) Bill can now go through a lengthy process of amendments by the House of Lords before becoming a law - since the bill got 330 votes in favour and 275 against.</p>

<p>MPs were deeply divided by this issue and were given a free vote without any constraints on the lines of parties.&nbsp;“People across the country will be paying extremely close attention to today's vote, but this is a matter of conscience,”&nbsp;Prime Minister Keir Starmer spokesperson said, who voted for the bill.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The legislation delineates a maximum 14-year prison sentence for anyone who coerces someone to take lethal medication or request assisted dying.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"We are not talking about a choice between life or death – we are talking about giving people a choice about how to die,"&nbsp;Labour MP Kim Leadbeater told MPs during a five-hour debate in the Commons. The bill was tabled by Leadbeater as a private member bill. She has actively been campaigning about this issue since weeks.&nbsp;</p>

<p>She has insisted that compared to any assisted dying legislation anywhere in the world, her bill contains "the most robust safeguards". The bill includes two independent doctors' approval for the decision, followed by a high-court judge and the concerned person having to administer the drugs themselves.</p>

<p>The bill has also attracted some high-profile support - like former Prime Minister David Cameron who agrees that people who are in agony and face imminent death, should have an option of shortening their pain.</p>

<p>However, there are challenges surrounding the bill, like the possibility of vulnerable people being coerced into opting for assisted dying.</p>

<p>British Indian Conservative MP Neil Shastri-Hurst backed the bill and argued that people should have access to "the death they deserve".</p>

<p>Former Prime Minister Rishi Sunak also voted in favour of the bill. Meanwhile&nbsp;Suella Braverman was among those voting against.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/7nqt8kvg_assisted-dying-bill-reuters_625x300_29_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[People in support of assisted dying hold placards as they gather outside the Parliament]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/international-court-to-begin-hearings-that-may-shape-global-climate-litigation-7135670]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[World Court To Begin Hearings That May Shape Global Climate Litigation]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/international-court-to-begin-hearings-that-may-shape-global-climate-litigation-7135670]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Nov 2024 20:40:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United Nations' top court next week begins hearings on the legal obligation of countries to fight climate change and the consequences for states of contributing to global warming, the outcome of which could influence litigation worldwide.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United Nations' top court next week begins hearings on the legal obligation of countries to fight climate change and the consequences for states of contributing to global warming, the outcome of which could influence litigation worldwide.</p>

<p>While the advisory opinions of the International Court of Justice's (ICJ) are non-binding, they are legally and politically significant. Experts say the ICJ's eventual opinion on climate change will likely be cited in climate change-driven lawsuits in courts from Europe to Latin America and beyond.</p>

<p>The hearings begin a week after developing nations denounced as woefully inadequate an agreement reached at the COP29 summit for countries to provide $300 billion in annual climate finance by 2035 to help poorer nations cope with climate change.</p>

<p>Ralph Regenvanu, Vanuatu's special envoy for climate change and the environment, said it was imperative fossil fuels be phased out and more money provided to poorer nations bearing the brunt of climate change, such as his Pacific island nation.</p>

<p>"We're not seeing that in the outcome of the COPs," Regenvanu told Reuters.</p>

<p>"We are hoping (the ICJ) can provide a new avenue to break through the inertia we experience when trying to talk about climate justice," he added.</p>

<p>Fiji's Attorney General Graham Leung called the hearings an historic opportunity for small island developing states in their quest for climate change justice.</p>

<h2><strong>CLIMATE LITIGATION</strong></h2>

<p>Climate litigation is on the rise.</p>

<p>Earlier this year, Europe's top human rights court ruled that the Swiss government had violated the rights of its citizens by failing to do enough to combat climate change. But it also rejected two other cases, pointing to the complexities of the growing wave of climate litigation.</p>

<p>Vanuatu, one of the small developing nations that pushed for an ICJ advisory opinion, says it disproportionately suffers the effects of climate change as a result of increasingly intense storms and rising sea levels.</p>

<p>Vanuatu will be the first of 98 countries and twelve international organisations to present arguments to the ICJ, also known as the World Court. It is the United Nations' highest court for resolving international disputes between states and can be tasked by the U.N. General Assembly to give advisory opinions.</p>

<p>In 2023, the assembly asked it for a formal opinion on questions including the legal obligations of states to protect the climate system and whether large states that contribute to greenhouse gas emissions may be liable for damages, in particular to small island nations.</p>

<p>"As COP29 failed to provide a clear direction for climate justice and ambition, any developments from the ICJ will now only become more weighty," said Lea Main-Klingst, a lawyer with ClientEarth.</p>

<p>Aside from small island states and numerous Western and developing countries, the court will also hear from the world's top two emitters of greenhouse gases, the United States and China. Oil producer group OPEC will also give its views.</p>

<p>The hearings will start at 10 a.m. (0900 GMT) local time on Monday and run until Dec. 13. The court's opinion will be delivered in 2025.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/g5jtre8g_international-court-of-justice-icj-the-hague-reuters_625x300_29_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A view of the International Court of Justice (ICJ) in The Hague, Netherlands.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/dozens-feared-dead-in-nigeria-boat-accident-7135527]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Dozens Feared Dead As Boat Capsizes In Nigeria]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/dozens-feared-dead-in-nigeria-boat-accident-7135527]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Nov 2024 20:21:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Dozens of people were feared dead after a boat capsized on the Niger River in central Nigeria, a waterways agency spokesperson said on Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dozens of people were feared dead after a boat capsized on the Niger River in central Nigeria, a waterways agency spokesperson said on Friday.</p>

<p>National Inland Waterways Authority (NIWA) spokesperson Makama Suleiman said the boat was carrying mostly traders from Missa community in the central Kogi state heading to a weekly market in the neighbouring Niger state.</p>

<p>Suleiman said that rescue operations were currently underway, but the exact number of fatalities was unknown.</p>

<p>None of the passengers were wearing life jackets, which significantly increased the risk of fatalities, he said.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2016-10/capsized-boat-ferry_650x400_71476688000.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[None of the passengers were wearing life jackets. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/notre-dame-reconstruction-teams-did-what-was-thought-impossible-emmanuel-macron-7135389]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Notre Dame Reconstruction Teams Did What Was Thought Impossible"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/notre-dame-reconstruction-teams-did-what-was-thought-impossible-emmanuel-macron-7135389]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Nov 2024 20:01:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[French President Emmanuel Macron on Friday inspected the gleaming restored interior of Notre Dame cathedral, saying workers had done the "impossible" by healing a "national wound" caused by a 2019 fire that ravaged the mediaeval landmark.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>French President Emmanuel Macron on Friday inspected the gleaming restored interior of Notre Dame cathedral, saying workers had done the "impossible" by healing a "national wound" caused by a 2019 fire that ravaged the mediaeval landmark.</p>

<p>Eight days ahead of the December 7 reopening of the cathedral, Macron conducted an inspection, broadcast live on television, which provided the first official insight into how the 850-year-old edifice now looks inside.</p>

<p>"You have achieved what was thought impossible," Macron told workers and officials who packed Notre Dame after the French president toured the cathedral.</p>

<p>"The blaze at Notre Dame was a national wound, and you have been its remedy through will, through work, through commitment," he said, adding the cathedral's re-opening will be a "shock of hope."</p>

<p>"This is an immense source of pride for the entire nation," Macron said, expressing hope that the spirit of "fraternity" would endure.</p>

<p>Notre Dame will welcome visitors and worshippers again over the December 7-8 weekend, after a sometimes challenging restoration to return the imposing Paris cathedral to its former glory after it was badly damaged by fire on April 19, 2019.</p>

<p>World leaders are expected to attend but the guest list has yet to be revealed.</p>

<p>The French president is hoping the re-opening of Notre Dame will be a major feather in his cap amid the current political deadlock following early parliamentary elections this summer.</p>

<p>"We were told many times at the beginning that it wouldn't be possible, that it was crazy, that it was arbitrary, that we were going to do it wrong," Macron said.</p>

<p>"But in the end," he added, "you did it."</p>

<p>Macron toured the key areas of the cathedral, including the nave, choir and chapel, and spoke to experts.</p>

<p>"Sublime," said a visibly pleased Macron, who was accompanied by Paris' archbishop Laurent Ulrich, the culture minister, the mayor of Paris and other officials.</p>

<p>"It is much more welcoming," he added, praising Notre Dame's pale-coloured stones and saying everyone involved in the reconstruction should "be proud".</p>

<p><strong>'Insane challenge'</strong></p>

<p>After the devastating fire Macron set the ambitious goal to rebuild Notre Dame within five years and make it "even more beautiful" than before, a target that the French authorities say has been met.</p>

<p>The "building site of the century" was a "challenge that many considered insane", Macron has said.</p>

<p>Some 250 companies and hundreds of experts were brought it for restoration work costing hundreds of millions of euros.</p>

<p>All 2,000 people who contributed to the effort had been invited to Friday's event.</p>

<p>The restoration cost a total of nearly 700 million euros (more than $750 million at today's rate).</p>

<p>It was financed from the 846 million euros in donations that poured in from 150 countries in an unprecedented surge of solidarity.</p>

<p>The 19th-century gothic spire has now been resurrected with an exact copy of the original, the stained windows have regained their colour, the walls shining after fire stains cleaned and a restored organ ready to thunder out again.</p>

<p>Unseen to visitors is a new mechanism to protect against any future fires, a discreet system of pipes ready to release millions of water droplets in case of a new disaster.</p>

<p>Notre Dame, which welcomed 12 million visitors in 2017, expects to receive an even higher figure of 14 to 15 million after the reopening, according to the church authorities.</p>

<p>French ministers have also floated the idea of charging tourists an entrance fee to the site but the Paris diocese has said free admission was an important principle to maintain.</p>

<p><strong>Reopening ceremony</strong></p>

<p>Macron had hoped to speak inside Notre Dame to mark the reopening but after negotiations with the diocese, he was now set to speak in the forecourt only.</p>

<p>France is by its constitution a secular country with a strict division between church and state.</p>

<p>The next day, Sunday December 8, will see the first mass and consecration of the new altar.</p>

<p>Macron said in December 2023 he had invited Pope Francis to the reopening of the cathedral but the head of the Catholic church announced in September, to the surprise of some observers, that he would not be coming.</p>

<p>Instead, the pontiff is making a landmark visit during the subsequent weekend to the French island of Corsica.</p>

<p>The French Catholic church has in recent years been rocked by a succession of sexual abuse allegations against clerics, including most recently the monk known as Abbe Pierre who became a household name for providing aid to the destitute.</p>

<p>Over five years on, the investigation into what caused the fire is ongoing, with initial findings backing an accidental cause such as a short circuit, a welder's torch or a cigarette.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/f19ipnn_notre-dame_625x300_29_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[French President Emmanuel Macron.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pics-pariss-iconic-notre-dame-cathedral-gutted-by-fire-restores-gothic-grandeur-7135327]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Pics: Gothic Grandeur Of Notre-Dame Cathedral, Gutted By Fire, Restored]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pics-pariss-iconic-notre-dame-cathedral-gutted-by-fire-restores-gothic-grandeur-7135327]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Nov 2024 19:54:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[French President Emmanuel Macron praised on Friday the more than 1,000 craftspeople who helped rebuild Paris' Notre-Dame Cathedral in what he called "the project of the century", five-and-a-half years after fire gutted the Gothic masterpiece.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>French President Emmanuel Macron praised on Friday the more than 1,000 craftspeople who helped rebuild Paris' Notre-Dame Cathedral in what he called "the project of the century", five-and-a-half years after fire gutted the Gothic masterpiece.</p>

<p>The 12th-century cathedral, one of the French capital's most beloved and visited monuments, will reopen its doors next week to tourists and to the Catholic faithful.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/5l7ge758_notre-dame-cathedral-paris-reuters_625x300_29_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>"Never before have we seen such a construction site. You all had your share in the project of the century," Macron told a gathering that included carpenters, stonemasons, art restorers, firefighters and donors.</p>

<p>"The burning of Notre-Dame was a national wound and you were its remedy, (restoring it) through determination, hard work and commitment."</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/bk36akpk_notre-dame-cathedral-paris-reuters_625x300_29_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>The workers, who include members of the elite 'Compagnons du Devoir', a centuries-old guild of artisans considered France's finest, burst into joyful applause when Macron concluded his address with a final 'thank you'.</p>

<p>The reconstruction work restored the cathedral's spire, its rib vaulting, flying buttresses, stained-glass windows and carved stone gargoyles to their past glory, with the white stone and gold decorations shining brighter than ever.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/4f05rlkc_notre-dame-cathedral-paris-reuters_625x300_29_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>It is a far cry from the evening of April 15, 2019, when TV viewers in France and worldwide watched with horror as the cathedral's roof and spire burst into flames and collapsed in a raging fire that also threatened the main bell towers, which narrowly avoided destruction.</p>

<p>On his visit to the site, Macron seemed deeply impressed as light poured into the nave through the renewed windows.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/bbtrkchc_notre-dame-cathedral-paris-afp_625x300_29_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>"This is overwhelming," he said as he toured the cathedral with his wife Brigitte, Paris mayor Anne Hidalgo and other senior officials.</p>

<h2><strong>'EXCEPTIONAL'</strong></h2>

<p>"It was an exceptional renovation project," stone-carver Samir Abbas, 38, told Reuters, relieved at having finished on schedule.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/1lghnd7k_notre-dame-cathedral-paris-afp_625x300_29_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>An opening ceremony - to which celebrities and heads of state have been invited - is planned for the evening of Dec. 7, followed by days of special Masses to celebrate the reopening and to thank those who helped save and rebuild the cathedral.</p>

<p>So much money poured in for the renovation from all over the world - more than 840 million euros ($882 million), according to Macron's office - that there are still funds left over for further investment in the building.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/6104jts_notre-dame-cathedral-paris-afp_625x300_29_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>The Catholic Church now expects the cathedral to welcome some 15 million visitors annually.</p>

<p>"We are very eager to welcome the whole world under the roof of our cathedral," Paris' Archbishop Laurent Ulrich said in a message on the cathedral website, expressing the Church's gratitude to all those who helped save it.</p>

<p>"On the night of April 15, hundreds of thousands of people committed themselves to what then seemed an impossible bet: to restore the cathedral and give it back its splendour within the unprecedented deadline of five years."</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/j6dchac8_notre-dame-cathedral-paris-afp_625x300_29_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>The guest-list for the reopening ceremony has not yet been published, but one source familiar with the planning said U.S. President Joe Biden's wife Jill would come, while President-elect Donald Trump had not yet confirmed his attendance.</p>

<p>Parisians expressed excitement and relief at the prospect of the cathedral reopening.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/436kgaac_notre-dame-cathedral-paris-afp_625x300_29_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>"I'm so happy," said 50-year-old architect Sebastien Truchot, who lives nearby. "Whether you believe in God or not, Notre-Dame is a universal symbol, and it's amazing to have it back and to rediscover it."</p>

<p>Albert Abid, a bookseller whose stall stands on the quay, was shocked to see it burn five years ago. "It's a relief. Finally, Notre Dame is restored," he said.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/30m1m4q_notre-dame-cathedral-paris-reuters_625x300_29_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A view of the facade of Notre-Dame de Paris cathedral in Paris, France ahead of its grand re-opening]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/asteroid-ryugu-sample-was-rapidly-colonised-by-earth-bacteria-study-7135273]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Asteroid Ryugu Sample Was 'Rapidly Colonised' By Earth Bacteria: Study]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/asteroid-ryugu-sample-was-rapidly-colonised-by-earth-bacteria-study-7135273]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Nov 2024 19:50:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The sample from the asteroid Ryugu was overrun with Earth-based life forms after they were brought to the planet, scientists have concluded in a study.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The sample from the asteroid Ryugu was overrun with Earth-based life forms after they were brought to the planet, scientists have concluded in a study. The research, published in the journal Meteoritics &amp; Planetary Science, explains how successful terrestrial microorganisms are at colonisation, even for extraterrestrial materials.</p>

<p>These samples have been collected by the Hayabusa2 spacecraft of the&nbsp;Japan&nbsp;Aerospace Exploration Agency (JAXA). It was launched in December 2014 and successfully rendezvoused with Ryugu in June 2018.</p>

<p>Later, it spent a year examining the asteroid having a diameter of roughly 3,000 feet (900 meters), before scooping out a sample, which returned to The Earth on December 6, 2020. Haybusa2 continued with its study of more asteroids.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The sample was split and sent to different teams of scientists, including the one that conducted the latest research. Team leader Matthew Genge, who is from Imperial College London told Space.com that they have discovered microorganisms in the sample returned from the asteroid.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"They appeared on the rock and spread with time before finally dying off," Genge said.</p>

<p>The "change in the number of microorganisms" further confirmed these were living microbes. "However, it also suggested they only recently colonised the specimen just before our analyses and were terrestrial in origin," Genge added.</p>

<p>The team observed filamentous microorganisms as the discovery took the form of filaments and rods of organic matter, Space.com reported.</p>

<p>However, the researcher noted the type of microorganisms was still unknown.</p>

<p>"Without studying their DNA, it is impossible to identify their exact type... However, they were most likely bacteria such as Bacillus since these are very common filamentous microorganisms, particularly in soil and rocks," Genge noted.</p>

<p>The team has ruled out the possibility of these microorganisms being already there on Ryugu when the samples were gathered.</p>

<p>"Before we prepared the sample, we performed nano-X-ray computed tomography, and no microbes were seen," Genge said, adding the change in population suggests they only appeared after the sample was exposed to the atmosphere upon its return to the Earth.</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/kmdghmag_asteroid-rygusu_625x300_29_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/turducken-and-how-nfl-legend-john-madden-made-it-popular-on-thanksgiving-7135171]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[As Thanksgiving Dish Turducken Trends, It's Link To NFL Legend John Madden]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/turducken-and-how-nfl-legend-john-madden-made-it-popular-on-thanksgiving-7135171]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Nov 2024 19:32:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[This celebrated dish was brought to prominence by NFL legend John Madden, football coach and commentator, in 1996 during a game between the New Orleans Saints and St. Louis Rams at the Louisiana Superdome.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Picture this: A matryoshka doll of bird meat - a turducken.<br />
<br />
A thanksgiving dish consisting of a boneless turkey, a boneless duck and a boneless chicken cooked together between layers of dressing.</p>

<p>This celebrated dish was brought to prominence by NFL legend John Madden, football coach and commentator, in 1996 during a game between the New Orleans Saints and St. Louis Rams at the Louisiana Superdome. He made it a focal point of his holiday game day shows, incidentally bringing Gourmet Butcher Block to national stature.</p>

<p>In an interview with the New York Times, Madden said, "The first one I ever had I was doing a game in New Orleans. The PR guy for the Saints brought me one. And he brought it to the booth. It smelled and looked so good. I didn't have any plates or silverware or anything, and I just started eating it with my hands."</p>

<p>Even his final public words on the dish were: "You can't beat a good turducken."</p>

<p>But apart from Louisiana, Europe also has a lengthy history of stuffing one bird in another. The French have Quail à la Talleyrand, which is essentially a quail in a chicken in a turkey! And the English have their gooducken with goose, duck and chicken.</p>

<p>Gordon Ramsey, British celebrity chef and restaurateur, recently went to meet Glenn Mistich of Gourmet Butcher Block, to make the infamous dish for a special episode of Thanksgiving on Fox NFL and was left blown away by it. He said, "Oh my goodness, it is like magic. Now I know why John went crazy for this."</p>

<p>Tom Brady, an NFL player and broadcaster also ate turducken on live TV this Thursday. Brady and his partner Kevin Burkhardt split up the turkey legs to keep Madden's Thanksgiving tradition alive.</p>

<p>"That's good!" Brady said after a bite, although viewers are not convinced he liked it. Some made jokes about him spitting it out after the camera panned away from him. But Brady even joked about abandoning the broadcast to continue eating.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Brady 100% spit this out as soon as the camera cut away <a href="https://t.co/vIvAgDIlHE">https://t.co/vIvAgDIlHE</a></p>
— Zach Regelin (@ZRegelin) <a href="https://twitter.com/ZRegelin/status/1862297676219654301?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 29, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>After almost 30 years of turducken's debut on NFL Thanksgiving broadcasts, the legacy continues.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/clq4g9f8_turducken-twitter_625x300_29_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Turducken was brought to prominence by NFL legend John Madden]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/swiss-socialite-jocelyn-wildenstein-claims-shes-never-had-plastic-surgery-report-7135056]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Jocelyn Wildenstein Claims She's "Never" Had Plastic Surgery: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/swiss-socialite-jocelyn-wildenstein-claims-shes-never-had-plastic-surgery-report-7135056]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Nov 2024 19:17:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Jocelyn Wildenstein, the 84-year-old Swiss socialite known as "Catwoman" due to her extensive plastic surgeries, has denied getting any work done on her face.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Jocelyn Wildenstein, the 84-year-old Swiss socialite known as "Catwoman" due to her extensive plastic surgeries, has denied getting any work done on her face. In an interview with <em>The Sun</em>, Ms Wildenstein claimed that she has "never" had plastic surgery because she is scared of the results. Her statement comes despite her former husband Alec Wildenstein once saying that they both got their respective first plastic surgeries together about a year after they got married.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"I haven't had plastic surgery. I am scared of what can happen, and I don't like to have something heavy. Sometimes it is a bit heavy and terrible," Ms Wildenstein told the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.thesun.co.uk/fabulous/31968684/catwoman-jocelyne-wildenstein-plastic-surgery-botox/" rel="noindex,nofollow">outlet</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The 84-year-old claims to have eschewed even Botox after a bad experience with the cosmetic treatment. "I don't like the Botox. Everyone has a different reaction to it," she explained, adding, "I have had Botox only twice. I don't know if I am allergic, but when I had it, it did not go well with me. It was not a good result. My face swelled up. If [other women] want to do it too strong, it doesn't work well."</p>

<p>Ms Wildenstein also insisted that she has never used any fillers. "I never did any fillers. I have some friends who had fillers and were not happy," she said.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/sophie-rain-this-adult-star-earns-rs-360-crore-annually-surpassing-nba-superstars-earnings-7133564">This Adult Star Earns Rs 360 Crore Annually, Surpassing NBA Superstar's Earnings</a></strong></p>

<p>Jocelyn Wildenstein became a tabloid fixture in the 1990s during her divorce from her billionaire art dealer husband Alec Wildenstein. Several reports suggest that she began her facial transmogrification because of her late ex-husband, who wanted her to look like a lynx.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://people.com/where-is-jocelyn-wildenstein-now-8645335" rel="noindex,nofollow">People </a>magazine, Mr Wildenstein once also claimed that he and Jocelyn both got some of their respective first plastic surgeries together about a year after they got married.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Notably, Ms Wildenstein's face has earned her the nickname "Catwoman". However, she has repeatedly said that some of her facial features are partially natural. "The lynx has perfect eyes. If I show you pictures of my grandmother, what you see is these eyes - cat eyes - and high cheekbones," she once said.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/93nvperg_jocelyn-wildenstein_625x300_29_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Ms Wildenstein also insisted that she has never used any fillers.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-germanys-patriot-air-defence-systems-will-protect-ukraine-via-poland-7134908]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How Germany's Patriot Air Defence Systems Will Protect Ukraine Via Poland]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-germanys-patriot-air-defence-systems-will-protect-ukraine-via-poland-7134908]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Nov 2024 18:57:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Germany has offered to re-deploy Patriot air defence systems to NATO ally Poland at the start of the new year, the German defence ministry said on Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Germany has offered to re-deploy Patriot air defence systems to NATO ally Poland at the start of the new year, the German defence ministry said on Thursday.</p>

<p>The units could be deployed for up to six months, the ministry said in a statement.</p>

<p>"With this we will protect a logistical hub in Poland which is of central importance for the delivery of materials to Ukraine," German Defence Minister Boris Pistorius said.</p>

<p>His Polish counterpart Wladyslaw Kosiniak-Kamysz said in a post on social media platform X that Warsaw welcomed the decision.</p>

<p>Germany previously deployed 300 troops along with three Patriot units to Poland from January to November 2022.</p>

<p>They were based in the town of Zamosc, about 50 km (31 miles) from the Ukrainian border, to protect the southern town and its crucial railway link to Ukraine.</p>

<p>The deployment was triggered by a stray Ukrainian missile that struck the Polish village of Przewodow in November 2022, in an incident that raised fears of the war in Ukraine spilling over the border.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/50d45sl_german-patriot-air-defence-system-reuters_625x300_29_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Germany has offered to re-deploy Patriot air defence systems to NATO ally Poland.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kayaker-trapped-on-australian-river-gets-leg-amputated-in-20-hour-rescue-7134891]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kayaker, Trapped On Australian River, Gets Leg Amputated In 20-Hour Rescue]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kayaker-trapped-on-australian-river-gets-leg-amputated-in-20-hour-rescue-7134891]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Nov 2024 18:54:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The man was navigating rapids in Tasmania's Franklin River with some friends on Friday when his leg got "wedged between rocks".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A kayaker's leg was amputated by a rescue crew on Saturday after it got stuck in a rocky crevice on a dangerous stretch of the Australian River, reported The <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/11/23/world/australia/tasmania-rescue-leg-amputated.html" rel="no follow noindex" target="_blank">New</a> York Times. The man, a foreign tourist in his 60s, was then taken to a hospital in Hobart and is currently in critical condition, said police.</p>

<p>The man was navigating rapids in Tasmania's Franklin River with some friends on Friday when his leg got "wedged between rocks". Emergency services were alerted by the man's smartwatch at 3:30 pm the same day, leading to a "complex and protracted" rescue effort. The operation lasted 20 hours but failed to free his limb from between the rocks.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Accompanied by the medical crew, the kayaker spent the night partly submerged in the river. Multiple attempts to free his leg turned out unsuccessful due to his worsening health. After consulting with the man, the medical team staff used specialist equipment to amputate his leg, the police said.</p>

<p>Doug Oosterloo, the acting assistant commissioner of the Tasmania Police, said in a statement, “This rescue was an extremely challenging and technical operation. Every effort was made to extract the man before the difficult decision to amputate his leg.</p>

<p>Located in the Franklin-Gordon Wild Rivers National Park, the 80-mile river is a popular location for rafting and kayaking. The Tasmanian Parks Department has issued a disclaimer warning of the "highly hazardous" character of the white water river systems and the frequent weather changes in the national park.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/6j66amc_tasmania-police-_625x300_29_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>