<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 12:24:32 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/thaad-anti-missile-system-is-in-place-in-israel-says-us-as-iran-attack-threat-looms-6837300]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[THAAD Anti-Missile System Is "In Place" In Israel, Says US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/thaad-anti-missile-system-is-in-place-in-israel-says-us-as-iran-attack-threat-looms-6837300]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 12:21:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[THAAD, or the Terminal High Altitude Area Defense system, is a critical part of the US military's layered air defense systems and adds to Israel's already formidable anti-missile defenses.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The US military has rushed its advanced anti-missile system to Israel and it is now "in place", Defense Secretary Lloyd Austin said.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/thaad-explained-the-advanced-missile-defense-system-the-us-is-deploying-to-israel-6784124" target="_blank">THAAD</a>, or the Terminal High Altitude Area Defense system, is a critical part of the US military's layered air defense systems and adds to Israel's already formidable anti-missile defenses.</p>

<p>"The THAAD system is in place," Austin said, speaking to reporters before his arrival in Ukraine on Monday.</p>

<p>He declined to say whether it was operational, but added: "We have the ability to put it into operation very quickly and we're on pace with our expectations."</p>

<p>President Joe Biden said the THAAD's deployment, along with about 100 US soldiers, was meant to help defend Israel, which is weighing an expected retaliation against Iran after Tehran fired more than 180 missiles at Israel on Oct 1.</p>

<p>The United States has been urging Israel to calibrate its response to avoid triggering a broader war in the Middle East, officials say, with Biden publicly voicing his opposition to an Israeli attack on Iran's nuclear sites and his concerns about a strike on its energy infrastructure.</p>

<p>Responding to questions from reporters, Biden said last week he had a good understanding of when and how Israel would attack Iran. But he also said he saw an opportunity to end the two enemies' back-and-forth strikes.</p>

<p>Austin was cautious.</p>

<p>"It's hard to say exactly what that (Israel's) strike will look like," Austin told reporters.</p>

<p>"At the end of the day, that's an Israeli decision, and whether or not the Israelis believe it's proportional and how the Iranians perceive it, I mean those may be two different things."</p>

<p>"We're going to do - continue to do - everything we can ... to dial down the tensions and hopefully get both parties to begin to de-escalate. So, we'll see what happens," he added.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/uvfb6l1o_thaad_625x300_21_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/david-cameron-speaks-about-rishi-sunak-recalls-a-prediction-he-had-made-6837297]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[David Cameron Speaks About Rishi Sunak, Recalls A Prediction He Had Made]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/david-cameron-speaks-about-rishi-sunak-recalls-a-prediction-he-had-made-6837297]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 12:21:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former Prime Minister of Britain Lord David Cameron today spoke about 'The India Century' at the NDTV World Summit in New Delhi. During his interaction, he mentioned about his prediction of Britain having an India-origin prime minister come true.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former Prime Minister of Britain Lord David Cameron today spoke about 'The India Century' at the NDTV World Summit in New Delhi. During his interaction, he mentioned about his prediction of Britain having an India-origin prime minister come true.</p>

<p>The former prime minister also spoke about why he firmly believes the 21st Century is indeed a defining one as India emerges as a leading global power. Backing India's bid for a permanent seat the UN Security Council, Lord Cameron said "it is India's rightful place to be the Security Council, but as these reforms and discussions take time, it is reassuring to see India being a key member of the Quad and G20 groupings and also now regularly being invited the G7 Summit too, as a fellow democracy. These are important for the entire world."</p>

<p>Remembering his meeting with Prime Minister Narendra Modi and the diaspora event held at the Wembley Stadium, Lord Cameron said, "Those are moments that hard to forget. As a party leader in the UK, one is used to addressing the largest of gatherings of two to three thousand people. But to go to Wembley Stadium which is packed with more than 85,000 people cheering for Prime Minister Modi as I introduced him was quite remarkable."</p>

<p>"But another thing I vividly remember, and one that I found out later, is that when I making my speech at Wembley introducing PM Modi, I had made a prediction that the Conservative Party will give the UK its first women prime minister, the first Jewish prime minister, and also the first Indian-origin prime minister. Little did I know that that prediction would come true so soon. That evening there was a young leader sitting way at the back - his name is Rishi Sunak and he went on to become UK's first Indian-origin PM soon after that prediction."</p>

<p>Taking about the India-UK partnership, Lord Cameron said he has been a strong advocate of it since the early 2000s. "I had said back in 2005 that the India-UK partnership needs to be given a special status, and ties must be a privileged partnership."<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/37kctquo_david-cameron-ndtv-world-summit_625x300_21_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Former Prime Minister of Britain Lord David Cameron spoke at the NDTV World Summit today.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/ai-search-startup-perplexity-in-talks-for-9-billion-valuation-6837047]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[AI Search Startup Perplexity In Talks For $9 Billion Valuation]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/ai-search-startup-perplexity-in-talks-for-9-billion-valuation-6837047]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 11:43:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The new valuation, which includes the amount the company would raise, could triple its previous value of $3 billion from a funding round earlier this year.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Perplexity AI Inc., an artificial intelligence company building a search product that aims to compete with Google, is in early talks to raise funding from investors at a valuation of about $9 billion, according to a person familiar with the matter.</p>

<p>The company is seeking to raise more than $500 million in the funding round, according to the person, who asked not to be identified discussing private information.</p>

<p>The new valuation, which includes the amount the company would raise, could triple its previous value of $3 billion from a funding round earlier this year. However, the discussions are still early, and the details could change, or talks could fall apart. The company declined to comment.</p>

<p>Perplexity's valuation has soared in recent months, reflecting venture capitalists' intense interest in backing AI companies. As recently as April of this year, the startup was valued at just $1 billion. Its peers and rivals have also raised large sums - including OpenAI, which completed a $6.6 billion financing at a $157 billion valuation earlier this month.</p>

<p>Perplexity's latest funding talks materialized after investors approached the company, the person said, not because the startup had set out to raise new cash.</p>

<p>Perplexity offers several services in addition to the paid and free versions of its search tool. It recently launched a product that allows organizations to search internal files alongside the internet and introduced new features for finance-related searches - including stock prices and company earnings data.</p>

<p>The company has also launched an array of revenue-sharing partnerships with major publishers, even as it has faced accusations of plagiarism from some news outlets.</p>

<p>Investors in the company include SoftBank Group Corp.'s Vision Fund 2, Amazon.com Inc. founder Jeff Bezos and Nvidia Corp.</p>

<p>The Wall Street Journal earlier reported on the deal talks.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/ok4fddqo_perplexity_625x300_21_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Investors in the company include SoftBank Group, Amazon and Nvidia Corp.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/big-moment-david-cameron-hails-tatas-takeover-of-jaguar-land-rover-6837033]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA['Big Moment': David Cameron On Tata's Takeover Of Jaguar Land Rover]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/big-moment-david-cameron-hails-tatas-takeover-of-jaguar-land-rover-6837033]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 11:40:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former British prime minister David Cameron hailed Tata Motors' takeover of Jaguar Land Rover, calling it a "big moment".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former British prime minister David Cameron hailed Tata Motors' takeover of Jaguar Land Rover, calling it a "big moment".</p>

<p>Speaking at the NDTV World Summit on Monday, he said it was <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/ratan-tata-death-jaguar-land-rover-ford-the-jaguar-land-rover-story-how-ratan-tata-triumphed-after-ford-snub-6758368">Tata's acquisition</a> of the British automobile company Ford's two businesses that was a "wake up moment" that the Indian economy had arrived on the global stage.</p>

<p>During his tenure as Prime Minister, Mr Cameron recalled that&nbsp;Indian investment took over Japanese investment in the United Kingdom. He also remembered industrialist Ratan Tata, who passed away earlier this month, as his advisor and also a man central to the milestone of an Indian company entering Britain and investing and growing on of its companies.</p>

<p>Mr Cameron also highlighted India's credibility in playing mediator in the Russia-Ukraine war. "We need India's perspective on the challenges we face in the world. India might be in a position to meditate but has to ensure that (Vladimir) Putin can't be allowed to take territory by force," he said.</p>

<p>On a lighter note, the former British PM said he used to follow Indian cricketer Bishan Singh Bedi, while also praising Rahul Dravid's centuries and Virat Kohli's extraordinary leadership.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/v4l6649g_david-cameron-at-ndtv_625x300_21_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ndtv-world-summit-david-cameron-on-pm-narendra-modis-wembley-stadium-event-in-2015-6836964]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Something You Don't Forget": David Cameron On PM's Wembley Event In 2015]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ndtv-world-summit-david-cameron-on-pm-narendra-modis-wembley-stadium-event-in-2015-6836964]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 11:31:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Speaking at the NDTV World Summit 2024, former British PM David Cameron recalled Prime Minister Narendra Modi's visit to the UK in 2015.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former British Prime Minister David Cameron today recalled Prime Minister Narendra Modi's event at London's Wembley Stadium in 2015 and said it was "something you don't forget".</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/after-james-bond-brooke-bond-we-go-to-rupee-bond-pm-modi-at-wembley-1243202" target="_blank">PM Modi</a> had addressed thousands of members of the Indian community at Wembley Stadium during his visit to the UK in November 2015.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Prime Minister Narendra Modi with David Cameron during the event at Wembley Stadium in 2015" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/dihe1te8_narendra-modi-wembley-stadium_625x300_21_October_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Prime Minister Narendra Modi with David Cameron during the event at Wembley Stadium in 2015" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">Prime Minister Narendra Modi with David Cameron during the event at Wembley Stadium in 2015</p>
</div>

<p>Speaking at the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ndtv-world-summit-2024-india-century-live-updates-pm-narendra-modi-david-cameron-s-jaishankar-to-speak-6830644" target="_blank">NDTV World Summit 2024</a>, Mr Cameron said that in the UK, if you're lucky as a prime minister or the party leader, you might speak to 3,000-4,000 people at your party conference.</p>

<p>"But to go to Wembley Stadium and introducing Prime Minister Modi, where he was speaking to 85,000 people, was quite an occasion," he said.</p>

<p>He also said that in his introduction at that event, he had said that his Conservative party - which gave the UK the first woman PM (Margaret Thatcher) - would one day give the country the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/wont-be-long-before-theres-british-indian-pm-david-cameron-1243198" target="_blank">first British-Indian prime minister</a>.</p>

<p>"When I said that I didn't know that there was a young man in the back row, who was Rishi Sunak. He was there that day," Mr Cameron said.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ex-conservative-ministers-race-to-succeed-rishi-sunak-for-party-leadership-6467368" target="_blank">Rishi Sunak</a>, 44, served as Britain's first Indian-origin Prime Minister from October 2022 to July 2024.</p>

<h3><strong>"India Has Credibility To Mediate In Ukraine War": David Cameron</strong></h3>

<p>David Cameron, speaking at the NDTV World Summit today, said that India can play a key role in scaling down the ongoing <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-has-credibility-to-mediate-in-ukraine-war-david-cameron-at-ndtv-world-summit-6836810#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">war between Russia and Ukraine</a>.</p>

<p>"India has the credibility to be a mediator in the Ukraine war," he said at the event.</p>

<p>More than two and a half years into the war, the Russia-Ukraine conflict has shown no signs of any breakthrough in ceasefire talks.</p>

<p>"India might be in a position to mediate but it has to ensure that Russian President Vladimir Putin cannot be allowed to take territory by force," Mr Cameron added.</p>

<p>He also said the world needs India's perspective on the challenges it faces and the country should get a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-needs-permanent-seat-at-un-security-council-david-cameron-at-ndtv-world-summit-6836795#pfrom=home-ndtvworld_world_top_scroll" target="_blank">permanent seat on the United Nations Security Council</a>.</p>

<p>"You see the rise of India, which will probably become the world's largest economy at some stage in this century. So, obviously, we need a reset and countries like India should be at its heart," he said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/7tbtj6q8_pm-modi-david-cameron_625x300_21_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/world-excited-about-indias-growth-investment-pm-narendra-modi-at-ndtv-world-summit-6836905]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[World Excited About India's Growth, Investment: PM Modi At NDTV World Summit]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/world-excited-about-indias-growth-investment-pm-narendra-modi-at-ndtv-world-summit-6836905]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 11:21:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[PM Modi today spoke about why the 21st Century is 'The India Century' and how the country is growing rapidly and how investors from around the world are excited about India being the fastest growing major economy.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi today spoke about India's rise globally at the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world" target="_blank">NDTV World Summit</a>. He spoke about why the 21st Century is 'The India Century', how the country is growing rapidly, and how investors from around the world are excited about India being the fastest growing major economy.</p>

<p>Launching <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world" target="_blank">NDTV World</a>, PM Modi spoke about the pace and momentum with which India is growing. The prime minister said, "Looking at India's rapid growth - the fastest in the world - and the infrastructure build-up in the country, several global ratings agencies have upgraded India's growth forecast." He went on to say that "Investors from around the world are keenly tracking India's growth and are excited about investing in the fastest growing market."</p>

<p>Mentioning global investor Mark Mobius, Prime Minister Narendra Modi said that he "advises global fund managers that they should invest at least 50 per cent of their funds in the Indian stock market." He said that this shows how closely investors like him are following the India growth story.</p>

<p>"Today, India is a nation that is both developing at a record pace, as well as an emerging global power," PM Modi said, adding that when India speaks, the world listens.</p>

<p>"India knows how to move towards eradicating poverty while also knowing how to build a road to progress," he further said.</p>

<p>In the last ten years, India's stock market has gone from 22,300 to over 81,000, while India's economy took 63 years, from Independence to 2010, to reach a GDP of $1 trillion, it took just seven years to reached $2 trillion - in 2017, and by 2020 it reached $3 trillion. India has gone from being the 11th largest economy to now being the 5th largest economy in the world in less than 10 years.</p>

<p>"I meet many people who tell me, 'India is now the fifth largest economy in the world, so many milestones have been achieved, reforms implemented, then why are you working so hard?' In the last 10 years, 12 crore toilets have been built, and 16 crore homes have gas connections... is this enough? My answer is no. This is not enough. Today India is among the youngest countries in the world. This youth potential can take us to the skies," the Prime Minister said.</p>

<p>"The dreams we have seen, the pledge we have made, there is no rest, no relaxation," he added.</p>

<p>PM Modi also said that when India grows, the world grows. There is no ill-feeling or negativity around India's growth story. That, he said, is because India has friendly ties with almost all nations in the world and takes everyone along.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/8gu2ovn_narendra-modi-ndtv-world-summit_625x300_21_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[PM Modi today spoke about India's growth story at the NDTV World Summit in New Delhi.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ndtv-world-summit-pm-modi-lok-sabha-haryana-elections-win-a-message-of-stability-pm-modi-6836864]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Lok Sabha, Haryana Elections Win A "Message Of Stability": PM Modi]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ndtv-world-summit-pm-modi-lok-sabha-haryana-elections-win-a-message-of-stability-pm-modi-6836864]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 11:15:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Victory in the April-June general election was a "message of stability" and victory in this month's Haryana Assembly election - have reinforced that sentiment, Prime Minister Narendra Modi said Monday at the NDTV World Summit.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Victory in the April-June general election was a "message of stability" and victory in this month's Haryana Assembly election - have reinforced that sentiment, Prime Minister Narendra Modi said Monday at the NDTV World Summit. "Stability, sustainability, and solutions... these are the most important conditions for a better future of humanity," he said.</p>

<p>Delivering the inaugural speech, Mr Modi underlined the importance of the 21st century and the many challenges facing the world, and said stable governance - in India and abroad - is needed to encourage growth and to address common concerns like climate change and global warming.</p>

<p>"This period is the most important in the 21st century. We need stability... and sustenance for growth... and India is working on it," he said, "Our third term gives this message of stability."</p>

<p>Expanding on the common concerns and India's possible contribution to solution, the Prime Minister said, "Climate change is a problem and we are trying take the lead in that fight..."</p>

<p>Acknowledging India's contribution in this fight as "insignificant" for now, Mr Modi said his government is "working on reducing carbon emissions and (other) solutions", such as the India - West Asia global corridor to improve trade and connectivity and a global solar alliance.</p>

<p>The Prime Minister also spoke extensively about India being a "beacon of hope" amid global crises over economic growth, unemployment, and public health that have been caused by the coronavirus and military tension in Ukraine and West Asia.</p>

<p>"During the coronavirus pandemic people were stressed about dealing with the virus. When that was controlled then people were worried about the economy... then climate change, the wars (in Ukraine and West Asia), global supply chains (for industries) ... these have become global worries."</p>

<p>"There are the challenges in front of India, but we feel a sense of positivity and that is why are here today - to discuss the 'India century'," the Prime Minister said.</p>

<p>Mr Modi's Bharatiya Janata Party had won the Lok Sabha election - boosted by 53 seats from its allies that helped it cross the finish line - and then, on October 8, defeated the Congress in Haryana, despite trailing in early rounds of counting.</p>

<p>In both cases the BJP recorded a hat-trick - Mr Modi became a three-time Prime Minister and the saffron party became the first to win the Haryana Assembly election three times in a row.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/n5nvjvlo_pm-modi_625x300_21_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/alexei-navalnys-wife-says-want-vladimir-putin-in-same-conditions-like-my-husband-was-6836852]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Want Putin In Same Conditions Like My Husband Was": Alexei Navalny's Wife]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/alexei-navalnys-wife-says-want-vladimir-putin-in-same-conditions-like-my-husband-was-6836852]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 11:12:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Yulia Navalnaya, the widow of Russian opposition leader Alexei Navalny, has announced her intention to become the president of Russia after President Vladimir Putin's regime comes to an end.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yulia Navalnaya, the widow of Russian opposition leader Alexei Navalny, has announced her intention to become the president of Russia after President Vladimir Putin's regime comes to an end. In an interview with the <a href="http://https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/ce3z4ydk90vo">BBC</a>, Navalnaya expressed her determination to continue her husband's fight for democracy. “I will participate in the elections… as a candidate. My political opponent is Vladimir Putin. And I will do everything to make his regime fall as soon as possible,” she said.</p>

<p>However, for now, her fight remains in exile, for returning to Russia could lead to her arrest on charges of extremism. She told the BBC that she cannot return as long as Putin remains in power.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/putin-critic-alexei-navalnys-wife-rejects-finding-he-died-from-combination-of-illnesses-6344527">Alexei Navalny</a> died under suspicious circumstances in a penal colony after being sentenced to 19 years on "politically motivated" charges. His pursuit of exposing government corruption, particularly through his Anti-Corruption Foundation, made him Putin's most outspoken critic. While Russia denied involvement in Alexei Navalny's death, US President Joe Biden expressed certainty that Putin was responsible.</p>

<p>Since her husband's death, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/yulia-navalnya-widow-of-putin-critic-world-banks-ajay-banga-in-time-influential-leaders-list-5466379">Yulia Navalnaya</a> said their shared political beliefs and decisions have affected their children, Dasha, 23, and Zakhar, 16. “I realise that they didn't have a say in this,” she said.</p>

<p>The Navalnys were united in their determination to challenge Putin's grip on power, despite knowing the risks. In 2021, after surviving a poisoning with Novichok, a nerve agent, Alexei Navalny returned to Russia, where he was detained. Yulia, in her BBC interview, mentioned the extent of her husband's suffering in prison, including spending 295 days in solitary confinement. “Usually, the normal practice is banishment just for two weeks and it's the most severe punishment. My husband spent there almost one year,” she said.</p>

<p>Navalnaya has criticised the international community's response to her husband's death, calling the sanctions imposed on Russian officials “a joke” and urging world leaders to be “a little less afraid” of Putin. She expressed a personal desire to see the Russian president face justice, saying, “I want him to be in a Russian prison. And it's not just that — I want him to be in the same conditions like Alexei was.”</p>

<p>Yulia Navalnaya now leads the Anti-Corruption Foundation, where she plans to release further evidence implicating the Putin regime.</p>

<p>Alexei Navalny began writing his memoir, Patriot, while recuperating in the German countryside after being poisoned with Novichok. Upon his return to Russia and subsequent imprisonment, he continued to document his thoughts and experiences through notebook entries, social media posts and prison diaries, many of which are being published for the first time.</p>

<p>Navalny reported that some of his writings were confiscated by prison officials. Patriot is both illuminating and harrowing — knowing the tragic outcome of Alexei Navalny's story makes his accounts of mistreatment and his resistance resonate with even greater impact.</p>

<p>Yulia recounts her final conversations with her husband, where they both acknowledged the likelihood that he would never leave prison alive. “I never let my brain think that he might be killed,” she said. But Alexei's humour and laughter remained intact until the end, a trait Yulia calls his “superpower.”</p>

<p>“He really, truly laughed at this regime and at Vladimir Putin. That's why Vladimir Putin hated him so much,” she said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/3a6i2p98_yulia-navalnaya-alexei-navalny-instagram_625x300_21_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Yulia Navalnaya criticised the international community's response to her husband's death.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-has-credibility-to-mediate-in-ukraine-war-david-cameron-at-ndtv-world-summit-6836810]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["India Has Credibility To Mediate In Ukraine War": David Cameron At NDTV World Summit]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-has-credibility-to-mediate-in-ukraine-war-david-cameron-at-ndtv-world-summit-6836810]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 11:06:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former UK Prime Minister David Cameron, speaking at the NDTV World Summit today, said that India can play a key role in scaling down the ongoing war between Russia and Ukraine.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former UK Prime Minister David Cameron, speaking at the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://special.ndtv.com/ndtv-world-summit-2024-167/#pfrom=home-ndtvworld_world%20site">NDTV World Summit</a> today, said that India can play a key role in scaling down the ongoing war between Russia and Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"India has the credibility to be a mediator in the Ukraine war," Mr Cameron said at the NDTV World Summit.</p>

<p>More than two and a half years into the war, the Russia-Ukraine conflict has shown no signs of any breakthrough in ceasefire talks.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"India might be in a position to mediate but it has to ensure that Russian President Vladimir Putin cannot be allowed to take territory by force," Mr Cameron added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>President Putin on Friday said it is difficult to specify a timeline for ending the prolonged war in Ukraine but claimed that his country will win, as he appreciated Prime Minister Narendra Modi's concern over the situation.</p>

<p>Both Russia and Ukraine have denied targeting civilians in the 2-1/2-year war that Russia launched against its smaller neighbour with a full-scale invasion.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Days ahead of the 16th BRICS Summit to be hosted by Moscow, President Putin endorsed PM Modi's description of the grouping, saying the Indian leader had "aptly" noted that it is "not an anti-western one but a non-western one".</p>

<p>He also made it clear the grouping, which has since been expanded from five initial members to include five more countries, should not be seen as a "bloc-style organisation".</p>

<p>PM Modi is due to visit Kazan to attend the BRICS summit on October 22-23.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/tejq1kn8_david-cameron-ndtv-world-summit-_625x300_21_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The NDTV World Summit is a two-day meet scheduled for October 21 and 22.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-needs-permanent-seat-at-un-security-council-david-cameron-at-ndtv-world-summit-6836795]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Permanent Seat On Security Council Should Be India's Right": David Cameron]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-needs-permanent-seat-at-un-security-council-david-cameron-at-ndtv-world-summit-6836795]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 11:02:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The world needs India's perspective on the challenges it faces and the country should get a permanent seat on the United Nations Security Council, former UK prime minister David Cameron has said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The world needs India's perspective on the challenges it faces and the country should get a permanent seat on the United Nations Security Council, former UK prime minister David Cameron has said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Speaking at the NDTV World Summit on Monday, Lord David Cameron said the world needs strong economic growth, more democracy and a green transition to deal with climate change and India is a shining example of all of those things.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Mr Cameron's session at the Summit was after Prime Minister Narendra Modi's keynote speech and the former UK prime minister began by commenting on that.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"It was great to hear PM Modi's speech. To have that energy level at the start of your third term is truly impressive... I made it into a second term (as UK prime minister) but since then we have had quite a number of prime ministers. We have not had anyone having three terms since Tony Blair and Margaret Thatcher before him. It's very impressive because it means you have the ability to get real change, real things done in a very consistent way, which is what we are seeing in India," he said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>On the India Century, Mr Cameron said there is a need for a reset because the world has changed "hugely" since the institutions were set up after the Second World War.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"You see the rise of India, which will probably become the world's largest economy at some stage in this century. So, obviously, we need a reset and countries like India should be at its heart," he said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>To a question on his statement from 2015 that India should have a permanent seat at the UN Security Council, Mr Cameron said that should be India's right.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"We do need reform of the United Nations Security Council and I made this argument as far back as 2005. When I became leader of the Conservative Party, India was the first country I visited outside Europe. It was the first country I visited outside Europe when I became prime minister in 2010. I like to think that I was an early believer in the Indian Century. Obviously, a permanent seat on the Security Council should be India's right in this changed world," he emphasised.</p>

<p>Stating that changing these institutions would take a long time, the former UK prime minister said it was good to see India take its place in institutions like the Quad and the G20. He also pointed out that the G7 regularly invites India to attend, almost as a standing member.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Free Trade Agreement</strong></p>

<p>On the free trade agreement (FTA) between India and the UK that former prime minister Boris Johnson had said would be concluded by Diwali in 2022, Mr Cameron said it was a pity it hadn't happened.</p>

<p>"I think it has not happened for a good reason. Britain and India both understand that you get only one chance to make an FTA and you have to make it a good one, which means both sides have to put more on the table. My plea, which I will be making to the foreign minister when I see him this afternoon, is that let's make our deal as good and as big and as generous (as possible)," Mr Cameron said.</p>

<p>"Of course, we have to cover scotch whisky and IT workers for India. We need Indian investment in the UK and trade with India, but also India needs the millions of jobs being created every year. So it is win-win, but we should both put more on the table and take some more risk, including political risk," he added.</p>

<p>Mr Cameron stressed that doing so was also important for India because it would set the standard for its deal with the European Union.</p>

<p><strong>Shift In Perception</strong></p>

<p>To a question on when he thought the West's perception of India shifted, the former UK prime minister said there have been various moments, including the Chandrayaan-3, which saw the first successful landing near the Moon's south pole. For him, he said, it was the year that Indian investment in the UK overtook Japanese investment because of the Jaguar Land Rover deal by the Tata Group.</p>

<p>"There have been so many moments in India's recent history which have woken people up to the potential of this great country - the opening in 1991, the moment when it was clear India's population would overtake China, this huge green transition and green investment, and the lunar mission, which was an extraordinary moment when the whole world saw what the potential of India is," Mr Cameron said.</p>

<p>"My answer, though, would be a bit more parochial. It was the year when Indian investment in the UK overtook Japanese investment because of the massive investment in Jaguar Land Rover. Here was this great iconic business, Tata - obviously mourning the loss of Ratan Tata, who was an advisor to me as prime minister - an Indian company coming into Britain, taking over one of our most famous car brands, investing in it, growing it and improving it. That to me was a real wake-up call that this economy has arrived on the global stage and is going to do great things," he added.</p>

<p><strong>Indian Students In UK</strong></p>

<p>Asked about the anti-immigration rhetoric in the UK and its possible impact on Indian students, who make up the biggest cohort of international students in the country, Mr Cameron made a distinction between that and illegal migration.</p>

<p>The former prime minister said there is no limit on the number of Indian students that can study at British universities and they want as many to come as possible because it is a "great industry" for them and builds great connections between the UK and India.</p>

<p>He pushed for taking student numbers out of immigration numbers and said the real problem in the UK was illegal migration from countries like Syria, Vietnam, Iraq, Iran and Afghanistan.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/fkrrv3uo_david-cameron-_625x300_21_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mr Cameron said he hopes to see a "big and generous" free trade agreement between the UK and India.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-appears-at-nfl-game-in-pennsylvania-as-white-house-race-campaign-heats-up-6836683]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump Appears At NFL Game In Pennsylvania As Campaign Heats Up]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-appears-at-nfl-game-in-pennsylvania-as-white-house-race-campaign-heats-up-6836683]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 10:45:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump’s presence at the game capped a busy weekend of election rallies in the swing state.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Republican presidential nominee Donald Trump made an appearance at Sunday night's NFL game between the Pittsburgh Steelers and New York Jets at Acrisure Stadium.</p>

<p>The former US president was spotted in the luxury box, waving to fans and soaking in the atmosphere as chants of “USA” rang out across the stadium.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">On average, NBC shows Taylor Swift 7 times during an NFL broadcast.<br />
<br />
Tonight, they showed Trump only once, and just for a few seconds.<br />
<br />
This is why:<br />
<br />
<a href="https://t.co/yI3SsqEbU0">pic.twitter.com/yI3SsqEbU0</a></p>
— John LeFevre (@JohnLeFevre) <a href="https://twitter.com/JohnLeFevre/status/1848185063252574397?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 21, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Fresh off a campaign stop in Pennsylvania that included a stint <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-turns-chef-at-mcdonalds-ahead-of-us-presidential-elections-2024-says-worked-more-than-kamala-harris-6835696 ">working at a local McDonald's</a>, Donald Trump's presence at the game capped a busy weekend of election rallies in the swing state.<br />
<br />
Earlier in the day, Trump was joined by two controversial ex-Steelers, Antonio Brown and Le'Veon Bell, who endorsed the GOP candidate. Before kickoff, Brown and Bell distributed Trump-Vance rally towels outside the stadium and encouraged people to register to vote. The two former football stars have a complicated history with the Steelers, having left the team under tense circumstances in 2019.<br />
<br />
Antonio Brown, in particular, is remembered for his tumultuous exit from the Steelers after a series of public incidents. His behaviour has since alienated him from the NFL, though he did win a Super Bowl with the Tampa Bay Buccaneers before being let go.<br />
<br />
Before the lead-up to Sunday's game, Donald Trump shared an AI-generated image of himself in a Steelers jersey on his social media account. The altered photo was posted ahead of the Week 7 matchup.</p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/DBXZw7usxOv/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DBXZw7usxOv/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DBXZw7usxOv/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DBXZw7usxOv/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by President Donald J. Trump (@realdonaldtrump)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p>When he arrived at the game, Donald Trump was greeted by supporters outside the stadium, including fans sporting Pittsburgh jerseys and holding a banner that read “Trump Nation.” The energy in the stands was palpable when a female fan ran onto the field in the third quarter, carrying a pro-Trump sign before being escorted off by security.<br />
<br />
The Steelers organisation remained neutral regarding Trump's attendance, with a spokesperson confirming that the former president was invited by a private suite holder and not the team itself.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
Meanwhile, other Steelers icons, including Hall of Famers Joe Greene and Jerome Bettis, have endorsed Democratic nominee Kamala Harris ahead of the November 5 presidential elections.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/fciiu9ng_donald-trump-nfl-game_625x300_21_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump attended a game between the NFL Pittsburgh Steelers and the New York Jets]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/digital-innovation-democratic-values-can-co-exist-pm-modi-at-ndtv-world-summit-6836676]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Digital Innovation, Democratic Values Can Co-Exist": PM At NDTV Summit]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/digital-innovation-democratic-values-can-co-exist-pm-modi-at-ndtv-world-summit-6836676]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 10:44:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA["Digital Innovation, Democratic Values Can Co-Exist": PM Modi At NDTV World Summit]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India showed the world that digital innovation and democratic values can co-exist, Prime Minister Narendra Modi said in his keynote address at the NDTV World Summit today.</p>

<p>The Prime Minister said India's Digital Public Infrastructure is a key talking point at global summits. "Paul Romer (Nobel laureate and former Chief Economist of the World Bank) is here. We have had many discussions. Paul has praised India's digital infrastructure, including Aadhaar and DigiLocker. In world summits, people are surprised at how India developed such a digital public infrastructure."&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Prime Minister said India did not have the first-mover advantage during the Internet era. "In the countries that had this advantage, private companies led the digital push. A revolution came, but its benefit was limited. India gave a new model to the world. India democratised technology and showed the world the way to digital public infrastructure," the Prime Minister said.</p>

<p>In India, he said, the government creates a platform and it undergoes several rounds of innovations. "Jandhan, Aadhaar and mobile connectivity have become a seamless system of fast and leakage-free service delivery. "Look at UPI, it has led to an expansion of fintech in India. More than 500 million digital transactions are happening through UPI daily. And this is not driven by big corporates, but by small shopowners and street vendors."</p>

<p>Mentioning the government's PM Gati Shakti and ONDC initiatives, the Prime Minister said, "India has shown digital innovation and democratic values can co-exist. India has shown that technology is a tool for inclusion, transparency and empowerment, not for control and division."</p>

<p>This is the most important time in the 21st century, he said. "We need stability and sustenance for growth and India is working on it. This is the first time in six decades that the people of India have given a government a mandate for the third term. This is a message of stability.</p>

<p>"Climate change is now a global problem and India is trying to take a lead in this fight too. Our contribution is negligible in global climate change, but we have made green transmission the fuel for growth," he said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/5q0od22_pm-modi-ndtv-_625x300_21_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/sweet-bobby-new-netflix-documentary-shows-london-womans-9-year-catfishing-nightmare-6836568]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Netflix Documentary Shows Indian-Origin Woman's 9-Year Catfishing Nightmare]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/sweet-bobby-new-netflix-documentary-shows-london-womans-9-year-catfishing-nightmare-6836568]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 10:37:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kirat Assi, a London resident and radio presenter, thought she was finally going to meet the man she'd fallen in love with. They had texted each other for nine years.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kirat Assi, a London resident and radio presenter, thought she was finally going to meet the man she'd fallen in love with. They had texted each other for nine years. However, when the two came face-to-face, Ms Assi found someone she never expected. In a shocking twist, her entire relationship had been an elaborate catfishing scheme, orchestrated not by a stranger but by someone much closer — a female cousin, Simran. Now, Netflix has released a documentary, <em>Sweet Bobby: My Catfish Nightmare,</em> retelling this story of betrayal.</p>

<p>It all began in 2009 when Ms Assi&nbsp;got a friend request from ‘Bobby,' a supposed cardiologist from west London. Soon, it evolved into a long-distance relationship. The two shared connections within their Sikh community, which made the relationship seem genuine.</p>

<p>Over time, their online conversations deepened, but as years passed, their connection remained virtual, with Bobby continually giving bizarre reasons for why they couldn't meet in person. The excuses were nothing short of dramatic — claims of being shot, suffering a stroke and even entering witness protection — according to a report in <a href="http://https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c20m3g1kdpvo">BBC</a>. However, what made these lies convincing to Ms Assi&nbsp;were the people she believed were corroborating his stories. They were always someone close to Bobby, or that's what she thought.</p>

<p>After nine years of emotional manipulation, Ms Assi&nbsp;finally confronted the truth — this entire thing was a hoax, and the man she thought she was in love with didn't even exist. She had been a victim of a catfishing scheme and the person behind the messages wasn't Bobby but her female cousin, Simran.</p>

<p>According to an article in Birmingham Live, throughout the ordeal, Ms Assi, in fact, leaned on Simran for support. However, one day, Simran dropped the bombshell, revealing to a devastated Ms Assi&nbsp;that she hadn't been communicating with Bobby all along — she had been speaking to Simran herself.</p>

<p>The discovery left Ms Assi&nbsp;devastated and questioning her judgement. “How could you have been so stupid?” she reflects now, according to a&nbsp;<a href="http://https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c20m3g1kdpvo">BBC</a> report.</p>

<p>Kirat Assi's experience was first shared in a popular 2021 podcast by Tortoise, but the story has since gained renewed attention with the release of the Netflix documentary, Sweet Bobby: My Catfish Nightmare.</p>

<p>Ms Assi says she has faced criticism and questions, with many asking how she could fall for such a scheme. “For people who might still think I'm stupid, that's fine, you're allowed your opinion,” she told BBC Asian Network News, adding, “I'm not stupid, I'm not dumb. I'm the one that's chosen to speak. I'm the one that's put myself out in the firing line and I hope others will come forward.”</p>

<p>Ms Assi feels it was important to publicly tell her story, especially given the stigmas surrounding such issues in the South Asian community in the UK. Explaining how the fear of judgement often silences victims, she said, “We are so scared to open up about these issues. Because of how a community will be seen by wider society, the victims in our communities keep suffering.”</p>

<p>This reluctance to address uncomfortable topics was evident even in her own family. Speaking of her father's experience with the situation, Kirat Assi said, “He doesn't want to know what happened. Because to face up to what happened, and how horrific it was, it's going to be painful.”</p>

<p>Despite the traumatic experience, Kirat Assi remains open to having conversations about her experience, encouraging people to approach her if they have questions.</p>

<p>Simran, however, has not faced criminal charges for the catfishing, but Ms Assi took civil action against her, resulting in compensation and an apology. In the Netflix documentary, a statement from Simran was included where she said she views the situation as a “private matter,” rejecting the accusations made against her.</p>

<p>Although Kirat Assi has sought closure, she says the motivation behind Simran's deceit remains a mystery. “I think I've long given up. The extent to which that person went, you can't ever justify it. I can't understand why you didn't stop,” Ms Assi&nbsp;said.</p>

<p>Despite this, she is determined to move forward, rebuilding her life and even starting to date again. “I'm going to carry on working towards goals and dreams,” she said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/0f2eaqp_sweet-bobby-netflix-documentary_625x300_21_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Netflix has released a documentary, Sweet Bobby, retelling this story of betrayal.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-on-path-of-unprecedented-growth-pms-top-quotes-at-ndtv-world-summit-6836611]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["India Doesn't Make Taken-For-Granted Relationships": PM At NDTV World Summit]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-on-path-of-unprecedented-growth-pms-top-quotes-at-ndtv-world-summit-6836611]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 10:33:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Narendra Modi, speaking at the NDTV World Summit, said India is a "ray of hope" for the world amid several global crises such as declining economies, unemployment and climate change, among others.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<ol class="CetSht_ol">
	<li class="CetSht_li">If we look at the discussions in the last four or five years, one thing is common: tension about the future. During the coronavirus pandemic, there was stress over economy, unemployment, and health, among other issues.&nbsp;</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">In India, we are discussing the 'India Century'. India is the ray of hope amid global crisis. India giving hope to the world engulfed in various concerns, it is working on unprecedented scale and speed in every field.&nbsp;</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">There are challenges in front of India but we are feeling a sense of positivity here and that is why we are discussing the 'India Century'. India's speed and scale are unprecedented.&nbsp;</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">We have completed 125 days of our term. Around 3 crore new homes for the poor were built, infra projects worth Rs 9 lakh crore infrastructure projects have started, 15 new Vande Bharat trains are running, 8 new airports are in operation, Rs 2 lakh crore package for youth have announced, 5 lakh health insurance for those above 70 - all of these things happened in just 125 days.&nbsp;</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Several agencies have revised upward India's growth forecast due to speed of work in our third term. In 125 days, we have approved 12 new industrial dots. BSE Indices have grown by 7 per cent.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">India's list of achievements is long and I am just discussing the first 125 days of our third term. The world has come to India to discuss various issues in the first 125 days. This shows India's vision and hope and these issues will decide the future of the world.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">A lot is happening in India. India has picked up the pace of growth in our third term. Our government is taking quick decisions and making reforms. I meet a lot of people in my public life who ask, "Why are you working so hard? India is doing well." But my answer is always, "With the dreams and goals that we have, we can't be at rest."</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">In the last ten years, 12 crore toilets have been built, and 16 crore homes have gas connections. Is it enough? My answer is no. This is not enough. India is a country with a young population and we have to do a lot for the country. There has been a change in India's vision.&nbsp;</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">There's a tradition that every government compares its work with the previous one. We used to walk this path but from now on we can't compare the past and present and be happy with it.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">The metric of success from now on would be 'What we want to achieve' - India has a forward-looking approach. A vision for a developed India by 2047 is a part of the mindset.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">
	<p>140 Crore people are driving the 'Viksit Bharat' vision. When the government started working on the idea, lakhs of people gave their suggestions, and based on that, India made its goals for the next 25 years.&nbsp;</p>
	</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">
	<p>This is the era of artificial intelligence (AI) and the future of the world is linked with AI. For the world, AI is artificial intelligence but for India, it is Aspirational India. India has started the AI mission this year. We are increasing the use of AI in every sector.&nbsp;</p>
	</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">
	<p>We are making decisions after considering everyone's aspirations. It is important to connect aspirations in India. We have focused on air travel and started the UDAAN scheme. We worked on two pillars - building airports in tier 2 and 3 cities and making air travel affordable. Over 3 lakh flights have taken off under the UDAAN scheme. Many flights connect the small cities. Now there are over 150 airports in India.&nbsp;</p>
	</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">
	<p>In the last 8-9 years, the participation of Indian universities has increased. Patent applications are at an all-time high. Over 2,500 research centres of companies across the world are located in India. We are taking the lead in giving a vision for the global future.&nbsp;</p>
	</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">
	<p>During Covid, we could have earned millions of dollars by selling drugs, but we did not do that. It is not a part of our tradition. We chose to help the countries and supplied medicines and vaccines to nations, which helped many. We don't make "taken-for-granted" relations with nations.</p>
	</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">
	<p>The world celebrated the Chandrayaan mission. When India grows, the world feels happy. India's growth will benefit the world. India drove the world's growth in the past but during colonialism, we could not. Now, we are independent and are ready to drive the growth.</p>
	</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">
	<p>I met Paul Romer several times. He has appreciated India's digital infrastructure. The world is amazed to see India's DPI. We didn't have the first-mover advantage. We have democratised tech and given DPI a new path. India has shown the world that digital innovation and democracy can coexist.</p>
	</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">
	<p>This period is the most important in the 21st century. We need stability, and sustenance for growth and India is working on it. Our third term gives a message of stability.&nbsp;</p>
	</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">
	<p>Climate change is a problem in the world and we are trying to take a lead in that. In the world's fight against global warming, our contribution is insignificant but we are working on reducing carbon emissions and green energy. We are also working on solutions.&nbsp;</p>
	</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">
	<p>Like the India-Middle East global corridor, mission millets, and global solar alliance. Initiatives taken by India are a solution to problems. We would aim to ensure that India's century is the world's century.&nbsp;</p>

	<p><br />
	&nbsp;</p>
	</li>
</ol>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/h6groiq8_pm-modi-world-summit-ndtv-_625x300_21_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[PM Modi termed India as a "ray of hope" for the world.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/second-ai-in-india-aspirational-india-pm-modi-at-ndtv-world-summit-6836601]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["India Has Double AI Power": What PM Modi Said On AI At NDTV World Summit]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/second-ai-in-india-aspirational-india-pm-modi-at-ndtv-world-summit-6836601]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 10:31:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In the era of Artificial Intelligence, India is powered by another AI Aspirational India which accelerates the country's growth, Prime Minister Narendra Modi said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In the era of Artificial Intelligence, India is powered by another AI&nbsp;— Aspirational India&nbsp;— which accelerates the country's growth, Prime Minister Narendra Modi said on Monday at the NDTV World Summit.</p>

<p>PM Modi said that in the Artificial Intelligence mission started this year, India will increase the use of the technology in every sector.</p>

<p>"This is the era of AI and the future of the world is linked with it. India is powered by two AIs. For the world, it is Artificial Intelligence but in India, it's Aspirational India plus Artificial Intelligence. When the two meet, it accelerates India's growth," he said.</p>

<p>The Prime Minister said there is <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/na-chain-na-araam-pm-modi-at-ndtv-world-summit-on-hard-work-6836565">no scope for rest</a> as his government works to make India's dreams come true. "India is the ray of <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-on-path-of-unprecedented-growth-pms-top-quotes-at-ndtv-world-summit-6836611">hope amid global crisis</a>. India giving hope to the world engulfed in various concerns, it is working on unprecedented scale and speed in every field," he said.</p>

<p>Mr Modi also took a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-has-emerged-as-a-beacon-of-hope-pm-modi-at-ndtv-world-summit-6836512">swipe at his political opposition</a>.&nbsp;"There is a tradition... every government compares its work to the previous. We used to walk this path but, from now on, we cannot compare past and present and be happy. The metric of success from now on will be what we want to achieve... and that is a 'developed India' by 2047," he said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/5u2dcue_modi-at-ndtv-world-summit_625x300_21_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/na-chain-na-araam-pm-modi-at-ndtv-world-summit-on-hard-work-6836565]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["People Ask Me Why Do You Still Work Like This...": PM At NDTV World Summit]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/na-chain-na-araam-pm-modi-at-ndtv-world-summit-on-hard-work-6836565]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 10:27:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Addressing the NDTV World Summit this morning, Prime Minister Narendra Modi said there is no scope for rest as his government works to make India's dreams come true.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Addressing the NDTV World Summit this morning, Prime Minister Narendra Modi said there is no scope for rest as his government works to make India's dreams come true and fulfill its pledge.</p>

<p>"I meet many people who tell me, 'India is now the fifth largest economy in the world, so many milestones have been achieved, reforms implemented, then why are you working so hard?'&nbsp;In the last 10 years, 12 crore toilets have been built, and 16 crore homes have gas connections... is this enough? My answer is no. This is not enough. Today India is among the youngest countries in the world. This youth potential can take us to the skies," the Prime Minister said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The dreams we have seen, the pledge we have made, there is no rest, no relaxation," he added.</p>

<p>The Prime Minister said India is now moving ahead with a 'look forward' approach. "There's a tradition that every government compares its work with that of the previous government. We used to walk this path too, but from now on we can't compare the past and the present and be happy with it. The metric of success from now on would be 'What we want to achieve'. India now has a forward-looking approach. The vision for a developed India by 2047 is a part of this mindset," he said.</p>

<p>At the beginning of his address, the Prime Minister said the developments in the last five years have been a cause for global concern. These include the Covid pandemic that resulted in the disruption of economies, price rise and unemployment, followed by wars in Ukraine and West Asia. Amid this turmoil, India has emerged as a beacon of hope, the Prime Minister said. "In India, we are discussing the India Century. India is the ray of hope amid the global crisis. There are challenges in front of India but we feel a sense of positivity here," he added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>India, he said, showed the world that digital innovation and democratic values can co-exist. The Prime Minister said India did not have the first-mover advantage during the Internet era. "In the countries that had this advantage, private companies led the digital push. A revolution came, but its benefit was limited. India gave a new model to the world. India democratised technology and showed the world the way to digital public infrastructure," the Prime Minister said.</p>

<p>In India, he said, the government creates a platform and it undergoes several rounds of innovations. "Jandhan, Aadhaar and mobile connectivity have become a seamless system of fast and leakage-free service delivery. "Look at UPI, it has led to an expansion of fintech in India. More than 500 million digital transactions are happening through UPI daily. And this is not driven by big corporates, but by small shopowners and street vendors."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/vbp7vs5g_pm-modi_625x300_21_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[PM Narendra Modi delivered the keynote address at NDTV World Summit today]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-has-emerged-as-a-beacon-of-hope-pm-modi-at-ndtv-world-summit-6836512]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["In Industry 4.0, This is India's Time": PM Modi at NDTV World Summit]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-has-emerged-as-a-beacon-of-hope-pm-modi-at-ndtv-world-summit-6836512]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 10:16:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India is a beacon of hope amid global crises over economic growth, unemployment, health, and geopolitical tension over disruptions caused by COVID-19 and military conflict, Prime Minister Narendra Modi said Monday at the NDTV World Summit.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The 21st century is "India's time", Prime Minister Narendra Modi said Monday at the NDTV World Summit, declaring, "We are in the age of 'Industry 4.0' (the fourth industrial revolution) and India is no longer a slave. India is a beacon of hope amid global crises over economic growth, unemployment, health, and geopolitical tension over disruptions caused by COVID-19 and military conflict."</p>

<p>"In this summit you will discuss numerous topics but, if we look at the last four or five years... one thing is common - stress about the future," the Prime Minister said.</p>

<p>"During the coronavirus pandemic people were stressed about dealing with the virus. When that was controlled then people were worried about the economy... then climate change, the wars (in Ukraine and West Asia), global supply chains (for industries) ... these have become global worries."</p>

<p>"There are the challenges in front of India, but we feel a sense of positivity and that is why are here today - to discuss the 'India century'," the Prime Minister said as he delivered the inaugural address and welcomed speakers - including global heads of state - at the NDTV World Summit.</p>

<p>Referring to the strides India has made, the Prime Minister - who began a third term in June, after the Bharatiya Janata Party-led National Democratic Alliance won the April-June general election - called the speed and scale of that development "unprecedented".</p>

<p>He also listed welfare and infrastructural schemes - three crore new homes for the poor, Rs 9 lakh crore in infra projects, Rs 2 lakh crore for jobs for young people - announced by his government.</p>

<p>Mr Modi also pointed to a stock market that has soared seven per cent in his third term and to the country's forex reserves, which he said had now crossed the $700 billion mark.</p>

<p>"A lot is happening in India... India has picked up growth in our third term and global financial ratings companies have increased India's growth outlook," the Prime Minister said, as he also claimed dissatisfaction with the progress so far. "People ask me... 'Why are you working so hard? India is doing well.' Many people ask me this... but for the goals we have, we cannot be at rest."</p>

<p>"So, is this (what India has achieved so far) enough? My answer is no. It is not. India is a country with a young population and we have a lot to do," the PM said, haling a "change in India's vision".</p>

<p>In his speech the PM also seemed to take a swipe at his political opposition.</p>

<p>"There is a tradition... every government compares its work to the previous. We used to walk this path but, from now on, we cannot compare past and present and be happy. The metric of success from now on will be what we want to achieve... and that is a 'developed India' by 2047," he said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/41k55oso_pm-modi-ndtv-world-summit-_625x300_21_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-this-florida-couple-stole-peoples-properties-using-just-a-dollar-6836406]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How This Florida Couple Stole People's Properties Using Just A Dollar]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-this-florida-couple-stole-peoples-properties-using-just-a-dollar-6836406]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 10:09:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Florida couple is facing charges of stealing properties through a simple scam that costs less than a dollar to execute]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Florida couple is facing charges of stealing properties through a simple scam that costs less than a dollar to execute. Victor Rodriguez, 50, and his wife Michelle Cherry, 33, allegedly forged “quitclaim deeds” to illegally transfer ownership of homes, including a property owned by Rodriguez's ex-father-in-law, in Tampa and Miami-Dade County, <a href="https://www.fox13news.com/news/property-fraud-investigation-extends-from-bay-area-south-florida-court-documents ">Fox News</a> reported.</p>

<p>Caroline Sauer, Rodriguez's ex-wife, discovered the scam when she found that her father's properties had changed ownership through quitclaim deeds. “We questioned, how did this happen?” Ms Sauer said. “Who forges a deceased person's signature? Who does that?”</p>

<p>According to authorities, the scam involved forging signatures on quitclaim deeds – a legal document that transfers property ownership with the owner's consent. These documents, however, can be easily manipulated. Fraudsters only need a notary and two signatures to process the transaction, often for as little as 70 cents in Florida.</p>

<p>Rodriguez and Cherry allegedly used the same scam on another Tampa property belonging to Larry and Dreama Bilby. The Bilbys were stunned when they learned in February that someone forged their signatures and transferred ownership of their home, which was unoccupied and under construction at the time.</p>

<p>“I was so angry, I almost couldn't talk,” Dreama Bilby told Fox13.</p>

<p>Hillsborough County Clerk Cindy Stuart explained how easy it was to commit the fraud. “It only requires a notary and two signatures with an address listed next to them,” she said.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Caroline Sauer and her family are battling her ex-husband in court. “The hardest thing for us emotionally has been, we've just tried to protect my father and his legacy,” she told the outlet.</p>

<p>To prove the forgery, Ms Sauer's family hired a handwriting expert and incurred significant legal fees.</p>

<p>Rodriguez and Cherry were arrested in March and pleaded not guilty. Rodriguez's legal team maintains his innocence. “Mr. Rodriguez maintains his innocence, and our office is entrusted with the responsibility of protecting his rights,” his lawyers said in a statement, adding that they are committed to ensuring “justice and fairness in legal proceedings.”</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-02/mts5qgco_canada-house-generic-_625x300_04_February_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The couple was arrested in March and pleaded not guilty.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/king-charles-lidia-thorpe-give-our-land-back-says-lawmaker-to-king-charles-at-australian-parliament-6836254]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Not Your Land": Australia Senator Heckles King Charles At Parliament]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/king-charles-lidia-thorpe-give-our-land-back-says-lawmaker-to-king-charles-at-australian-parliament-6836254]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 09:23:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Indigenous senator Lidia Thorpe, known for her fierce opposition to the monarchy, shouted anti-colonial slogans at King Charles during his visit to the Australian parliament on Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Indigenous senator Lidia Thorpe shouted anti-colonial slogans at King Charles during his visit to the Australian parliament on Monday, shocking assembled lawmakers and other dignitaries.</p>

<p>"Give us our land back! Give us what you stole from us!" Thorpe screamed in an almost minute-long diatribe, after the 75-year-old king's speech.</p>

<p>"This is not your land, you are not my king," the independent lawmaker said, decrying what she described as a "genocide" of Indigenous Australians by European settlers.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Not the reception King Charles was hoping for in Australia as he receives an almighty heckling<br />
“Give us our land back. Give us what you stole from us.”? <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/AlwaysWasAlwaysWillbe?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#AlwaysWasAlwaysWillbe</a> <a href="https://t.co/JEYJ5Y7BEd">pic.twitter.com/JEYJ5Y7BEd</a></p>
— stranger (@strangerous10) <a href="https://twitter.com/strangerous10/status/1848203654060290438?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 21, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Australia was a British colony for more than 100 years, during which time thousands of Aboriginal Australians were killed and entire communities displaced.</p>

<p>The country gained de facto independence in 1901, but has never become a fully fledged republic. King Charles is the current head of state.</p>

<p>Charles is on a nine-day jaunt through Australia and Samoa, the first major foreign tour since his life-changing cancer diagnosis earlier this year.</p>

<p>Thorpe is known for her attention-grabbing political stunts and fierce opposition to the monarchy.</p>

<p>When she was sworn into office in 2022, Thorpe raised her right fist as she begrudgingly swore to serve Queen Elisabeth II, who was then Australia's head of state.</p>

<p>"I sovereign, Lidia Thorpe, do solemnly and sincerely swear that I will be faithful and I bear true allegiance to the colonising Her Majesty Queen Elizabeth II," she said before being rebuked by a Senate official.</p>

<p>"Senator Thorpe, Senator Thorpe, you are required to recite the oath as printed on the card," said the chamber's president Sue Lines.</p>

<p>In 1999, Australians narrowly voted against removing the queen, amid a row over whether her replacement would be chosen by members of parliament, not the public.</p>

<p>In 2023 Australians overwhelmingly rejected measures to recognise Indigenous Australians in the constitution and to create an Indigenous consultative assembly.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/486o395o_king-charles-_625x300_21_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[King Charles is on a nine-day jaunt through Australia]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/looking-forward-to-addressing-ndtv-world-summit-pm-modi-6836251]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Looking Forward To Addressing NDTV World Summit": PM Modi]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/looking-forward-to-addressing-ndtv-world-summit-pm-modi-6836251]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 09:22:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Narendra Modi said on Sunday that he is looking forward to addressing the 'NDTV World Summit 2024 - The India Century' which will take place today.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi said on Sunday that he is looking forward to addressing the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://special.ndtv.com/ndtv-world-summit-2024-167/">'NDTV World Summit 2024 - The India Century' </a>which will take place today.</p>

<p>"At 10 AM tomorrow morning, I look forward to addressing the #NDTVWorldSummit on 'The India Century.' India's growth trajectory has truly captured global attention. Our Yuva Shakti is taking our nation to new heights. I will be talking about India's key strides and why we remain a global bright spot," the Prime Minister wrote on X.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">At 10 AM tomorrow morning, I look forward to addressing the <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/NDTVWorldSummit?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#NDTVWorldSummit</a> on ‘The India Century.' India's growth trajectory has truly captured global attention. Our Yuva Shakti is taking our nation to new heights. I will be talking about India's key strides and why we remain a…</p>
— Narendra Modi (@narendramodi) <a href="https://twitter.com/narendramodi/status/1848042562214355194?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 20, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>The two-day NDTV World Summit will see PM Modi speak on his vision for a developed India by 2047.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The "NDTV World Summit 2024 - The India Century" will also feature former UK Prime Minister David Cameron and External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar, among a host of other dignitaries, to discuss key global issues.</p>

<p>The NDTV World Summit will also see the participation of Tshering Tobgay, Prime Minister of Bhutan; Mia Mottley, Prime Minister of Barbados; Prof. Paul Romer, Nobel Laureate, Economics, 2018 &amp; Former Chief Economist, World Bank and William Dalrymple, Author &amp; Historian.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/ui2un49o_narendra-modi-pti-modi-namaste-pti_625x300_23_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The NDTV World Summit is a two-day meet scheduled for October 21 and 22.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>