<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Thu, 11 Jul 2024 03:12:58 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-pm-starmer-vows-robust-ukraine-support-on-international-debut-6078973]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK PM Starmer Vows Robust Ukraine Support On International Debut]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-pm-starmer-vows-robust-ukraine-support-on-international-debut-6078973]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 11 Jul 2024 02:39:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[New Prime Minister Keir Starmer promised Wednesday to keep up Britain's steadfast support for Ukraine and gave his blessing for strikes inside Russia with British missiles as he made his international debut at a NATO summit in Washington.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>New Prime Minister Keir Starmer promised Wednesday to keep up Britain's steadfast support for Ukraine and gave his blessing for strikes inside Russia with British missiles as he made his international debut at a NATO summit in Washington.</p>

<p>Starmer's unstinting message of continuity on Ukraine comes as questions grow over Kyiv's most vital partner, the United States, where presidential contender Donald Trump has mused about cutting a quick deal with Russia.</p>

<p>Days after his Labour Party swept elections and threw out the Conservatives in power for 14 years, Starmer said he had a "very good" meeting with Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky on the sidelines of NATO's 75th anniversary summit.</p>

<p>"I made it absolutely clear that as far as the UK is concerned, the change of government makes no difference to the support that we will provide," Starmer told reporters.</p>

<p>"We'd been united on this when we were in opposition, and it was really important to me to be able to affirm that face to face at the meeting," said Starmer, who already spoke to Zelensky by telephone after entering Downing Street.</p>

<p>On his flight to Washington, Starmer said that decisions on the use of British-supplied Storm Shadow missiles were for the Ukrainian armed forces to make.</p>

<p>UK military aid is "for defensive purposes but it is for Ukraine to decide how to deploy it for those defensive purposes," he said.</p>

<p>Britain under three Conservative prime ministers has been among the staunchest supporters of Ukraine in the war, taking the lead in pushing for more advanced military systems and looser restrictions on Kyiv.</p>

<p>US President Joe Biden, who has strongly backed Ukraine but has been careful not to start a direct conflict with Russia, recently made a similar move by letting Ukraine strike Russian offensive positions just across the border with US weapons.</p>

<p>Zelensky hailed the decision on the Storm Shadow missiles, writing on Telegram, "Thank you for your continued support of Ukraine and our people!"</p>

<p>Kremlin spokesman Dmitry Peskov warned that Russia will take "appropriate measures" in response to Starmer's decision.</p>

<p>"If it is true, it is certainly another absolutely irresponsible step towards fueling tensions and seriously escalating the situation," Peskov told reporters.</p>

<p><strong>- 'Clear-eyed' on Russia -</strong></p>

<p>Starmer will meet later with Biden at the White House, and spoke with other Western leaders including French President Emmanuel Macron.</p>

<p>Starmer has taken Labour on a more centrist path than his leftist predecessor and, along with his foreign and defense secretaries, all noted in Washington that Britain helped found NATO in 1949 under Labour prime minister Clement Atlee.</p>

<p>Starmer said he hoped the NATO summit would send a message to Russian President Vladimir Putin that the alliance is "bigger now than it's ever been, more united than it's ever been, and absolutely clear-eyed about the threat of Russian aggression."</p>

<p>A NATO summit in Britain in 2014 set a goal of each ally contributing at least two percent of GDP to defense, a long-running demand of the United States.</p>

<p>Only the United States, Britain and Greece then met the target but since the invasion of Ukraine the number has gone up to 23 members of the 32-nation alliance.</p>

<p>Britain's new defense secretary, John Healey, called for NATO to consider moving toward a 2.5 percent goal.</p>

<p>The growing threats around the world suggest that "all NATO nations are going to need to do more than simply two percent," Healey told reporters.</p>

<p>He said, whatever the result of the US election, Washington's priorities are "increasingly going to shift to the Indo-Pacific."</p>

<p>"European nations in NATO must do more of the heavy lifting," Healey said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/n2t3o094_keir-starmer_625x300_11_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Starmer will meet later with Biden at the White House.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nato-leaders-express-profound-concern-over-china-russia-ties-6078947]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[NATO Leaders Express "Profound Concern" Over China-Russia Ties]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nato-leaders-express-profound-concern-over-china-russia-ties-6078947]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 11 Jul 2024 02:23:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[NATO leaders on Wednesday said China's deepening ties with Russia are a cause of "deep concern" and accused Beijing of playing a key role in helping Moscow's assault on Ukraine.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>NATO leaders on Wednesday said China's deepening ties with Russia are a cause of "deep concern" and accused Beijing of playing a key role in helping Moscow's assault on Ukraine.</p>

<p>China "has become a decisive enabler of Russia's war against Ukraine through its so-called 'no limits' partnership and its large-scale support for Russia's defense industrial base," NATO leaders said in a declaration from their summit in Washington.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/iqkn6re4_nato-meet_625x300_11_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[NATO leaders accused Beijing of playing a key role in helping Moscow's assault on Ukraine.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-has-given-buddha-to-the-world-not-yuddha-pm-modi-in-austria-6078393]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India Has Given 'Buddha' To The World, Not ' Yuddha ': PM Modi In Austria]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-has-given-buddha-to-the-world-not-yuddha-pm-modi-in-austria-6078393]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 10 Jul 2024 23:38:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Narendra Modi on Wednesday said India has given 'Buddha' to the world, not 'Yuddha' (war) which means it has always given peace and prosperity, and therefore the country is going to strengthen its role in the 21st century.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi on Wednesday said India has given 'Buddha' to the world, not 'Yuddha' (war) which means it has always given peace and prosperity, and therefore the country is going to strengthen its role in the 21st century.</p>

<p>Addressing the Indian community in Vienna, PM Modi also said that India is working towards being the best, the brightest, achieving the biggest and reaching the highest milestones.</p>

<p>"For thousands of years, we have been sharing our knowledge and expertise. We didn't give 'Yuddha' (war), we gave the world 'Buddha'. India always gave peace and prosperity, and therefore India is going to strengthen its role in the 21st century," PM Modi said in Austria, a day after he arrived here from Moscow where he highlighted the importance of finding a peaceful solution to the Ukraine conflict during his talks with President Vladimir Putin.</p>

<p>Describing his first visit to Austria as "meaningful", PM Modi said that after 41 years, an Indian Prime Minister has visited the country.</p>

<p>"This long wait has come to an end on a historic occasion. India and Austria are celebrating 75 years of their friendship," he said.</p>

<p>"India and Austria are geographically on two different ends, but we have many similarities. Democracy connects both countries. Our shared values are liberty, equality, pluralism, and respect for the rule of law. Our societies are multicultural and multilingual. Both countries celebrate diversity, and a big medium to reflect these values are elections," he said, amid chants of 'Modi, Modi'.</p>

<p>Recalling the recently concluded general elections, PM Modi said 650 million people exercised their right to vote and despite such a big election, the results of the elections were declared within hours.</p>

<p>"It is the power of our electoral machinery and democracy," he said.</p>

<p>More than 31,000 Indians are living in Austria. The number of Indian students in the country is more than 450, according to the Indian embassy here.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/71p053lo_modi_625x300_10_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["For thousands of years, we have been sharing our knowledge and expertise," he said.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/people-in-west-dissatisfied-with-state-of-democracy-indians-say-6078202]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[People In West Dissatisfied With State Of Democracy, Indians Say...]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/people-in-west-dissatisfied-with-state-of-democracy-indians-say-6078202]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 10 Jul 2024 23:01:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Elections are taking place in major democracies across the globe, incorporating almost half of the world's population. The United States will go to polls in November.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Elections are taking place in major democracies across the globe, incorporating almost half of the world's population. The United States will go to polls in November. Halfway through the year, elections have taken place in Russia, South Korea, the European Union, Belgium, Mexico, Pakistan, France, and Taiwan. India, the world's largest democracy, concluded the electoral exercise in human history.</p>

<p>Interestingly, a report from Pew Research suggests that high-income nations, mostly in the West, are dissatisfied with the way democracy is working in their country.</p>

<h2><strong>Who All Are Dissatisfied?</strong></h2>

<p>The Pew Research Center conducted over 900 interviews in 27 countries and asked respondents, "How satisfied are you with the democracy working in your country?"</p>

<p>In North America, 68 per cent of people are dissatisfied with the current functioning of democracy. The decline in satisfaction witnessed since 2021, shows a 10 per cent dip in the US. In Mexico, an equal percentage of respondents were satisfied and dissatisfied. In Canada under Prime Minister Justin Trudeau, only 52 per cent of people are okay with the functioning of democracy.&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.pewresearch.org/short-reads/2024/06/18/satisfaction-with-democracy-has-declined-in-recent-years-in-high-income-nations/sr_2024-06-18_satisfaction-democracy_3/"><em>Read the full report here</em></a></p>

<p>In Europe, only Sweden fared well, with 75 per cent of respondents feeling satisfied with the way democracy is. Interestingly, France, one of the oldest democracies in the world saw 35 per cent pleased. &nbsp;Greece was the lowest at 22 per cent.</p>

<p>In Asia, only Singapore and India reported over 75% satisfaction. In India, 77 per cent were satisfied with the way democracy is. In Singapore, the percentage stands at 80 per cent. Japan was at the lowest at 31 per cent.</p>

<p>Out of 27 countries, over 50 per cent of respondents in 11 countries are satisfied with democracy. Respondents from 11 countries in the west out of 17, are not majorly not satisfied.</p>

<p>The UK saw a major shift in political inclination with the Conservatives under Rishi Sunak voted out and Keir Starmer's Labour securing a landslide win after 13 years. In France, a major political turmoil is being witnessed as the &nbsp;National Assembly delivered a hung parliament, making it hard to know who will be in key government positions.</p>

<p>In the US, Joe Biden is seeking another term amid concerns over his health, while Donald Trump, who is facing legal troubles, is hoping to come back to power.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Claudia Sheinbaum was elected Mexico's first woman president by a landslide, making history in a country plagued by rampant criminal and gender-based violence.</p>

<p>Putin tightened its grip on Russia with a reelection which saw little to no opposition. He has been in power since the last day of 1999, he is now on course to become the longest-serving Russian leader in more than two centuries.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/ktsmedf_uk-generic_625x300_23_May_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Out of 27 countries, over 50 per cent of respondents in 11 countries are satisfied with democracy]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/quantum-tech-spirituality-what-pm-modi-discussed-with-nobel-laureate-anton-zeilinger-6078003]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Quantum Tech, Spirituality: What PM Modi Discussed With Nobel Laureate]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/quantum-tech-spirituality-what-pm-modi-discussed-with-nobel-laureate-anton-zeilinger-6078003]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 10 Jul 2024 22:33:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Narendra Modi on Wednesday met Austrian Nobel physics laureate Anton Zeilinger and explored the possibilities around quantum technologies, along with a discussion over spirituality.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi on Wednesday met Austrian Nobel physics laureate Anton Zeilinger and explored the possibilities around quantum technologies, along with a discussion over spirituality.</p>

<p>After meeting PM Modi, the Austrian scientist said he experienced that PM Modi is a very spiritual person.</p>

<p>"I think this is the feature that many leaders in the world should have today," said Mr Zeilinger.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Had an excellent meeting with Nobel Laureate Anton Zeilinger. His work in quantum mechanics is pathbreaking and will continue to guide generations of researchers and innovators. His passion for knowledge and learning was clearly visible. I talked about India's efforts like the… <a href="https://t.co/YVCnGEu8fR">pic.twitter.com/YVCnGEu8fR</a></p>
— Narendra Modi (@narendramodi) <a href="https://twitter.com/narendramodi/status/1811077035210510756?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 10, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>"We discussed the possibilities of Quantum Information and Quantum technologies, and also spirituality," he added. Zeilinger is a Professor of Physics Emeritus at the University of Vienna and a senior scientist at the Institute for Quantum Optics and Quantum Information of the Austrian Academy of Sciences.</p>

<p>In October 2022, he received the Nobel Prize in Physics, jointly with Alain Aspect and John Clauser for their work involving experiments with entangled photons, establishing the violation of Bell inequalities, and pioneering quantum information science.</p>

<p>Earlier in the day, PM Modi held talks with Austrian Chancellor Karl Nehammer and said a blueprint for cooperation over the coming decades has been prepared, including artificial intelligence (AI), and quantum technology. India has produced over 40 quantum technology startups in two years, a few of them with global potential. India is currently on an equal pedestal with other nations in terms of quantum technologies.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/b0f9u9qg_pm-modi-and-nobel-laureate_625x300_10_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Prime Minister Narendra Modi met Austrian Nobel physics laureate Anton Zeilinger]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistan-extends-1-45-million-afghan-refugees-right-to-remain-by-1-year-6077968]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Pakistan Extends 1.45 Million Afghan Refugees' Right To Remain By 1 Year]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistan-extends-1-45-million-afghan-refugees-right-to-remain-by-1-year-6077968]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 10 Jul 2024 22:29:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Some 1.45 million Afghan refugees in Pakistan will be allowed to stay for another year, Islamabad said Wednesday, but it insisted evictions of undocumented migrants would continue.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Some 1.45 million Afghan refugees in Pakistan will be allowed to stay for another year, Islamabad said Wednesday, but it insisted evictions of undocumented migrants would continue.</p>

<p>More than 600,000 Afghans have fled Pakistan since Islamabad last year ordered undocumented migrants to leave or face arrest as relations with Kabul soured over security.</p>

<p>Human rights monitors warned those sent to Taliban-ruled Afghanistan were given little support and some faced persecution by Kabul's new rulers.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Shehbaz Sharif's cabinet said it approved an extension until June 2025 for the 1.45 million Afghan refugees legally residing in the country who hold Proof of Registration cards.</p>

<p>The cards expired at the end of last month, leaving holders without legal certainty about their right to remain in Pakistan.</p>

<p>Not all Afghan citizens in Pakistan have such cards and even those who do hold them have reported being harassed and intimidated to leave the country.</p>

<p>Islamabad's announcement came the day after a three-day visit by the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR), Filippo Grandi.</p>

<p>In a statement on Tuesday, the UNHCR said Grandi "expressed appreciation that the 'Illegal Foreigners Repatriation Plan' had been suspended".</p>

<p>However a foreign office spokeswoman said "this is not true".</p>

<p>Mumtaz Zahra Baloch told reporters in a statement: "No such understanding has been given by Pakistan to the UNHCR" and the scheme "remains in place and is being implemented in an orderly and phased manner".</p>

<p>Meanwhile, a Pakistani immigration official at the Torkham border crossing said they had begun seizing documents, including refugee registration cards, from departing Afghans.</p>

<p>"We are implementing this directive following instructions from the Ministry of Interior," said the official at the busiest crossing between Pakistan and Afghanistan.</p>

<p>"This measure aims to ensure they do not return to Pakistan and instead depart permanently, though they may re-enter after obtaining a visa," he told AFP on condition of anonymity.</p>

<p>Millions of Afghans have poured into Pakistan over the years, fleeing decades of cascading conflict.</p>

<p>An estimated 600,000 arrived since the Taliban government seized power in August 2021 and imposed its stark interpretation of Islamic law.</p>

<p>Islamabad has previously said its massive eviction scheme is justified by security concerns and its faltering economy.</p>

<p>Analysts say it is pressuring Kabul over rising attacks in Pakistan's border regions with Afghanistan, where the Taliban government is accused of giving militants safe haven.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-11/5rdl4q1_pakistan-immigrants_625x300_02_November_23.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[An estimated 600,000 arrived since the Taliban government seized power in August 2021. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/43-get-lifetime-imprisonment-in-uae-over-terrorist-links-report-6077756]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[43 Get Lifetime Imprisonment In UAE Over "Terrorist" Links: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/43-get-lifetime-imprisonment-in-uae-over-terrorist-links-report-6077756]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 10 Jul 2024 21:56:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A court in the United Arab Emirates has handed life sentences to 43 Emiratis for "terrorist" links, state media said Wednesday, after a mass trial heavily criticised by UN experts and rights groups.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A court in the United Arab Emirates has handed life sentences to 43 Emiratis for "terrorist" links, state media said Wednesday, after a mass trial heavily criticised by UN experts and rights groups.</p>

<p>Government critics and human rights activists were among the 84 defendants brought before the Abu Dhabi Federal Court of Appeal, most of whom have been in jail since a similar trial of 94 people in 2013, according to rights groups.</p>

<p>The Abu Dhabi court "sentenced 43 defendants to life imprisonment for the crime of creating, establishing, and managing a terrorist organisation" linked to the outlawed Muslim Brotherhood, the official WAM news agency said.</p>

<p>Ten others were jailed for 10-15 years, WAM said, with one defendant acquitted and 24 cases ruled inadmissible. It did not give details of the remaining cases.</p>

<p>Defendants can still appeal the verdicts before the Federal Supreme Court.</p>

<p>The trial, which kicked off in December, has been condemned by rights groups and United Nations experts who accuse the oil-rich Gulf monarchy of cracking down on dissent.</p>

<p>Most of the defendants have already been in prison for more than a decade since the "UAE 94" trial 11 years ago, according to Human Rights Watch (HRW) and Amnesty International.</p>

<p>But UAE authorities say the latest charges are "materially distinct" from those brought in 2013, which did not include accusations of financing a "terrorist organisation".</p>

<p>- 'Violent events' -</p>

<p>The UAE has not named the 84 defendants but the Emirates Detainees Advocacy Center, a UK-based watchdog, has identified more than 70 people, most of them already imprisoned.</p>

<p>The latest verdict makes a "mockery of justice", said Joey Shea, HRW's UAE researcher, calling it "another nail in the coffin for the UAE's nascent civil society".</p>

<p>Among those sentenced to life in prison is Emirati academic Nasser bin Ghaith who has been held since August 2015 over social media posts, according to Shea.</p>

<p>Renowned human rights defender Ahmed Mansoor who has been held since 2017 is also likely among thos convicted, though the details of his sentence remain unclear, Shea said.</p>

<p>Amnesty International called it a "shameless parody of justice," alleging fair trial violations.</p>

<p>"Trying 84 Emiratis at once, including 26 prisoners of conscience and well-known human rights defenders is a scarcely disguised exercise in punishing dissenters," said Devin Kenney, Amnesty's UAE Researcher.</p>

<p>The UAE has denied any wrongdoing.</p>

<p>WAM said the court had "guaranteed the defendants all their rights".</p>

<p>The report said they were trying to "create and replicate violent events" that would have left "dead and injured in the squares and streets".</p>

<p>- 'Deeply regressive' -</p>

<p>The UAE, a federation of seven absolute monarchies, prohibits criticism of its rulers and any speech that is deemed to create or encourage social unrest.</p>

<p>Defamation as well as verbal and written insults, whether published or made privately, are crimes punishable by fines and imprisonment.</p>

<p>In 2012, in the wake of the so-called Arab Spring revolts across the Middle East, the UAE launched a spate of arrests and prosecutions targeting dozens of Emirati dissidents who demanded political reform.</p>

<p>About 60 of the "UAE 94" put on trial then remain behind bars for alleged links to the Muslim Brotherhood, an Islamist movement that is outlawed in the Gulf state.</p>

<p>In a letter sent to UAE authorities in January, independent UN experts said they were concerned that the latest proceedings against the 84 defendants reflect "a broader pattern of suppression of dissent and civil society in the UAE".</p>

<p>They questioned "alleged irregularities" such as "the use of torture or other cruel, inhuman, or degrading treatment or punishment to extract forced confessions".</p>

<p>Ben Saul, the UN's special rapporteur on human rights and counter-terrorism, said the latest charges "relate to the same conduct for which many of these defendants were tried the first time around a decade ago".</p>

<p>The trial was a "deeply regressive step" and a "terrible example of the misuse of counter-terrorism measures against civil society", he told an expert panel hosted by the Geneva Press Club in March.</p>

<p>Last week, HRW said many of the defendants have been kept incommunicado for at least a year and have reported abuses including physical assault, lack of access to medicine, incessant loud music and forced nudity.</p>

<p>The wealthy country's allies, including the United States, Britain and the European Union, should speak out about the "unfair mass trial", HRW said.</p>

<p>"Emirati authorities have long used their country's economic and security relationships to prevent criticism of its rights record, but rarely, if ever, has the silence from its allies been so deafening," said HRW's Shea.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2019-07/att9hsso_court-generic_625x300_27_July_19.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Defendants can still appeal the verdicts before the Federal Supreme Court. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rare-mid-sized-black-hole-spotted-at-center-of-swallowed-galaxy-study-6077697]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Rare Mid-Sized Black Hole Spotted At Center Of Swallowed Galaxy: Study]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rare-mid-sized-black-hole-spotted-at-center-of-swallowed-galaxy-study-6077697]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 10 Jul 2024 21:46:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Astronomers have scrutinized a cluster of stars that is the apparent remnant core of a relatively small galaxy that was swallowed by the sprawling Milky Way 8 to 10 billion years ago. What lurks at the center of this cluster has them excited.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Astronomers have scrutinized a cluster of stars that is the apparent remnant core of a relatively small galaxy that was swallowed by the sprawling Milky Way 8 to 10 billion years ago. What lurks at the center of this cluster has them excited.</p>

<p>The researchers said on Wednesday the unusual motion of seven stars in this cluster provides compelling evidence for the presence of an elusive mid-sized black hole at its heart. These are bigger than the class of ordinary black holes formed in the implosion of a single star but smaller than the behemoths residing at the nucleus of most galaxies.</p>

<p>The cluster, called Omega Centauri, contains about 10 million stars. The black hole within it is at least 8,200 times as massive as our sun, the researchers said.</p>

<p>The supermassive black hole called Sagittarius A* at the center of the Milky Way possesses 4 million times the mass of the sun. And that is dwarfed by supermassive black holes billions of times the mass of the sun in other galaxies.</p>

<p>"There has been a long debate whether intermediate-mass black holes exist in general, and specifically in Omega Centauri, and our detection might help to resolve that debate," said astronomer Maximilian Haberle of the Max Planck Institute for Astronomy in Germany, lead author of the study published in the journal Nature.</p>

<p>This black hole is located about 17,700 light-years from Earth. A light-year is the distance light travels in a year, 5.9 trillion miles (9.5 trillion km). The Milky Way's only larger-known black hole is Sagittarius A*, located about 26,700 light years from Earth.</p>

<p>Black holes are extraordinarily dense objects with gravity so strong not even light can escape, making it difficult to spot them. This one was detected based on how its gravitational pull influences the velocity of seven fast-moving stars in its vicinity, documented in two decades of Hubble Space Telescope observations.</p>

<p>The researchers believe the smaller galaxy, which had been perhaps 10% the Milky Way's size, harbored a black hole that, if left undisturbed, would have become supermassive as it fed off gas and other nearby material drawn by its gravitational pull. But the galactic merger, which occurred when the Milky Way was about a quarter or third its current age, left the black hole frozen in time.</p>

<p>"In this merger process, the galaxy lost all of its gas, and hence the growth of its central black hole got interrupted, leaving it in an intermediate-mass state," Max Planck Institute for Astronomy astronomer and study co-author Nadine Neumayer said.</p>

<p>The merger stripped away most of the smaller galaxy's stars, leaving just the central batch - now the Omega Centauri star cluster.</p>

<p>"Intermediate-mass black holes have been suspected in the centers of low-mass galaxies or also in the center of certain star clusters. However, they have been very challenging to detect. Due to their lower mass with respect to supermassive black holes, their region of influence is small," Haberle said.</p>

<p>Other candidates for mid-sized black holes have been identified in previous research.</p>

<p>Black holes that are the mass of a single star form when large stars explode at the end of their life cycle and the core collapses in on itself.</p>

<p>"The most likely scenario for the formation of the intermediate-mass black hole at the center of Omega Centauri is the collision and merging of very massive stars very early on during the formation of the star cluster. These stars get very close to each other, collide and form even more massive stars that evolve to black holes fairly rapidly. The intermediate-mass black hole can grow via the merger of several of these black holes," Neumayer said.</p>

<p>These mid-sized black holes may be the key to understanding the formation of the supermassive ones.</p>

<p>"Intermediate-mass black holes are likely very common, especially in the early evolution of the universe," Neumayer said. "They are thought to be the seeds for supermassive black holes."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/35355b9g_black-hole-awakening_625x300_18_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Black holes are extraordinarily dense objects. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-austria-agree-to-push-for-quicker-india-european-union-free-trade-deal-6077676]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India, Austria Agree To Push for Quicker India-EU Free Trade Deal]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-austria-agree-to-push-for-quicker-india-european-union-free-trade-deal-6077676]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 10 Jul 2024 21:42:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Emphasising that India and the European Union have "the largest and most vibrant free-market space in the world," India and Austria on Wednesday discussed the India-EU relationship and said the long-pending EU Free Trade Agreement must be expedited.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Emphasising that India and the European Union have "the largest and most vibrant free-market space in the world," India and Austria on Wednesday discussed the India-EU relationship and said the long-pending EU Free Trade Agreement must be expedited.</p>

<p>Noting that deeper EU-India ties will be mutually beneficial as well as have a positive global impact, Austrian Chancellor Karl Nehammer and Prime Minister Narendra Modi also reaffirmed their strong support for the ongoing India-EU trade and investment negotiations and the early implementation of the EU-India Connectivity Partnership.</p>

<p>PM Modi paid an official two-day visit to Austria at the invitation of Chancellor Nehammer, the first visit to Austria of an Indian Prime Minister after 41 years in a year that marks the 75th year of diplomatic relations between the two countries.</p>

<p>"A set of issues on which both Chancellor and the Prime Minister focused was India-EU relationship, as you know, in their EU Free Trade Agreement (FTA) has been under negotiation for over 23 years," Foreign Secretary Vinay Kwatra said at a media briefing here on PM Modi's visit.</p>

<p>"Prime Minister Modi and the Austrian Chancellor agreed that this was an awfully long time for discussions to have been dragged on and they agreed that this is something that both India and they should try to try in terms of taking it forward at a quicker pace," Mr Kwatra said.</p>

<p>"They of course, also spoke about the range of opportunities both in the economic and political space," he said, adding, "They are in India-EU partnership and also how India-Austria relationship positions synergistically in the overall India-EU relationship."&nbsp;</p>

<p>The EU is India's third largest trading partner, accounting for 88 billion Euros worth of trade in goods in 2021 or 10.8 per cent of total Indian trade. India is the EU's 10th largest trading partner, accounting for 2.1 per cent of EU total trade in goods. Trade in services between the EU and India reached 30.4 billion Euros in 2020, according to the figures available on the EU website.</p>

<p>An India-Austria joint statement at the end of the official state visit said the two leaders emphasised that India and the European Union have the largest and most vibrant free-market space in the world, and noted that deeper EU-India ties will be mutually beneficial as well as have a positive global impact.</p>

<p>"Chancellor Nehammer and Prime Minister Modi agreed to support various initiatives to bring India and the EU closer. In this context, they reaffirmed their strong support for the ongoing India-EU trade and investment negotiations and the early implementation of the EU-India Connectivity Partnership," it said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/rn0emf0o_modi-austria_625x300_10_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[PM Modi paid an official two-day visit to Austria]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-supporter-george-clooney-requests-him-to-leave-presidential-race-6077438]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden Supporter George Clooney Requests Him To Leave Presidential Race]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-supporter-george-clooney-requests-him-to-leave-presidential-race-6077438]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 10 Jul 2024 21:02:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Actor George Clooney, one of the Democratic Party's leading fundraisers, on Wednesday made an emotional and heartfelt plea for President Joe Biden to end his faltering reelection campaign.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Actor George Clooney, one of the Democratic Party's leading fundraisers, on Wednesday made an emotional and heartfelt plea for President Joe Biden to end his faltering reelection campaign.</p>

<p>Clooney -- a member of the Hollywood elite that provides key support to the Democrats -- joined a growing list of public figures calling for Biden, 81, to step aside after his terrible debate performance against Donald Trump last month.</p>

<p>"I love Joe Biden," Clooney wrote in the New York Times. "I consider him a friend, and I believe in him... But the one battle he cannot win is the fight against time."</p>

<p>A self-described "lifelong Democrat," Clooney co-hosted a star-studded fundraiser with Biden in Los Angeles only last month featuring former president Barack Obama.</p>

<p>The Biden campaign said that the event brought in a record $28 million.</p>

<p>"It's devastating to say it, but the Joe Biden I was with three weeks ago at the fund-raiser was not the Joe 'big F-ing deal' Biden of 2010," Clooney wrote, referencing a famous hot-mic clip from Biden's vice presidency.</p>

<p>"He wasn't even the Joe Biden of 2020. He was the same man we all witnessed at the debate," Clooney said -- a direct challenge to Biden's claim that his poor debate showing was a one-off.</p>

<p>"The dam has broken" on Democratic lawmakers publicly calling for Biden to withdraw, Clooney said, asking more come forward.</p>

<p>"Top Democrats -- Chuck Schumer, Hakeem Jeffries, Nancy Pelosi -- and senators, representatives and other candidates who face losing in November need to ask this president to voluntarily step aside."</p>

<p>The Oscar-winner brushed aside worries that Biden's exit would create chaos four months before an election in which the Democrats hope to keep Trump from power, and did not endorse a replacement candidate.</p>

<p>The party should hear from contenders such as Vice President Kamala Harris, Maryland Governor Wes Moore and others, "then we could go into the Democratic convention next month and figure it out," he wrote.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-11/njeophf_george-clooney_625x300_18_November_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["I love Joe Biden," George Clooney wrote in the New York Times. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/historic-game-changing-russia-on-outcomes-of-pm-modi-putin-talks-6076727]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Historic, Game-Changing": Russia On Outcomes Of PM Modi, Putin Talks]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/historic-game-changing-russia-on-outcomes-of-pm-modi-putin-talks-6076727]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 10 Jul 2024 19:25:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Narendra Modi's two-day visit to Moscow and the outcomes of his summit talks with President Vladimir Putin were "historic and game-changing" considering the prevailing turbulent geopolitical environment, Russia's Charge d'affaires Roma]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi's two-day visit to Moscow and the outcomes of his summit talks with President Vladimir Putin were "historic and game-changing" considering the prevailing turbulent geopolitical environment, Russia's Charge d'affaires Roman Babushkin said on Wednesday.</p>

<p>The Russian diplomat said the focus of the talks between the two leaders was on expanding India-Russia trade and economic ties.</p>

<p>In his first trip since the start of Russia's invasion of Ukraine, PM Modi paid a two-day visit to Moscow on July 8 and 9 during which he held summit talks with Putin.</p>

<p>"The leaders have decided to strengthen cooperation in all areas. It is a historic and game-changing move, especially given the turbulent environment around us," Mr Babushkin said at a media briefing.</p>

<p>"It has got unprecedented coverage and presumably overshadowed all other events. It seemed that the whole world was watching it," he said.</p>

<p>Mr Babushkin also criticised the US for making certain comments ahead of PM Modi's visit to Moscow and described the remarks as interference in ties between the two nations.</p>

<p>"It was the conduct of two independent global powers based on mutual trust and respect. The external factors don't play much role when it comes to Russia-India relations," he said.</p>

<p>India and Russia have established foundational convergences in key areas of our cooperation, he said.</p>

<p>The senior diplomat said both sides vowed to expand cooperation in a range of key areas including fossil fuel, nuclear energy and trade.</p>

<p>Highlighting key outcomes of the summit talks, Babushkin said India and Russia decided to go ahead with a bilateral payment system using national currencies.</p>

<p>If you noticed, one of the most important points of the joint statement was that we have decided to go ahead with the establishment of a payment system under the framework of national currency settlement, he said.</p>

<p>In the PM &nbsp;Modi-Putin talks, the two sides set a target of USD 100 billion in annual trade volume by 2030 and vowed to develop a robust bilateral payment settlement mechanism using national currencies.</p>

<p>On India's demand to Russia to ensure the return of Indians working in the Russian Army, he said, "We are on the same page with India on this issue." We hope it will be resolved soon, he said when the Indians return home.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/u8f6mif_pm-modi-and-putin_625x300_09_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[PM Modi paid a two-day visit to Moscow on July 8 and 9 (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/june-2024-becomes-the-12th-month-to-surpass-1-5-degrees-celsius-global-warming-threshold-6076578]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[June 2024 Becomes The 12th Month to Surpass 1.5 Degrees Warming Threshold]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/june-2024-becomes-the-12th-month-to-surpass-1-5-degrees-celsius-global-warming-threshold-6076578]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 10 Jul 2024 19:02:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[As the world grapples with climate change and soaring temperatures, a worrying statistic has come to light - last month was the hottest June ever recorded on earth, according to the European Union's climate agency.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As the world grapples with climate change and soaring temperatures, a worrying statistic has come to light - last month was the hottest June ever recorded on earth, according to the European Union's climate agency. Not just that, June also became the 12th consecutive month to surpass the 1.5 degrees celsius threshold for global warming.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The last month was 0.14 degrees warmer than June 2023, said <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://climate.copernicus.eu/copernicus-june-2024-marks-12th-month-global-temperature-reaching-15degc-above-pre-industrial">EU's Copernicus Climate Change Service</a> (C3S) report. The figures from the EU's climate agency highlight that each month over the past year has consistently broken records for unprecedented heat, making it the hottest respective month ever recorded on the planet. While it is an unusual phenomenon, a similar streak of monthly global temperature records happened previously in 2015-2016.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The 1.5 degrees global warming mark was internationally accepted in the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://unfccc.int/files/essential_background/convention/application/pdf/english_paris_agreement.pdf">2015 Paris agreement</a>, where the world leaders of over 200 nations agreed to limit the increase in global average temperature to 1.5 degrees Celsius over pre-industrial levels to reduce the risks and impacts of climate change. &nbsp;</p>

<p>According to C3S Director Carlo Buontempo, the record-breaking temperatures in the last one year point to a "large and continuing shift in our climate." "Even if this specific streak of extremes ends at some point, we are bound to see new records being broken as the climate continues to warm. This is inevitable, unless we stop adding [greenhouse gases] into the atmosphere and the oceans," he said in a statement. &nbsp;</p>

<p>The new concerning figures also point out that 2024 could surpass 2023 as the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/2024-could-be-worlds-hottest-year-as-june-breaks-records-6063105">hottest year ever </a>recorded, said a report by news agency Reuters.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to Zeke Hausfather, a research scientist at US non-profit Berkeley Earth, there is an approximately 95% chance that 2024 beats 2023 to be the warmest year since global surface temperature records began in the mid-1800s.&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Finally, with the first six months of data in for the year, I now estimate that there is an approximately 95% chance that 2024 beats 2023 to be the warmest year since global surface temperature records began in the mid-1800s: <a href="https://t.co/nWLfRJ7Yd8">pic.twitter.com/nWLfRJ7Yd8</a></p>
— Zeke Hausfather (@hausfath) <a href="https://twitter.com/hausfath/status/1808411956564361542?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 3, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The soaring temperatures across the globe brought with them devastating consequences. Over 1,300 people reportedly died during Hajj this year, said Saudi Arabia.&nbsp;</p>

<p>India reported over 40,000 cases of suspected heat stroke and over 100 heat-related deaths during the relentless and continuous heatwave. According to the Centre for Holistic Development, a non-governmental organization, as many as 192 homeless deaths were reported in Delhi during June 11-19.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/m4omo1m_india-heatwave-reuters_625x300_20_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The 1.5 degrees global warming mark was globally accepted in 2015 Paris agreement (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/public-to-get-rare-glimpse-of-buckingham-palace-balcony-room-for-first-time-6076467]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Public To Get Rare Glimpse Of Buckingham Palace Balcony Room For First Time]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/public-to-get-rare-glimpse-of-buckingham-palace-balcony-room-for-first-time-6076467]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 10 Jul 2024 18:49:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The room behind Buckingham Palace's famous balcony opens to the public for the first time next week, giving a rare glimpse into one of the royal residence's inner sanctums.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The room behind Buckingham Palace's famous balcony opens to the public for the first time next week, giving a rare glimpse into one of the royal residence's inner sanctums.</p>

<p>For decades the royal family has been seen emerging from the room after coronations, weddings and other landmark occasions.</p>

<p>From the appearance of World War II leader Winston Churchill alongside the royal family in 1945 to the wedding of King Charles III and Princess Diana in 1981, the balcony and the room behind it has repeatedly played witness to history.</p>

<p>But despite endless images of the balcony, the room itself has always been kept under wraps.</p>

<p>Charles most recently appeared on it following his birthday parade last month along with his daughter-in-law Catherine, Princess of Wales.</p>

<p>The 42-year-old princess's presence drew huge interest as it was her first appearance at an official royal event since she announced she was undergoing cancer treatment earlier this year.</p>

<p><strong>'Connect' with the people</strong></p>

<p>Visitors will be able to see the room as part of a tour of the palace's east wing -- the first time it has been opened to the public since it was created around 175 years ago.</p>

<p>Almost 6,000 tickets for the new tour were snapped up within hours of going on sale in April.</p>

<p>The wing was added between 1847-49 to accommodate the growing family of Queen Victoria and her husband Prince Albert.</p>

<p>"It was Prince Albert's idea to have a balcony at Buckingham Palace, because he saw it as a way of enabling the royal family to connect with the people, and of course that's exactly how, in a sense, it continues to be used on important occasions," said Caroline de Guitaut, surveyor of the king's works of art.</p>

<p>Guitaut, responsible for 700,000 works of art at 13 royal residences including Buckingham Palace, said some of the earliest occasions on which the royal family used the balcony included waving off troops headed to the 1853-1856 Crimean War -- and welcoming them back.</p>

<p>Much of the wing reflects early 19th centry king George IV's love of Chinese-themed art.</p>

<p><strong>Pagodas and porcelain</strong></p>

<p>Tours of the east wing will also include the palace's state rooms, which have been open to the public during the summer since 1993.</p>

<p>The east wing part of the tour will take visitors along much of the 73-metre (240-feet) long principal corridor, and include the yellow drawing room and centre room behind the balcony.</p>

<p>The yellow drawing room features a Chinese-style fireplace from George IV's seaside pleasure palace in Brighton on the English south coast and even some of the pavilion's wallpaper that was discovered in storage by Queen Elizabeth II's grandmother and hung at her request.</p>

<p>The Brighton royal pavilion was sold to finance the Buckingham Palace extension with its contents moved to the east wing's principal rooms.</p>

<p>Victoria and Albert furnished the corridor with chairs, side tables, large pagodas and Chinese porcelain, including an incense burner in the shape of a Buddha.</p>

<p>Highlights in the room behind the balcony include a newly restored glass chandelier, shaped to resemble a lotus flower, and two Chinese 18th-century imperial silk wall hangings, presented to Victoria by the Chinese emperor Guangxu to mark her Diamond Jubilee in 1897.</p>

<p>Although visitors will have views down the Mall, the avenue leading to the palace, they will not be able to step out onto the balcony.</p>

<p>They will, however, be able to view Jonathan Yeo's new portrait of the king in which he is painted almost entirely in red.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-03/9u6oarpg_buckingham-palace_625x300_20_March_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Tours of the east wing will also include the palace's state rooms (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pre-arrest-bail-petitions-of-ex-pak-pm-imran-khan-in-may-9-violence-case-dismissed-6076346]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Pre-Arrest Bail Petitions Of Imran Khan In May 9 Violence Case Dismissed]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pre-arrest-bail-petitions-of-ex-pak-pm-imran-khan-in-may-9-violence-case-dismissed-6076346]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 10 Jul 2024 18:33:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Pakistani anti-terrorism court has dismissed pre-arrest bail petitions of jailed former prime minister Imran Khan in three cases of riots on May 9 last year, prompting his party to reject the ruling as a ploy to prolong his detention.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Pakistani anti-terrorism court has dismissed pre-arrest bail petitions of jailed former prime minister Imran Khan in three cases of riots on May 9 last year, prompting his party to reject the ruling as a ploy to prolong his detention.</p>

<p>The Pakistan Tehreek-e-Insaf founder was booked on the charges of abetment in attacks on Lahore Corps Commander House known as Jinnah House, Askari Tower, and Shadman police station on May 9, 2023.</p>

<p>Supporters of Mr Khan attacked several important government buildings and army installations following his arrest in an alleged corruption case in May last year.</p>

<p>ATC Lahore Judge Khalid Arshad refused pre-arrest bail to Mr Khan and dismissed his petitions in the three cases, after the prosecution equated the May 9 violence to the United States Capitol Hill attacks by supporters of former US president Donald Trump in 2021.</p>

<p>The prosecution said the police required custody of the former premier to complete the investigation in the three cases.</p>

<p>The 71-year-old cricketer-turned-politician is facing over 200 cases and has been in Rawalpindi's Adiala jail since August last year.</p>

<p>Judge Arshad announced the short order at 7 pm, which he reserved on July 6 after hearing the final arguments of the prosecution and the petitioner's counsel, the Dawn newspaper reported on Wednesday.</p>

<p>Due to the absence of Mr Khan's legal team, the judge decided that the court would announce a short order and come out with a detailed order later.</p>

<p>Reacting sharply to the court's ruling, Mr Khan's party on Wednesday said it was a ploy to keep the former prime minister in jail.</p>

<p>"Rejection of pre-arrest bail pleas is a ploy to keep Imran Khan in jail for a longer period," PTI spokesperson Raoof Hasan said in a statement on Wednesday.</p>

<p>He said the judiciary's surrender to the oppressive, anti-democratic and anti-constitutional forces' personal agenda is the biggest catalyst for the "painful death of law and justice and a major obstacle to justice in Pakistan".</p>

<p>"The state of Pakistan is under the grip of the worst personal dictatorship and the law of the jungle and the sole purpose to dismiss Imran Khan's bail pleas was to prolong his unlawful incarceration after his acquittal in all others false, fabricated and politically motivated cases," he said.</p>

<p>He said that despite propaganda for the past year, no evidence has been presented in any court regarding the allegations made against&nbsp;<br />
Mr Khan.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/t32m7b7o_imran-khan-reuters_625x300_06_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The 71-year-old cricketer-turned-politician is facing over 200 cases (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bbc-commentators-wife-2-daughters-killed-in-crossbow-attack-in-london-manhunt-underway-6076345]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[BBC Commentator's Wife, 2 Daughters Killed In Crossbow Attack In London]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bbc-commentators-wife-2-daughters-killed-in-crossbow-attack-in-london-manhunt-underway-6076345]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 10 Jul 2024 18:33:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[UK police were searching Wednesday for a suspect who may have a crossbow after the wife and two daughters of a BBC radio racing commentator were killed in a suspected "targeted" attack.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>UK police were searching Wednesday for a suspect who may have a crossbow after the wife and two daughters of a BBC radio racing commentator were killed in a suspected "targeted" attack.</p>

<p>Kyle Clifford, 26, from Enfield in north London, is wanted in connection with the deaths of the three women in the town of Bushey, north of London, on Tuesday night.</p>

<p>The victims were Carol Hunt, the 61-year-old wife of BBC radio and Sky Sports racing commentator John Hunt, and their two daughters, Louise, 25, and Hannah, 28, the broadcasters said.</p>

<p>Local police said officers were called to a house in the leafy commuter town where the three women were pronounced dead at the scene.</p>

<p>Chief Superintendent Jon Simpson said armed officers and specialist search teams were involved in the manhunt, with the suspect believed to be in north London or around Bushey.</p>

<p>Simpson also urged Clifford to contact police and warned the public not to approach the suspect.</p>

<p>He called it "a horrific incident involving what is currently believed to be a crossbow, but other weapons may also have been used".</p>

<p>A primary school in nearby Enfield kept children indoors during the police search.</p>

<p>There is no licence required to own a crossbow in the UK, but it is illegal to carry one in public without a reasonable excuse.</p>

<p>Interior minister Yvette Cooper called the deaths "truly shocking" and said she was being kept updated about the inquiry.</p>

<p>A spokeswoman for her department said legislation was "under constant review and a call for evidence was launched earlier this year to look at whether further controls on crossbows should be introduced".</p>

<p>She said the minister would "swiftly consider the findings to see if laws need to be tightened further".</p>

<p><strong>'Shocking'</strong></p>

<p>BBC Radio Five Live sent a note to staff calling the incident "utterly devastating".</p>

<p>Sky Sports Racing said on X that the team was "deeply saddened by the tragic deaths" and "our thoughts are with our colleague John Hunt, his family and friends at this awful time".</p>

<p>One neighbour described hearing "shrill" screams from the home on Tuesday.</p>

<p>The 46-year-old who lives near the scene, said "absolute chaos" then broke out as armed police put the road into lockdown.</p>

<p>"We had armed police running down, screaming 'stay in your house'", she added.</p>

<p>Another neighbour told reporters the victims were a friendly family.</p>

<p>"We would see them every day passing by and they would say good morning," she said. "It's really sad what's happened, very shocking."</p>

<p>In March, a 47-year-old man was arrested after two people were injured in separate crossbow attacks in London's Shoreditch area.</p>

<p>Last October Jaswant Singh Chail, 21, was jailed after being found in the grounds of Windsor Castle, west of London, with a loaded crossbow.</p>

<p>He broke into the royal residence on Christmas Day 2021 and told police he was trying to kill Queen Elizabeth II.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-12/ima4e49o_uk-police_625x300_14_December_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[There is no licence required to own a crossbow in the UK. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/all-you-need-to-know-about-bird-flu-virus-found-in-humans-in-2024-6076224]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[All You Need To Know About Bird Flu Virus Found In Humans In 2024]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/all-you-need-to-know-about-bird-flu-virus-found-in-humans-in-2024-6076224]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 10 Jul 2024 18:17:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Avian influenza, or bird flu, has public health officials on alert after an unprecedented spread in dairy cows in the United States this year. Four dairy workers have also tested positive in the country.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Avian influenza, or bird flu, has public health officials on alert after an unprecedented spread in dairy cows in the United States this year. Four dairy workers have also tested positive in the country.</p>

<p>A particularly severe variant of the H5N1 strain has been spreading around the world in animals since 2020, causing lethal outbreaks in commercial poultry and sporadic infections in other species from alpacas to house cats. Until this year, it had never infected cows.</p>

<p>Different bird flu strains have been found in Australia and Mexico in humans, while different H5 subtypes are also present around the world in both animals and humans, in countries including China and Cambodia.</p>

<p>Most of the human cases reported exposure to poultry, live poultry markets, or dairy cattle prior to infection, but scientists are worried the virus could mutate in ways that make it more easily spread from person-to-person, which could spark a pandemic. The World Health Organization says the risk to people is low at this point.</p>

<p>Below are occurrences of varying types of the bird flu virus that have been found in humans this year.</p>

<p><strong>UNITED STATES:</strong></p>

<p>The first known cases of infected dairy cattle occurred in Texas in March, and is now in dairy herds in 12 states. The U.S. Agriculture Department said tests so far indicate that the virus detected in cows is the same H5N1 virus affecting wild birds and commercial poultry flocks. The four dairy workers who have tested positive for the virus this year had mild symptoms such as conjunctivitis, or pink eye.</p>

<p>The H5N1 virus in the United States belongs to the clade 2.3.4.4b, genotype B3.13, a genotype detected only in North America so far, the European Food Safety Agency said in a scientific report.</p>

<p><strong>MEXICO:</strong></p>

<p>A resident of Mexico died with the first known cases of H5N2 avian influenza in humans, the WHO said on June 5. Mexico's government said chronic illness, rather than bird flu, was the cause of death. The person had no known exposure to animals.</p>

<p><strong>AUSTRALIA:</strong></p>

<p>The WHO on June 7 said a child with H5N1 bird flu reported by Australia had traveled to Kolkata, India. Genetic sequencing showed the virus was a subtype of H5N1 and part of a strain that circulates in Southeast Asia and has been detected in previous human infections and in poultry.</p>

<p>Australia is separately dealing with three outbreaks of different strains of the virus on poultry farms - H7N3, H7N8 and H7N9 - that authorities say likely arrived on farms via wild birds.</p>

<p><strong>INDIA:</strong></p>

<p>The WHO on June 11 reported a case of human infection with bird flu caused by the H9N2 subtype in a four-year-old child in the eastern Indian state of West Bengal. It was the second human infection of H9N2 bird flu from India following a case in 2019, the agency said. While the H9N2 virus typically tends to cause mild illness, the United Nations agency said further sporadic human cases could occur as this is one of the most prevalent avian influenza viruses circulating in poultry in different regions.</p>

<p><strong>VIETNAM:</strong></p>

<p>Vietnam reported a 21-year-old student had died from the H5N1 bird flu in March. He had no underlying medical conditions, but had been exposed to wild birds from hunting a couple of weeks prior to onset of symptoms. No contact with dead or sick poultry was reported at the time.</p>

<p>Vietnam also reported an outbreak of H9N2 in a 37-year-old man, EFSA said.</p>

<p><strong>CAMBODIA:</strong></p>

<p>The Southeast Asia nation and Vietnam neighbor has reported five human cases of H5N1 as of June 20.</p>

<p><strong>CHINA:</strong></p>

<p>China this year detected human cases caused by the H5N6, H9N2 and H10N3 strains, with two fatal H5N6 cases in the Fujian province. Both of those cases had exposure to backyard poultry before the onset of symptoms, EFSA said.</p>

<p>The case of H10N3 avian influenza was the third one ever reported globally.</p>

<p><strong>GERMANY:</strong></p>

<p>Germany reported a rare outbreak of highly pathogenic H7N5 bird flu on a farm in the western part of the country, near the border with the Netherlands, the World Organisation for Animal Health said on July 4. It was the first outbreak anywhere of H7N5 on WOAH's public records.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/mb1heeog_bird-flu-generic-reuters_625x300_10_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The World Health Organization says the risk to people is low at this point. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/60-percent-of-hamas-fighters-dead-or-wounded-israel-defence-minister-6075976]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["60 Percent" Of Hamas Fighters Dead Or Wounded: Israel Defence Minister]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/60-percent-of-hamas-fighters-dead-or-wounded-israel-defence-minister-6075976]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 10 Jul 2024 17:42:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel's Defence Minister Yoav Gallant said Wednesday that 60 percent of Hamas fighters had been "eliminated or wounded" in the Gaza war since the militant group's October 7 attacks.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel's Defence Minister Yoav Gallant said Wednesday that 60 percent of Hamas fighters had been "eliminated or wounded" in the Gaza war since the group's October 7 attacks.</p>

<p>Gallant reaffirmed in a statement to parliament on the first nine months of the conflict that Israel was "determined" to meet its war goals of eradicating Hamas and bringing all hostages back from Gaza.</p>

<p>The minister praised Israeli soldiers for "performing their work with dedication, sacrifice and success" and said "the achievements are many".</p>

<p>Israel has launched major new offensives in Gaza City in the north and around Rafah and Khan Yunis in the south, even as it also embarks on contacts with international mediators on conditions for negotiating a truce with Hamas.</p>

<p>"We have eliminated or wounded 60 percent of the Hamas terrorists" and "dismantled" most the Palestinian group's 24 battalions, Gallant said.</p>

<p>The minister did not give figures for the casualties and the Israeli military said it did not immediately have statistics.</p>

<p>The October 7 attack on southern Israel resulted in the deaths of 1,195 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli figures.</p>

<p>The operatives also seized 251 hostages, 116 of whom remain in Gaza, including 42 the military says are dead.</p>

<p>Israel's military retaliation has killed at least 38,295 people in Gaza, also mostly civilians, according to figures from the Hamas-run territory's health ministry.</p>

<p>While many countries expressed solidarity with Israel after the October 7 attacks, the government has also faced a wave of criticism for its military campaign that has devastated Gaza.</p>

<p>Gallant insisted Israel would stick to its aims.</p>

<p>"We have returned half of the hostages and we are determined to return the rest," he said.</p>

<p>"The security establishment, and myself heading it, are determined to achieve the goals of the war and complete them."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/j16pmol_hamas-reuters-_625x300_11_June_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel's military retaliation has killed at least 38,295 people in Gaza, says Hamas (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-gaza-palestine-explained-how-accurate-are-gaza-death-figures-does-hamas-control-them-6075524]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: How Accurate Are Gaza Death Figures, Does Hamas Control Them?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-gaza-palestine-explained-how-accurate-are-gaza-death-figures-does-hamas-control-them-6075524]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 10 Jul 2024 16:46:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Palestinian health authorities say Israel's ground and air campaign in Gaza has killed more than 38,000 people, mostly civilians, and driven most of the enclave's 2.3 million people from their homes.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Palestinian health authorities say Israel's ground and air campaign in Gaza has killed more than 38,000 people, mostly civilians, and driven most of the enclave's 2.3 million people from their homes.</p>

<p>The war began on Oct. 7 when Hamas operatives rushed across the border into Israeli communities. Israel says the operatives killed more than 1,200 people, mostly civilians, and dragged 253 into captivity in Gaza.</p>

<p>This explainer examines how the Palestinian death count is calculated, how reliable it is, the breakdown of civilians and fighters killed and what each side says.</p>

<p><strong>HOW DO GAZA HEALTH AUTHORITIES CALCULATE THE DEATH COUNT?</strong></p>

<p>In the first months of the war, death counts were calculated entirely from counting bodies that arrived in hospitals and data included names and identity numbers for most of those killed.</p>

<p>As the conflict ground on, and fewer hospitals and morgues continued to operate, the authorities adopted other methods too.</p>

<p>From early May, the Health Ministry updated its breakdown of total fatalities to include unidentified bodies which account for nearly a third of the overall deaths. Omar Hussein Ali, head of the ministry's emergency operations centre in the Israeli-occupied West Bank, said these were bodies that had arrived at hospitals or medical centres without personal data such as identity numbers or full names.</p>

<p>It also began including deaths reported online by family members who had to input information including identity numbers.</p>

<p><strong>IS THE GAZA DEATH COUNT COMPREHENSIVE?</strong></p>

<p>The numbers "do not necessarily reflect all victims due to the fact that many victims are still missing under the rubble", the Palestinian Health Ministry says. In May it estimated that some 10,000 bodies were uncounted in this way.</p>

<p>The Lancet medical journal published a letter from three academics on July 5 estimating that indirect deaths, caused by factors such as disease, might mean the death count is several times higher than official Palestinian estimates.</p>

<p>The letter said it was "not implausible to estimate that up to 186,000 or even more deaths could be attributable to the current conflict in Gaza".</p>

<p>The authors said the figure, which made global headlines, was based on what they said was the conservative estimate of four indirect deaths to one direct death based on trends from prior conflicts.</p>

<p>The U.N. human rights office and the Humanitarian Research Lab at the Yale School of Public Health have also said during the conflict that the true figures are likely higher than those published, without giving specifics.</p>

<p><strong>HOW CREDIBLE IS THE GAZA DEATH COUNT?</strong></p>

<p>Pre-war Gaza had robust population statistics and better health information systems than in most Middle East countries, public health experts told Reuters.</p>

<p>A spokesperson for the World Health Organisation said the ministry has "good capacity in data collection/analysis and its previous reporting has been considered credible".</p>

<p>The United Nations regularly cites the ministry's death count figures, while naming the ministry as the source.</p>

<p>Early in the conflict, after U.S. President Joe Biden cast doubt on casualty figures, the health ministry published a detailed list of the 7,028 deaths that had been registered by that point.</p>

<p>Academics looking at details of listed casualties said in a peer-reviewed article in the Lancet medical journal in November that it was implausible that the patterns shown in the list could be the result of fabrication.</p>

<p>However, there are specific questions over the inclusion of 471 people said to have been killed in an Oct. 17 blast at al-Ahli al-Arab hospital in Gaza City. An unclassified U.S. intelligence report estimated that death count "at the low end of the 100 to 300 spectrum".</p>

<p><strong>DOES HAMAS CONTROL THE FIGURES?</strong></p>

<p>While Hamas has run Gaza since 2007, the enclave's Health Ministry also answers to the overall Palestinian Authority ministry in Ramallah in the West Bank.</p>

<p>Gaza's Hamas-run government has paid the salaries of all those hired in public departments since 2007, including in the Health Ministry. The Palestinian Authority still pays the salaries of those hired before then.</p>

<p>The extent of Hamas control in Gaza now is difficult to assess with Israeli forces occupying most of the territory, including around locations of major hospitals that provide casualty figures, and with fighting ongoing.</p>

<p><strong>WHAT DOES ISRAEL SAY?</strong></p>

<p>Israeli officials have said the figures are suspect because of Hamas' control over government in Gaza. Foreign Ministry spokesperson Oren Mamorstein said the numbers were manipulated and "do not reflect the reality on the ground".</p>

<p>However, Israel's military has also accepted in briefings that the overall Gaza casualty numbers are broadly reliable.</p>

<p>In May, Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said 14,000 Hamas fighters and 16,000 Palestinian civilians had been killed in the war.</p>

<p><strong>HOW MANY CIVILIANS HAVE BEEN KILLED?</strong></p>

<p>The Health Ministry figures do not differentiate between civilians and Hamas combatants, who do not wear formal uniform or carry separate identification.</p>

<p>Israel periodically provides estimates of how many Hamas fighters it believes have been killed. The most recent was Netanyahu's estimate of 14,000.</p>

<p>Israeli security officials say such estimates are reached through a combination of counting bodies on the battlefield, intercepts of Hamas communications and intelligence assessments of personnel in targets that were destroyed.</p>

<p>Hamas has said Israeli estimates for its losses are exaggerated but has not said how many of its fighters have been killed.</p>

<p>The Palestinian Health Ministry says more than 70% of the dead are women and children. For most of the conflict its figures showed children as representing slightly over 40% of all those killed.</p>

<p>However, conditions in hospitals compiling figures have worsened amid the fighting and many of those killed may not be identifiable due to their injuries.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/4e11d1u8_gaza-school-attack_625x300_09_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Palestinian Health Ministry says more than 70% of the dead are women and children. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ai-startups-green-energy-what-pm-modi-discussed-with-austrian-chancellor-6075437]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[AI, Startups, Green Energy: What PM Discussed With Austrian Chancellor]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ai-startups-green-energy-what-pm-modi-discussed-with-austrian-chancellor-6075437]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 10 Jul 2024 16:35:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Narendra Modi engaged in "extensive and fruitful" discussions with Austrian Chancellor Karl Nehammer on Wednesday, bolstering the bilateral relationship between India and Austria.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi engaged in "extensive and fruitful" discussions with Austrian Chancellor Karl Nehammer on Wednesday, bolstering the bilateral relationship between India and Austria.</p>

<p>The meeting, described as comprehensive by the Ministry of External Affairs spokesperson Randhir Jaiswal, covered a wide array of subjects pivotal to both nations.</p>

<p>Key areas of discussion included trade and investment, with both leaders expressing a commitment to enhancing economic cooperation.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The talks also delved into science and technology, green energy, artificial intelligence, and startups, reflecting the shared interest in advancing technological and innovative collaborations.</p>

<p>Environmental and climate change issues were also on the agenda, with both leaders recognising the need for concerted efforts to address these global challenges.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Cultural cooperation and people-to-people ties were highlighted as crucial elements in strengthening the bilateral partnership and fostering deeper mutual understanding and engagement between the two countries.</p>

<p>In addition to bilateral matters, PM Modi and Chancellor Nehammer exchanged views on regional and global issues of mutual interest, underscoring the importance of collaborative approaches to international challenges.</p>

<p>"Energising India-Austria ties! PM @narendramodi held extensive and fruitful talks with Austrian Chancellor @karlnehammer today. Discussions covered various dimensions of the bilateral partnership, including trade &amp; investment, S&amp;T, green energy, AI, startups, environment &amp; climate change, cultural cooperation and people-to-people ties. The leaders also exchanged views on regional and global issues of mutual interest," said the MEA spokesperson in a post on X.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Strengthening ??-?? economic ties!<br />
<br />
PM <a href="https://twitter.com/narendramodi?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@narendramodi</a> and Austrian Chancellor <a href="https://twitter.com/karlnehammer?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@karlnehammer</a> jointly addressed renowned Austrian and Indian CEOs at a round table business meeting in Hofburg Palace, Vienna today.<br />
<br />
PM highlighted significant potential for collaboration between… <a href="https://t.co/jf9LzdN1uu">pic.twitter.com/jf9LzdN1uu</a></p>
— Randhir Jaiswal (@MEAIndia) <a href="https://twitter.com/MEAIndia/status/1810992110776242202?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 10, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>PM Modi and Austrian Chancellor Nehammer also participated in the India-Austria Business Meeting, bringing together around 40 businesses from both nations to explore new economic opportunities and strengthen bilateral trade relations.</p>

<p>The two also addressed India-Austria joint press meet, following their delegation-level talks.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Modi arrived in Vienna on Tuesday evening for a day-long State visit. Notably, this is the first time an Indian Prime Minister has visited Austria in 41 years. Indira Gandhi was the last PM to visit Austria in 1983.</p>

<p>PM Modi's visit to Austria comes after his two-day official visit to Russia, where he met Russian President Vladimir Putin.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/rn0emf0o_modi-austria_625x300_10_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Environmental and climate change issues were also on the agenda]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/connected-by-shared-values-commitment-to-better-planet-pm-modi-in-austria-6075355]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Connected By Shared Values, Commitment To Better Planet": PM In Austria]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/connected-by-shared-values-commitment-to-better-planet-pm-modi-in-austria-6075355]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 10 Jul 2024 16:21:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Narendra Modi, who is on a state visit to Austria, called his trip to the country historic and special and asserted that he is happy that he got an opportunity to visit Austria at the beginning of his third term.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi, who is on a state visit to Austria, called his trip to the country historic and special and asserted that he is happy that he got an opportunity to visit Austria at the beginning of his third term.</p>

<p>Addressing the media, PM Modi said, "I am happy that during the beginning of my third term itself, I got the opportunity to visit Austria. This trip of mine is historic and special. After 41 years, an Indian PM has visited Austria."</p>

<p>Notably, this is the first time an Indian Prime Minister has visited Austria in 41 years. Indira Gandhi was the last PM to visit Austria in 1983. PM Modi's visit to Austria comes after his two-day official visit to Russia, where he met Russian President Vladimir Putin.</p>

<p>The Prime Minister further expressed happiness over the fact that both nations have completed 75 years of their ties. "It is also a happy coincidence that this visit is taking place at a time when 75 years of our mutual relations have been completed," he said.</p>

<p>Elaborating further on the relationship between India and Austria, PM Modi added, "Democracy and rule of law are the foundation of our relations. Our relationships are strengthened by mutual trust and shared interests."</p>

<p>Speaking on his meeting with the Austrian Chancellor, PM Modi said that talks between them took place to boost their relations. "Today, between Austrian Chancellor Karl Nehammer and me, a very meaningful discussion took place. We discussed new possibilities to strengthen our ties further. We have decided to give these ties a strategic direction."</p>

<p>He added, "For the coming decade, an outline has been prepared for cooperation, which is not only limited to economic support and investment but will cover sectors like infrastructure development, renewable energy, hydrogen, water and waste management, artificial intelligence, quantum. We will work towards linking each other's capabilities."</p>

<p>The Prime Minister also talked about linking the youth power and said, "To connect the youth power and ideas of both the countries, the startup bridge will be given impetus. An agreement has already been reached on mobility and migration partnership, which will support legal migration and skilled workforce movement."</p>

<p>PM Modi held delegation-level talks with Karl Nehammer at the Federal Chancellery in Vienna on Wednesday.</p>

<p>External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar, National Security Advisor (NSA) Ajit Doval, Foreign Secretary Vinay Mohan Kwatra and other officials were present in the meeting.</p>

<p>Earlier, PM Modi signed the Guestbook at the Federal Chancellery in Austria's Vienna. He also received a Ceremonial Reception at the Federal Chancellery in Vienna. Karl Nehammer accompanied PM Modi.</p>

<p>In a post on X, Ministry of External Affairs (MEA) spokesperson Randhir Jaiswal stated, "Scripting a new chapter in bilateral relations. PM @narendramodi was warmly received by Austrian Chancellor @karlnehammer at the Federal Chancery and accorded a ceremonial welcome. This landmark visit by an Indian Prime Minister to Austria is taking place after 4 decades."</p>

<p>Upon arrival in Vienna, the Indian Prime Minister was welcomed by Austrian Foreign Minister Alexander Schallenberg. Indian Ambassador to Austria, Shambhu Kumaran was also present at the airport.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Landed in Vienna. This visit to Austria is a special one. Our nations are connected by shared values and a commitment to a better planet. Looking forward to the various programmes in Austria including talks with Chancellor <a href="https://twitter.com/karlnehammer?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@karlnehammer</a>, interactions with the Indian community and… <a href="https://t.co/PJaeOWVOm1">pic.twitter.com/PJaeOWVOm1</a></p>
— Narendra Modi (@narendramodi) <a href="https://twitter.com/narendramodi/status/1810745236437778478?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 9, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Taking to X, PM Modi stated, "Landed in Vienna. This visit to Austria is a special one. Our nations are connected by shared values and a commitment to a better planet. Looking forward to the various programmes in Austria including talks with Chancellor @karlnehammer, interactions with the Indian community and more.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/mrk165e_pm-modi-austria-chancellor_625x300_10_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["This trip of mine is historic and special," PM Modi said in Austria]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>