<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Thu, 18 Jul 2024 09:21:33 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jd-vances-wife-usha-chilukuri-vance-describes-him-meat-potatoes-guy-who-cooks-indian-food-6130104]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Meat, Potatoes" Guy Who Cooks Indian Food: JD Vance's Wife Describes Him]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jd-vances-wife-usha-chilukuri-vance-describes-him-meat-potatoes-guy-who-cooks-indian-food-6130104]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 18 Jul 2024 08:55:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Usha Chilukuri Vance, wife of JD Vance, Donald Trump's vice-presidential pick, spoke at the Republican National Convention in Milwaukee where she revealed her husband's culinary skills in Indian cuisine.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Usha Chilukuri Vance, wife of <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-jd-vances-wife-usha-vance-said-about-her-hindu-upbringing-its-influence-on-life-6116180">JD Vance</a>, Donald Trump's vice-presidential pick, spoke at the Republican National Convention in Milwaukee where she revealed her husband's culinary skills in Indian cuisine.</p>

<p>Describing him as a "meat and potatoes" kind of guy, she mentioned his newfound ability to cook Indian food.</p>

<p>Recalling their meeting at Yale Law School, Ms Vance portrayed their relationship as "a testament to this great country".</p>

<p>"We started as friends," she said. "He was then, as he is now, the most interesting person I knew - a working class guy who had overcome childhood traumas that I could barely fathom to end up at Yale Law School, a tough marine who had served in Iraq, but who enjoys spending his leisure time playing with puppies and watching the movie 'Babe'."</p>

<p>Ms Vance also highlighted the diverse backgrounds they come from.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/why-donald-trump-picked-jd-vance-as-his-vice-president-candidate-6123635">JD Vance</a> has acknowledged the influence of his Hindu wife, Usha Chilukuri Vance, on his personal and spiritual life.</p>

<p>In an interview with Fox News, he explained how his wife's Hindu faith had been pivotal in guiding him through challenges and reconciling his Catholic beliefs.</p>

<p>Previously, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-an-honor-jd-vance-after-being-declared-donald-trumps-vice-president-pick-6116429">JD Vance</a> has often credited Usha for supporting his success. During a 2020 interview with The Megyn Kelly Show, Vance described his wife as a "strong female voice" that grounds him. "Usha definitely brings me back to earth. If I get a little too confident or proud, I remind myself that she's way more accomplished than I am," he had said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/e30s6508_usha-chilukuri-vance-jd-vance-afp_625x300_18_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Usha Vance also highlighted the diverse backgrounds they come from.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/switzerland-portable-suicide-pods-press-button-to-die-switzerland-to-soon-use-portable-suicide-pods-6130028]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Press Button To Die": Switzerland To Soon Use Portable Suicide Pods]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/switzerland-portable-suicide-pods-press-button-to-die-switzerland-to-soon-use-portable-suicide-pods-6130028]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 18 Jul 2024 08:39:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An assisted dying group expects a portable suicide pod to be used for the first time in Switzerland, potentially within months, providing death without medical supervision, it said Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An assisted dying group expects a portable suicide pod to be used for the first time in Switzerland, potentially within months, providing death without medical supervision, it said Wednesday.</p>

<p>The space-age-looking Sarco capsule, first unveiled in 2019, replaces the oxygen inside it with nitrogen, causing death by hypoxia. It would cost $20 to use.</p>

<p>The Last Resort organisation said it saw no legal obstacle to its use in Switzerland, where the law generally allows assisted suicide if the person commits the lethal act themselves.</p>

<p>"Since we have people indeed queueing up, asking to use the Sarco, it's very likely that it will take place pretty soon," The Last Resort's chief executive Florian Willet told a press conference.</p>

<p>"I cannot imagine a more beautiful way (to die), of breathing air without oxygen until falling into an eternal sleep," he added.</p>

<h3><strong>'Press this button' to die&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>The person wishing to die must first pass a psychiatric assessment of their mental capacity -- a key legal requirement.</p>

<p>The person climbs into the purple capsule, closes the lid, and is asked automated questions such as who they are, where they are and if they know what happens when they press the button.</p>

<p>"'If you want to die', the voice says in the processor, 'Press this button'," said Sarco inventor Philip Nitschke, a leading global figure in right-to-die activism.</p>

<p>He explained that once the button is pressed, the amount of oxygen in the air plummets from 21 per cent to 0.05 per cent in less than 30 seconds.</p>

<p>"Within two breaths of air of that low level of oxygen, they will start to feel disorientated, uncoordinated and slightly euphoric before losing consciousness," Nitschke said.</p>

<p>"They will then stay in that state of unconsciousness for... around about five minutes before death will take place," he added.</p>

<p>The Sarco monitors the oxygen level in the capsule, the person's heart rate and the oxygen saturation of the blood.</p>

<p>"We will be able to see quite quickly when that person has died," said Nitschke.</p>

<p>As for someone changing their mind at the very last minute, Nitschke said: "Once you press that button, there's no way of going back."</p>

<h3><strong>First user&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>No decision has been made over the date and location of the first death, or who the first user might be.</p>

<p>Such details would not be made public until after the event.</p>

<p>"We really don't want a person's desire for a peaceful passing Switzerland to turn into a media circus," said lawyer Fiona Stewart, who is on The Last Resort's advisory board.</p>

<p>She said it would be used "in a very secluded location, in the beauty of nature", though it had to be on private property.</p>

<p>Asked if the first use would be this year, she replied: "I would say yes."</p>

<p>The minimum age limit is set at 50, though if someone over 18 was seriously ill, "we would not want to deny a suffering person based on their age", said Stewart.</p>

<p>The capsule can be reused.</p>

<p>Nitschke's Exit International organisation, which owns the Sarco, is a non-profit group funded by donations.</p>

<p>Stewart said the only cost for the user would be 18 Swiss francs ($20) for the nitrogen.</p>

<h3><strong>Development and debate</strong></h3>

<p>The capsule's potential use has raised a host of legal and ethical questions in Switzerland, reigniting debate on assisted dying.</p>

<p>The Wallis cantonal doctor has banned its use, while other cantons have voiced reservations.</p>

<p>"It's our understanding that there's no legal impediment to the Sarco being used... despite what any canton says," Stewart insisted.</p>

<p>Nitrogen, which forms 78 per cent of the air, is "not a medical product... it's not a dangerous weapon", she added.</p>

<p>"We're looking to de-medicalise assisted suicide because a Sarco doesn't require a doctor to be in close proximity," said Stewart.</p>

<p>Only once a person has died would the Swiss authorities be called.</p>

<p>The 3D-printable capsule cost more than 650,000 euros ($710,000) to research and develop in the Netherlands over 12 years.</p>

<p>Stewart said it had been tested with instruments in a workshop in Rotterdam over the last 12 months. It has not been tested on humans or animals.</p>

<p>The current Sarco could only accommodate someone five feet and eight inches (1.73 metres) tall. The development team is seeking to build a double Sarco so couples could end their lives together.</p>

<p>Future Sarcos could cost around 15,000 euros. The Sarco will never be permitted for use in capital punishment, said The Last Resort.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p><p><div class='table-div suicide'><table class='table'><thead><tr><th colspan='2'>Helplines</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>Vandrevala Foundation for Mental Health</td><td><a href='tel:+919999666555'>9999666555</a> or <a href='mailto:help@vandrevalafoundation.com'>help@vandrevalafoundation.com</a> </td></tr><tr><td>TISS iCall</td><td><a href='tel:+912225521111'>022-25521111</a> (Monday-Saturday: 8 am to 10 pm)</td></tr> <tr><td colspan='2'>(If you need support or know someone who does, please reach out to your nearest mental health specialist.)</td></tr></tbody></table></div></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ps1g567o_sarco-suicide-capsule-afp-_625x300_18_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The space-age-looking Sarco capsule replaces the oxygen inside it with nitrogen, causing death by hypoxia]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/indians-abroad/jaahnavi-kandula-death-case-us-cop-who-laughed-after-indian-students-death-fired-6129895]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Cop Who Laughed After Indian Student Jaahnavi Kandula's Death Fired]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/indians-abroad/jaahnavi-kandula-death-case-us-cop-who-laughed-after-indian-students-death-fired-6129895]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 18 Jul 2024 08:03:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Seattle police officer, whose insensitive comments and laughter following the death of an Indian student had caused outrage, has been fired.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Seattle police officer, whose insensitive comments and laughter following the death of an Indian student had caused outrage, has been fired.</p>

<p>Jaahnavi Kandula, 23, was struck by a police vehicle driven by Seattle Police Officer Kevin Dave as she was crossing a street on January 23. Dave was driving 74 mph (more than 119 kmh) on the way to a report of a drug overdose call. Kandula was thrown 100 feet when she was struck by the speeding police patrol vehicle.</p>

<p>In bodycam footage released by the Seattle Police Department, Officer Daniel Auderer laughed about the deadly crash and remarked that “Uh, I think she went up on the hood, hit the windshield, and then when he hit the brakes, flew off the car...But she is dead.” After making these comments, Auderer “laughed hard for four seconds,” the Disciplinary Action Report said.</p>

<p>Interim Chief Sue Rahr at the Seattle Police Department said in an internal email that the hurt Auderer's words have inflicted on Kandula's family “cannot be erased. The actions this individual police officer have brought shame on the Seattle Police Department and our entire profession, making the job of every police officer more difficult”.</p>

<p>Rahr said as the leader of the organisation, it is her duty to uphold the high standards necessary to maintain public trust. “For me to allow the officer to remain on our force would only bring further dishonour to the entire department. For that reason, I am going to terminate his employment,” she said in the internal email seen by PTI.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-02/livp1oog_jaahnavi-kandula_625x300_22_February_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Daniel Auderer was heard laughing about the deadly crash.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/on-kamala-harris-vs-jd-vance-debate-donald-trump-campaign-shares-big-update-6129772]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[On Kamala Harris vs JD Vance Debate, Trump Campaign Shares Big Update]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/on-kamala-harris-vs-jd-vance-debate-donald-trump-campaign-shares-big-update-6129772]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 18 Jul 2024 07:29:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The campaign for former US president and the Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump has said that it will not commit to vice-presidential debate dates until after the Democratic National Convention, starting August 19.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The campaign for former US president and the Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump has said that it will not commit to vice-presidential debate dates until after the Democratic National Convention, starting August 19.</p>

<p>Vice President Kamala Harris had extended the debate invitation to Senator JD Vance after he was named Trump's running mate earlier this week.</p>

<p>"We don't know who the Democratic nominee for vice president is going to be, so we can't lock in a date before their convention," Trump Campaign Senior Advisor Brian Hughes said on Wednesday.</p>

<p>"To do so would be unfair to Gavin Newsom, JB Pritzker, Gretchen Whitmer, or whoever Kamala Harris picks as her running mate," he said, rejecting the offer of Harris to debate Vance.</p>

<p>Biden-Harris 2024 Communications Director for Vice President Harris, Brian Fallon said Trump is the one whose campaign said he would debate "anytime, anyplace" and who picked Vance specifically for his debating skills.</p>

<p>"Now suddenly right after a damning new leak showing his support for a nationwide abortion ban, Vance is backing off a debate against Vice President Harris, who has spent the last two years prosecuting the case on behalf of reproductive freedom," Fallon said.</p>

<p>"This debate has been discussed for two months now. If JD Vance is unwilling to defend the Trump-Vance record on the debate stage, he should just say so," he said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/c69vc5t_kamala-harris-jd-vance-afp_625x300_16_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Vice President Kamala Harris had extended the debate invitation to Senator JD Vance earlier this week.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-covid-case-delivers-latest-blow-to-hard-luck-campaign-6129739]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Joe Biden's Covid Case Delivers Latest Blow to Hard-Luck Campaign]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-covid-case-delivers-latest-blow-to-hard-luck-campaign-6129739]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 18 Jul 2024 07:16:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[President Joe Biden's hopes of counter-programming the Republican National Convention were dashed Wednesday after he learned he had contracted COVID-19, forcing him to cancel an appearance before a key Latino advocacy group.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>President Joe Biden can't catch a break.</p>

<p>The president's hopes of counter-programming the Republican National Convention were dashed Wednesday after he learned he had contracted COVID-19, forcing him to cancel an appearance before a key Latino advocacy group.</p>

<p>While Biden's symptoms are mild, the diagnosis both removes him from the campaign trail and thrusts his health back into the spotlight - all at a critical moment when he is trying desperately to prove that concerns over his age and mental acuity are overblown.</p>

<p>Earlier Wednesday, Adam Schiff - the California congressman and Democratic candidate in that state's US Senate race - restarted the drumbeat of allies calling for Biden to exit the race, urging him to "pass the torch."</p>

<p>Then came a pair of reports from ABC News and the Washington Post that Senate Majority Leader Chuck Schumer and House Minority Leader Hakeem Jeffries had warned Biden in private conversations last week about the risk his continued candidacy posed.</p>

<p>Biden told the leaders he was the nominee of the party and planned to win, White House spokesman Andrew Bates said in a statement. Still, both joined forces in the following days to lobby the Democratic National Committee against a July virtual roll call that would have cemented Biden's nomination and effectively terminated efforts to replace him atop the ticket.</p>

<p>The president stoked the melodrama even more by suggesting in a BET interview taped Tuesday that he would consider dropping out of the race if new health issues emerged. Meanwhile, Senator Bernie Sanders, a defender of the president, conceded in an interview with the New Yorker that Biden had trouble completing sentences.</p>

<p>Even worse, Biden's struggles played out against scenes from the GOP convention, where Republican candidate Donald Trump appeared on stage for a walk-through sporting a bandaged ear from the unsuccessful assassination attempt he survived last weekend.</p>

<p>Trump's defiant, fist-pumping response to the shooting proved instantly iconic, galvanizing voices of doubt within the Republican Party behind his cause. On Tuesday night, former primary foes Nikki Haley and Ron DeSantis took to the stage in Milwaukee to lay out their argument for supporting Trump's candidacy.</p>

<p>The events contributed to a growing sense of two campaigns headed in opposite directions: one on the rise and the other in turmoil.</p>

<p>Public opinion polls underscore reason for Democrats to be concerned.</p>

<p>Nearly two-thirds of Biden's own party say he should withdraw from the race, according to an Associated Press-NORC poll released hours before Biden's Covid diagnosis. Just three in 10 Democrats are extremely or very confident in his ability to serve effectively as president.</p>

<h3><strong>Off the Rails</strong></h3>

<p>Biden had hoped to reverse those perceptions over a three-day trip that quickly flew off the rails.</p>

<p>The president originally planned to travel on Monday to Austin, Texas to deliver remarks marking the 60th anniversary of the Civil Rights Act at the Lyndon Baines Johnson Presidential Library. The White House had seen the address as an opportunity for Biden to link himself to previous Democratic efforts to expand protections for minorities while painting Trump as enabling new restrictions on abortion and voting rights.</p>

<p>But that event was scrapped in the aftermath of Saturday's shooting at the Trump rally, and a planned interview with NBC News was moved to the White House. Without the event as a backdrop, the interview devolved into a tense and combative exchange focused largely on Biden's rhetoric and questions about his age.</p>

<p>"Sometime come and talk to me about what we should be talking about," Biden told NBC anchor Lester Holt at the conclusion. "OK? The issues."</p>

<p>Biden resumed campaign events Tuesday with an appearance at the NAACP's national convention, but quickly bungled the centrepiece of his speech: a new proposal to cap rent increases by corporate landlords at 5% annually.</p>

<p>Instead, Biden appeared to struggle to read his teleprompter, eventually saying the limit would be $55.</p>

<h3><strong>Medical Condition</strong></h3>

<p>After the event, BET News released excerpts from an interview with Biden where he appeared to open the door to reconsidering his reelection bid if doctors advised it.</p>

<p>"If I had some medical condition that emerged, if somebody, if doctors came to me and said, you got this problem and that problem," Biden said.</p>

<p>On Wednesday, things didn't improve. Biden held a call with Jeffrey Katzenberg, the Hollywood executive leading his fundraising effort, and was told that donations were drying up over concerns about his age, Semafor reported. Katzenberg subsequently issued a statement to the outlet calling it a "misread of a private meeting."</p>

<p>The president then went to tape a radio interview with Univision but left it feeling unwell. A Covid test confirmed his infection and the president quickly spirited back to the Las Vegas airport to return to his home in Rehoboth Beach, Delaware.</p>

<p>About the only positive news for the president was that his symptoms were mild, according to the White House: a runny nose, cough, and - appropriately enough - "general malaise."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/hhf01ec8_joe-biden-covid-bloomberg-_625x300_18_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[While Joe Biden's symptoms are mild, the diagnosis removes him from the campaign trail.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-covid-19-inquiry-to-issue-first-report-on-preparedness-6129568]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK Covid-19 Inquiry To Issue First Report On Preparedness]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-covid-19-inquiry-to-issue-first-report-on-preparedness-6129568]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 18 Jul 2024 06:20:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A public inquiry examining Britain's response to the COVID-19 outbreak will issue its first report on Thursday, focusing on how well prepared the nation was for handling such a pandemic.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;A public inquiry examining Britain's response to the COVID-19 outbreak will issue its first report on Thursday, focusing on how well prepared the nation was for handling such a pandemic.</p>

<p>Britain recorded one of the world's highest number of fatalities from COVID with more than 230,000 deaths reported by December 2023.</p>

<p>Former Prime Minister Boris Johnson ordered the inquiry in May 2021, and it was formally launched the following year with former judge Heather Hallett as its chair.</p>

<p>The inquiry was told in early evidence that the government was under-prepared and had failed to anticipate measures needed to protect the vulnerable.</p>

<p>That echoed the findings of the government's spending watchdog which concluded in a 2021 report that the government was not prepared for a crisis like the pandemic, had failed to learn from simulation exercises and was distracted by Britain's departure from the European Union.</p>

<p>"We know that for lives to be saved in the future, lessons must be learnt from the mistakes of the past," said Brenda Doherty on behalf of the campaign group, COVID-19 Bereaved Families for Justice UK. "Sadly, nobody knows the true cost of the government's failure to prepare as we do."</p>

<p>The inquiry's first module has only examined Britain's preparedness. Later reports will provide assessments of the more politically charged issues of governance and decision-making during the pandemic against a backdrop of wide criticism of government incompetence.</p>

<p>Johnson himself was forced from office in July 2022, with revelations of parties during COVID lockdowns among the many scandals that ended his premiership. A parliamentary committee later concluded he had misled lawmakers over the parties.</p>

<p>His later successor as prime minister and the finance minister during the pandemic Rishi Sunak was also fined for breaking lockdown rules.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-12/n9q4att_uk-covid-testing-reuters_625x300_30_December_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[More than 230,000 deaths were reported by December 2023 due to Covid in the UK.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/secret-service-head-to-testify-to-us-house-panel-on-donald-trump-shooting-6129452]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Secret Service Head To Testify To US House Panel On Trump Shooting]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/secret-service-head-to-testify-to-us-house-panel-on-donald-trump-shooting-6129452]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 18 Jul 2024 05:42:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Secret Service Director Kimberly Cheatle has agreed to testify before the U.S. House of Representatives Oversight Committee on July 22 for a hearing related to the shooting of former President Donald Trump at a rally, the panel said on Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Secret Service Director Kimberly Cheatle has agreed to testify before the U.S. House of Representatives Oversight Committee on July 22 for a hearing related to the shooting of former President Donald Trump at a rally, the panel said on Wednesday.</p>

<p><strong>WHY IT IS IMPORTANT</strong></p>

<p>Security at the Republican presidential candidate's rally in Pennsylvania has been under scrutiny after the former president was shot on Saturday at the event. The FBI said it was probing the shooting as an assassination attempt.</p>

<p>The shooting has raised serious concerns about how the suspect was able to access a nearby rooftop with a direct line of sight to where Trump was speaking.</p>

<p>Trump has since said he was doing well and has appeared at the Republican National Convention this week but the shooting left his face streaked with blood after his right ear was hit. A rally attendee was killed in the shooting, two others were wounded and the suspect is dead.</p>

<p><strong>KEY QUOTES</strong></p>

<p>"Americans demand and deserve answers from Director Cheatle about the attempted assassination of President Trump and the Secret Service's egregious failures," the Republican-led House oversight panel said on Wednesday, adding Cheatle agreed to comply with a subpoena issued by the committee's chair.</p>

<p>"The hearing will take place as scheduled on Monday, July 22," the panel added.</p>

<p><strong>CONTEXT</strong></p>

<p>Democratic U.S. President Joe Biden, who will face Republican Trump in November's election, said on Sunday he had ordered an independent review, and Republican lawmakers in Congress have also vowed swift investigations.</p>

<p>Cheatle said on Monday the Trump rally shooting was "unacceptable" and that she would not resign her post. Top Republicans in the U.S. Congress called on Wednesday for her to resign.</p>

<p>The Secret Service is responsible for protecting presidents and former presidents.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/b4bmjc0g_donald-trump_625x300_18_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Secret Service is responsible for protecting presidents and former presidents.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/florida-man-arrested-for-making-threats-against-joe-biden-6129397]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Florida Man Arrested For Making Threats Against Biden]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/florida-man-arrested-for-making-threats-against-joe-biden-6129397]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 18 Jul 2024 05:20:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Florida man has been arrested for making threats against US President Joe Biden, just days after an assassination attempt on his Republican rival Donald Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Florida man has been arrested for making threats against US President Joe Biden, just days after an assassination attempt on his Republican rival Donald Trump.</p>

<p>Jason Patrick Alday, 39, was arrested on Monday, the US Attorney's Office for the Northern District of Florida said.</p>

<p>Alday, of Quincy, Florida, allegedly "engaged in sending threatening communications, making threats against President Joe Biden and other federal officials," the office said in an announcement Wednesday.</p>

<p>According to the criminal complaint, Alday made threatening statements about Biden while being checked into a mental health facility in Tallahassee, Florida, last month.</p>

<p>He allegedly made further threats in posts on X.</p>

<p>Alday has been ordered detained pending trial.</p>

<p>Trump, 78, was wounded in the ear when a gunman opened fire during a campaign rally on Saturday in Butler, Pennsylvania.</p>

<p>A rally attendee was killed. The 20-year-old gunman, Thomas Matthew Crooks, was shot dead by Secret Service snipers.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-06/q6pll2vo_joe-biden-afp_625x300_03_June_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A Florida man has been arrested for making threats against US President Joe Biden.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-tests-positive-for-covid-as-age-worries-mount-6129310]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Joe Biden Tests Positive For Covid As Age Worries Mount]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-tests-positive-for-covid-as-age-worries-mount-6129310]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 18 Jul 2024 04:51:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden tested positive for Covid on Wednesday, shortly after conceding that he would consider dropping his troubled reelection bid if he was diagnosed with a serious medical condition.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden tested positive for Covid on Wednesday, shortly after conceding that he would consider dropping his troubled reelection bid if he was diagnosed with a serious medical condition.</p>

<p>The 81-year-old Democrat gave media the thumbs up from his limousine and said "I feel good" as he cut short a campaign trip to Las Vegas following the diagnosis.</p>

<p>The White House said he was suffering from a runny nose, cough and "general malaise," was taking Covid medication, and was flying straight to isolation at his beach house in Rehoboth, Delaware.</p>

<p>The diagnosis came hours after the release of comments by Biden in an interview conducted on Tuesday, in which he said he could step aside as a presidential candidate "if I had some medical condition that emerged."</p>

<p>It was also the latest development over a dramatic few days in the already frenetic and polarized White House race that saw his rival Donald Trump survive an assassination at a campaign rally of his own.</p>

<p>Biden has been fighting for political survival since a disastrous debate against Trump nearly three weeks ago, in which his tired and confused appearance sparked concerns about his age.</p>

<p>White House Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre said Biden had tested positive shortly after the first in a series of events in Las Vegas targeting crucial Latino voters.</p>

<p>"He is vaccinated and boosted and he is experiencing mild symptoms. He will be returning to Delaware where he will self-isolate and will continue to carry out all of his duties fully during that time," Jean-Pierre said.</p>

<p>Biden's doctor said he was suffering from a runny nose and a "non-productive cough" along with "general malaise," the White House said in an accompanying note.</p>

<p>He has received the Covid drug Paxlovid and has already taken his first dose, the statement read.</p>

<p>"His symptoms remain mild, his respiratory rate is normal at 16, his temperature is normal at 97.8 and his pulse oximetry is normal at 97 percent," it added.</p>

<p>- 'I feel good' -</p>

<p>Biden later leaned out of his limousine, dubbed the Beast, as he arrived at a Las Vegas airport to give the thumbs up.</p>

<p>"Good," he said to the press as he walked to Air Force One without a mask. "I feel good."</p>

<p>Janet Murguia, the president of the Unidos union for Latino workers, told the crowd about the diagnosis shortly before the White House announcement.</p>

<p>"I was just on the phone with President Biden, and he shared his deep disappointment at not being able to join us this afternoon," she said.</p>

<p>The furor over Biden's health is now set to go into overdrive, with a growing number of Democrats calling on him to step aside.</p>

<p>Asked what could make him rethink his presidential bid, Biden told the Black media outlet BET in an interview taped Tuesday in Las Vegas: "If I had some medical condition that emerged, if somebody, if the doctors came and said 'you've got this problem, that problem.'"</p>

<p>He suffered a major blow hours earlier on Wednesday when a top Democrat, Representative Adam Schiff of California, urged Biden to "pass the torch."</p>

<p>"A second Trump presidency will undermine the very foundation of our democracy, and I have serious concerns about whether the President can defeat Donald Trump in November," Schiff said in a statement to the Los Angeles Times.</p>

<p>Around 20 House Democrats and one senator have now called on Biden to leave the White House race.</p>

<p>Most polls show Biden trailing the election in a tight race with Trump.</p>

<p>Biden insists that Democratic voters support him, but a poll by the Associated Press and NORC Center for Public Affairs Research said Wednesday that nearly two-thirds want him to step aside.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/6v5grhls_joe-biden_625x300_18_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The White House said Biden was suffering from a runny nose, cough and "general malaise.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-says-could-drop-election-bid-if-medical-condition-emerged-6128736]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden Says Could Drop Election Bid If "Medical Condition" Emerged]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-says-could-drop-election-bid-if-medical-condition-emerged-6128736]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 18 Jul 2024 01:36:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden said he might re-evalute his election bid if a "medical condition" emerged, according to an extract of an interview released Wednesday, as his health faces scrutiny after a disastrous debate.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden said he could drop his reelection bid if doctors found he had a medical condition, as a top Democrat on Wednesday urged the 81-year-old to step aside.</p>

<p>Biden's comments were the first time he has even slightly opened the door to abandoning the White House race, and came as Representative Adam Schiff, a key ally from California, urged Biden to "pass the torch."</p>

<p>"If I had some medical condition that emerged, if somebody, if the doctors came and said 'you've got this problem, that problem,'" Biden told the Black media outlet BET in an interview taped Tuesday, when asked what could make him rethink.</p>

<p>Biden however defended his decision to stay on for a rematch with Republican Donald Trump in November, and explained why he had not handed over to a younger generation after one term.</p>

<p>"I said I was going to be a transitional candidate, and I thought I'd be able to move on from this, pass it on to someone else," he said. "But I didn't anticipate things getting so, so, so divided."</p>

<p>Biden has been fighting for political survival since a disastrous debate against Trump nearly three weeks ago, in which his tired and confused appearance sparked concerns about his age.</p>

<p>Schiff became the first Democrat to call for him to step aside since the assassination attempt against Trump on Saturday, which had briefly silenced the growing chorus against Biden.</p>

<p>"A second Trump presidency will undermine the very foundation of our democracy, and I have serious concerns about whether the President can defeat Donald Trump in November," Schiff said in a statement to the Los Angeles Times.</p>

<p>Schiff, who is expected to win a Senate seat this November, is a key White House ally in the legislature and shot to nationwide prominence as lead prosecutor during then-president Trump's first impeachment trial.</p>

<p>Biden was set to make a fresh attempt to prop up his candidacy in a speech to crucial Latino voters in the battleground state of Nevada later Wednesday.</p>

<p>- 'Pretty damn good' -</p>

<p>Around 20 House Democrats and one senator have now called on Biden to leave the White House race but Biden has refused, insisting he is best placed to beat Trump.</p>

<p>Most polls show Biden trailing in a tight race, with Trump pulling ahead in key swing states but no dramatic movement since the debate debacle or shooting.</p>

<p>Biden said his mental acuity was "pretty damn good" in an NBC interview on Monday, one of a series of unscripted outings aimed at showing he has what it takes.</p>

<p>With pressure on Biden mounting, Democrats said on Wednesday they plan a virtual nomination for the president in the first week of August, ahead of the Democratic National Convention (DNC) on August 19.</p>

<p>Some Democrats have slammed the scheme, accusing the party of trying to ram through Biden's candidacy and avoid a full discussion of alternative choices.</p>

<p>Party chiefs say they need to carry out the virtual roll-call by August 7, which is the deadline set by the Republican-led state of Ohio for the submission of nominations.</p>

<p>Biden otherwise risks not being on the ballot in Ohio, the home state of Trump's new running mate J.D. Vance.</p>

<p>While Ohio's governor has signed a law giving Biden more time, the DNC said it feared further legal challenges.</p>

<p>"None of this will be rushed," the heads of the DNC's rules committee said in a letter to lawmakers obtained by AFP. "No matter what may be reported, our goal is not to fast-track."</p>

<p>But several lawmakers are planning to sign a letter against the virtual nomination plan and others have criticized it, according to US media.</p>

<p>Biden insists that Democratic voters support him, but a poll by the Associated Press and NORC Center for Public Affairs Research said Wednesday that nearly two-thirds want him to step aside.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/dkviueqo_joe-biden-afp-_625x300_15_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Biden has been fighting for political survival since a disastrous debate against Trump 3 weeks ago.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-says-its-ready-to-work-with-any-us-leader-6128735]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russia Says It's Ready To Work With Any US Leader]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-says-its-ready-to-work-with-any-us-leader-6128735]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 18 Jul 2024 01:31:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russia is prepared to work with any US president who is open to dialogue, its foreign minister said Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russia is prepared to work with any US president who is open to dialogue, its foreign minister said Wednesday.</p>

<p>"We will work with any American leader, we will remain ready to work with any US leader that the US people elect, and who will be willing to engage in equitable, mutually respectful dialogue," Sergei Lavrov said at a UN press briefing.</p>

<p>He was answering a question about relations between Moscow and Washington if Donald Trump is reelected in November and defeats President Joe Biden.</p>

<p>Trump, the Republican candidate, said in May 2023 that he could end the war in Ukraine "in 24 hours" if he returns to the White House.</p>

<p>Trump is regularly attacked by Democrats as being too soft on Russia. He has often spoken admiringly of President Vladimir Putin, who has been charged with war crimes over the invasion of Ukraine.</p>

<p>"We worked with President Trump," Lavrov said.</p>

<p>He said US sanctions were repeatedly imposed on Moscow while Trump was in power. However, "at that time dialogue was under way between us and Washington at the highest levels. Right now, there is no such dialogue."</p>

<p>Asked about Trump's running mate, Senator J.D. Vance, a fierce opponent of US aid to Ukraine, Lavrov praised his position.</p>

<p>"He's in favor of peace, in favor of ending the assistance that's been provided, and we can only welcome that, because that's what we need -- to stop pumping Ukraine full of weapons and then the war will end," he said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-05/rn1gdkl8_sergei-lavrov_625x300_20_May_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Lavrov said that said US sanctions were repeatedly imposed on Moscow while Trump was in power.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-people-die-after-drowning-in-lake-in-telangana-cops-6128708]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[3 People Die After Drowning In Lake In Telangana: Cops]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-people-die-after-drowning-in-lake-in-telangana-cops-6128708]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 18 Jul 2024 01:24:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Two men and a 12-year-old girl have died after drowning in a lake in the Suryapet district of Telangana, police said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Two men and a 12-year-old girl have died after drowning in a lake in the Suryapet district of Telangana, police said.</p>

<p>The incident occurred on the outskirts of Bopparam village within Atmakur police station limits in the district on Wednesday, they said.</p>

<p>Police said that the victims were attending a birthday party in the village when the incident took place. The bodies have been shifted to Suryapet District Hospital for post-mortem examination.</p>

<p>According to police, the deceased have been identified as Tippareddy Sripalreddy (42), a builder from Khammam, and his friend Shavalya Raju (45), a software professional from Narsaraopet, Andhra Pradesh, and Shavalya Raju's daughter, Shavalya Usha (12), a student.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-12/0htt5beg_india-police-generic_625x300_23_December_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Two men and a 12-year-old girl have died after drowning in a lake in the Suryapet district of Telangana.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-military-declares-end-of-troubled-gaza-aid-pier-mission-6128558]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Military Declares End Of Troubled Gaza Aid Pier Mission]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-military-declares-end-of-troubled-gaza-aid-pier-mission-6128558]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:33:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The US military's problem-plagued mission to deliver aid to Gaza via a temporary pier has ended, a senior American officer said on Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The US military's problem-plagued mission to deliver aid to Gaza via a temporary pier has ended, a senior American officer said on Wednesday.</p>

<p>"The maritime surge mission involving the pier is complete, so there's no more need to use the pier," Vice Admiral Brad Cooper told journalists.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/bc53ut38_israel-hamas-war_625x300_14_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The US military's problem-plagued mission to deliver aid to Gaza via a temporary pier has ended.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/assassination-attempt-has-sealed-the-election-donald-trump-close-aide-shalabh-kumar-to-ndtv-6128460]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Assassination Attempt Has Sealed The Election": Trump's Close Aide]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/assassination-attempt-has-sealed-the-election-donald-trump-close-aide-shalabh-kumar-to-ndtv-6128460]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:10:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Unless a miracle happens for Democrats, Donald Trump is set to be the 47th President of the United States of America, a beaming Shalabh Kumar, a close aide of Trump, told NDTV.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Unless a miracle happens for Democrats, Donald Trump is set to be the 47th President of the United States of America, a beaming Shalabh Kumar, a close aide of Trump, told NDTV. The Chicago businessman underlined that the failed assassination attempt means it is game, set, match for Trump in the November election.</p>

<p>"This particular event, the assassination attempt, has practically sealed the election campaign. It is almost over. It is very challenging at this point for Democrats to figure out what to do. Such a contrast has been laid out in the minds of the electorate. Two weeks prior to this, you had this debate between Trump and Biden where everybody recognises, including president Biden, that it was really a bad night for him. He just seemed to be lost. He didn't seem to be anywhere; could not answer any question. Sleepy Joe as he has been known," said Mr Kumar, Chairman of the Republican Hindu Coalition.</p>

<p>"In contrast to that we have a man of steel, a fighter. Doesn't look like a 78-year-old. After getting shot in his right ear, if he had been looking straight it would have gone straight to his head. He gets up and has this fighting spirit, says fight, fight, fight. That's what Americans like to see in their presidents. As it stands right now, unless the Democrats come up with a different candidate, they still have a month to go, this election is over," said the prominent Indian-American businessman.</p>

<p>Pressed to answer if there is a rethink on the presidential candidate on the Democratic side, he said he is hoping for a last-minute change to make for an exciting contest. They still have a month to decide, he said.</p>

<p>"I am still betting on President Barack Obama convincing his wife Michelle Obama to step in at the last minute. Then there would be a real contest. I would probably say then between Trump and Michelle Obama there will be a contest. Between Trump and Joe Biden there is no contest. Between Trump and Kamala Harris there is no contest. Behind the scenes, everybody wishes on the Democrat part that Michelle Obama is persuaded to become the Democrat nominee. A good contest is always a good thing," said the man, who was involved in the Ronald Reagan re-election campaign in 1984.</p>

<p>"They have to come up with something different. I am hoping Obama convinces Michelle to step up. Then there will be a real contest. They have to find somebody else," said the businessman.</p>

<p>Asked how the fundraising is coming along post the assassination attempt, Mr Kumar said it has seen a dramatic increase.</p>

<p>"Money is going like crazy. Donor class is seeing that the DJT (Donald John Trump) is coming back as the 47th president. Am sure you are aware of what Elon Musk has done. $45 million a month till the election. Peter Thiel. Big time people are coming forward and funding the campaign. Money raising has increased dramatically after the assassination attempt," said the businessman who is not just a financial backer but is on the ground getting people out to vote as Trump limbers for a second showdown with Joe Biden.</p>

<p>Donald Trump won the formal nomination Monday as the Republican presidential candidate and picked a right-wing loyalist, JD Vance, for his running mate, kicking off a triumphalist party convention in the wake of the weekend's failed assassination attempt.</p>

<p>"We have 6 million Hindu Americans in the country, out of that 3.3 million are registered voters. Hindu Americans, Indian Americans, they like to declare themselves independent. They go back and forth. 2008, 2012 they were majorly for the Democrat. And 2016 we changed that significantly, especially in the battleground states. Then in 2020, they shifted back to Democrats. Maybe they are fence-sitters. Hindu Americans, they decide practically at the last minute who they are going to vote for. Maybe on the day of the election itself. They are not committed to any particular party," he said.</p>

<p>The 78-year-old former president was injured but survived the assassination attempt, a brazen attack that shocked a nation already deeply polarized ahead of the November election.</p>

<p>"The country is divided. However, even before the debate, particularly after the debate, the country was pulling towards Trump," he said.</p>

<p>Trump was speaking when multiple bangs rang out. He clutched his ear, with blood visible on his ear and cheek, then ducked to the floor as Secret Service agents swarmed onto the podium, surrounding him and rushing him to a nearby vehicle.</p>

<p>Iconic images of a bloodied Trump waving his fist after the shooting are already galvanizing Republican hopes that voters will further rally behind him for a landslide victory in November.</p>

<p>"The campaign after the assassination attempt has become a different campaign. It's altogether different. The enthusiasm in the delegates and people on the ground, the MAGA crowd, the enthusiasm is through the roof. As everybody can sense that at this point in time, unless a miracle happens for Democrats, he is the 47th president of the US and we are all very happy about it," he stressed.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/vua35aao_shalabh-kumar-ndtv_625x300_18_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-cant-defeat-us-if-we-revive-american-dream-vivek-ramaswamy-6128269]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[China Can't Defeat US If We Revive "American Dream": Vivek Ramaswamy]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-cant-defeat-us-if-we-revive-american-dream-vivek-ramaswamy-6128269]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 17 Jul 2024 23:30:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Indian-origin Republican leader Vivek Ramaswamy, during the Republican National Convention, stressed the 'American Dream' and called on people to shed all forms of fear and be free to speak up their minds.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Indian-origin Republican leader Vivek Ramaswamy, during the Republican National Convention, stressed the 'American Dream' and called on people to shed all forms of fear and be free to speak up their minds.</p>

<p>He said that this 'American Dream' won US the American Revolution, two world wars, and the Cold War, and if that can be revived again, not a nation, not a virus, or China can defeat the US.</p>

<p>He was addressing the Republican National Convention in Milwaukee, Wisconsin, on Tuesday night.</p>

<p>"Fear has been infectious in this country. But courage can be contagious, too. That, too, is what it means to be an American...If you're at home and you disagree with everything I just said, our message to you is this: We will still defend to the death your right to say it, because that is who we are as Americans," said the GOP leader, who dropped out of the presidential race earlier this year.</p>

<p>"We are the country where we can disagree like hell and still get together at the dinner table at the end of it. That is the America I know. That is the America we miss," he added.</p>

<p>Tesla CEO Elon Musk also reacted on Mr Ramaswamy's remarks.</p>

<p>"Well said!!" Mr Musk posted on his X handle.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Well said!!<a href="https://t.co/CgKPa1rnnt">pic.twitter.com/CgKPa1rnnt</a></p>
— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1813388983109357933?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 17, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Further stating "We don't need to be a nation in decline," Mr Ramaswamy asserted that US can still be a nation in ascent, and whose best days are still ahead of it.</p>

<p>Elaborating on it further, he said that in US, people, irrespective of their identity, surname, can get ahead with their commitment, dedication and hard work.</p>

<p>"That country where, no matter who you are, where your parents came from or what your skin colour is, or how long your last name is, you will still get ahead in this country with your own hard work, your own commitment, your own dedication, and that you know what? You are free to speak your mind at every step of the way," Mr Ramaswamy said.</p>

<p>The Indian-origin leader further said that this "American exceptionalism" will be revived when Donald Trump returns to the White House.</p>

<p>"That is the American dream. That is what won us the American Revolution. That is what reunited us after the civilizational war. That is what won us two world wars and the Cold War. That is what still gives hope to the free world," Mr Ramaswamy said.</p>

<p>He added, "And if we can revive that dream over group identity, victimhood, and grievance, then nobody in the world, not a nation, not a corporation, not a virus, not China, is going to defeat us. That is what American exceptionalism is all about. And that is what we will revive this November when we send Donald J. Trump back to the White House."</p>

<p>Earlier in the day, the 38-year-old said that illegal immigrants will be 'returned' to the country of their origin.</p>

<p>"Our message to illegal immigrants is also this; we will return you to your country of origin. Not because you're all bad people, but because you broke the law, and the United States of America was founded on the rule of law," he stated.</p>

<p>Mr Ramaswamy added that he would seal the southern border on the first day if they came to power.</p>

<p>Addressing black Americans, he said, "The media has tried to convince you for decades that Republicans don't care about your communities. We want for you what we want for every American: safe neighborhoods, clean streets, good jobs, a better life for your children, and a justice system that treats everyone equally - regardless of your skin colour or your political beliefs."</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-12/7t9l89g_vivek-ramaswamy-afp_625x300_20_December_23.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Vivek Ramaswamy asserted that US can still be a nation in ascent (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-agency-probing-secret-services-security-handling-at-trump-rally-shooting-6128260]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Agency Probing Secret Service's Security Handling At Trump Rally Shooting]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-agency-probing-secret-services-security-handling-at-trump-rally-shooting-6128260]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 17 Jul 2024 23:29:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The US Department of Homeland Security's inspector general said Wednesday that it is investigating the Secret Service's handling of security at the campaign rally where a gunman tried to assassinate former president Donald Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The US Department of Homeland Security's inspector general said Wednesday that it is investigating the Secret Service's handling of security at the campaign rally where a gunman tried to assassinate former president Donald Trump.</p>

<p>The office of DHS inspector general Joseph Cuffari said in an online posting that the probe is intended to "evaluate the United States Secret Service's process for securing" the campaign event.</p>

<p>The Secret Service has faced intense scrutiny since Saturday's shooting in Butler, Pennsylvania, during which a gunman opened fire on the Republican presidential candidate from an exposed rooftop some 150 yards (meters) away from the stage where Trump was speaking.</p>

<p>Trump was wounded in the ear and a rally attendee was killed. The 20-year-old gunman, Thomas Matthew Crooks, was shot dead by Secret Service snipers.</p>

<p>President Joe Biden has ordered an independent review of the Secret Service's handling of the assassination attempt, which is also being investigated by the FBI as a case of potential domestic terrorism.</p>

<p>Members of the House of Representatives and Senate are to receive briefings from the Secret Service, the Justice Department and the FBI later Wednesday on the status of the various probes, according to US media reports.</p>

<p>The House Judiciary Committee on Wednesday announced plans to hold a hearing on July 24 into the FBI's investigation into the assassination attempt and Republican House Speaker Mike Johnson told Fox News he would seek the resignation of Secret Service director Kimberly Cheatle.</p>

<p>Cheatle is scheduled to appear before the House Committee on Oversight and Accountability on Monday for a hearing into the assassination attempt.</p>

<p>The Secret Service is responsible for the safety of the president, vice president and former presidents, and their families, as well as major election candidates and visiting foreign heads of state.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/eutnrp9_us-secret-service-in-trump-assassination-bid-afp_625x300_17_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Secret Service is responsible for the safety of the President. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-ukraine-exchange-95-prisoners-of-war-6128195]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russia, Ukraine Exchange 95 Prisoners Of War]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-ukraine-exchange-95-prisoners-of-war-6128195]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 17 Jul 2024 23:15:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russia and Ukraine have released a total of 190 captured soldiers in the latest prisoner exchange between the two sides, officials in Moscow and Kyiv announced Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russia and Ukraine have released a total of 190 captured soldiers in the latest prisoner exchange between the two sides, officials in Moscow and Kyiv announced Wednesday.</p>

<p>Thousands of POWs have been freed in more than 50 individual exchanges throughout the war -- an area where the two sides have been able to strike rare agreements since Russia invaded in February 2022.</p>

<p>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky and Russia's defence ministry each said Wednesday that 95 of their soldiers had been freed.</p>

<p>"We continue to bring our people home. Another 95 defenders have been released from Russian captivity," Zelensky said in a post on Telegram.</p>

<p>He said the exchange was mediated by the United Arab Emirates.</p>

<p>"As a result of a negotiation process, 95 Russian servicemen... have been returned," Russia's defence ministry said on Telegram.</p>

<p>Russian President Vladimir Putin said in June that 1,348 Russian soldiers were being held in Ukrainian captivity, and that Russia had detained 6,465 Ukrainian POWs.</p>

<p>Exchanges have taken place sporadically throughout the conflict.</p>

<p>In a rare instance of direct talks between officials from Moscow and Kyiv, Russian Human Rights Commissioner Tatyana Moskalkova said her office met with a counterpart from Ukraine at the exchange.</p>

<p>The first such meeting took place at an exchange in June, Ukraine's human rights commissioner Dmytro Lubinets told AFP at the time.</p>

<p>The officials discussed "joint humanitarian actions, including those related to the reunification of families," Moskalkova said.</p>

<p>Kyiv accuses Russia of having forcibly deported thousands of Ukrainian children from territory which came under Moscow's control, and is working to secure their return.</p>

<p>Moscow says children were moved for their own protection.</p>

<p>Several have been returned, including through deals brokered by Qatar.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/egrtpg4_russia-prisoners-of-war_625x300_17_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Exchanges have taken place sporadically throughout the conflict. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/press-this-button-portable-suicide-pod-to-be-used-in-switzerland-soon-6127732]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Press This Button": Portable Suicide Pod To Be Used In Switzerland Soon]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/press-this-button-portable-suicide-pod-to-be-used-in-switzerland-soon-6127732]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 17 Jul 2024 21:53:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An assisted dying group expects a new portable suicide pod to be used for the first time in Switzerland potentially within months to provide death without medical supervision, they said Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An assisted dying group expects a new portable suicide pod to be used for the first time in Switzerland potentially within months to provide death without medical supervision, they said Wednesday.</p>

<p>The space-age-looking Sarco capsule first unveiled in 2019 replaces the oxygen inside of it with nitrogen, causing death by hypoxia.</p>

<p>The recently-formed organisation The Last Resort said it saw no legal obstacle to its use in Switzerland, where the law generally allows assisted suicide if the person commits the lethal act themselves.</p>

<p>"Since we have people indeed queuing up, asking to use the Sarco, it's very likely that it will take place pretty soon. But it's all I can say," Last Resort's chief executive Florian Willet told a press conference.</p>

<p>"I cannot imagine a more beautiful way (to die), of breathing air without oxygen until falling into an eternal sleep," he added.</p>

<p>The person wishing to die must first pass a psychiatric assessment of their mental capacity -- a key legal requirement.</p>

<p>The person climbs into the capsule, closes the lid, and is asked automated questions such as who they are, where they are and if they know what happens when they press the button.</p>

<p>"'If you want to die', the voice says in the processor, 'Press this button'," said euthanasia campaigner and Sarco inventor Philip Nitschke.</p>

<p>He said that once the button is pressed, the amount of oxygen in the air plummets from 21 percent to 0.05 percent in less than 30 seconds.</p>

<p>"They will then stay in that state of unconsciousness for... around about five minutes before death will take place," he added.</p>

<p><strong>No way back</strong></p>

<p>As for someone changing their mind at the very last minute, Nitschke said: "Once you press that button, there's no way of going back."</p>

<p>No decision has been made over the time, date and place of the first death, or who the first user might be.</p>

<p>Such details would not be made public until after the event because "we really don't want a person's desire for a peaceful passing Switzerland to turn into a media circus", said lawyer Fiona Stewart, who is on The Last Resort's advisory board.</p>

<p>Asked if the first use would be this year, she replied: "I would say yes".</p>

<p>She said the only cost for the user would be 18 Swiss francs ($20) for the nitrogen.</p>

<p>But the capsule's potential use has raised a host of legal and ethical questions in Switzerland, reigniting debate on assisted dying.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p><p><div class='table-div suicide'><table class='table'><thead><tr><th colspan='2'>Helplines</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>Vandrevala Foundation for Mental Health</td><td><a href='tel:+919999666555'>9999666555</a> or <a href='mailto:help@vandrevalafoundation.com'>help@vandrevalafoundation.com</a> </td></tr><tr><td>TISS iCall</td><td><a href='tel:+912225521111'>022-25521111</a> (Monday-Saturday: 8 am to 10 pm)</td></tr> <tr><td colspan='2'>(If you need support or know someone who does, please reach out to your nearest mental health specialist.)</td></tr></tbody></table></div></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/cd7mah7g_sarco-capsule_625x300_17_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The space-age-looking Sarco capsule was first unveiled in 2019. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uks-new-government-vows-to-remove-92-unelected-peers-from-upper-house-6127617]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK's New Government Vows To Remove 92 Unelected Peers From Upper House]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uks-new-government-vows-to-remove-92-unelected-peers-from-upper-house-6127617]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 17 Jul 2024 21:38:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The UK government on Wednesday announced plans to axe 92 House of Lords seats retained for hereditary lawmakers, resurrecting reform of the unelected chamber started under Tony Blair's Labour government in the 1990s.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p>

<p>The UK government on Wednesday announced plans to axe 92 House of Lords seats retained for hereditary lawmakers, resurrecting reform of the unelected chamber started under Tony Blair's Labour government in the 1990s.</p>

<p>King Charles III, opening the first parliamentary session after Keir Starmer's general election win for Labour, said removing the peers' right to sit and vote in the Lords was part of "measures to modernise" Britain's uncodified constitution.</p>

<p>Labour won the July 4 election by a landslide, returning it to power for the first time since 2010, allowing it to put its manifesto pledges into law, including the much-touted Lords reforms.</p>

<p>Parliament's unelected upper chamber has long been subject to demands for reform to make it more representative and less "a chamber festering with grotesques and has-beens", as one newspaper columnist famously described it in 2022.</p>

<p>But the extent of Labour's plans remain unclear.</p>

<p>The scrapping of the hereditary peers -- the hundreds of members of the aristocracy whose titles are inherited -- has been described as a "first step in wider reform".</p>

<p>"The continued presence of hereditary peers in the House of Lords is outdated and indefensible," the government said in briefing notes accompanying the King's Speech.</p>

<p><strong>Removing hereditary seats</strong></p>

<p>Comprising around 800 lawmakers, the House of Lords is comfortably larger than any other equivalent in a democracy.</p>

<p>Its members, whose current average age is 71, are mostly appointed for life.</p>

<p>They include former MPs, typically appointed by departing prime ministers, along with people nominated after serving in prominent public- or private-sector roles, and Church of England clerics.</p>

<p>The primary role of the centuries-old chamber is to scrutinise the government.</p>

<p>It cannot override legislation sent from the popularly elected House of Commons, but it can amend and delay bills and initiate new draft laws.</p>

<p>That job occasionally propels the Lords into the political spotlight, such as during its recent delays to the previous Conservative government's contentious Rwanda deportation plan -- quickly scrapped by the new government.</p>

<p>Like the Commons, the Lords has specialised scrutiny committees.</p>

<p>The new government's planned legislation revisits the House of Lords reform agenda that Blair's Labour government initiated in the late 1990s.</p>

<p>His government had intended to abolish all the seats held by hundreds of hereditary members who sat in the chamber at that time.</p>

<p>But it ended up retaining 92 in what was supposed to be a temporary compromise.</p>

<p>"25 years later, they form part of the status quo more by accident than by design," said the briefing from Prime Minister Keir Starmer's government.</p>

<p>"No other modern comparable democracies allow individuals to sit and vote in their legislature by right of birth," it added.</p>

<p>"Holding membership of a seat within a Parliament on a hereditary basis is incredibly rare."</p>

<p><strong>'Overdue and essential'</strong></p>

<p>The government said the reforms were in part motivated by the gender imbalance of hereditary peers -- currently all male, because most peerages can only be passed down the male line.</p>

<p>The rest of the House of Lords fares better, with 242 of other members -- 36 percent -- female.</p>

<p>Starmer's new administration also argues that hereditary peers are too politically "static" for a democracy.</p>

<p>Of the 92 seats allotted for them under the 1999 reforms, 42 are for Conservatives, 28 for so-called crossbenchers, three for the Liberal Democrats and just two for Labour.</p>

<p>Meanwhile 15 are elected by the entire chamber from the hundreds of hereditary peers that exist in the UK.</p>

<p>Reformers also argue that hereditary peers do not face propriety checks, compared to life peers who are subject to a vetting procedure from the House of Lords Appointment Committee.</p>

<p>"In the 21st century, there should not be almost 100 places reserved for individuals who were born into certain families, nor should there be seats effectively reserved only for men," the government argued</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/pv54baeo_kings-speech_625x300_17_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The House of Lords is comfortably larger than any other equivalent in a democracy. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/record-heat-temperatures-in-ukraine-after-russian-attacks-on-power-plants-6127565]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Record Heat Temperatures In Ukraine After Russian Attacks On Power Plants]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/record-heat-temperatures-in-ukraine-after-russian-attacks-on-power-plants-6127565]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 17 Jul 2024 21:29:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Several cities across Ukraine were recording historic scorching temperatures, officials said Wednesday, at a time when major urban hubs are suffering long periods without electricity after Russian attacks on power plants.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Several cities across Ukraine were recording historic scorching temperatures, officials said Wednesday, at a time when major urban hubs are suffering long periods without electricity after Russian attacks on power plants.</p>

<p>In the capital Kyiv, Ukrainians have been seeking respite from oppressive heat by swimming in the Dnipro river that cuts through the city, where some districts have been without power for hours at a time due to electricity rationing.</p>

<p>"This is the hottest summer of my life," said 22-year-old Dmytro, who complained he had no electricity for about 20 hours a day.</p>

<p>Another resident, 18-year-old Diana, told AFP the temperature in her workplace was unbearable.</p>

<p>"Air conditioners don't run at work when there is no power. This is how we are living," she said.</p>

<p>A state meteorological station covering the Kyiv region said Wednesday that air temperatures one day earlier reached 36 degrees Celsius, beating by 0.2C a previous record for the same date set in 1931.</p>

<p>The Ukrainian Hydrometeorological Center said historic records were set in Vinnytsia, Chernivtsi and Mykolaiv -- cities in the centre and south of Ukraine.</p>

<p>The records come as the energy ministry has stepped up imports of electricity from European countries and imposed strict rationing due to Russian attacks that have halved Ukraine's electricity generation capacity, compared to one year ago.</p>

<p>The ministry said Wednesday that with temperatures at their "maximum", there would be rolling power outages across the country.</p>

<p>Electricity consumption is "also expected to reach a record level which significantly exceeds the capacity of Ukrainian power plants", the ministry explained in a statement.</p>

<p>Last month, Kyiv urged officials to turn off air conditioners in government buildings and called on regional authorities to limit street lighting to ease pressure on the grid.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-01/sc8es8l_ukraine-afp-_625x300_02_January_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Last month, Ukraine urged officials to turn off air conditioners in government buildings. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>