<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 11:32:30 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sri-lanka-polls-frontrunners-whats-at-stake-implications-for-india-6591362]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Sri Lanka Polls: Frontrunners, What's At Stake, Implications For India]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sri-lanka-polls-frontrunners-whats-at-stake-implications-for-india-6591362]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 11:28:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The political landscape in Sri Lanka is set to change as its citizens elect a new President on Saturday. Sri Lanka's 17 million voters will choose from among 39 candidates.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The political landscape in Sri Lanka is set to change as its citizens elect a new President on Saturday. Sri Lanka's 17 million voters will choose from among 39 candidates in the country's first election after the people's uprising of 2022, which led to then President Gotabaya Rajapaksa's ouster.</p>

<p>This year's election is dominated by two major alliances, the SJB (Samagi Jana Balawegaya) and the NPP (National People's Power), apart from various smaller parties and independent candidates.</p>

<p>President Ranil Wickremesinghe of the UNP (United National Party) is contesting as an independent. Wickremesinghe, popularly known as RW, is being supported by many rebel legislators of the SLPP (Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna) headed by former president Mahinda Rajapaksa. Also in the contest are opposition leader Sajith Premadasa from the SJB alliance; leftist leader Anura Kumara Dissanayake of the JVP (Janatha Vimukthi Peramuna) - the presidential candidate of NPP - and Mahinda's son, Namal Rajapaksa, as the SLPP candidate.</p>

<p>Poll surveys and experts suggest that Lankan voters are prioritising issues such as economy, education, health, law, and security. Matters of corruption and wrongdoing among politicians, which dominated the electoral narrative, have receded into the background after the 2022 unrest. Since most governments in the past didn't solve the corruption issue, people feel it's better to talk about development. They hope to elect a leader who can pull them out of dire poverty.</p>

<h2><strong>Gloomy past</strong></h2>

<p>In the last election, held after the Easter bombings on April 21, 2019, Gotabaya Rajapaksa of SLPP (Namal's uncle) won a decisive victory and Sajith Premadasa came second. However, three years later, the world saw Sri Lankans oust President Gotabaya Rajapaksa, having endured a steady economic slide. The flawed economic and monetary policies of Gotabaya, along with the COVID-19 pandemic that dented tourism - a chunk of the economy - resulted in an unsustainable debt level. In April 2022, Sri Lanka defaulted on its debt and asked the International Monetary Fund (IMF) for assistance. The Russia-Ukraine war further aggravated the crisis with rising food, medicine and fuel prices resulting in mass protests never seen before in the country's history.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Sri Lankas Samagi Jana Balawegaya party leader Sajith Premadasa waves to supporters." id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/oaet1ah_sajith-premadasa-afp_625x300_18_September_24.jpg" title="Sri Lankas Samagi Jana Balawegaya party leader Sajith Premadasa waves to supporters." /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">Sri Lanka's Samagi Jana Balawegaya party leader Sajith Premadasa waves to supporters.</p>
</div>

<p>The uprising was given the name of '<em>Janatha Aragalaya</em>' (a Sinhala term). Then Prime Minister Mahinda Rajapaksa resigned and subsequently, his brother Gotabaya Rajapaksa quit as President and fled. Ranil Wickremesinghe, a former minister, became Prime Minister. In July 2022, Ranil took over as president through a parliamentary vote with the support of the Rajapaksas' party SLPP, which still has the majority in the legislature. Ranil Wickremesinghe adopted severe austerity measures, with support from the IMF.</p>

<h2><strong>New leaders</strong></h2>

<p>Gotabaya Rajapaksa's inept governance and his decision to leave the country tarred the image of the Rajapaksa clan and the SLPP the most. Most SLPP MPs are supporting either Ranil or Sajith in this election. Namal Rajapaksa, they say, is just a symbolic candidate to keep the SLPP alive.</p>

<p>Sajith's SJB has the support of the Tamil and Muslim minorities, who form 11% and 9% of the population.</p>

<p>Though Tamil parties have fielded a common candidate, the largest party ITAK (Ilankai Tamil Arasu Kachchi) has extended its support to Sajith Premadasa. In 2019 also, Tamils had voted for Sajith but there was an unprecedented consolidation of Sinhala votes behind Gotabhaya Rajapaksa after the Easter bombings, which helped him win the election.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="National Peoples Power (NPP) presidential candidate Anura Kumara Dissanayaka gestures during an election rally." id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/jcgsatu_anura-kumara-dissanayaka-afp_625x300_18_September_24.jpg" title="National Peoples Power (NPP) presidential candidate Anura Kumara Dissanayaka gestures during an election rally." /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">National People's Power (NPP) presidential candidate Anura Kumara Dissanayaka gestures during an election rally.</p>
</div>

<p>The political space created by Rajapaksas' dismissal was filled by Anura Kumara Dissanayake and the JVP, who urged Sri Lankans to go for a broader change. Once in the margins, the party has emerged as a credible, major political force.</p>

<p>As far as Ranil Wickremesinghe is concerned, most members of his party UNP are now with Sajith, though he has support from some legislators of the SLPP like state Defence Minister Premitha Bandara Tennakoon. Ranil is banking on his handling of the economic crisis to fetch him votes.</p>

<p>"People want change this time. They don't want to vote for the same party and old candidates. The new voters, especially on social media, are rooting for Anura Dissanayake. However, on the ground Sajith has a lot of support base, especially in the rural areas," says Thushara Gooneratne, editor-in-chief, Mawrata News.</p>

<p>"Most people think of Sajith as pro-poor just like his father, former President R Premadasa."</p>

<h2><strong>India's Stake</strong></h2>

<p>In recent times, anti-India sentiment has surged in the neighbourhood, because of various reasons. Be it Nepal, Maldives, Sri Lanka or Bangladesh, politicians have been successful in diverting the people's ire towards India.</p>

<p>For India, the sorry plight of the Tamil population in the north and east of Sri Lanka has been a concern for a long time. Successive Lankan governments have failed to implement the 13th Amendment signed as part of India-Sri Lanka agreement in 1987, which provided for devolution of powers to local governments in the north and the east. India, in fact, raised the Sri Lankan Tamil issue at the 51st session of the United Nations Human Rights Council in Geneva in 2022. With the new government, India would like to push for the restoration of provincial councils, which would give a measure of autonomy to Lankan Tamils.</p>

<p>India has stakes in a stable and peaceful Sri Lanka. It wants to restrict China's growing interference in the country because of its geo-strategic location in the Indo-Pacific. The 99-year lease of Hambantota port to China in 2017, feeding the debt-trap narrative, has exacerbated India's concerns.</p>

<p>Anura Dissanayake's party has often been seen as close to China, India's principal geopolitical rival. But for some time now, Dissanayake has enjoyed a different kind of authority within Sri Lankan politics, which has in turn earned him recognition as a rising political force even from India's point of view. As a reflection of this, New Delhi invited Dissanayake in February to engage with him.</p>

<p>"Whoever wins this time will engage with India. Sajith is pro-India. But even Dissanayake, who was known to be anti-India before. India is important for Sri Lanka's growth and stability," says Thushara.</p>

<p>India needs all the goodwill it can command in order to navigate the increasing complexities in the neighbourhood, The escalating regional conflicts and a continuous shift in the global economic order. A friendly, stable neighbourhood is a good start.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/8ougknao_sri-lanka-polls_625x300_18_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sri Lanka's 17 million voters will choose from among 39 candidates.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-how-instagrams-teen-accounts-will-protect-underage-users-6591169]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: How Instagram's "Teen Accounts" Will Protect Underage Users]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-how-instagrams-teen-accounts-will-protect-underage-users-6591169]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 10:58:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Instagram has introduced new safety measures to better protect underage users from online harm.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Instagram has introduced new safety measures to better protect underage users from online harm. The key change is the creation of "Teen Accounts," designed to shield users aged 13 to 17 from the mental health challenges often linked to social media use.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>Why the update?</strong></h2>

<p>Experts and authorities have long criticised Instagram for its role in worsening mental health problems such as anxiety, addiction, cyberbullying, eating disorders and low self-esteem, among teens. Governments and advocacy groups around the world have called for stronger safeguards. Some, like in the US and Australia, are setting age restrictions for social media use.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Meta, Instagram's parent company, response is this significant update that defaults teens' accounts to private, limits who can contact them, and controls what content they are exposed to.</p>

<h2><strong>Features of "Teen Accounts"</strong></h2>

<ul>
	<li>Private accounts - Teens aged 13 to 17 will have their accounts set to private by default, making it harder for strangers to view or interact with their profiles.</li>
	<li>Messaging restrictions - Direct messaging (DM) will have tighter controls, allowing teens to receive messages only from people they follow. This reduces the chances of contact with unwanted or harmful individuals.</li>
	<li>Sensitive content restrictions - Teens will have limited exposure to potentially harmful or inappropriate content.</li>
	<li>Limited interactions - Interaction with adult accounts that do not follow them back will be limited, reducing risks like unsolicited DMs or predatory behaviour.</li>
	<li>Time limit reminders - Teens will receive notifications encouraging them to set time limits on how long they use the app. This will promote healthier usage habits.</li>
</ul>

<h2><strong>Parental supervision</strong></h2>

<p>Meta is also introducing a 'Parents' Supervision Feature', providing parents with more control over their teen's Instagram activity:</p>

<ul>
	<li>Parents can set maximum daily screen time for their children.</li>
	<li>They can see what topics their teen is viewing and monitor who they are chatting with.</li>
	<li>Parents can block access to the app during certain hours to help regulate screen time.</li>
</ul>

<h2><strong>Age Verification: How it works</strong></h2>

<p>Instagram will use new technology to verify user ages:</p>

<ul>
	<li>Partnering with Yoti, Instagram will allow teens to verify their age through a video selfie.</li>
	<li>Teens can also ask their mutual friends to verify their age if required.</li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-02/qqv8pi2_instagram-generic-unsplash_625x300_23_February_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The new Instagram update defaults teenagers' accounts to private.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/tupperware-files-for-bankruptcy-after-years-long-sales-struggle-6591096]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Tupperware Files For Bankruptcy After Years-Long Sales Struggle]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/tupperware-files-for-bankruptcy-after-years-long-sales-struggle-6591096]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 10:41:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Tupperware Brands Corp. filed for bankruptcy following a years-long struggle with sales declines and growing competition.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Tupperware Brands Corp. filed for bankruptcy following a years-long struggle with sales declines and growing competition.</p>

<p>Publicly-traded Tupperware filed for Chapter 11 bankruptcy protection, listing assets of between $500 million to $1 billion and liabilities of $1 billion to $10 billion, according to its court filing. The company will seek court approval to facilitate a sale process of the business and to continue operating during bankruptcy proceedings, it said in a separate statement.</p>

<p>The kitchenware company, which for decades dominated the world of food storage, since 2020 had warned of doubt in its ability to stay in business. As of June of this year, it planned to close its only US factory and lay off almost 150 employees.</p>

<p>The bankruptcy filing in Delaware follows months-long negotiations between Tupperware and its lenders over how to manage more than $700 million in loans. The creditors had agreed to give it some breathing room on that debt, but the business continued to deteriorate.</p>

<p>Tupperware founder Earl Tupper in 1946 introduced its plastic products to the public, and subsequently patented their flexible airtight seal. The brand's goods later flooded into American homes, largely by way of independent sales parties hosted in suburban homes.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/6as4m1f8_tupperware-bloodmberg_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Publicly-traded Tupperware filed for Chapter 11 bankruptcy protection. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-israel-lebanon-page-attacks-what-is-a-pager-and-why-hezbollah-still-relies-on-this-outdated-device-6590890]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What Is A Pager And Why Hezbollah Still Relies On This Outdated Device]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-israel-lebanon-page-attacks-what-is-a-pager-and-why-hezbollah-still-relies-on-this-outdated-device-6590890]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 10:09:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A pager or ‘beeper’ is a small, portable communication device that receives short messages, typically numeric or alphanumeric, over a radio frequency signal. ]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At least nine people were killed and nearly 3,000 wounded in Lebanon after thousands of wireless devices used by <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-grams-of-explosives-per-pager-israel-complex-op-to-hurt-hezbollah-6590229 ">Hezbollah members</a> exploded on Tuesday. A senior Lebanese security source claimed that Israel's Mossad spy agency planted explosives inside 5,000 Taiwan-made pagers or “beepers” ordered by the Iran-backed&nbsp;group months before the blasts.</p>

<h3><strong>What are pagers?</strong></h3>

<p>A pager or ‘beeper' is a small, portable communication device that receives short messages, typically numeric or alphanumeric, over a radio frequency signal. Pagers were widely used before cell phones became popular. It was a crucial communication tool, especially for professionals like doctors, journalists, technicians, and managers. It allowed them to receive important messages, even in remote areas.</p>

<h3><strong>How do pagers work?</strong></h3>

<p>The operation of a pager was straightforward yet efficient. When a message was sent via radio waves, the device would alert the user with a distinct beep. This prompt would then require the user to locate a nearby public or landline phone to respond to the message.</p>

<p>As technology progressed, pagers underwent significant improvements. The newer models were equipped with a small screen, enabling them to display short messages directly on the device.</p>

<p>However, by the 1990s, mobile phones started to replace these little devices. The convenience of mobile phones quickly diminished the demand for pagers, and by the late 1990s, beepers had mostly vanished from public use.</p>

<h3><strong>Why Hezbollah members still use pagers</strong></h3>

<p>The recent cyberattack targeting Iran-backed Hezbollah revealed that pagers, which many assumed had become obsolete, were still in use by the group.</p>

<p>The pagers were used by Hezbollah fighters as a low-tech means of communication to evade Israeli location-tracking.</p>

<p>According to reports, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-grams-of-explosives-per-pager-israel-complex-op-to-hurt-hezbollah-6590229#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll">Israel's Mossad spy agency</a> planted explosives inside 5,000 pagers imported by Hezbollah months before Tuesday's detonations.</p>

<p>The Lebanese security source told Reuters said the pagers were from Taiwan-based Gold Apollo, but the company said in a statement it did not manufacture the devices. It said they were made by a company called BAC which has a licence to use its brand, but gave no more details.</p>

<p>The senior Lebanese security source said the group had ordered 5,000 beepers from Gold Apollo, which several sources say were brought into the country earlier this year.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/j8sqsfc_pagers_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Representational Image]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-donald-trump-said-on-getting-a-call-from-kamala-harris-after-2nd-assassination-bid-6590390]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Shares What Kamala Harris Told Him On Call After Assassination Bid]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-donald-trump-said-on-getting-a-call-from-kamala-harris-after-2nd-assassination-bid-6590390]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 10:00:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump says that he got "a very nice call" from his Democratic adversary Kamala Harris on Tuesday following the second assassination attempt.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump says that he got "a very nice call" from his Democratic adversary Kamala Harris on Tuesday following the second assassination attempt.</p>

<p>"Today, a little while ago, I got a very nice call from Kamala," he said on Tuesday, mispronouncing her name as "Kamaala".</p>

<p>"It was very nice... was very, very nice. and we appreciate that," he said at a townhall meeting in Flint, Michigan, without elaborating on their conversation.</p>

<p>While a section of the crowd appeared to boo, he added, "But we have to take back our country. We have to win. We're going to win."</p>

<p>Giving her version of the call, Vice-President Harris said, "I checked on him to see if he was OK."</p>

<p>"And I told him what I have said publicly, there's no place for political violence in our country," she said at a meeting of Black journalists in Philadelphia.</p>

<p>US President Joe Biden had also talked to him by phone on Monday and Trump mentioned that at the meeting.</p>

<p>About his brushes with assassination attempts, Trump boasted, "Only consequential Presidents get shot at."</p>

<p>Trump's Secret Service detail thwarted an attack on him on Sunday when an agent spotted a man with a semi-automatic rifle hidden in bushes at the periphery of a golf course in Florida where he was playing.</p>

<p>The agent fired at the gunman, who fled and was later captured.</p>

<p>The man identified as Ryan Routh had donated to a committee supporting Democratic candidates and had voted in the party's primary election.</p>

<p>In an interview with Fox News Digital on Monday, Trump blamed Biden and Kamala Harris for the attempted attack.</p>

<p>Routh "believed the rhetoric of Biden and Harris, and he acted on it," he said.</p>

<p>"Their rhetoric is causing me to be shot at, when I am the one who is going to save the country," Trump asserted.</p>

<p>Trump was injured in his ear when a sniper shot at him at a Pennsylvania rally in July.</p>

<p>Trump and Harris first met face-to-face at their debate last Tuesday in Philadelphia where she walked up to him and shook his hand.</p>

<p>The next day at the commemoration of the 9/11 terrorist attack in New York they spoke to each other and shook hands.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/t62tibb8_donald-trump-kamala-harris-_625x300_11_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump said he got "a very nice call" from his Democratic adversary Kamala Harris.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-xec-covid-variant-spreads-to-27-countries-heres-what-we-know-so-far-6590482]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[New XEC Covid Variant Spreads To 27 Countries, Here's What We Know So Far]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-xec-covid-variant-spreads-to-27-countries-heres-what-we-know-so-far-6590482]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 08:39:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Scientists have warned that a "more contagious" variant of Covid-19, dubbed XEC, is spreading more rapidly across Europe and could soon become the dominant strain.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Scientists have warned that a "more contagious" variant of Covid-19, dubbed XEC, is spreading more rapidly across Europe and could soon become the dominant strain. According to<em> the BBC</em>, the new variant was first identified in Germany in June, and since then, the XEC variant has emerged in the UK, US, Denmark and several other countries. Experts have said that the new variant, a sublineage of the omicron variant, has some new mutations that might help it spread this autumn, although vaccines should still help prevent severe cases.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The XEC variant is a hybrid of the earlier omicron subvariants KS.1.1 and KP.3.3, which is currently dominant in Europe. So far, 500 samples from 27 countries, including Poland, Norway, Luxembourg, Ukraine, Portugal and China, have been found to contain XEC, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.independent.co.uk/news/science/new-xec-covid-variant-symptoms-signs-b2613998.html" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>The Independent</em></a> reported. Experts point to strong growth of the variant in Denmark, Germany, the UK, and the Netherlands.</p>

<p>Professor Francois Balloux, Director of the Genetics Institute at University College London, told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c1jddenj5p5o" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>BBC&nbsp;</em></a>that although XEC has a "slight transmission advantage" over other recent Covid variants, vaccines should still offer good protection. But he also added that XEC may become the dominant subvariant over the winter.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/wear-proper-undergarments-delta-airlines-new-memo-for-flight-attendants-6587880">"Wear Proper Undergarments": Delta Airlines' New Memo For Flight Attendants</a></strong></p>

<p>Director of the Scripps Research Translational Institute, in California, Eric Topol said XEC is "just getting started". "And that's going to take many weeks, a couple months, before it really takes hold and starts to cause a wave," he said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"XEC is definitely taking charge. That does appear to be the next variant. But it's months off from getting into high levels," said Mr Topol.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>Symptoms of XEC Covid</strong></h2>

<p>The symptoms of the XEC variant are similar to those of previous Covid variants, including fever, sore throat, cough, loss of sense of smell, loss of appetite, and body aches.&nbsp;</p>

<p>But since it is still only a sub-family of the same omicron lineage, experts say keeping up to date with vaccines and booster shots would offer sufficient protection against severe illness and hospitalisation.</p>

<p>Separately, the US Centres for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) has also advised people to practise good hygiene and take steps for cleaner air.</p>

<p>Moreover, researchers have called for monitoring the XEC more closely to better understand its symptoms.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-01/d31ktkno_covid-19-_625x300_11_January_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[So far, 500 samples from 27 countries have been found to contain XEC.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-after-second-assassination-bid-only-consequential-presidents-get-shot-at-6590479]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Only Consequential Presidents Get Shot At": Trump After Assassination Bid]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-after-second-assassination-bid-only-consequential-presidents-get-shot-at-6590479]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 08:39:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump's election rival Kamala Harris said Tuesday she had reached out to the former president after the thwarted attack.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump resumed campaigning Tuesday for the first time since a second apparent attempt on his life, boasting "only consequential presidents get shot at" while praising Kamala Harris for making a phone call to check on him. Trump spoke at a town hall meeting before fervent supporters in Flint, a beleaguered industrial city that was once a jewel of the US automotive industry in swing state Michigan, before factories closed due to foreign competition.</p>

<p>Trump drew a link between what the FBI called a foiled assassination bid against him Sunday at his golf course in Florida and his pledge to slap heavy tariffs on imports of cars from Mexico and China.</p>

<p>"And then you wonder why I get shot at, right? You know, only consequential presidents get shot at," Trump said.</p>

<p>Trump's election rival Harris, campaigning in another swing state, Pennsylvania, said Tuesday she had reached out to the former president after the thwarted attack.</p>

<p>"I checked on him to see if he was OK. And I told him what I have said publicly -- there's no place for political violence in our country," Harris said in an interview with the National Association of Black Journalists (NABJ).</p>

<p>The White House described it as a "cordial and brief conversation." Trump said Harris "could not have been nicer."</p>

<p>Trump has said the would-be shooter was a follower of what he called President Joe Biden's and Harris's rhetoric insisting that he is a threat to US democracy.</p>

<p>At the town hall meeting, Trump supporters said the foiled attack made them support him even more.</p>

<p>"I believe that they want to kill Trump so that Trump cannot try to make his second term in office," said retired autoworker Donald Owen, 71.</p>

<h3><strong>'Zero jobs'</strong></h3>

<p>Trump depicted himself at the event as the savior of the US auto industry as it competes with foreign companies.</p>

<p>He insisted: "If a tragedy happens, and we don't win, there will be zero car jobs, manufacturing jobs, it will all be out of here."</p>

<p>Trump also defended his convoluted, rambling way of speaking, and then in a tangent on fossil fuel drilling he said, "We have Bagram in Alaska. They say it might be as big, might be bigger than all of Saudi Arabia."</p>

<p>But Bagram is an air base in Afghanistan. Trump may have confused it with a place in Alaska called the Arctic National Wildlife Refuge, or ANWR.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Harris used her interview in Pennsylvania to give her first reaction to a row over false stories spread by Trump that Haitian immigrants were eating residents' cats and dogs in a town in Ohio.</p>

<p>Dozens of bomb threats were made against the community in the town of Springfield after Trump and his running mate JD Vance publicly boosted the fake story, forcing the closure of some schools.</p>

<p>"It's a crying shame, literally, what's happening to those families, those children in that community," Harris said.</p>

<h3><strong>'Hateful'</strong></h3>

<p>"It's got to stop. We've got to say that you cannot be entrusted with standing behind the seal of the president of the United States engaging in that hateful rhetoric," she added.</p>

<p>On Sunday, Trump was whisked away by the US Secret Service after gunman Ryan Routh was discovered in a hedgerow at his Florida golf course.&nbsp;</p>

<p>It was the second such close call for the Republican nominee in as many months, after a bullet grazed his ear in a shooting at a rally in Pennsylvania that left one man dead in June.</p>

<p>The dueling visits of Trump in Michigan and Harris in Pennsylvania come as both focus on the half-dozen swing states critical to winning in the election.</p>

<p>A new poll from Suffolk University and USA Today shows Harris with a slight 49-46 percent edge over Trump in Pennsylvania, thanks in large part to major support from women voters.</p>

<p>It confirms a large gender gap in the race, at least in Pennsylvania, with Harris leading with women by 56 percent to 39 percent, and Trump earning male votes by a slimmer 53-41 percent.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/3gpq8if_donald-trump_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[File photo]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-on-alert-as-hezbollah-vows-retaliation-over-pager-attacks-in-lebanon-6590328]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Israel Will Certainly Receive Its Punishment": Hezbollah After Pager Attacks]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-on-alert-as-hezbollah-vows-retaliation-over-pager-attacks-in-lebanon-6590328]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 07:57:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iran-backed Hezbollah vowed to retaliate against Israel after accusing it of detonating pagers across Lebanon, that killed nine people and injured about 2,800 others on Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<ol>
	<li>Hezbollah warned Israel it would be punished after <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/thousands-of-pagers-explode-in-lebanon-several-members-injured-in-biggest-security-breach-says-hezbollah-6587184#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">hundreds of pagers used by its members exploded</a> in its strongholds in southern Lebanon.&nbsp;</li>
	<li>The Iran-backed group said at least two of its fighters and a young girl were among the dead.&nbsp;</li>
	<li>Lebanese Health Minister Firass Abiad said some "2,800 people were injured, about 200 of them critically" with injuries mostly reported to the face, hands and stomach.</li>
	<li>According to media reports, Iran's ambassador in Beirut was also wounded in a pager explosion but his injuries were not serious.</li>
	<li>The New York Times reported that <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-grams-of-explosives-per-pager-israel-complex-op-to-hurt-hezbollah-6590229" target="_blank">Israel hid explosive material in the Taiwan-made Gold Apollo pagers</a> before they were imported to Lebanon. The material was implanted next to the battery with a switch that could be triggered remotely to detonate. Gold Apollo, however, said it did not make the pagers used in the explosion and said they were made by a company in Europe that had the right to use the Taiwanese firm's brand.</li>
	<li>Hezbollah said it holds the Israeli enemy "fully responsible for this criminal aggression". Israel "will certainly receive its just punishment for this sinful aggression," it said in a statement.</li>
	<li>The US, which is <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/not-aware-not-involved-us-on-lebanon-pager-blasts-6589968" target="_blank">Israel's top arms provider</a> and close ally, said it was "not involved" and "not aware of this incident in advance".</li>
	<li>Hamas, which is waging war with Israel in Gaza, said the pager blasts were an "escalation" that would only lead Israel to "failure and defeat".</li>
	<li>The pager attacks came hours after Israel announced it was broadening the aims of the Gaza war to include its fight against Hezbollah along its border with Lebanon.</li>
	<li>Hezbollah and the Israeli military have been exchanging fire since the October 7 attacks by Hamas on Israel that triggered the Gaza war.</li>
</ol>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/3egae548_lebanon-hospital_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[About 2,800 people were injured after pagers used by Hezbollah exploded across Lebanon]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-brazil-mayoral-candidate-attacks-opponent-with-chair-on-live-tv-6590259]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Video: Brazil Mayoral Candidate Attacks Opponent With Chair On Live TV]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-brazil-mayoral-candidate-attacks-opponent-with-chair-on-live-tv-6590259]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 07:37:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A mayoral debate in Brazil turned ugly when one of the candidates attacked a rival with a metal chair on live TV.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A mayoral debate in Brazil turned ugly when one of the candidates attacked a rival with a metal chair on live TV. According to <em>CNN</em>, the incident took place on Sunday, September 15. Pablo Marcal was delivering his speech when Jose Luiz Datena suddenly appeared from the shadows and attacked Mr Marcal with the chair. A video from the debate, broadcast live by <em>TV Cultura</em>, showed the tense exchange between the two before Mr Datena launched the heavy chair from close range at his counterpart's head.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The footage showed Mr Datena walking up to his victim and swinging the metal chair at his counterpart, although the latter managed to raise an arm at the last minute and deflect the blow slightly. Following the incident, Mr Marcal was hospitalised with suspected fractured ribs and breathing difficulties. The hospital said he had suffered trauma to his chest and wrist, but without any major complications, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/09/16/americas/sao-paulo-mayoral-debate-chair-attack-intl-latam/index.html" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>CNN </em></a>reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Take a look at the video below:&nbsp;</strong></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">?????? ??? ??? ???? ???????<br />
??During the debate for the São Paulo mayoral race in Brazil, socialist candidate José Luiz Datena threw a chair at libertarian candidate Pablo Marçal. I'd pay more attention to the debates in my country if they were like this. <a href="https://t.co/zvKKXardrD">pic.twitter.com/zvKKXardrD</a></p>
— Ara American Uncensored (@realaraamerican) <a href="https://twitter.com/realaraamerican/status/1836025771858522457?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 17, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Mr Datena later told TV Cultura that he had attacked Mr Marcal because he had brought up old sexual harassment allegations against Mr Datena that were dismissed several years ago. "He came with a case that was archived, that was not even investigated by the police because there was no evidence. Something from 11 years ago that caused a very serious situation within my family," Mr Datena said, per the outlet.&nbsp;</p>

<p>After the incident, Mr Datena was expelled from the debate. However, on Monday he insisted that while he had made a mistake he did not regret his actions.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/wear-proper-undergarments-delta-airlines-new-memo-for-flight-attendants-6587880">"Wear Proper Undergarments": Delta Airlines' New Memo For Flight Attendants</a></strong></p>

<p>Mr Marcal, on the other hand, compared the attack to the July assassination attempt against former US President Donald Trump and the stabbing of former Brazilian President Jair Bolsonaro during the 2018 election. His team has vowed to take legal action.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Pablo Marcal was cowardly attacked by Jose Luiz Datena, who hit him in the ribs with an iron chair," Mr Marcal's team said, adding that it was unfortunate the debate had continued without him.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the remaining candidates Guilherme Boulos, Marina Helena, Ricardo Nunes and Tabata Amaral continued the debate following the attack. <em>TV Cultura</em> said it regretted the incident and had pressed ahead with the discussion in accordance with the rules after the other candidates agreed.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/o6o0qve_brazil-mayor-debate_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The incident took place on Sunday, September 15.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-grams-of-explosives-per-pager-israel-complex-op-to-hurt-hezbollah-6590229]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[3 Grams Of Explosives Per Pager: Israel's Complex Op To Hurt Hezbollah]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-grams-of-explosives-per-pager-israel-complex-op-to-hurt-hezbollah-6590229]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 07:29:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel's Mossad spy agency planted a small amount of explosives inside 5,000 Taiwan-made pagers ordered by Lebanese group Hezbollah months before Tuesday's detonations, a senior Lebanese security source and another source told Reuters.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel's Mossad spy agency planted a small amount of explosives inside 5,000 Taiwan-made pagers ordered by Lebanese group Hezbollah months before Tuesday's detonations, a senior Lebanese security source and another source told Reuters.</p>

<p>The operation was an unprecedented Hezbollah security breach that saw thousands of pagers detonate across Lebanon, killing nine people and wounding nearly 3,000 others, including the group's fighters and Iran's envoy to Beirut.</p>

<p>Iran-backed Hezbollah has vowed to retaliate against Israel, whose military declined to comment on the blasts.</p>

<p>The plot appears to have been many months in the making, several sources told Reuters.</p>

<p>The senior Lebanese security source said the group had ordered 5,000 beepers made by Taiwan-based Gold Apollo, which several sources say were brought into the country earlier this year.</p>

<p>Gold Apollo founder Hsu Ching-Kuang said the pagers used in the explosion were made by a company in Europe that had the right to use the Taipei-based firm's brand, the name of which he could not immediately confirm.</p>

<p>"The product was not ours. It was only that it had our brand on it," he told reporters on Wednesday, without naming the company which did make the devices.</p>

<p>The senior Lebanese security source identified a photograph of the model of the pager, an AP924, which like other pagers wirelessly receive and display text messages but cannot make telephone calls.</p>

<p>Hezbollah fighters have been using pagers as a low-tech means of communication in an attempt to evade Israeli location-tracking, two sources familiar with the group's operations told Reuters this year.</p>

<p>But the senior Lebanese source said the devices had been modified by Israel's spy service "at the production level."</p>

<p>"The Mossad injected a board inside of the device that has explosive material that receives a code. It's very hard to detect it through any means. Even with any device or scanner," the source said.</p>

<p>The source said 3,000 of the pagers exploded when a coded message was sent to them, simultaneously activating the explosives.</p>

<p>Another security source told Reuters that up to three grams of explosives were hidden in the new pagers and had gone "undetected" by Hezbollah for months.</p>

<p>Neither Israel nor Gold Apollo immediately responded to Reuters requests for comment.</p>

<p>Images of destroyed pagers analyzed by Reuters showed a format and stickers on the back that were consistent with pagers made by Gold Apollo, based in Taipei.</p>

<p>Hezbollah was reeling from the attack, which left fighters and others bloodied, hospitalised or dead. One Hezbollah official, speaking on condition of anonymity, said the detonation was the group's "biggest security breach" since the Gaza conflict between Israel and Hezbollah ally Hamas erupted on Oct. 7.</p>

<p>"This would easily be the biggest counterintelligence failure that Hezbollah has had in decades," said Jonathan Panikoff, the U.S. government's former deputy national intelligence officer on the Middle East.</p>

<p><strong>Break Your Phones, Group Ordered</strong></p>

<p>In February, Hezbollah drew up a war plan that aimed to address gaps in the group's intelligence infrastructure. Around 170 fighters had already been killed in targeted Israeli strikes on Lebanon, including one senior commander and a top Hamas official in Beirut.</p>

<p>In a televised speech on Feb. 13, the group's Secretary General Hassan Nasrallah sternly warned supporters that their phones were more dangerous than Israeli spies, saying they should break, bury or lock them in an iron box.</p>

<p>Instead, the group opted to distribute pagers to Hezbollah members across the group's various branches - from fighters to medics working in its relief services.</p>

<p>The explosions maimed many Hezbollah members, according to footage from hospitals reviewed by Reuters. Wounded men had injuries of varying degrees to the face, missing fingers and gaping wounds at the hip where the pagers were likely worn.</p>

<p>"We really got hit hard," said the senior Lebanese security source, who has direct knowledge of the group's probe into the explosions.</p>

<p>The pager blasts came at a time of mounting concern about tensions between Israel and Hezbollah, which have been engaged in cross-border warfare since the Gaza conflict erupted last October.</p>

<p>While the war in Gaza has been Israel's main focus since the Oct. 7 attack by Hamas-led gunmen, the precarious situation along Israel's northern border with Lebanon has fueled fears of a regional conflict that could drag in the United States and Iran.</p>

<p>A missile barrage by Hezbollah the day after Oct. 7 opened the latest phase of conflict and since then there have been daily exchanges of rockets, artillery fire and missiles, with Israeli jets striking deep into Lebanese territory.</p>

<p>Hezbollah has said it does not seek a wider war but would fight if Israel launched one.</p>

<p>Israeli Defence Minister Yoav Gallant told US Defense Secretary Lloyd Austin on Monday that the window was closing for a diplomatic solution to the standoff with the Iranian-backed Hezbollah movement in southern Lebanon.</p>

<p>Still, experts said they did not see the pager blasts as a sign that an Israeli ground offensive was imminent.</p>

<p>Instead, it was a sign of Israeli intelligence's apparently deep penetration of Hezbollah.</p>

<p>"It demonstrates Israel's ability to infiltrate its adversaries in a remarkably dramatic way," said Paul Pillar, a 28-year veteran of the U.S. intelligence community, mainly at the CIA.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/rqune5nk_israel-hezbollah-attack_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russian-propaganda-group-behind-fake-kamala-harris-hit-and-run-story-microsoft-6590096]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russian Group Behind Fake Kamala Harris Hit-And-Run Story: Microsoft]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russian-propaganda-group-behind-fake-kamala-harris-hit-and-run-story-microsoft-6590096]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 06:48:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A false claim circulating on social media that Democratic presidential candidate Kamala Harris left a 13-year-old girl paralyzed after an alleged hit-and-run is the work of a Russian disinformation operation, according to research by Microsoft.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A false claim circulating on social media that Democratic presidential candidate Kamala Harris left a 13-year-old girl paralyzed after an alleged hit-and-run in San Francisco in 2011 is the work of a covert Russian disinformation operation, according to new research by Microsoft.</p>

<p>Researchers found that the operation created a video, paid an actor to appear as the alleged victim, and spread the claim through a fake website for a non-existent San Francisco news outlet named "KBSF-TV". The Russian group responsible, which Microsoft dubs Storm-1516, is described as a Kremlin-aligned troll farm.</p>

<p>The discovery is a sign of Russia ramping up its foreign influence efforts ahead of the Nov. 5 presidential election, Microsoft said.</p>

<p>A spokesperson for the Russian embassy in Washington did not respond to a request for comment.</p>

<p>"Russian influence operations initially struggled to pivot operations aimed at the Democratic campaign following President Biden's departure from the U.S. 2024 presidential race," a blog published on Tuesday by Microsoft said.</p>

<p>"In late August, however, elements of prolific Russian actor Storm-1516 began producing content implicating Vice President Harris and Governor Walz in outlandish fake conspiracy theories," Microsoft said, referring to Harris' running mate, Tim Walz.</p>

<p>Storm-1516 is known for producing misleading videos featuring on-screen or voice actors who impersonate whistleblowers or journalists that share false, scandalous information, experts say.</p>

<p>A website for KBSF-TV was created shortly before publishing its first related article about the alleged driving incident, according to online registration records. The claim was circulated on social media platforms, including X.com, using the hashtag #HitAndRunKamala.</p>

<p>The video was also shared on Sept. 3 on X.com by Aussie Cossack, who describes himself as a "Registered foreign agent for Sputnik News," with the message "make this go viral MAGA folks." In total, it is estimated the video has been viewed more than 2.7 million times.</p>

<p>"Many entities within the pro-Russian ecosystem advanced the video and its claims," said Microsoft's Threat Analysis Center. "Storm-1516 relies on some of these personalities, such as Aussie Cossack, to drive amplification of its videos."</p>

<p>Cossack did not immediately respond to a request for comment.</p>

<p>Earlier this month the U.S. Justice Department filed money-laundering charges against two employees of Russian state media network RT for what officials said was a scheme to hire an American company to produce online content to influence the election.</p>

<p>U.S. officials say Russia's goal is to exacerbate U.S. political divisions and weaken public support for American military aid to Ukraine. Harris says if elected she will continue supporting Ukraine in its defence against Russia's invasion.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-11/e2btjtrg_kamala-harris-reuters_625x300_18_November_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The fake video claims that Kamala Harris left a teen paralyzed in an alleged hit-and-run case in 2011]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/pm-modi-us-visit-donald-trump-says-he-will-meet-with-pm-modi-next-week-6590066]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump Says He Will Meet PM Modi Next Week]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/pm-modi-us-visit-donald-trump-says-he-will-meet-with-pm-modi-next-week-6590066]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 06:39:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former US President Donald Trump said on Tuesday that he will meet Prime Minister Narendra Modi next week during his visit to the US.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former US President Donald Trump said on Tuesday that he will meet Prime Minister Narendra Modi next week during his visit to the US. The Republican presidential candidate made the announcement while campaigning in Michigan. PM Modi is a "fantastic man", said Trump, at the same time calling India a "very big abuser" of trade ties.</p>

<p>Stressing that India imposes heavy tariffs on imports, Trump told the crowd: "So when India, which is a very big abuser. He (Modi) happens to be coming to meet me next week, and Modi, he's fantastic. I mean, fantastic man. A lot of these leaders are fantastic."</p>

<p>He did not elaborate on the meeting.</p>

<p>PM Modi will visit the United States from September 21 to 23. He will take part in the Quad Summit and address the 'Summit of the Future' at the United Nations General Assembly in New York.</p>

<p><strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-modi-us-visit-quad-un-summits-pm-modi-on-3-day-us-visit-from-september-21-6587190">Read: Quad, UN Summits: PM Modi On 3-Day US Visit From September 21</a></strong></p>

<p>The visit will start with the fourth Quad Leaders' Summit hosted by President Joe Biden in his hometown Wilmington in Delaware.</p>

<p>PM Modi will then travel to New York to address a gathering of the Indian community in Long Island on Sunday.</p>

<p>A day later, the Prime Minister will address the 'Summit of the Future' at the United Nations General Assembly. The theme of the Summit is 'Multilateral Solutions for a Better Tomorrow'.</p>

<p>The Prime Minister will also interact with the CEOs of leading US-based companies to foster greater collaborations between the two countries in the cutting-edge areas of AI, quantum computing, semiconductors and biotechnology, the foreign ministry said.</p>

<p>He is expected to interact with thought leaders and other stakeholders active in the India-US bilateral landscape.</p>

<p>PM Modi and Donald Trump last met in February 2020, when the then US President visited India. PM Modi described it as a "path-breaking" moment in strengthening the relations between the two nations.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-09/du4a6k3_donald-trump-pm-modi-afp-pic_650x400_08_September_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[PM Modi and Donald Trump last met in February 2020. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-delivery-agent-55-dies-while-resting-on-bike-after-working-18-hour-days-6590063]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[China Delivery Agent, 55, Dies On Bike After Working 18-Hour Days]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-delivery-agent-55-dies-while-resting-on-bike-after-working-18-hour-days-6590063]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 06:36:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 55-year-old food delivery man in China died during a nap on his bike after enduring gruelling 18-hour workdays.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 55-year-old food delivery man in China died during a nap on his bike after enduring gruelling 18-hour workdays. According to the <em>South China Morning Post</em>, the incident took place in Hangzhou, Zhejiang Province in eastern China earlier this month. A video going viral on Chinese social media platforms captured the food delivery worker, surnamed Yuan, who died in his sleep while resting on his electric bike after a taxing day of fulfilling multiple orders. This incident has sparked a discussion online about the welfare and legal rights of delivery drivers across the country.&nbsp;</p>

<p>A witness revealed that the food delivery worker had been at his post from 9pm on September 5 until he was discovered at 1am the following morning by another delivery driver. The <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3278707/china-delivery-rider-collapses-dies-bike-after-working-18-hour-days-leaves-family-hardship" rel="noindex, nofollow">outlet </a>reported that Mr Yuan had earned a reputation for his relentless work ethic, which earring him the nickname "Order King". He usually earned between 500 and 600 yuan ($70 and $85) a day, with earnings exceeding 700 yuan on rainy days.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"He would sometimes work until 3am, then rise at 6am to start again. When he felt fatigued, he would take a brief nap on his bike, ready to return to work as soon as an order came in," a person close to the delivery driver said, per <em>SCMP</em>.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Another colleague of Mr Yuan said that a month before his death, the 55-year-old had suffered a leg fracture in a traffic accident while delivering an order. He rested for about 10 days before returning to work, and then two weeks later he passed away.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The colleague said that Mr Yuan relocated to earn a living but also to support his 16-year-old son who is studying in Hangzhou. He also has an elder son who is married with children.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/all-good-here-haunting-last-message-before-oceangates-titan-submersible-imploded-6585522">"All Good Here": Haunting Last Message Before OceanGate's Titan Submersible Imploded</a></strong></p>

<p>In response to the incident, the Xianlin Sub-district Office in Yuhang district released an official statement confirming that Mr Yuan had "collapsed and died despite emergency treatment".</p>

<p>"The food delivery platform, the insurance company, and the family have reached an agreement. Follow-up arrangements are being carried out in an orderly manner," the announcement stated.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, on social media, the incident has sparked outrage. "Another 'Order King' has fallen. Is there really no way to avoid these tragedies?" one person said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"He was in his 50s, the sole breadwinner of his family, working day and night. May he rest in peace. I hope in his next life, he will not have to race against time like this," another commented.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/dl2opgdo_delivery-driver-generic_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[This incident has sparked a discussion online. (Representative pic)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-planted-explosives-in-hezbollahs-taiwan-made-pagers-report-6590000]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Planted Explosives In Hezbollah's Taiwan-Made Pagers: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-planted-explosives-in-hezbollahs-taiwan-made-pagers-report-6590000]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 06:10:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel's Mossad spy agency planted a small amount of explosives inside 5000 Taiwan-made pagers ordered by Lebanese group Hezbollah months before Tuesday's detonations, a senior Lebanese security source and another source told Reuters.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel's Mossad spy agency planted a small amount of explosives inside 5000 Taiwan-made pagers ordered by Lebanese group Hezbollah months before Tuesday's detonations, a senior Lebanese security source and another source told Reuters.</p>

<p>The details shed light on an unprecedented Hezbollah security breach that saw thousands of pagers detonate across Lebanon, killing nine people and wounding nearly 3,000 others, including the group's fighters and Iran's envoy to Beirut.</p>

<p>Iran-backed Hezbollah has vowed to retaliate against Israel, whose military declined to comment on the blasts.</p>

<p>The plot appears to have been many months in the making, several sources told Reuters.</p>

<p>The senior Lebanese security source said the group had ordered 5,000 beepers made by Taiwan-based Gold Apollo, which several sources say were brought into the country in the spring.</p>

<p>The senior Lebanese security source identified a photograph of the model of the pager, an AP924, which like other pagers wirelessly receive and display text messages but cannot make telephone calls.</p>

<p>Hezbollah fighters have been using pagers as a low-tech means of communication in an attempt to evade Israeli location-tracking, two sources familiar with the group's operations told Reuters this year.</p>

<p>But the senior Lebanese source said the devices had been modified by Israel's spy service "at the production level."</p>

<p>"The Mossad injected a board inside of the device that has explosive material that receives a code. It's very hard to detect it through any means. Even with any device or scanner," the source said.</p>

<p>The source said 3,000 of the pagers exploded when a coded message was sent to them, simultaneously activating the explosives.</p>

<p>Another security source told Reuters that up to three grams of explosives were hidden in the new pagers and had gone "undetected" by Hezbollah for months.</p>

<p>Neither Israel nor Gold Apollo immediately responded to Reuters requests for comment.</p>

<p>Images of destroyed pagers analyzed by Reuters showed a format and stickers on the back that were consistent with pagers made by Gold Apollo, based in Taipei.</p>

<p>Hezbollah was reeling from the attack, which left fighters and others bloodied, hospitalised or dead. One Hezbollah official, speaking on condition of anonymity, said the detonation was the group's "biggest security breach" since the Gaza conflict between Israel and Hezbollah ally Hamas erupted on Oct. 7.</p>

<p>"This would easily be the biggest counterintelligence failure that Hezbollah has had in decades," said Jonathan Panikoff, the U.S. government's former deputy national intelligence officer on the Middle East.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/vjs64oc_lebanon-pagers-attack_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Iran-backed Hezbollah has vowed to retaliate against Israel after pagers blasts in Lebanon.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/not-aware-not-involved-us-on-lebanon-pager-blasts-6589968]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Not Aware, Not Involved": US On Lebanon Pager Blasts]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/not-aware-not-involved-us-on-lebanon-pager-blasts-6589968]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 06:03:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United States said Tuesday it was not aware in advance and had no involvement in mass explosions of pagers used by Lebanon's Hezbollah, as it urged restraint by Iran in response.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United States said Tuesday it was not aware in advance and had no involvement in mass explosions of pagers used by Lebanon's Hezbollah, as it urged restraint by Iran in response.</p>

<p>"I can tell you that the US was not involved in it, the US was not aware of this incident in advance and, at this point, we're gathering information," State Department spokesman Matthew Miller told reporters.</p>

<p>Miller declined to comment on widespread suspicion that the blasts were carried out by Israel, which has been regularly trading fire with Hezbollah after the October 7 attack on Israel by another Iranian ally, Hamas.</p>

<p>The blasts came after weeks of private diplomacy by the United States to discourage a major Iranian retaliation against Israel for the killing of the Hamas political chief, Ismail Haniyeh, on a visit to Tehran.</p>

<p>Miller said the US message to Iran remained unchanged.</p>

<p>"We would urge Iran not to take advantage of any incident to try to add further instability and to further increase tensions in the region," Miller said.</p>

<p>A senior US envoy, Amos Hochstein, a day earlier met with Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu and other Israeli officials as he sought to discourage a full-scale war against Lebanon.</p>

<p>"We do want to see a diplomatic resolution to the conflict between Israel and Hezbollah," Miller said.</p>

<p>"We want to see one that allows the tens of thousands of Israelis who've been displaced from their homes and the tens of thousands of Lebanese who have been displaced from their homes to be able to return home," Miller said.</p>

<p>But Miller suggested that Hezbollah -- considered a terrorist group by the United States -- was fair game to strike, without confirming Israeli involvement.</p>

<p>"Terrorist members of a terrorist organization are legitimate targets for countries to launch operations against," Miller said.</p>

<p>The United States is a close ally of Israel and foe of Iran since the 1979 Islamic revolution overthrew the Western-oriented shah.</p>

<p>Iran's new president, Masoud Pezeshkian, who is considered a reformist within the cleric-run state, at a news conference on Monday said that he sought better relations with the United States, including restoration of a 2015 nuclear accord.</p>

<p>"We do not want to fight with America if it respects our rights," he said.</p>

<p>Asked about his remarks, Miller said the United States had "great fondness" for the Iranian people but that "when it comes to the regime, ultimately, we'll judge them by their actions, not their words."</p>

<p>"The way to show brotherhood would not be through rhetoric. It would be to stop arming and encouraging terrorist groups, to stop nuclear escalation, blocking the work of the International Atomic Energy Agency, it would be to stop plotting to kill political opponents, stop transferring missiles and drones to Russia, and ultimately stop cracking down on the human rights of its own people," Miller said.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/3bp2jl5c_lebanon-pagers-attack_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Thousands of people have been injured in Lebanon in pagers attacks across Lebanon.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-security-arrangements-needed-if-head-of-us-secret-service-to-trump-6589882]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[New Security Arrangements Needed If...: Head Of Secret Service To Trump]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-security-arrangements-needed-if-head-of-us-secret-service-to-trump-6589882]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 05:34:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The head of the Secret Service told Donald Trump in a private meeting that significant new security arrangements will be needed if he wants to keep playing golf, The New York Times reported on Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The head of the Secret Service told Donald Trump in a private meeting that significant new security arrangements will be needed if he wants to keep playing golf, The New York Times reported on Tuesday.</p>

<p>Trump asked Ronald Rowe, the Secret Service's acting director, in a meeting on Monday whether it was safe for him to continue playing, the newspaper said. Rowe said the Secret Service views the golf course at Joint Base Andrews in Maryland as easier to secure because it is a military course.</p>

<p>That meeting occurred a day after the Secret Service thwarted a second apparent assassination attempt on Trump in less than two months. On Sunday, Secret Service agents fired on Ryan Wesley Routh, the apparent would-be assassin, when they saw the barrel of his gun poking through the fenceline at Trump's golf course in West Palm Beach, Florida, and local police officers later arrested him.</p>

<p>The incident has raised questions within Trump's orbit and among lawmakers about whether Trump's protection is sufficient.</p>

<p>"Former President Trump is receiving the highest level of protection that the U.S. Secret Service can provide, and we will continue to evaluate and adjust our specific protective measures and methodology based on each location and situation," Secret Service spokesperson Melissa McKenzie said on Tuesday.</p>

<p>Still, at least one local official suggested otherwise. On Sunday, West Palm Beach Sheriff Ric Bradshaw told reporters that Trump's security detail was not as tight as that of a sitting president.</p>

<p>Since the incident, both Democrats and Republicans have accused each other of using overheated rhetoric that is inspiring political violence.</p>

<p>White House press secretary Karine Jean-Pierre said in a press briefing on Tuesday that Republican vice presidential candidate JD Vance's comments about Vice President Kamala Harris not having faced an assassination attempt are dangerous.</p>

<p>"The big difference between conservatives and liberals is that ... no one has tried to kill Kamala Harris in the last couple of months," Vance said on Monday.</p>

<p>Jean-Pierre said that language could put Harris in danger.</p>

<p>"When you make comments like that, all it does is ... opens an opportunity for people to listen to you and potentially take you very seriously, and so it's dangerous to have that type of rhetoric out there," she said.</p>

<p>Trump was due to speak at a campaign event in Michigan on Tuesday evening in his first public political event since the apparent assassination attempt over the weekend.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-02/37qfcsp8_donald-trump-650_625x300_23_February_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The meeting between Trump and head of the Secret Service held after apparent assassination attempt.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korea-fires-unidentified-ballistic-missile-report-6589705]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[North Korea Fires 'Unidentified Ballistic Missile': Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korea-fires-unidentified-ballistic-missile-report-6589705]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 04:44:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[North Korea fired an "unidentified ballistic missile" early Wednesday, the Yonhap news agency cited Seoul's military as saying, Pyongyang's second such launch in a week.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>North Korea fired an "unidentified ballistic missile" early Wednesday, the Yonhap news agency cited Seoul's military as saying, Pyongyang's second such launch in a week.</p>

<p>Seoul's Joint Chiefs of Staff (JCS) said "it detected the launch" but gave no further details, Yonhap said, adding that an analysis was under way. Tokyo also confirmed the launch, with the coastguard warning vessels to take care.</p>

<p></p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/bcqk7j4_north-korea-missile-launch-afp-_625x300_30_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[North Korea fired an "unidentified ballistic missile" early Wednesday.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/un-says-lebanon-pager-blasts-extremely-concerning-escalation-6589172]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UN Says Lebanon Pager Blasts 'Extremely Concerning Escalation']]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/un-says-lebanon-pager-blasts-extremely-concerning-escalation-6589172]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 01:47:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United Nations said pager explosions that killed nine people and wounded 2,800 across Lebanon Tuesday marked "an extremely concerning escalation" nearly one year into the Gaza war.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United Nations said pager explosions that killed nine people and wounded 2,800 across Lebanon Tuesday marked "an extremely concerning escalation" nearly one year into the Gaza war.</p>

<p>"The developments today mark an extremely concerning escalation in what is an already unacceptably volatile context," UN special coordinator for Lebanon Jeanine Hennis-Plasschaert said in a statement.</p>

<p>She urged "all concerned actors to refrain from any further action, or bellicose rhetoric, which could trigger a wider conflagration that nobody can afford".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/3fk03je_lebanon-pagers-blast_625x300_17_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[At least 2,800 people injured in pager explosionsacros in Lebanon on Tuesday]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-calls-for-end-to-war-in-gaza-no-israeli-reoccupation-6589166]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris Calls For End To War In Gaza, No Israeli Reoccupation]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-calls-for-end-to-war-in-gaza-no-israeli-reoccupation-6589166]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 01:41:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[U.S. Democratic presidential candidate Kamala Harris called on Tuesday for an end to the Israel-Gaza war and said that Israel must not reoccupy the Palestinian enclave once the nearly year-old conflict comes to an end.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>U.S. Democratic presidential candidate Kamala Harris called on Tuesday for an end to the Israel-Gaza war and said that Israel must not reoccupy the Palestinian enclave once the nearly year-old conflict comes to an end.</p>

<p>Speaking in Philadelphia to the National Association of Black Journalists, she called for a ceasefire between Israel and Palestinian Hamas militants, a two-state solution and Middle East stability in a way that does not empower Iran.</p>

<p>"We've made ourselves very clear this deal needs to get done in the best interest of everyone in the region," Harris, the U.S. vice president, said in response to questions asked by three journalists.</p>

<p>At least 41,252 people have been killed and 95,497 wounded in the Israeli offensive in the Hamas-ruled strip since Oct. 7, the Gaza health ministry said. The war began that day when Hamas attacked Israel, killing 1,200 people, mostly civilians, and taking about 250 hostages, according to Israeli tallies.</p>

<p>Harris was asked about Springfield, Ohio, a city that for days has found itself at the center of a social media maelstrom after right-wing agitators latched onto false claims that Haitian arrivals were eating household pets.</p>

<p>Former President Donald Trump, Harris' Republican rival in the Nov. 5 presidential election, has pledged to conduct mass deportations of Haitian immigrants from Springfield if elected, even though the majority are in the United States legally.</p>

<p>"This is exhausting and it's harmful and it's hateful and grounded in some age-old stuff that we should not have the tolerance for," Harris said.</p>

<p>The 45-minute interview began with economic issues. Harris said that if elected president she will work with private investors to boost housing supply, acknowledging that more work was needed to lower prices for Americans.</p>

<p>"One of the big issues that affects people right now in terms of the economy and their economic wellbeing is we have a shortage of housing supply," Harris said. "It's too expensive."</p>

<p>Harris reiterated a plan to expand the child tax credit to $6,000. She repeated a pledge that Americans not pay more than 7% of their income on childcare.</p>

<p>The interview was scheduled after Harris did not attend the group's convention in Chicago in July when Trump, in an interview, questioned her Black identity.</p>

<p><strong>HARRIS, TRUMP COURT BLACK VOTERS</strong></p>

<p>In the 2020 presidential election, Black voters supported then-candidate Joe Biden 92% to 8% over the then-incumbent Trump, according to the Pew Research Center. Most Black voters, 63%, plan to support Harris, compared with 13% for Trump, according to an NAACP survey released this month.</p>

<p>However, some Black voters are losing faith in the Democratic Party. Over one quarter of younger Black men say they would support Trump this election, the NAACP poll showed.</p>

<p>"Black men are like any other voting group," Harris said. "You gotta earn their vote."</p>

<p>The interview was conducted by NABJ members from TheGrio and Politico as well as an anchor for WHYY-FM, a public radio station.</p>

<p>Both Harris and Trump have made efforts to win over Black voters, whose support may be decisive in the closely fought Nov. 5 vote, especially in a handful of battleground states such as Pennsylvania and Georgia.</p>

<p>Some forecasters regard Pennsylvania as a must-win state.</p>

<p>In Georgia, an intense battle is being waged for the Black voters who make up a third of the state's population, the biggest proportion of Black voters in any of the seven battleground states.</p>

<p>Trump's attempt to pull in more support from Black voters is complicated by their traditional loyalty to the Democratic Party, his past racist remarks and a history of Republican-backed voting restrictions that activists say make it harder for Black residents to vote. Republicans deny trying to suppress the vote.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/53o1fa8s_kamala-harris-reuters_625x300_11_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kamala Harris called on Tuesday for an end to the Israel-Gaza war.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-calls-trump-after-apparent-assassination-attempt-6589017]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris Dials Trump After Apparent Assassination Attempt]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-calls-trump-after-apparent-assassination-attempt-6589017]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Sep 2024 00:56:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Democrat Kamala Harris had a "cordial and brief" phone conversation Tuesday with US election rival Donald Trump to express relief that he is safe after an apparent assassination attempt, the White House said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Democrat Kamala Harris had a "cordial and brief" phone conversation Tuesday with US election rival Donald Trump to express relief that he is safe after an apparent assassination attempt, the White House said.</p>

<p>"Vice President Harris called former President Trump this afternoon to speak with him directly to express that she is grateful he is safe," a White House official said in a statement.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/h0ho4s7g_kamala-harris-afp_625x300_22_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kamala Harris had a "cordial and brief" phone conversation Tuesday with Donald Trump.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>