<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Thu, 14 Nov 2024 13:49:02 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/lucy-at-50-paleontologist-recalls-discovery-of-fossil-that-became-an-icon-of-human-evolution-7016298]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[50 Years Ago, Discovery Of This Fossil Changed Understanding Of Evolution]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/lucy-at-50-paleontologist-recalls-discovery-of-fossil-that-became-an-icon-of-human-evolution-7016298]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 14 Nov 2024 13:48:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A fossilised skeleton, Australopithecus afarensis, best known by her nickname 'Lucy', was unearthed by researchers 50 years ago this month in the Afar region of Ethiopia.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A fossilised skeleton, Australopithecus afarensis, best known by her nickname 'Lucy', was unearthed by researchers 50 years ago this month in the Afar region of Ethiopia. It eventually went on to transform scientists' understanding of human evolution.<br />
<br />
Opening a new chapter in human history, the discovery by Don Johanson, an American palaeontologist and graduate student Tom Gray on November 24, 1974, provided proof that the ancient hominins could walk upright on two feet 3.2 million years ago — a trait thought to have evolved more recently, <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/11/12/science/lucy-fossil-discovery-50th-anniversary-don-johanson/index.html">CNN </a>reported.<br />
<br />
Lucy had a mixture of ape and humanlike traits, suggesting she occupied a pivotal branch in the family tree of humans. Over the past few decades, she has encouraged multiple researches and debates, besides igniting a broader public fascination with human origins.<br />
<br />
Although researchers have now unearthed fossil hominins twice as old as Lucy, she continues to remain a key subject for scientific studies.<br />
<br />
At the time when it was found, Lucy had 47 bones and was the oldest known and the most complete skeleton of early human ancestors.<br />
<br />
Reminiscing his 1974 Ethiopia visit, Don Johanson told CNN he was walking on sediment 3.2 million years in age to search for the fossilised remains of various kinds of animals, "but particularly the remains of our ancestors."&nbsp;<br />
<br />
"I happened to look over my right shoulder. If I had looked over my left shoulder, I would have missed it," he said.<br />
<br />
At first, he witnessed a little fragment of bone, a little part of the elbow as well as a part of a forearm.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
He could tell "immediately that it was from a human ancestor," Johanson said, adding when he and his student, Tom Gray, kneeled to have a closer look, they saw "fragments of the skull and fragments of a pelvis and fragments of an arm bone and the leg bone."&nbsp;<br />
<br />
"I realized at that moment that here was the childhood dream... I'd always wanted to go to Africa to find something and by golly this was something. But we didn't know how much it would become an icon in the study of human origins," Johanson said.<br />
<br />
At the time of discovery, Lucy's bones were "very fragile" because they had mineralised and changed into stone. So, the team did a "very careful crawl to pick up the obvious pieces," before they put them into the burlap bags.<br />
<br />
Later, they water-washed them in the stream via fine screening. The whole process took two and a half weeks.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
Johanson recalled it was wonderful to see Lucy come together on the lab table in the field. "The femur there was only about a foot long, or 28 centimetres long. What is this? I thought. Is this a child? Well, let's look at the jaw. The wisdom teeth had erupted so she was an adult. But my god, if this was an adult, it had to have been only about 3 and a half feet tall, a meter tall," he added.<br />
<br />
Asked how it got the name Lucy, Johanson said it had a delicate nature of the bones and the short stature, so they felt "she was probably a female."<br />
<br />
He went on to say that while Lucy's species did not give rise directly to modern humans, "her pivotal place on the human family tree led to all later hominin species, most of which went extinct."&nbsp;<br />
<br />
"The Homo lineage persisted and ultimately gave rise to us, Homo sapiens," he concluded.<br />
<br />
<br />
&nbsp;</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-06/bi3v4o6c_human-evolution-generic-pixabay_625x300_09_June_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[At the time when it was found, Lucy had 47 bones.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-koreas-morphing-wheel-could-make-wheelchairs-climb-stairs-7016963]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[South Korea's 'Morphing Wheel' Could Make Wheelchairs Climb Stairs]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-koreas-morphing-wheel-could-make-wheelchairs-climb-stairs-7016963]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 14 Nov 2024 13:45:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The morphing wheel consists of an outer hoop of a chain and a series of spoke wires running through the hub.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Imagine a wheelchair equipped with wheels flexible enough to navigate all manner of obstacles from kerbs to humps and even staircases.</p>

<p>Or perhaps an unmanned delivery vehicle using the same wheels that take the stairs to deliver food and groceries right to your doorstop.</p>

<p>This is what researchers from the Korea Institute of Machinery and Materials (KIMM) envision for their 'morphing' wheel, which can roll over obstacles up to 1.3 times the height of its radius.</p>

<p>Inspired by the surface tension of water droplets, it goes from solid to fluid when it encounters impediments.</p>

<p>Other possible applications include robots that spy on the enemy in the battlefield.</p>

<p>The KIMM team also hopes that morphing wheels will eventually be used with two and four-legged robots, which are currently limited in movement efficiency and susceptible to vibration, that can carry payloads that need stable movement in industrial settings.</p>

<p>"The goal is to make this viable for speed up to 100 kph, or the speed of an average car," said Song Sung-hyuk, principal researcher at South Korea's KIMM.</p>

<p>Wheels developed for a similar purpose such as non-pneumatic or airless tires have flexibility but are limited in their ability to overcome obstacles, said Song, who is a member of KIMM's AI robotics research team.</p>

<p>The morphing wheel consists of an outer hoop of a chain and a series of spoke wires running through the hub. The stiffness of the spokes - and hence the wheel - is automatically regulated by a sensor as it reacts to the terrain.</p>

<p>Song's team demonstrated to Reuters a prototype wheelchair mounted on morphing wheels as it climbed stairs with 18 cm steps with a life-size dummy sitting in it. The team has also tested a device mounted with the wheel at speeds of up to 30 kph.</p>

<p>The morphing wheel was the cover article of the journal Science Robotics in August.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/1a0haae8_south-korea_625x300_14_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The morphing wheel was the cover article of the journal Science Robotics in August.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chinese-womans-illegal-surrogacy-case-sparks-debate-online-7016854]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Chinese Woman's Illegal Surrogacy Case Sparks Debate Online]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chinese-womans-illegal-surrogacy-case-sparks-debate-online-7016854]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 14 Nov 2024 13:31:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 22-year-old Chinese woman's account of how she was lured into the country's illegal surrogacy industry before suffering a miscarriage went viral on Chinese social media this week.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 22-year-old Chinese woman's account of how she was lured into the country's illegal surrogacy industry before suffering a miscarriage went viral on Chinese social media this week and raised heated debates over women's rights and social inequality.</p>

<p>Surrogacy is banned in China, and authorities have vowed to severely crack down on illegal practices, including the buying and selling of sperm, egg, and surrogacy services.</p>

<p>The incident comes as Chinese authorities grapple with how to increase the country's birth rate as more young couples put off having children or opt to have none.</p>

<p>China's population fell for a second consecutive year in 2023 and Beijing in October rallied local governments to direct resources towards fixing China's population crisis to create a "birth-friendly" society.</p>

<p>Zhang Jing, 22, told state-backed Phoenix TV magazine that she donated her eggs out of financial desperation and then agreed to "rent out her uterus" to be impregnated for a total of 30,000 yuan ($4,152).</p>

<p>If she "successfully" delivered the baby, she would be paid a total of 240,000 yuan. At five months pregnant, she experienced severe complications and had to have an abortion.</p>

<p>Zhang's story amassed more than 86 million views and 10,000 comments on the Chinese social media platform Weibo, with the hashtag "#2000s-born Surrogate Miscarriage Girl Speaks Out#."</p>

<p>The majority of comments strongly opposed surrogacy. Some warned that legalising surrogacy in China could lead to increased competition that would lower compensation and further devalue women.</p>

<p>"No woman could escape this if surrogacy were legalised," one user wrote, while another said, "Legalising surrogacy would drive down prices and commodify women."</p>

<p>Zhang's story ignited calls for a more thorough crackdown on illegal surrogacy by authorities, with some commenters warning that allowing the black market to continue to operate could even normalise human organ trafficking.</p>

<p>"Life should not be traded as a commodity," one user wrote. "If this extends to the sale of organs, it will only get darker and darker, and women will have no future."</p>

<p>The incident comes a few weeks after a 28-year-old pregnant woman who acted as a surrogate in China's southwestern city of Chengdu was allegedly abandoned by her surrogacy agency.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/apnjl7n8_surrogacy_625x300_14_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Surrogacy is banned in China. (Representational image)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/dominica-to-award-its-highest-national-honour-to-pm-modi-7016821]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Dominica To Award Its Highest National Honour To PM Modi]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/dominica-to-award-its-highest-national-honour-to-pm-modi-7016821]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 14 Nov 2024 13:28:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Commonwealth of Dominica will honour Prime Minister Narendra Modi with its highest national award, the Dominica Award of Honour, in recognition of his contributions to Dominica during the COVID-19 pandemic.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Commonwealth of Dominica will honour Prime Minister Narendra Modi with its highest national award, the Dominica Award of Honour, in recognition of his contributions to Dominica during the COVID-19 pandemic. The award will also recognise PM Modi's dedication to strengthening the partnership between India and Dominica. Sylvanie Burton, President of the Commonwealth of Dominica will present the award during the India-CARICOM Summit in Georgetown, Guyana next week.</p>

<p>During the first year of the COVID-19 pandemic, in February 2021, PM Modi supplied Dominica with 70,000 doses of the AstraZeneca COVID-19 vaccine—"a generous gift which enabled Dominica to extend support to its Caribbean neighbours”, notes the press release issued by the Prime Minister's office.</p>

<p>Dominica appreciates India's support not just in the healthcare sector but also in education, and information technology. It also recognises India's role in promoting climate resilience-building initiatives and sustainable development on a global level.</p>

<p>“Prime Minister Modi has been a true partner to Dominica, particularly during our time of need amid a global health crisis. It is an honour to present him with Dominica's highest national accolade as a symbol of our gratitude for his support and as a reflection of the strong ties between our countries,” said PM Skerrit.</p>

<p>PM Skerrit showed interest in building on this partnership and working on the common goal of progress and resilience.</p>

<p>As per the official release, PM Modi accepted the offer of the award and emphasised the importance of collaboration in tackling global challenges such as climate change and geopolitical conflicts. PM Modi affirmed India's commitment to working alongside Dominica and the Caribbean in addressing these issues.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/gactj2g_pm-modi-twitter_625x300_11_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sylvanie Burton, President of the Commonwealth of Dominica will present the award to PM Modi.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/quite-disturbing-human-head-washes-ashore-on-popular-tourist-beach-in-florida-7016820]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Quite Disturbing": Human Head Found On Popular Tourist Beach In Florida]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/quite-disturbing-human-head-washes-ashore-on-popular-tourist-beach-in-florida-7016820]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 14 Nov 2024 13:28:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Locals said the disturbing find has left them traumatised, with some saying that they are now too scared to go to the beach.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A disturbing discovery was made on Key Biscayne Beach, Florida, on November 12 when a human head washed ashore. According to <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://fox8.com/news/human-head-washes-up-on-beach-in-key-biscayne-florida/">Fox News</a></em>, a beach maintenance worker found the remains near the Key Colony II Ocean Sound condos while raking the sand.&nbsp;Investigators were quickly called to the scene, and aerial helicopter footage showed them covering the remains with a blue tarp as they conducted their examination. The shocking find has sparked mystery surrounding the identity and age of the individual and the circumstances leading to the tragic event.</p>

<p>Preliminary findings suggest that the head belongs to a man, as confirmed by Miami-Dade Police Detective Andre Martin. Mr Martin noted that it's currently uncertain whether the individual was a victim of a crime or if other factors, such as a marine animal encounter or boating accident, resulted in the decapitation.</p>

<p>"We have not been able to determine exactly how the head became separated from the body, but there are a couple [of] working theories," he said.</p>

<p>Locals said the disturbing find has left them traumatised, with some saying that they are now too scared to go to the beach. Resident Bahman Amini said, "We have seen all things here but nothing like this what was found this morning, the head of a person. It makes us scared to go to the beach that we love."</p>

<p>Alex Portuondo told<em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.cbsnews.com/miami/news/miami-dade-police-investigate-report-of-head-human-on-key-biscayne-beach/">&nbsp;CBS</a></em>, "That's pretty scary and crazy. I&nbsp;have never heard of anything like this happening before on this kind of beach. I guess I am curious if they have any information on where it came from if anything else has been found if it happened here on the island or washed up on the shore."</p>

<p>''This is shocking, shocking. You don't hear a lot about that. You heard about drugs washing up on shore and things like that, but a head,''&nbsp;another resident said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The local medical examiner's office now has custody of the remains and is working to identify the person. The beach is a popular destination for tourists and locals alike.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/t4mqs0h8_human-head-on-florida-beach_625x300_14_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A section of the beach was cordoned off with yellow police tape for an investigation.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/transgender-at-35-man-explores-his-masculine-identity-7016126]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Meet The 35-Year-Old YouTuber Who Is Exploring What It Means To Be A Man]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/transgender-at-35-man-explores-his-masculine-identity-7016126]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 14 Nov 2024 13:20:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A YouTuber recently embarked on a new chapter of his life as a transgender man. Ash Perez, a member of the online content creators community Try Guys, documented his journey of exploration of masculinity in a video series called New Guy Tries.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A YouTuber recently embarked on a new chapter of his life as a transgender man. Ash Perez, a member of the online content creators community Try Guys, documented his journey of exploration of masculinity in a video series called New Guy Tries. While some aspects of Perez's experience as a transgender man were specific to his quest to define masculinity for himself, there were moments when even his friends - some gay, some straight and cis-gendered - also shared their concepts of masculinity. They were able to sort out some of their thoughts, thanks to the series.</p>

<p>Ryan Garcia, a cisgender male cast member of the series, shared, “There was never really time to stop and reflect on where I belong in masculinity. It was just doing the things to fit in and be accepted. Being in this series with Ash was kind of a form of therapy where you stopped and actually reflected.”</p>

<p>Ash Perez's coming-out journey taught him and some of the other Try Guys a lot about masculinity and how to accept its positive aspects while pushing it beyond its conventional bounds.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Before starting his gender transition, Perez lost his father to the Covid-19 pandemic, so he had to learn how to be a man without parental supervision. He said, “It's almost impossible to figure out what manhood means in the absence of a father figure who has some knowledge or direct take on manhood.”</p>

<p>During the video series, Perez spent time talking and participating in masculine rites of passage with his male friends and coworkers on manhood and masculinity. He observed his friends found it difficult to fit into the narrow criteria society gave them. According to Perez, many of his friends and coworkers felt inadequate because the social ideal of a guy was centred around sports, meat, muscles, and earning money.</p>

<p>Perez stated one can start by looking inward if one wants to figure out how to be comfortable with one's own masculinity.&nbsp;</p>

<p>“You can have conversations with yourself. You can journal. You can begin to examine things yourself, and then start to slowly branch out in a way that feels safe for you,” he said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/9mtsdseo_ash-perez-instagram-_625x300_14_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Before starting his gender transition, Perez lost his father to the Covid-19 pandemic.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/us-home-prices-surge-leaving-buyers-struggling-how-much-money-do-you-need-to-afford-a-house-in-us-7016644]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How Much Money Do You Need To Afford A House In US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/us-home-prices-surge-leaving-buyers-struggling-how-much-money-do-you-need-to-afford-a-house-in-us-7016644]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 14 Nov 2024 13:10:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Want to buy a home in the United States? Well, think about it only if you earn at least $1,08,000 (around Rs 91.15 lakh) or more, a report said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Want to buy a home in the United States? Well, think about it only if you earn at least $1,08,000 (around Rs 91.15 lakh) or more, a report said. This change, highlighted in a recent report from Oxford Economics, underscores the rapid shift in the housing market. In the third quarter of 2024, only 36% of US households had enough income to afford a new home, compared to 59% in the same period five years ago. This sharp decline reflects the challenges many Americans now face buying a property.</p>

<p>The new numbers are in stark contrast to just a few years ago. In 2019, a household needed only $56,800 (around Rs 48 lakh) to comfortably cover the cost of a new single-family home, including property taxes and insurance.</p>

<p>The massive surge in housing prices over the last five years is largely due to the disruption caused by the pandemic. During COVID-19, many Americans sought larger homes, leading to a surge in demand. Simultaneously, the country experienced a shortage of available homes, which, combined with rising demand, pushed home prices to new heights.</p>

<p>The affordability crisis is most apparent in certain cities. San Jose, California, for example, has become the least affordable metro area in the US, with a median house price of $1.89 million (around Rs 16 crore). To afford a home there, a household would need to earn $4,61,000 (Rs 3.89 crore) annually. Other major California cities such as San Francisco, Los Angeles and San Diego also rank among the least affordable regions.</p>

<p>Cleveland, Louisville, Detroit and St. Louis were among the more affordable cities, where households needed an income ranging from $64,600 to $75,300 (Rs 54 lakh to Rs 64 lakh) to manage housing costs.</p>

<p>Oxford Economics defines a home as affordable if the monthly payment does not exceed 28% of a person's income. “While house prices increased in every metro, the rise in mortgage rates eroded affordability more significantly as rates nearly doubled from 3.7% in Q3 2019 to a high of 7.3% in Q4 2023,” Barbara Denham, a senior economist at Oxford Economics, told <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/11/13/economy/home-buyer-salary-household-income/index.html">CNN</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-08/c4qfcckk_new-york-generic_625x300_13_August_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The new numbers are in stark contrast to just a few years ago.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-marco-rubio-donald-trump-s-nominee-for-us-secretary-of-state-7016545]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[5 Facts About Marco Rubio, Donald Trumps Pick For US Secretary Of State]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-marco-rubio-donald-trump-s-nominee-for-us-secretary-of-state-7016545]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 14 Nov 2024 13:08:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President-elect Donald Trump has nominated Florida Senator Marco Rubio, a prominent critic of China, for the position of US Secretary of State.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President-elect Donald Trump has nominated Florida Senator <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-nominates-florida-senator-marco-rubio-as-secretary-of-state-7014420">Marco Rubio</a>, a prominent critic of China, for the position of US Secretary of State. In his statement, Trump praised Rubio as “a very powerful voice for freedom” and a “fearless warrior who will never back down to our adversaries.”</p>

<p><strong>Here are 5 facts about Marco Rubio and his career:&nbsp;</strong><br />
<br />
1) Early life and immigrant roots<br />
<br />
Born in 1971 in Miami, Florida, Marco Rubio is the son of Cuban immigrants who came to America in pursuit of their American Dream. His father worked as a banquet bartender, while his mother balanced being a stay-at-home mom with working as a hotel maid. From a young age, Rubio learned the values of faith, family, community, and hard work.<br />
<br />
2) A career in public service before becoming a US senator in 2010<br />
<br />
Rubio served in various roles, including as a city commissioner in West Miami and as Speaker of the Florida House of Representatives. In 2010, he won a seat in the US Senate. The Center for Effective Law Making ranked Rubio as the most effective Republican, while the Lugar Center named him one of the most bipartisan senators. His work includes expanding the child tax credit, reforming the VA system, supporting small businesses during the pandemic, reshaping US policy towards China and strengthening national security.<br />
<br />
3) 2016 Presidential bid<br />
<br />
In April 2015, Marco Rubio entered the US presidential race. Early on, he was the choice of the Republican establishment. But by February 2016, his campaign was struggling, winning just one state and trailing behind Donald Trump and Ted Cruz in the delegate count. Rubio's campaign was heavily impacted by Trump's mockery, with Trump dubbing him “Little Marco” and Rubio responding by calling Trump “the most vulgar person to ever aspire to the presidency.” After losing the Florida primary in March 2016, Rubio suspended his campaign. Though initially considering leaving politics, Rubio returned to the Senate race, winning re-election in 2016. Following Trump's victory, Rubio shifted toward a conservative populist stance, becoming a key ally of the new president.<br />
<br />
4) Legislative achievements<br />
<br />
Throughout his Senate tenure, Rubio has championed a wide range of policies aimed at improving the lives of everyday Americans. He played a key role in expanding the child tax credit for working families and reforming the US Department of Veterans Affairs, particularly securing healthcare for veterans exposed to toxic burn pits. During the pandemic lockdown, Rubio helped pass the Paycheck Protection Program, keeping millions of small businesses afloat. He also wrote and passed the Uyghur Forced Labor Prevention Act, which marked a significant shift in US-China relations.<br />
<br />
5) Family life<br />
<br />
Rubio often underlines that being a father is his most important role. He lost his own father just two months before his election to the US Senate, but his lessons of hard work, responsibility, and family continue to guide him. He met his wife, Jeanette, a fellow Miami native, through mutual friends, and they married in 1998. They have four children — Amanda, Daniella, Anthony and Dominick.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/4dcjqha_marco-rubio_625x300_14_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Marco Rubio often underlines that being a father is his most important role.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/italian-city-florence-is-cracking-down-on-overtourism-with-restrictions-7016137]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[This Italian City Is Cracking Down On Overtourism With Restrictions]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/italian-city-florence-is-cracking-down-on-overtourism-with-restrictions-7016137]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 14 Nov 2024 13:03:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Italian city of Florence in Tuscany is introducing new rules to address the growing problem of overtourism.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Italian city of Florence in Tuscany is introducing new rules to address the growing problem of overtourism. The measures include a ban on key boxes used by short-term rental owners and restrictions on loudspeakers used by tour guides. The key boxes, particularly in the UNESCO-listed centre, have become a source of frustration for residents, with some locals going as far as taping them up in protest.</p>

<p>As the city prepares to host G7 tourism ministers, Florence's mayor, Sarah Funaro, introduced a 10-point plan to address these concerns. The new decree also targets the increasing use of “atypical vehicles,” such as golf carts, used by tour guides to navigate areas where car traffic is restricted.</p>

<p>In a statement, Florence's council said the measures were a response to the unsustainable influx of tourists. More than 7.8 million people have visited Florence so far in 2024. “The city is no longer able to support, without weakening its heritage value and seeing its overall livability compromised, such a massive presence of activities and means for exclusive tourist use concentrated in just five square kilometres (about 2 square miles),” the city council said in the statement, reported <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/11/13/travel/italy-florence-bans-key-boxes-tour-guide-loudspeakers-overtourism/index.html">CNN</a>.</p>

<p>The decision follows a series of incidents that have further strained relations between locals and tourists. In one incident, a female tourist was filmed mimicking a sexual act on a statue of Bacchus. In January, the head of the Galleria dell'Accademia, Cecilie Hollberg, controversially described Florence as a “prostitute” for having succumbed to overtourism, adding that once a city becomes “a prostitute,” it is difficult to restore its original character.</p>

<p>Florence, famed for its Renaissance art and architecture, has long been a top tourist destination. In recent years, the city has seen a dramatic rise in visitor numbers, leading to concerns from residents who feel their lives were disrupted and property prices inflated. This surge in tourism has sparked a backlash, with locals demanding action to preserve the city's unique character.</p>

<p>Florence is not the only Italian destination facing the pressures of mass tourism. The archaeological site of Pompeii announced it would limit daily visitor numbers to 20,000 and introduce personalised tickets. Similarly, Venice will reintroduce an entrance fee for tourists in 2025, while Rome will implement restrictions on visitor access to the Trevi Fountain after its renovation.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/j43ofl8g_florence-pixabay_625x300_14_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Florence is not the only Italian destination facing the pressures of mass tourism.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/openai-says-us-allies-should-partner-on-ai-to-take-on-china-7016584]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[OpenAI Says US Allies Should Partner On AI To Take On China]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/openai-says-us-allies-should-partner-on-ai-to-take-on-china-7016584]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 14 Nov 2024 12:58:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The proposal was included in a new policy blueprint from OpenAI unveiled at an event in Washington.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>OpenAI is calling for the US and its allies to work together to support the infrastructure needed to develop artificial intelligence systems and compete with China.</p>

<p>The AI startup said Wednesday that the US and neighbouring countries should form a "North American Compact for AI" that can streamline access to talent, financing and supply chains for building out the technology. The company said this collaboration could later expand to include a "global network of US allies and partners," including countries in the Middle East.</p>

<p>The proposal was included in a new policy blueprint from OpenAI unveiled at an event in Washington hosted by the Center for Strategic and International Studies. The document offers OpenAI's most detailed public suggestions yet for how the US can maintain its lead in artificial intelligence and meet the technology's significant energy demands.</p>

<p>OpenAI said the US should backstop costly energy infrastructure projects by committing to purchase power from them. The company recommended the US establish "AI Economic Zones" that speed up the permitting process and help bring nuclear reactors back online. It also proposed expanding nuclear energy capacity by tapping the US Navy, which has built compact reactors to power submarines.</p>

<p>"AI presents an unmissable opportunity to reindustrialize the US, and through that, generate the kind of broad-based economic growth that will revitalize the American Dream," OpenAI said. "It also presents a national security imperative to protect our nation and our allies against a surging China by offering an AI shaped by democratic values, promoting individual choice and benefiting the most people possible."</p>

<p>OpenAI's leadership previously sought to raise billions in funding from investors in the Middle East and other markets to expand the supply of chips, energy and data centres needed to develop AI. Chief Executive Officer Sam Altman has also met with US officials to get them on board with the plan.</p>

<p>The latest proposal comes as the US government prepares for a change in administration. President-elect Donald Trump has acknowledged the need to expand US energy capacity to stay competitive in AI and suggested loosening permitting requirements as well as using fossil fuels and nuclear energy.</p>

<p>At the policy event on Wednesday, Chris Lehane, OpenAI's vice president of global affairs, said the startup has spent "a lot of time" with both the Biden administration and Trump's team discussing AI infrastructure needs.</p>

<p>"I'm an optimist," Lehane said. "I think that this is going to be one of the subject areas in the next Congress and with the next administration that folks are going to want to work on because the stakes are just so big."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ngd53j08_sam-altman_625x300_14_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/openai-nears-launch-of-ai-agent-tool-to-automate-tasks-for-users-7016548]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[OpenAI Nears Launch Of AI Agent Tool To Automate Tasks For Users]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/openai-nears-launch-of-ai-agent-tool-to-automate-tasks-for-users-7016548]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 14 Nov 2024 12:51:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In a staff meeting on Wednesday, OpenAI's leadership announced plans to release the tool in January as a research preview]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>OpenAI is preparing to launch a new artificial intelligence agent codenamed "Operator" that can use a computer to take actions on a person's behalf, such as writing code or booking travel, according to two people familiar with the matter.</p>

<p>In a staff meeting on Wednesday, OpenAI's leadership announced plans to release the tool in January as a research preview and through the company's application programming interface for developers, said one of the people, who spoke on the condition of anonymity to discuss internal matters.</p>

<p>OpenAI did not immediately respond to a request for comment.</p>

<p>The planned release is part of a broader industry push toward agents, or AI software that can complete multi-step tasks for users with minimal supervision. Anthropic unveiled a similar agent that can process what's happening on the user's computer in real time and take actions on their behalf. OpenAI-backer Microsoft Corp. also recently launched a set of agent tools designed to send emails and manage records for workers. And Alphabet Inc.'s Google is said to be preparing to release an AI agent, according to The Information.</p>

<p>OpenAI has been working on several agent-related research projects, according to three people. The one nearest completion will be a general-purpose tool that executes tasks in a web browser, one of the people said.</p>

<p>OpenAI Chief Executive Officer Sam Altman hinted at the shift to agents in response to a question last month during an Ask Me Anything session on Reddit. "We will have better and better models," Altman wrote. "But I think the thing that will feel like the next giant breakthrough will be agents."</p>

<p>The move to release an agentic AI tool also comes as OpenAI and its competitors have seen diminishing returns from their costly efforts to develop more advanced AI models.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/1mq2a6g_openai_625x300_14_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[AI industry is pushing toward agents that can complete multi-step tasks with minimal supervision.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-book-details-a-brooklyn-neighborhoods-role-in-rise-of-new-york-mafia-7015718]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How A Brooklyn Neighbourhood Gave Rise To The Dreaded New York Mafia]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-book-details-a-brooklyn-neighborhoods-role-in-rise-of-new-york-mafia-7015718]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 14 Nov 2024 12:28:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Red Hook, a neighbourhood in southwestern Brooklyn famous for its diverse community and unique geography today, was once among the most stigmatised places for its crime and extreme violence, according to a new book.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Red Hook, a neighbourhood in southwestern Brooklyn famous for its diverse community and unique geography today, was once among the most stigmatised places for its crime and extreme violence, according to a new book. The hardscrabble dock area played a pivotal part in Brooklyn's history, emerging as a place from where goods and contraband entered the city, the <a href="https://nypost.com/2024/11/13/us-news/how-brooklyns-red-hook-was-key-to-the-rise-of-the-mafia/">New York Post </a>reported.<br />
<br />
“When I was a kid, I not only dreamed of growing up to be a gangster; it was the only ambition I had, the only life path I could envision,” Frank Dimatteo, who grew up as a youngster in the region, wrote in ‘Red Hook – Brooklyn Mafia, Ground Zero' (Citadel), which he has co-authored with Michael Benson.<br />
<br />
Shockingly, Dimatteo mentioned that he witnessed his first mob murder when he was just five and was quick enough to learn in life that killing people “is just business”.&nbsp;During the early 20th century, the docks in Red Hook were under the control of an Irish gang -- the White Hand.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
“At first they robbed everyone blind, but there was little violence,” Dimatteo wrote in the book.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
But "things got rough" with time. "Young, savage White Hand goons, chips on their shoulders, fists clenched and ready to bust," they wrote.<br />
<br />
Later, the Irish gang was outnumbered by the Italians, while greater violence was witnessed in the region due to intense competition, especially at the time of 'Prohibition' when both groups worked their way to move illicit liquor.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
“In later years, there was cooperation between Italian and Irish mobs, but at the turn of the twentieth century, they couldn't be in the same room,” read the book.<br />
<br />
A problem for the Irish was that they couldn't match their rivals. The writers said the Italian takeover of the piers was "inevitable”.<br />
<br />
The number rulers in Red Hook came to be known as 'la Mano Nera' – or the Black Hands.<br />
<br />
Soon, local youngsters got involved in the underworld. A major reason behind this was that any alternative jobs, like labouring, meant working for long hours for little compensation. “Better to rob cargo trucks...It was more lucrative and a hell of a lot easier on the back," Dimatteo stated.<br />
<br />
Among the five boroughs of New York City, Red Hook had the worst percentage of juvenile delinquency.<br />
<br />
Today, Red Hook is left with abandoned warehouses as well as underdeveloped tracts of land. While 'gentrification' is believed to have taken hold of the region, its process has been slow, the authors said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/j357297_mafia-generic-_625x300_14_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Among the five boroughs of New York City, Red Hook had the worst percentage of juvenile delinquency.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-earns-key-position-in-donald-trumps-world-first-buddy-7016337]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["First Buddy": Elon Musk Earns Key Position In Donald Trump's World]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-earns-key-position-in-donald-trumps-world-first-buddy-7016337]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 14 Nov 2024 12:27:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[As Donald Trump prepares his return to the White House, one of his most omnipresent confidants has been not his running mate or wife but a fellow brash billionaire, Elon Musk.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As Donald Trump prepares his return to the White House, one of his most omnipresent confidants has been not his running mate or wife but a fellow brash billionaire, Elon Musk.</p>

<p>Since campaigning for Trump -- with such enthusiasm that Musk literally jumped in the air at a rally -- Musk has been a near-constant presence at Trump's side.</p>

<p>The Tesla and SpaceX CEO has joined telephone calls with world leaders and dispensed advice on personnel choices both directly and publicly through X, the social media platform he bought.</p>

<p>In between his constant postings of memes of himself and Trump, Musk has even embraced a title suggested for his role: "First Buddy."</p>

<p>When the president-elect triumphantly returned to Washington on Wednesday, tagging along aboard his plane was Musk, the world's richest person, who appears to have spent most of the week since the election hobnobbing at Trump's Florida estate, Mar-a-Lago.</p>

<p>Musk, trading his Silicon Valley bro sweatshirts for a crisp and somber black suit, was given a front-row seat among Republican House lawmakers who gathered to hear the president-elect.</p>

<p>"Elon, you've been so good," Trump said, as the elected representatives offered Musk a standing ovation, according to footage posted by a congressman.</p>

<p>On Tuesday, Trump appointed Musk and another billionaire, former Republican presidential contender Vivek Ramaswamy, to a new "Department of Government Efficiency" tasked with trimming down Washington bureaucracy.</p>

<p>Musk, who sacked 80 percent of Twitter's workforce when he bought it and rechristened it as X, vowed in an announcement to "send shockwaves through the system, and anyone involved in government waste."</p>

<p>Musk has also offered advice well outside of any defined lane for him.</p>

<p>He called for the appointment of the president-elect's daughter-in-law Lara Trump to a US Senate seat expected to open up in Florida should Marco Rubio become secretary of state.</p>

<p>Musk -- and not career diplomats, as would be customary -- reportedly joined Trump in calls with the leaders of Turkey and Ukraine, where Musk's Starlink has provided a vital source of communication during the war.</p>

<p>He also has taken to X while advising Trump to back efforts to defeat Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau.</p>

<h3><strong>Trump's perilous inner circle</strong></h3>

<p>The South African-born Musk, who controversially ran a $1 million-a-day sweepstakes in swing states in a clear bid to attract Trump voters, has so far managed to avoid blowback from the mercurial president-elect.</p>

<p>Trump has gone so far as to suggest he would put aside some of his climate skepticism and back electric cars due to Musk.</p>

<p>The president-elect was said to fume after a first-term consigliere, far-right political strategist Steve Bannon, appeared on the cover of Time magazine and was described as the "second most powerful man in the world."</p>

<p>Trump eventually fired him and nicknamed him "Sloppy Steve."</p>

<p>Musk, whose Tesla cars had been status symbols for wealthy liberals, has also quickly become a lightning rod for criticism from Democrats.</p>

<p>Senator Elizabeth Warren mocked the new initiative of Musk and Ramaswamy, writing on X that the effort for efficiency was "off to a great start with split leadership: two people to do the work of one person."&nbsp;</p>

<p>Until the latest election, Musk said he voted for Democrats for president, including Joe Biden.</p>

<p>The turning point, according to a Wall Street Journal report, was when Biden invited automaker executives to the White House but snubbed Musk because Tesla, unlike the Detroit Big Three, is not unionized.</p>

<p>Whatever the causes, Musk's political transformation has paid off with access unimaginable with most presidents.</p>

<p>On Election Night, a beaming Trump gathered his family together for a picture at Mar-a-Lago. His wife Melania was missing but, at Trump's urging, into the picture came Musk, one of his dozen children in his arms.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/lpgnudlg_elon-musk-donald-trump-bloomberg_625x300_09_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Trump appointed Musk as lead of Department of Government Efficiency.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/whistleblowers-claim-us-government-is-running-secret-ufo-programs-we-are-not-alone-7016321]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Whistleblowers Claim US Is Running Secret UFO Programs: "We Are Not Alone"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/whistleblowers-claim-us-government-is-running-secret-ufo-programs-we-are-not-alone-7016321]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 14 Nov 2024 12:24:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Mr Elizondo claimed that the claimed the US government has been conducting secret UAP research and has retrieved materials from non-human craft.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>During a Congressional hearing on Wednesday, a team of experts testified before lawmakers, claiming that the US is running secret Unidentified Anomalous Phenomena (UAP) programs.&nbsp;The hearing, titled "Unidentified Anomalous Phenomena: Exposing the Truth," featured <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kT2iWKZr0qA">testimony</a> from four experts, including Tim Gallaudet, a retired rear admiral, and Luis Elizondo, a former Department of Defense official, reported <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.npr.org/2024/11/13/nx-s1-5189426/ufo-uap-hearing-congress-2024#:~:text=%22Let%20me%20be%20clear%3A%20UAP,are%20some%20of%20our%20adversaries.%22">NPR.&nbsp;</a></em></p>

<p>Mr Elizondo claimed that the US government has been conducting secret UAP research and has retrieved materials from non-human craft. "Advanced technologies not made by our government – or any other government – are monitoring sensitive military installations around the globe. Furthermore, the US has UAP technologies, as are some of our adversaries," he said.</p>

<p>He also alleged that individuals who provided classified testimonies to government officials have faced threats to their careers.&nbsp;Mr Elizondo remarked that excessive secrecy has led to "grave misdeeds" against loyal civil servants, military personnel, and the public, all to hide the fact that "we are not alone in the cosmos".</p>

<p>We are "in the midst of a multi-decade, secretive arms race  — one funded by misallocated taxpayer dollars and hidden from our elected representatives and oversight bodies," Mr Elizondo stated during his testimony.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Other experts, including Tim Gallaudet and Michael Shellenberger, a journalist and founder of the news site Public,&nbsp;also shared their insights during the hearing. Mr Gallaudet said he first encountered UAPs during his career as a Navy meteorologist&nbsp;and has since advocated for transparency, pushing back against secrecy surrounding these incidents. He also expressed a moral obligation to support whistleblowers who have shared their UAP experiences, often facing ridicule and scepticism.</p>

<p>"Unelected officials in the US government do not have an exclusive right to this knowledge about the nature of reality. The American people have a right to that knowledge," Mr Gallaudet said.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Mr Shellenberger shared his findings on the alleged "Immaculate Constellation" secret government program, claiming it's a Pentagon-led initiative to collect and quarantine UFO sighting information. According to Mr Shellenberger, a whistleblower revealed the program's existence, which has been denied by Department of Defense spokesperson Sue Gough. He further highlighted the need for Congress and the White House to address UFOs, <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.space.com/space-exploration/search-for-life/ufo-whistleblowers-tell-congress-we-are-not-alone-in-the-cosmos-video">Space.com</a></em> reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"What the American people need to know is that the US, military and intelligence community are sitting on a huge amount of visual and other information: still photos, video, photos, other sensor information, and they have for a very long time. And it's not those fuzzy photos and videos that we've been given. There's very clear, high resolution [files]," Mr Shellenberger said.&nbsp;</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">IMMACULATE CONSTELLATION - Report on the US government's secret UAP (UFO) program<br />
<br />
From a whistleblower and released today by <a href="https://twitter.com/NancyMace?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@NancyMace</a> and discussed in today's Congressional hearing<br />
<br />
FULL REPORT <a href="https://t.co/FKCywpnhsU">pic.twitter.com/FKCywpnhsU</a></p>
— Michael Shellenberger (@shellenberger) <a href="https://twitter.com/shellenberger/status/1856773415983820802?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 13, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://oversight.house.gov/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Written-Testimony-Gold.pdf">Michael Gold</a>, a former NASA associate administrator, also emphasised the importance of overcoming the stigma surrounding UAP discussions to facilitate open and scientific dialogue.</p>

<p>Notably, the hearing comes over a year after whistleblower David Grusch accused the Pentagon of running a secret UFO retrieval program. However, no concrete physical evidence has ever emerged to support these claims.</p>

<p>A statement from a Pentagon spokesperson said the department "has not found any verifiable evidence that any UAP observation represented extraterrestrial activity nor has the department discovered any verifiable information to substantiate claims that any programs regarding the possession or reverse-engineering of extraterrestrial materials have existed in the past or exist currently."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/gchagi9g_ufos_625x300_14_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The hearing featured testimony from four experts.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/flights-to-bali-resume-following-volcanic-eruption-7016302]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Flights To Bali Resume Following Volcanic Eruption]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/flights-to-bali-resume-following-volcanic-eruption-7016302]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 14 Nov 2024 12:21:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Several airlines resumed flights to Bali on Thursday, after cancelling trips to and from the Indonesian resort island due to huge eruptions at a nearby volcano.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Several airlines resumed flights to Bali on Thursday, after cancelling trips to and from the Indonesian resort island due to huge eruptions at a nearby volcano.</p>

<p>Eighty-three international routes were cancelled on Wednesday, the general manager of Bali's international airport said in a statement, after Mount Lewotobi Laki-Laki spewed a nine-kilometre (5.6-mile) tower of ash into the sky.</p>

<p>The volcano has erupted more than a dozen times over the last two weeks, killing at least nine people and forcing the evacuation of thousands.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Qantas and Jetstar were resuming their services to Bali, Australia's Qantas Group said in a statement Thursday, noting "improved" conditions.</p>

<p>Two delayed Qantas flights from yesterday were among those set to take off, Qantas said.</p>

<p>"We will continue to monitor the changing conditions and volcanic activity," it said in the statement.&nbsp;</p>

<p>AirAsia planned to resume some flights to and from Bali later today, the company said in a statement to AFP, while Virgin Australia said on its website it would resume flights to and from Denpasar starting today.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Singapore's Scoot airline, meanwhile, said it had rescheduled flights from Singapore to Bali and Surabaya as well as their return flights due to Lewotobi Laki-Laki's volcanic activity.</p>

<p>As of 3 am Thursday, Bali's airport had recorded another 32 international flight cancellations, general manager Ahmad Syaugi Shahab said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>He added that volcanic ash from Mount Lewotobi Laki-Laki had been heading away from the airport since Wednesday evening.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"We hope affected airline passengers can resume their travel on Thursday," Ahmad said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Lewotobi erupted again overnight into Thursday morning, and a thick ash column and lava flows could be seen pouring from its crater, according to the volcanology agency.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The airport in the tourist hotspot of Labuan Bajo near the volcano reopened on Thursday, according to the airport's Instagram account.</p>

<p>Laki-Laki, which means "man" in Indonesian, is twinned with a calmer volcano named after the Indonesian word for "woman".</p>

<p>Bali's economy is heavily reliant on tourism but Indonesia is one of the most disaster-prone nations on Earth, straddling the Pacific Ring of Fire where tectonic plates collide.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/oruq0i7g_bali-airport-afp_625x300_14_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Two delayed Qantas flights from yesterday were among those set to take off, Qantas said.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-makes-orwell-jab-at-senior-nato-official-make-it-fiction-again-7016250]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Make It Fiction...": Elon Musk Makes 'Orwell' Jab At Senior NATO Official]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-makes-orwell-jab-at-senior-nato-official-make-it-fiction-again-7016250]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 14 Nov 2024 12:13:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Tesla and SpaceX CEO Elon Musk accused a senior NATO officer of Orwellian tendencies in a post on X Wednesday, a day after Donald Trump named the world's richest man to a top government post.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Tesla and SpaceX CEO Elon Musk accused a senior NATO officer of Orwellian tendencies in a post on X Wednesday, a day after Donald Trump named the world's richest man to a top government post.</p>

<p>"Make Orwell Fiction Again! Guys like this think 1984 is an instruction manual," Musk wrote in response to a clip of Admiral Rob Bauer -- the chair of NATO's military committee -- speaking at a think tank event.</p>

<p>In remarks at the International Institute for Strategic Studies, Bauer warned of "disinformation and cyber attacks and all the things that are happening influencing elections," saying that the use of social media is "basically amplifying everything that is being done by bot factories."</p>

<p>"I'm very much in favor of freedom of speech, but I'm not necessarily convinced that what... Mr Musk is doing on X is the right approach," the admiral said.</p>

<p>The day before Musk made the comment about Bauer, Trump announced that he would lead a new US government efficiency group tasked with cutting federal waste -- a potentially powerful position in the administration.</p>

<p>Trump said Musk and businessman Vivek Ramaswamy "will pave the way for my Administration to dismantle Government Bureaucracy, slash excess regulations, cut wasteful expenditures, and restructure Federal Agencies."</p>

<p>Musk became a key ally to Trump during his campaign, reportedly spending over $100 million to help the Republican win and repeatedly boosting Trump's candidacy on X, the platform he owns.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/vvhbh134_elon-musk-reuters_625x300_29_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Musk became a key ally to Trump during his campaign.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/worlds-longest-nonstop-flights-to-get-821-million-luxury-upgrade-7015532]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[World's Longest Nonstop Flights To Get $821 Million Luxury Upgrade]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/worlds-longest-nonstop-flights-to-get-821-million-luxury-upgrade-7015532]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 14 Nov 2024 12:06:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The world's longest nonstop commercial flights are getting a major upgrade. Singapore Airlines (SIA) recently announced a multi-year program worth 1.1 billion Singapore dollars (about $821 million).]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The world's longest nonstop commercial flights are getting a major upgrade. Singapore Airlines (SIA) recently announced a multi-year program worth 1.1 billion Singapore dollars (about $821 million) to install new long-haul cabin goods in its 41 Airbus A350-900 aircraft, reported <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/11/13/travel/singapore-airlines-a350-cabins-hnk-intl/index.html">CNN</a>. The ultra-long-range A350ULR, which operates on marathon routes such as nonstop flights from Singapore to New York, will also get four exclusive first-class seats. It only has business class and premium economy cabins.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
In a statement, SIA said the new A350-900 first and business-class products are “designed from the ground up, with a spacious layout and ergonomic elements that cater to every customer's needs.”<br />
<br />
Goh Choon Phong, CEO, SIA, said that over the past six years, the airline engaged customers and stakeholders to help design its next-generation long-haul cabin products, "anticipating their evolving preferences and expectations down to the finest detail."&nbsp;<br />
<br />
The new first class and business class seat designs will incorporate thoughtful elements that push the boundaries of comfort, luxury and modernity, allowing our customers to relax or work effortlessly on board, he added. "Premium economy class and economy class customers can also look forward to refreshed cabin interiors that enhance their travel experience," he said.<br />
<br />
The first retrofitted A350-900ULR is expected to enter service in the first quarter of 2027, while the first refitted A350-900 long-haul aircraft is anticipated to enter service in the second quarter of 2026. According to the airline, its next Boeing 777-9 aircraft will also have the revised seat designs.<br />
<br />
ULR in A350-900ULR stands for ultra-long-range flights. These seven aircraft are flown to and from the United States. They take 18 to 19 hours, on average, and cover over 9,500 miles between Singapore's Changi Airport and New York's John F. Kennedy International Airport.<br />
<br />
For now, passengers who wish to take advantage of SIA's most opulent offers can reserve a private "suite" on one of its Airbus A380s or a first-class seat on one of its Boeing 777 aircraft.</p>

<p><br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/i4c00nd_singapore-airlines_625x300_12_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[It only has business class and premium economy cabins.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bob-lees-accused-killer-says-tech-executive-went-crazy-on-me-7016047]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bob Lee's Accused Killer Says Tech Executive "Went Crazy On Me"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bob-lees-accused-killer-says-tech-executive-went-crazy-on-me-7016047]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 14 Nov 2024 11:46:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Technology executive Bob Lee's accused killer told a jury he acted in self-defense after Lee tried to attack him with a knife on a San Francisco street a year and a half ago, saying "he went crazy on me" after losing his temper.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Technology executive Bob Lee's accused killer told a jury he acted in self defense after Lee tried to attack him with a knife on a San Francisco street a year and a half ago, saying “he went crazy on me” after losing his temper.</p>

<p>Nima Momeni, defending himself at his murder trial, testified Wednesday that during a late night of socializing in April 2023, Lee became enraged, pulled a knife out of his jacket pocket and took a swing, before Momeni grabbed his arm and redirected the blade at his upper chest.</p>

<p>“I was in shock. I was just attacked,” Momeni told jurors. “This is not a normal situation.”</p>

<p>Lee was revered by the Bay Area's tech community as a master coder who helped develop Google's Android and Square's Cash App before becoming a top executive at MobileCoin. The slaying of the 43-year-old father of two drew nationwide attention and at first fueled speculation that he was a random victim of violence in a city falling into post-pandemic lawlessness.</p>

<p>The narrative shifted sharply when police arrested Momeni, a technology entrepreneur who knew Lee, and charged him with premeditated murder. Prosecutors have argued that Momeni was an “overprotective, wanna-be tough guy” who stabbed Lee following an argument over whether the executive had an inappropriate relationship with Momeni's sister, Khazar.</p>

<p><strong>‘Bad Joke'</strong></p>

<p>Momeni testified that after leaving Khazar's apartment in his car late at night, a friendly conservation between the two men quickly turned violent when Momeni made what he called a “bad joke.”</p>

<p>Lee “blew up” after Momeni suggested that “if it was my last night in town, I'd go hang out with my family” instead of going to strip clubs, Momeni testified, adding that his attempt to defuse the situation only made Lee angrier.</p>

<p>“I was afraid for my life,” Momeni testified under questioning from his own lawyer as he gave a blow-by-blow account of the physical confrontation that he says ended with Lee “casually” walking away, appearing to be uninjured, and Momeni throwing the knife over a fence. Lee died in the hospital hours after he called 911 for help and was found bleeding from multiple wounds, including one that pierced his heart.</p>

<p><strong>Binging on Cocaine</strong></p>

<p>Momeni's lawyers told the jury when the trial started a month ago that Lee had been binging on cocaine and sleeping little before he tried to attack Momeni.</p>

<p>In Wednesday's testimony, Momeni said he arrived in the US from Iran when he was 15, alongside his mother and sister, as they sought to escape his allegedly abusive father. He also said he'd been trained in Krav Maga, the Israeli military style of martial arts.</p>

<p>Momeni testified that he first met Lee just a couple of days before the fatal encounter, saying Khazar “always spoke highly of him.” When the two men met, Lee “was energized, super chatty,” Momeni said. “He was coming from a party. I forget which one.”</p>

<p>Momeni also said his sister's “drug addiction had taken over everything.” Drug use by Momeni, Khazar and Lee has been a frequent topic of witness testimony during the trial.</p>

<p>Following the fight with Lee, Momeni said he called his sister.</p>

<p><strong>‘Went Crazy'</strong></p>

<p>“Don't let him back in,” he recalled telling her. “He went crazy on me, tried to attack me.”</p>

<p>Momeni testified that when he later learned that Lee had died, he was “heartbroken, still to this point.”</p>

<p>“He attacked me but he didn't deserve this,” he said, as Lee's brother shook his head sitting in the courtroom gallery. “I didn't see this coming at all.”</p>

<p>Before Wednesday, the most dramatic testimony came from Khazar, who sought to defend her brother but acknowledged on the stand that her memory was foggy because she'd been on a drug bender before and after Lee's death.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/v7h26uf8_nima-momeni-bob-lee-accused-killer_625x300_14_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/this-us-county-switched-to-32-hour-workweek-last-year-here-are-the-results-7016037]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[This US County Switched To 32-Hour Workweek Last Year. Here Are The Results]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/this-us-county-switched-to-32-hour-workweek-last-year-here-are-the-results-7016037]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 14 Nov 2024 11:44:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[San Juan County in Washington has reported an 85.5% spike in job applications, with open positions getting filled 23.75% faster after it shifted to the 32-hour workweek last year.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Amid the ongoing discussion over work-life balance globally, the San Juan county in Washington has reported an 85.5% spike in job applications, with open positions getting filled 23.75% faster after it shifted to the 32-hour workweek last year.</p>

<p>The officials released a report on the key findings on Tuesday, detailing a host of positive outcomes it has witnessed from recruiting new people to retention and employee happiness, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/11/13/economy/four-day-workweek-washington/index.html" rel="nofollow,noindex">CNN</a> reported.</p>

<p>The report suggests the separation rate -- employees quitting or retiring -- has dropped by 48% and 84% of employees have said their work-life balance was better. San Juan is a small network of islands located north of Seattle.</p>

<p>Earlier, the union of workers employed by the county was negotiating a raise for the employees, but the 'cash-strapped' administration was in no position to afford a hike beyond a small amount.</p>

<p>Instead, they agreed upon the 32-hour workweek strategy, wherein the employees could retain their full-time positions with certain benefits and also enjoy reduced work hours as well as schedule flexibility.</p>

<p>It has helped the county save over $975,000 compared to what it would have if it had gone ahead accepting the union's pay hike demands.</p>

<p>County Manager Jessica Hudson said that there are lots of methods to provide employee benefits. “As long as you're open to different solutions, you might find a different way of doing things that allows you to keep wonderful talented employees, even if it's not a direct pay raise," CNN quoted Hudson as saying.</p>

<p><strong>How 32-hour workweek works</strong></p>

<p>Departments across the county have implemented this schedule depending on their requirements, with some shortening the schedules to remain open for just four days a week.</p>

<p>Hudson noted they witnessed a "little bit of culture shock" during the first six months of the workweek as people tried to settle into the new norm.</p>

<p>"But now that we're hitting a one-year mark, while there's still a little bit of confusion, most people are not mad. They understand that this is really a benefit for their fellow community members who want to continue to live and work in the islands. It's kind of becoming a new normal," she added.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/hn280q1g_office-generic_625x300_03_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[In 32-hour workweek, employees enjoy reduced work hours and schedule flexibility.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-xi-jinping-to-meet-in-peru-this-week-as-world-leaders-shift-focus-to-donald-trump-7015973]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden, Xi To Meet In Peru This Week As World Leaders Shift Focus To Trump]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-xi-jinping-to-meet-in-peru-this-week-as-world-leaders-shift-focus-to-donald-trump-7015973]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 14 Nov 2024 11:38:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden will meet his Chinese counterpart, Xi Jinping, in Peru on Saturday for the last of three in-person sit-downs between the leaders during the US president's term in office.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden will meet his Chinese counterpart, Xi Jinping, in Peru on Saturday for the last of three in-person sit-downs between the leaders during the US president's term in office, according to senior administration officials.</p>

<p>Both leaders will be in Lima for the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation forum. They last saw each other in person a year ago at the same summit when Biden hosted Xi outside of San Francisco.</p>

<p>With his term ending, Biden will have significantly diminished power when he sits across from Xi, while the Chinese leader likely is already focused on dealing with Republican President-elect Donald Trump.</p>

<p>Trump for his second term in the White House has threatened to double down on his trade war with China, with plans to impose steep tariffs on all imports from the country.</p>

<p>The senior Biden administration officials, who requested anonymity to discuss the upcoming meeting, declined to comment when asked whether the US president planned to mention Trump or his proposed policies in his conversation with Xi. They also referred to Trump's transition team any questions on whether the incoming president and his advisers have been receiving - or requested - classified intelligence briefings on China.</p>

<h3><strong>US President Joe Biden</strong></h3>

<p>Presidential transitions are "uniquely consequential moments in geopolitics" and Biden will emphasize with Xi the need to maintain "stability, clarity, predictability" in the US-China relationship during this time, National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan said in a separate briefing with reporters Wednesday. He called competition with China "a paramount priority" for the next administration.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Unlike the Biden-Xi meeting in 2023, the focus this time will be less on delivering outcomes or building on progress they have made. Biden is instead expected to use their last face-to-face encounter as a check-in that gives him the chance to emphasize issues of concern.</p>

<p>Among them is China's ongoing support for Russia's defense industrial base, which a senior official said is unlikely to stop and therefore a topic that is going to occupy the incoming administration as well.</p>

<p>Still, Biden will be at pains to point out successes of his strategy of "intense diplomacy" with China, and progress on the three achievements the White House cited out of the leaders' last meeting in California: on military-to-military communications, counter-narcotics efforts and artificial intelligence - each an area where the US has sought to at east enhance dialogue with Chinese officials to limit misunderstanding and instability.</p>

<p>For Beijing, this might be an opportunity to take stock of bilateral ties, which have stabilized over the past year. The Xi-Biden meeting in 2023 has led to a flurry of diplomatic engagements and the restart of communication channels, helping to ease tensions at a time when the world's No. 2 economy is slowing.</p>

<p>But it may be hard for the momentum to continue. Trump has picked people with track records of being harsh on Beijing for key posts in his administration - especially China-sanctioned Marco Rubio as secretary of state, and Mike Waltz as national security adviser. This could bring fresh turbulence to US-China ties.</p>

<h3><strong>Alleged Hack</strong></h3>

<p>The meeting follows an alleged Chinese hack of American telecommunications networks that the US intelligence community is investigating. US officials believe a Chinese hacking group that Microsoft Corp. dubbed Salt Typhoon may have been inside US telecoms for months and found a route into an access point for court-authorized wiretapping.</p>

<p>The sweeping hack targeted the Trump campaign as well as that of Vice President Kamala Harris, his Democratic general-election rival.</p>

<p>Sullivan on Sunday called it "an absolutely significant attack" in an interview on CBS's Face the Nation and said that Biden brings up cyber-enabled espionage every time he speaks with Xi.</p>

<p>"It's something that the FBI, our Department of Homeland Security, our entire national security enterprise is digging into in a big way," he said. "And of course, it will be on the agenda between every American official and every Chinese official in the weeks ahead."</p>

<p>A senior administration official said Biden would warn Xi about what they cast as reckless attacks against critical US networks and that such actions would only lead to further decoupling from Chinese-origin technology.</p>

<p>The two superpowers continue to spar over issues ranging from Taiwan to Ukraine to the South China Sea. The Biden administration has also imposed technology restrictions and a ban on Chinese electric vehicles, as well as added more tariffs to the existing ones they inherited from the first Trump term.</p>

<p>The Biden team often touts its efforts to keep open channels of communication, including via Sullivan and his counterpart Wang Yi, that have helped steady ties.</p>

<p>The US official had one piece of unsolicited advice: Whatever the next administration decides to do, they will need to find ways to manage the relationship somehow.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/t633r7jg_joe-biden-xi-jinping_625x300_29_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Biden, Xi will be in Lima for the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation forum.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>