<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Tue, 05 Nov 2024 08:21:31 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-woman-23-goes-blind-in-one-eye-after-swimming-with-contact-lenses-most-pain-ive-ever-experienced-6945856]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Woman, 23, Goes Blind In One Eye After Swimming With Contact Lenses]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-woman-23-goes-blind-in-one-eye-after-swimming-with-contact-lenses-most-pain-ive-ever-experienced-6945856]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 05 Nov 2024 07:45:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A woman in the US lost vision in one eye due to a rare parasite infection that developed after she went swimming with her contact lenses on.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A woman in the US lost vision in one eye due to a rare parasite infection that developed after she went swimming with her contact lenses on. 23-year-old Brooklyn McCasland was visiting Alabama with her friends in August when she contracted the parasite acanthamoeba keratitis (AK) - an amoeba that can damage the cornea and cause vision loss. "This infection mimics other common infections so at the time I was put on steroids and a handful of other drops," Ms McCasland explained on a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.gofundme.com/f/help-brooklyn-mccasland-recover-from-acanthamoeba-keritis">GoFundMe page</a> created to help her pay her medical bills.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Ms McCasland said that the delay in diagnosing the rare infection caused it to worsen. "I was in the most pain I've ever experienced and eventually went fully blind in my right eye," she said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The 23-year-old said she was seeing an eye doctor every two days and was referred to different eye specialists as she sought an answer for the pain and vision loss. When she got her results back that confirmed that she had AK, she said she was told she could possibly go permanently blind or lose her eye if she didn't start treatment immediately.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Because this infection is so rare, the drops that are used for treatment are only made in the UK. Luckily, the doctor's office in Dallas had a couple of samples so I could start treatment as soon as possible," Ms McCasland said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Ms McCasland needs to put drops in her eyes every 30 minutes because "it is such a slow healing process". "I'm thankful that we know exactly what it is and I'm able to start the correct treatment," she said. "If I would have known that from not swimming in my contacts I could've avoided all of this pain, I would have never done it."</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/united-airlines-passenger-charged-after-violently-attacking-nonverbal-deaf-man-mid-flight-6945698">United Airlines Passenger Charged After Violently Attacking Nonverbal, Deaf Man Mid-Flight</a></strong></p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://my.clevelandclinic.org/health/diseases/21560-acanthamoeba-keratitis"><em>Cleveland Clinic</em></a>, acanthamoeba keratitis infections are rare, with an estimated 1,500 infections in the US annually, however, contact lens wearers make up a whopping 90% of those cases. The clinic explains that wearing contacts for too long, improperly storing or cleaning them, and wearing them while swimming or showering can increase your risk of contracting the parasite.&nbsp;</p>

<p>For Ms McCasland, her struggle is far from over as she shared in an update that a recent visit to the doctor confirmed that the infection "looked not completely worse but not better than last time". "There is a possibility I will need to get a cornea transplant once we get rid of the infection. This could take months but I'm thankful that we know exactly what it is. I hope my journey will help prevent anyone else from going through this," McCasland said.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/7uhmsl6_brooklyn-mccasland-_625x300_05_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Brooklyn McCasland contracted parasite acanthamoeba keratitis (AK) in August.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/over-three-dozen-indian-americans-running-for-state-legislations-local-bodies-6945853]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Over Three Dozen Indian Americans Running For State Legislations, Local Bodies]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/over-three-dozen-indian-americans-running-for-state-legislations-local-bodies-6945853]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 05 Nov 2024 07:42:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Over three dozen Indian Americans are running for local bodies and state legislation elections across the country reflecting the growing interest among this small ethnic community to be part of political mainstream.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Over three dozen Indian Americans are running for local bodies and state legislation elections across the country reflecting the growing interest among this small ethnic community to be part of political mainstream.</p>

<p>"If you are not at the table, you are on the menu," Indian American Congressman Raja Krishnamoorthi comments at various Indian American gatherings motivating and encouraging community members to run for elections at all levels.</p>

<p>Probably the largest number of Indian Americans running for local offices are in the state of California, which sends two members to the House of Representatives - Ro Khanna and Dr Ami Bera - in addition to Vice President Kamala Harris whose mother was from India.</p>

<p>Those include Adlah Chisti who is running for County Supervisor for District 11, Aliya Chisti for City College Board San Francisco, Darshana Patel for State Assembly, Nicole Fernandez for San Mateo City Council, Nithya Raman for Los Angeles City Council, Richa Awasthi for Foster City Council and Sukhdeep Kaur for Emeryville City Council.</p>

<p>Tara Sreekrishnan is seeking to enter California's State Assembly from District 26 in Silicon Valley.</p>

<p>With close to 900,000 Indian Americans residents, California boasts the largest Indian American population in the entire country. Michigan is a presidential battleground, with elections decided by merely 10,000 votes.</p>

<p>Dr Ajay Raman, is running for Oakland County Commissioner for District 14; while Anil Kumar and Ranjeev Puri are running for the Michigan State House.</p>

<p>Indian Americans are a crucial part of Arizona's growth and diversity. Priya Sundareshan is running for the State Senate in Arizona and Ravi Shah is running for School Board. In Pennsylvania, Anand Patek, Anna Thomas, and Arvind Venkat are running for State House, while Nikil Saval is seeking to enter the State Senate.</p>

<p>In Illinois, Anusha Thotakura is running for school board and Nabeel Syed for State House.</p>

<p>If elected Ashwin Ramaswamy would be the youngest ever elected to the Georgia State Senate. Of late he has been subject to racial and hate attacks by his opponents.</p>

<p>In Ohio, Chantel Raghu is running for County Commissioner and Pavan Parikh for County Clerk of Courts, while in Virginia Danny Avula is running for Mayor of Richmond.</p>

<p>In New York, Jeremy Cooney and Manita Sanghvi are running for State Senate while Zohran Mamdani is seeking to enter the State Assembly.</p>

<p>Indian Americans running for local offices in Texas are Ashika Ganguly for City Council, Karthik Soora (State Senate), Nabil Shike (County Constable), Ramesh Premkumar (City Council), Ravi Sandill (Judge), Salman Bhojani (State House), Shekhar Sinha (State House), Sherine Thomas (Judge), Suleman Lalani (State House) and Sumbel Zeb as County Appraisals Court.</p>

<p>Manka Dhingra is running for Attorney General of Washington State while Mona Das is running for Commissioner of Public Lands. PTI LKJ GSP GSP</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-03/c9dj4vlg_us-voting-afp_625x300_04_March_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Tara Sreekrishnan is seeking to enter California's State Assembly from District 26 in Silicon Valley.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/canada-cop-who-attended-khalistani-protest-outside-hindu-temple-suspended-6944649]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Canada Cop Who Attended Khalistani Protest Outside Hindu Temple Suspended]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/canada-cop-who-attended-khalistani-protest-outside-hindu-temple-suspended-6944649]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 05 Nov 2024 07:05:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Canadian police officer was suspended on Monday after a video went viral on social media showing him participating in a pro-Khalistan protest outside a Hindu temple in Brampton, media reports said, quoting authorities.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Canadian police officer was suspended on Monday after a video went viral on social media showing him participating in a pro-Khalistan protest outside a Hindu temple in Brampton, media reports said, quoting authorities.</p>

<p>The suspended Peel Regional Police officer, identified as Harinder Sohi, was caught on camera holding a Khalistan flag, while others in the protest chanted anti-India slogans, CBC News reported.</p>

<p>Sohi was a Sergeant of the Peel Regional Police.</p>

<p>Media Relations Officer Richard Chin emailed CBC News to say the police force is "aware of a video circulating on social media which shows an off-duty Peel Police officer involved in a demonstration".</p>

<p>"This officer has since been suspended in accordance with the Community Safety and Policing Act," he said.</p>

<p>"We are investigating the circumstances in totality depicted in the video and are unable to provide further information until this investigation is complete."</p>

<p>Peel Regional Police previously said three people have been charged after violence erupted as Indian consular officials visited the Hindu Sabha Mandir temple on Sunday.</p>

<p>Videos circulating on social media appear to show demonstrators holding banners in support of Khalistan, a proposed independent Sikh homeland in northern India, and clashing with other individuals, including some holding India's national flag.</p>

<p>The videos appear to show fist fights and people striking each other with poles on what appears to be the grounds surrounding the Hindu Sabha Mandir temple.</p>

<p>Peel police said the event was eventually moved to two other locations in neighbouring Mississauga, where further demonstrations also took place.</p>

<p>On Sunday noon, Peel police said they were aware of the protest and had increased their presence at the Hindu Sabha Mandir temple to maintain public order and safety.</p>

<p>"We respect the right to protest peacefully and safely but will not tolerate violence and criminal acts," Chief Nishan Duraiappah said after the videos began circulating.</p>

<p>"Those that do participate in this activity will be pursued, arrested, and charged."</p>

<p>The violence drew condemnations from Canadian political leaders at all levels of government and also prompted Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi to issue a rare comment at a time of escalating diplomatic tensions between the two countries.</p>

<p>Taking strong note of the "deliberate attack", Prime Minister Narendra Modi sought accountability from the Justin Trudeau-led Canadian government and expected it would ensure justice and uphold the rule of law.</p>

<p>In a post on X, PM Modi said, "I strongly condemn the deliberate attack on a Hindu temple in Canada. Equally appalling are the cowardly attempts to intimidate our diplomats. Such acts of violence will never weaken India's resolve."</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the Minister of External Affairs (MEA) said it remains "deeply concerned" about the safety and security of Indian nationals in Canada, adding that it expects that those indulging in violence will be prosecuted.</p>

<p>"We condemn the acts of violence perpetrated by extremists and separatists at the Hindu Sabha Temple in Brampton, Ontario yesterday. We call on the government of Canada to ensure that all places of worship are protected from such attacks," MEA Spokesperson Randhir Jaiswal said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/3surcddg_peel-regional-police-officer-harinder-sohi_625x300_05_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Canadian cops clashed with Hindu devotees protesting an attack on a temple.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/united-airlines-passenger-charged-after-violently-attacking-nonverbal-deaf-man-mid-flight-6945698]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Man Charged After Violently Attacking Nonverbal, Deaf Passenger Mid-Air]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/united-airlines-passenger-charged-after-violently-attacking-nonverbal-deaf-man-mid-flight-6945698]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 05 Nov 2024 06:57:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A man in the United States violently attacked a deaf and nonverbal passenger while he was sleeping until the cabin was spattered with blood on a United Airlines flight last week.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A man in the United States violently attacked a deaf and nonverbal passenger while he was sleeping until the cabin was spattered with blood on a United Airlines flight last week. According to the <em>New York Post</em>, the incident took place on Monday aboard a United Airlines Flight from San Francisco to Washington Dulles. Authorities identified the suspect as 44-year-old Everett Chal Nelson. The incident unfolded when Mr Nelson got up to use the bathroom. When he was returning to his seat, he stopped at seat 12F and started punching the man who was sleeping there, according to the affidavit, which didn't identify the victim.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The 44-year-old stopped at seat 12F and "without notice, began physically attacking a sleeping male passenger by punching him repeatedly in the face and head until blood was drawn," the complaint states, per the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/10/31/us-news/florida-man-beats-passenger-bloody-on-united-flight-to-dulles/" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>Post</em></a>. "The next thing I know, I just hear these blood-curdling screams," Sandhya Gupta, who was sitting a row behind the victim, told <em>ABC 7 News</em>.</p>

<p>"He was just very violently and very aggressively just pummeling the guy who was in the window seat who was in front of me and it was vicious. This wasn't like a barroom, 'I'm going to throw a couple of punches around,' I mean this was vicious," she said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to the officials, Mr Nelson punched the defenceless man's face for a full minute. He stopped the attack after another passenger rushed up the aisle and wrapped his arms around him.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The complaint states that Mr Nelson split the man's nose open, causing blood to splash all over his seat, the cabin wall and the window. The victim was left with two black eyes.&nbsp;</p>

<p>After the two were separated, a doctor onboard treated the man for his injuries - which is when passengers and the crew discovered the man could not speak or hear. "When he was trying to communicate with us in sign language, that's when we realised he was deaf and non-verbal," Ms Gupta said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The victim communicated with the crew through phone messages. "He also just kept texting, 'I'm so scared'. Like it was just awful," the plane passenger added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Mr Nelson escaped unscathed and "there was no indication that (the alleged victim) struck him in defence," the complaint says, per the outlet. Flight attendants moved the suspect to a seat up front and put the same man who got involved in charge of keeping watch over him until the plane landed.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The motive behind the violent attack is not known. It is also not clear whether the two men had any prior relationship before the attack.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/feature/american-airlines-plane-diverted-due-to-noise-in-cargo-heres-what-happened-6943485">American Airlines Plane Diverted Due To "Noise In Cargo". Here's What Happened</a></strong></p>

<p>The TSA contacted the FBI mid-flight and indicated there was a "Level 2 disturbance" onboard, which constitutes "physically abusive behaviour," according to the Federal Aviation Administration. That places the incident a step above "Level 1," which is "disruptive behaviour" but before "Level 3," which is an "attempted or actual breach of the flight deck."</p>

<p>"Thanks to the quick action of our crew and customers, one passenger was restrained after becoming physically aggressive toward another customer on a flight from San Francisco to Washington Dulles on Monday," a United Airlines spokesperson said in a statement, adding, "The flight landed safely and was met by paramedics and local law enforcement."</p>

<p>Mr Nelson has been charged with one count of assault by beating, striking, and wounding in the special aircraft jurisdiction of the US. If convicted, he could face up to a year in prison.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-01/88lc6k88_united-airlines-plane_625x300_11_January_24.png' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The incident took place on Monday last week. (Representative pic)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/is-the-us-election-really-so-close-6945533]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Is The US Election Really So Close?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/is-the-us-election-really-so-close-6945533]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 05 Nov 2024 06:01:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United States stands on edge as polls suggest one of the closest presidential races in history between former president Donald Trump and Vice President Kamala Harris.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United States stands on edge as polls suggest one of the closest presidential races in history between former president Donald Trump and Vice President Kamala Harris.</p>

<p>Major polling outlets show the candidates virtually deadlocked.</p>

<p>In battleground states on election eve, polling aggregator FiveThirtyEight reported a 47.8 percent tie in Pennsylvania, near-identical numbers in Nevada, and mere one-point differences in Wisconsin, Michigan, and North Carolina.</p>

<p>But these razor-thin margins may not tell the whole story.</p>

<p>"I wonder, is it really this close?" asked W. Joseph Campbell, professor at American University in Washington.</p>

<p>His questions stems from pollsters' troubled track record in recent elections and a potential overreaction to past failures.</p>

<p>The political establishment was blindsided in 2016 when Trump won despite trailing in polls, while Joe Biden's 2020 victory margin proved much narrower than predicted.</p>

<p>In 2022, Republicans secured only a slim Congressional majority despite forecasts of a "red wave."</p>

<p>"The 2020 presidential election was collectively the worst for pollsters in forty years and an embarrassment for many," Campbell said.</p>

<p>Trump's emergence on the political scene largely explains these polling mishaps. His supporters were consistently undercounted in 2016 and 2020, prompting polling companies to adjust their methodologies.</p>

<p>- 'Traumatic for pollsters' -</p>

<p>History offers an intriguing parallel: In 1980, polls showed incumbent Jimmy Carter neck-and-neck with Ronald Reagan. Reagan ultimately won by 10 points, benefiting from a late surge while Carter lost support to a third-party candidate.</p>

<p>"I'm not saying that's going to be the model in 2024, but it is something to keep in mind," Campbell added.</p>

<p>Leading polling analysts openly acknowledged these challenges.</p>

<p>"No, you can't trust the polls... You can't safely assume that the candidate leading in the polls is going to win," wrote Nate Cohn, the New York Times chief political analyst and polling director.</p>

<p>Cohn explained that pollsters are working to correct systemic biases that emerged in the Trump era.</p>

<p>"It's hard to overstate how traumatic the 2016 and 2020 elections were for many pollsters. For some, another underestimate of Trump could be a major threat to their business and their livelihood."</p>

<p>However, he warned that while adjusting methods to better capture Trump voters, pollsters might now be underestimating Harris.</p>

<p>"On balance, these changes add up to a case for cautious optimism on better accuracy, but there are no guarantees," Cohn concluded.</p>

<p>Some experts suspect pollsters may be falling victim to groupthink, or "herding", adjusting results that deviate significantly from the consensus.</p>

<p>Professors Joshua Clinton and John Lapinski warned to NBC news: "State polls are showing not just an astonishingly tight race, but also an improbably tight race."</p>

<p>They suggest that "a risk-averse pollster who gets a 5-point margin in a race they think is tied may choose to 'adjust' the results to something closer to what other polls are showing, lest their outlier poll adversely affects their reputation..."</p>

<p>They said this raised a crucial question: "Is 2024 going to be as close as 2020 because our politics are stable, or do the polls in 2024 only look like the results of 2020 because of the decisions that state pollsters are making?"</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/t62tibb8_donald-trump-kamala-harris-_625x300_11_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US Presidential Elections: Major polling outlets show the candidates virtually deadlocked.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korea-fires-another-ballistic-missile-ahead-of-us-election-6945423]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[North Korea Fires Another Ballistic Missile Ahead Of US Election]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korea-fires-another-ballistic-missile-ahead-of-us-election-6945423]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 05 Nov 2024 05:25:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[North Korea launched a ballistic missile early Tuesday toward the East Sea, South Korea's military said, referring to the body of water also known as the Sea of Japan.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>North Korea fired a ballistic missile early Tuesday, Seoul's military said, its second launch in days and just hours before Americans vote for a new president.</p>

<p>"North Korea fires unidentified ballistic missile," Seoul's Joint Chiefs of Staff said, without giving further details, adding that an analysis was under way.</p>

<p>It said the missile was fired off North Korea's east coast, into what South Korea calls the East Sea, also known as the Sea of Japan.</p>

<p>Tokyo also confirmed the launch, with the prime minister's office saying Pyongyang had "launched a suspected ballistic missile".</p>

<p>On Thursday, the nuclear-armed North test-fired what it said was its most advanced and powerful solid-fuel intercontinental ballistic missile (ICBM).</p>

<p>That launch was Kim Jong Un's first weapons test since being accused of sending soldiers to Russia.</p>

<p>It also came just hours after US and South Korean defence chiefs called on Pyongyang to withdraw its troops, warning that North Korean soldiers in Russian uniforms were being deployed for possible action against Ukraine.</p>

<p>On Sunday, South Korea, Japan, and the United States conducted a joint air drill involving a heavy bomber in response to the ICBM launch.</p>

<p>The drill mobilised the US' B-1B bomber, South Korea's F-15K and KF-16 fighter jets, and Japan's F-2 jets.</p>

<p>Such joint drills infuriate Pyongyang, which views them as rehearsals for invasion.</p>

<p>- 'Aggressive nature' -</p>

<p>Kim Yo Jong, sister of the country's leader and a key spokesperson, said the drill was "just another outright action-based explanation of the most hostile and dangerous aggressive nature of the enemy toward our Republic."</p>

<p>In a statement carried Tuesday by the official Korean Central News Agency, she said the drill was "absolute proof of the validity and urgency of the line of building up the nuclear forces we have opted for and put into practice."</p>

<p>She warned that any "upset of the balance of power between rivals on the Korean peninsula and in the region precisely means a war."</p>

<p>Experts have suggested the spate of weapons tests by Pyongyang could be a bid to distract attention from its purported troop deployment to Russia -- or bump itself up the agenda ahead of the US election.</p>

<p>Seoul has long accused the nuclear-armed North of sending weapons to help Moscow fight Kyiv and alleged that Pyongyang has moved to deploy soldiers en mass in the wake of Kim Jong Un's signing of a mutual defence deal with Russian President Vladimir Putin in June.</p>

<p>It has also warned that Russia may be providing new technology or expertise in return for weapons and troops to help them fight Ukraine.</p>

<p>Seoul, a major weapons exporter, has said it is reviewing whether to send weapons directly to Ukraine in response, something it has previously resisted due to longstanding domestic policy that prevents it from providing weaponry into active conflicts.</p>

<p>North Korea has denied sending troops, but its vice foreign minister has said any such deployment would be in line with international law.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/bcqk7j4_north-korea-missile-launch-afp-_625x300_30_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[It said the missile was fired off North Korea's east coast, into what South Korea calls the East Sea.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-if-the-us-election-ends-in-a-trump-kamala-harris-tie-6945029]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What If The US Election Ends In A Trump-Kamala Harris Tie?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-if-the-us-election-ends-in-a-trump-kamala-harris-tie-6945029]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 05 Nov 2024 03:15:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[While not highly likely, such an outcome remains possible, tormenting Americans already perched painfully on the edge of their seats ahead of the November 5 election.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>So what exactly happens if neither Kamala Harris or Donald Trump achieves the Electoral College majority required to win the US election?</p>

<p>While not highly likely, such an outcome remains possible, tormenting Americans already perched painfully on the edge of their seats ahead of the November 5 election.</p>

<p>Under the US system, it is not the national popular vote that decides who becomes president, but a 538-member "Electoral College," in which each state gets as many "electors" as their representation in Congress.</p>

<p>Every state except Nebraska and Maine award all of their electors to whomever comes first in the state-wide popular vote.</p>

<p>If both Harris and Trump fail to reach the majority threshold of 270 electors, the US Constitution says that Congress would play a deciding role.</p>

<p>Specifically, the newly elected House of Representatives would select the president in January, while the Senate would designate the next vice president.</p>

<p>Several possible scenarios could produce a 269-269 Electoral College split.</p>

<p>One example would occur if Democrat Harris prevails in the states of Wisconsin, Michigan and Pennsylvania, while the Republican former president carries Georgia, Arizona, Nevada and North Carolina, plus a single left-leaning district in Nebraska.</p>

<p><strong>- 200 years -</strong></p>

<p>A tie would force a so-called contingent election in Congress -- something which has never happened in modern American history.</p>

<p>The last time a tie forced Congress to pick the president was in the 1800 election, which pitted Thomas Jefferson against incumbent president John Adams.</p>

<p>Lawmakers in a badly divided House struggled mightily to agree, finally selecting Jefferson on their 36th ballot.</p>

<p>The excruciating muddle led to the adoption four years later of the 12th Amendment to the US Constitution, to somewhat clarify procedures around the election.</p>

<p>This time, if such a House vote should be necessary, it would take place on January 6, 2025.</p>

<p>How would that vote proceed?</p>

<p><strong>- One state, one vote -</strong></p>

<p>"Each state, regardless of population, casts a single vote for President in a contingent election," according to the Congressional Research Service (CRS).</p>

<p>In other words, Republican-leaning Wyoming with its city-sized population of 500,000 would have the same influence as Democratic California, where 39 million people live.</p>

<p>Though the US capital city Washington has three Electoral College votes, it would not get a vote in a contingent election, as it is not a state.</p>

<p>States with two or more representatives would need to hold an internal vote to determine which candidate to support, a CRS report said.</p>

<p>A candidate needs to win a majority of the 50 states, or 26 votes. At present, that would likely give Republicans the edge.</p>

<p>Specific rules to govern the process would likely have to be adopted by the House, potentially leading to intense disagreements and a protracted period of constitutional crisis.</p>

<p>It is not hard to imagine how such a process, at the end of a razor-close campaign, would weigh on the already badly frayed nerves of American voters, many of whom are convinced that the vote has been rife with irregularities.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/tmn8quvo_kamala-harris-donald-trump_625x300_03_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Several possible scenarios could produce a 269-269 Electoral College split.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-election-2024-longer-wait-for-the-winning-president-6944912]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[We May Not Know The Results Of 2024 US Elections On November 5. Here's Why]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-election-2024-longer-wait-for-the-winning-president-6944912]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 05 Nov 2024 02:39:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The U.S. presidential election will take place on November 5, but the winner of the razor-thin race between Democrat Kamala Harris and Republican Donald Trump may not be known for days after the polls close.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The U.S. presidential election will take place on Nov. 5, but the winner of the razor-thin race between Democrat Kamala Harris and Republican Donald Trump may not be known for days after the polls close.</p>

<p>As ballots are counted, one candidate may appear to be leading based on early returns, only for a rival to close the gap as more votes are tallied.</p>

<p>In 2020, some states experienced a "red mirage," in which Trump appeared to be leading on election night, before a "blue shift" saw Democrat Joe Biden overtake him, a phenomenon Trump used to amplify his false claims that the election was stolen.</p>

<p>Nothing untoward had occurred. Democrats tend to live in more populous urban areas, where counting votes takes longer. Democrats also have embraced mail voting more readily than Republicans after Trump's false claims that mail ballots are untrustworthy, and those ballots take longer to count than Election Day votes. Trump has both encouraged and criticized early and mail-in voting in 2024.</p>

<p>Democrats are outpacing Republicans in mail ballots once again this year, according to an early vote tracker maintained by the University of Florida's Election Lab, though Republicans have narrowed the gap.&nbsp;</p>

<p>There are seven battleground states likely to decide the election, each with its own rules for handling and counting ballots. Here's what to expect on Election Day and beyond:</p>

<p><strong>Arizona&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p>Voting by mail is extremely popular in Arizona; nearly 90% of voters cast their ballots early, most by mail, in 2020. Election officials in Arizona can begin processing and tabulating mail ballots upon receipt, but results cannot be released until one hour after polls close.</p>

<p>Any mail ballots dropped off on Election Day itself cannot be processed until the polls have closed. That is often a sizable number – in 2022, those "late early" votes comprised one-fifth of all ballots in Maricopa County, the state's largest – and can take days to count.</p>

<p>The initial results on election night should be mostly early votes, which could favor Harris, before the numbers shift toward Trump as Election Day votes are tallied.</p>

<p><strong>Georgia&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p>Early in-person voting is popular in Georgia, where officials expect 65% to 70% of ballots to be cast at early poll locations. Absentee or mail ballots, which may comprise around 5% of the vote, can be processed - which includes steps such as verifying signatures - starting two weeks before the election, though workers must wait until Election Day to begin counting them.</p>

<p>All early votes – in-person and mail – must be counted and reported by 8 p.m. ET (0000 GMT) on election night, according to state law, which could create a "blue mirage" in Harris' favor at first. Officials are aiming to have all votes, including those from Election Day, tallied by midnight.</p>

<p>Ballots from overseas and military voters will be accepted up to three days after the election if postmarked by Nov. 5. There were more than 21,000 such ballots requested, so an extremely close election might not be resolved until those votes are tabulated.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Michigan</strong></p>

<p>Since the 2020 election, Michigan has instituted early in-person voting for the first time and begun permitting jurisdictions with more than 5,000 people to begin processing and tabulating mail ballots eight days before Election Day. Smaller jurisdictions can do so the day before Nov. 5.</p>

<p>Officials hope those changes will allow the state to report results more quickly than in 2020, when mail ballots could not be processed in advance. That created a "red mirage" on election night, when the state's early counts of Election Day votes favored Trump. Biden eventually surpassed Trump on the strength of mail ballots, which took longer to tally. Trump falsely claimed he was the victim of fraud.</p>

<p><strong>Nevada</strong></p>

<p>Nevada's slow vote counting in 2020 – news outlets did not call the state for Biden until five days after Election Day – launched countless memes, but officials say changes since then should speed up the process.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Most notably, counties were permitted to begin processing and counting mail ballots on Oct. 21. In addition, workers can start tabulating early in-person votes at 8 a.m. PT (1500 GMT) on Election Day, rather than waiting until polls close.</p>

<p>But Nevada still might not get called right away. Mail voting has grown popular in the state, and it is the only battleground that accepts late-arriving mail ballots. That could also create a "blue shift" as more votes are counted.</p>

<p>Any ballot postmarked by Nov. 5 will still be counted if it arrives within four days. Those late ballots historically favor Democrats, so a shift toward Harris could occur as votes are counted after Election Day.</p>

<p><strong>North Carolina</strong></p>

<p>Election officials start processing and scanning mail ballots ahead of Election Day. After polls close, the first reported results will likely be mostly mail ballots as well as early in-person votes. Election Day votes will be counted and reported throughout the evening, with full results expected by midnight.</p>

<p>Harris may appear to lead early thanks to mail ballots, while Trump could close the gap as Election Day votes are counted.</p>

<p>If the election is as close as polls suggest, the outcome in North Carolina may remain unclear for a week or more. Absentee ballots that arrive on Nov. 5, as well as ballots from overseas and military voters, are tallied during the 10-day canvass period that follows Election Day. In 2020, media outlets did not call North Carolina for Trump until Nov. 13, 10 days after the election.</p>

<p><strong>Pennsylvania</strong></p>

<p>Perhaps the most important battleground, Pennsylvania did not have a clear winner in 2020 for four days after Election Day, as officials sifted through a huge backlog of mail ballots. The state is among only a handful that do not permit election workers to process or tabulate mail ballots until 7 a.m. ET on Election Day, which means it will likely again take days before the outcome is known.</p>

<p>With more Democrats than Republicans voting by mail, the early results – based on in-person Election Day votes – will probably show Trump ahead, but his lead will likely shrink as more mail ballots are counted.</p>

<p>That pattern in 2020 prompted Trump to falsely claim fraud. This year, a new law requires most counties to announce at midnight on election night how many mail ballots remain to be counted in an effort to forestall conspiracy theories.</p>

<p><strong>Wisconsin</strong></p>

<p>Like Pennsylvania, Wisconsin is among the few states that do not allow election officials to process or count mail ballots until the morning of the election, which means there can be a delay in reporting the results of those early votes.</p>

<p>In addition, many of the state's largest cities transport mail ballots to a centralized location for processing and tabulating. That can lead to significant batches of votes getting reported all at once in the early morning after polls close.</p>

<p>In 2020, Trump and his allies falsely claimed fraud after Milwaukee, the state's largest city, reported nearly 170,000 absentee ballots around 3:30 a.m. CT (0830 GMT), giving Biden a huge spike that moved him into the lead for the first time. But that increase was expected due to the way the city processes those ballots and the fact that Democrats were more likely to vote by mail. A similar pattern is probable in 2024.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/17ftfae_kamala-harris-donald-trump-afp_625x300_04_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US Election 2024: A razor-thin race between Democrat Kamala Harris and Republican Donald Trump.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/abortion-rights-issue-influencing-indian-american-womens-voting-preference-6944853]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Abortion Rights Issue Influencing Indian American Women's Voting Preference]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/abortion-rights-issue-influencing-indian-american-womens-voting-preference-6944853]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 05 Nov 2024 02:16:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In the upcoming US presidential election, the issue of abortion rights is emerging as a significant factor that is influencing Indian American women's voting preferences.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In the upcoming US presidential election, the issue of abortion rights is emerging as a significant factor that is influencing Indian American women's voting preferences.</p>

<p>This demographic group, which is a part of the second-largest immigrant community in the United States, is showing a strong inclination towards supporting candidates who advocate for reproductive rights.</p>

<p>Meeta Damani, an Indian American documentary filmmaker living in the New Jersey area, has been working in the community with a particular focus on women and children.</p>

<p>"It is a crucial issue for both men and women in the Indian American community as well. It is interconnected like if there is a woman and the child is going to be born unhealthy, that is going to affect the entire family. At the end of the day, it is about freedom and one's choice. I feel the women voters will make their voice very clear," she said.</p>

<p>Looking at the clarity of thought on this subject among Indian American women, it is not a surprise that abortion and reproductive rights have become a top-tier policy issue in the 2024 election cycle.</p>

<p>Priya, a marketing professional, is also a vocal member of the Indian American diaspora in the New Jersey region. She feels that this shouldn't even have been an issue.</p>

<p>"Who would have thought that after coming to a first world country like America, abortion rights would even be an issue for women. If it is my body, it should be my choice. As simple as that. As women voters, if you have the opportunity to support a party that wants to keep your rights intact you will absolutely do that," she said.</p>

<p>In 2022, the Supreme Court overturned the landmark 1973 Roe v. Wade decision. The ruling ended the constitutional right to abortion, allowing states to ban or restrict abortion access. There were subsequent restrictive abortion laws in various states.</p>

<p>The potential for further limitations on reproductive rights is making it an important issue in the country among women. The majority of the public disapproved of the decision. Many Democratic-led states have taken action to protect abortion rights, and some have become sanctuaries for people seeking care out of state.</p>

<p>Supreet, an IT professional, says that women have been impacted by this in many ways. She also thinks many employers in the US had to find ways to mitigate the challenges that the women workers faced.</p>

<p>"The good part is that a lot of employers are coming up with policies that support women. So even if the company is in a state where it is illegal, they are giving them the means to go to other states. The good part is that corporate America is supportive of women but the government may or may not be. That is why it is important to look at it seriously. I definitely feel the women voters will support the party that is pro-abortion," Supreet said.</p>

<p>The Indian American Attitudes Survey (IAAS) conducted a nationally representative online survey of Indian American citizens between September 18 and October 15. It has identified a new, striking gender gap in voting preferences.</p>

<p>According to the survey, 67 per cent of Indian American women intend to vote for Kamala Harris while 53 per cent of men, a significantly smaller share, say they plan to vote for Harris.</p>

<p>When further disaggregated by age, this gender gap appears starkest with younger voters. In the cohort above the age of 40, more than 70 per cent of women and 60 per cent of men plan to vote for Harris.</p>

<p>Sonal Sharma, an immigration lawyer working with a lot of Indian American population, has a word of caution to offer. She feels that while women do feel strongly about the abortion issue, it is not the only thing that matters to others.</p>

<p>"It is a complex issue, despite abortion being so sensitive the polls are 50-50 divided. So, one can see it is not the only issue important to people. We however saw in states where the legislature tried to bring more strict abortion laws, those were rejected. We will have to see what happens," she said.</p>

<p>The importance of abortion rights for Indian American women has not gone unnoticed by political campaigns. Harris has made abortion rights a central part of her campaign strategy and reproductive rights advocacy groups are actively engaging Indian American voters.</p>

<p>In the United States, there are more than 5.2 million people of Indian origin today. It is the second-largest immigrant group in the United States and has emerged as an important political actor. Women form a very significant subset of this unit and as the election draws near, the abortion rights issue is likely to remain a key factor in mobilising and influencing this important demographic.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/njs5i84o_donald-trump-kamala-harris_625x300_08_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[According to the survey, 67 per cent of Indian American women intend to vote for Kamala Harris]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-says-hit-hezbollah-intel-headquarters-in-syria-strike-6944648]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Says Hit Hezbollah Intel Headquarters In Syria Strike]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-says-hit-hezbollah-intel-headquarters-in-syria-strike-6944648]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 05 Nov 2024 01:12:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel's military said its air force struck the intelligence headquarters of Hezbollah's Syrian branch in a strike on Damascus on Monday, an attack a war monitor said killed two people.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel's military said its air force struck the intelligence headquarters of Hezbollah's Syrian branch in a strike on Damascus on Monday, an attack a war monitor said killed two people.</p>

<p>It was a rare acknowledgement by Israeli authorities of an attack against Syria.</p>

<p>The military has intensified its strikes on targets in Syria since launching its war against Hezbollah in neighbouring Lebanon more than a month ago.</p>

<p>Warplanes "conducted an aerial operation and struck Hezbollah terror targets belonging to Hezbollah's intelligence headquarters in Syria", the military said in a statement.</p>

<p>The Syria branch "includes an independent intelligence gathering, coordination, and assessment network", the military said, adding that the attack aimed to degrade Hezbollah's intelligence capabilities.</p>

<p>The Syrian Observatory for Human Rights, a Britain-based war monitor, said Israeli strikes killed two Hezbollah members near the Sayyeda Zeinab area south of Damascus, home to a Shiite sanctuary guarded by pro-Iran groups.</p>

<p>The strikes hit a house "used by members of Hezbollah and the Iranian Revolutionary Guard" at a farm, the Observatory said.</p>

<p>Syria's foreign ministry condemned the attack, saying it targeted "civilian areas" south of Damascus and caused significant material damage.</p>

<p>It did not refer to casualties.</p>

<p>Syrian state media said the strike occurred at approximately 5:18 pm (14:15 GMT) and came "from the direction of the occupied Golan Heights".</p>

<p>Mehdi Mahfouz, a 34-year-old resident of the area, said he "heard three successive explosions, one of which was very strong".</p>

<p>"Then I saw a large black cloud of smoke rising," Mahfouz added. &nbsp;</p>

<p>The blasts were heard in the neighbouring Jaramana suburb of Damascus, an AFP photographer said, as ambulances headed to the area.</p>

<p>Since the Syrian civil war began in 2011, Israel has carried out hundreds of strikes there, mainly targeting army positions and Iran-backed fighters including from Hezbollah.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/264s9o48_israel-hezbollah_625x300_29_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[It was a rare acknowledgement by Israeli authorities of an attack against Syria.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-kamala-harris-ancestral-village-in-india-prays-for-her-election-win-6944069]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris' Ancestral Village In India Prays For Her Election Win]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-kamala-harris-ancestral-village-in-india-prays-for-her-election-win-6944069]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 04 Nov 2024 23:00:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Residents in US Democratic presidential candidate Kamala Harris' ancestral village in southern India were preparing to hold prayers on election day on Tuesday in a Hindu temple more than 8,000 miles (13,000 km) from Washington.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Residents of US Democratic presidential candidate Kamala Harris' ancestral village in southern India were preparing to hold prayers on election day on Tuesday in a Hindu temple more than 8,000 miles (13,000 km) from Washington.</p>

<p>Harris' maternal grandfather P.V. Gopalan was born more than a century ago in the leafy village of Thulasendrapuram in what is now Tamil Nadu.</p>

<p>"There will be a special prayer on Tuesday morning at the temple," G. Manikandan, a villager who runs a small store near the temple, said. "Celebrations will follow if she wins."</p>

<p>At the temple, Harris' name is engraved into a stone that lists public donations, along with that of her grandfather. Outside, a large banner wishes "the daughter of the land" success in the election.</p>

<p>Gopalan and his family migrated a few hundred miles to the coastal city of Chennai, where he worked as a high-ranking government official until his retirement.</p>

<p>The village received global attention four years ago when its residents prayed for victory for Harris' Democratic Party in 2020 before celebrating her inauguration as US Vice President by setting off firecrackers and distributing food.</p>

<p>Harris and her Republican rival Donald Trump were scrambling to get supporters to the polls in a historically close contest, which means it could take days for the winner to emerge.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/va1ud0t_kamala-harris-ancestral-village_625x300_04_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[At the temple, Kamala Harris' name is engraved into a stone that lists public donations.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/this-new-update-on-x-allows-blocked-users-to-view-your-public-posts-6943791]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[This New Update On X Allows Blocked Users To View Your Public Posts]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/this-new-update-on-x-allows-blocked-users-to-view-your-public-posts-6943791]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 04 Nov 2024 22:16:00 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Elon Musk-run X social media platform has started to launch an update that will allow people you've blocked to continue to see your posts and your followers' lists.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Elon Musk-run X social media platform has started to launch an update that will allow people you've blocked to continue to see your posts and your followers' lists.</p>

<p>According to the company, If your posts are set to public, accounts you have blocked can see your posts.</p>

<p>"We're starting to launch the block function update," said X Engineering in a post.</p>

<p>"However, they cannot engage (like reply, repost, etc.) with your posts," according to X guidelines.</p>

<p>Block is a feature that helps you control how you interact with other accounts on X. This feature helps people restrict specific accounts from following, Direct Messaging, and engaging with them.</p>

<p>The tech billionaire had earlier claimed that stopping people from seeing your public posts "makes no sense."</p>

<p>Now, X is rolling out its controversial update to the block feature, allowing people to view your public posts even if you have blocked them.</p>

<p>"Accounts you have blocked cannot follow you, and you cannot follow an account you have blocked. Blocking an account you are currently following will cause you to unfollow that account (and them to unfollow you). If you decide to unblock that account, you will have to follow that account again," according to X.</p>

<p>Blocked users still can't follow the person who has blocked them, engage with their posts, or send direct messages to them.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, software engineer Tracy Chou has built an app that lets users automate blocking, saying that even though users can get around the block by creating other accounts, friction matters.</p>

<p>"Making it easy for the creeper to creep is not a good thing," she said in a post on X.</p>

<p>The social network has argued that the block feature can be used to share and hide harmful or private information about someone. However, people have protested this change.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.gadgets360cdn.com/large/x_twitter_logo_1730725137910.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Block is a feature that helps you control how you interact with other accounts on X. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/the-us-election-by-numbers-6943707]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[The US Election By Numbers]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/the-us-election-by-numbers-6943707]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 04 Nov 2024 22:01:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Swing states, electoral college votes, candidates up and down the ballot, and millions of potential voters: Here is the US election, broken down by numbers.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Swing states, electoral college votes, candidates up and down the ballot, and millions of potential voters: Here is the US election, broken down by numbers.<br />
- Two -</p>

<p>Several independents ran -- and at least one, Robert F. Kennedy Jr, stumbled into a number of eyebrow-raising headlines.</p>

<p>But in the end, the presidential race comes down to a binary choice, with the two candidates from the major parties -- Democrat Kamala Harris and Republican Donald Trump -- seeking to lead a polarized America.</p>

<p>- Five -</p>

<p>November 5 -- Election Day, traditionally held on the Tuesday following the first Monday in November.</p>

<p>- Seven -</p>

<p>The number of swing states -- those which don't clearly favor one party over the other, meaning they are up for grabs.</p>

<p>Harris and Trump are courting voters in Arizona, Georgia, Michigan, Nevada, North Carolina, Pennsylvania and Wisconsin, concentrating their campaign efforts there in a push to ensure victory.</p>

<p>In a razor-tight election, just a handful of votes in any of those states could decide the outcome.</p>

<p>- 34 and 435 -</p>

<p>Voters won't just decide the White House occupant on Election Day -- they will also hit refresh on the US Congress.</p>

<p>Thirty-four Senate seats and all 435 spots in the House of Representatives are up for grabs.</p>

<p>In the House, members serve a two-year term. Republicans currently have the majority, and Harris's Democrats will be hoping for a turnaround.</p>

<p>In the Senate, 34 seats out of 100 are available, for a six-year term. Republicans are hoping to overturn the narrow Democratic majority.</p>

<p>- 538 -</p>

<p>Welcome to the Electoral College, the indirect system of universal suffrage that governs presidential elections in the United States.</p>

<p>Each state has a different number of electors -- calculated by adding the number of their elected representatives in the House, which varies according to population, to the number of senators (two per state).</p>

<p>Rural Vermont, for example, has just three electoral votes. Giant California, meanwhile, has 54.</p>

<p>There are 538 electors in total scattered across the 50 states and the District of Columbia. To take the White House, a candidate must win 270 votes.</p>

<p>- 774,000 -</p>

<p>The number of poll workers who made sure the 2020 election ran smoothly, according to the Pew Research Center.</p>

<p>There are three types of election staff in the United States.</p>

<p>The majority are poll workers -- recruited to do things like greet voters, help with languages, set up voting equipment, and verify voter IDs and registrations.</p>

<p>Election officials are elected, hired or appointed to carry out more specialized duties such as training poll workers, according to Pew.</p>

<p>Poll watchers are usually appointed by political parties to observe the ballot count -- expected to be particularly contentious this year, thanks to Trump's refusal to agree to unconditionally accept the result.</p>

<p>Many election workers have already spoken to AFP about the pressure and threats they are receiving ahead of the November 5 vote.</p>

<p>- 75 million -</p>

<p>As of November 2, more than 75 million Americans had voted early, according to a University of Florida database.</p>

<p>Most US states permit in-person voting or mail-in voting to allow people to deal with scheduling conflicts or an inability to cast their ballots on election day itself on November 5.</p>

<p>- 244 million -</p>

<p>The number of Americans who will be eligible to vote in 2024, according to the Bipartisan Policy Center.</p>

<p>How many of those will actually cast their ballot remains to be seen, of course. But the Pew Research Center says that the midterm elections of 2018 and 2022, and the presidential vote of 2020, produced three of the highest turnouts of their kind seen in the United States in decades.</p>

<p>"About two-thirds (66 percent) of the voting-eligible population turned out for the 2020 presidential election -- the highest rate for any national election since 1900," Pew says on its website.</p>

<p>That translated to nearly 155 million voters, according to the Census Bureau.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/eoi3ebi_us-election_625x300_02_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[In a razor-tight election, just a handful of votes in any of those states could decide the outcome]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/the-seven-states-that-will-decide-the-us-presidency-6943603]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[The Seven States That Will Decide The US Presidency]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/the-seven-states-that-will-decide-the-us-presidency-6943603]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 04 Nov 2024 21:48:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[And in the handful of critical states framing the 2024 race, there is little daylight between the rivals with barely a week before Election Day.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US Vice President Kamala Harris and former president Donald Trump are hurtling toward their November 5 election showdown, one of the closest contests in modern American history.</p>

<p><br />
And in the handful of critical states framing the 2024 race, there is little daylight between the rivals with barely a week before Election Day.</p>

<p><br />
Under the US Constitution, America's founding fathers established that each of the 50 states would hold its own vote for president.&nbsp;</p>

<p><br />
Under the complex Electoral College system, each state has a certain number of "electors," based on population. Most states have a winner-take-all system that awards all electors to whoever wins the popular vote.</p>

<p><br />
With candidates needing 270 of the 538 electoral votes to win, elections tend to be decided in the hotly contested "swing states" with a history of alternating between Republican and Democratic candidates.</p>

<p><br />
This year, there are seven such battlegrounds, and every one is a toss-up within the margin of error. Here is a look:</p>

<p><br />
- Pennsylvania (19 Electoral College votes) -<br />
Pennsylvania was once reliably Democratic, but these days, they don't come much tighter than the Keystone State.</p>

<p><br />
Republican Trump won the most populous battleground, with 13 million residents, by 0.7 percentage points in 2016. Joe Biden claimed it by 1.2 percentage points in 2020.</p>

<p><br />
Known for its "Rust Belt" cities like Philadelphia and Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania has been blighted for decades by the steady decline of its industrial manufacturing base.</p>

<p><br />
Trump and Harris have campaigned repeatedly in the eastern state, where the pair held their one and only presidential debate. Trump, who survived an assassination attempt at a July rally in Pennsylvania, is courting the rural white population and warning that migrants are overwhelming small towns.</p>

<p><br />
Harris is touting recent infrastructure wins, and in Pittsburgh she outlined plans to invest $100 billion in manufacturing, a key issue for state residents.</p>

<p><br />
- Georgia (16) -<br />
This southeastern state was an election flashpoint at the end of Trump's first term, and the controversy simmers.</p>

<p><br />
Prosecutors in Georgia indicted Trump in an election interference case after he called state officials urging them to "find" enough votes to overturn Biden's narrow 2020 victory.&nbsp;</p>

<p><br />
But in a boost for Trump, the case is paused until after the election.</p>

<p><br />
Biden was the first Democrat to win the Peach State since 1992. Demographic changes are likely to benefit Harris, who has courted minority voters across Georgia.</p>

<p><br />
- North Carolina (16) -<br />
The southeastern state has voted Democratic only once since 1980, but Harris believes it's back in play.</p>

<p><br />
The population, now over 10 million, is expanding and growing more diverse, benefiting Democrats.</p>

<p><br />
Complicating matters for Trump, a scandal involving the state's Republican gubernatorial candidate has infuriated party officials who worry it could sink Trump in a close race.</p>

<p><br />
As in neighboring Georgia, one wild card is how the devastation from storm Helene, which recently laid waste to towns in western North Carolina, might impact the vote.&nbsp;</p>

<p><br />
- Michigan (15) -<br />
Trump flipped Michigan, a former Democratic stronghold, on his way to defeating Hillary Clinton in 2016.</p>

<p><br />
Biden returned it to the blue column in 2020, buoyed by unionized workers and a large Black community.</p>

<p><br />
But this time, Harris risks losing the support of a 200,000-strong Arab-American community that has denounced Biden's -- and by extension her -- handling of the Israel-Hamas war in Gaza.</p>

<p><br />
- Arizona (11) -<br />
The Grand Canyon state was among 2020's tightest races, with Biden triumphing by just 10,457 votes.</p>

<p><br />
Trump hopes frustrations over the Biden-Harris administration's immigration policy will swing Arizona, which shares a border with Mexico, back in his favor.</p>

<p><br />
Harris visited Arizona's border in September vowing to crack down on migration and work on reviving last year's bipartisan border bill, which she said Trump "tanked" for political purposes.</p>

<p><br />
- Wisconsin (10) -<br />
Clinton lost Wisconsin after giving the state a wide berth during the 2016 campaign.</p>

<p><br />
As with Midwestern neighbor Michigan, it was a different story when Trump's opponent was Biden, who turned a 23,000-vote deficit into a winning margin of 21,000 for Democrats.</p>

<p><br />
Trump considers it winnable, and his party held its summer national convention there.&nbsp;</p>

<p><br />
While Trump led early against Biden, Harris has made the state race a nailbiter.&nbsp;</p>

<p><br />
- Nevada (6) -<br />
The Silver State, with a population of 3.1 million, hasn't voted Republican since 2004. Conservatives, buoyed by Trump's headway with Hispanic voters, are convinced they can flip the script.</p>

<p><br />
Trump held a significant lead here against Biden.&nbsp;</p>

<p><br />
But within weeks of becoming the Democratic nominee, Harris -- promoting her economic plans to help small businesses and combat inflation -- has erased that advantage in the western state, whose largest city Las Vegas is dominated by the hospitality industry.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/17ftfae_kamala-harris-donald-trump-afp_625x300_04_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[America's founding fathers established that each of the 50 states would hold its own vote for president.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-election-trump-harris-showdown-revives-debate-on-americas-electoral-college-6943320]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump-Harris Showdown Revives Debate On US' Electoral College]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-election-trump-harris-showdown-revives-debate-on-americas-electoral-college-6943320]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 04 Nov 2024 21:06:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[When political outsider Donald Trump defied polls and expectations to defeat Hillary Clinton in the 2016 US presidential election, he described the victory as "beautiful."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When political outsider Donald Trump defied polls and expectations to defeat Hillary Clinton in the 2016 US presidential election, he described the victory as "beautiful."</p>

<p>Not everyone saw it that way -- considering that Democrat Clinton had received nearly three million more votes nationally than her Republican rival. Non-Americans were particularly perplexed that the second-highest vote-getter would be the one crowned president.</p>

<p>But Trump had done what the US system requires: win enough individual states, sometimes by very narrow margins, to surpass the 270 Electoral College votes necessary to win the White House.</p>

<p>Now, on the eve of the 2024 election showdown between Trump and Democrat Kamala Harris, the rules of this enigmatic and, to some, outmoded, system is coming back into focus.</p>

<p><strong>Why an Electoral College?</strong></p>

<p>The 538 members of the US Electoral College gather in their state's respective capitals after the quadrennial presidential election to designate the winner.</p>

<p>A presidential candidate must obtain an absolute majority of the "electors" -- or 270 of the 538 -- to win.</p>

<p>The system originated with the US Constitution in 1787, establishing the rules for indirect, single-round presidential elections.</p>

<p>The country's Founding Fathers saw the system as a compromise between direct presidential elections with universal suffrage, and an election by members of Congress -- an approach rejected as insufficiently democratic.</p>

<p>Because many states predictably lean Republican or Democratic, presidential candidates focus heavily on the handful of "swing" states on which the election will likely turn -- nearly ignoring some large states such as left-leaning California and right-leaning Texas.</p>

<p>Over the years, hundreds of amendments have been proposed to Congress in efforts to modify or abolish the Electoral College. None has succeeded.</p>

<p>Trump's 2016 victory rekindled debate. And if the 2024 race is the nail-biter that most polls predict, the Electoral College will surely return to the spotlight.</p>

<p><strong>Who are the 538 electors?</strong></p>

<p>Most are local elected officials or party leaders, but their names do not appear on ballots.</p>

<p>Each state has as many electors as it has members in the US House of Representatives (a number dependent on the state's population), plus the Senate (two in every state, regardless of size).</p>

<p>California, for example, has 54 electors; Texas has 40; and sparsely populated Alaska, Delaware, Vermont and Wyoming have only three each.</p>

<p>The US capital city, Washington, also gets three electors, despite having no voting members in Congress.</p>

<p>The Constitution leaves it to states to decide how their electors' votes should be cast. In every state but two (Nebraska and Maine, which award some electors by congressional district), the candidate winning the most votes theoretically is allotted all that state's electors.</p>

<p><strong>Controversial institution</strong></p>

<p>In November 2016, Trump won 306 electoral votes, well more than the 270 needed.</p>

<p>The extraordinary situation of losing the popular vote but winning the White House was not unprecedented.</p>

<p>Five presidents have risen to the office this way, the first being John Quincy Adams in 1824.</p>

<p>More recently, the 2000 election resulted in an epic Florida entanglement between Republican George W. Bush and Democrat Al Gore.</p>

<p>Gore won nearly 500,000 more votes nationwide, but when Florida -- ultimately following a US Supreme Court intervention -- was awarded to Bush, it pushed his Electoral College total to 271 and a hair's-breadth victory.</p>

<p><strong>True vote or simple formality?</strong></p>

<p>Nothing in the Constitution obliges electors to vote one way or another.</p>

<p>If some states required them to respect the popular vote and they failed to do so, they were subjected to a simple fine. But in July 2020, the Supreme Court ruled that states could impose punishments on such "faithless electors."</p>

<p>To date, faithless electors have never determined a US election outcome.</p>

<p><strong>Electoral College schedule</strong></p>

<p>Electors will gather in their state capitals on December 17 and cast votes for president and vice president. US law states they "meet and cast their vote on the first Tuesday after the second Wednesday in December."</p>

<p>On January 6, 2025, Congress will convene to certify the winner -- a nervously watched event this cycle, four years after a mob of Trump supporters attacked the US Capitol attempting to block certification.</p>

<p>But there is a difference. Last time, it was Republican vice president Mike Pence who, as president of the Senate, was responsible for overseeing the certification. Defying heavy pressure from Trump and the mob, he certified Biden's victory.</p>

<p>This time, the president of the Senate -- overseeing what normally would be the pro forma certification -- will be none other than today's vice president: Kamala Harris.</p>

<p>On January 20, the new president is to be sworn in.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ntovuvd8_trump-kamala_625x300_04_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The system establishes rules for indirect, single-round presidential elections. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/axe-attack-on-paris-train-leaves-4-teens-injured-6943174]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Axe Attack On Paris Train Leaves 4 Teens Injured]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/axe-attack-on-paris-train-leaves-4-teens-injured-6943174]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 04 Nov 2024 20:48:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Four teens were wounded, two of them seriously, by an axe wielded during a fight on Monday on a suburban train outside Paris, police sources said, with the main suspect later arrested.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Four teens were wounded, two of them seriously, by an axe wielded during a fight on Monday on a suburban train outside Paris, police sources said, with the main suspect later arrested.</p>

<p>One of the victims -- all aged 16 or 17 -- had a hand cut off and another had their skull split open.</p>

<p>Two others were more lightly injured in the struggle that one police source said had broken out around 8:00 am (0700 GMT) as the teenagers involved were on their way to secondary school.</p>

<p>It was not immediately clear what triggered the fight, in which weapons including the axe, a knife, a samurai sword and baseball bats were used.</p>

<p>All the wounded people were brought to hospital and none were in danger for their life, the source added.</p>

<p>The main suspect, a 16-year-old, was later arrested at his home and held in custody, another police source said.</p>

<p>An axe was found and confiscated during the search, they added.</p>

<p>The incident happened while the RER suburban express train was at the station of Ozoir-la-Ferriere southeast of Paris.</p>

<p>Since the train was halted at a station, the violence did not affect traffic on the RER E line, which runs east-west through Paris and its suburbs, state rail operator SNCF said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/gdfg1md8_paris-axe-attack_625x300_04_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The main suspect was later arrested at his home and held in custody. (Represebtational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/is-the-us-presidential-election-a-battle-of-the-sexes-6942826]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Is The US Presidential Election A Battle Of The Sexes?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/is-the-us-presidential-election-a-battle-of-the-sexes-6942826]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:57:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Historically speaking, women have leaned towards voting for Democrats more than men have, since the 1980s and this gap has only grown wider since.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The US presidential election 2024 is a battle of the sexes.</p>

<p>Historically speaking, women have leaned towards voting for Democrats more than men have, since the 1980s and this gap has only grown wider since.</p>

<p>This time around, Democrats have been losing support from key demographics such as Black and Latino men. However, they have gained support in other areas - women voters.</p>

<p>According to the Center For American Women and Politics, "The number of female voters has exceeded the number of male voters in every presidential election since 1964" so voter turnout is crucial for both the parties.</p>

<p>Apart from the major issues, such as economy and employment, two important topics that will heavily impact election results are abortion and immigration, Democrat Kamala Harris is gaining ground with the former and Republican Donald Trump with the latter.</p>

<p>Based on an analysis by Gallup, "Women aged 18 to 29 today are more liberal than young women in the past on specific issues, particularly the environment and abortion" which explains the surge in women voters for the Democratic Party.</p>

<p>Trump has struggled to connect with women voters. In fact, women tend to favor Harris over Trump by a significant margin. This trend is consistent with previous elections, where Trump has failed to win over female voters. In 2020, Joe Biden took a major slice of women voters at 55% while Trump only won 44%. Similarly, in 2016, Hillary Clinton claimed 54% of women voters while Trump won 39%.</p>

<p>Charlie Kirk, a conservative activist posted, "Early vote has been disproportionately female. If men stay at home, Kamala is president. It's that simple. If you want a vision of the future if you don't vote, imagine Kamala's voice cackling, forever. Men need to GO VOTE NOW" urging men to cast their ballot.</p>

<p>Women are of utmost importance in this election because they can make or break the election. "The women's vote will be decisive this election," Katherine Tate, a Brown University political scientist, said. "If Harris wins, it will be because women elected her." She also added that, "Trump has alienated female voters by his abrasive language and aggression."</p>

<p>On that note, Trump touched a nerve when he said, "You will no longer have anxiety from all of the problems our country has today. You will be protected, and I will be your protector. Women will be happy, healthy, confident and free. You will no longer be thinking about abortion." He was posing as the liberator and messiah for women, at a campaign rally in Indiana. It had a patronising tone that snatched agency from the voices of women and took America back several years.</p>

<p>However, according to a CNN report, Trump has been asking his close allies why women don't like him. The gender gap is a serious concern for the Trump campaign. Speaking for the Republican candidate, Karoline Leavitt, the campaign's spokesperson, told The Independent, that he is "loved by millions of women across the country, and those who know him personally, myself included, will tell you he's supportive, generous and kind."</p>

<p>It is also noteworthy that since the 1970s at least 27 women have accused Trump of sexual assault and misconduct, all of which the former president has denied.</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/unkf30o8_donald-trump-kamala-harris_625x300_04_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Women are of utmost importance in this election because they can make or break the election]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-to-launch-two-private-iranian-satellites-into-orbit-6942615]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russia To Launch Two Private Iranian Satellites Into Orbit]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-to-launch-two-private-iranian-satellites-into-orbit-6942615]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:29:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Russian rocket will launch two privately built Iranian satellites into orbit early Tuesday, the Iranian embassy in Moscow said, hailing close space cooperation between Moscow and Tehran.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Russian rocket will launch two privately built Iranian satellites into orbit early Tuesday, the Iranian embassy in Moscow said, hailing close space cooperation between Moscow and Tehran.</p>

<p>The two countries have deepened ties and trade amid Russia's military offensive on Ukraine and conflict in the Middle East, with space launches just one aspect of their burgeoning partnership.</p>

<p>"In continuation of the development of Iran-Russia scientific and technological cooperation, two Iranian satellites -- Koswar and Hodhod -- will be launched into 500-kilometre orbit," Iran's ambassador in Moscow, Kazem Jalali, said Monday on social media.</p>

<p>He said the launch will take place at 02:48 Tehran time (2318 GMT on Monday) using a Russian Soyuz rocket.</p>

<p>The imaging and communications satellites were designed and built by Iran's Omid Faza Company, the statement said, and will support agriculture, environmental monitoring and communications in remote areas.</p>

<p>Russia has previously launched some Iranian satellites, but this is the first instance for a private sector initiative, Jalali said.</p>

<p>"There is hope that with the launch of these two satellites, a firm and decisive first step will be taken towards the entry of the private sector of the Islamic Republic of Iran into the space sphere," he said.</p>

<p>The West has raised concerns over Iran's fledgling space programme, fearing the same technology could also be used to launch nuclear-equipped ballistic missiles.</p>

<p>Tehran says its space programme is peaceful and complies with a UN Security Council resolution that aims to restrict Iran's ballistic missile programme.</p>

<p>Moscow has been accused of using Iranian military hardware and technology, most notably self-detonating Shahed drones, throughout its offensive on Ukraine.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2016-10/satellite-generic_650x400_41476444487.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The launch will take place at 02:48 Tehran time using a Russian Soyuz rocket. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-says-he-would-not-mind-somebody-shooting-at-him-through-fake-news-6942604]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Says He Would Not Mind Somebody 'Shooting' At Him Through Fake News]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-says-he-would-not-mind-somebody-shooting-at-him-through-fake-news-6942604]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:26:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Having survived two assassination attempts this summer, Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump on Sunday suggested that he would not mind if somebody took a shot at him through fake news.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Having survived two assassination attempts this summer, Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump on Sunday suggested that he would not mind if somebody took a shot at him through fake news.</p>

<p>Addressing his supporters at an election rally at Lititz in the battleground state of Pennsylvania, Trump generated another controversy by saying that he should not have left the White House after his defeat in the 2020 elections.</p>

<p>"I shouldn't have left, I mean, honestly. We did so well," Trump said in his speech but immediately changed the topic. "So now, every polling booth has hundreds of lawyers standing there."</p>

<p>Trump had refused to accept the results of the November 2020 elections. His supporters ended up attacking the US Capitol on January 6, which is considered to be the worst day in American democracy.</p>

<p>The former president, who is now 78, expressed frustration over the enhanced security around him after his recent assassination bids.</p>

<p>"I have a piece of glass over here. I don't have a piece of glass there. And I have this piece of glass here. But all we have really over here is the fake news, right? And to get me, somebody would have to shoot through the fake news. I don't mind that so much. I don't mind. I don't mind that," Trump said, referring the thick bullet proof glass around him and the gap in his protective glass.</p>

<p>"I have a piece of glass here. The problem with that glass is it's - I don't look great on television when you have a four-inch piece of glass that a howitzer can't go through. No, when you see yourself on television, you say, boy, you're really not very recognizable, to be honest with you, which is good. But here's the problem. So I have glass here. I have glass here. Now, I'm not worried about this. Look, what do I have? A couple of people. And they're friends, generally. There are a couple of people I don't like in that group, but that's like," he said.</p>

<p>His remarks were criticized by the Democrats. Harris-Walz Director of Rapid Response Ammar Moussa said as Harris spent today at church in Detroit, talking to voters about her vision to lift up all Americans, Donald Trump was busy violating the Ninth Commandment.</p>

<p>"Trump is spending the closing days of his campaign angry and unhinged, lying about the election being stolen because he's worried he will lose. The American people deserve a leader who tells the truth and will walk into the Oval Office focused on them - that's Vice President Harris," Moussa said.</p>

<p>Steven Cheung, Trump Campaign Communications Director, said Trump was talking about the two assassination attempts on his own life, including one that came within 1/4 of an inch from killing him, something that the media constantly talks and jokes about.</p>

<p>"The President's statement about protective glass placement has nothing to do with the Media being harmed, or anything else. It was about threats against him that were spurred on by dangerous rhetoric from Democrats," he said.</p>

<p>"In fact, President Trump was stating that the Media was in danger, in that they were protecting him and, therefore, were in great danger themselves, and should have had a glass protective shield, also. There can be no other interpretation of what was said. He was actually looking out for their welfare, far more than his own!" Cheung said.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/bdehpaas_donald-trump_625x300_17_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Trump suggested that he would not mind if somebody took a shot at him through fake news]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/maldives-recalls-top-diplomat-over-unauthorised-meet-with-afghan-envoy-6942597]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Maldives Recalls Diplomat In Pak Over Unauthorised Meet With Taliban Envoy]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/maldives-recalls-top-diplomat-over-unauthorised-meet-with-afghan-envoy-6942597]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:22:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Maldives recalled its top diplomat in Pakistan, official sources said Monday, after he had an unauthorised meeting with an Afghan envoy in Islamabad.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Maldives recalled its top diplomat in Pakistan, official sources said Monday, after he had an unauthorised meeting with an Afghan envoy in Islamabad.</p>

<p>The Maldives Foreign ministry said the much publicised meet between the Maldives High Commissioner Mohamed Thoha and Taliban representative Sardar Ahmad Shakeeb on Friday was "not sanctioned" by the government.</p>

<p>"Consequently, appropriate action has been taken by the government of Maldives," the ministry statement said without giving details.</p>

<p>Thoha's name has been taken down from the website of the Maldives mission in Islamabad, and an official source told AFP that he had been recalled.</p>

<p>Since the Taliban ousted the Western-backed administration in 2021 and imposed an austere interpretation of Islamic law, no foreign country has yet officially recognised their government.</p>

<p>But three years into their rule, Taliban authorities have been making diplomatic inroads.</p>

<p>Pakistan, China, Russia, Iran and Central Asian republics have established de facto diplomatic relations with Kabul, while Western embassies in the capital have been closed for over three years.</p>

<p>The Maldives, the smallest Islamic republic in South Asia, does not recognise the Taliban government.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/m5i631uo_maldives-taliban-meet_625x300_04_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Maldives, the smallest Islamic republic in South Asia, does not recognise the Taliban government.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>