<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Thu, 29 Aug 2024 23:05:29 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-agree-to-zoned-3-day-pauses-for-gaza-polio-vaccinations-who-6447671]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel, Hamas Agree To Zoned 3-Day Pauses For Gaza Polio Vaccinations: WHO]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-agree-to-zoned-3-day-pauses-for-gaza-polio-vaccinations-who-6447671]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 29 Aug 2024 22:47:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Israeli military and Palestinian militant group Hamas have agreed to three separate, zoned three-day pauses in fighting in the Gaza Strip to allow for the vaccination of some 640,000 children against polio, a senior WHO official said on Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Israeli military and Palestinian militant group Hamas have agreed to three separate, zoned three-day pauses in fighting in the Gaza Strip to allow for the vaccination of some 640,000 children against polio, a senior WHO official said on Thursday.</p>

<p>The vaccination campaign is due to start on Sunday, said Rik Peeperkorn, the World Health Organization's senior official for the region.</p>

<p>He said the campaign would start in central Gaza with a three-day pause in fighting, then move to southern Gaza, where there would be another three-day pause, followed by northern Gaza. Peeperkorn added that there was an agreement to extend the humanitarian pause in each zone to a fourth day if needed.</p>

<p>The WHO confirmed on Aug. 23 that at least one baby has been paralyzed by the type 2 polio virus, the first such case in the territory in 25 years.</p>

<p>The Israeli military's humanitarian unit (COGAT) said on Wednesday that the vaccination campaign would be conducted in coordination with the Israeli military "as part of the routine humanitarian pauses that will allow the population to reach the medical centers where the vaccinations will be administered."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/id5us9h_gaza-polio-scare_625x300_19_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-amends-law-scrapping-special-security-for-sheikh-hasina-family-6447607]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh Amends Law Scrapping Special Security For Sheikh Hasina, Family]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-amends-law-scrapping-special-security-for-sheikh-hasina-family-6447607]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 29 Aug 2024 22:37:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The interim government in Bangladesh on Thursday withdrew the special security cover accorded to deposed prime minister Sheikh Hasina and her close relatives, days after revoking their diplomatic passports.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The interim government in Bangladesh on Thursday withdrew the special security cover accorded to deposed Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina and her close relatives, days after revoking their diplomatic passports.</p>

<p>The Council of Advisers with Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus in the chair decided to amend the Special Security Force Act 2021 lifting special security for former prime minister Sheikh Hasina and her close relatives, the official BSS news agency reported.</p>

<p>After Sheikh Hasina, 76, fled to India on August 5, Bangladesh President Mohammad Shahabuddin dissolved Parliament.</p>

<p>Sheikh Hasina currently faces more than 75 cases in Bangladesh, nearly half of them murder charges.</p>

<p>"Against the backdrop of student-people mass upsurge the interim government has been formed on August 8, 2024, comprising the Chief Adviser and other advises," the chief adviser's office (CAO) said in a statement following an advisory council meeting.</p>

<p>The statement noted that the act was enacted and enforced following the previous government's decision. Subsequently, on May 15, 2015, a gazette was issued under this law to provide special security and benefits to Sheikh Hasina and her close relatives.</p>

<p>"The law was made solely to provide special state benefits to the members of one family, which constitutes clear discrimination." The interim government is firmly committed to eliminating all forms of discrimination, it said.</p>

<p>Because of the changed scenario "it is not possible to implement under administrative management the provisions relating to 'Father of the Nation Bangabandhu Sheikh Mujibur Rahman's family' in line with the existing law, it said.</p>

<p>Talking to journalists after the meeting, advisory council member Syeda Rizwana Hasan said "The interim government was the outcome of an anti-discrimination movement".</p>

<p>Syeda Rizwana, entrusted with the portfolio of environment, forest and climate change ministry, said the council decided to amend the law considering it "discriminatory".</p>

<p>Recently, the Ministry of Home Affairs cancelled the diplomatic passports of Sheikh Hasina, her advisers, former cabinet members, and all members of the 12th Parliament. Diplomatic passports for their spouses and children have also been revoked with immediate effect.</p>

<p>Syeda Rizwana said Bangladesh signed the Instrument of Accession to the International Convention for the Protection of All Persons from Enforced Disappearance on Thursday, "demonstrating its commitment to investigate each and every case of enforced disappearances".</p>

<p>"The Chief Advisor has signed the instrument. About 700 people are still missing due to enforced disappearance.</p>

<p>The International Convention for the Protection of All Persons from Enforced Disappearance was adopted in New York on December 20, 2006.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/6etffbkg_sheikh-hasina-afp_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sheikh Hasina currently faces more than 75 cases in Bangladesh. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-army-blasts-donald-trumps-staff-over-push-during-cemetery-visit-6447576]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Army Blasts Donald Trump's Staff Over "Push" During Cemetery Visit]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-army-blasts-donald-trumps-staff-over-push-during-cemetery-visit-6447576]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 29 Aug 2024 22:31:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The US Army on Thursday took aim at Donald Trump's staff over a visit by the Republican presidential candidate to the country's most hallowed resting place for its war dead.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The US Army on Thursday took aim at Donald Trump's staff over a visit by the Republican presidential candidate to the country's most hallowed resting place for its war dead.</p>

<p>Trump went to the Arlington National Cemetery just outside Washington with family members of some of the 13 service members killed in a 2021 bombing during the last hours of the US withdrawal from Afghanistan.</p>

<p>His campaign posted photos from the visit, including one showing him giving a thumbs-up gesture while standing with relatives at the grave of one of the Marines killed.</p>

<p>The Army said an Arlington employee was "abruptly pushed aside" when she sought to ensure a law prohibiting political activity on cemetery grounds was followed.</p>

<p>"This incident was unfortunate, and it is also unfortunate that the (Arlington National Cemetery) employee and her professionalism has been unfairly attacked," an Army spokesperson said in a statement.</p>

<p>Going on the offensive, Trump's campaign co-manager Chris LaCivita has described the employee as a "despicable individual," while campaign spokesman Steven Cheung said she was "clearly suffering from a mental health episode."</p>

<p>Trump has made criticism of President Joe Biden's handling of the US retreat from Afghanistan a key note of his campaign ahead of the November election.</p>

<p>The withdrawal was made as part of a peace deal signed by the Trump administration with the Taliban.</p>

<p>Uproar over the incident at Arlington on Monday is the latest controversy in Trump's troubled relationship with the military.</p>

<p>While often touting his support for the armed forces, he privately mocked the war dead while president and did not want to be seen near military amputees, according to his former chief of staff.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/jov97jn8_arlington-cemetery-reuters_625x300_29_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump's team posted photos from the visit, including one showing him giving a thumbs-up. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/the-man-with-4-passports-telegram-ceo-pavel-durovs-international-network-6447484]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[The Man With 4 Passports: Pavel Durov's International Network]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/the-man-with-4-passports-telegram-ceo-pavel-durovs-international-network-6447484]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 29 Aug 2024 22:19:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The arrest and charging by France of Telegram founder Pavel Durov has thrown a spotlight on the international connections of a man with at least four passports and high-level contacts but who has also aroused the attention of security agencies around]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The arrest and charging by France of Telegram founder Pavel Durov has thrown a spotlight on the international connections of a man with at least four passports and high-level contacts but who has also aroused the attention of security agencies around the world.</p>

<p>Born in 1984 under the USSR into a family of academics in Leningrad, now known as Saint Petersburg, Durov spent his childhood in Italy before his family returned to Russia when the Soviet Union fell.</p>

<p>He stopped living in Russia a decade ago as he set up the Telegram messenger, picking up the citizenship of the Caribbean archipelago of Saint Kitts and Nevis as he sought a base.</p>

<p>Finally basing his company in Dubai, he was given Emirati citizenship in 2021 and in the same year, via a special procedure that remains shrouded in secrecy, French nationality.</p>

<p>Here AFP looks at Durov's key relationships with world powers.</p>

<h3><strong>Russia</strong></h3>

<p>Durov says he left Russia in 2014, accusing Kremlin allies of seizing ownership of his first social network, the Russian-language VKontakte, after he refused to hand over data of users involved in 2011-2012 protests in Russia and then 2013-2014 demonstrations in Ukraine.</p>

<p>He was regarded by many at the time as a dissident. The Russian authorities in later years sought to block Telegram but unsuccessfully, and the app is seen as a key tool for the military in the invasion of Ukraine.</p>

<p>Speaking to US right-wing talk show host Tucker Carlson in an interview in April, Durov said only people with "very limited knowledge of where Telegram came from" could claim it was an instrument of the Russian government.</p>

<p>But Moscow has in no way disowned Durov during his current legal problems, with Kremlin spokesman Dmitry Peskov warning France against turning the case into "political persecution".</p>

<p>According to the Vazhnye Istorii news site, citing leaked border data, his departure from Russia was anything but an abrupt exile and he visited the country more than 50 times between 2015 and 2021.</p>

<h3><strong>France</strong></h3>

<p>Media have repeatedly noted that Durov's reception when he was arrested on arrival at Paris Le Bourget airport Saturday was in stark contrast to previous visits.</p>

<p>Le Monde newspaper reported Wednesday that Durov had met President Emmanuel Macron on several occasions prior to receiving French nationality in 2021, via a special procedure reserved for those deemed to have made a special contribution to France.</p>

<p>A source close to the case, who asked not to be named, told AFP on Thursday that after his arrest Durov requested that French telecoms tycoon Xavier Niel, chairman and founder of the Iliad mobile operator and seen as close to Macron, be informed of his arrest.</p>

<p>Durov has said his name in his French passport is written as Paul du Rove, a humorous French translation. His personal Telegram channel is called "Du Rove's Channel".</p>

<p>Another source close to the investigation said Durov had emphasised his links to the French head of state during questioning.</p>

<p>Both Pavel Durov and his elder brother Nikolai, a lower-profile figure seen as the mathematical brain behind Telegram, have been wanted by France since March this year.</p>

<h3><strong>United Arab Emirates</strong></h3>

<p>Durov says he chose to base Telegram in Dubai after finding the UAE offered a far better business climate than European cities, allowing the company to hire the best people, enjoy a tax-efficient regime and the city's infrastructure.</p>

<p>"We tried several places. We first went to Berlin... We tried London, Singapore. San Francisco. You name it -- we have been everywhere," Durov told Carlson.</p>

<p>"The bureaucratic hurdles were too difficult to overcome," whereas the UAE "turned out to be a great place", he said, lauding the state as "a neutral place... not aligned geopolitically".</p>

<h3><strong>The United States</strong></h3>

<p>There is no indication Durov ever sought US citizenship but his interview with Carlson threw up some interesting -- if unconfirmed -- insights about his relationship with the country.</p>

<p>He said that at one point he thought San Francisco "would be the place for us" but he was then attacked by "three big guys" who tried to grab his phone while he was tweeting about meeting then Twitter chief Jack Dorsey.</p>

<p>Durov claimed to have come out the better in the altercation. "There was a short fight and a bit of blood involved."</p>

<p>He also said US security agencies gave him "too much attention" whenever he visited, complaining that two FBI agents would always meet him at the airport asking questions.Durov's international network</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/rk920a2o_pavel-durov_625x300_29_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/germany-to-impose-tougher-knife-laws-after-deadly-stabbing-attack-6447206]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Germany To Limit Support For Illegal Migrants After Knife Attack: Minister]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/germany-to-impose-tougher-knife-laws-after-deadly-stabbing-attack-6447206]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 29 Aug 2024 21:33:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[German Interior Minister Nancy Faeser said Thursday the government would toughen knife controls and limit the support given to some illegal migrants following a suspected Islamist stabbing.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>German Interior Minister Nancy Faeser said Thursday the government would toughen knife controls and limit the support given to some illegal migrants following a suspected Islamist stabbing.</p>

<p>Three people were killed and eight others injured at a festival in the western city of Solingen on Friday, in an attack allegedly carried out by a 26-year-old Syrian man with links to the Islamic State group.</p>

<p>The knife attack has inflamed the debate over immigration in Germany and put pressure on the government to act ahead of key regional elections on Sunday.</p>

<p>The stabbing has "shocked us deeply", Faeser said at a press conference on Thursday.</p>

<p>In response to the threat highlighted by the attack, the government is preparing "tough measures", Faeser said alongside Justice Minister Marco Buschmann.</p>

<p>Carrying knives at festivals, like the one in Solingen, as well as "sports events and other similar public events" will be banned, Faeser said.</p>

<p>There will be reasoned exceptions to the ban, including for those working in hospitality and performers, she added.</p>

<p>A ban will also be introduced on long-distance trains, the minister said, with police given more powers to search members of the public for knives.</p>

<p>Germany will also refuse benefits payments to migrants set to be deported to other countries in the European Union, Faeser announced.</p>

<p>The government will continue to work "intensively" to restart deportations to Afghanistan and Syria, which have been halted for years, she said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/irump6t_germany-festival-stabbing-victims_625x300_25_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Carrying knives at festivals will be banned,  German Interior Minister said. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/tourists-play-temple-run-in-cambodias-angkor-wat-temple-sparking-outrage-6447203]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Tourists Play Temple Run In Cambodia's Angkor Wat Temple, Sparking Outrage]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/tourists-play-temple-run-in-cambodias-angkor-wat-temple-sparking-outrage-6447203]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 29 Aug 2024 21:32:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The videos, shot at the UNESCO World Heritage site, have raised concerns about potential damage to the nearly 900-year-old temple structures and the disrespect of their spiritual and cultural significance.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A growing trend on social media has sparked concern among conservationists and historians as tourists film themselves reenacting the popular "Temple Run" video game at Cambodia's ancient temple. The temple run videos are being shot at the UNESCO World Heritage Site Angkor Wat, a Hindu-Buddhist temple in Siem Reap, Cambodia, which has received an influx of tourists reportedly disrespecting their religious structure by replicating a Temple Run mobile game experience that was very popular in 2011.</p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-08-22/tiktok-tourists-trample-on-angkor-wat-in-viral-temple-run-recreation"><em>Bloomberg,</em></a> TikTokers, Facebook users, and <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://youtube.com/shorts/w5dEBa9Sg_g?si=V_xaVvRx6IAJU0YN">YouTubers </a>are making videos of themselves running, jumping, and crashing through the historic Angkor Wat complex and other temple ruins as a mimic of what happens in the game. These short videos, set with fun sound effects, have gained widespread attention, with some clips receiving more than 2 million views.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="tl">When History Meets TikTok: Angkor Wat Edition <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/NoCoinsCollected?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#NoCoinsCollected</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/TempleRunners?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#TempleRunners</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/CambodiaGoneWild?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#CambodiaGoneWild</a> <a href="https://t.co/dntL8U7PvZ">pic.twitter.com/dntL8U7PvZ</a></p>
— Ottster Gaming (@OttsterG) <a href="https://twitter.com/OttsterG/status/1829118046398550314?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 29, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>However, experts caution that such stunts might seriously damage the structures, which are nearly 900 years old. Conservationists are afraid that in the gambit for viral content, sacred sites are being disrespected and cause a serious threat to the preservation of ancient cultural treasures. The trend continues to rise because new videos pop up every day.</p>

<p><iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="315" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/G921t4GjUak?si=v3tizWdHuBEkyIeW" title="YouTube video player" width="560"></iframe></p>

<p>"It's not just potential damage to the stones by people bumping into them and falling or knocking things over-which is real," conservation consultant Simon Warrack told Bloomberg, "but it's also damage to the spiritual and cultural value of the temples."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/61i6jcug_angkor-wat_625x300_29_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The trend continues to gain popularity, with new videos emerging daily.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/stealth-disease-claims-four-lives-in-milan-origin-remains-a-mystery-6446846]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Stealth Disease Claims Four Lives In Milan, Origin Remains A Mystery]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/stealth-disease-claims-four-lives-in-milan-origin-remains-a-mystery-6446846]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 29 Aug 2024 20:48:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An outbreak of Legionnaires' disease in Milan has resulted in four deaths and numerous hospitalizations. Authorities are disinfecting the city's water supply while investigations continue to identify the source of the infection.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A recent outbreak of Legionnaires' disease in Milan, Italy, has killed at least four people and hospitalised several dozen more, according to <em>The Metro</em>. The health authorities say that at least 53 cases have been confirmed in two regions inside the Milan metropolitan area of a severe lung infection.</p>

<p>In response, local authorities are taking urgent measures to control the situation, including deploying chemicals to disinfect the city's water supply. However, despite extensive testing of water supply systems in private residences and cooling towers, the exact source of the outbreak remains unidentified, according to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://metro.co.uk/2024/08/26/no-one-knows-source-stealth-disease-killed-four-milan-21492952/"><em>news report.</em></a></p>

<p>The continuous investigation of finding the source of infection has left the city in great suspense, and sensitivity has developed regarding what efforts should be present to prevent further cases.</p>

<p><strong>What is Legionnaires' disease?</strong></p>

<p>According to a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/wellness/2024/08/13/legionnaires-disease-symptoms-cause-treatment/"><em>Washington Post report,</em></a> Legionnaires' is a serious form of pneumonia caused by the bacteria Legionella. The pathogen can also cause Pontiac fever, a flu-like illness considered to be a less serious disease.</p>

<p>The bacteria was first discovered decades ago when a mysterious illness sickened dozens attending a 1976 convention of the American Legion in Philadelphia. In that outbreak, 221 people were infected, and 34 died.</p>

<p>The disease initially alarmed health officials, who feared the sickness might spread beyond the conferencegoers. Ultimately, scientists found the bacteria bred in the water of a cooling tower of the air-conditioning system at the Bellevue-Stratford Hotel, where the conference was being held.</p>

<p><strong>How does Legionnaires' disease spread?</strong></p>

<p>Legionella grow in biofilms lining water pipes, pipes that lead to showers, drinking faucets, and HVAC systems for cooling, said Panagis Galiatsatos, an associate professor of medicine in pulmonary and critical care medicine at the Sidney Kimmel Comprehensive Cancer Centre at Johns Hopkins University.</p>

<p>Legionella can even grow in the tanks that hold windscreen wiper fluid in a car, according to the Centres for Disease Control and Prevention.</p>

<p>People can become infected by breathing in mist or swallowing water into the lungs that's contaminated with the bacteria. "Less commonly, people can get sick by aspiration of drinking water containing Legionella," a CDC spokeswoman said Tuesday.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/5itm4vjo_legionnaires-disease_625x300_29_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Legionnaires' disease, a serious pneumonia caused by the Legionella bacteria.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/why-telegram-ceo-pavel-durovs-arrest-raises-red-flags-for-tech-bosses-6446750]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Why Telegram CEO Pavel Durov's Arrest Raises 'Red Flags' For Tech Bosses]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/why-telegram-ceo-pavel-durovs-arrest-raises-red-flags-for-tech-bosses-6446750]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 29 Aug 2024 20:33:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Now that France has charged Telegram's founder with failing to stop illegal activity on his platform, other tech bosses may have reason to weigh the wisdom of jetting into Europe themselves.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Now that France has charged Telegram's founder with failing to stop illegal activity on his platform, other tech bosses may have reason to weigh the wisdom of jetting into Europe themselves.</p>

<p>Russia-born Pavel Durov is accused of "complicity" in running an online platform that allowed illicit transactions, child sex abuse images and other illegal content.</p>

<p>French lawyers told AFP it was "unprecedented" for an individual to be held criminally liable for what users chose to do on a tech platform.</p>

<p>Chat apps like Telegram -- which boasts having more than 900 million users -- were almost certainly hosting illegal content whether the bosses knew it or not, experts told AFP.</p>

<p>"It's clear that if they take this case against Pavel Durov all the way, any other platform could be threatened with the same thing," lawyer Guillaume Martine told AFP.</p>

<p>However, the idea of X owner Elon Musk or Mark Zuckerberg, whose Meta group includes Facebook and WhatsApp, being arrested in Europe remained beyond the realms of likelihood.</p>

<p>"I would be very surprised if any EU member state, including France, arrested Elon Musk under similar charges," Jan Penfrat of the European Digital Rights (EDRi) advocacy group told AFP.</p>

<p>"But then again, I was also surprised that they arrested Durov."</p>

<h3><strong>'Limited cooperation'</strong></h3>

<p>Although comparing these platforms is superficially appealing -- like its competitors, Telegram is not based in France, and Durov is an ally of Musk -- there are key differences.</p>

<p>For one, Durov is a French citizen, making him a much likelier target in France.</p>

<p>But also, although Musk trumpets an extreme free-speech position, he generally complies with government takedown orders on X, the social platform formerly known as Twitter.</p>

<p>Telegram, however, refuses on principle.</p>

<p>"It's true that Telegram is characterised by extremely limited cooperation, if any at all," said digital rights lawyer Alexandre Lazaregue.</p>

<p>"They don't respond to letters, they don't respond to summonses, they don't even have legal representation in court... Whereas Facebook, Twitter, etc still have well-known lawyers in Paris."</p>

<p>And Penfrat said comparisons with services like Signal or WhatsApp were also misleading as they are encrypted by default -- unlike Telegram.</p>

<p>"So Signal and WhatsApp can say: 'We're cooperating, we just don't have the information,'" he said.</p>

<p>"But Telegram says: 'Well, we could give you all that information because it's in plain text on our servers, but we're not going to, sorry.'"</p>

<h3><strong>'Red flags'</strong></h3>

<p>The particular position of Durov and Telegram suggests other tech bosses do not have anything immediately to worry about.</p>

<p>But Penfrat said he was concerned that the move against Telegram could be used as a precedent to go after other encrypted services.</p>

<p>Law enforcement agencies across the world have long argued they need access to encrypted messages to stop criminal activity.</p>

<p>But services like WhatsApp and Signal have pushed back, saying the only way to do that would be to outlaw encryption.</p>

<p>"It does raise a lot of red flags to see these charges, which seem random and also are just not very convincing," said Penfrat, suggesting it was like trying to blame a knife-maker for a stabbing.</p>

<p>Lawyer Martine said it was "extremely dangerous" to try to hold Telegram accountable for the actions of its users, likening it to prosecuting Europcar for renting a vehicle to a drug trafficker.</p>

<p>Lazaregue concluded that the charges against Durov were pushing the legal definition of "complicity" to breaking point.</p>

<p>"To be convicted of complicity, you still need to be aware that a crime is happening and intend to participate in it," he said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/rk920a2o_pavel-durov_625x300_29_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[For one, Durov is a French citizen, making him a much likelier target in France]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukrainian-f-16-jet-destroyed-in-crash-report-6446690]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ukrainian F-16 Jet Destroyed In Crash: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukrainian-f-16-jet-destroyed-in-crash-report-6446690]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 29 Aug 2024 20:23:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Ukrainian F-16 jet was destroyed in a crash on Monday, the Wall Street Journal reported citing a U.S. official.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Ukrainian F-16 fighter jet was destroyed in a crash on Monday, a U.S. defense official told Reuters.</p>

<p>According to the official, the crash did not appear to be the result of Russian fire. It was still to be determined what caused the incident - pilot error or mechanical failure.</p>

<p>Russia staged a "massive" missile and drone attack on Ukraine on Monday, Ukraine's Air Force commander said, which was followed by another major strike on Tuesday.</p>

<p>President Volodymyr Zelenskiy said on Tuesday that F-16 jets were used to repel the attack on Monday and showed good results.</p>

<p>Ukraine's Air Force had no immediate comment.</p>

<p>Zelenskiy announced on Aug. 5 that Ukraine had started flying F-16s for operations within the country, confirming the long-awaited arrival of the U.S.-made fighter jets nearly 2-1/2 years after Russia's full-scale invasion.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/5svqebb_f16-jet_625x300_29_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A Ukrainian Air Forces F-16 fighting aircraft on the ground, amid Russia's attack on Ukraine (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/floods-in-nigeria-kill-at-least-179-displace-around-200-000-6446682]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Floods In Nigeria Kill At Least 179, Displace Around 200,000]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/floods-in-nigeria-kill-at-least-179-displace-around-200-000-6446682]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 29 Aug 2024 20:21:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Floods have killed at least 179 people and displaced around 200,000 more in parts of Nigeria after a "few weeks" of intense rain, an emergency official said on Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Floods have killed at least 179 people and displaced around 200,000 more in parts of Nigeria after a "few weeks" of intense rain, an emergency official said on Thursday.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Most of the serious flooding has been in the north of Nigeria so far. At least 107,600 hectares (265,885 acres) of farmlands have also been affected, figures published by the National Emergency Management Agency (NEMA) showed.</p>

<p>Most of the deaths were in the country's northern region, but NEMA spokesman Ezekiel Manzo said the central and southern parts of Nigeria may be hit harder as rain intensifies.</p>

<p>He did not say exactly when the deaths and displacements had occurred.</p>

<p>"The collection of water from the northern part flowing downward will also mean that the situation being witnessed the same in central and southern parts of the country will become worse," Manzo told AFP.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Communities along the banks of major rivers Niger and Benue are at higher risk. Some parts of the country previously not known to be flood-prone have seen floods, Manzo said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Flooding, usually caused by abundant rains and poor infrastructure, has caused large-scale destruction in Africa's most populous country in the past.&nbsp;</p>

<p>More than 360 people died and more than 2.1 million were displaced in 2012.</p>

<p>In 2022, more than 500 people died and 1.4 million were displaced in the worst floods in a decade.&nbsp;</p>

<p>President Bola Ahmed Tinubu said in a statement on Wednesday that authorities would provide warnings to mitigate the impact of environmental mishaps.</p>

<p>Manzo said emergency officials have mapped out plans to forestall a recurrence.</p>

<p>"We don't have time to waste any longer so people will not be caught unaware," he told AFP.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/kijgbd4g_flashflood-generic_625x300_08_August_18.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[In 2012, more than 2.1 million people were displaced due to floods in Nigeria. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-bans-2-hezbollah-hamas-financiers-from-entering-country-6446533]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK Bans 2 Hezbollah, Hamas Financiers From Entering Country]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-bans-2-hezbollah-hamas-financiers-from-entering-country-6446533]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 29 Aug 2024 20:00:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The British government said on Thursday it had imposed a travel ban on Mustafa Ayash, who it sanctioned earlier this year for promoting terrorism, and suspected Hezbollah financier Nazem Ahmad.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The British government said on Thursday it had imposed a travel ban on Mustafa Ayash, who it sanctioned earlier this year for promoting terrorism, and suspected Hezbollah financier Nazem Ahmad.</p>

<p>The pair, who were already subject to asset freezes under domestic counter-terrorism powers, now cannot enter Britain, it said.</p>

<p>"The travel bans are a part of continued efforts to protect the integrity of the UK economy from terrorist financing threats," the British government said in a statement.</p>

<p>Ayash was sanctioned in March this year for providing financial support to a media network which the government said supported the Palestinian Hamas militant group and promotes terrorism.</p>

<p>Britain banned Hamas in 2021 and under the Terrorism Act, anyone expressing support for the group, flying its flag or arranging meetings for the organisation is in breach of the law.</p>

<p>Britain sanctioned Ahmad in April 2023 on suspicion of financing Lebanon's Iran-backed Hezbollah movement. He was also sanctioned by the US in 2019.</p>

<p>He has an extensive art collection in the UK and conducts business with multiple UK-based artists, art galleries and auction houses, according to a 2023 statement by the British government.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/b1hg4pfo_london_625x300_24_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Britain banned Hamas in 2021 and under the its Terrorism Act. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/britain-urges-citizens-to-leave-lebanon-amid-border-tensions-with-israel-6446108]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK Urges Citizens to Leave Lebanon Amid Border Tensions With Israel]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/britain-urges-citizens-to-leave-lebanon-amid-border-tensions-with-israel-6446108]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 29 Aug 2024 19:05:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Britain on Tuesday urged its citizens in Lebanon to leave the country, warning that tensions along the Israeli border could worsen quickly.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Britain on Tuesday urged its citizens in Lebanon to leave the country, warning that tensions along the Israeli border could worsen quickly.</p>

<p>"There are frequent artillery exchanges and air strikes, tensions are high, and the situation could deteriorate rapidly," Foreign Secretary David Lammy told parliament.</p>

<p>"I am working with foreign office consular teams to make sure we are prepared for all scenarios, but if this conflict escalates, the government cannot guarantee we will be able to evacuate everyone immediately. People may be forced to shelter in place."</p>

<p>British Prime Minister Keir Starmer chaired a meeting of the government's emergency response committee, known as COBRA, on the matter earlier on Tuesday, Lammy said.</p>

<p>"My message to British nationals in Lebanon is therefore quite simple: leave," Lammy said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/m82ddhoo_israel-hezbollah_625x300_23_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Frequent artillery exchanges and air strikes cause UK to suspect the situation might deteriorate. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/name-legal-representative-for-x-or-face-suspension-brazil-top-court-to-musk-6446066]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Name Representative For X Or Face Suspension: Brazil Top Court To Musk]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/name-legal-representative-for-x-or-face-suspension-brazil-top-court-to-musk-6446066]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 29 Aug 2024 19:00:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Brazilian Supreme Court justice on Wednesday ordered billionaire Elon Musk to name a legal representative for his messaging platform X in Brazil within 24 hours or face the site's suspension in the country.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Brazilian Supreme Court justice on Wednesday ordered billionaire Elon Musk to name a legal representative for his messaging platform X in Brazil within 24 hours or face the site's suspension in the country.</p>

<p>Earlier this month, X announced it would close its operations and fire its staff in Brazil due to what it called "censorship orders" from the judge, Alexandre de Moraes. Its service would remain available for users in Brazil, it said.</p>

<p>X, at the time, claimed Moraes secretly threatened one of the company's legal representatives in Brazil with arrest if it did not comply with legal orders to take down some content from its platform.</p>

<p>In Wednesday's ruling, Moraes says that under the country's law regulating internet issues, companies that do not respect Brazilian legislation or the confidentiality of private information could have their activities temporarily suspended.</p>

<p>The Supreme Court posted a screenshot of Wednesday's court decision on its X account, tagging Musk's and X's Global Government Affairs accounts.</p>

<p>Hours after the judge's decision, Musk said on X that Moraes "has repeatedly broken the laws he has sworn to uphold".</p>

<p>Earlier this year, Moraes ordered X to block certain accounts implicated on investigations of so-called "digital militias" that have been accused of spreading fake news and hate messages during the government of far-right former President Jair Bolsonaro.</p>

<p>After Musk challenged that decision and said he would reactivate accounts on X that the judge had ordered blocked, Moraes opened an inquiry into the billionaire in early April.</p>

<p>X representatives eventually reversed course and told the Supreme Court that the social media giant would obey the legal rulings. In April, however, Moraes asked X to explain why it allegedly had not fully complied with his decisions.</p>

<p>In response, lawyers representing X in Brazil told the Supreme Court that "operational faults" had allowed users who were ordered blocked to stay active on the social media platform.</p>

<p>Musk has called the Moraes' decisions regarding X "unconstitutional".</p>

<p>Topics such as "Twitter will end", "Elon Musk" and "Alexandre de Moraes" were trending on X in Brazil on Thursday, with hundreds of thousands of posts. Public reaction included mostly "memes" making light of the situation.</p>

<p>Among more serious reactions, some X users shared harsh criticism over Moraes' decisions, saying he was harming freedom of speech in Brazil. On the other hand, other users sided with Moraes, saying Musk should not be above Brazilian law.</p>

<p>X, formerly Twitter, is widely used in Brazil, and is an important means of communication for politicians especially.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/l4qn72h8_brazil-supreme-court_625x300_29_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Supreme Court posted a screenshot of court decision on its X account (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/out-on-bail-telegram-ceo-pavel-durov-banned-from-leaving-france-6446033]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Out On Bail, Telegram CEO Pavel Durov Banned From Leaving France]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/out-on-bail-telegram-ceo-pavel-durov-banned-from-leaving-france-6446033]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 29 Aug 2024 18:58:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Telegram chief Pavel Durov was spending Thursday out on bail after four days of detention in France, banned from leaving the country as he faces a possible trial related to illegal content carried on his messaging app.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Telegram chief Pavel Durov was spending Thursday out on bail after four days of detention in France, banned from leaving the country as he faces a possible trial related to illegal content carried on his messaging app.</p>

<p>Russian-born Durov, dressed in black and wearing dark glasses, walked briskly out of the Paris court house late Wednesday into a waiting car after being charged but allowed to go free under judicial supervision.</p>

<p>He thanked his laywer and was rapidly ushered into the vehicle by a burly man appearing to be a bodyguard, video posted on social media channels showed.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/france-charges-telegram-chief-pavel-durov-prosecutor-6440551" target="_blank">Durov</a>, 39, was charged on several counts of failing to curb extremist and illegal content on the popular messaging app which now has over 900 million followers but has become increasingly controversial.</p>

<p>His lawyer David-Olivier Kaminski said it was "absurd" to suggest Durov could be implicated in any crime committed on the app, adding: "Telegram complies in all respects with European rules concerning digital technology."</p>

<p>In Moscow, Kremlin spokesman Dmitry Peskov warned France against turning the case into <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kremlin-warns-france-against-political-persecution-of-telegram-founder-pavel-durov-6444991" target="_blank">"political persecution"</a>, emphasising he is a "Russian citizen" and "we will be watching what happens next."</p>

<p>Among those also voicing support for Durov is fellow tech tycoon and chief executive of X, Elon Musk, who has posted comments under the hashtag #FreePavel.</p>

<p>After the charges, Musk posted a meme on X of a surveillance camera attached to buildings inscribed with France's motto, "liberty, equality, fraternity."</p>

<h3><strong>Near total absence</strong></h3>

<p>Durov was arrested at Le Bourget airport outside Paris late Saturday and questioned in subsequent days by investigators.</p>

<p>He was granted conditional release on a bail of <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/video/telegram-ceo-pavel-durov-s-5-million-bail-but-with-conditions-831241" target="_blank">five million euros</a> and on the condition he must report to a police station twice a week as well as remaining in France, Paris prosecutor Laure Beccuau said in a statement.</p>

<p>The charges concern alleged crimes involving an organised group, including "complicity in the administration of an online platform to enable an illicit transaction".</p>

<p>This charge alone could see him jailed for up to 10 years and fined 500,000 euros if convicted.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pavel-durov-mysterious-and-controversial-telegram-founder-6441269" target="_blank">Durov </a>has also been charged with refusing to share documents demanded by authorities as well as "dissemination in an organised group of images of minors in child pornography" as well as drug trafficking, fraud and money laundering.</p>

<p>The Paris prosecutor said the French judicial authorities had been made aware of the "near total absence of a response" from Telegram to requests from the authorities and had first opened an investigation in February 2024.</p>

<p>The next step will be for the case to be sent to trial.</p>

<p>Separately, Durov is also being investigated on suspicion of "serious acts of violence" towards one of his children while he and an ex-partner, the boy's mother, were in <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/video/explained-why-telegram-ceo-was-arrested-in-france-831224" target="_blank">Paris</a>, a source said. She filed a criminal complaint against Durov in Switzerland last year.</p>

<p>The tech mogul founded Telegram as he was in the process of quitting his native Russia a decade ago following a dispute with authorities related to ownership of his first project, the Russian-language social network VKontakte.</p>

<p>An enigmatic figure who rarely speaks in public, Durov is a citizen of Russia, France and the United Arab Emirates, where Telegram is based.</p>

<p>Forbes magazine estimates his current fortune at <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/feature/mysterious-woman-linked-to-arrest-of-telegram-ceo-called-mossad-agent-all-about-juli-vavilova-6420329" target="_blank">$15.5 billion</a>, though he proudly promotes the virtues of an ascetic life that includes ice baths and not drinking alcohol or coffee.</p>

<h3><strong>Special procedure</strong></h3>

<p>Numerous questions have been raised about the timing and circumstances of Durov's detention, with supporters seeing him as a freedom of speech champion while his detractors paint him as a menace who wilfully allowed Telegram to get out of control.</p>

<p>Le Monde newspaper reported Wednesday that Durov had met President Emmanuel Macron on several occasions prior to receiving French nationality in 2021, via a special procedure reserved for those deemed to have made a special contribution to France.</p>

<p>The Wall Street Journal added that at one lunch in 2018, Macron -- who along with his team was in the past an avid user of Telegram -- had suggested it should be headquartered in Paris, but Durov refused.</p>

<p>According to a source, both Pavel Durov and his elder brother Nikolai, a lower-profile figure seen as the mathematical brain behind Telegram, have been wanted by France since March this year.</p>

<p>Durov's departure from Russia was reportedly not an abrupt exile: according to the Vazhnye Istorii news site, citing <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/telegram-ceo-pavel-durov-allowed-child-pornography-drug-trafficking-on-app-rules-france-court-6441623" target="_blank">leaked</a> border data, he visited the country more than 50 times between 2015 and 2021, adding to questions about his relationship with the Russian authorities.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, a UAE government official said it "prioritises the welfare of its citizens" and was "in touch with the French authorities about this case."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/g6g94rr_pavel-durov_625x300_29_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Pavel Durov was granted conditional release on a bail of five million euros (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-race-2024-kamala-harris-unveils-50-million-fearless-ad-campaign-against-trump-6445673]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris Unveils $50 Million "Fearless" Ad Campaign Against Trump]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-race-2024-kamala-harris-unveils-50-million-fearless-ad-campaign-against-trump-6445673]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 29 Aug 2024 18:12:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Democratic presidential candidate Kamala Harris launched a $50 million advertising blitz on Tuesday, capitalizing on the momentum of a fledgling campaign against Republican rival Donald Trump with a one-minute spot titled "Fearless."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Democratic presidential candidate Kamala Harris launched a $50 million advertising blitz on Tuesday, capitalizing on the momentum of a fledgling campaign against Republican rival Donald Trump with a one-minute spot titled "Fearless."</p>

<p>It was Harris' first big ad buy since consolidating support for the Democratic nomination after President Joe Biden dropped out of the race on July 21 and endorsed her.</p>

<p>In addition to garnering the backing of big-money donors, Harris has sparked newfound energy among groups such as young voters that <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-2024-joe-biden-wins-huge-ovation-at-democratic-convention-farewell-6375158" target="_blank">Biden</a> had been struggling to win over.</p>

<p>Public opinion polls in the last week have shown Harris, 59, closing the gap with 78-year-old Trump, who still leads in some national surveys.</p>

<p>The ads will be rolled out on television as well as streaming and social channels across election battleground states in the weeks before the Democratic National Convention that starts on Aug. 19.</p>

<p>The first ad in the campaign begins with images of Harris as a little girl and follows her progression to a prosecutor, attorney general and <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/vice-president-tim-walz-pick-set-to-star-on-day-3-of-democratic-convention-6388689" target="_blank">U.S. vice president</a>. "The one thing Kamala Harris has always been: fearless," the ad says.</p>

<p>Since stepping into her new role, Harris has focused on Trump's felony convictions in a hush-money trial involving a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-stormy-daniels-porn-star-at-center-of-donald-trumps-criminal-conviction-5783027" target="_blank">porn star</a> and the other criminal charges he faces, and portrayed him as responsible for a wave of anti-abortion measures in Republican-led states around the country.</p>

<p>The Harris campaign's ad buy dwarfed the $10 million advertising buy announced by <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-campaign-staff-had-physical-altercation-with-army-cemetery-official-report-6437702" target="_blank">Trump's</a> campaign on Monday, to be launched in six battleground states this week as it tries to counter a surge of voter enthusiasm and donations for Harris.</p>

<p>That was Trump's biggest ad buy since January.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/qp4pb238_kamala-harris-afp-_625x300_23_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The First ad in campaign shows images of Kamala Harris as a little girl following her progression (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/spanish-actors-son-jailed-for-life-for-brutal-murder-of-plastic-surgeon-6445512]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Spanish Actor's Son Jailed For Life For Brutal Murder Of Plastic Surgeon]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/spanish-actors-son-jailed-for-life-for-brutal-murder-of-plastic-surgeon-6445512]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 29 Aug 2024 17:50:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Sancho was found guilty of premeditated murder, concealing a corpse, and destroying property.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The son of a well-known Spanish actor has been sentenced to life imprisonment for killing and dismembering a man on the Thai island of Koh Phangan last year. Daniel Sancho Bronchalo, the son of television star Rodolfo Sancho Aguirre, claimed he acted in self-defence when he killed Colombian plastic surgeon Edwin Arrieta Arteaga. He pleaded guilty to the murder in August 2023, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cwyxry3k9rgo" rel="nofollow, noindex"><em>BBC </em></a>reported.</p>

<p>Sancho, now 30, told the Spanish news agency EFE at the time that he had been a "hostage" to Arrieta, whom he described as obsessed with him. The case has attracted significant attention in Spain, with many journalists travelling to Thailand to cover the trial.</p>

<p>Sancho was found guilty of premeditated murder, concealing a corpse, and destroying property.</p>

<p>A court on the nearby island of Koh Samui, where the trial took place, initially sentenced him to death for murder. However, this was reduced to life imprisonment due to his cooperation during the trial.</p>

<p>Sancho, a chef with his own YouTube channel, was also ordered to pay 4 million baht ($118,000) to compensate Arrieta's family. Bussakorn Kaewleeled, the victim's family lawyer, expressed satisfaction with the verdict.</p>

<p>"The plaintiff is satisfied with the sentence because he (Sancho) will be put in prison for life and they (the plaintiff) receive some financial compensation," Bussakorn told reporters outside the Koh Samui court, as reported by AFP news agency.</p>

<p>Police found parts of Arrieta's body at a landfill in Koh Phangan in early August last year.</p>

<p>Around that time, Sancho reported to the police that Arrieta, then 44, was missing. After further questioning, Sancho confessed to the murder.</p>

<p>Thai media reported that investigations had shown Sancho had purchased a knife, rubber gloves, and a bottle of cleaning agent, leading police to conclude the murder was premeditated.</p>

<p>Sancho later led police to seven locations around the island where he had disposed of Arrieta's dismembered body in plastic bags.</p>

<p>Reports stated that Sancho and Arrieta had agreed to meet after becoming acquainted online.</p>

<p>The defence argued that Sancho acted in self-defence when Arrieta tried to force him into a sexual encounter. In a statement published by the Spanish newspaper El Mundo, Sancho said the plastic surgeon "tried to rape [him]."</p>

<p>Sancho comes from a family of actors; his mother is actress Silvia Bronchalo, and his grandfather was the late actor Felix Angel Sancho Gracia.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/kgggoac8_daniel-sancho-bronchalo_625x300_29_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sancho, a chef with his own YouTube channel, was also ordered to pay 4 million baht]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hong-kong-outlet-stand-news-and-editors-convicted-of-sedition-judge-rules-6445341]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hong Kong Pro-Democracy News Outlet, Editors Found Guilty Of Sedition]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hong-kong-outlet-stand-news-and-editors-convicted-of-sedition-judge-rules-6445341]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 29 Aug 2024 17:29:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hong Kong pro-democracy news outlet Stand News and its two former chief editors were found guilty of sedition on Thursday, the first conviction of its kind since the city came under Chinese rule in 1997.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hong Kong pro-democracy news outlet Stand News and its two former chief editors were found guilty of sedition on Thursday, the first conviction of its kind since the city came under Chinese rule in 1997.</p>

<p>The verdict is part of a crackdown on free speech in the former British colony that has seen critics of China jailed or forced into exile, following huge pro-democracy protests in 2019.</p>

<p>Editors Chung Pui-kuen, 54, and Patrick Lam, 36, are the first journalists to be convicted of sedition since Britain handed Hong Kong over to China in 1997, and the ruling drew resounding international condemnation.</p>

<p>Chung and Lam were in charge of Stand News, a Chinese-language website that gained a massive following during the protests in 2019, before it was raided and shut down in December 2021.</p>

<p>On Thursday, district court judge Kwok Wai-kin said the pair were guilty of "conspiracy to publish and reproduce seditious publications". The parent company of Stand News, Best Pencil Limited, was also found guilty.</p>

<p>"The line (Stand News) took was to support and promote Hong Kong local autonomy," according to a written judgement by Kwok.</p>

<p>"It even became a tool to smear and vilify the Central Authorities (Beijing) and the (Hong Kong) SAR Government."</p>

<p>Kwok also pointed to 11 articles published by Stand News that "caused potential detrimental consequences to national security" and had the intention of "seriously undermining" authorities in Beijing and Hong Kong.</p>

<p>Lam was absent from court on Thursday due to illness.</p>

<p>The judge granted the duo bail before their sentencing on September 26.</p>

<h3><strong>Colonial-era law</strong></h3>

<p>Chung and Lam were charged under a colonial-era law, which punishes sedition with a maximum jail term of two years.</p>

<p>A recent security law enacted in March raised the jail term for sedition to seven years.</p>

<p>In response to the verdict, the European Union called on Hong Kong to "stop prosecuting journalists".</p>

<p>"The ruling risks inhibiting the pluralistic exchange of ideas and the free flow of information, both cornerstones of the economic success of Hong Kong," a EU spokesperson said.</p>

<p>Speaking outside court, police chief superintendent Steve Li said the verdict "clearly illustrated the necessity and lawfulness" of the enforcement actions in 2021 against Stand News.</p>

<p>Asked if the verdict would further affect press freedom, Li said it would "actually help".</p>

<p>"It would let everyone know what kind of problems could risk breaching the law," he said.</p>

<h3><strong>Not seditious</strong></h3>

<p>But Beh Lih Yi from the Committee to Protect Journalists said the ruling showed that Hong Kong was "descending further into authoritarianism".</p>

<p>"Journalism is not seditious," she said.</p>

<p>Sarah Brooks, Amnesty International's China Director, called the verdict "one more nail in the coffin for press freedom in Hong Kong".</p>

<p>Hong Kong has seen its standing in global press freedom rankings plummet in recent years.</p>

<p>Chung had testified that the outlet was a platform for free speech and defended his decisions to publish articles critical of the government.</p>

<p>But prosecutors accused them of bringing "hatred or contempt" to the Chinese and Hong Kong governments.</p>

<p>More than 100 people, including supporters and media professionals, queued up for spots in the public gallery on Thursday morning.</p>

<p>The verdict was also attended by representatives from various consulates -- including the United States, Britain, France, European Union, and Australia.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/565lduf_hong-kong_625x300_29_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The parent company of Stand News, Best Pencil Limited, was also found guilty (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/oscar-winner-errol-morris-blasts-donald-trumps-inhumane-treatment-of-migrant-children-6445238]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Oscar-Winner Blasts Trump's "Mean, Inhumane" Treatment Of Migrant Children]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/oscar-winner-errol-morris-blasts-donald-trumps-inhumane-treatment-of-migrant-children-6445238]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 29 Aug 2024 17:14:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Film legend Errol Morris said the separation of thousands of migrant children from their parents by Donald Trump's US administration was "inhumane and cruel" as his new documentary about the policy premiered at the Venice Film Festival Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Film legend Errol Morris said the separation of thousands of migrant children from their parents by Donald Trump's US administration was "inhumane and cruel" as his new documentary about the policy premiered at the Venice Film Festival Thursday.</p>

<p>"Do we need borders? Do we need immigration law? We do," the Oscar-winning US director told AFP ahead of the screening of his film "Separated". "But the idea is laws should be fair and humane."</p>

<p>"And this particular policy struck me, still strikes me, as inhumane, as cruel as mean."</p>

<p>In 2017, during Donald Trump's first year as US president, his administration raised the idea of separating children from their parents as a way to deter illegal immigration -- a key plank of his campaign.</p>

<p>Officially launched in April 2018, the "zero-tolerance" policy allowed criminal proceedings to be brought against anyone who crossed the US-Mexico border illegally, resulting in parents being immediately taken into custody without their children.</p>

<p>According to the documentary, which cited official government figures, at least 4,227 children were taken from their parents -- and more than 1,000 are still separated.</p>

<p>"What horrifies me is that they didn't keep records. They separated families in such a way that it might be impossible ever to reunite them," said Morris, 76.</p>

<p>The veteran director won an Oscar in 2004 for "The Fog of War", an astonishingly frank account of the Vietnam War by one of its architects, former US Secretary of defence Robert McNamara.</p>

<h3><strong>Divisive</strong></h3>

<p>Morris's new film -- being shown out of competition in Venice -- is based on a book by US journalist Jacob Soboroff, who helped expose the desperate plight of the children.</p>

<p>"He had called me and asked me if I knew anybody who might be willing to turn his book into a movie... I volunteered myself," Morris said.</p>

<p>The documentary is largely based on statements by Jonathan White, who was deputy director of the US Office for Refugee Resettlement (ORR) at the time and who opposed the policy applied by his superior, Scott Lloyd, who is also interviewed.</p>

<p>Lawsuits and a public outcry, even among Trump's own Republican Party, forced the administration by mid-2018 to halt the separations.</p>

<p>In practice, however, the Trump administration continued to separate families under another regulation which allowed undocumented parents to be arrested and deported if they had committed a serious crime.</p>

<p>Immigration remains a hugely divisive issue for many Americans ahead of November's presidential election, in which Trump is running against Vice President Kamala Harris.</p>

<p>A recent official US report found the government may have lost track of up to 32,000 unaccompanied migrant children in the past four years.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/avicfb7_us-camp-mexico-chiapas_625x300_29_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[They didn't keep records, and separated families in a way that made reuniting them impossible. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/massive-sinkhole-opens-up-on-seoul-road-swallows-suv-with-2-people-inside-6445148]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Massive Sinkhole Opens Up In Seoul, Swallows SUV With 2 People Inside]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/massive-sinkhole-opens-up-on-seoul-road-swallows-suv-with-2-people-inside-6445148]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 29 Aug 2024 17:03:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Dramatic photos from the scene revealed a white sport utility vehicle almost entirely swallowed by a massive sinkhole.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A sudden sinkhole appeared on a busy road in western Seoul's Seodaemun district on Thursday, swallowing an SUV, with two passengers inside. The vehicle, carrying a woman in her 70s and a man in his 80s, rolled over and crashed into the sinkhole, leaving both injured. The couple's white Tivoli "rolled over sideways, crashing into the sinkhole", the <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://m.koreaherald.com/view.php?ud=20240829050448" rel="nofollow, noindex">Korea Herald</a></em>&nbsp;reported. Both sustained serious injuries and were promptly transported to a hospital. The unexpected sinkhole caused chaos on the roads, leading to severe traffic congestion.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Dramatic photos from the scene revealed a white sport utility vehicle almost entirely swallowed by a massive sinkhole that unexpectedly opened on the road.&nbsp;No one else was hurt in the incident, which occurred at around 11:20 am (0220 GMT), according to Seoul's Seodaemun district fire station,&nbsp;<em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://news.sky.com/story/seoul-elderly-couple-injured-after-their-car-falls-into-sinkhole-13205224" rel="nofollow, noindex">Sky News</a></em> reported.</p>

<p><strong>See the pictures here:</strong></p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="in">Sinkhole in Seoul <a href="https://t.co/JpxNi72NMO">pic.twitter.com/JpxNi72NMO</a></p>
— @ (@anthraxxx781) <a href="https://twitter.com/anthraxxx781/status/1829045090649874926?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 29, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Authorities later cordoned off the area, restricting access as they launched an investigation into the cause of the sinkhole.</p>

<p>Sinkholes are a recurring issue in South Korea, with at least 879 reported cases between 2019 and June 2023, according to the Ministry of Land, Infrastructure and Transport. The ministry attributed nearly half of these incidents to damaged sewer pipes.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Recently, a 48-year-old <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/indians-abroad/andhra-woman-swept-away-in-malaysia-sewage-drain-after-footpath-collapses-6414411">Indian tourist fell into a sinkhole</a> in Kuala Lumpur.&nbsp;The woman, identified as Vijayalakshmi from Chittoor district's &nbsp;Animiganipalle village, was reportedly walking along a footpath when the ground collapsed. While her husband and son managed to escape the collapse, she was swept into the underground sewer.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Rescue operations were launched immediately by the civic authorities in Kuala Lumpur and are ongoing.&nbsp;Vijayalakshmi was known for frequently travelling to Malaysia and Singapore as part of her business.&nbsp;In response to the incident, Andhra Pradesh Chief Minister N Chandrababu Naidu has directed officials from the Andhra Pradesh Non-Resident Telugu (APNRT) Society to ensure that the search operations are conducted effectively.&nbsp;</p>

<p></p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/gjvkfvg8_sinkhole-in-seoul_625x300_29_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The SUV was later removed.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/coastal-cities-not-doing-enough-to-adapt-to-climate-change-study-shows-6445007]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Coastal Cities "Not Doing Enough" To Adapt To Climate Change, Study Shows]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/coastal-cities-not-doing-enough-to-adapt-to-climate-change-study-shows-6445007]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 29 Aug 2024 16:47:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Coastal cities are not doing enough to adapt to climate change, taking too long and implementing insufficient measures, according to a major study published this week.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Coastal cities are not doing enough to adapt to climate change, taking too long and implementing insufficient measures, according to a major study published this week.</p>

<p>While flood barriers and pumping systems are a step in the right direction, "across all regions and income groups, scientifically reported adaptation in coastal cities remains at rather low depth, scope and speed," said the study published in Nature Cities, which looked at 199 cities worldwide.</p>

<p>Given the high exposure and vulnerability of many <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-east-coast-cities-are-literally-sinking-millions-at-risk-study-shows-4853339" target="_blank">coastal cities</a>, "this finding is alarming as adaptation to future climate change will require many cities to go beyond business as usual risk management," it said.</p>

<p>Short- and mid-term solutions, as many cities are implementing, could even have an adverse effect, the study warned, leading to a "lock-in and maladaptive path dependency in the long-term."</p>

<p>Instead, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-study-warns-climate-change-will-make-you-poorer-5468268" target="_blank">adaptation</a> must aim at "transformation" of cities -- a change both of infrastructure and at the institutional level.</p>

<p>Positive models cited in the report include Singapore, Hong Kong and several Swedish cities.</p>

<p>But in the majority, the study found that coastal cities focus primarily on combating sea level rise, various types of flooding, and to a lesser extent the risks posed by erosion and storms.</p>

<p>And for scientists such a scope is too narrow -- cities need to address other problems linked to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/humanity-is-killing-the-great-barrier-reef-warns-report-6413023" target="_blank">climate change</a>, such as heatwaves.</p>

<h3><strong>Institutions and households</strong></h3>

<p>By comparing data from 199 cities, listed in 683 scientific articles, the researchers found that the actors driving adaptation changed according to the country and income category.</p>

<p>The richest coastal areas take a technological approach to dealing with climate change and the major players are institutions.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, lower-income cities located mainly in Africa, Asia, and South and Central <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-climate-change-has-forced-us-to-change-policy-5651674" target="_blank">America</a>, have no other choice but to rely on a "behavioural and cultural" effort for populations to adapt.</p>

<p>In lower-income coastal cities, there is a lack of institutional and/or technological support, making it "more likely individuals/households are reported as prime adaptation actors."</p>

<p>The poorest economies remain under-represented in the scientific literature, which complicates their adaptation.</p>

<p>"A considerable gap in research that needs to be addressed urgently," the study warned.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/8ha7a6tg_coastal-city_625x300_29_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Researchers compared the data from 199 cities, listed in 683 scientific articles (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>