<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Mon, 05 Aug 2024 17:11:52 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-says-has-legal-right-to-punish-israel-for-hamas-chief-ismail-haniyehs-killing-6268527]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[vIran Says Has "Legal Right" To Punish Israel For Hamas Chief's Killing]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-says-has-legal-right-to-punish-israel-for-hamas-chief-ismail-haniyehs-killing-6268527]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 05 Aug 2024 17:16:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iran said Monday it has the "legal right" to respond to the assassination in Tehran last week of Hamas chief Ismail Haniyeh, an attack blamed on Israel amid the Gaza war.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Iran said Monday it has the "legal right" to respond to the assassination in Tehran last week of Hamas chief Ismail Haniyeh, an attack blamed on Israel amid the Gaza war.</p>

<p>"No one has the right to doubt Iran's legal right to punish the Zionist regime", Iranian foreign ministry spokesman Nasser Kanani told a regular news conference, referring to Israel.</p>

<p>He maintained that Iran "does not seek to aggravate tensions in the region", which have soared since the Israel-Hamas war broke out in early October and rose further since Wednesday's attack in Tehran.</p>

<p>Iran's Revolutionary Guards said Israel killed Haniyeh using a "short-range projectile" launched from outside his residence in the Iranian capital which he was visiting to attend the inauguration of President Masoud Pezeshkian.</p>

<p>Iran and Hamas as well as other Tehran-aligned armed groups in the Middle East have vowed to retaliate.</p>

<p>Israel has not directly commented on the killing, which came just hours the assassination of Lebanese group Hezbollah's military chief Fuad Shukr in an Israeli strike on Beirut.</p>

<p>Iran-backed Hezbollah and Israeli forces have traded near-daily fire since early October.</p>

<p>Calls for de-escalation have intensified following the high-profile killings, with world powers fearing an all-out regional war.</p>

<p>Nasser Kanani on Monday said: "We believe the consolidation of stability and security in the region will be achieved by punishing the aggressor and creating a deterrent against the adventurous behaviour and extraterritorial terrors of the Zionist regime".</p>

<p>Iran, which does not recognise Israel, has held talks with multiple Arab countries including Jordan, Egypt, Oman and Qatar since Haniyeh's killing.</p>

<p>Tehran has repeatedly reaffirmed its "inherent right" to take action against foe Israel.</p>

<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu has said his country was at "a very high level" of preparedness for any scenario, "defensive and offensive".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/v49bimrg_ismail-haniyeh_625x300_31_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel has not directly commented on the killing of Ismail Haniyeh (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-aircraft-spotted-over-india-where-is-sheikh-hasina-headed-6268099]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh Aircraft Spotted Over India. Where Is Sheikh Hasina Headed?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-aircraft-spotted-over-india-where-is-sheikh-hasina-headed-6268099]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 05 Aug 2024 16:20:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Bangladesh Prime Minister Shiekh Hasina resigned today and left the country following more than a month of deadly anti-government protests.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bangladesh Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina resigned today and left the country following more than a month of deadly anti-government protests. Army chief General Waker-Us-Zaman said that an interim government would be formed.</p>

<p>The 76-year-old leader is said to have flown in a Bangladesh military aircraft with her sister, reports said.</p>

<p>Footage from airline tracker Flight Radar showed an aircraft of Bangladesh Air Force - Lockheed C-130J Hercules - flying over India. The plane was seen flying over Jharkhand.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/9q7ge9bg_sheikh-hasina-plane_625x300_05_August_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Earlier, some reports claimed that Ms Hasina would fly to West Bengal but as per the airline data, the aircraft bypassed the state.</p>

<p>Ms Hasina, who has ruled since 2009, had defied weeks of demands for her to stand down but fled following a brutal day of unrest on Sunday in which nearly 100 people died.</p>

<p>As per sources, her security team asked her to leave and that she did not find any time to prepare.</p>

<p>The country witnessed chaotic scenes from this morning that culminated in Ms Hasina's resignation. Huge crowds were seen waving flags, and dancing on top of a tank in the streets before hundreds broke through the gates of Ms Hasina'a official residence.</p>

<p>Some smashed a statue of her father Sheikh Mujibur Rahman, the country's independence hero.</p>

<p>Earlier, Ms Hasina's son urged the security forces to block any takeover from her 15-year-rule.</p>

<p>"Your duty is to keep our people safe and our country safe and to uphold the constitution," her son, US-based Sajeeb Wazed Joy, said in a post on Facebook.</p>

<p>"It means don't allow any unelected government to come in power for one minute, it is your duty."</p>

<p>The country's military and other security forces had supported Ms Hasina's government through the unrest that began last month against civil services jobs. The protests escalated into wider calls for her to stand down.</p>

<p>The demonstrations were about the reintroduction pf a quota scheme that reserved more than half of all government jobs for certain groups.</p>

<p>Ms Hasina won her fourth consecutive election in January in an election without a genuine opposition.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-01/3bjks7os_sheikh-hasina_625x300_07_January_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sheikh Hasina, who has ruled since 2009, had defied weeks of demands for her to stand down.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-waker-uz-zaman-army-general-to-take-bangladesh-charge-6268066]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Who Is Waker-Uz-Zaman, Army General To Take Bangladesh Charge]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-waker-uz-zaman-army-general-to-take-bangladesh-charge-6268066]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 05 Aug 2024 16:19:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Shortly after Sheikh Hasina resigned as the Prime Minister of Bangladesh and fled the country, General Waker-Uz-Zaman, the Chief of Army Staff, announced that he would form the interim government.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Shortly after Sheikh Hasina resigned as the Prime Minister of Bangladesh and fled the country, General Waker-Uz-Zaman, the Chief of Army Staff, announced that he would form the interim government. With the world's cameras pointing at him, he stood in front of a podium stating, "I am taking full responsibility."</p>

<p>The 76-year-old Sheikh Hasina resigned and fled Ganabhaban, the palatial residence of the Bangladeshi PM while protesters stormed its premises.&nbsp;</p>

<p>General Waker-Uz-Zaman, donning his military fatigues and cap, spoke to the nation via state television. "We will form an interim government," he said, confirming the resignation of Sheikh Hasina. "The country has suffered a lot, the economy has been hit, many people have been killed - it is time to stop the violence. I hope after my speech, the situation will improve."&nbsp;</p>

<p>But who is General Waker-Uz-Zaman, the man who will replace Sheikh Hasina as the new head of the state for Bangladesh?</p>

<p>A career infantry officer, he has dedicated nearly four decades to the service, including two tours as a UN peacekeeper. His tenure as Chief of Army Staff began in June, succeeding former General SM Shafiuddin Ahmed. His extensive experience spans commanding an infantry battalion, an independent infantry brigade, and an infantry division. His staff appointments include roles at the Infantry Brigade, School of Infantry and Tactics, and Army Headquarters, among others.</p>

<p>Educated at the Bangladesh Military Academy and furthering his studies at the Defence Services Command and Staff College in Mirpur and the Joint Services Command and Staff College in the UK, &nbsp;General Waker-Uz-Zaman holds advanced degrees in Defence Studies from both the National University of Bangladesh and King's College, University of London.</p>

<p>As the principal staff officer of Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina at the Armed Forces Division, &nbsp;General Waker-Uz-Zaman was deeply involved in national defence strategies and international peacekeeping affairs.&nbsp;</p>

<p>His accolades include the Army Medal of Glory (SGP) and the Extraordinary Service Medal (OSP) for his pivotal role in modernizing the army.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/4mqs5ei8_general-wakeruzzaman-_625x300_05_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A career infantry officer, he has dedicated nearly four decades to the service.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/indian-astronauts-set-for-space-mission-touchdown-in-us-for-training-6267896]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Indian Astronauts, Set For Space Mission, Touchdown In US For Training]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/indian-astronauts-set-for-space-mission-touchdown-in-us-for-training-6267896]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 05 Aug 2024 15:57:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Indian Gaganyatri's or astronaut designates set to fly to the International Space Station (ISS) have reached the United Stated and joined their training at Houston based American commercial company Axiom Space.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Indian Gaganyatri's or astronaut designates set to fly to the International Space Station (ISS) have reached the United Stated and joined their training at Houston based American commercial company Axiom Space.</p>

<p>ISRO has assigned Group Captain Shubhanshu Shukla and Group Captain Prasanth Balakrishnan Nair - part of India's Gaganyaan Mission - for training at Axiom Space and NASA's Kennedy Space Center and SpaceX. While Group Captain Shukla is the primary astronaut for the Axiom mission, Group Captain Nair is the back-up astronaut for the project. The upcoming flight is designated as the Axiom-4 (Ax-4) mission.</p>

<p>Axiom Space said the two Indian Air Force test pilots have joined the astronaut training regimen that may last several months before the flight to ISS in 2025. It also confirmed that the "crew is expected to spend up to 14 days on the space station".</p>

<p>In a statement Axiom Space said "Axiom-4 will launch to the orbiting laboratory aboard a SpaceX Falcon 9 rocket and Dragon spacecraft from Florida." No launch date has been disclosed just yet.</p>

<p>The Ax-4 crewmembers begin training with Axiom Space, NASA, and SpaceX. The crew assigned to Ax-4 includes American astronaut Commander Peggy Whitson, Mission Pilot Shubhanshu Shukla of India, Mission Specialist Slawosz Uznanski of European Space Agency (ESA)/Poland, and Mission Specialist Tibor Kapu of Hungary.</p>

<p>This will be the fourth commercial crew program spearheaded by Axiom Space and "Ax-4 represents Axiom Space's continued efforts to build opportunity for countries to research, innovate, test, and engage with people around the world while in low-Earth orbit," said Michael Suffredini, CEO of Axiom Space.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"This mission broadens horizons for nations with ambitious goals of advancing scientific, technological, and economic pursuits. Our collaboration with ESA for a second time and the inclusion of Hungary and India underscores Axiom Space's ability to cultivate global partners, expand the scope of exploration, and open up new avenues to grow a global space economy."</p>

<p>A trained biochemist and America's most experienced astronaut, 64-year-old Dr Peggy Annette Whitson, is the designated Commander of the Axiom-4 mission on which Group Captain Shubhanshu Shukla, 39, is likely to fly to the International Space Station in early 2025.</p>

<p>Dr Whitson is a veteran of four flights to space and while she retired as a NASA astronaut in 2018, she now works for Axiom Space, the Houston-based private space company, where she is the director of the human space flight programme.</p>

<p>Axiom Space describes Dr Whitson as "America's most experienced astronaut, who flew on three NASA long-duration space flights and Axiom Mission 2 (Ax-2), accumulating 675 days in space, more than any other American astronaut or woman astronaut in the world."</p>

<p>"I look forward to commanding my second commercial human spaceflight mission with Axiom Space," said Peggy Whitson, Ax-4 commander. "With a culturally diverse crew, we are not only advancing scientific knowledge but also fostering international collaboration".</p>

<p>Axiom Space is confident of pulling of the mission for which India has paid to acquire this astronaut seat. It says Axiom Mission 1 was the first all-private mission to the space station, Axiom Mission 2 launched the first Saudi female to space, and Axiom Mission 3 included both the first Turkish astronaut and first ESA astronaut to fly on a commercial space mission.</p>

<p>Whitson says "now, with Ax-4, we ascend even higher, bringing even more nations to low-Earth orbit and expanding humanity's reach among the stars."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/jva5tt48_space-mission-_625x300_05_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Ax-4 crewmembers begin training with Axiom Space, NASA, and SpaceX.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/stop-murder-stop-violence-appeals-bangladesh-army-chief-after-taking-over-6267837]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Stop Murder, Stop Violence, Appeals Bangladesh Army Chief After Taking Over]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/stop-murder-stop-violence-appeals-bangladesh-army-chief-after-taking-over-6267837]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 05 Aug 2024 15:49:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[End violence, will meet your demands, said Bangladesh's army chief Waker-Uz-Zaman Monday to protesters, adding that he will form an interim government after prime minister Sheikh Hasina resigned and fled the capital.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>End violence, will meet your demands, said Bangladesh's army chief Waker-Uz-Zaman Monday to protesters, adding that he will form an interim government after prime minister Sheikh Hasina resigned and fled the capital in the face of overwhelming protests.</p>

<p>"We will form an interim government," Waker said in a broadcast to the nation on state television, assuring the protesters that their demands will be met.</p>

<p>"The country has suffered a lot, the economy has been hit, many people have been killed -- it is time to stop the violence," he added.</p>

<p>"I hope after my speech, the situation will improve."</p>

<p>Waker,&nbsp;a career infantry officer who has spent nearly four decades in the military, was appointed to the military's top job as chief of army staff earlier this year.</p>

<p>"If the situation gets better, there is no need for emergency", he said, vowing the new authorities would "prosecute all murders" following weeks of deadly protests.</p>

<p>"Now the task of the students is to keep calm and help us," he said.</p>

<p>Ms Hasina, who has ruled Bangladesh since 2009, had defied weeks of demands for her to stand down but fled following a brutal day of unrest on Sunday in which nearly 100 people died.</p>

<p>Protests broke out over the reintroduction of a quota scheme that reserved more than half of all government jobs for certain groups.</p>

<p>The protests escalated despite the scheme having been scaled back by Bangladesh's top court.</p>

<p>In a hugely symbolic rebuke of Ms Hasina, a former army chief demanded the government "immediately" withdraw troops and allow protests.</p>

<p>The anti-government movement had attracted people from across society in the South Asian nation of about 170 million people, including film stars, musicians and singers.</p>

<p>The 76-year-old prime minister fled the country by helicopter, say reports, shortly after protesters had stormed her palace in Dhaka. Multiple reports say she is headed to an undisclosed location in India.</p>

<p>Bangladesh's Channel 24 broadcast images of crowds running into the compound, waving to the camera as they celebrated.</p>

<p>Others smashed a statues of Hasina's father Sheikh Mujibur Rahma, the country's independence hero.</p>

<p>Ms Hasina and won her fourth consecutive election in January after a vote without genuine opposition.</p>

<p><em>(With AFP Inputs)</em><br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-03/0frtahd_bangladesh-violence-afp_625x300_28_March_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Bangladesh Army Chief]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladeshi-protesters-vandalise-sheikh-mujibur-rahmans-statue-6267746]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bangladeshi Protesters Vandalise Sheikh Mujibur Rahman's Statue]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladeshi-protesters-vandalise-sheikh-mujibur-rahmans-statue-6267746]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 05 Aug 2024 15:39:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hundreds of thousands of Bangladeshi protesters defied curfew and stormed the Prime Minister's palace in capital Dhaka after reports surfaced that Sheikh Hasina has resigned and left the country.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Thousands of Bangladeshi protesters defied curfew and stormed the Prime Minister's palace in capital Dhaka after reports surfaced that Sheikh Hasina has resigned and left the country.</p>

<p>Jubilant looking crowds waved flags on the streets of Dhaka, before hundreds broke through the gates of Sheikh Hasina's official residence.</p>

<p>The crowd also vandalised Ms Hasina's father and former Bangladesh President Sheikh Mujibur Rahman statue in Dhaka.</p>

<p>Soldiers and police with armoured vehicles in Dhaka had barricaded routes to Ms Hasina's office with barbed wire, AFP reporters said, but vast crowds flooded the streets, tearing down barriers.</p>

<p>Local media estimated as many as 400,000 protesters were on the streets but it was impossible to verify the figure.</p>

<p>At least 98 people were killed yesterday, including 14 police officers, in the deadliest day of the unrest. The day's violence took the total number of people killed since protests began in early July to at least 300.</p>

<p>Rallies that began last month against civil service job quotas have escalated into some of the worst unrest of Prime Minister Hasina's 15-year rule and shifted into wider calls for the 76-year-old to step down.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/2re61o78_protester_625x300_05_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Jubilant looking crowds waved flags on the streets of Dhaka]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-sheikh-hasina-who-once-saved-bangladesh-from-military-rule-6267638]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Who Is Sheikh Hasina Who Once Saved Bangladesh From Military Rule]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-sheikh-hasina-who-once-saved-bangladesh-from-military-rule-6267638]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 05 Aug 2024 15:26:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Sheikh Hasina once helped rescue Bangladesh from military rule, but her time in power has seen the mass arrest of her political opponents and human rights sanctions against her security forces.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sheikh Hasina once helped rescue Bangladesh from military rule, but her time in power has seen the mass arrest of her political opponents and human rights sanctions against her security forces.</p>

<p>Since July, the autocratic premier has faced mass protests that began as university student-led rallies against civil service job quotas, but which have morphed into some of the worst unrest of her 15-year tenure, with opponents demanding she step down.</p>

<p>The protests were largely peaceful until attacks on demonstrators by police and pro-government student groups, sparking international condemnation.</p>

<p>The 76-year-old won a fifth term as prime minister in January, with the opposition boycotting a vote they said was neither free nor fair.</p>

<p>At the time, Hasina branded the main opposition party a "terrorist organisation".</p>

<p>Critics accuse her government of a litany of rights abuses including the murder of opposition activists.</p>

<p>The daughter of a revolutionary who led Bangladesh to independence, Hasina has presided over breakneck economic growth in a country once written off by US statesman Henry Kissinger as an irredeemable "basket case".</p>

<p>Last year she promised to turn all of Bangladesh into a "prosperous and developed country", but around 18 million young Bangladeshis are out of work, according to government figures.</p>

<p><strong>- Economic rise -</strong></p>

<p>Hasina was 27 and travelling abroad when renegade military officers murdered her father, prime minister Sheikh Mujibur Rahman, along with her mother and three brothers in a 1975 coup.</p>

<p>She returned after living in exile for six years to take the reins of her father's Awami League party, beginning a decade-long struggle that saw her subjected to lengthy stretches of house arrest.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Hasina joined forces with Khaleda Zia's Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) to help oust military dictator Hussain Muhammad Ershad in 1990.</p>

<p>But they soon fell out and their ensuing rivalry has since dominated Bangladeshi politics.</p>

<p>Hasina first served a term as prime minister in 1996, but lost to Zia five years later.</p>

<p>The pair were then imprisoned on corruption charges in 2007 after a coup by a military-backed government.</p>

<p>The charges were dropped and they were free to contest an election the following year.</p>

<p>Hasina won in a landslide and has been in power ever since.</p>

<p>The 78-year-old Zia meanwhile is in ailing health and confined to hospital after graft charges saw her sentenced to a 17-year prison term in 2018, with top leaders from her party also behind bars.</p>

<p>Hasina has been praised by supporters for leading Bangladesh through a remarkable economic boom, largely on the back of the mostly female factory workforce powering its garment export industry.</p>

<p>Bangladesh, one of the world's poorest countries when it gained independence from Pakistan in 1971, has grown an average of more than six percent each year since 2009.</p>

<p>Poverty has plummeted and more than 95 percent of the country's 170 million people now have access to electricity, with per capita income overtaking India in 2021.</p>

<p>Hasina also received international acclaim for opening Bangladesh's doors to hundreds of thousands of Rohingya refugees fleeing a 2017 military crackdown in neighbouring Myanmar.</p>

<p>And she has been hailed for a decisive crackdown on Islamist militants in the Muslim-majority nation after five homegrown extremists stormed a Dhaka cafe popular with Western expatriates and killed 22 people in 2016.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>- Silencing dissent -</strong></p>

<p>But her government's intolerance towards dissent has given rise to resentment at home and expressions of concern from Washington and elsewhere.</p>

<p>Five top Islamist leaders and a senior opposition figure were executed over the past decade after convictions for crimes against humanity committed during the country's brutal 1971 liberation war.</p>

<p>Instead of healing the wounds of that conflict, the trials triggered mass protests and deadly clashes.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Her opponents branded them a farce, saying they were a politically motivated exercise to silence dissent.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The United States imposed sanctions in 2021 on an elite branch of Bangladesh's security forces and seven of its top officers over charges of widespread human rights abuses.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In the face of mounting protests, Hasina has insisted she has worked for her nation.</p>

<p>Last month she toured areas of Dhaka damaged during days of deadly unrest, including a metro station that was among several government buildings torched or vandalised.</p>

<p>"Over 15 years, I've built this country," she told reporters, condemning the damage to infrastructure. "What didn't I do for the people?</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/qd5o8k6g_sheikh-hasina_625x300_05_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sheikh Hasina first served a term as prime minister in 1996, but lost to Zia five years later.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-protests-sheikh-hasina-resigns-bangladesh-army-gave-sheikh-hasina-45-minutes-to-quit-top-developments-6267616]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Sheikh Hasina Quits After Bangladesh Army's 45-Min Notice: Top Developments]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-protests-sheikh-hasina-resigns-bangladesh-army-gave-sheikh-hasina-45-minutes-to-quit-top-developments-6267616]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 05 Aug 2024 15:23:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Sheikh Hasina quit as Prime Minister of Bangladesh and fled the nation Monday after violent clashes that have killed over 300 people so far. The army - which has taken charge to form an "interim government" gave her 45 minutes to step down.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<ol>
	<li><a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/topic/sheikh-hasina" target="_blank">Sheikh Hasina</a>&nbsp;left in a military aircraft and is heading to an unspecified "safe space"; there are reports this will be London&nbsp;but a stopover in&nbsp;Delhi is expected. Indian <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-aircraft-spotted-over-india-where-is-sheikh-hasina-headed-6268099#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">security agencies are monitoring a C-130 aircraft</a> heading towards Delhi that is believed to be carrying the former Prime Minister and some members of her entourage.</li>
	<li>According to news agency AFP, she wanted to address the nation but the proximity of the violence meant her security detail vetoed the proposal. Bangladeshi sources told AFP her security team asked her leave, and that "she did not find any time to prepare a speech".</li>
	<li>In a televised address to the troubled nation, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-waker-uz-zaman-army-general-to-take-bangladesh-charge-6268066#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">Army chief General Waker-Uz-Zaman</a> said the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladeshs-sheikh-hasina-quits-flies-out-amid-massive-protests-report-6267468#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">military will form an "interim government"</a>&nbsp;and urged to protesters to stand down.</li>
	<li>"There is a crisis. I have met Opposition leaders and we have decided to form an interim government to run this country. I take all responsibility and promise to protect your life and property. Your demands will be fulfilled. <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/stop-murder-stop-violence-appeals-bangladesh-army-chief-after-taking-over-6267837#pfrom=home-ndtv_topstories_lastestImg" target="_blank">Please&nbsp;stop the violence</a>," he said.</li>
	<li>India's Border Security Force is on high alert across the country's 4,096 km border with Bangladesh. BSF field commanders are to take "on ground" positions and the Railways has stopped all trains to Bangladesh.</li>
	<li>Earlier today <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-pm-sheikh-hasina-leaves-dhaka-palace-for-safer-place-report-6267175#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">protesters broke into Gonobhaban - the Dhaka residence of the Prime Minister</a>. But by then the veteran politician - who began a fifth term as PM this year - had fled; sources said she and her younger sister, Sheikh Rehana, left in a military helicopter.</li>
	<li><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-unrest-live-updates-pm-sheikh-hasina-bangladesh-violence-bangladesh-violence-live-6267300" target="_blank">100 people were killed and over 1,000 injured</a> in clashes that took place between police and protesters on Sunday. The protests, which began late last month, have escalated dramatically over the past few days after a pitched battle between students and police.</li>
	<li>The <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-protests-sheikh-hasina-awami-league-explained-what-led-to-bangladesh-protests-that-has-seen-over-300-killed-6265524#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">protests began over a quota system</a>&nbsp;that reserves up to 30 per cent of government jobs for family members of veterans from Bangladesh's 1971 war against Pakistan.</li>
	<li>The demonstrations quickly grew into a wider anti-government movement that attracted people from all strata of Bangladeshi society, including film stars, musicians and singers.</li>
	<li>The Bangladesh Supreme Court cut the reservations to 5 per cent. Student leaders then put protests on hold but it flared up after they said the government ignored their call to release all their leaders. This triggered demands for Sheikh Hasina to quit.<em> </em></li>
</ol>

<p><em><strong>With input from agencies</strong></em></p>

<p><em>NDTV is now available on WhatsApp channels. <a href="https://www.whatsapp.com/channel/0029Va4lixw7z4kcvZI9JM12">Click on the link</a> to get all the latest updates from NDTV on your chat. </em></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/chefhsdo_sheikh-hasina-_625x300_22_June_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[PM Sheikh Hasina: Sheikh Hasina resigned as Prime Minister of Bangladesh (File).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladeshs-sheikh-hasina-quits-flies-out-amid-massive-protests-report-6267468]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh PM Sheikh Hasina Quits, Army Coup Amid Massive Protests]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladeshs-sheikh-hasina-quits-flies-out-amid-massive-protests-report-6267468]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 05 Aug 2024 15:03:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Sheikh Hasina has resigned as Bangladesh Prime Minister and fled the country amid violent clashes between her party Awami League's supporters and protesters demanding that she quit, news agency Reuters has reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sheikh Hasina has quit as Bangladesh Prime Minister and the Army is moving to take control amid violent protests demanding her exit. Bangladesh Army chief General <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-waker-uz-zaman-army-general-to-take-bangladesh-charge-6268066">Waker-Uz-Zaman</a> told the media that the Army will form an interim government and has appealed to the protesters to return to the path of peace.</p>

<p>"There is a crisis in the country. I have met Opposition leaders and we have decided to form an interim government to run this country. I take all responsibility and promise to protect your life and property. Your demands will be fulfilled. Please support us and stop violence. If you work with us, we can move towards a proper solution. We cannot achieve anything through violence," he said. The Army chief also confirmed that Ms Hasina has stepped down.&nbsp;</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont">
<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Over 300 people lost their lives as security forces cracked down on in the protests. AFP" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/64dpq37g_bangladesh-protests_625x300_05_August_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Over 300 people lost their lives as security forces cracked down on in the protests. AFP" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">Over 300 people lost their lives as security forces cracked down on in the protests. AFP</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>

<p>The Army General said leaders of Opposition parties and civil society were present at today's meeting, and clarified that nobody from the ruling Awami League attended it.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Ms Hasina, who started her fifth term as Prime Minister earlier this year, left state capital Dhaka in a military aircraft and <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-aircraft-spotted-over-india-where-is-sheikh-hasina-headed-6268099">may be headed to India</a>.</p>

<p>The 76-year-old is accompanied by her younger sister, Sheikh Rehana. Protesters demanding her resignation have, meanwhile, stormed Gono Bhaban, the Prime Minister's official residence, local media reports have said. The Bangladesh Army, it is learnt, had given a 45-minute ultimatum to the Prime Minister to step down.</p>

<p>Shocking visuals of protesters vandalising a statue of Sheikh Mujibur Rahman, Ms Hasina's father and the tallest leader in the country's history who led its fight for Independence from Pakistan, are playing out on Dhaka's streets. The visuals mark a massive shift in the country's political landscape. The legacy of Mujibur Rahman, fondly known as Bangabandhu, is no longer a symbol of Bangladesh's war of liberation. Instead, it represents her daughter's politics that protesters claim has focused on suppressing dissent.</p>

<p><strong>What's Behind The Protests</strong></p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-protests-sheikh-hasina-awami-league-explained-what-led-to-bangladesh-protests-that-has-seen-over-300-killed-6265524">The protests</a> in Bangladesh, which began last month and escalated swiftly, started as an agitation against a quota system under which 30 per cent of government jobs were reserved for family members of Muktijoddhas -- those who fought in Bangladesh's war of independence in 1971. The protesters have said this system favours supporters of the ruling Awami League and want a merit-based system to replace it. As the protests grew, the Awami League dispensation tried to crush it with an iron hand. In the clashes that followed, more than 300 people were killed.</p>

<p>What added to the protesters' anger was a remark by Prime Minister Hasina. "If not the grandchildren of the freedom fighters, then who will get quota benefits? The grandchildren of the 'Razakars'?" she asked. "This is my question. I want to ask the people of the nation. If the protesters don't comply, I can do nothing. They can continue their protest. If protesters damage properties or attack cops, the law will take its course. We can't help."</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="The Sheikh Hasina administration initially tried to crush the protests. AFP" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/gbk16bvg_the-sheikh-hasina-administration-initially-tried-to-crush-the-protests_625x300_05_August_24.jpg?im=FitAndFill,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="The Sheikh Hasina administration initially tried to crush the protests. AFP" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">Displayed in a protest, this poster here says Sheikh Hasina is a "murderer of students". AFP</p>
</div>

<p>The Razakar remark touched a raw nerve. A paramilitary force recruited by Pakistan Army during the 1971 liberation war, Razakars carried out mass atrocities, including mass killings, rapes, and torture.</p>

<p>Reservation has been a burning issue in Bangladesh for several years now. In 2018, an agitation on this issue forced the government to water down the reservation system and cancelled quotas for some positions.</p>

<p>The latest unrest was sparked by a high court order that declared illegal the 2018 government circular cancelling 30 per cent quota for freedom fighters' descendants in government jobs.</p>

<p>This order was scrapped by the country's Supreme Court. The Supreme Court ordered that 93 per cent of government jobs must be allocated on the basis of merit and the remaining be reserved for relatives of freedom fighters. But even the top court's order could not pacify the protesters.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-01/lj3t5fn_sheikh-hasina-oath_625x300_11_January_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sheikh Hasina left Dhaka in a military aircraft and may be headed to India]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-eyes-indian-ocean-island-as-possible-military-base-to-deter-china-6267262]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Eyes Indian Ocean Island As Possible Military Base To Deter China]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-eyes-indian-ocean-island-as-possible-military-base-to-deter-china-6267262]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 05 Aug 2024 14:44:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A remote Australian island close to an Indian Ocean chokepoint for Chinese oil shipments is on a list of possible locations for US military construction aimed at deterring China, with the US saying it "may or may not" support American forces.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A remote Australian island close to an Indian Ocean chokepoint for Chinese oil shipments is on a list of possible locations for US military construction aimed at deterring China, with the US saying it "may or may not" support American forces.</p>

<p>Australia's Cocos Islands is listed along with the Philippines, Timor Leste and Papua New Guinea for anticipated construction projects under the Pacific Deterrence Initiative, designed to enhance US force posture and infrastructure to counter China.</p>

<p>The Cocos Islands, with a population of 600, sits 3,000 km west of the Australian mainland and is described by the Australian Defence Force as key to its maritime surveillance operations in the Indian Ocean, where China is increasing submarine activity.</p>

<p>A US Navy construction tender published in June for various base infrastructures in the Indo-Pacific lists Cocos Islands as a possible project location, an indication the US military is also seeking access to the Indian Ocean territory.</p>

<p>"These projects may or may not support the Darwin Marines Rotational Force," a spokesman for NAVFAC Pacific, the US Navy's Pacific Fleet engineering arm, said in an emailed response to Reuters.</p>

<p>Around 2,000 US Marines are hosted in the northern Australian city of Darwin for six months of the year.</p>

<p>There was no immediate response from the Chinese foreign ministry when asked for comment on the US Navy tender list and Cocos Islands as a possible project.</p>

<p>Cocos Islands is closer to the Strait of Malacca, a chokepoint for half of China's oil shipments than the US Navy base of Diego Garcia, a launch pad for US bombers in the Iraq and Afghanistan conflicts, but whose long-term future is under a cloud.</p>

<p>Darshana Baruah, director of security and geopolitics for the Australia India Institute, told a US Congressional hearing last year that Cocos Islands would be "critical geography" for the US to put pressure on China to deter an attack on Taiwan.</p>

<p>"Cocos is much closer to the theatre where Washington anticipates conflict scenarios," she told Reuters.</p>

<p>"The strategic location of Cocos Islands, close to both the Strait of Malacca as well as Australia's northern approaches, gives it immense geostrategic advantages," she added.</p>

<p>Australia has said it will start construction on an expanded airfield on the island this year, to carry heavier military aircraft, including the submarine-hunting P-8A Poseidon.</p>

<p>"There is currently no US investment at Cocos (Keeling) Island," an Australian Defence Force spokesman said in a statement.</p>

<p>"Australia and the US cooperate closely together to advance our force posture cooperation across various locations in Australia," the statement added.</p>

<p>The US military is constructing bomber runways and facilities at two key northern Australian air bases.</p>

<p>The US has said its Diego Garcia air base plays a vital role in regional security, and it was a matter for Britain and Mauritius to work out its future after the United Nations General Assembly voted in 2019 that it should be returned to Mauritius.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/gqad7vv_military-base-pixabay_625x300_05_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Construction will start on an expanded airfield to carry heavier military aircraft, Australia says.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/french-climber-benjamin-vedrines-breaks-speed-record-on-k2-summit-in-under-11-hours-6266703]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[French Climber Achieves Fastest-Ever Ascent Of K2, Credits Patience]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/french-climber-benjamin-vedrines-breaks-speed-record-on-k2-summit-in-under-11-hours-6266703]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 05 Aug 2024 14:41:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[French mountaineer Benjamin Vedrines counted every second as he made history's fastest-ever ascent of K2, but says he doesn't add up the growing number of records to his name.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>French mountaineer Benjamin Vedrines counted every second as he made history's fastest-ever ascent of K2, but says he doesn't add up the growing number of records to his name.</p>

<p>"It's not the records themselves that interest me, it's also the links that I create with certain mountains and especially in the case of K2," the 32-year-old told AFP.</p>

<p>"It fascinated me from the first moment I saw it."</p>

<p>Vedrines scaled the world's second-highest mountain -- standing at 8,611 metres (28,251 feet) on the border of Pakistan and China -- in 10 hours, 59 minutes and 59 seconds on Sunday, July 28th.</p>

<p>The ascent slashed by more than half the previous record for climbing K2 without bottled oxygen, completed in 23 hours by fellow Frenchman Benoit Chamoux in 1986.</p>

<p>The remarkable feat on the "Savage Mountain" came exactly two years to the day since Vedrines was forced to abort his first attempt as the high altitude starved his brain of oxygen a mere 200 metres from the top.</p>

<p>While his record has made headlines worldwide for its speed, for Vedrines it is remarkable for the opposite reason -- because it was so long in the making.</p>

<p>"I wanted to arrive there really ready, prepared, body, mind," he said. "I pay attention to doing things well, to building them. These are projects that take time."</p>

<h3><strong>'Go slow to go fast'</strong></h3>

<p>Vedrines is considered one of France's pre-eminent climbers and in 2022 set a speed record climbing Pakistan's Broad Peak -- the world's 12th highest mountain -- before descending by paraglider.</p>

<p>Back home in the French Alps, he has also broken a host of records.</p>

<p>He uses the "alpine style" of climbing which relies on minimal use of cumbersome ropes in favour of moving swiftly up the slopes.</p>

<p>But without the aid of oxygen tanks to counteract the thin atmosphere, he faced a paradox on K2 -- needing to move quickly, in one of the world's most unforgiving environments, with minimal effort.</p>

<p>"It requires knowing how to go slowly to go fast," he quips. "It is a little bit of a contradiction that we have to negotiate."</p>

<p>To make matters worse, poor weather on the mountain prevented his attempts to acclimatise.</p>

<p>"I had to face a lot of unforeseen events during this expedition," he said.</p>

<p>"I knew how to persevere. I knew how to be determined, patient and above all humble because this K2 mountain requires a lot of humility."</p>

<p>While Nepal's Mount Everest is around 240 metres taller than K2, the Pakistan peak first scaled in 1954 is regarded as a more challenging ascent.</p>

<p>Elite climbers often talk of a special connection to the mountain despite its fatal reputation.</p>

<p>Historically around one in four ascent attempts have ended in death.</p>

<p>Recent years have seen fewer fatalities, but two Japanese climbers also attempting to scale K2 using the "alpine style" fell the day before Vedrines' ascent, with their motionless bodies spotted by a helicopter.</p>

<p>A rescue was deemed impossible.</p>

<h3><strong>'K2 accepted me'</strong></h3>

<p>At times Vedrines was climbing solo, as well as at record speed.</p>

<p>"I had to forge a little path in the snow and there was this slightly mystical atmosphere that is specific to K2," he said.</p>

<p>Vedrines left K2's Advanced Base Camp at 5,350 metres just after midnight, and covered the 3,261 metres to the top before lunchtime the next day.</p>

<p>After making his descent, he spoke to AFP a week later, on Sunday, in the resort town of Skardu -- the gateway to northern Pakistan which is home to five of the world's 14 mountains above 8,000 metres.</p>

<p>"I feel very grateful that the K2 mountain finally accepted me this year," said Vedrines.</p>

<p>"It was not a form of revenge but a form of reconciliation."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/b2mhp9no_benjamin-vedrines-afp_625x300_05_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Vedrines scaled the world's second-highest mountain at 8,611 meters in 10 hours, 59 minutes, 59 seconds.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-unrest-live-updates-pm-sheikh-hasina-bangladesh-violence-bangladesh-violence-live-6267300]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[LIVE: Sheikh Hasina Quits As Bangladesh PM Amid Massive Unrest, Say Reports]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-unrest-live-updates-pm-sheikh-hasina-bangladesh-violence-bangladesh-violence-live-6267300]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 05 Aug 2024 14:40:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Uncertainty looms over the future of Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina after Bangladesh witnessed one of its deadliest days. Tens of thousands of protesters have hit the streets and clashed with cops, demanding Hasina's resignation.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Uncertainty looms over the future of Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina after Bangladesh witnessed one of its deadliest days. Tens of thousands of protesters have hit the streets and clashed with cops, demanding Hasina's resignation. At least 98 people were killed in Sunday violence, surpassing the 67 deaths reported on July 19 when students protested against the quota system for government jobs.</p>

<p>Bangladeshi Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina resigned and fled the country on Monday. The Army chief said that the an interim government will be formed and Army will run the country.</p>

<h2><strong>Here are the LIVE updates on Bangladesh unrest:</strong></h2>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/s1eoet7o_bangladesh-unrest-afp_625x300_05_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sheikh-hasinas-son-issues-your-duty-call-to-bangladesh-army-amid-clashes-6267260]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Your Duty Is...": Sheikh Hasina's Son To Bangladesh Army Amid Clashes]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sheikh-hasinas-son-issues-your-duty-call-to-bangladesh-army-amid-clashes-6267260]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 05 Aug 2024 14:37:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The son of Bangladesh's Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina on Monday urged the country's security forces to block any takeover from her rule as hundreds of thousands of protesters demanded she quit.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The son of Bangladesh's Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina on Monday urged the country's security forces to block any takeover from her rule as hundreds of thousands of protesters demanded she quit. "Your duty is to keep our people safe and our country safe and to uphold the constitution," US-based Sajeeb Wazed Joy said in a post on Facebook.</p>

<p>"It means don't allow any unelected government to come in power for one minute, it is your duty."</p>

<p>Joy, who is also an information and communications technology advisor to Hasina, warned progress made by Bangladesh would be threatened if she were forced out.</p>

<p>"Everything of our development and progress will vanish. Bangladesh would not be able to come back from there," he said.</p>

<p>"I don't want that and you also do not want that," he added. "Myself, Sajeeb Wazed Joy, will not let that happen as long as I can."</p>

<p>His warning comes as Bangladesh's army chief Waker-Uz-Zaman is set to address the nation, a military spokesman told AFP without giving further details.</p>

<p>Rallies that began last month against civil service job quotas have escalated into some of the worst unrest of Hasina's 15-year rule and shifted into wider calls for the 76-year-old to resign.</p>

<p>A senior advisor to Hasina told AFP Monday that the resignation of the embattled leader was a "possibility" after being questioned as to whether she would quit.</p>

<p>"The situation is such that this is a possibility, but I don't know how it will happen," the aide close to the premier said, speaking on condition of anonymity.</p>

<p>The military declared an emergency in January 2007 after widespread political unrest and installed a caretaker government for two years.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/ock6bi28_bangladesh-protests-afp-_625x300_05_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[His warning comes as Bangladesh's army chief Waker-Uz-Zaman is set to address the nation.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/meta-is-offering-hollywood-stars-millions-for-ai-voice-projects-6267255]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Meta Is Offering Hollywood Stars Millions For AI Voice Projects]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/meta-is-offering-hollywood-stars-millions-for-ai-voice-projects-6267255]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 05 Aug 2024 14:36:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Negotiations between Meta and some talent representatives have stopped and started many times because the parties can't agree on terms for use of the actors' voices.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Meta Platforms Inc. is offering Hollywood celebrities millions of dollars for the right to record and use their voices for artificial intelligence projects, according to several people familiar with the negotiations.<br />
<br />
The company is talking with Judi Dench, Awkwafina and Keegan-Michael Key, said the people, who asked not to be identified because the project is confidential. Representatives for Meta declined to comment.<br />
<br />
Meta, the owner of Facebook and Instagram, is racing to close deals so it has time to develop a suite of AI tools for unveiling at its Connect 2024 event in September. While it's not entirely clear how Meta will be using the voices, it has discussed a chatbot that could serve as a digital assistant, a la Apple's Siri, or a friend, the people said. Users could speak with a chatbot that has the voice of Awkwafina, for example.</p>

<p>Negotiations between Meta and some talent representatives have stopped and started many times because the parties can't agree on terms for use of the actors' voices. Meta would like to secure rights to voices for many uses over a fixed term on a single project. Representatives for the actors are seeking stricter limits.</p>

<p>The use of artificial intelligence has spooked many in the Hollywood creative community who fear losing work as a result of the technology. Screenwriters and actors fought for protections against the use of AI during labor stoppages last year. Yet SAG-AFTRA, the primary unions for actors, has reached an agreement with Meta on terms, according to the people.</p>

<p>Meta has experimented with creating text-based chatbots inspired by celebrities like Dwyane Wade and Paris Hilton. The company has already ended that program. It has also unveiled an AI studio that allows content creators to make chatbots of themselves.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/drdv4sso_meta-ai-voice-actors_625x300_05_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Meta is in talks with American Actress and Comedian Awkwafina for its AI models]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-pm-sheikh-hasina-leaves-dhaka-palace-for-safer-place-report-6267175]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh Protesters Storm Sheikh Hasina's Palace Amid Violent Clashes]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-pm-sheikh-hasina-leaves-dhaka-palace-for-safer-place-report-6267175]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 05 Aug 2024 14:24:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Bangladesh Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina has resigned and left the capital Dhaka amid violent protests demanding her resignation, a source close to the embattled leader told the news agency AFP.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bangladesh Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina today resigned and left the capital Dhaka amid violent clashes as vast crowds of angry protesters demanded her resignation.</p>

<p>"She and her sister have left Ganabhaban (the Prime Minister's official residence) for a safer place," the source told AFP. "She wanted to record a speech. But she could not get an opportunity to do that," the source said.</p>

<p>Hundreds of thousands of protesters defied curfew, marching on the capital's streets and later storming the Prime Minister's palace. Visuals showed crowds running into the premier's official residence in Dhaka, waving to the camera as they celebrated.</p>

<p>Soldiers and police with armoured vehicles in Dhaka had barricaded routes to Ms Hasina's office with barbed wire, AFP reporters said, but vast crowds flooded the streets, tearing down barriers.</p>

<p>Local media estimated as many as 400,000 protesters were on the streets but it was impossible to verify the figure.</p>

<p>Bangladesh's army chief Waker-Uz-Zaman said an interim government will be formed after the prime minister resigned and fled the capital in the face of overwhelming protests. "We will form an interim government," he said.</p>

<p>At least 98 people were killed in fierce clashes yesterday, taking the death count since protests erupted last month to over 300.</p>

<p>Rallies that began last month against civil service job quotas have escalated into some of the worst unrest of Prime Minister Hasina's 15-year rule and shifted into wider calls for the 76-year-old to step down.</p>

<p>The demonstrations have grown into a wider anti-government movement across Bangladesh. It has attracted people from all strata of Bangladesh society, including film stars, musicians and singers. Songs calling for people's support have spread widely on social media.</p>

<p>The protesters had earlier dismissed Ms Hasina's invitation for dialogue aimed at quelling escalating violence and consolidated their demands into a unified call for her resignation.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-01/ndjlqm4_sheikh-hasina_625x300_11_January_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Bangladesh PM Sheikh Hasina has resigned and left the capital Dhaka  (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/man-who-forced-son-to-run-on-treadmill-causing-his-death-gets-25-years-jail-6266232]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Man Who Forced Son To Run On Treadmill, Causing His Death Gets 25 Years Jail]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/man-who-forced-son-to-run-on-treadmill-causing-his-death-gets-25-years-jail-6266232]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 05 Aug 2024 14:10:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A New Jersey father has been sentenced to 25 years in prison for abusing his 6-year-old son to death.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A New Jersey father has been sentenced to 25 years in prison for abusing his 6-year-old son to death. Christopher Gregor was found guilty of child endangerment and manslaughter in May after a jury heard evidence that he forced his son, Corey Micciolo, to perform abusive treadmill workouts, leading to the boy's death. The prosecutor alleged the child died from injuries sustained during the father's abuse.</p>

<p>The sentence comes after a four-week trial and nearly three-and-a-half years after the boy's death in April 2021, reports Newsnation.</p>

<p>A video shown in the courtroom showed Gregor increasing the speed on a treadmill, causing his son to fly off and fall six times. Gregor allegedly thought the boy was too fat. On April 2, Corey woke up from a nap nauseated, stumbling around and slurring his words. Surveillance footage shows Gregor carrying the boy's limp and battered body into the hospital shortly before he died.</p>

<p>A registered nurse testified the little boy was not showing any signs that he was verbal as his head tilted backwards in the examination room. The injuries were so severe that Corey suffered a seizure during a CT scan, forcing medical staff to take emergency measures. Despite their efforts, the child was pronounced dead shortly before 5 pm.</p>

<p>In a statement to the judge ahead of his sentencing, Christopher Gregor denied responsibility for his son's death. I did nothing to cause Corey's passing, Gregor said, as per <a href="https://www.newsnationnow.com/crime/treadmill-abuse-dad-sentencing-corey-micciolo/">Newsnation</a>. I didn't hurt my son. I loved him, and I still do. I regret not bringing him to the hospital sooner. I didn't know how sick he was. I didn't know. I just thought he was tired.</p>

<p>Corey's mother, Breanna Micciolo called Gregor a monster who had made her life an absolute living nightmare. Are you that crazy that you convinced yourself you didn't do this? she asked, adding, I hate you, and I will never forgive you.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/0kc54m6o_man-forces-son-to-run-on-treadmill-_625x300_02_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The accused was arrested on March 9, 2022, for his son's death]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-strike-kills-2-in-lebanon-amid-growing-middle-east-tensions-6266986]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israeli Strike Kills 2 In Lebanon Amid Growing Middle East Tensions]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-strike-kills-2-in-lebanon-amid-growing-middle-east-tensions-6266986]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 05 Aug 2024 14:00:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Lebanon's health ministry said two people were killed Monday in an Israeli strike on the country's south, where Hezbollah has been trading near-daily fire with Israel since the start of the Gaza war in October.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lebanon's health ministry said two people were killed Monday in an Israeli strike on the country's south, where Hezbollah has been trading near-daily fire with Israel since the start of the Gaza war in October.</p>

<p>Since last week, tensions have soared as Iran and Tehran-backed groups, including Hezbollah, vowed <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-allies-vow-revenge-after-top-hamas-hezbollah-leaders-killed-6252277" target="_blank">revenge for the killing of Hamas's political leader</a> in Tehran and Israel's killing of Hezbollah's military chief in Beirut.</p>

<p>"The enemy raid that took place near the (Mais Al-Jabal) town's cemetery killed two people," Lebanon's Health Ministry said in a statement.</p>

<p>"One of the two martyrs who fell in the Mais Al-Jabal raid this morning was a Risala Scouts paramedic," Lebanon's state-run National News Agency said.</p>

<p>Ali Abbas, a rescue worker from the Risala Scouts which is affiliated with Hezbollah ally the Amal movement, told AFP that the paramedic had travelled by motorcycle with another person to inspect the site of an earlier strike.</p>

<p>He went "to see if there were civilians or people (in the area)... and the second strike happened immediately," Abbas said.</p>

<p>Mais al-Jabal, a frontline village less than two kilometres away from the border with Israel, has experienced heavy bombardment since the cross-border clashes began, forcing most residents to leave.</p>

<p>Early on Monday, Hezbollah said it had targeted military sites in northern Israel with "explosive-laden drones" in response to Israeli "attacks and assassinations" in southern Lebanon.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said "numerous suspicious aerial targets were identified crossing from Lebanon" into northern Israel, starting a fire and leaving an officer and a soldier "moderately injured".</p>

<p>The cross-border violence since October has killed at least 549 people in Lebanon, mostly fighters but also including at least 116 civilians, according to an AFP tally.</p>

<p>On the Israeli side, including the annexed Golan Heights, 22 soldiers and 25 civilians have been killed, according to army figures.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/2caj1vvo_israel-lebanon-fight_625x300_03_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The cross-border violence since October has killed at least 549 people in Lebanon said a report (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-israel-war-gaza-conflict-airlines-that-have-cancelled-flights-to-israel-air-india-cancels-israel-flights-which-other-airlines-have-also-stopped-6266975]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Air India Cancels Israel Flights. Which Other Airlines Have Also Stopped?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-israel-war-gaza-conflict-airlines-that-have-cancelled-flights-to-israel-air-india-cancels-israel-flights-which-other-airlines-have-also-stopped-6266975]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 05 Aug 2024 13:59:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Several international airlines unsettled by the threat of a multi-front war in the Middle East - following Iran-Israel tension, to add to the violence in Gaza, which has impacted neighbouring countries, like Lebanon - have cancelled or cut flights.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Several international airlines unsettled by the threat of a multi-front war in the Middle East - following <a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/topic/iran-israel-tension" target="_blank">Iran-Israel tension</a>, to add to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/topic/israel-gaza-war" target="_blank">violence in Gaza</a>, which has claimed nearly 40,00 lives and impacted neighbouring countries, like Syria, Lebanon, Egypt, and Jordan, among other nations - have cancelled, or reduced, flights to and from Tel Aviv.</p>

<p>The result is thousands of people have been left stranded, in Israel and elsewhere, or are scrambling for alternate routes (often at great expense) to get home.</p>

<p>Airlines - including <a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/topic/air-india" target="_blank">Air India</a>, which last week said it was suspending all services to Israel "in view of the ongoing situation in parts of the Middle East" - are in wait-and-watch mode while they assess safety levels and threats to aircraft, crew, and passengers.</p>

<p>Nearly a dozen airlines, including Air India and United Airlines, have cancelled or reduced flights till now. United has stopped all flights indefinitely, while Air India has done so till Thursday.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/air-india-suspends-tel-aviv-flights-amid-escalating-middle-east-tensions-6246272" target="_blank">Air India Suspends israel Flights Amid Escalating Middle East Tensions</a></p>

<p>One of the world's biggest carrier conglomerates - Germany's Lufthansa Group - has suspended all flights, passenger and cargo - to Tel Aviv, also till Thursday.</p>

<p>This is a list of international airlines that have cancelled, or cut, flights to and/or from Israel.</p>

<p><strong>Italian airline ITA&nbsp;</strong>has halted flights to and from the Israeli capital "due to the geopolitical developments in the Middle East and to ensure safety of passengers and crew".</p>

<p>Flights have been suspended till Tuesday.</p>

<p><strong>German carrier Lufthansa Group</strong> and its subsidiaries, including <strong>Switzerland's Swiss International Airlines</strong>, have cancelled all passenger and cargo flights to and from Tel Aviv.</p>

<p>This cancellation is effective till Thursday, when it will be reviewed.</p>

<p>"The reason for this is the current development in the region," a Lufthansa spokesperson said.</p>

<p>Swiss International is suspending flights from Zurich to Tel Aviv (again, till Thursday) and to Beirut (in Lebanon, till Monday next), a company spokesperson said.</p>

<p>Services from the United States have also been affected, with <strong>Delta</strong>, <strong>United Airlines</strong>, and <strong>American Airlines</strong> also halting flights till further notice.</p>

<p>Flagship carriers of Greece (<strong>Aegean Air</strong>) and Poland (<strong>LOT</strong>), as well as budget Hungarian airline <strong>Wizz Air</strong>, followed suit. Aegean and LOT have paused flights till Tuesday and Friday.</p>

<p>Wizz Air had said it was cancelling flights till Sunday; it is unclear if services have resumed.</p>

<p>The Netherlands' flagship, <strong>KLM Airlines</strong>, has stopped flights till Tuesday.</p>

<p>Spain's three biggest carriers - <strong>Iberia Express</strong>, <strong>Vueling</strong>, and <strong>Air Europa</strong> - also briefly cancelled flights. As of this morning Iberia Express and Vueling have re-started flights. Air Europa's services remain suspended till Wednesday.</p>

<p>Several other airlines from European nations, including Belgium and Croatia, have made similar announcements. And it isn't just foreign services.</p>

<p>Israeli low-cost airline <strong>Arkia</strong> had to scramble to bring back hundreds of passengers stuck in Prague in Czechia after the foreign crew of one of its planes refused to fly to Tel Aviv.</p>

<p>Tensions in the Middle East have skyrocketed after Iran and the Hamas, with the Hezbollah, vowed revenge for the assassination of their leaders, which has been blamed on Israel.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-israel-hezbollah-hamas-iran-could-attack-israel-today-netanyahu-eyes-preemptive-strike-report-6264899" target="_blank">Iran Could Attack Israel Today, Netanyahu Eyes Preemptive Strike</a></p>

<p>Tel Aviv has been accused of assassinating Hamas chief Ismail Haniyeh in Tehran in Iran, hours after reportedly killing Hezbollah's military chief Fuad Shukr in Beirut in Lebanon.</p>

<p>United States Secretary of State Antony Blinken has reportedly warned global leaders that an attack by Iran and Hezbollah against Israel could commence at any time. The Times of Israel reported the Benjamin Netanyahu-led government could sanction a pre-emptive strike.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-israel-conflict-gaza-war-hezbollah-hamas-fears-of-all-out-war-grow-in-middle-east-as-iran-israel-conflict-widens-6258750" target="_blank">Fear Of War In Middle East As Iran-Israel Conflict Widens: 10 Facts</a></p>

<p>Concerns have heightened dramatically, as months of cross-border skirmishes risk devolving into a full-scale conflict between Hezbollah and Israel. The two adversaries last engaged in a war in 2006, which saw Israel bombing Lebanon's only passenger airport in Beirut.</p>

<p>The intensity of the current situation has led various embassies, including India's, to urge their citizens to leave Lebanon while some commercial flights remain available. Multiple countries, including the US and the United Kingdom, have issued similar warnings to their citizens.</p>

<p><em>NDTV is now available on WhatsApp channels. <a href="https://www.whatsapp.com/channel/0029Va4lixw7z4kcvZI9JM12">Click on the link</a> to get all the latest updates from NDTV on your chat. </em></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-11/7281frb8_air-india-generic_625x300_24_November_23.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Iran Vs Israel War: The US has reportedly warned of conflict between the two soon (File).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-pm-keir-starmer-calls-for-emergency-meet-as-riots-intensify-6266842]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK PM Keir Starmer Calls For Emergency Meet As Riots Intensify]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-pm-keir-starmer-calls-for-emergency-meet-as-riots-intensify-6266842]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 05 Aug 2024 13:47:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[British Prime Minister Keir Starmer will hold an emergency meeting with police chiefs on Monday after days of violent anti-immigration protests intensified, with buildings and vehicles torched and hotels holding asylum seekers targeted.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>British Prime Minister Keir Starmer will hold an emergency meeting with police chiefs on Monday after days of violent anti-immigration protests intensified, with buildings and vehicles torched and hotels holding asylum seekers targeted.</p>

<p>Riots have erupted across towns and cities in the last week after three girls were killed in a knife attack in Southport in northwest England, with 420 people arrested so far.</p>

<p>The murders were seized on by anti-immigrant and anti-Muslim groups as misinformation spread online that the suspected attacker was a radical Islamist who had just arrived in Britain. Police have said the suspect was born in Britain and are not treating it as a terrorist incident.</p>

<p>Interior Minister Yvette Cooper said rioters had felt "emboldened by this moment to stir up racial hatred", with bricks thrown at police officers, shops looted and mosques and Asian-owned businesses attacked.</p>

<p>Over the weekend riots broke out in Liverpool, Bristol, Tamworth, Middlesbrough and Belfast, in Northern Ireland, with largely young men wearing balaclavas and draped in the British flags hurling rocks and shouting "Stop the Boats", a reference to migrants arriving on the south coast in recent years.</p>

<p>In Rotherham, northern England, protesters sought to break into a hotel that housed asylum seekers.</p>

<h3><strong>Police Blame on Online Disinformation</strong></h3>

<p>Police have blamed online disinformation, amplified by high-profile figures for driving the violence. One of the most prominent of these, Stephen Yaxley-Lennon who led the anti-Islam English Defence League group, has been blamed by media for spreading misinformation to his 875,000 followers on X.</p>

<p>"They are lying to you all," Yaxley-Lennon, who is known by the pseudonym Tommy Robinson, wrote. "Attempting to turn the nation against me. I need you, you are my voice."</p>

<p>Elon Musk, the owner of X, also weighed in on the violence. Responding to a post on X that blamed mass migration and open borders for the disorder in Britain, he wrote: "Civil war is inevitable."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Civil war is inevitable</p>
 Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1819933223536742771?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 4, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Interior Minister Yvette Cooper told broadcasters that tensions had been amplified and inflamed online, and the government would be pursuing the issue with social media companies.</p>

<p>"I think what you've seen is that networks of different individuals and groups that have been trying to fan the flames," she told Sky News, swerving questions on whether foreign states had been involved.</p>

<p>While she said people had views and concerns about issues such as immigration, she blamed extremist, racist, violent groups for the violence.</p>

<p>"Reasonable people who have all those sorts of views and concerns do not pick up bricks and throw them at the police," she said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/repgssu8_keir-starmer-afp_625x300_05_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Police have blamed online disinformation, amplified by high-profile figures for driving the violence.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uks-honey-fraud-crises-explained-beekeepers-scientists-troubled-6266688]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK's Honey Fraud Crises Explained: Beekeepers, Scientists Troubled]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uks-honey-fraud-crises-explained-beekeepers-scientists-troubled-6266688]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 05 Aug 2024 13:32:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The practice of adulterating honey is well known, and historically adulterants such as ash and potato flour have been used. Now, advancements in technology and science have made it much easier, with "bespoke, designer or bioengineered" syrups.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lynne Ingram cuts a peaceful figure as she tends to a row of humming beehives in a leafy corner of Somerset, southwest England.</p>

<p>But the master beekeeper, who has been keeping hives for more than 40 years, has found herself in a fight against a tricky and evolving foe -- honey fraudsters.</p>

<p>The practice of adulterating honey is well known, and historically adulterants such as ash and potato flour have been used.</p>

<p>Now, advancements in technology and science have made it much easier, with "bespoke, designer or bioengineered" syrups used as diluting agents capable of fooling authenticity tests, Ingram said.</p>

<p>She founded the UK Honey Authenticity Network (HAN UK) in 2021 to raise awareness about natural honey and warn of the threat posed by fraud.</p>

<p>"One of the impacts we're seeing all over the world is beekeepers going out of business," she said.</p>

<p>Adulterated honey can be sold to retailers for a price several times lower than genuine producers can afford.</p>

<p>As well as producing their own honey, many larger-scale beekeepers have crop pollination contracts with farmers, delivering thousands of colonies to growers across the country.</p>

<p>If they go out of business due to unfair competition, this vital natural method of pollinating crops is reduced and food production suffers.</p>

<p>The British Beekeepers Association, which represents more than 25,000 producers and where Ingram is a honey ambassador, wants the risk of fraud to be recognised to protect the industry and consumers.</p>

<p>"I'd like to see an acknowledgement that there is actually an issue here," she said.</p>

<h3><strong>Better labelling</strong></h3>

<p>In May, the European Union updated its honey regulations to ensure clearer product labelling and a "honey traceability system" to increase transparency.</p>

<p>On the labelling for blended honeys, for example, all countries of origin are now required to appear near a product's name, where previously it was only mandatory to state whether blending had occurred.</p>

<p>Labelling in the UK, which has now left the EU, is not as stringent and Ingram believes consumers are "being misled" by vague packaging.</p>

<p>Behind the EU action is an apparent increase in adulterated honey arriving in the 27-nation bloc.</p>

<p>The substandard adulterates can have adverse effects on consumers' health, such as raising the risk of diabetes, obesity, and liver or kidney damage.</p>

<p>Between 2021 and 2022, 46 percent of the honey tested as it entered the EU was flagged as potentially fraudulent, up from 14 percent in the 2015-17 period.</p>

<p>Of the suspicious consignments, 74 percent were of Chinese origin.</p>

<p>Honey imported from the UK had a 100-percent suspicion rate.</p>

<p>The EU said this honey was probably produced in third countries and blended again in the UK before being sent to the bloc.</p>

<p>The UK is the second largest importer of honey in terms of volume in the whole of Europe. China is its top supplier.</p>

<p>Not all of the UK's imported honey leaves the country, however. Considerable quantities stay on the domestic market.</p>

<p>"We think there's an awful lot of it on the shelves," said Ingram, adding that adulterated honey was "widely available" in big supermarkets.</p>

<h3><strong>Lasers</strong></h3>

<p>Behind the closed blinds of a research laboratory at Aston University in Birmingham, central England, researchers fighting honey fraud are harnessing cutting-edge technology.</p>

<p>Aston scientists and beekeepers, including Ingram, are using light to reveal the contents of honey samples at the molecular level.</p>

<p>The technique -- known as Fluorescence Excitation-Emission Spectroscopy (FLE) -- involves firing lasers into samples.</p>

<p>The light frequencies re-emitted are then collated into a three-dimensional image -- or "molecular fingerprint" -- of the honey tested.</p>

<p>Alex Rozhin, the project lead and a reader in nanotechnology, said the test "can trace different molecules through the spectrum and confirm which type of biochemicals are present".</p>

<p>In the darkened lab, the light from different honeys is clearly visible.</p>

<p>The first gives off a vivid green and the second a cooler blue, indicating distinct chemical compositions.</p>

<p>Using FLE, Rozhin says his team "can immediately trace a concentration of fraud inside samples" with "different spectral bands corresponding to syrup (or) to natural honey".</p>

<p>Rozhin said FLE is more accurate than existing tests and can provide results far quicker, at a greatly reduced cost and without the need for highly trained personnel.</p>

<p>One of the Aston team's aims is to create a version of FLE that can be used by honey producers or even consumers with scaled-down equipment or eventually just a smartphone.</p>

<p>Rolling the test out like this would also accelerate the creation of a honey database which, through machine learning, could be used as a catalogue of biometric signatures.</p>

<p>"If we get a new sample and it's been tampered with and it's different from how the database is built up, we'll know there's something obscure," said Steven Daniels, an Aston research associate specialising in machine learning.</p>

<p>Ingram said the test could close international gaps in testing methods by establishing a unified standard, but the government needed to monitor the sector too.</p>

<p>"We really need to get to grips with this," she said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/8titciuo_honeybees-generic_625x300_05_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["One of the impacts we're seeing all over the world is beekeepers going out of business" (Generic)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>