<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Sep 2024 03:42:20 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistani-man-arrested-in-canada-for-plotting-terror-attack-on-jews-in-us-6508543]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Pakistani Man Arrested In Canada For Plotting Terror Attack On Jews In US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistani-man-arrested-in-canada-for-plotting-terror-attack-on-jews-in-us-6508543]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Sep 2024 03:10:00 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Pakistani man living in Canada has been arrested on charges of plotting to carry out an attack on Jews in New York City, the US Justice Department said Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Pakistani man living in Canada has been arrested on charges of plotting to carry out an attack on Jews in New York City, the US Justice Department said Friday.</p>

<p>Muhammad Shahzeb Khan, 20, also known as Shahzeb Jadoon, was arrested on Wednesday on charges filed in the United States, the department said.</p>

<p>"The defendant is alleged to have planned a terrorist attack in New York City around October 7 of this year with the stated goal of slaughtering, in the name of (the Islamic State), as many Jewish people as possible," Attorney General Merrick Garland said in a statement.</p>

<p>"Thanks to the investigative work of the FBI, and the quick action of our Canadian law enforcement partners, the defendant was taken into custody," he said.</p>

<p>According to the criminal complaint, Khan planned to travel to New York and carry out a mass shooting in support of IS at a Jewish center in Brooklyn on the anniversary of the October 7 Hamas attack on Israel.</p>

<p>He revealed his plans in conversations with conspirators who were actually undercover law enforcement officers, it said.</p>

<p>Khan was taken into custody by Canadian authorities in the town of Ormstown some 12 miles (19 kilometers) from the US-Canada border.</p>

<p>The Justice Department said it will seek his extradition from Canada.</p>

<p>Khan is charged with attempting to provide material support and resources to a designated foreign terrorist organization. He could face up to 20 years in prison if convicted.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-09/n36j3h0s_canada-police-generic_625x300_27_September_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The accused Muhammad Shahzeb Khan was taken into custody by Canadian authorities. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukraine-shoots-down-27-russian-drones-6508381]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ukraine Shoots Down 27 Russian Drones]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukraine-shoots-down-27-russian-drones-6508381]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Sep 2024 02:07:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ukraine shot down 27 out of 44 Shahed-131 and Shahed-136 drones launched by Russia overnight, the Ukrainian Air Force said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ukraine shot down 27 out of 44 Shahed-131 and Shahed-136 drones launched by Russia overnight, the Ukrainian Air Force said.</p>

<p>Eight drones have disappeared from the radars, while another one has flown in the direction of the Russia-held area in the Donetsk region, it said on Friday in a post on social media app Telegram.</p>

<p>Several drones remained in the Ukrainian airspace as of Friday morning, the Air Force said.</p>

<p>Apart from the drones, Russia fired Kh-59 guided missiles and Kh-31P anti-radiation missiles at Ukraine, Xinhua news agency reported.</p>

<p>In the attack one person was killed and 30 others injured in the town of Pavlograd in the central Dnipropetrovsk region, said regional governor Sergii Lysak.</p>

<p>The air defence was also activated in the Kyiv region, but there were no casualties or damage to critical and housing infrastructure, according to the Kyiv Regional Military Administration.</p>

<p>The governor of the northeastern region of Kharkiv said a missile attack damaged residential buildings and injured three people in the town of Liubotyn on Friday morning.</p>

<p>Lysak said the Air Force shot down five drones and one missile over the region.</p>

<p>Various overnight attacks in this central region injured two people, damaged over 12 homes and impacted power lines and gas pipelines, he added.</p>

<p>Lviv regional authorities said drone debris fell in an industrial zone, setting fire to four trucks. A team of 32 firefighters had doused the fire by Friday morning and the governor reported no injuries during the attack.</p>

<p>Another fire caused by falling debris had been put out in the southern region of Mykolaiv where the Air Force shot down seven drones, its governor said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-04/2134kk8g_ukraine-russia-war-afp-650_625x300_15_April_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Several drones remained in the Ukrainian airspace as of Friday morning, the Air Force said.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-welcomes-new-york-sentencing-delay-6508069]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Did Nothing Wrong": Trump Welcomes New York Sentencing Delay]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-welcomes-new-york-sentencing-delay-6508069]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Sep 2024 00:32:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Republican US presidential candidate Donald Trump on Friday welcomed a delay in his New York hush money fraud case that pushed sentencing on his 34 felony convictions until after the election.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Republican US presidential candidate Donald Trump on Friday welcomed a delay in his New York hush money fraud case that pushed sentencing on his 34 felony convictions until after the election.</p>

<p>"The Manhattan D.A. Witch Hunt has been postponed because everyone realizes that there was NO CASE, I DID NOTHING WRONG!... This case should be rightfully terminated, as we prepare for the Most Important Election in the History of our Country," he posted on his Truth Social platform.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/poomt16k_donald-trump_625x300_06_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[New York Court on Friday delayed Trump's sentencing in hush money case until after November's election.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/weight-speed-of-nepal-plane-in-july-crash-didnt-match-guidelines-finds-probe-6507957]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Speed Of Nepal Plane In July Crash Didn't Match Guidelines, Finds Probe]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/weight-speed-of-nepal-plane-in-july-crash-didnt-match-guidelines-finds-probe-6507957]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Sep 2024 00:00:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The small passenger plane involved in a crash that killed 18 people in Nepal in July was carrying a load and travelling at a speed that did not match guidelines at the time of the accident, a government-led investigation team said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The small passenger plane involved in a crash that killed 18 people in Nepal in July was carrying a load and travelling at a speed that did not match guidelines at the time of the accident, a government-led investigation team said in a preliminary report on Friday.</p>

<p>The aircraft owned by Nepal's Saurya Airlines crashed shortly after taking off from the capital Kathmandu on July 24, killing all 17 passengers and the co-pilot, with only the captain surviving.</p>

<p>The report said the airline had not complied with the "load weighing, loading and securing of load requirements" and that the plane speed given in the "operation flight plan of the event flight, as well as recorded in the FDR, were inconsistent with the Quick Reference Handbook".</p>

<p>"We found problems with the plane's speed and the load it was carrying. Also, proper, secure latching of load was absent," Ratish Chandra Lal Suman, chairman of the probe team, told Reuters by phone.</p>

<p>The panel said that guidelines on baggage and cargo weighing, its distribution and latching should all be adhered to.</p>

<p>The 50-seater CRJ-200 plane carrying two crew members and 17 technicians was heading for regular maintenance to Nepal's new Pokhara airport, which has aircraft maintenance hangars that are unavailable in adequate numbers at Kathmandu airport.</p>

<p>Those on board were Nepali citizens except for one engineer from Yemen.</p>

<p>Nearly 360 people have died in plane or helicopter crashes in the country since 2000.</p>

<p>Nepal has been criticised for its poor air safety record, where many airlines fly to small airports in remote hills and near mountains shrouded in cloud. Nepal is home to eight of the world's 14 tallest mountain peaks.</p>

<p>The country's main airport is ringed by mountains, affecting wind direction and intensity and making takeoff and landing a challenge for pilots.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/fsjl2gf_nepal-plane-crash-_625x300_24_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Nepal has been criticised for its poor air safety record (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/french-mass-rape-suspect-among-worst-sexual-criminals-says-daughter-6507920]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[French Mass Rape Suspect Among "Worst Sexual Criminals," Says Daughter]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/french-mass-rape-suspect-among-worst-sexual-criminals-says-daughter-6507920]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Sep 2024 23:55:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The daughter of a Frenchman on trial for enlisting strangers to rape his drugged wife Friday described him as "likely one of the worst sexual criminals in past 20 years".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The daughter of a Frenchman on trial for enlisting strangers to rape his drugged wife Friday described him as "likely one of the worst sexual criminals in past 20 years".</p>

<p>Dominique Pelicot, a 71-year-old retiree, has admitted to abusing his wife without her knowledge between 2011 and 2020, drugging her with sleeping pills and then recruiting dozens of strangers to rape her in her own home.</p>

<p>"How are we supposed to rebuild ourselves when we know" what he did, said his daughter, 45-year-old Caroline Darian who uses a pen name, speaking in court in the southern city of Avignon on the fifth day of a case that has horrified France.</p>

<p>Pelicot kept meticulous records of the abuse of his wife, which police only discovered by chance after he was caught filming up women's skirts in a supermarket.</p>

<p>For years his wife Gisele Pelicot, now aged 71 and in divorce proceedings, says she was troubled by strange memory lapses until she was contacted by police.</p>

<p>Speaking to the court on Friday morning, their daughter Darian recounted learning of the alleged abuse on November 2, 2020 from her mother after she had spoken to investigators.</p>

<p>"My life was literally turned upside down," Darian said.</p>

<p>"My mother said: 'I spent most of the day at the police station. Your father drugged me to rape me with strangers. I was made to look at the photos.'"</p>

<p>"It was what you call a tipping point, the start of a slow descent into hell where you have no idea how low you will sink," she said, breaking down into tears.</p>

<p>"I called my brothers... We didn't know what was happening to us."</p>

<p>Darian had left the room in tears less than 20 minutes into the second day of the trial on Tuesday, as the presiding judge recounted how naked photomontages of her had also been found on Dominique Pelicot's computer in a folder titled "Around my daughter, naked".</p>

<p>Darian in 2022 wrote a book "Et j'ai cesse de t'appeler papa" ("And I stopped calling you dad") about the effect the discovery of the crimes had on the family.</p>

<p>- 'Utmost restraint' -</p>

<p>Gisele Pelicot has requested the trial of her husband be public to raise awareness about the use of drugs to commit sexual abuse.</p>

<p>The case has shaken France, with many commenting and some even circulating purported lists of the accused online.</p>

<p>Gisele Pelicot and her family through their lawyers on Friday thanked members of the public for their support but called for "the utmost restraint on social media" during the court case.</p>

<p>"Our clients understand perfectly that this case is a tragedy for all families," included those of the defendants, said one of them, Antoine Camus.</p>

<p>Paul-Roger Gontard, the lawyer of two of the accused, praised the move as protecting the families of his clients and other suspects who could be found innocent.</p>

<p>At least one person has set up a crowdfunding campaign for the family.</p>

<p>Gisele Pelicot "does not wish for any crowdfunding campaigns to be launched and requests any already existing be ended," her attorneys Camus and Stephane Babonneau also wrote in a statement.</p>

<p>The investigators counted around 200 instances of rape, most of them by Gisele Pelicot's husband and more than 90 by strangers.</p>

<p>Investigators drew up a list of 72 suspects besides the husband, and have so far managed to identify 50 of them, aged between 26 and 74, all on trial.</p>

<p>Gisele Pelicot said on Thursday she had recognised only one of her alleged rapists, a man who had come to discuss cycling with her husband at their home, and whom later used to greet at the bakery.</p>

<p>Most of the suspects face up to 20 years in jail for aggravated rape if convicted.</p>

<p>Eighteen of the 51 accused are in custody, including Dominique Pelicot. Thirty-two other defendants are attending the trial as free men. The last is being tried in absentia.</p>

<p>The trial is to last until December 20.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/9v8di4hg_dominique-pelicot-courtroom-sketch_625x300_06_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Dominique Pelicot kept meticulous records of the abuse of his wife]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-strikes-kill-27-palestinians-in-gaza-as-polio-vaccination-resumes-6507867]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israeli Strikes Kill 27 Palestinians In Gaza As Polio Vaccination Resumes]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-strikes-kill-27-palestinians-in-gaza-as-polio-vaccination-resumes-6507867]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Sep 2024 23:45:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli military strikes killed at least 27 Palestinians across the Gaza Strip on Friday, medics said, as health officials resumed vaccination of tens of thousands more children in the enclave against polio.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli military strikes killed at least 27 Palestinians across the Gaza Strip on Friday, medics said, as health officials resumed vaccination of tens of thousands more children in the enclave against polio.</p>

<p>In Nuseirat, one of the territory's eight historic refugee camps, an Israeli airstrike killed two women and two children, while eight other people were killed in two other airstrikes in Gaza City, the medics said. The rest were killed in subsequent strikes across the enclave, they added.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Israeli forces battled Hamas-led militants in the Zeitoun suburb of Gaza City, where residents said tanks have been operating for over a week, in eastern neighbourhoods of Khan Younis, and in Rafah, near the border with Egypt, where residents said Israeli forces blew up several houses.</p>

<p>Eleven months into the war, multiple rounds of diplomacy have so far failed to clinch a ceasefire deal to end the conflict and bring the release of Israeli and foreign hostages held in Gaza as well as many Palestinians jailed in Israel.</p>

<p>The two warring sides continued to blame one another for the fruitless efforts of mediators including Qatar, Egypt and the United States. The US is preparing to present a new ceasefire proposal to hammer out differences, but prospects of a breakthrough remain dim as gaps between the sides remain wide.</p>

<p>On Thursday, US Secretary of State Antony Blinken said that it was incumbent on both Israel and the Palestinian Islamist group Hamas to say yes on remaining issues to reach a Gaza ceasefire deal.</p>

<p>Nearly 90% of the Gaza ceasefire deal is agreed but critical issues remain where there are gaps, including the so-called Philadelphi corridor along Gaza's southern border with Egypt, Blinken told a press briefing. Israel has said it will not leave the corridor; Hamas says a deal isn't possible unless it does.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, residents of Khan Younis and displaced families from Rafah continued to crowd medical facilities, bringing their children to be vaccinated against polio. The campaign was launched after the discovery of a case of a one-year-old baby who was partially paralyzed.</p>

<p><strong>Polio Campaign To Move To North Gaza</strong></p>

<p>This was the first known case of the disease in Gaza - one of the world's most densely populated places - in 25 years. It re-emerged as Gaza's health system has virtually collapsed and many hospitals have been knocked out of action due to the war.</p>

<p>The United Nations agency for Palestinian refugees, UNRWA, said at least 160,000 children received the drops in southern areas of Gaza on Thursday where medical staffers began the second stage of the campaign, benefiting from an Israeli and Hamas agreement on limited pauses in the fighting.</p>

<p>"Since 1 September @UNRWA &amp; partners have vaccinated nearly 355,000 children against #polio in #Gaza middle &amp; southern areas," UNRWA said in a post on X.</p>

<p>"In the next few days we'll continue rolling out the polio vaccination campaign aiming to reach around 640,000 children under 10 with this critical vaccine," it added.</p>

<p>Juliette Touma, UNRWA's Director of Communications, hailed the campaign as very welcome progress. She said UNRWA was working with UNICEF, the World Health Organization and local health partners around the clock and in a race against time to vaccinate every child across the Gaza Strip.</p>

<p>"These temporary pauses do not however replace our calls for a ceasefire, it's long overdue. It's time to reach a deal that would bring respite for the people in Gaza, release all hostages and bring in a steady flow of commercial and humanitarian supplies into Gaza," Touma told Reuters.</p>

<p>The campaign will shift on Sunday to the northern Gaza Strip, which has been the focus of the major Israeli military offensive in the past 11 months. According to the World Health Organization, a second round of vaccinations would be required four weeks after the first round.</p>

<p>The latest bloodshed in the decades-old Israeli-Palestinian conflict was triggered last Oct. 7 when Hamas-led militants stormed into Israel, killing 1,200 and taking about 250 hostages, according to Israeli tallies.</p>

<p>Israel's subsequent assault on the Hamas-governed enclave has since killed over 40,800 Palestinians, according to the local health ministry, while also displacing nearly the entire population of 2.3 million, causing a hunger crisis and leading to genocide allegations at the World Court that Israel denies.</p>

<p>According to the United Nations, at least 1.9 million people - or nine in 10 -across the Gaza Strip are internally displaced, including people who have uprooted up to 10 times or more.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/jnn5lhqg_gaza-polio-vaccination_625x300_06_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel-Gaza war has been going on since October 7 (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-york-judge-delays-donald-trump-hush-money-sentencing-until-after-polls-6507782]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[New York Judge Delays Donald Trump Hush Money Sentencing Until After Polls]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-york-judge-delays-donald-trump-hush-money-sentencing-until-after-polls-6507782]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Sep 2024 23:28:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The New York judge who presided over Donald Trump's hush money trial on Friday delayed sentencing until after November's US presidential election.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The New York judge who presided over Donald Trump's hush money trial on Friday delayed sentencing until after November's US presidential election.</p>

<p>The Republican White House candidate had been scheduled to be sentenced on September 18 for falsifying business records during a scheme to silence a porn star.</p>

<p>Instead, Judge Juan Merchan postponed it to November 26 -- well past the November 5 election in which Trump faces Vice President Kamala Harris.</p>

<p>Trump's lawyers had sought the delay.</p>

<p>Trump was convicted in May of 34 counts of doctoring business records to cover up hush money payments to porn star Stormy Daniels to stop her from publishing her account of an alleged sexual encounter on the eve of the 2016 election.</p>

<p>He was originally scheduled to be sentenced on July 11 but that was delayed after the Supreme Court ruled that a former US president has broad immunity from criminal prosecution.</p>

<p>Trump's lawyers had asked that his New York conviction be dismissed following the Supreme Court immunity ruling.</p>

<p>Merchan said he would rule on the dismissal motion on November 12 and delayed sentencing until after the election.</p>

<p>"This is not a decision this Court makes lightly but it is the decision which in this Court's view, best advances the interests of justice," he said.</p>

<p>Trump in theory faces up to four years in prison on each count. However, he is considered more likely to receive probation.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/q5p67c08_donald-trump-reuters_625x300_06_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Trump's lawyers had sought the delay. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/17-boys-killed-70-missing-after-fire-breaks-out-in-kenya-school-dorm-6507766]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[17 Boys Killed, 70 Missing After Fire Breaks Out In Kenya School Dorm]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/17-boys-killed-70-missing-after-fire-breaks-out-in-kenya-school-dorm-6507766]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Sep 2024 23:22:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[At least 17 young boys were killed and 70 missing after a fire ripped through a primary school dormitory in central Kenya, officials said Friday, leaving distraught relatives desperate for news of their loved ones.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At least 17 young boys were killed and 70 missing after a fire ripped through a primary school dormitory in central Kenya, officials said Friday, leaving distraught relatives desperate for news of their loved ones.</p>

<p>The blaze at the Hillside Endarasha Academy in Nyeri county began around midnight, engulfing rooms where more than 150 boys were sleeping.</p>

<p>"We still have 70 kids that are unaccounted -- that does not mean they are perished or they are injured... the word is that they are unaccounted for," Deputy President Rigathi Gachagua told reporters at the scene, adding that 27 children were in hospital.</p>

<p>Police said earlier that 17 children had been confirmed dead.</p>

<p>"The bodies recovered at the scene were burnt beyond recognition," national police spokesperson Resila Onyango told AFP.</p>

<p>But Gachagua said the number of dead was not verified, urging relatives and members of the community to help in tracing the missing.</p>

<p>He described the scene as "gory" and said painstaking investigative work using DNA would be required to help identify the victims.</p>

<p>The government said the dormitory housed boys between grades four to eight, meaning the victims were aged between nine and 12 or 13.</p>

<p>Tensions were rising among families gathered at the school for news, and many broke down into wailing and tears after officials took them to see the charred bodies in the destroyed dorm.</p>

<p>"Please look for my kid. He can't be dead. I want my child," one woman said in distress as she left the school.</p>

<p><strong>'Panic mode'</strong></p>

<p>The cause of the inferno was not yet known but Kenya's National Gender and Equality Commission said initial reports indicated the dorm was "overcrowded, in violation of safety standards" and called for an immediate inquiry.</p>

<p>"We parents are in panic mode," said Timothy Kinuthia, who has been hunting for news of his 13-year-old boy.</p>

<p>"We have been here since 5:00 am and we have been told nothing."</p>

<p>AFP footage showed the blackened shell of the dormitory, with its corrugated iron roof completely collapsed.</p>

<p>The destroyed building was sealed off by yellow police tape, with officers stationed at all access points.</p>

<p>The school, which reportedly catered to some 800 children, is located in a semi-rural area around 170 kilometres (100 miles) north of the capital Nairobi.</p>

<p>An AFP journalist saw survivors wrapped in blue blankets against the cold, being loaded into school buses.</p>

<p>Alice Wanjiku said she had come from Nairobi to search for her orphaned nephew.</p>

<p>"We have not heard anything since morning. I will camp here until I find our baby. He is the joy of our family and I hope to find him."</p>

<p><strong>'Traumatised' children</strong></p>

<p>Speaking at the scene, Interior Minister Kithure Kindiki said some of the pupils had ended up in neighbouring homes.</p>

<p>"There are some children who are alive and well, but they are of course traumatised and they are in the hands of those who gave them refuge last night," said Kindiki.</p>

<p>President William Ruto, currently in Bejing for a China-Africa summit, expressed his condolences in a post on X.</p>

<p>He instructed officials to "thoroughly investigate this horrific incident", and promised that those responsible will be "held to account".</p>

<p>The Kenyan Red Cross said it was on the ground assisting a multi-agency response team and providing psychosocial support.</p>

<p>There have been numerous school fires in Kenya and across East Africa.</p>

<p>In 2016, nine students were killed by a fire at a girls' high school in the sprawling slum neighbourhood of Kibera in Nairobi.</p>

<p>In 2001, 67 pupils were killed in an arson attack on their dormitory at the Kyanguli Mixed Secondary School David Mutiso in Kenya's southern Machakos district.</p>

<p>Two pupils were charged with murder, and the headmaster and deputy of the school were convicted of negligence.</p>

<p>In 1994, 40 school children were burned alive and 47 injured in a fire that ravaged the Shauritanga Secondary School for Girls in the northern region of Kilimanjaro in Tanzania.</p>

<p>In 2022, a blaze ravaged a school for the blind in eastern Uganda. Eleven pupils died after they were trapped inside their shared bedroom because the building had been burglar-proofed, government ministers said at the time.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/lf2eso0o_kenya-school-fire_625x300_06_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The school reportedly catered to some 800 children]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-troops-shoot-turkish-american-woman-dead-at-west-bank-protest-6507724]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israeli Troops Shoot Turkish-American Woman Dead At West Bank Protest]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-troops-shoot-turkish-american-woman-dead-at-west-bank-protest-6507724]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Sep 2024 23:18:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli troops shot and killed a Turkish-American woman who had been taking part in a protest against settlement expansion in the Israeli-occupied West Bank on Friday, Palestinian and Turkish officials said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli troops shot and killed a Turkish-American woman who had been taking part in a protest against settlement expansion in the Israeli-occupied West Bank on Friday, Palestinian and Turkish officials said.</p>

<p>The White House said it was deeply disturbed by the death of Aysenur Ezgi Eygi and called on Israel to investigate. Turkey's foreign ministry said she was shot in the head, and placed blame on Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's government for her death.</p>

<p>Palestinian officials described her as a 26-year-old activist who held both US and Turkish citizenship.</p>

<p>Israel's military said its troops had fired toward a male "main instigator" who posed a threat by hurling rocks at soldiers.</p>

<p>The military was looking into reports that a female foreign national "was killed as a result of shots fired in the area. The details of the incident and the circumstances in which she was hit are under review."</p>

<p>There was no immediate comment on the incident from Netanyahu's office.</p>

<p>Fouad Nafaa, head of Rafidia Hospital in Nablus, told Reuters that Eygi arrived there in critical condition, with a serious head injury.</p>

<p>"We tried to perform a resuscitation operation on her, but unfortunately she died," he said.</p>

<p>The Palestinian Authority's official news agency, WAFA, said the incident occurred during a regular protest march by activists in Beita, a village near Nablus that has seen repeated attacks on Palestinians by Jewish settlers.</p>

<p><strong>"Deeply Disturbed"</strong></p>

<p>In a statement, Sean Savett, a spokesperson for the White House's National Security Council, said Washington was "deeply distributed by the tragic death of an American citizen" in the West Bank on Friday.</p>

<p>"We have reached out to the Government of Israel to ask for more information and request an investigation into the incident," Savett said.</p>

<p>Turkey's President Tayyip Erdogan condemned Eygi's death, saying in a post on social media that Turkey "will continue to work in every platform to halt Israel's policy of occupation and genocide". Israel denies its actions in occupied Palestinian territories amount to genocide.</p>

<p>In a separate incident in the West Bank village of Qaryut on Friday, a 13-year-old girl was killed during clashes with Israeli forces, Palestinian health officials said, after settlers attacked two residents there.</p>

<p>WAFA quoted the girl's father as saying that she was in their home when it was hit by gunfire. The Israeli military said it was looking into the report.</p>

<p>Since the 1967 Middle East war, Israel has occupied the West Bank of the Jordan River, which Palestinians want as the core of an independent state. Israel has built Jewish settlements there that most countries deem illegal, which Israel disputes citing historical and biblical ties to the land.</p>

<p>A rise in violent attacks by Israeli settlers on Palestinians in the West Bank has stirred anger among Western allies of Israel, including the United States, which has imposed sanctions on some Israelis involved in the settler movement.</p>

<p>Several weeks ago around 100 settlers attacked the village of Jit, in the northern West Bank, drawing worldwide condemnation and an Israeli government promise of swift action against anyone found guilty of violence.</p>

<p>Palestinians and human rights groups regularly accuse Israeli forces of standing by as attacks take place and even joining in themselves.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/n9ofku8o_west-bank_625x300_06_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[There was no immediate comment on the incident from Netanyahu's office. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/indy-nelson-man-who-visited-every-country-had-to-prove-hes-not-a-spy-4-times-6507497]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Man Who Visited Every Country Had To Prove He's Not A Spy 4 Times]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/indy-nelson-man-who-visited-every-country-had-to-prove-hes-not-a-spy-4-times-6507497]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Sep 2024 22:31:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Indy Nelson, a seasoned American traveler, has visited every country in the world, often facing unique challenges along the way.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Travel enthusiasts often face a variety of challenges when crossing multiple international borders. These can range from document issues like passport renewals and ID verification to money-related concerns, and most commonly, language barriers. One seasoned traveler, however, has encountered a more unusual problem-having to prove he's not a spy on four separate occasions to avoid imprisonment during his journeys. Extended travel comes with its own set of complications, as demonstrated by American globetrotter Indy Nelson, who has visited every country in the world, including repeat trips to places like North Korea. His remarkable travels have been met with unique obstacles along the way.</p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.guinnessworldrecords.com/news/2024/9/man-who-broke-record-visiting-every-country-had-to-prove-hes-not-a-spy-four-times"><em>Guinness World Records</em></a>, Indy Nelson has navigated his way through numerous war-torn areas and been detained four times on suspicion of being a spy (in Iran, Libya, Papua New Guinea and Russia).But it was all worth it, because he now holds a Guinness World Records title: the most airlines flown on.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/o9mpq8oo_guinness-world-records_625x300_06_September_24.jpg?im=FitAndFill,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: Guinness World Records</span></p>
</div>

<p>Indy has flown on 170 unique airlines, most of them during an 18-month trip around the world which he embarked on in 2017, aged 22.The previous record was 156, achieved by a Japanese man named Ryuji Furusho from 1996 to 2014.</p>

<p>Adding up the four times he was detained, Indy was interrogated for a total of 24 hours.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"I feared for my life several times," he told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.guinnessworldrecords.com/news/2024/9/man-who-broke-record-visiting-every-country-had-to-prove-hes-not-a-spy-four-times"><em>Guinness World Records.</em></a> "There were definitely several times that I did not think that I was going to get out of that country. By the fourth time, it was like 'no big deal anymore.'"</p>

<p>Indy's least favourite country was the Comoros, a small group of islands off the southeastern coast of Africa, where he had encounters with "not too friendly" people. His favourite, on the other hand, was Cambodia, where he enjoyed the culture and "super friendly" locals.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/0pradn6g_guinness-world-records_625x300_06_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Indy Nelson now holds World Record for flying on the most airlines-170 in total.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-calls-for-assault-weapons-ban-a-day-after-georgia-school-shooting-in-united-states-6507449]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Joe Biden Calls For Assault Weapons Ban After Yet Another US School Shooting]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-calls-for-assault-weapons-ban-a-day-after-georgia-school-shooting-in-united-states-6507449]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Sep 2024 22:23:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A day after a shooting incident in United State's Georgia left four people dead, US President Joe Biden has called for a complete ban on assault weapons.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A day after a shooting incident in United State's Georgia left four people dead, US President Joe Biden has called for a complete ban on assault weapons.</p>

<p>Speaking at an event on Thursday, President Biden said, "I'd like to say a few words about the school shooting yesterday. As a nation, we cannot continue to accept the carnage of gun violence. I'm a gun owner. I believe strongly in the amendment. We need more than thoughts and prayers," CNN quoted the president as saying.</p>

<p>While urging the US Congress to take strong action for gun control in the US, he reached out to Republican lawmakers, saying some of its leaders should "finally say enough is enough", adding that "We have to do something together. Let's ban assault weapons."</p>

<p>Mr Biden further said, "I realise I'm in a rural area, like the rural parts of my state, where guns -- we all have them and it's not popular to talk about it, but the truth is, there's a difference between rational and irrational."</p>

<p>He acknowledged that the decision "won't bring back those children." However, it would "help save lives if we do the things we're talking about." He went on to say, "We can do if we do it together...and I really think we can."</p>

<p><strong>JOE BIDEN'S APPEAL</strong></p>

<p>Joe Biden has been appealing for a total ban on assault weapons across the United States. He has been calling for the ban for a long time, but has been stymied by Republican leaders in Congress.</p>

<p>Mr Biden also called for proper check of background checks, an end to immunity for gun manufacturers and for parents who allow their children to have weapons to be held accountable, according to a CNN report.</p>

<p><strong>SCHOOL SHOOTING IN GEORGIA</strong></p>

<p>At least four people, including two students, were killed and nine others wounded when a another student from the same high school opened fire in the US state of Georgia on Wednesday.</p>

<p>The suspected gunman was caught and is currently in custody. He was identified as 14-year-old Colt Cray, a student of Apalachee High School in Winder, Georgia, which is around an hour's drive from state capital Atlanta.</p>

<p>Two of the people killed were students and two were teachers. Law enforcement agencies are still investigating the shooting and the motive behind it.</p>

<p><strong>USA's GUN VIOLENCE PROBLEM</strong></p>

<p>The school shooting in Georgia is the latest among dozens across the US in recent years, including deadly ones in Connecticut, Parkland, Florida, Newtown, and Uvalde, Texas.</p>

<p>So far, at least 385 mass shooting incidents have taken place in the US in 2024, according to the Gun Violence Archive, which, like CNN, considers mass shootings as those in which four or more victims are shot. That's an average of more than 1.5 mass shootings every day.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/vj7m4c84_joe-biden-afp-joe-biden-white-house-afp_625x300_06_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden has called for a complete ban on assault weapons.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pavel-durov-private-chats-no-longer-safe-telegram-to-moderate-after-ceos-france-arrest-6507262]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Private Chat No Longer Safe? Telegram To Moderate After CEO's France Arrest]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pavel-durov-private-chats-no-longer-safe-telegram-to-moderate-after-ceos-france-arrest-6507262]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Sep 2024 21:59:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Following CEO Pavel Durov's arrest in France, Telegram has made changes to its privacy policies, removing an earlier commitment to protect user data from law enforcement.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a covert upgrade, Telegram deleted an earlier guarantee that it wouldn't assist law enforcement in obtaining user data. <em>The Verge</em> revealed this modification on September 5, which raises questions about the platform's dedication to customer confidentiality. Contrary to WhatsApp and Signal, Telegram does not automatically encrypt conversations, which might put user information at risk.</p>

<p>The FAQ originally stated, "All Telegram chats and group chats are private amongst their participants. We do not process any requests related to them." However, this language has been replaced with instructions for reporting illegal content. The updated section now informs users that all Telegram apps have "Report" buttons, enabling users to flag inappropriate material quickly. Additionally, Telegram has provided an email address, abuse@telegram.org, for automated takedown requests. This update has hinted at the shifting landscape of online privacy as platforms like Telegram adapt their policies in response to legal pressures.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/9/5/24237254/telegram-pavel-durov-arrest-private-chats-moderation-policy-change"><em>The Verge </em></a>has reported Telegram spokesperson Remi Vaughn as saying the app's source code has not changed. "Private chats are still private too, although you could always report a new incoming chat to moderators by using Block &gt; Report. Anyone can check Telegram's open source code and see there were no changes."</p>

<p>CEO Pavel Durov issued his first public statement since his arrest on Thursday evening and said, "Telegram's abrupt increase in user count to 950 million caused growing pains that made it easier for criminals to abuse our platform."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">I'm still trying to understand what happened in France. But we hear the concerns. I made it my personal goal to prevent abusers of Telegram's platform from interfering with the future of our 950+ million users.<br />
<br />
My full post below. <a href="https://t.co/cDvRSodjst">https://t.co/cDvRSodjst</a></p>
â€” Pavel Durov (@durov) <a href="https://twitter.com/durov/status/1831826862936633657?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 5, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>"That's why I made it my personal goal to ensure we significantly improve things in this regard. We've already started that process internally, and I will share more details on our progress with you very soon."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/m7qorqqs_pavel-durov_625x300_29_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[This change follows the recent arrest of Telegram founder Pavel Durov in France.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/apple-event-2024-apple-glowtime-event-2024-everything-to-expect-from-apples-iphone-16-launch-on-september-9-6506923]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Apple Event 2024: Everything To Expect From Apple's iPhone 16 Launch]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/apple-event-2024-apple-glowtime-event-2024-everything-to-expect-from-apples-iphone-16-launch-on-september-9-6506923]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Sep 2024 21:05:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Apple Inc.'s most important event of the year takes place Monday, when the company will roll out its latest iPhones and set the stage for a new artificial intelligence platform.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Apple Inc.'s most important event of the year takes place Monday, when the company will roll out its latest iPhones and set the stage for a new artificial intelligence platform.</p>

<p>The event kicks off from Apple's headquarters in Cupertino, California, on Sept. 9 at 10 a.m. local time. Apple doesn't typically hold this event on a Monday, but the earlier timing lets the company get out ahead of an eventful Tuesday: There's a US presidential debate that day, and the European Commission is slated to announce a decision on whether Apple has to pay $14 billion in taxes stemming from a longstanding agreement with Ireland.</p>

<p>The most significant product announcement will be the iPhone 16 line, but the company is also preparing major updates to both the Apple Watch and AirPods. Apple Intelligence - a new suite of AI tools that includes an updated Siri digital assistant - also will feature prominently. The theme of the event, "It's Glowtime," is a reference to Siri's new interface.</p>

<p>The stakes are high for Apple, which looks to prove to both consumers and Wall Street that it's now a major player in generative artificial intelligence. But the company's AI technology is still a work in progress. Apple Intelligence has faced numerous delays, and many key features won't arrive until next year. For now, the technology is focused on summarizing messages and notifications, rather than matching the dazzling interactivity of rival systems.</p>

<p>Even so, Monday's updates will breathe new life into products that sit at the heart of the Apple device lineup and generate roughly 60% of the company's annual revenue. They also drive consumer spending on services, an increasingly vital source of sales. Apple's finances could use the boost. The company has only just begun to emerge from its longest sales slump in decades.</p>

<p><strong>Here's everything that's expected to be announced at Monday's presentation:</strong></p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Apple's iPhone 15 Pro.(Photographer: David Paul Morris / Bloomberg)" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/9eb18i6o_apple-iphone-bloomberg_625x300_06_September_24.jpg" title="Apple's iPhone 15 Pro.(Photographer: David Paul Morris / Bloomberg)" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">Apple's iPhone 15 Pro.(Photographer: David Paul Morris / Bloomberg)</p>
</div>

<p><strong>iPHONE</strong></p>

<p>In line with the past several years, Apple will introduce four new iPhone models: the iPhone 16, 16 Plus, 16 Pro and 16 Pro Max.</p>

<p>Like in 2023, the changes to the non-Pro iPhones will be minor. The iPhone 16 and 16 Plus will look like last year's versions, including 6.1-inch and 6.7-inch screen sizes and aluminum cases. They'll gain faster processors and include a total of 8 gigabytes of memory (up from 6). That memory will help support Apple Intelligence and other features.</p>

<p>Those lower-end phones will get the same Action button currently featured on the Pro models, as well as vertically stacked rear cameras that support spatial video recording - the 3D clips that can be viewed with Apple's Vision Pro headsets.</p>

<p>The iPhone 16 Pro and Pro Max, meanwhile, will retain the iPhone 15 Pro line design save for one noticeable change: the displays. The screen sizes are increasing to 6.3 inches on the smaller model (up from from 6.1 inches) and going to 6.9 inches from 6.7 inches on the Max version. While the changes represent an increase of less than 5% on both models, the shift will come with bezels that are now about a third slimmer. That should make for a sleeker overall look.</p>

<p>Like the iPhone 15 Pro line, the 16 Pro models will support Apple Intelligence with the inclusion of 8 gigabytes of memory. They'll also get speedier chips with an enhanced neural engine that Apple will say is optimized for AI.</p>

<p>Both of the iPhone 16 Pro models will get camera upgrades as well, including a move to a 48-megapixel lens from a 12-megapixel one for the ultrawide-angle camera. That will match the megapixels of the standard, wide-angle camera on last year's model. The smaller iPhone 16 Pro will also gain 5x optical zoom on the telephoto lens, up from 3x, to match the Max version.</p>

<p>The most significant camera enhancement coming to both models: a dedicated, touch-sensitive button on the right side of the phone for taking photos and video. This button will be the biggest selling point for the new iPhones, other than AI. It will work similarly to a shutter button on a DSLR camera, allowing a user to lightly press it to focus on a subject and then press harder to take a picture. It will also be capacitive, allowing a user to swipe across it to move between still and video modes and zoom in and out.</p>

<p>While the phones will all look mostly the same as last year, Apple is shaking up its color palette. The Pro models will now come in a gold titanium to replace blue titanium, while the black, white and natural options will still be available. The non-Pro versions will trade in yellow for white and get new shades of green, pink and blue.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="An AirPods display at an Apple retail store. (Photographer: Hollie Adams / Bloomberg)" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/uika34ag_apple-airpods-bloomberg_625x300_06_September_24.jpg" title="An AirPods display at an Apple retail store. (Photographer: Hollie Adams / Bloomberg)" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">An AirPods display at an Apple retail store. (Photographer: Hollie Adams / Bloomberg)</p>
</div>

<p><strong>AIRPODS</strong></p>

<p>Apple is preparing two new AirPods models to replace the entry-level, second-generation earbuds and mid-tier, third-generation model. Both new versions will look similar to the AirPods Pro and include a new case, USB-C charging and improved audio quality.</p>

<p>Apple will distinguish the two models by giving the new mid-tier version a higher-end case with a speaker - making it easier to locate with Apple's Find My feature - as well as noise cancellation to match the AirPods Pro.</p>

<p>A few weeks ago, Apple discovered a bug in the upcoming AirPods that made the earbuds quickly drain battery life. This issue was determined to be software-related and resolved prior to factories shipping out the products.</p>

<p>One major new feature is a bigger push into hearing health. Apple has been working to turn the AirPods into a replacement for hearing aids as well as a device for conducting hearing tests. The company is preparing to announce the enhancements - codenamed Yodel - but they've suffered some delays and may not be available until later.</p>

<p>A new version of the AirPods Pro remains in the works, including an upgraded design and improved noise cancellation. It's due as early as next year.</p>

<p>And Apple has been working on updated AirPods Max headphones that will come in new colors and switch the Lightning connector to USB-C to comply with the latest laws from the European Union. But there's still plenty of current AirPods Max inventory on hand, suggesting that the update could be coming later.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="The Apple Watch Ultra 2. (Photographer: David Paul Morris / Bloomberg)" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/v974p7o4_apple-watch-ultra-2-bloomberg_625x300_06_September_24.jpg" title="The Apple Watch Ultra 2. (Photographer: David Paul Morris / Bloomberg)" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">The Apple Watch Ultra 2. (Photographer: David Paul Morris / Bloomberg)</p>
</div>

<p><strong>APPLE WATCH</strong></p>

<p>For the first time in two years, the company is preparing to update all of its Apple Watch models at once. There will be a new low-end Apple Watch SE, a mid-level Series 10 model and an Ultra 3.</p>

<p>The Apple Watch Ultra will only get minor tweaks, focusing on internal upgrades rather than outside changes.</p>

<p>The biggest upgrade to the Apple Watch line will be with the Series 10 model, which marks the decade anniversary of the product's introduction in 2014. For the first time since the Series 7, the flagship Apple Watch model will get an updated look.</p>

<p>The overall design will be similar to the Apple Watch Series 9, but the company will now offer slightly larger screen-size options and the watch case itself will be noticeably thinner.</p>

<p>Though new AI features are coming to the iPhone, iPad and Mac, don't expect the watches to get major Apple Intelligence capabilities. Any AI technology will probably be tied specifically to a future health coach service.</p>

<p>At the start of the year, Apple was forced to remove blood-oxygen sensing from new watches due to a lawsuit with Masimo Corp. over patents. There's been no evidence that the feature is returning in time for the latest models, and that may affect whether users want to upgrade their existing watches to versions that won't have the function.</p>

<p>A major new health feature is coming, though: sleep apnea detection, which will build on the existing sleep tracking. This feature will attempt to determine if a wearer has sleep apnea and then suggest further testing with a medical professional. While Apple has been preparing to announce it, the enhancement may not be available on day one of the new model going on sale.</p>

<p>On the other hand, while Apple aimed to bring hypertension - or high blood pressure - detection to the Apple Watch this year, signs point to that feature being delayed and no longer in the cards for an immediate release.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Apple's MacBook Pro. (Photographer: Samsul Said / Bloomberg)" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/11iik5sk_apple-macbook-pro-bloomberg_625x300_06_September_24.jpg" title="Apple's MacBook Pro. (Photographer: Samsul Said / Bloomberg)" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">Apple's MacBook Pro. (Photographer: Samsul Said / Bloomberg)</p>
</div>

<p><strong>OTHER PRODUCTS</strong></p>

<p>Apple is working on transitioning its entire Mac line to M4 chips, starting with the MacBook Pro, Mac mini and iMac. But any Mac upgrades are likely to come at a follow-up launch - no earlier than October - rather than at the September event.</p>

<p>While the company has been working on an update to the Apple TV set-top box for as early as this year, no new model has come to fruition and stable inventory of the device suggests a new version isn't on the immediate horizon.</p>

<p>A new iPhone SE with an OLED display, edge-to-edge screen and no home button is in advanced testing, but a release isn't planned until next year. A fresh AirTag is also in development, though Apple isn't planning a release until next year either.</p>

<p>There are also new iPads in the works, including an upgraded mini version. They're on deck for Apple's October event alongside the M4 Macs.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/c9mf5958_apple-logo-apple-event-reuters_625x300_06_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Apple Event: Apple Glowtime Event, where the iPhone 16 will be launched, is scheduled for September 9]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-iraq-deal-would-see-hundreds-of-troops-withdraw-in-1st-year-report-6506853]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US-Iraq Deal Would See Hundreds Of Troops Withdraw In 1st Year: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-iraq-deal-would-see-hundreds-of-troops-withdraw-in-1st-year-report-6506853]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:53:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United States and Iraq have reached an understanding on plans for the withdrawal of US-led coalition forces from Iraq, according to multiple sources familiar with the matter.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United States and Iraq have reached an understanding on plans for the withdrawal of US-led coalition forces from Iraq, according to multiple sources familiar with the matter.</p>

<p>The plan, which has been broadly agreed but requires a final go-ahead from both capitals and an announcement date, would see hundreds of troops leave by September 2025, with the remainder departing by the end of 2026, the sources said.</p>

<p>"We have an agreement, its now just a question of when to announce it," a senior US official said.</p>

<p>The US and Iraq are also seeking to establish a new advisory relationship that could see some US troops remain in Iraq after the drawdown.</p>

<p>An official announcement was initially scheduled for weeks ago but was postponed due to regional escalation related to Israel's war in Gaza and to iron out some remaining details, the sources said.</p>

<p>The sources include five US officials, two officials from other coalition nations, and three Iraqi officials, all speaking on condition of anonymity as they were not authorized to discuss the matter publicly.</p>

<p>Several sources said the deal could be announced this month.</p>

<p>Farhad Alaaldin, foreign affairs adviser to the Iraqi prime minister, said technical talks with Washington on the coalition drawdown had concluded.</p>

<p>"We are now on the brink of transitioning the relationship between Iraq and members of the international coalition to a new level, focusing on bilateral relations in military, security, economic, and cultural areas," he said.</p>

<p>He did not comment on details of the plan and the US-led coalition did not respond to emailed questions.</p>

<p>The agreement follows more than six months of talks between Baghdad and Washington, initiated by Prime Minister Mohammed Shia al-Sudani in January amid attacks by Iran-backed Iraqi armed groups on US forces stationed at Iraqi bases.</p>

<p>The rocket and drone attacks have killed three American troops and wounded dozens more, resulting in several rounds of deadly US retaliation that threatened government efforts to stabilize Iraq after decades of conflict.</p>

<p>The US has approximately 2,500 troops in Iraq and 900 in neighbouring Syria as part of the coalition formed in 2014 to combat Islamic State as it rampaged through the two countries.</p>

<p>The group once held roughly a third of Iraq and Syria but was territorially defeated in Iraq at the end of 2017 and in Syria in 2019. Iraq had demonstrated its ability to handle any remaining threat, Alaaldin said.</p>

<p>The US initially invaded Iraq in 2003, toppling dictator Saddam Hussein before withdrawing in 2011, but returned in 2014 at the head of the coalition to fight Islamic State.</p>

<p>Other nations, including Germany, France, Spain, and Italy, also contribute hundreds of troops to the coalition.</p>

<p>Under the plan, all coalition forces would leave the Ain al-Asad airbase in western Anbar province and significantly reduce their presence in Baghdad by September 2025.</p>

<p>US and other coalition troops are expected to remain in Erbil, in the semi-autonomous northern Kurdistan region, for approximately one additional year, until around the end of 2026, to facilitate ongoing operations against Islamic State in Syria.</p>

<p>Exact details of troop movements are being kept secret due to their military sensitivity.</p>

<p>The drawdown would mark a notable shift in Washington's military posture in the region.</p>

<p>While primarily focused on countering Islamic State, US officials acknowledge their presence also serves as a strategic position against Iranian influence.</p>

<p>This position has grown more important as Israel and Iran escalate their regional confrontation, with US forces in Iraq shooting down rockets and drones fired towards Israel in recent months, according to US officials.</p>

<p>Prime Minister al-Sudani has stated that, while he appreciates their help, US troops have become a magnet for instability, frequently targeted and responding with strikes often not coordinated with the Iraqi government.</p>

<p>The agreement, when announced, would likely present a political win for al-Sudani as he balances Iraq's position as an ally of both Washington and Tehran. The first phase of the drawdown would end one month before Iraqi parliamentary polls set for October 2025.</p>

<p>For the US , the two-year time frame provides "breathing room," allowing for potential adjustments if the regional situation changes, a US official said.</p>

<p>The State Department and US Embassy in Baghdad did not respond to requests for comment.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/tbrtu2s_us-iraq-officials_625x300_06_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Exact details of troop movements are being kept secret due to their military sensitivity. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pak-court-orders-removal-of-serving-army-general-from-key-position-in-rare-verdict-6506336]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Pak Court Orders Removal Of Army General From Key Position In Rare Verdict]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pak-court-orders-removal-of-serving-army-general-from-key-position-in-rare-verdict-6506336]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Sep 2024 19:39:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In a rare verdict, a Pakistani court on Friday ordered the removal of a serving general of the Pakistan Army from heading a key organisation.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a rare verdict, a Pakistani court on Friday ordered the removal of a serving general of the Pakistan Army from heading a key organisation, which regulates government databases and statistically manages the sensitive registration database of all citizens of the country, stating that his appointment to the position was â€œunauthorisedâ€ and in violation of the rules.</p>

<p>The Lahore High Court (LHC) annulled the appointment of National Database and Registration Authority (Nadra) Chairman Lieutenant General Munir Afsar on a petition filed by a citizen, Ashba Kamran.</p>

<p>In October 2023, Afsar became the first serving military officer to be appointed as Nadra's chairman. The appointment was initially made by the caretaker government led by the then-prime minister Anwaarul Haq Kakar and later confirmed by the elected federal government of Shehbaz Sharif for a three-year term till 2027 in March this year.</p>

<p>In the petition, Kamran challenged that the appointment of Afsar was â€œin violation of the provisions of Nadra Ordinance, 2000â€ and it did not adhere â€œto the requirements of conducting a fair and competitive process for appointment by inviting potential aspirantsâ€.</p>

<p>Justice Asim Hafiz in the verdict noted that the army general's appointment was illegal.</p>

<p>â€œLest anyone misunderstand this, we make it clear that the appointment to any post under the government can only be made after a proper advertisement has been made, inviting applications from eligible candidates. Without holding a proper selection where all eligible candidates get a fair chance to compete would violate the guarantee enshrined under Articles 18 and 27 of the Constitution," he remarked.</p>

<p>â€œI am afraid that illegality committed by way of an unauthorised appointment, one cannot hide the elephant in a mouse-hole,â€ the judge noted.</p>

<p>The powerful Pakistan Army, which has ruled coup-prone Pakistan for more than half of its 75-plus years of existence, has hitherto wielded considerable power in matters of security and foreign policy. According to experts, the LHC's decision is seen as a setback for the backers of the current regime as the military wants to have its men in important positions in civil organisations.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-06/n8bq0sp8_pakistan-flag-unsplash_625x300_12_June_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Pak court in the verdict noted that the army general's appointment was illegal.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/alina-kabaeva-vladimir-putin-has-2-sons-with-ex-olympic-gymnast-and-girlfriend-alina-kabaeva-report-6505721]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Vladimir Putin Has 2 Sons With Ex Olympic Gymnast Alina Kabaeva: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/alina-kabaeva-vladimir-putin-has-2-sons-with-ex-olympic-gymnast-and-girlfriend-alina-kabaeva-report-6505721]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Sep 2024 18:16:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A report by an investigative site reveals that Russian President Vladimir Putin has two sons with former Olympic gymnast Alina Kabaeva.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russian President Vladimir Putin and his rumoured partner, former Olympic gymnast Alina Kabaeva, have two sons-ages five and nine-according to <em>the Dossier Centre</em>, a report in <em>Forbes</em> claimed. The outlet has attributed the info to a Russian investigative organisation that cited unnamed sources who claimed to regularly see the children.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://dossier.center/succession-en/">The<em> portal </em></a>claims that the couple's children are growing up in a highly secured residence in complete privacy. The boys live a solitary existence away from the spotlight and seldom see their parents.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/feature/vladimir-putin-buys-luxury-mansion-shares-it-with-girlfriend-alina-kabaeva-report-3826223"><strong>Also Read | Vladimir Putin Buys Luxury Mansion, Shares It With "Girlfriend" Alina Kabaeva: Report</strong></a></p>

<p>Mr Putin, 71, has <a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://en.putin.kremlin.ru/bio/page-3">declared in public</a> that he is the father of two daughters, Maria, 39, and Katerina, 38, with his former spouse Lyudmila Putin, whom he wed in 1983.</p>

<p><em>The Dossier Centre </em>claims Ms Kabaeva and Mr Putin started dating in 2008, which was six years prior to the official end of his divorce from Lyudmila. According to the report, Ms Kabaeva, 41, gave birth to Ivan in a maternity centre in Lugano, Switzerland, and to Vladimir Jr in Moscow.</p>

<p>Both Ivan and Vladimir Jr live in Mr Putin's mansion northwest of Moscow, though they have no interaction with other children their age, the Dossier Centre report claimed, and they receive music lessons and have personal trainers for swimming and artistic gymnastics.</p>

<p>Ivan has reportedly competed in artistic gymnastics competitions and often plays in hockey matches with his father.</p>

<p>Last year, a report about Russian President Vladimir Putin secretly spending millions on his girlfriend to buy big properties for her and their young children came out. <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.telegraph.co.uk/world-news/2023/02/28/putin-secretly-living-gymnast-girlfriend-children-luxury-mansion/">The Telegraph</a>&nbsp;</em>claimed that the leader allegedly funnelled millions in illicit funds to buy a big mansion and a large penthouse for his girlfriend, Alina Kabaeva.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/ho7g7odg_vladimir-putinalina-kabaeva_625x300_06_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Vladimir Putin's sons with Alina Kabaeva live a life of luxury isolated from the world.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/watch-donald-trump-announces-major-role-for-elon-musk-should-he-win-the-2024-us-election-6502018]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Watch: Trump Announces Major Role For Musk Should He Win The US Election]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/watch-donald-trump-announces-major-role-for-elon-musk-should-he-win-the-2024-us-election-6502018]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Sep 2024 17:19:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump revealed his initial plans, should he be voted to power in the 2024 US presidential election. Mr Trump said he will set up a task force shortly after assuming office, aimed at conducting a thorough audit of the entire federal government.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump has revealed his initial plans, should he be voted to power in the 2024 US presidential election. Mr Trump said he will set up a task force shortly after assuming office, aimed at conducting a thorough financial and performance audit of the entire federal government.</p>

<p>Donald Trump went on to say that once the audit is complete, the new task force will then make recommendations for drastic reforms, which he believes, is the need of the hour.</p>

<p>Elaborating his plan about the committee and who will head it, Donald Trump said that SpaceX, Tesla and X CEO Elon Musk shall head the task force, adding that Mr Musk has already agreed to take up the responsibility. A video of Donald Trump announcing this was shared on social media website X by local media outlet CSpan News Network.</p>

<p>Elon Musk too, welcomed Donald Trump's decision stating that such a move is "badly needed."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">This is badly needed <a href="https://t.co/H9AKYbDssZ">https://t.co/H9AKYbDssZ</a></p>
â€” Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1831778370180329962?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 5, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>Talking more about his plans for the United States, Mr Trump said he aims to "Make America the world's capital for crypto and bitcoin." He also said he plans to eliminate at least ten old regulations and will bring in ten new ones to replace them.</p>

<p>Addressing the Economic Club of New York, Donald Trump said on September 5, "To stop this onslaught at lower prices, I'm pledging today that in my second term we will eliminate a minimum of ten old regulations. For every one new regulation, we'll be able to do that quite easily. Actually, and instead of attacking industries of the future, we will embrace them, including making America the world capital for crypto and bitcoin."</p>

<p>Donald Trump heaped praise on Elon Musk saying, "At the suggestion of Elon Musk, who has given me his complete and total endorsement, that's a nice smart guy. He knows what he's doing. Very much appreciated. I will create a Government Efficiency Commission task with conducting a complete financial and performance audit of the entire federal government and making recommendations for drastic reforms we need to do. It can't go on the way we are now. And Elon, because he's not very busy, has agreed to head that task force, be interesting if he has the time be good one to do it, but he's agreed," Donald Trump said.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">"At the suggestion of <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@elonmusk</a>...I will create a Government Efficiency Commission tasked with conducting a complete financial &amp; performance audit of the entire federal government and making recommendations for drastic reforms. And Elon...has agreed to head that task force." <a href="https://t.co/ep2WU9ySRT">pic.twitter.com/ep2WU9ySRT</a></p>
â€” CSPAN (@cspan) <a href="https://twitter.com/cspan/status/1831738407476977868?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 5, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>Mr Trump spoke about how improper and fraudulent payments cost US taxpayers an estimated "hundreds of billions of dollars" in 2022. He announced that the commission will create an action plan to eliminate payments within months and added that it will "save trillions of dollars", according to the video posted by CSpan on X.</p>

<p>Donald Trump said, "In 2022, fraud and improper payments alone cost taxpayers an estimated hundreds of billions of dollars. As the first order of business, this commission will develop an action plan to totally eliminate fraud and improper payments within six months. This will save trillions of dollars trillions. It's massive for the same service that you have right now, trillions of dollars is wasted and gone, and nobody knows where it went further, taming inaction and bringing prices way down."</p>

<p>He also pledged to make 'Trump tax cuts' permanent and announced that there will be no tax on tips. He alleged that US Vice President Kamala Harris copied his plan and announced to impose no tax on tips. He claimed that Kamala Harris will not move ahead with it and will stick to her plan.</p>

<p>Mr Trump said, "The 5th pillar of my plan is to make the Trump tax cuts permanent. They are massive tax cuts, biggest ever permanent and to cut tax even more, and we will have no tax on tips, something which they copied four weeks after I said it. She got upset and said no tax on tips. I said I just said that she is actually copying a lot of my plan. In fact, we're going to send her a MAGA sometime in the next week....But we also know she doesn't mean it. She's going to stick with what has been about and also no tax on Social security benefits."</p>

<p>Pledging to save social security, Donald Trump said that he will not impose tax on the benefits of people in social security, stressing that they have been wiped out by inflation.</p>

<p>Mr Trump said, "People in social security have been wiped out by inflation and now on top of it, we tax their benefits. We're not going to tax their benefits. We have so many different ways of making so much money. This country, the potential is so incredible. We don't have to take it away from people on social security. We're not going to do that. We're going to save social security. She's going to destroy Social Security."</p>

<p>The former US President said that his administration has proved that targeted tax cuts do not increase the deficit. He said that it reduces the deficit by growing the economy and raising revenue, according to the video posted by CSpan on X.</p>

<p>He said, "After we gave the massive tax cuts, we took in the following year with a much lower rate. Billions and billions of dollars more than we did the previous year with a high rate, think of that. So, with a much lower rate, we took in more money because people were incentivised."</p>

<p>Speaking about reducing the corporate tax burden, Mr Trump said he plans to reduce the corporate tax rate from 21 per cent to 15 per cent for companies that make their product in the US.</p>

<p>"Corporate tax revenues are 31 per cent higher today than before, my tax law was signed with all of those cuts 31 percent higher. To further support the revival of American manufacturing, my plan calls for expanded R&amp;D tax credits, 100 percent bonus depreciation, expensing for no manufacturing investments, and a reduction in corporate tax rate from 21 percent to 15 per cent solely for companies that make their product in America," he said.</p>

<p>Responding to the video which shows Donald Trump announcing his plans, Elon Musk took to X to post, "This is badly needed."<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/hl6ceebk_donald-trump-afp_625x300_06_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump said Elon Musk has agreed to take up a major role should Trump win the 2024 US election.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/victims-family-pardons-pakistan-industrialist-wife-natasha-danish-who-killed-2-with-luxury-suv-6505070]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Victims' Family Pardons Pak Industrialist's Wife Who Killed 2 With SUV]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/victims-family-pardons-pakistan-industrialist-wife-natasha-danish-who-killed-2-with-luxury-suv-6505070]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Sep 2024 16:58:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Relatives of a father-daughter duo have forgiven a female from a wealthy, influential Pakistani business family here who ran down a luxurious SUV over them, her lawyer said on Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Relatives of a father-daughter duo have forgiven a female from a wealthy, influential Pakistani business family here who ran down a luxurious SUV over them, her lawyer said on Friday.</p>

<p>The incident drew widespread condemnation as the two killed came from lower middle class. The rich lady also injured three other motorcyclists on the main Karsaz Road in the city as she lost control of her car.</p>

<p>The accident on August 19 garnered lot of attention on social media and became a raging debate on television channels as videos of Natasha Danish appearing disoriented and unrepentant over her actions went viral.</p>

<p>As Natasha Danish hit Imran Arif and his daughter Amna Arif from behind, their motorcycle went flying, according to videos of the incident shared on social media and by the police.</p>

<p>Imran used to sell papers to shops while his daughter was employed in a private firm.</p>

<p>After the hearing at a Sessions Court earlier on Friday, Barrister Uzair Ghouri, representing the bereaved families, told the media outside the court that they (the families) had forgiven the driver in the name of Allah.</p>

<p>The defence lawyer had claimed after the incident that the accused had mental health issues and was under treatment since 2005.</p>

<p>The victims' family submitted an affidavit in the court forgiving the accused.</p>

<p>The agreement between the affected families and the accused were presented in the court of a judicial magistrate where the case was under trial, after which the accused was granted bail.</p>

<p>Soon after social media erupted with blames that the family accepted blood money.</p>

<p>"The bereaved families have forgiven the accused in the name of Allah and it is baseless rumours that they have taken blood money (Diyat in Islamic Shariah laws) to forgive her for the deaths," he said.</p>

<p>In Pakistan, under Sharia laws, a victim's family/heirs can forgive an accused even if he or she has caused deaths.</p>

<p>The law is called Qisas and Diyat law. Qisas, defined as "punishment by causing similar hurt at the same part of the body of the convict," and diyat meaning, "compensation ... payable to the heirs of the victims." "The court has released Natasha on bail, she can go anywhere in the world," said defence lawyer barrister Amir Mansoob.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/pa7a5bko_natasha-danish-ali_625x300_28_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Videos of Natasha Danish appearing disoriented and unrepentant over her actions went viral]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/video-asteroid-burns-up-in-earths-atmosphere-lighting-up-philippine-sky-6504974]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Video: Asteroid Burns Up In Earth's Atmosphere, Lighting Up Philippine Sky]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/video-asteroid-burns-up-in-earths-atmosphere-lighting-up-philippine-sky-6504974]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Sep 2024 16:45:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A small asteroid, 2024 RW1, burned up in Earth's atmosphere over Luzon Island, Philippines, after being discovered just hours earlier by astronomers in Arizona.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>American space agency NASA has confirmed that early on Wednesday afternoon, over Luzon Island in the Philippines, a minor asteroid, about the size of a meter, broke apart in Earth's atmosphere.</p>

<p>Astronomers in Arizona initially discovered the space rock, known as 2024 RW1, a few hours before it entered the Earth. There was a brilliant flare in the sky as the asteroid burnt up over the Philippine shore.</p>

<p>2024 RW1 is only the ninth asteroid to be detected before impact, according to the European Space Agency. The incident strengthens astronomers' increasing capacity to foresee the presence of near-Earth objects.</p>

<p>The beautiful celestial event was caught on camera and shared on social media: an orange tail that vanished fast and a green fireball that flashed, lighting up the sky behind clouds. A bright green flame could be seen blazing across the Philippines in many of the internet videos.</p>

<p><strong>Watch the video here:</strong></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Here's how Asteroid RW1 looks like from Gonzaga, Cagayan, Philippines. Best shot so far!! ? <a href="https://t.co/eYgQsHqxFP">pic.twitter.com/eYgQsHqxFP</a></p>
â€” Raymon Dullana (@raymongdullana) <a href="https://twitter.com/raymongdullana/status/1831378111453392958?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 4, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The impact was expected to be visible from the east coast of the nation as a fireball, according to NASA's Asteroid Watch prediction. Space aficionados all around the world were captivated by the spectacle in no time.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">âš ï¸â˜„ï¸Incoming!<br />
<br />
A roughly 1 metre asteroid will strike Earth's atmosphere over the Philippines near Luzon Island at 17:08 UTC today, 4 September.<br />
<br />
The object is harmless, but people in the area may see a spectacular fireball!<br />
<br />
Discovered this morning by the Catalina Sky Survey,â€¦ <a href="https://t.co/UjQLbh3fFr">pic.twitter.com/UjQLbh3fFr</a></p>
â€” European Space Agency (@esa) <a href="https://twitter.com/esa/status/1831270255454191893?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 4, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The impact of the asteroid was confirmed by various sensors, according to NASA's Planetary Defence Coordination Office. This sighting, which came just hours after astronomers first noticed the tiny asteroid, increased popular curiosity with the celestial event.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/m325o_asteroid-2024-rw1_625x300_06_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The green fireball, followed by an orange tail, lit up the sky and was captured in videos shared online.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/pakistan-must-stop-blaming-others-for-its-balochistan-problem-6504755]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: It's Time Pakistan Stopped Blaming Others For Its Balochistan Problem]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/pakistan-must-stop-blaming-others-for-its-balochistan-problem-6504755]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Sep 2024 16:20:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Pakistan needs to abandon the policy of rewarding those who attack Baloch nationalists and stop promoting conspiracy theories that India, Iran, and Afghanistan are behind all the chaos in Balochistan.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2017-05/pakistan-flag_650x400_71493967261.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>On August 26, one of the bloodiest attacks in Pakistan's Balochistan province occurred, with over 70 people, including Pakistan Army soldiers, reportedly killed by the separatist group Balochistan Liberation Army (BLA). The date held significant meaning for Balochistan as it marked the 18th death anniversary of Nawab Akbar Bugti, a Baloch nationalist leader killed by the Pakistani military in 2006.</p>

<p>The BLA's Majeed Brigade, its suicide squad, conducted a coordinated attack across various parts of Balochistan. The assault involved blowing up infrastructure such as railway tracks and bridges and resulted in the deaths of migrant labourers from Punjab.</p>

<p>The Baloch rebellion in Pakistan stems from both historical and contemporary resentments, impacting stability in India and the broader region. Balochistan has a long history of political unrest, economic oppression, anti-Punjabi sentiment, enforced disappearances, and extrajudicial killings. These issues have rekindled the fight for Baloch nationalism. For two decades, the mineral-rich province has experienced low-level insurgency against Pakistan's central government, accompanied by brutal retaliatory actions.</p>

<p>Pakistan has described the recent attacks as a "nefarious scheme supported by external rivals to undermine its development ties with Beijing".</p>

<p>The BLA is considered the largest armed group in Balochistan, with thousands of members. It collaborates closely with the Baloch Liberation Front (BLF), another major separatist militant group advocating for Baloch self-determination. Both groups have been labelled as "terrorist organisations" by Pakistan.</p>

<h2><b>The 1999 Coup</b></h2>

<p>Many Baloch believe they were coerced into joining Pakistan in 1948. The princely state of Kalat, now part of Balochistan, briefly enjoyed independence before being 'forced' into accession with Pakistan. Apart from initial resistance, there were uprisings in 1958 and 1977 seeking either independence or greater autonomy.</p>

<p>Pervez Musharraf's military coup in 1999 further alienated the Baloch from Pakistan. Distrust of Punjabi dominance in the Pakistani army and bureaucracy, along with the lack of Baloch representation, has been a persistent issue. In one of Musharraf's counter-insurgency operations, Baloch leader Nawab Akbar Bugti was killed in 2006. Pakistan has not made significant efforts to integrate the region or address the local issues of its inhabitants.</p>

<p>"The Baloch have been alienated by the Pakistani state since the country's inception. This alienation has intensified over the past two decades due to Pakistan's failure to engage in meaningful reflection and its numerous cases of enforced disappearances, torture, and killings of Baloch activists," says Malik Siraj Akbar, a political analyst based in Washington, D.C.</p>

<h2><strong>How Things Stand Today</strong></h2>

<p>Balochistan is Pakistan's largest province by area but remains one of its most impoverished regions. Years of poverty, neglect, and mistreatment by the central government have fueled anger, which is exploited by separatists. Revenue from Balochistan's rich natural resources has been used to develop other parts of Pakistan, including Punjab and Sindh, which are more prosperous. Balochistan contributes only 4% to Pakistan's economy.</p>

<p>The province also lags in social development indicators, with the highest infant and maternal mortality rates, the highest poverty rate, and the lowest literacy rate in Pakistan.</p>

<p>There is no forum for dissent, as enforced disappearances of thousands of Balochs continue. Political parties in Balochistan, which previously formed most provincial governments, lost power in controversial elections. Later, Islamabad supported puppet leaders, worsening the situation.</p>

<p>"While Pakistan may appear to be a democratic state, real power rests with its military and intelligence agencies, which are primarily blamed for the violence in Balochistan," says Akbar. "Unless the military ends its illegal operations and is held accountable, any confidence-building measures with the Baloch and prospects for negotiations are unlikely," he adds.</p>

<p>Apart from using brutal force and repression, the Pakistani establishment has also failed to engage with civil rights movements in Balochistan. Resentment is so high that in the current uprising, the Baloch nationalist movement has garnered support from women, children, and the families of the missing persons, with some even joining the suicide bombers.</p>

<p>Baloch separatists are also opposed to the China-Pakistan Economic Corridor (CPEC), which passes through Balochistan and is seen as an example of exploitation. They have targeted Chinese workers as part of their resistance. Balochistan is a crucial location in China's multi-billion-dollar CPEC, part of President Xi Jinping's Belt and Road Initiative (BRI). In January, insurgents attacked government offices in Gwadar, a key hub for Chinese investments in energy and infrastructure. The BLA also targeted Pakistan's largest naval air force base.</p>

<p>The current insurgency is driven by the construction of Gwadar, a Chinese-funded project announced in 2001 intended to transform the small village into a port city like Dubai. The Pakistani government has excluded Baloch from the development process, employing Chinese engineers and non-Baloch Pakistani workers, fueling antipathy and violence. The Taliban's seizure of neighbouring Afghanistan has also enhanced the capabilities of armed groups in the region, including Baloch separatists.</p>

<h2><b>Pakistan Should Stop Blaming Others</b></h2>

<p>Pakistan has accused India of providing arms, training, and financial support to insurgent groups in Balochistan. India denies these allegations and has urged Pakistan to examine its own support for terrorism. In 2016, Prime Minister Narendra Modi's remarks highlighting Pakistan's atrocities and repression of the Baloch people had sparked controversy in Islamabad.</p>

<p>India has been closely monitoring the situation in Balochistan and has expressed concerns about rising attacks in both Khyber Pakhtunkhwa and Balochistan since the Taliban's return to Kabul. Pakistan needs to abandon the policy of rewarding those who attack Baloch nationalists and stop promoting conspiracy theories that India, Iran, and Afghanistan are behind all the tumult in Balochistan.</p>

<p>"Pakistan has mastered the art of externalising responsibility for its self-created problems. Unable to address the two-decade-long insurgency in Balochistan despite using brutal tactics similar to those in East Pakistan in 1971, Pakistan has intermittently blamed India for its troubles," says Tilak Devasher, a member of the National Security Advisory Board, India. "It has, however, failed to produce any evidence to substantiate its claims. Consequently, its assertions are not taken seriously by the international community," adds Devasher.</p>

<p>Pakistan must demonstrate political will to address the Balochistan issue by engaging with civil rights groups, involving Baloch in the development process, and alleviating their poverty and suffering. Meanwhile, India continues to observe the situation closely.</p>

<p><em>(Bharti Mishra Nath is Contributing Editor, NDTV)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2017-05/pakistan-flag_650x400_71493967261.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>