<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Wed, 14 Aug 2024 18:39:56 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/2-french-rafale-jets-collide-mid-air-instructor-pilot-missing-6337097]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[2 French Rafale Jets Collide Mid-Air, Instructor, Pilot Missing]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/2-french-rafale-jets-collide-mid-air-instructor-pilot-missing-6337097]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 14 Aug 2024 18:39:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Two Rafale fighter jets collided in midair before crashing to the ground in northeastern France on Wednesday, civil and military authorities said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Two Rafale fighter jets collided in midair before crashing to the ground in northeastern France on Wednesday, civil and military authorities said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>A search for one of the crews was under way. The two jets were from the Saint-Dizier air base, an air force spokesman in Paris told AFP.&nbsp;</p>

<p>One of the pilots ejected himself, he said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>But an instructor and a student pilot from the second aircraft were still missing.</p>

<p>"We are still looking for the second crew," the spokesman said.</p>

<p>The accident occurred in Colombey-les-Belles, a town in northeastern France, according to the prefecture.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/olvkr6vo_rafale_625x300_14_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The accident occurred in Colombey-les-Belles (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-woman-accidentally-runs-over-12-year-old-daughter-on-first-day-of-school-drop-off-6337030]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Woman Accidentally Runs Over 12-Year-Old Daughter At School Drop-off]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-woman-accidentally-runs-over-12-year-old-daughter-on-first-day-of-school-drop-off-6337030]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 14 Aug 2024 18:29:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 12-year-old in the US was severely injured after her mother accidentally ran her over on her first day of school.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 12-year-old in the US was severely injured after her mother accidentally ran her over on her first day of school. According to <em>People</em>, the incident took place on Monday morning outside Boker Middle School in Florida. The mother, 30, was dropping her daughter off when she accidentally hit her. The child was airlifted to Johns Hopkins All Children's Hospital in St. Petersburg with critical injuries, cops said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to the Florida Highway Patrol (FHP), the 12-year-old had dropped some markers and pens and bent down to pick them up from under the vehicle. Tragically, however, the mother did not realise what her daughter was doing and began to drive off, running over her. "She immediately stopped when she heard her child screaming," FHP Trooper Kenn Watson said, per <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://people.com/mom-accidentally-runs-12-year-old-daughter-over-school-drop-off-8694383"><em>People</em></a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p>A Sarasota County Schools spokesperson confirmed the accident, saying, "A parent accidentally hit their child as the parent was dropping the child off on the street". "The school district encourages all families to follow district &amp; school safety protocols and use the designated student pickup and drop off areas on school campuses," they added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Separately, Mr Watson said, "Here we are, day one, and we've already had a tragedy. We're hoping this does not happen again, but we have to remember to have that good spatial awareness when you are anywhere around a school zone and most certainly when you are letting your kid out of your vehicle".&nbsp;</p>

<p>"You want to avoid being in a hurry and dropping off our kids in the turn lane when we should be directly in front of the school," he continued, adding, "This is a tragedy that one hundred percent could have been avoided by simply paying a little more attention and not being in a hurry."</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/24-year-old-us-man-arrested-for-giving-4-month-old-baby-gasoline-to-drink-6336388">24-Year-Old US Man Arrested For Giving 4-Month-Old Baby Gasoline To Drink</a></strong></p>

<p>In a message to families, Booker Middle School principal LaShawn Frost said the crash "serves as a reminder of the importance of following our established safety procedures".&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Please remember that students should not be dropped off in the middle of Myrtle Street," the principal said. "This practice poses a significant risk to our students' safety and the safety of others on the road," he added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>On Tuesday, officials said that the child is in stable condition. "Johns Hopkins All Children's Hospital has advised that the 12-year-old victim has been upgraded to 'Stable' as of 4:00 p.m. Eastern Time," said Mr Watson.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/an15mbcg_caution-tape-generic_625x300_17_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The incident took place on Monday. (Representative pic)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korea-to-open-borders-for-foreign-tourists-in-december-6336908]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[North Korea To Open Borders For Foreign Tourists In December]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korea-to-open-borders-for-foreign-tourists-in-december-6336908]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 14 Aug 2024 18:13:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[North Korea will resume international tourism to its northeastern city of Samjiyon in December, and possibly the rest of the country, tour companies said on Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>North Korea will resume international tourism to its northeastern city of Samjiyon in December, and possibly the rest of the country, tour companies said on Wednesday.</p>

<p>The move is a sign that the reclusive country is readying to reopen borders to bigger groups of foreign tourists after years of strict COVID border controls.</p>

<p>"We have received confirmation from our local partner that tourism to Samjiyon and likely the rest of the country will officially resume in December 2024," the Beijing-based Koryo Tours said on its website.</p>

<p>International flights in and out of North Korea resumed last year and a small group of Russian tourists flew to North Korea for a private tour in February. Top foreign officials, including Russian President Vladimir Putin in June, have been visiting the country.</p>

<p>However, North Korea has not been fully open to international tourists since 2020.</p>

<p>"Having waited for over four years to make this announcement, Koryo Tours is very excited for the opening of North Korean tourism once again," the firm said, adding its local partner would confirm itineraries and dates in coming weeks.</p>

<p>North Korea has been building what it called a "socialist utopia" in Samjiyon, a city near the Chinese border, and "a model of highly-civilised mountain city" with new apartments, hotels, a ski resort and commercial, cultural and medical facilities.</p>

<p>Leader Kim Jong Un in July sacked or demoted some senior officials for their "irresponsible" handling of his flagship Samjiyon project.</p>

<p>Another travel agency, KTG Tours, also announced that tourists would be able to go to Samjiyon from this winter.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/mnt7e4vo_kim-jong-un-_625x300_14_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[However, North Korea has not been fully open to international tourists since 2020.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-airstrikes-target-gaza-ahead-of-ceasefire-talks-6336678]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israeli Airstrikes Target Gaza Ahead Of Ceasefire Talks]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-airstrikes-target-gaza-ahead-of-ceasefire-talks-6336678]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 14 Aug 2024 17:44:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli air strikes targeted Gaza on Wednesday ahead of ceasefire talks that the United States hopes will stop Iran striking Israel in retaliation for the killing of a Hamas leader.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli air strikes targeted Gaza on Wednesday ahead of ceasefire talks that the United States hopes will stop Iran striking Israel in retaliation for the killing of a Hamas leader.</p>

<p>Iran and its allies blamed Israel for the July 31 killing of Hamas political leader Ismail Haniyeh in Tehran during a visit for the inauguration of President Masoud Pezeshkian. Israel has not commented.</p>

<p>The West has urged Iran to stand down its threat to avenge his death, which came hours after an Israeli strike in Beirut killed a senior commander of Hezbollah, the powerful Iran-backed rebel group in Lebanon.</p>

<p>The escalation has raised fears of a wider conflict after more than 10 months of war in Gaza, which has claimed nearly 40,000 lives, according to the health ministry in the Hamas-run Palestinian territory.</p>

<p>So far, there has been only one, week-long truce in the Gaza fighting, in November, when dozens of hostages in Gaza were released in exchange for Palestinian prisoners held in Israeli jails.</p>

<p>Ahead of Thursday's ceasefire talks, a Hamas official said the Islamist movement was "continuing its consultations with the mediators".</p>

<p>"Hamas really wants an end to the war and a ceasefire agreement on the basis of the (Biden) plan," another Hamas official said, referring to a proposal US President Joe Biden laid out on May 31.</p>

<p>The office of Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu on Tuesday detailed its conditions for a truce, including "a veto on certain prisoners" being released from its jails.</p>

<p>Biden said on Tuesday that a Gaza ceasefire deal could deter Iran from attacking Israel.</p>

<p>Asked if a truce between Israel and Hamas could stave off an Iranian assault, Biden said: "That's my expectation". He added that while negotiations were "getting hard", he was "not giving up".</p>

<p>His envoy for the conflict, Amos Hochstein, was in Beirut on Wednesday where he warned the clock was ticking for a Gaza ceasefire.</p>

<p>"There is no more time to waste and there's no more valid excuses from any party for any further delay," he said after talks with Lebanon's parliament speaker Nabih Berri.</p>

<p>Iran has rejected Western calls for restraint, with foreign ministry spokesman Nasser Kanani saying the demand "brazenly asks Iran to take no deterrent action against a regime which has violated its sovereignty and territorial integrity".</p>

<h3><strong>Israel on 'high alert'</strong></h3>

<p>Israeli President Isacc Herzog said on social media platform X that the country remained on "high alert".</p>

<p>"I want to express my appreciation and thanks to our allies standing united with us in the face of the hate-filled threats of the Iranian regime and its terrorist proxies," he said.</p>

<p>The escalation has prompted Western governments to issue advisories against travel to Lebanon as well as prepare contingency plans to evacuate their nationals from the region if full-scale war breaks out.</p>

<p>A ferry seen off Limassol, Cyprus was on standby to provide assistance "in the event of an evacuation of the conflict zone", a spokesperson for its charterer said.</p>

<p>Fearing an attack by Iran and Hezbollah, the Tel Aviv Museum of Art said it had stashed away its most valuable pieces, including paintings by Pablo Picasso and Gustav Klimt.</p>

<p>"In the last three, four, five days, when this new threat from Hezbollah and from Iran came on the table again, we understood that we needed to take other precautions," said museum director Tania Coen-Uzzielli.</p>

<p>The Biden administration approved more than $20 billion in new weapons sales to Israel on Tuesday, including 50 F-15 fighter jets.</p>

<p>The United States has deployed an aircraft carrier strike group and a guided missile submarine to the region in support of Israel.</p>

<h3><strong>Gaza death count nears 40,000</strong></h3>

<p>The Gaza war began with Hamas's October 7 attack on southern Israel which resulted in the deaths of 1,198 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally of Israeli official figures.</p>

<p>Hamas also seized 251 people, 111 of whom are still held captive in Gaza, including 39 the military says are dead.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory military offensive in Gaza has killed at least 39,965 people, according to the latest count from the territory's health ministry, which does not provide a breakdown of civilian and Hamas deaths.</p>

<p>In the latest violence, the Israeli military said it carried out dozens of air strikes across the Gaza Strip.</p>

<p>It said its troops were "continuing precise, intelligence-based operational activity in the area of Tel al-Sultan" in the southern city of Rafah.</p>

<p>In the past 24 hours, the army said it had "struck over 40" sites across Gaza, including structures from which Hamas fired anti-tank missiles.</p>

<p>The Gaza civil defence agency said its emergency teams pulled the bodies of four people from the same family from the rubble of a bombed apartment in the Qatari-built residential complex of Hamad, near Khan Yunis.</p>

<p>Residents of central Gaza's Nuseirat refugee camp said it was struck by a missile after midnight.</p>

<p>"We were sleeping... and were surprised by a missile targeting the neighbours, children, their father and mother," Jihad al-Sharif told AFPTV.</p>

<p>"The explosion was terrible," he said, adding his family emerged to find the remains of children in the middle of the street.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/d48qn25o_israel-gaza-war_625x300_14_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Gaza war began with Hamas's October 7 attack on southern Israel]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-navys-newest-air-to-air-missile-could-tilt-balance-in-south-china-sea-6336606]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Navy's Newest Air-To-Air Missile Could Tilt Balance In South China Sea]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-navys-newest-air-to-air-missile-could-tilt-balance-in-south-china-sea-6336606]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 14 Aug 2024 17:36:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The U.S. Navy's deployment of new extremely long-range air-to-air missiles in the Indo-Pacific could erase China's advantage in aerial reach, experts say, part of an intensifying focus on projecting power amid high tensions in the region.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The U.S. Navy's deployment of new extremely long-range air-to-air missiles in the Indo-Pacific could erase China's advantage in aerial reach, experts say, part of an intensifying focus on projecting power amid high tensions in the region.</p>

<p>The AIM-174B, developed from the readily available Raytheon SM-6 air defence missile, is the longest-range such missile the United States has ever fielded and was officially acknowledged in July.</p>

<p>It has three key advantages: it can fly several times farther than the next-best U.S. option, the AIM-120 AMRAAM; it does not require new production lines; and it is compatible with the aircraft of at least one ally, Australia.</p>

<p>Crucially, a weapon such as the AIM-174B, which can attack aerial targets as far away as 400 km (250 miles), outranges China's PL-15 missile, allowing U.S. jets to keep threats farther from aircraft carriers, and safely strike "high-value" Chinese targets, such as command-and-control planes.</p>

<p>"The United States can ensure the safety of their important assets, such as carrier groups, and launch long-range strikes on PLA targets," said Chieh Chung, a researcher at a Taipei-based thinktank, the Association of Strategic Foresight, using an abbreviation for the People's Liberation Army.</p>

<p>The West has not easily been able to do that until now.</p>

<p>The AIM-120, the standard long-range missile for U.S. aircraft, has a maximum range of about 150 km (93 miles), which requires the launching aircraft to fly deeper into contested territory, exposing aircraft carriers to greater danger of anti-ship attacks.</p>

<p>Any type of South China Sea conflict, within the so-called First Island Chain, which runs roughly from Indonesia northeast to the Japanese mainland, means the U.S. Navy would operate within a few hundred kilometres of its Chinese adversary.</p>

<p>Supporting Taiwan in an invasion would pull the Navy in even closer.</p>

<p>The AIM-174B changes that equation, keeping PLA carrier-hunting aircraft out of firing range and even endangering their planes attacking Taiwan, Cheih said. That increased the likelihood the United States would get involved in a major conflict in the region, he added.</p>

<p>"The big thing is that it lets the United States push in a little bit further" into the South China Sea during a conflict, said a senior U.S. defence technical analyst, who declined to be identified because the matter is a sensitive one.</p>

<p>"And it's going to potentially change Chinese behaviour because it's going to hold large, slow, unmanoeuvrable aircraft at greater risk."</p>

<p><strong>RANGE ADVANTAGE</strong></p>

<p>For decades, the United States' advantage in stealth fighters, first with the F-117 and then with the F-22 and F-35, meant that missiles such as the AIM-120 were all that was needed.</p>

<p>The U.S. military also leaned into developing the AMRAAM as a cheaper alternative to a new missile, drastically improving its performance over decades, said Justin Bronk, an airpower and technology expert at London's Royal United Services Institute.</p>

<p>The SM-6 is estimated to cost about $4 million each, says the Missile Defense Advocacy Alliance, while an AMRAAM costs about $1 million.</p>

<p>European nations, which lacked access to stealth technology until recent years, developed the ramjet-powered Meteor missile, with a range of 200 km (124 miles), produced by MBDA.</p>

<p>MBDA did not respond to a request for comment.</p>

<p>The advent of Chinese stealth aircraft such as the J-20, and more important, the PL-15 missile it can carry internally - with a range of 250 km (155 miles) or more - eroded the U.S. edge, said Kelly Grieco, a senior fellow at the Stimson Center.</p>

<p>Now a stealthy Chinese aircraft could theoretically spot non-stealthy U.S. aircraft and shoot them down well outside the range where they could even fight back, she said.</p>

<p>Even U.S. stealth aircraft might be forced to fly dangerously close to fire their missiles.</p>

<p>"If a Chinese fighter can outrange an American fighter, it means they can get the first shot," she said. "It's hard to outrun something that's travelling at Mach 4."</p>

<p>The AIM-174B was developed to quickly address that need.</p>

<p>The secretive Lockheed Martin AIM-260, a separate U.S. Air Force program to develop an extremely long-range air-to-air missile small enough for stealth aircraft to carry internally, has been in development for at least seven years.</p>

<p>Lockheed Martin declined to comment on the project.</p>

<p>China is developing missiles with longer range than the PL-15, Bronk said, but the radar of launching aircraft may be unable to spot targets at such distances.</p>

<p>"If you go too big and too heavy with the missiles, you end up trading off fuel" for the aircraft, he added.</p>

<p><strong>AVAILABILITY</strong></p>

<p>Using Raytheon's SM-6, originally designed for a ship-launched air defence role, means production lines are already available. Funding has already been earmarked for more than 100 SM-6 missiles a year.</p>

<p>Raytheon declined to comment on how many AIM-174Bs would be produced or if existing SM-6s would be converted.</p>

<p>So far it has only been shown on U.S. Navy F/A-18E/F Super Hornet aircraft, which are operated by the U.S. and Australian militaries.</p>

<p>The United States sees Australia as a crucial ally and location for projecting power into the South China Sea, and is investing hundreds of millions of dollars in military infrastructure there.</p>

<p>Australia's defence ministry said it "works closely with the U.S. to understand capability options available for Australian consideration".</p>

<p>The U.S. Defense Department referred questions about the AIM-174B to the U.S. Navy.</p>

<p>The Navy said the missile was "operationally deployed" but declined to comment on whether it would be supplied to allies, whether it would be integrated onto other aircraft, and how many AIM-174Bs it wanted each year.</p>

<p>The versatility of the SM-6, which has also been used to hit ships, land targets and missiles, opens up possibilities beyond the AIM-174B, said Peter Layton, a defence and aviation expert at the Griffith Asia Institute.</p>

<p>For instance, if fitted with an anti-radar seeker, it could attack and disrupt surface-to-air missile batteries from extremely long range.</p>

<p>For now, though, adding the AIM-174B to the U.S. Navy's arsenal, even if not yet in large numbers, changes the calculus of a regional conflict, the senior technical analyst said.</p>

<p>"If this is enough to push (China's high-value) aircraft way back, then you don't need many," the analyst added.</p>

<p>"Because the threat has caused the adversary to change their behaviour ... It makes a South China Sea scenario easier."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/jrahrc9o_aim174b-missile_625x300_14_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[An F-18 Hornet fighter jet with an AIM-174B long-range missile.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukrainian-troops-moving-further-in-russias-kursk-says-zelensky-6336396]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ukrainian Troops Moving Further In Russia's Kursk, Says Zelensky]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukrainian-troops-moving-further-in-russias-kursk-says-zelensky-6336396]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 14 Aug 2024 17:10:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[President Volodymyr Zelensky on Wednesday said Ukraine's army was advancing in the Russian region of Kursk where it launched a surprise offensive last week.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>President Volodymyr Zelensky on Wednesday said Ukraine's army was advancing in the Russian region of Kursk where it launched a surprise offensive last week.</p>

<p>"In the Kursk region, we are moving further. From one to two kilometres in different areas since the beginning of the day. And more than 100 more captured Russian servicemen over the same period... This will speed up the return home of our boys and girls," Zelensky said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/qcc3qau8_zelensky-reuters_625x300_11_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/24-year-old-us-man-arrested-for-giving-4-month-old-baby-gasoline-to-drink-6336388]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[24-Year-Old US Man Arrested For Giving 4-Month-Old Baby Gasoline To Drink]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/24-year-old-us-man-arrested-for-giving-4-month-old-baby-gasoline-to-drink-6336388]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 14 Aug 2024 17:09:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 24-year-old man in the United States has been charged with attempted capital murder after he allegedly tried to kill his 4-month-old baby by feeding the infant gasoline.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 24-year-old man in the United States has been charged with attempted capital murder after he tried to kill his 4-month-old baby by feeding the infant gasoline. According to <em>Newsweek</em>, Edgar James Bridgemon of Texas confessed to administering the poison, intending to end the child's life. He was arrested on Saturday for attempted capital murder and later processed and jailed. In addition to the attempted murder charge, he has also been charged with evading arrest, cops said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>After responding to a distressing emergency call, cops learned that the baby was allegedly given a gasoline drink by Bridgemon. While officers assessed the situation, the 24-year-old attempted to flee on foot. But after a brief chase, cops arrested Bridgemon and took into custody, where he later confessed to the crime.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.newsweek.com/texas-father-charged-after-giving-baby-gasoline-drink-1938613"><em>Newsweek</em></a>, the 24-year-old admitted that he had given the baby gasoline with the deliberate intention of ending the child's life.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The 4-month-old, on the other hand, was immediately rushed to Paris Regional Medical Center, where medical staff began initial treatment. However, due to the severity of the poisoning, the child was later transferred to a different hospital in the Dallas-Fort Worth area for more advanced care.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Bridgemon now faces charges including attempted capital murder, which is classified as a first-degree felony in Texas. If convicted, the 24-year-old could face a life sentence.</p>

<p>Additionally, Bridgemon has also been charged with evading arrest, further complicating his legal situation. He is currently being held at the Lamar County Jail with a bond set at $255,000. The case is still under investigation by local authorities.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/feature/chinas-most-handsome-shaolin-monk-dies-in-car-accident-at-21-6334946">China's ''Most Handsome'' Shaolin Monk Dies In Car Accident At 21</a></strong></p>

<p>Meanwhile, in another incident, a mother was recently arrested for allegedly throwing her newborn baby into a trash bag and dumping it in a dumpster. Everilda Cux-Ajtzalam reportedly told police she did this because she feared her boyfriend would break up with her if she didn't. Court records reviewed by Law&amp;Crime show that she was taken into custody on Thursday and charged with felony abandoning a child without the intent to return.</p>

<p>Medics from the Houston Fire Department transported the baby to Texas Children's Hospital, where authorities reported that the child was stable and in good condition. After receiving treatment, the baby was placed in the custody of Child Protective Services.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-11/3eb3kf1_us-police-generic_625x300_14_November_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[If convicted, the 24-year-old could face a life sentence. (Representative pic)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/taliban-three-years-on-still-searching-for-manna-6336026]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: Opinion | Taliban, Three Years On: Still Searching for Manna]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/taliban-three-years-on-still-searching-for-manna-6336026]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 14 Aug 2024 16:25:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[On August 15, 2021, the Taliban swiftly took over Kabul following the withdrawal of the US-led International Security Assistance Force (ISAF), marking a significant diplomatic setback for India.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On August 15, 2021, the Taliban swiftly took over Kabul following the withdrawal of the US-led International Security Assistance Force (ISAF), marking a significant diplomatic setback for India. The Taliban were believed to have support from the Tehreek-e-Taliban-e-Pakistan (TTP) operating around the Durand Line, as well as from moderates in Doha.</p>

<p>Amidst the ensuing chaos, India was forced to shut down its embassy in Kabul, evacuating diplomats and citizens. New Delhi had invested heavily in Afghanistan, but the future seemed uncertain under the shadow of conflict. As of August 2020, there were approximately 1,710 Indians in Afghanistan, working in sectors such as banking, IT, construction, healthcare, NGOs, telecom, security, and education, as well as with Afghan and UN missions.</p>

<p><strong>Aid to Afghanistan</strong></p>

<p>The Taliban's return and the subsequent withdrawal of international forces led many countries, including India, to pull out. However, the Taliban leadership soon realized that running a government required more than just military might-it needed external funds and assistance. New Delhi has cautiously responded to Kabul's appeals for aid. Important delegations visited Afghanistan, and a technical mission was established in June 2022 to better understand and coordinate humanitarian efforts.</p>

<p>Since 2001, India has committed over USD 3 billion to development and reconstruction projects in Afghanistan. Bilateral trade between India and Afghanistan was valued at USD 1.5 billion in 2019-20. India has supported projects such as a new Parliament building in Kabul and two major river dams. More than 500 projects span across 34 Afghan provinces, addressing critical areas such as power, water supply, road connectivity, healthcare, education, agriculture, and capacity building.</p>

<p>Various bilateral and multilateral meetings have taken place, and the Union Budget for 2024-25 allocated Rs. 200 crores to Afghanistan. This represents a decrease from Rs. 350 crores in the 2021-22 budget.</p>

<p>The Taliban have urged India to resume development projects, arguing that such initiatives would create job opportunities, alleviate poverty, and support development.</p>

<p><strong>The China Factor</strong></p>

<p>India's outreach to Afghanistan is influenced by the regional dynamics, including China's growing activity. Initially excluded from China's expansive Belt and Road Initiative (BRI) in Asia, Afghanistan has seen increased Chinese involvement and funding. A Parliamentary Committee on External Affairs report from last year noted the strategic importance for India to deepen ties with its smaller neighbours in response to China's BRI and America's Indo-Pacific vision.</p>

<p>China is courting the Taliban to counter the Uyghur separatist movement. Beijing wants the Taliban to address the Eastern Turkestan Islamic Movement, which, according to a 2021 UN report, is active in Badakhshan, Faryab, Kabul, and Nuristan provinces. The report indicated that the group seeks to establish a Uyghur state in Xinjiang, China, and facilitates the movement of fighters from Afghanistan to China.</p>

<p>Despite its efforts, Beijing's support for Afghanistan has not met all expectations. China has provided funds, machinery, and technical support, but not as generously as Afghanistan hoped. The country's economic growth was recorded at -6.2% in 2022, according to Afghanistan's National Statistics and Information Authority (NSIA).</p>

<p><strong>Pakistan No Longer a Friend</strong></p>

<p>Pakistan has long served as a training ground and launchpad for the Mujahideen in their struggle against Soviet forces. Reportedly supported by the CIA, Peshawar in Pakistan quickly became a crucial hub for the fighters. This is well-documented in The Bear Trap by Brigadier Mohammed Yousuf and Mark Adkin. Yousuf, who led Pakistan's Inter-Services Intelligence (ISI) Afghan desk from 1983 to 1987, and Adkin, a major in the British Army, detail the logistical and military support Pakistan received from the CIA during the Soviet occupation of Afghanistan.</p>

<p>Beyond the USA and the former USSR, several other countries have played strategic games in Afghanistan due to its geopolitical significance. This has resulted in the division of its people along ethnic and cultural lines to serve the interests of these external powers. Peter Hopkirk chronicles this history in The Great Game, a term coined by British intelligence officer Captain Arthur Conolly during the British occupation of the country in the 19th century.</p>

<p>Despite their ethnic differences, Afghans have resisted aggressors for centuries. During the Soviet era, Pashtuns from the south and Tajiks and Uzbeks from the north employed guerrilla tactics, striking and retreating across the country's rugged terrain.</p>

<p>A paper by Amna Puri-Mirza, a researcher specializing in the Middle East, published in September 2022, reveals that as of 2020, Afghanistan's population of approximately 33 million was composed of 42% Pashtuns, 27% Tajiks, and 9% Hazaras. The CIA World Factbook estimates that in 2020, Afghan Persian (Dari) and Pashto were spoken by 77% and 48% of the population, respectively.</p>

<p>The Durand Line, established in November 1893 as the official boundary between undivided India and Afghanistan, remains contentious. Afghanistan has never accepted this boundary, seeking its shift eastward to incorporate Pashtun-majority areas in Pakistan. This disagreement has led to intermittent conflicts.</p>

<p>Relations between Islamabad and Kabul have deteriorated as Pakistan has increased its pressure on Afghanistan for harbouring "Pakistani Taliban" and for alleged strikes on Pakistani soil. Frequent gunfights have led to the closure of the border, causing significant disruptions for Afghan traders. Key border crossings like Torkham and Spin Boldak have been particularly affected, with long queues of stranded vehicles.</p>

<p>India has faced setbacks in its involvement in Afghanistan over the past three decades. In the ongoing great game, countries like China, Russia, and Iran are influential in shaping Afghanistan's future, and India must navigate these shifting alliances carefully.</p>

<p><em>(Jayanta Bhattacharya is a senior journalist writing on polls and politics, conflict, farmer and human interest issues)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/a09f28p_taliban-anniversary-celebration_625x300_14_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-extends-petrol-exports-ban-until-2025-to-maintain-stable-situation-6336012]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russia Extends Petrol Exports Ban Until 2025 To "Maintain Stable Situation"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-extends-petrol-exports-ban-until-2025-to-maintain-stable-situation-6336012]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 14 Aug 2024 16:23:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Russian government announced Wednesday that it was reintroducing a ban on petrol exports for another six months to "maintain a stable situation" on the domestic fuel market after major price hikes.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Russian government announced Wednesday that it was reintroducing a ban on petrol exports for another six months to "maintain a stable situation" on the domestic fuel market after major price hikes.</p>

<p>The government said in a statement that it has "brought in a restriction on exports of petrol from September 1 to December 31, 2024".</p>

<p>The measure is intended to keep prices stable "during a period of continued seasonal demand and planned repairs on oil refineries", the government said.</p>

<p>Russia in March introduced a six-month ban on petrol exports, but then suspended it temporarily between May and July, saying the domestic market was saturated.</p>

<p>The new restriction will not affect deliveries carried out under intergovernmental agreements including those with the Eurasian Economic Union member countries -- Belarus, Kazakhstan, Kyrgyzstan and Armenia -- the government said.</p>

<p>Despite its massive energy reserves, Russia announced a similar export ban on diesel and petrol last year as pump prices hit Russians' purchasing power, already affected by weakening of the ruble due to sanctions.</p>

<p>In 2023, Russia produced 43.9 million tonnes of petrol, according to official figures.</p>

<p>Revenues from oil and gas sales remain essential to Moscow as it gears its economy towards efforts to sustain the military offensive in Ukraine.</p>

<p>In recent months, Ukrainian forces have targeted fuel depots with drone attacks, cutting off vital resources for Russia's forces.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/kog4sr3g_petrol-export_625x300_14_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[In 2023, Russia produced 43.9 million tonnes of petrol, according to official figures. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ousted-thai-pm-srettha-thavisin-says-he-respects-court-decision-6335882]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ousted Thai PM Srettha Thavisin Says He "Respects" Court Decision]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ousted-thai-pm-srettha-thavisin-says-he-respects-court-decision-6335882]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 14 Aug 2024 16:03:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ousted Thai prime minister Srettha Thavisin said Wednesday that he respected a court ruling that removed him from office in an ethics case.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ousted Thai prime minister Srettha Thavisin said Wednesday that he respected a court ruling that removed him from office in an ethics case.</p>

<p>"I respect the verdict. I reiterate that for the almost one year I have been in this role, I have tried with good intentions to lead the country with honesty," Srettha told reporters outside his office after the Constitutional Court ruling.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/465cpv78_srettha-thavisin-afp-_625x300_14_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Prime Minister Srettha Thavisin has been removed from office on Wednesday (file).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rarely-seen-titanic-artefacts-kept-in-secret-warehouse-6335881]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Rarely Seen Titanic Artefacts Stored In Secret Warehouse In US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rarely-seen-titanic-artefacts-kept-in-secret-warehouse-6335881]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 14 Aug 2024 16:02:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The collection includes a range of personal belongings and relics, such as handbags, perfume vials still containing fragrances, and countless other items.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Since the Titanic's wreckage was discovered in 1985, a vast array of over 5,000 artefacts have been recovered from the depths of the Atlantic Ocean. A significant portion of these treasures are stored in a secretive warehouse in Atlanta, Georgia, with limited access for viewing.&nbsp;However, the exact location is not known.</p>

<p>As per <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c1vd9k33r00o">BBC</a></em>, the collection includes a range of personal belongings and relics, such as handbags, perfume vials still containing fragrances, and countless other items. In a rare and exclusive opportunity, the BBC was granted access to the secretive storage facility.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Notably, RMS Titanic Inc, a US-based company, holds the exclusive rights to salvage artefacts from the Titanic wreck site, granted by a US court in 1994. However, the company is prohibited from breaking or dividing any of the recovered items, ensuring they remain intact and preserved for historical and cultural significance.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Among the treasures in the Titanic collection, is a small, exquisite alligator skin handbag that belonged to Marian Meanwell, a 63-year-old milliner who was travelling in third class, bound for the United States, to be with her daughter who was recently widowed.</p>

<p>''It's a really beautiful, fashionable little bag,'' said Tomasina Ray, director of collections for RMS Titanic Inc.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The handbag endured the unforgiving North Atlantic waters for decades, safeguarding its precious contents. Inside the bag was a faded photograph, yellowed paperwork, and a heartfelt, handwritten reference letter from her former landlord in London. However, the most heartbreaking discovery was her medical inspection card, revealing that she had initially booked passage on the Majestic, but when it failed to sail, her booking was transferred to the ill-fated Titanic.</p>

<p>A collection of miniature perfume vials, that belonged to Adolphe Saalfeld, a second-class passenger and perfume connoisseur, was also found.&nbsp;Miraculously, the vials remained sealed, and their aroma was intact.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Other items recovered are a champagne bottle, still sealed with a cork, metal pins used to hold the ship's steel plates together etc.&nbsp;</p>

<p></p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/nkl2onfg_titanic_625x300_14_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[However, the exact location is not known.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/france-probes-cyberbullying-of-olympic-boxer-imane-khelif-amid-gender-row-6335523]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[France Probes Cyberbullying Of Olympic Boxer Imane Khelif Amid Gender Row]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/france-probes-cyberbullying-of-olympic-boxer-imane-khelif-amid-gender-row-6335523]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 14 Aug 2024 15:18:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[France has launched a cyberbullying probe following a complaint by Algerian Olympic boxing champion Imane Khelif, who was at the centre of a gender controversy at the Paris Olympic Games, prosecutors said on Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>France has launched a cyberbullying probe following a complaint by Algerian Olympic boxing champion Imane Khelif, who was at the centre of a gender controversy at the Paris Olympic Games, prosecutors said on Wednesday.</p>

<p>The investigation was opened Tuesday into "cyberharrassment" following the high-profile gender row at the Games, the Paris public prosecutor's office told AFP.</p>

<p>The athlete's lawyer Nabil Boudi said last week that Khelif, 25, had filed a complaint for online harassment, calling it a "fight for justice."</p>

<p>"The investigation will determine who was behind this misogynist, racist and sexist campaign, but will also have to concern itself with those who fed the online lynching," he said at the time.</p>

<p>Khelif won the women's 66kg final against China's Yang Liu in a unanimous points decision, having been the focus of intense scrutiny in the French capital during the Olympics.</p>

<p>Together with Taiwan's Lin Yu-ting, who won the 57kg women's final, Khelif was disqualified from last year's world championships after they failed gender eligibility testing.</p>

<p>However, they were cleared to compete in Paris, setting the stage for one of the biggest controversies of the Games.</p>

<p>The International Boxing Association's Russian president Umar Kremlev has targeted both athletes, claiming that Khelif and Lin had undergone "genetic testing that shows that these are men".</p>

<p>The IBA was responsible for the world championships in 2023 that Lin and Khelif were thrown out of, but the IOC cleared them to box in Paris.</p>

<p>Khelif said she is "a woman like any other."</p>

<p>"I was born a woman, lived a woman and competed as a woman," she told reporters about her eligibility.</p>

<p>Russia's team has been banned from the Paris Olympics over Moscow's invasion of Ukraine.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/ttmus568_imane-khelif_625x300_14_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Imane Khelif won the women's 66kg final against China's Yang Liu in a unanimous points decision (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/thai-court-removes-pm-from-office-over-ethics-case-6335511]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Thai Court Removes PM Over Appointment Of Minister With Criminal Conviction]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/thai-court-removes-pm-from-office-over-ethics-case-6335511]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 14 Aug 2024 15:15:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Thailand's Constitutional Court removed Prime Minister Srettha Thavisin from office on Wednesday as it ruled against him in an ethics case that threw the kingdom into fresh political turmoil.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Thailand's Constitutional Court removed Prime Minister Srettha Thavisin from office on Wednesday, ruling against him in an ethics case that throws the kingdom into fresh political turmoil.</p>

<p>The judges ruled 5-4 that Srettha breached regulations by appointing a lawyer with a criminal conviction to his cabinet, in a case brought by a group of former senators appointed by Thailand's former ruling junta.</p>

<p>The ruling comes a week after the same court dissolved the main opposition Move Forward Party (MFP) and banned its former leader from politics for 10 years.</p>

<p>"The court rules by a majority of five to four that the ministerial position of the prime minister is terminated under the constitution, because he has not shown honesty in appointing this minister," Judge Punya Udchachon said in reading the court's judgment.</p>

<p>Punya said that Srettha must have known about lawyer Pichit Chuenban's 2008 conviction when he appointed him to the cabinet.</p>

<p>"The appointment of the second respondent (Pichit) shows the first respondent (Srettha) has no honesty and breached ethical standards," Punya added.</p>

<p>Srettha leaves office after less than a year in the job -- the third prime minister from the Pheu Thai party to be kicked out by the Constitutional Court.</p>

<p>Thai politics has endured two decades of chronic instability, marked by coups, street protests and court orders, much of it energised by the long-running battle between the military, pro-royalist establishment and progressive parties linked to Pheu Thai patriarch Thaksin Shinawatra.</p>

<p>The court ruling dismisses not only Srettha but also his whole cabinet, and parliament will now have to meet to choose a new prime minister.</p>

<p><strong>Cycle of turmoil</strong></p>

<p>The case against Srettha centred around the appointment of Pichit, a lawyer associated with the family of billionaire former prime minister Thaksin -- former Manchester City owner and longtime bete noire of the kingdom's conservative pro-royalist, pro-military elite.</p>

<p>Pichit, sentenced to six months' jail in 2008 for a graft-related offence, quit the cabinet in a bid to save Srettha, but the court pressed ahead with a case initiated by a complaint by senators appointed by Thailand's former junta.</p>

<p>Srettha came to power less than a year ago at the head of a coalition led by Pheu Thai, after striking a deal with army-linked parties.</p>

<p>The ruling highlights old divisions in Thai politics between the conservative establishment and progressive parties such as Pheu Thai and its new rival MFP.</p>

<p>Thailand has endured a cycle of coups, court rulings, street protests and elections since the early 2000s as the establishment battled Thaksin and his allies for dominance.</p>

<p>The 40 senators who brought the complaint were all appointed by the military junta that ousted the elected Pheu Thai government in a 2014 coup.</p>

<p>The senate also played a crucial role in thwarting MFP's attempt to form a government after it won the most seats in last year's general election.</p>

<p>Senators alarmed by its pledges to reform lese-majeste laws and break up powerful business monopolies refused to endorse MFP's then-leader Pita Limjaroenrat as prime minister and the party was forced into opposition.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/465cpv78_srettha-thavisin-afp-_625x300_14_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Prime Minister Srettha Thavisin has been removed from office on Wednesday (file).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-zealand-charity-apologises-for-donating-sweets-containing-lethal-meth-6335236]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[New Zealand Charity Apologises For Donating Sweets Containing Lethal Meth]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-zealand-charity-apologises-for-donating-sweets-containing-lethal-meth-6335236]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 14 Aug 2024 14:36:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A New Zealand charity apologised on Wednesday for distributing dozens of pineapple-flavoured candies that were found to be laced with potentially lethal amounts of methamphetamine.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A New Zealand charity apologised on Wednesday for distributing dozens of pineapple-flavoured candies that were found to be laced with potentially lethal amounts of <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/lethal-amount-of-meth-found-hidden-in-sweets-in-new-zealand-probe-underway-6332877" target="_blank">methamphetamine.</a></p>

<p>The Auckland City Mission, that donates parcels of essentials to New Zealanders who cannot afford food, said it first became aware of the issue on Tuesday afternoon when some recipients complained about the foul-tasting candies.</p>

<p>Three people - a child, a teenager and a charity worker - sought medical treatment after tasting the boiled sweets, though none are currently in hospital, Detective Inspector Glenn Baldwin from Auckland police told reporters.</p>

<p>There was no suggestion of wrongdoing by the charity, he added.</p>

<p>"To say we are devastated is an understatement," the Mission said in a statement.</p>

<p>The candy, which was donated by an unknown member of the public, was tested by the New Zealand Drug Foundation charity, which found they contained a potentially lethal 3 grams (0.1 oz)of methamphetamine.</p>

<p>"A common dose to swallow is between 10-25mg, so this contaminated lolly contained up to 300 doses," said foundation Executive Director Sarah Helm.</p>

<p>Police believed the candies were the by product of an international drug trafficking operation and have called for them to be handed them over to the authorities. They are also investigating how the candies entered the country, Baldwin said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-05/pu18h51o_candies_625x300_11_May_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The candy contained a potentially lethal 3 grams (0.1 oz) of methamphetamine (Representational).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/brian-niccol-the-chipotle-boss-who-has-replaced-indian-origin-starbucks-ceo-laxman-narasimhan-6335111]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Brian Niccol: The Chipotle Boss Who Has Replaced Indian-Origin Starbucks CEO]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/brian-niccol-the-chipotle-boss-who-has-replaced-indian-origin-starbucks-ceo-laxman-narasimhan-6335111]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 14 Aug 2024 14:16:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Brian Niccol will take charge as the Starbucks CEO, effective September 1, the company announced on Wednesday. Mr Niccol, a seasoned executive with a proven track record, will succeed Laxman Narasimhan, who stepped down after just over a year.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<ul>
	<li>Brian Niccol is from California, US. He graduated in 1996 with an Engineering degree from Miami University, where he was a member of the Phi Delta Theta fraternity. He later pursued an MBA from the University of Chicago's Booth School of Business.&nbsp;</li>
	<li>Mr Niccol began his professional career with a decade-long stint at Procter &amp; Gamble. He then held leadership positions at Pizza Hut, Taco Bell and Yum!. Mr Niccol became the CEO of Taco Bell in 2015.&nbsp;</li>
	<li>In March 2018, he took over as the CEO of Chipotle Mexican Grill. At the time, the company was facing challenges related to an E. coli outbreak. Under his leadership, Chipotle's stock soared by nearly 800%. He focused on improving digital ordering/sales, menu expansion and restoring the brand's reputation.</li>
	<li>Mr Niccol has been recognised for his leadership and impact in the industry, receiving accolades such as Bloomberg's 'People Who Defined 2019' (The Bloomberg 50) and Comparably's 'Best CEO's' (2019). In 2024, he joined the Board of Directors for Walmart. Prior to this, Mr Niccol served on the Board of Directors for KB Home and Harley Davidson.</li>
	<li>Brian Niccol is an avid sports fan, regularly watching ESPN's Sportscenter. His passion for athletics extends beyond just being a viewer. Recently, he pledged a $2 million gift to his alma mater, Miami University in Ohio, specifically to improve its men's basketball programme.&nbsp;</li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/kmc4mm8o_brian-niccol_625x300_14_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Brian Niccol is from California]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-why-starbucks-is-being-boycotted-6334266]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Why Starbucks Is Facing Global Boycott Calls: The Controversy Explained]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-why-starbucks-is-being-boycotted-6334266]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 14 Aug 2024 14:01:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Starbucks has come under fire for its alleged connection with Israel. The calls for a boycott intensified, especially after Israel's ongoing war in Gaza killed nearly 40,000 Palestinians and left about 100,000 injured.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Starbucks, on Tuesday, announced that Brian Niccol, the CEO of Chipotle, would take over as its new CEO, just over a year after <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/laxman-narasimhan-brian-niccol-starbucks-indian-origin-ceo-who-was-recently-fired-almost-never-worked-past-6-pm-6333521">Laxman Narasimhan</a> assumed the role. Under Mr Narasimhan's leadership, Starbucks struggled with declining sales, partly attributed to a broader consumer backlash due to the corporation's alleged links to Israel. This resulted in growing calls for a boycott of American coffee houses across the Middle East and South Asia.</p>

<h2><strong>Why Starbucks is being boycotted</strong></h2>

<p>Starbucks has come under fire for its alleged connection with Israel. The calls for a boycott intensified, especially after Israel's ongoing war in Gaza killed nearly 40,000 Palestinians and left about 100,000 injured.</p>

<p>The controversy began with a hoax letter that claimed Starbucks was funding the Israeli military. This sparked outrage, particularly in regions sympathetic to the Palestinian cause. The boycott gained traction, especially on social media platforms such as TikTok and X, where the hashtag #boycottstarbucks had millions of views.&nbsp;Many continue to say that Starbucks is either directly or indirectly supporting Israel.&nbsp;</p>

<p>But there's more to it. Starbucks is an American company, and the US has been a staunch ally of Israel, providing substantial military aid and diplomatic support for their 10-month-long military campaign in Gaza. Since October 7, in what Israel has described as "retaliatory" action, nearly all schools and hospitals have been targeted and scores of tent camps have been bombed killing thousands -- a vast majority of the children and women. The roughly 360 square km&nbsp;area of Gaza has been reduced to rubble. At least 1.9 million people have been displaced internally, with many forced to move nine to ten times during the course of this war.<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Progressive groups in the US and abroad are increasingly vocal about their opposition to Israeli policies, fuelling the boycotts of American companies perceived to be pro-Israel.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>Starbucks' stance on the Israeli genocide</strong></h2>

<p>Starbucks has firmly denied claims of supporting Israel or any other government or military operation in the Middle East. In a statement, the coffee giant said they "condemned violence" and stressed their commitment to providing a welcoming and inclusive environment for all customers worldwide.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Starbucks is a global company committed to providing a place where everyone feels welcome and a sense of belonging, anywhere in the world. Our hearts break for all affected by the violence and conflict in the Middle East. We've always condemned violence against the innocent," they <a href="https://stories.starbucks.com/press/2023/what-has-starbucks-said-about-the-conflict-in-israel-and-gaza/">wrote</a>.</p>

<p>The company reiterated that it has "never contributed to any government or military operation", but the damage was done, and the brand continues to face backlash, particularly in the Middle East. In response to declining sales, Starbucks' Middle East franchises had to fire 2,000 employees in March.</p>

<h2><strong>Other brands facing calls for boycott</strong></h2>

<p>Starbucks is not alone in facing these challenges. Other global brands have also been targeted for boycotts due to perceived or real connections with Israel.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Fast food giant McDonalds was boycotted due to its support for Israel. The controversy began when Omri Padan, the CEO of McDonald's Israeli franchise, offered free meals to Israeli forces. This gesture was seen as a show of support for the Israeli military, sparking calls for a boycott. The boycott gained momentum in other countries such as Kuwait, Malaysia and Pakistan, where consumers accused McDonald's of having a pro-Israel stance.</p>

<p>Disney+ has faced boycotts due to its perceived support of Israel, with activists calling for a boycott of the platform. Clothing brand <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/feature/zara-pulls-out-controversial-ad-amid-boycott-calls-4658825#:~:text=People%20on%20X%20(formerly%20Twitter,at%20mass%20graves%20in%20Gaza.">Zara was boycotted</a>&nbsp;after its marketing campaign featured rubble and body bags, leading to protests outside stores in several countries. Critics called the campaign "tone-deaf", forcing the clothing brand to pull it down from all platforms.</p>

<p>Puma has been targeted by boycotts due to its sponsorship of the Israeli Football Association.</p>

<p>Other fast-food chains have also faced boycotts in the Middle East due to their perceived support of Israel. Domino's, Pizza Hut, and KFC have all faced challenges in the region, while Burger King has faced boycotts in Turkey due to its perceived support of Israel. Coca-Cola, too, has faced similar boycotts in Turkey and parts of South Asia.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-10/gll77q1o_starbucks_625x300_15_October_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Starbucks has firmly denied claims of supporting Israel or any other government.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-shares-breathtaking-aerial-view-of-tesla-headquarters-pic-inside-6334591]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk Shares Breathtaking Aerial View Of Tesla Headquarters. Pic Inside]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-shares-breathtaking-aerial-view-of-tesla-headquarters-pic-inside-6334591]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 14 Aug 2024 13:08:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Billionaire Elon Musk has shared a "beautiful" photograph of the Tesla headquarters in Texas, leaving many awestruck.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Billionaire Elon Musk has shared a "beautiful" photograph of the Tesla headquarters in Texas, leaving many awestruck. The Tesla CEO posted the picture on X, a social media platform he owns. The image, clicked in the morning, is an aerial view of the company headquarters. Soon after, the photograph went viral and received more than 4.3 million views.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Tesla HQ pic taken this morning <a href="https://t.co/qfucSpBK17">pic.twitter.com/qfucSpBK17</a></p>
 Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1823590581190492398?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 14, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>In the comments section, several users called it "magnificent," while others wondered if it was AI-generated.<br />
<br />
"Gorgeous sunrise," one user wrote.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Gorgeous sunrise.</p>
 Bella (@stockbella) <a href="https://twitter.com/stockbella/status/1823590912405995864?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 14, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Another one added, "That looks beautiful!"</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">That looks beautiful!</p>
 Gambino (@GambinoXBT) <a href="https://twitter.com/GambinoXBT/status/1823594650092896761?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 14, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>A third person wrote, "Even Planet Earth shows the futuristic Tesla HQ in all its glory"<br />
<br />
Some questioned whether the image was even real. "Gorgeous, I thought it's generated by Grok-2 with the prompt &nbsp;"future hyperrealistic gigafactory on Mars," one user wrote.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Gorgeous, I thought it's generated by Grok-2 with prompt "future hyperrealistic gigafactory on Mars"</p>
 Yuchen Jin (@Yuchenj_UW) <a href="https://twitter.com/Yuchenj_UW/status/1823592285474578486?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 14, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Another one commented, "This isn't AI?"</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">This isn't AI? ????</p>
 The Crypto Network (@raffayalvi) <a href="https://twitter.com/raffayalvi/status/1823591915855413588?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 14, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>In December 2021, Tesla officially moved its corporate headquarters from Silicon Valley to a large factory in Austin, Texas. The announcement was made by the company in a filing with US securities regulators.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
The company has relocated from Palo Alto, California, to what it has called a Gigafactory on Harold Green Road near Austin, Texas. Before that, Musk, in October 2021, at the company's annual meeting, hinted at the imminent move.<br />
<br />
In April this year, Reuters, citing an internal memo, &nbsp;reported that Tesla would lay off over 10% of its global workforce. This came as the company reportedly grappled with falling sales and an intensified price war for electric vehicles (EVs).<br />
<br />
In a post on X, Elon Musk earlier said, "About every five years, we need to reorganize and streamline the company for the next phase of growth".<br />
<br />
According to filings with the US regulators, the company's strength has jumped from around 1,00,000 in late 2021 to more than 140,000 in late 2023.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/do8o3bco_elon-musk-reuters-_625x300_26_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The image, clicked in the morning, is an aerial view of the company headquarters.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/taliban-mark-3-years-in-power-since-afghanistan-takeover-with-military-show-6334539]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Taliban Mark 3 Years In Power Since Afghanistan Takeover With Military Show]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/taliban-mark-3-years-in-power-since-afghanistan-takeover-with-military-show-6334539]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 14 Aug 2024 12:58:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Afghanistan's Taliban rulers celebrated three years in power on Wednesday with a military parade paying homage to their homemade bombs used in war, fighter aircraft and goose-stepping security forces.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Afghanistan's Taliban rulers celebrated three years in power on Wednesday with a military parade paying homage to their homemade bombs used in war, fighter aircraft and goose-stepping security forces.</p>

<p>The Taliban's armed forces towed Soviet-era tanks and artillery pieces through the former US air base in Bagram, where Chinese and Iranian diplomats were among hundreds who gathered for the parade and speeches.</p>

<p>The former Bagram base once served as the linchpin for US-led operations against the Taliban for two decades.</p>

<p>A swarm of motorbikes strapped with yellow jerry cans, often used to carry homemade bombs during the fight against international forces, also rumbled past assembled officials.</p>

<p>There were also US-made armoured personnel carriers, the black-and-white flag of the Islamic Emirate of Afghanistan -- the Taliban government's formal name for the country -- fluttering above them.</p>

<p>Helicopters and fighter aircraft flew over the base, where Taliban fighters were once imprisoned, about 40 kilometres (25 miles) north of Kabul.</p>

<p>Taliban forces seized the capital on August 15, 2021, after the US-backed government collapsed and its leaders fled into exile. The anniversary is marked a day earlier on the Afghan calendar.</p>

<p>Their government remains unrecognised by any other state, with restrictions on women, who bear the brunt of policies the United Nations has called "gender apartheid", remaining a key sticking point.</p>

<p>"Three years have passed since the dreams of girls have been buried," Madina, a 20-year-old university student in Kabul, told AFP.</p>

<p>"It's a bitter feeling that every year, the celebration of this day reminds us of the efforts, memories, and goals we had for our future."</p>

<p>Prime Minister Mohammad Hassan Akhund, who had been scheduled to appear at Bagram, praised the Taliban authorities' victory over "Western occupiers" in a statement read by his chief of staff.</p>

<p>The Taliban government has "the responsibility to maintain Islamic rule, protect property, people's lives and the respect of our nation", he said.</p>

<h3><strong>'Victory'</strong></h3>

<p>Security has been a key priority for Taliban authorities as they consolidated their grip on power over the past three years, implementing laws based on their strict interpretation of Islam.</p>

<p>However, attacks by the Islamic State group remain a threat and extra security was deployed in Kabul and the Taliban's spiritual home of Kandahar in southern Afghanistan ahead of the "day of victory".</p>

<p>Helicopters also flew over the Ghazi stadium in Kabul, where hundreds of men gathered to watch an exhibition of athletics and performances of Taliban anthems.</p>

<p>The Taliban takeover is marked both in mid-August around the date Kabul fell and at the end of the month, when the last foreign troops left Afghanistan after a chaotic withdrawal.</p>

<p>The black-and-white standard decorated streets and trucks full of young men that choked Kabul streets.</p>

<p>Happy young boys carried a large flag in the Green Zone, once a secure enclave of foreign embassies, saying "We're ready to do a suicide attack!"</p>

<p>While many Afghans expressed relief at the end of 40 years of successive conflicts, the economy remains stagnant and the population mired in a worsening humanitarian crisis.</p>

<p>A joint statement from international non-governmental groups warned of the growing aid funding gap, with 23.7 million people in need of humanitarian assistance.</p>

<p>Women have been squeezed from public life -- banned from many jobs as well as parks and gyms -- and barred from secondary and higher education.</p>

<p>Human Rights Watch (HRW) reiterated calls for pressure on the Taliban government to lift restrictions on women.</p>

<p>"The third anniversary of the Taliban's takeover is a grim reminder of Afghanistan's human rights crisis, but it should also be a call for action," said Fereshta Abbasi, HRW's Afghanistan researcher.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/a09f28p_taliban-anniversary-celebration_625x300_14_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The economy remains stagnant and the population mired in a worsening humanitarian crisis.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/disappeared-bangladeshi-lawyer-recounts-hasinas-secret-jail-6334392]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bangladeshi Lawyer Reveals Sheikh Hasina's Secret Jail "House Of Mirrors"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/disappeared-bangladeshi-lawyer-recounts-hasinas-secret-jail-6334392]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 14 Aug 2024 12:39:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Blindfolded, handcuffed and bundled out of his secret prison for the first time in eight years, Bangladeshi barrister Ahmad Bin Quasem held his breath and listened for the sound of a cocked pistol.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Blindfolded, handcuffed and bundled out of his secret prison for the first time in eight years, Bangladeshi barrister Ahmad Bin Quasem held his breath and listened for the sound of a cocked pistol.</p>

<p>Instead, he was tossed from a car and into a muddy ditch on Dhaka's outskirts -- alive, at liberty, and with no knowledge of the national upheaval that had prompted his abrupt release.</p>

<p>"That's the first time I got fresh air in eight years," Quasem, 40, told AFP. "I thought they were going to kill me."</p>

<p>Sheikh Hasina, the premier responsible for Quasem's abduction and disappearance, had fled the country hours earlier.</p>

<p>Her August 5 departure brought a sudden curtain down on 15 years of autocracy that included the mass detention and extrajudicial killing of her political opponents.</p>

<p>But Quasem was in the dark.</p>

<p>He had been confined in the "House of Mirrors" (Aynaghar), a facility run by army intelligence, given its name because its detainees were never supposed to see any other person besides themselves.</p>

<p>Throughout his long incarceration, Quasem was shackled around the clock in windowless solitary confinement.</p>

<p>His jailers were under strict instruction not to relay news from the outside world.</p>

<h3><strong>Screaming</strong></h3>

<p>Elsewhere in the detention centre, guards blared music throughout the day that drowned out the Islamic call to prayer from nearby mosques.</p>

<p>It prevented Quasem, a devout Muslim, from knowing when he should offer his prayers -- and from keeping track of how long had elapsed since his abduction.</p>

<p>When the music was off, he heard the anguished sounds of other detainees.</p>

<p>"Slowly, slowly, I could realise that I am not alone," he said. "I could hear people crying, I could hear people being tortured, I could hear people screaming."</p>

<p>Human Rights Watch last year said security forces had committed "over 600 enforced disappearances" since Hasina came to power in 2009.</p>

<p>Rumours abounded of a secret black site housing some of that number, but Aynaghar was unknown to the public until the publication abroad of a 2022 whistleblower report.</p>

<p>Hasina's government consistently maintained afterwards that it did not exist.</p>

<p>It also denied committing enforced disappearances, claiming some of those reported missing had drowned in the Mediterranean while trying to reach Europe.</p>

<h3><strong>Days before my father's execution</strong></h3>

<p>Quasem is certain of the reason for his abduction.</p>

<p>His father, Mir Quasem Ali, a senior member of Bangladesh's largest Islamist party Jamaat-e-Islami, was on trial that year.</p>

<p>Ali was accused of running a paramilitary group that tortured pro-independence Bangladeshis during the country's 1971 liberation war against Pakistan.</p>

<p>He and several others were indicted by a war crimes tribunal, ostensibly to bring justice to the victims of that devastating conflict, but widely seen as a means for Hasina to eliminate political opponents.</p>

<p>Whether or not Ali was guilty, there was no way of knowing from the mockery of justice that accompanied his prosecution.</p>

<p>Quasem, called to the bar in London and then aged 32, was running his father's defence.</p>

<p>His regular media briefings on procedural lapses and judicial bias at the tribunal, echoed by rights groups and UN experts, put a target on his back.</p>

<p>Plainclothes men entered his house one night, snatched him from his family, dragged him down the stairs and threw him in a waiting car.</p>

<p>"I never could believe in my wildest dreams that they would subject me to disappearance just days before my father's execution," Quasem said.</p>

<p>"I kept telling them, "Do you know who I am? I need to be there to conduct my case. I need to be there with my family.'"</p>

<p>Quasem's father was hanged four weeks later. Quasem did not know until about three more years had passed, when one of his jailers accidentally let it slip.</p>

<h3><strong>It felt like eight lifetimes</strong></h3>

<p>After the car that had carried him out of prison sped away, Quasem walked through the night to try and find his way home.</p>

<p>By sheer coincidence, he came across a medical clinic operated by a charity for which his father had once been a trustee.</p>

<p>He was recognised by a staff member and a phone number was frantically tracked down to contact his family, who came rushing to be with him.</p>

<p>But first, the excited chatter of those around him filled Quasem in on the weeks of student protests that had resulted in his release.</p>

<p>"This entire thing, it was made possible by few teenagers," he said.</p>

<p>"When I see these children, these kids, leading the way," he added. "I am really hopeful this will be the opportunity where Bangladesh finds a new direction."</p>

<p>Quasem and his family received AFP warmly into their home -- but the trauma of his detention was immediately apparent.</p>

<p>The thick, coiffed hairdo he sported before his detention has receded into a few wild tufts, and he has lost an alarming amount of weight.</p>

<p>His wife Tahmina Akhter said the publicity around Quasem's case left her feeling ostracised by other mothers at their children's school.</p>

<p>The family was reliably hounded every anniversary of his disappearance and warned to stop publicising it.</p>

<p>His two young daughters were three and four years old when he was taken away.</p>

<p>The elder witnessed his abduction and is still scared of certain authority figures, such as the private security guard posted outside her school.</p>

<p>The younger did not remember him at all.</p>

<p>"It didn't feel like eight years for us," Quasem's mother Ayesha Khatoon told AFP.</p>

<p>"It felt like eight lifetimes."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/urs0b0a_ahmad-bin-quasem-afp-_625x300_14_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Ahmad Bin Quasem was freed from prison after 8 years as the autocratic regime of Sheikh Hasina collapsed.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-palestine-war-girls-in-gaza-lack-access-to-basic-supplies-due-to-israeli-blockade-medic-explains-6334242]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[No Soap, No Water: Girls In War-Torn Gaza Forced To Cut Their Hair]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-palestine-war-girls-in-gaza-lack-access-to-basic-supplies-due-to-israeli-blockade-medic-explains-6334242]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 14 Aug 2024 12:18:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[When girls complain to Gaza paediatrician Lobna al-Azaiza that they have no comb, she tells them to cut off their hair.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When girls complain to Gaza paediatrician Lobna al-Azaiza that they have no comb, she tells them to cut off their hair.</p>

<p>It's not just combs. Israel's blockade of the territory, ravaged by 10 months of war, means there is little or no shampoo, soap, period products or household cleaning materials.</p>

<p>Waste collection and sewage treatment have also collapsed, and it's easy to see why contagious diseases that thrive on overcrowding and lack of cleanliness - such as scabies or fungal infections - are on the rise.</p>

<p>"In the past period, the most common disease we have seen was skin rashes, skin diseases, which have many causes, including the overcrowding in the camps, the increased heat inside the tents, the sweating among children, and the lack of sufficient water for bathing," the doctor said.</p>

<p>Azaiza used to work at Kamal Adwan Hospital in Beit Lahia until Israeli tanks separated the north of the besieged enclave from the south.</p>

<p>Like most of Gaza's medics, she has adapted and continues to treat patients, walking to work past her own ruined house, demolished by an Israeli strike.</p>

<p>The tent clinic she set up with a small team began by treating children but has by necessity become a practice for whole families, most of whom have also been ordered or bombed out of their homes, like the vast majority of Gaza's 2.3 million people.</p>

<p>Even the medication that is available is often unaffordable; a tube of simple burn ointment can now cost 200 shekels ($53).</p>

<p>International aid deliveries have been dramatically reduced since Israel seized control of the Rafah border crossing from Egypt, exacerbating a humanitarian crisis.</p>

<p>Israel denies responsibility for delays in getting urgent humanitarian aid in, saying that the UN and others are responsible for its distribution inside the enclave.</p>

<p>Azaiza has little doubt about where the immediate solution lies:</p>

<p>"The border crossing must be opened so that we can bring in medications, as most of the current ones are ineffective: zero effect, there is no effect on the skin diseases that we see."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/vek51ji_palestine-girl_625x300_14_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel's blockade means there is little or no soap, period products or household cleaning materials.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>