<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Sep 2024 07:30:13 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-calls-new-zealands-spy-report-claims-entirely-baseless-6493639]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[China Calls New Zealand's Spy Report Claims "Entirely Baseless"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-calls-new-zealands-spy-report-claims-entirely-baseless-6493639]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Sep 2024 07:30:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[China insisted Thursday it did not pose a threat to New Zealand's national security after the country's spy service singled out Beijing-backed groups as a "complex intelligence concern".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>China insisted Thursday it did not pose a threat to New Zealand's national security after the country's spy service singled out Beijing-backed groups as a "complex intelligence concern".</p>

<p>New Zealand's Security Intelligence Service levelled unusually candid criticisms at China in its annual threat report, released this week, saying ongoing foreign interference efforts were "complex and deceptive".</p>

<p>China's embassy in New Zealand hit back on Thursday, branding such claims "entirely baseless" and "a figment of imagination or sheer fabrication".</p>

<p>"There is no competition to speak of between the two countries, and China is not a threat to New Zealand," an embassy spokesperson said in a statement.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Beijing was accused of infiltrating local groups, replacing authentic community views with those approved by the ruling party.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In one example, a Chinese-language community news outlet was accused of regurgitating government talking points.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The report's blatant attempts to discredit the Chinese diaspora and students are nothing but an effort to sow discord, create fear, and foster division," replied China's embassy spokesperson.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"This is highly irresponsible, reckless, and deeply unfair to the Chinese community."&nbsp;</p>

<p>China's embassy suggested external forces -- likely a veiled reference to the United States -- had been meddling to undermine relations between the trading partners.&nbsp;</p>

<p>New Zealand's centre-right government has shifted the country's foreign policy closer to traditional Western allies such as the US.&nbsp;</p>

<p>This has come with an increased willingness to speak out against China.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In March, Wellington said a Chinese state-sponsored group was behind a 2021 malicious cyber attack that infiltrated sensitive government computer systems.&nbsp;</p>

<p>China remains New Zealand's biggest trading partner -- exporting dairy, meat and wood products that exceeded NZ$21.39 billion (US$13.2 billion), according to the most recent official data.&nbsp;</p>

<p>New Zealand Prime Minister Christoper Luxon has warned that although China was "a country of undoubted influence", different values mean "there are issues on which we cannot and will not agree".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-06/b6t3g4kg_china-flag-reuters_625x300_13_June_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[China's embassy suggested external forces have meddled to undermine relations between trading partners.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/joe-biden-expresses-concerns-about-peoples-safety-in-bangladesh-with-pm-modi-6493404]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden Expresses Concerns About People's Safety In Bangladesh With PM Modi]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/joe-biden-expresses-concerns-about-peoples-safety-in-bangladesh-with-pm-modi-6493404]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Sep 2024 07:12:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In his call with Prime Minister Narendra Modi last week, US President Joe Biden expressed his concerns about the safety of people in Bangladesh and the future of democratic institutions there, the White House has said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In his call with Prime Minister Narendra Modi last week, US President Joe Biden expressed his concerns about the safety of people in Bangladesh and the future of democratic institutions there, the White House has said.</p>

<p>During the call, President Biden and PM Modi “shared concerns” on the recent developments in Bangladesh, White House national security communications adviser John Kirby told a press conference on Wednesday.</p>

<p>"I mean, the president made clear his continued concerns about the safety and security of the people in Bangladesh and the future of their democratic institutions," he said in response to a question.</p>

<p>The statement issued by the White House after the August 26 call did not mention Bangladesh. However, a post on X by PM Modi and a statement issued by his office mentioned that Bangladesh was discussed during the telephonic conversation.</p>

<p>"The two leaders expressed their shared concern over the situation in Bangladesh. They emphasized restoration of law and order and ensuring safety and security of the minorities, particularly Hindus, in Bangladesh," the Prime Minister's Office (PMO) had said.</p>

<p>In his post on X, PM Modi had said,“We also discussed the situation in Bangladesh and stressed on the need for early restoration of normalcy, and ensuring the safety and security of minorities, especially Hindus, in Bangladesh."&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-06/8c193nh_pm-modi-joe-biden-650_625x300_22_June_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Joe Biden expressed his concerns about the safety of people in Bangladesh with PM Modi.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-says-must-vote-for-trump-as-civilization-as-we-know-it-on-line-6493574]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk Says Must Vote For Trump As "Civilization As We Know It On Line"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-says-must-vote-for-trump-as-civilization-as-we-know-it-on-line-6493574]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Sep 2024 07:09:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In yet another endorsement of Republican candidate Donald Trump, tech billionaire Elon Musk said the former US president must win if the American people want to "preserve freedom and meritocracy".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In yet another endorsement of Republican candidate Donald Trump, tech billionaire Elon Musk said the former US president must win if the American people want to "preserve freedom and meritocracy".</p>

<p>"I have never been materially active in politics before, but this time I think civilization as we know it is on the line. If we want to preserve freedom and a meritocracy in America, then Trump must win," he wrote in a post on X.</p>

<p>Musk was responding to a post that praised him as the "one of the best in the world at synthesizing complex information". The post was responding to a X user accusing Musk of spreading misinformation and joining the "MAGA cult", a reference to Trump's campaign slogan Make America Great Again.</p>

<p>The Tesla CEO had first openly endorsed Trump after he was shot at during a campaign rally in Pennsylvania.</p>

<p>"I fully endorse President Trump and hope for his rapid recovery. Last time America had a candidate this tough was Theodore Roosevelt," he wrote on X while sharing a video of Trump raising his fist in the air after a bullet grazed the top of his ear during an assassination attempt.</p>

<p>Since then, Musk has not shied away from throwing his weight behind the former president's re-election bid. From wanting to work on Trump's cabinet to holding an exclusive interview with the Republican candidate on X, years after the platform banned him for "incitement of violence" after the January 6 violence.</p>

<p>Musk has also hit out at Trump's rival and US Vice President Kamala Harris. On Wednesday, he shared a shared an AI-generated image of Harris and said she "vows to be a communist dictator on day one".&nbsp;</p>

<p>This came after Harris attacked Trump for "vowing to be a dictator on day one" of his job if he is elected President of USA again.</p>

<p>In the past, Musk had backed Joe Biden in the 2020 US Presidential Election. He has said he worked closely with the Obama administration and he voted for Hilary Clinton in 2016 against Trump.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/d89c4me8_elon-musk-donald-trump-_625x300_20_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-welcomes-role-of-any-nation-to-help-end-ukraine-conflict-white-house-6493344]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Welcomes Role Of Any Nation To Help End Ukraine Conflict: White House]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-welcomes-role-of-any-nation-to-help-end-ukraine-conflict-white-house-6493344]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Sep 2024 07:08:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The US welcomes any nation that is willing to try to help end the conflict in Ukraine, White House national security communications adviser John Kirby has said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The US welcomes any nation that is willing to try to help end the conflict in Ukraine, White House national security communications adviser John Kirby has said.</p>

<p>His remarks came after he was asked at a press conference on Wednesday about President Joe Biden's call to Prime Minister Narendra Modi after the latter's trip to Ukraine that was preceded by his visit to Moscow, and if he thought India could play a role in ending the war.</p>

<p>Kirby said, "Any nation that is willing to try to help end this war and do so in keeping with President Zelenskyy's prerogatives, the Ukrainian people's prerogatives, his plan for a just peace, we would certainly welcome a role like that." On whether he thought India could play a role in bringing peace, the White House official said, "Well, we certainly hope so."</p>

<p>In his call, President Biden commended PM Modi for his historic visits to Poland and Ukraine, the first by an Indian Prime Minister in decades, and for his message of peace and ongoing humanitarian support for Ukraine, including its energy sector.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/t43et4i_ukraine-war_625x300_26_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[White House said that they welcome any nation that is willing to try to help end the conflict in Ukraine.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-will-not-leave-gaza-border-corridor-until-says-benjamin-netanyahu-6493343]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Will Not Leave Gaza Border Corridor Until...: Netanyahu]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-will-not-leave-gaza-border-corridor-until-says-benjamin-netanyahu-6493343]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Sep 2024 05:52:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli PM Benjamin Netanyahu said on Wednesday that Israel will only agree to a permanent ceasefire in Gaza that guarantees the border area between southern Gaza and Egypt could never be used as a lifeline for the Islamist movement Hamas.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said on Wednesday that Israel will only agree to a permanent ceasefire in Gaza that guarantees the border area between southern Gaza and Egypt could never be used as a lifeline for the Islamist movement Hamas.</p>

<p>"Until that happens, we're there," he told a news conference in Jerusalem.</p>

<p>Netanyahu repeated his outright rejection of a withdrawal from the so-called Philadelphi corridor in the first phase of a deal, expected to last 42 days, saying international pressure would make it effectively impossible to return.</p>

<p>For a permanent ceasefire to be agreed upon after that, Israel would need guarantees that whoever ran postwar Gaza would be able to prevent the corridor from being used as a route for smuggling weapons and supplies for Hamas.</p>

<p>"Somebody has to be there," he said. "Bring me anyone who will actually show - not on paper, not in words, not on a slide - but day after day, week after week, month after month, that they can actually prevent a recurrence of what happened there before," he said, referring to Hamas' Oct. 7 attack on Israel.</p>

<p>"We're open to consider it, but I don't see that happening right now."</p>

<p>The Philadelphi corridor, along the southern edge of the Gaza Strip bordering Egypt, has been one of the main obstacles to a deal to halt the fighting in Gaza and bring Israeli hostages home in exchange for Palestinian prisoners.</p>

<p>Netanyahu has insisted on retaining control of the corridor, where Israeli troops have uncovered dozens of tunnels that officials say have been used to supply Hamas with weapons and ammunition.</p>

<p>The prime minister has faced heavy criticism from many in Israel for holding out on the issue, including from many in his own security establishment who believe Israeli troops can make targeted interventions if needed to prevent any smuggling.</p>

<p>The families of many hostages, including some of the six whose bodies were recovered from a tunnel in southern Gaza on Sunday, have accused him of sacrificing their loved ones by insisting on keeping troops in the corridor.</p>

<p>But he said maintaining pressure on Hamas was the best way to return the 101 hostages still remaining in Gaza.</p>

<p>"You need to squeeze them, to put pressure on them to release the remaining hostages. So if you want to release the hostages, you've got to control the Philadelphi corridor," he said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/i85alm98_benjamin-netanyahu_625x300_25_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Benjamin Netanyahu has insisted on retaining control of the corridor.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-sees-no-need-for-new-gaza-ceasefire-talks-urges-pressure-on-israel-6493176]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hamas Sees No Need For New Gaza Ceasefire Talks, Urges Pressure On Israel]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-sees-no-need-for-new-gaza-ceasefire-talks-urges-pressure-on-israel-6493176]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Sep 2024 04:50:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hamas said on Thursday there was no need for new ceasefire proposals for Gaza and pressure should be put on Israel to agree to a U.S. plan that the Islamist group had already accepted.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hamas said on Thursday there was no need for new ceasefire proposals for Gaza and pressure should be put on Israel to agree to a U.S. plan that the Islamist group had already accepted.</p>

<p>The United States was expected to present a new truce proposal aimed at breaking an impasse between Hamas and Israel.</p>

<p>In a statement, Hamas said that Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu sought to thwart an agreement by insisting that Israel will not withdraw from the Philadelphi corridor in southern Gaza.</p>

<p>"We warn against falling into Netanyahu's trap and tricks, as he uses negotiations to prolong the aggression against our people," the statement said.</p>

<p>Hamas said it accepted a July 2 proposal put forward by the U.S.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/qdcfgucg_israel-hamas-war-reuters_625x300_04_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hamas said it accepted a July 2 proposal put forward by the U.S.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uss-georgia-school-shooter-was-14-year-old-student-police-6492821]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US's Georgia School Shooter Was 14-Year-old Student: Police]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uss-georgia-school-shooter-was-14-year-old-student-police-6492821]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Sep 2024 02:45:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The perpetrator of a shooting at a US high school on Wednesday was a 14-year-old student and two of the four people killed were fellow pupils, authorities said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The perpetrator of a shooting at a US high school on Wednesday was a 14-year-old student and two of the four people killed were fellow pupils, authorities said.</p>

<p>"Of those that are deceased, two were students and two were teachers here at the school," said Chris Hosey, director of the Georgia Bureau of Investigation. "The shooter is in custody... He is a fourteen year old student here at the high school."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/k2t4q4co_school-shooting_625x300_04_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The 14-year-old shooter is in custody, police said.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/benjamin-netanyahu-says-hamas-rejected-everything-in-gaza-truce-talks-6492794]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Netanyahu Says Hamas "Rejected Everything" In Gaza Truce Talks]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/benjamin-netanyahu-says-hamas-rejected-everything-in-gaza-truce-talks-6492794]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Sep 2024 02:33:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said on Wednesday that Hamas had rejected all elements of a proposal for a ceasefire in Gaza that would help facilitate the release of hostages.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said on Wednesday that Hamas had rejected all elements of a proposal for a ceasefire in Gaza that would help facilitate the release of hostages.</p>

<p>"Hamas has rejected everything... I hope that changes because I want those hostages out," Netanyahu told a news conference, casting doubt on the possibility of a breakthrough one day after the State Department said it was "time to finalise that deal".</p>

<p>"We're trying to find some area to begin the negotiations," Netanyahu said.</p>

<p>"They (Hamas) refuse to do that... (They said) there's nothing to talk about."</p>

<p>Netanyahu has come under added domestic and international pressure to seal a deal that would free Israeli hostages after authorities announced on Sunday the deaths of six whose bodies were recovered from a tunnel in southern Gaza.</p>

<p>On Monday, Netanyahu said Israeli forces would retain control over the Philadelphi Corridor along the Egypt-Gaza border, vowing "not to give in to pressure" over the issue.</p>

<p>Hamas, whose unprecedented October 7 attack on southern Israel started the war, is demanding a complete Israeli withdrawal from the area as part of the stalled talks mediated by the United States, Qatar and Egypt.</p>

<p>At Wednesday's news conference, Netanyahu reiterated his position on the Philadelphi Corridor, saying that ceding control would allow Hamas to smuggle weapons in and hostages and "terrorists" out.</p>

<p>"You need something to squeeze them, to prevent them, to put pressure on them to release the remaining hostages," he said.</p>

<p>"So if you want to release the hostages, you've got to control the Philadelphi Corridor."</p>

<p>State Department spokesman Matthew Miller told reporters on Wednesday that Washington recognised "the very real needs that Israel has to ensuring that there can't be smuggling across the Philadelphi Corridor", but said "we think that there are ways to address" the issue.</p>

<p>Reaching a deal "is going to require flexibility from the government of Israel, just as it's going to require Hamas to finally find a way to get to yes," Miller said.</p>

<p>Netanyahu, for his part, said he was "flexible when I can be" and "firm when I have to be".</p>

<p><strong>- 'Whole thing' unresolved -</strong></p>

<p>He also stressed that the debate over the Philadelphi Corridor was not the sole sticking point.</p>

<p>Also unanswered, he said, were questions over how many Palestinian prisoners would be freed in exchange for hostages, whether Israel could veto the release of certain prisoners and where released prisoners should go.</p>

<p>"The whole thing has not been resolved," he said.</p>

<p>The October 7 attack by Hamas resulted in the deaths of 1,205 people, mostly civilians including some hostages killed in captivity, according to official Israeli figures.</p>

<p>Of 251 hostages seized by Palestinian militants during the attack, 97 remain in Gaza including 33 the Israeli military says are dead. Scores were released during a one-week truce in November -- the only one so far.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory military offensive in Gaza has so far killed at least 40,861 people, according to the health ministry in the Hamas-run territory.</p>

<p>Most of the dead are women and children, according to the UN rights office.</p>

<p>At protests in several Israeli cities this week, Netanyahu's critics have blamed him for hostages' deaths, saying he has refused to make necessary concessions for striking a ceasefire deal.</p>

<p>US President Joe Biden said this week he did not think Netanyahu was working hard enough to free the hostages.</p>

<p>Also on Wednesday, an Israeli far-right minister stepped up pressure on Netanyahu to end negotiations for a Gaza ceasefire altogether.</p>

<p>"A country whose six hostages are murdered in cold blood does not negotiate with the killers, but ends the talks, stops the transfer of fuel and electricity, and crushes them until they collapse," National Security Minister Itamar Ben Gvir wrote on the social media platform X.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/kf761ie8_israeli-pm-benjamin-netanyahu-afp_625x300_03_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Netanyahu, for his part, said he was "flexible when I can be" and "firm when I have to be".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-calls-georgia-school-shooter-sick-and-deranged-monster-6492697]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Calls Georgia School Shooter "Sick And Deranged Monster"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-calls-georgia-school-shooter-sick-and-deranged-monster-6492697]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Sep 2024 02:02:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Republican US presidential candidate Donald Trump said Wednesday the perpetrator of a high school shooting in Georgia that killed at least four people was a "sick and deranged monster."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Republican US presidential candidate Donald Trump said Wednesday the perpetrator of a high school shooting in Georgia that killed at least four people was a "sick and deranged monster."</p>

<p>"Our hearts are with the victims and loved ones of those affected by the tragic event in Winder, GA," the former president posted on his Truth Social platform. "These cherished children were taken from us far too soon by a sick and deranged monster."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-02/kr9u49fk_donald-trump-reuters_625x300_20_February_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/time-to-end-this-epidemic-of-us-gun-violence-says-kamala-harris-6492567]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Must End Gun Violence "Epidemic": Kamala Harris After Georgia Shooting]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/time-to-end-this-epidemic-of-us-gun-violence-says-kamala-harris-6492567]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Sep 2024 01:23:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Democratic presidential candidate Kamala Harris on Wednesday implored Americans to bring a halt to the "epidemic of gun violence" plaguing the United States, after a mass shooting at a Georgia high school left four people dead.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Democratic presidential candidate Kamala Harris on Wednesday implored Americans to bring a halt to the "epidemic of gun violence" plaguing the United States, after a mass shooting at a Georgia high school left four people dead.</p>

<p>The US vice president, speaking at a rally in New Hampshire, also reiterated her call for an assault-weapons ban -- a position widely opposed by Republicans -- and support for the further tightening of US gun safety laws.</p>

<p>"This is just a senseless tragedy, on top of so many senseless tragedies," Harris said of the shooting at Apalachee High School in Winder, Georgia, the latest spasm of gun violence to impact a country that has already seen hundreds of mass shootings this year.</p>

<p>"And it's just outrageous that every day in our country, in the United States of America, that parents send their children to school worried about whether or not their child will come home alive," she added.</p>

<p>"We have to end this epidemic of gun violence in our country once and for all. It doesn't have to be this way," Harris, locked in a tight race with Republican former president Donald Trump, told the crowd before she started laying out elements of her economic plan.</p>

<p>Trump, seen by his party as a champion for gun rights, posted on social media that "our hearts are with the victims," and said "these cherished children were taken from us far too soon by a sick and deranged monster."</p>

<p>Harris, a onetime prosecutor and attorney general of California and former US senator, called on Congress to "finally" pass an assault weapons ban, similar to the one current President Joe Biden helped write as a senator and get passed into law in 1994.</p>

<p>That ban expired in 2004, and Congress did not renew it.</p>

<p>Harris also called for adopting universal background checks and implementing so-called red flag laws -- state protective orders aimed at preventing certain individuals seen as a threat from purchasing or possessing firearms.</p>

<p>"It is a false choice to say you're either in favor of the Second Amendment or you want to take everyone's guns away," Harris said. "I'm in favor of the Second Amendment, and I know we need reasonable gun safety laws in our country."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/jv0fo328_kamala-harris_625x300_18_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["This is just a senseless tragedy", Kamala Harris said after Georgia school shooting.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/vladimir-putin-was-aware-of-russian-election-interference-white-house-6492388]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Putin Was Aware Of Russian Election Interference: White House]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/vladimir-putin-was-aware-of-russian-election-interference-white-house-6492388]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Sep 2024 00:30:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russian President Vladimir Putin was aware of actions by state-funded news outlet RT to influence the 2024 US presidential election, the White House said on Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russian President Vladimir Putin was aware of actions by state-funded news outlet RT to influence the 2024 US presidential election, the White House said on Wednesday.</p>

<p>"We believe Mr Putin was witting of these actions," National Security Council spokesman John Kirby said after Washington indicted two RT employees and imposed sanctions on its top editors.</p>

<p>"He was witting of RT's activities."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/etden2mo_vladimir-putin_625x300_13_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/priti-patel-eliminated-from-tory-leadership-race-in-1st-round-of-voting-6492189]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Priti Patel Eliminated From Tory Leadership Race In 1st Round Of Voting]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/priti-patel-eliminated-from-tory-leadership-race-in-1st-round-of-voting-6492189]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Sep 2024 23:47:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The UK's Conservative Party leadership candidate Priti Patel has been eliminated from the contest after the first round of voting.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The UK's Conservative Party leadership candidate Priti Patel has been eliminated from the contest after the first round of voting.</p>

<p>Ms Patel, who was the home secretary in former Prime Minister Boris Johnson's government, was running to succeed Rishi Sunak as the party's leader. Mr Sunak stepped down from the post after the Conservatives lost the general election in July.</p>

<p>Former immigration minister Robert Jenricks came out on top with 28 votes followed by Kemi Badenoch with 22 votes. James Cleverly was in the third position as he secured 21 votes and Tom Tugendhat won 17. Mel Stride was fifth with 16 and the last was Ms Patel with 14 votes.</p>

<p>The next vote will take place next Tuesday after which four candidates would remain before the party's annual conference at the end of September.</p>

<p>Multiple rounds of voting will take place after the conference from October 8. The voting will last three days until there are only two candidates left.</p>

<p>The MPs will then finally choose their leader, with the result announced on November 2.</p>

<p>During her term as home secretary, Ms Patel was known for her tough stance on immigration. She led the Conservative government's flagship scheme to send some asylum seekers to Rwanda.</p>

<p>In her Tory leadership campaign, she had promised to unite the party and get it ready for the next general election.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-11/ondrnt5_priti-patel-reuters_625x300_19_November_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Priti Patel was the home secretary in former Prime Minister Boris Johnson's government. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pure-rubbish-russian-lawmaker-on-us-election-meddling-claims-6492184]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Pure Rubbish": Russian Lawmaker On US Election Meddling Claims]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pure-rubbish-russian-lawmaker-on-us-election-meddling-claims-6492184]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Sep 2024 23:46:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russian lawmaker Maria Butina said on Wednesday that reported US claims that Russia was trying to influence the 2024 election were nonsense and that Moscow felt that the only winner of the election would be the US military-industrial complex.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russian lawmaker Maria Butina said on Wednesday that reported US claims that Russia was trying to influence the 2024 election were nonsense and that Moscow felt that the only winner of the election would be the US military-industrial complex.</p>

<p>Butina was responding after CNN reported that the United States plans to accuse Russia later on Wednesday of a campaign to influence the presidential election using online platforms to target American voters with disinformation.</p>

<p>"The US claims were and are pure rubbish and a witch hunt," Butina, who spent 15 months in US prison for acting as an unregistered Russian agent and is now a lawmaker for the ruling United Russia party, told Reuters when asked about the CNN report.</p>

<p>"Russia thinks it does not matter who wins the US elections - the only winner is the US private military-industrial complex. That is what matters - and nothing else," Butina said.</p>

<p>The Kremlin and the Russian Foreign Ministry have repeatedly said that Moscow has not meddled in the US election, but is watching it closely.</p>

<p>The Kremlin in June dismissed as absurd US intelligence assertions that Russia was seeking to meddle in the presidential election and has said that US spies were intent on casting Russia as an enemy.</p>

<p>President Vladimir Putin had suggested in the past that, for Russia, Joe Biden would have been preferable to Donald Trump, though he spoke with irony about Biden.</p>

<p>Kremlin spokesman Dmitry Peskov said in an interview published on Sunday that Russia saw US Democratic presidential candidate Kamala Harris as a more predictable opponent than Trump, but said there was no prospect of an improvement in relations with Washington anyway.</p>

<p>Previous US intelligence assessments have found that Moscow tried to meddle in the 2016 and 2020 elections. Russian officials have suggested that the United States has also meddled in its domestic affairs.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/ni6clac_maria-butina_625x300_04_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Russia thinks the only winner is the US private military-industrial complex, said Butina (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/justin-trudeau-weakened-after-key-sikh-ally-withdraws-support-6492183]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Justin Trudeau Weakened After Key Sikh Ally Withdraws Support]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/justin-trudeau-weakened-after-key-sikh-ally-withdraws-support-6492183]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Sep 2024 23:46:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau suffered an unexpected blow on Wednesday when the small political party helping keep his minority Liberal government in power withdrew its support.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau suffered an unexpected blow on Wednesday when the small political party helping keep his minority Liberal government in power withdrew its support.</p>

<p>The announcement by Jagmeet Singh, leader of the left-leaning New Democratic Party (NDP), does not mean Trudeau is in immediate danger of having to step down and call new elections.</p>

<p>However, he will have to find support from other opposition legislators in the House of Commons chamber if he is to pass budgets and survive confidence votes.</p>

<p>Jagmeet Singh said in a video that he was "ripping up" a deal the two men struck in 2022 and accused Justin Trudeau of not being able to take on the opposition Conservatives, who polls indicate are set to easily win an election that must be held by end-October 2025.</p>

<p>"The Liberals are too weak, too selfish and too devoted to corporate interests to fight for people. They cannot be the change - they cannot restore the hope," said Jagmeet Singh.</p>

<p>Under the 2022 deal, the NDP agreed to keep Justin Trudeau in power until mid-2025 in return for more social spending. Justin Trudeau first took office in November 2015 and polls suggest he is suffering from voter fatigue.</p>

<p>The same tiredness appears to have spread to the New Democratic Party, which despite successfully pushing the Liberals to introduce measures such as a national dental program are languishing in third place in polls.</p>

<p>A Justin Trudeau aide, speaking before the NDP announcement, said it "would be a shame if their own weakness and desperation causes them to walk away from a progressive agreement that is delivering for Canadians".</p>

<p>Jagmeet Singh is not due to speak to media until Thursday.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/tr908qo8_justin-trudeau-jagmeet-singh_625x300_04_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Jagmeet Singh said in a video that he was "ripping up" a deal the two men struck in 2022 (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gaza-musician-sings-for-children-enduring-daily-horrors-of-war-6492130]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Gaza Musician Sings For Children Enduring Daily Horrors Of War]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gaza-musician-sings-for-children-enduring-daily-horrors-of-war-6492130]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Sep 2024 23:38:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Braving the constant threat of airstrikes and bombings, 15-year-old Youssef Saad, a Gazan oud player, rides his bicycle through the war-ravaged streets of northern Gaza's Jabalia refugee camp, his instrument strapped to his back.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Braving the constant threat of airstrikes and bombings, 15-year-old Youssef Saad, a Gazan oud player, rides his bicycle through the war-ravaged streets of northern Gaza's Jabalia refugee camp, his instrument strapped to his back.</p>

<p>Saad sings for children who have endured daily horrors in 11 months of conflict, trying to offer them a little joy or distraction.</p>

<p>"The homes in my city were once full of dreams," Saad said, gazing at the rubble of the decades-old urban refugee camp, which before the war was built-up and heavily populated.</p>

<p>"Now, they're gone," he says.</p>

<p>Saad was studying at the Edward Said National Conservatory of Music in nearby Gaza City before it was reduced to ruins in the war that has devastated much of the enclave.</p>

<p>Now, living with relatives after his own home was destroyed, he is one of five siblings whose futures have been upended.</p>

<p>His father, a government employee with the Palestinian Authority, always supported Saad's dream of becoming a musician.</p>

<p>But now, Saad's focus has shifted. He spends his days at a Jabalia day centre, playing his oud and singing for children traumatized by war.</p>

<p>The latest bloodshed in the decades-old Israeli-Palestinian conflict was triggered on October 7 when Palestinian Islamist group Hamas attacked Israel, killing 1,200 and taking about 250 hostages, according to Israeli tallies.</p>

<p>Israel's subsequent assault on Hamas-governed Gaza has since killed more than 40,800 Palestinians, according to the Hamas-run health ministry, displaced almost the entire population and laid the besieged enclave to waste.</p>

<p>"Every house holds a tragedy," Saad said. "Some have lost their mother, others their father, their neighbour, or their friend."</p>

<p>Despite the danger, Saad is determined to continue his mission.</p>

<p>"We try to help improve their mental health, even if it means putting myself at risk," he said. "This is my duty to the children."</p>

<p>And he refuses to give up on his dreams for the future: "We, the children of Palestine, strive to stay resilient, even in the face of genocide."</p>

<p>Saad says he lives by a saying that carries him through the darkest days: "If you live, live free, or die standing like trees."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/7c1db79o_gaza-singer-reuters_625x300_04_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Despite the danger, Saad is determined to continue his mission]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/romes-ancient-arch-of-constantine-damaged-by-lightning-6492024]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Rome's Ancient Arch Of Constantine Damaged By Lightning]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/romes-ancient-arch-of-constantine-damaged-by-lightning-6492024]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Sep 2024 23:16:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Rome's ancient Arch of Constantine was hit by lightning during a heavy storm, causing some fragments to fall off, an official said Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Rome's ancient Arch of Constantine was hit by lightning during a heavy storm, causing some fragments to fall off, an official said Wednesday.</p>

<p>"All the fragments were recovered and made safe" following the strike on Tuesday afternoon, a spokeswoman for the Colosseum archaeological park told AFP.</p>

<p>"Damage assessments have already begun and analyses are continuing this morning with a works site already operational," she added.</p>

<p>The arch, built in 315 to celebrate the victory of Emperor Constantine in the battle of Ponte Milvio, was already undergoing maintenance work, which had begun on Monday.</p>

<p>Standing about 25 metres high, it is the largest of the three triumphal arches still preserved in Rome. It is located along the route followed by triumphal processions, near the Colosseum.</p>

<p>After a hot, dry summer, the centre of Rome was hit on Tuesday afternoon by a sudden storm, bringing heavy rain, high winds, thunder and lightning.</p>

<p>More than 80 millimetres (3.1 inches) of rain per square metre fell on the historic centre -- about the same amount that falls on average in a month in autumn, the municipality said.</p>

<p>The "downburst" caused floods and winds of up to 90 kilometres per hour (56mph) that brought down trees, it said.</p>

<p>Experts say climate change is shifting weather patterns and increasing the number of extreme weather events.</p>

<p>"It is increasingly evident that the issue of climate change and its impact on our lives is now unavoidable for everyone," said Rome mayor Roberto Gualtieri.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/f364nk18_arch-of-constantine_625x300_04_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The arch was built in 315 to celebrate the victory of Emperor Constantine in the battle of Ponte Milvio]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/meta-clears-use-of-palestinian-slogan-from-the-river-to-the-sea-6492009]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Meta Clears Use Of Palestinian Slogan "From The River To The Sea"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/meta-clears-use-of-palestinian-slogan-from-the-river-to-the-sea-6492009]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Sep 2024 23:11:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Meta's Oversight Board ruled on Wednesday that the standalone use of the phrase "From the River to the Sea," a slogan oft-used by pro-Palestinian users, does not violate the company's content policies.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Meta's Oversight Board ruled on Wednesday that the standalone use of the phrase "From the River to the Sea," a slogan oft-used by pro-Palestinian users, does not violate the company's content policies.</p>

<p>The phrase "From the river to the sea, Palestine will be free," has been used as a rallying cry for many since the outbreak of the war in Gaza, with Israel accusing those who use it of "anti-Semitism."</p>

<p>The independent Meta board is the top authority in Meta's content moderation decisions. It reviewed three cases involving Facebook posts containing the controversial phrase, which has gained prominence due to the conflict and the worldwide protests against it.</p>

<p>The board found that the content did not break Meta's rules on hate speech, violence and incitement, or dangerous organizations and individuals, and should not lead to post removal on its platforms.</p>

<p>"In upholding Meta's decisions to keep up the content, the majority of the Board notes the phrase has multiple meanings and is used by people in various ways and with different intentions," it said.</p>

<p>"Specifically, the three pieces of content contain contextual signs of solidarity with Palestinians -- but no language calling for violence or exclusion," it added.</p>

<p>The phrase "From the River to the Sea" refers to the geographical area between the Jordan River and the Mediterranean Sea, which encompasses Israel, the West Bank, and Gaza.</p>

<p>It is often used in support of Palestinians as a call for self-determination and equal rights, or to advocate for a one-state solution to the conflict with Jews and Palestinians as citizens of the same nation.</p>

<p>Many Israelis and Jews, however, interpret the phrase as a call for the violent elimination of Israel as a Jewish state.</p>

<p>The board said that a minority of board members felt that given armed group Hamas's October 7 attacks that sparked the war, the phrase's use in a post should be presumed to constitute glorification of the group and violence "unless there are clear signals to the contrary."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/o6cm085g_meta-generic-_625x300_30_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Meta's Oversight Board found that the content did not break company's rules (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/digital-pause-france-pilots-mobile-phone-ban-in-schools-6491975]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA['Digital Pause': France Pilots Mobile Phone Ban In Schools]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/digital-pause-france-pilots-mobile-phone-ban-in-schools-6491975]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Sep 2024 23:07:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Tens of thousands of pupils in France are going through a slightly different return to school this autumn, deprived of their mobile phones.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Tens of thousands of pupils in France are going through a slightly different return to school this autumn, deprived of their mobile phones.</p>

<p>At 180 "colleges", the middle schools French children attend between the ages of 11 and 15, a scheme is being trialled to ban the use of mobile phones during the entire school day.</p>

<p>The trial of the "pause numerique" ("digital pause"), which encompasses more than 50,000 pupils, is being implemented ahead of a possible plan to enforce it nationwide from 2025.</p>

<p>Right now, pupils in French middle schools must turn off their phones. The experiment takes things further, requiring children to hand in their phones on arrival.</p>

<p>It is part of a move by President Emmanuel Macron for children to spend less time in front of screens, which the government fears is arresting their development.</p>

<p>The use of "a mobile phone or any other electronic communications terminal equipment" has been banned in nurseries, elementary schools and middle schools in France since 2018.</p>

<p>In high schools, which French children attend between the ages of 15 and 18, internal regulations may prohibit the use of a cell phone by pupils in "all or part of the premises."</p>

<p>Bruno Bobkiewicz, general secretary of SNPDEN-Unsa, France's top union of school principals, said the 2018 law had been enforced "pretty well overall".&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The use of mobile phones in middle schools is very low today", he said, adding that in case of a problem "we have the means to act".&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>- Improving 'school climate' -&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p>The experiment comes after Macron said in January he wanted to "regulate the use of screens among young children."&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to a report submitted to Macron, children under 11 should not be allowed to use phones, while access to social networks should be limited for pupils under 15.</p>

<p>With an increasing amount of research showing the risks of excessive screen time for children, the concern has become a Europe-wide issue.</p>

<p>Sweden's Public Health Agency said this week children under the age of two should be kept away from digital media and television completely and it should be limited for more senior ages.</p>

<p>One of Britain's biggest mobile network operators, EE, has warned parents they should not give smartphones to children under the age of 11.</p>

<p>The French education ministry hopes that the cellphone-free environment would improve "school climate" and reduce instances of violence including online harassment and dissemination of violent images.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The ministry also wants to improve student performance because the use of telephones harms "the ability to concentrate" and "the acquisition of knowledge".&nbsp;</p>

<p>The experiment also aims to "raise pupils' awareness of the rational use of digital tools".&nbsp;</p>

<p>Jerome Fournier, national secretary of the SE-UNSA teachers' union, said the experiment will seek "to respond to the difficulties of schools for which the current rule is not sufficient", even if "in the vast majority of schools it works".</p>

<p><strong>- 'Complicated to implement' -&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p>According to the education ministry, "it is up to each establishment to determine practical arrangements", with the possibility of setting up a locker system.</p>

<p>Pupils will have to hand in their phones on arrival, putting them in boxes or lockers. They will collect them at the end of classes. The ban also extends to extracurricular activities and school trips.</p>

<p>But the enforcement of the measure across all schools in France from January 2025 could be expensive.</p>

<p>According to local authorities, the measure could cost "nearly 130 million euros" for the 6,980 middle schools in France.</p>

<p>If a phone goes missing from a locker, this would also cause an added financial problem.</p>

<p>Education Minister Nicole Belloubet said on Tuesday that the ban would be "put in place gradually".</p>

<p>"The financial costs seem quite modest to me", she added.</p>

<p>Many are sceptical.</p>

<p>For the leading middle and high school teachers' union Snes-FSU, the ban raises too many questions.</p>

<p>"How will things work on arrival?" wondered the head of the union, Sophie Venetitay. "How will things work during the day," she said, adding that some students have two mobile phones.</p>

<p>The SE-UNSA teachers' union also expressed reservations.</p>

<p>"We're going to need staff to manage arrivals, drops-off and departures, and the collection of mobile phones," said Fournier.</p>

<p>"Sometimes pupils just have time to put their things away when classes end, and run to the bus so as not to miss it", he added.</p>

<p>Bobkiewicz of SNPDEN-Unsa, France's top union of school principals, agreed.</p>

<p>He said he did not want to rummage through pupils' bags to look for their phones.</p>

<p>&nbsp;"It's going to be complicated to implement."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/3akrnrp_phone-generic_625x300_24_June_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Many are sceptical about the trial. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/i-am-evil-i-did-this-uks-baby-killer-lucy-letbys-confession-notes-were-written-as-part-of-therapy-6491673]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["I Am Evil": UK Baby Killer Lucy Letby's Confession Notes Were Part Of...]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/i-am-evil-i-did-this-uks-baby-killer-lucy-letbys-confession-notes-were-written-as-part-of-therapy-6491673]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Sep 2024 22:18:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Letby was convicted in 2023 for the murder of seven babies and the attempted murder of six others, including two attempts on one child.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Personal notes that played a key role in convicting child serial killer Lucy Letby were reportedly written under the guidance of counsellors to help the nurse manage severe stress. The handwritten notes, which included disturbing phrases such as "I am evil I did this" and "I killed them on purpose because I am not good enough to care for them," were used as evidence during Letby's trial.</p>

<p>Letby was convicted in 2023 for the murder of seven babies and the attempted murder of six others, including two attempts on one child. Earlier this year, she proclaimed her innocence while receiving an additional whole-life sentence for the attempted murder of another baby girl. She is currently serving 15 whole-life sentences for her crimes, committed at the Countess of Chester Hospital's neonatal unit between June 2015 and June 2016.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-08/7tmm299o_lucy-letby-note-i-am-evil_625x300_19_August_23.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Sources close to the case told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/article/2024/sep/03/i-am-evil-i-did-this-lucy-letbys-so-called-confessions-were-written-on-advice-of-counsellors" rel="nofollow, noindex"><em>The Guardian </em></a>that the notes, labelled as confessions, were produced as part of a therapeutic process during counselling sessions. Letby was reportedly advised to document her troubling thoughts and feelings to cope with intense stress. The notes, written after some of her colleagues began suspecting her of murder, included references to her family, pets, and coworkers, and described recurring suicidal thoughts.</p>

<p>The prosecution built its case against Letby by highlighting incriminating phrases like "I am evil I did this," which were repeatedly brought to the jury's attention. However, other phrases in the notes, which were also considered confessions, included statements like "Why me?", "I haven't done anything wrong," and "Police investigation slander discrimination victimisation."</p>

<p>Some experts have dismissed Letby's notes as "meaningless" and argued they held no value as evidence, especially if written as part of therapy. David Wilson, a professor of criminology at Birmingham City University, commented, "Many people say things under stress that may imply one thing but mean nothing, other than reflecting their underlying stress." He added that if the notes were part of therapy, they should not be considered confessions.</p>

<p>Richard Curen, chair of the Forensic Psychotherapy Society, echoed this sentiment, stating that "doodling and journaling are ways to take control of one's thoughts," and do not indicate a confession. He noted that Letby's response about the notes in court was "robust" and aligned with her explanation that she was expressing how she felt she was being perceived.</p>

<p>A public inquiry into Letby's case is set to begin next week amid growing questions about the safety of her conviction. Sources revealed that Kathryn de Beger, the head of occupational health and wellbeing at the hospital where Letby worked, had encouraged her to write down her feelings to cope with extreme stress. Letby's Chester GP also advised her to write down thoughts she found difficult to process.</p>

<p>Letby had received several counselling sessions from Ms. de Beger, and her notes frequently referenced her. During her trial, Letby explained that she had always written things down to help understand her feelings, describing the notes as random thoughts. She questioned herself, wondering if she had unintentionally caused harm by not being knowledgeable enough or by not being a good enough nurse.</p>

<p>In her defence, it was argued that the notes reflected her distressed state of mind after being accused of killing babies, rather than an admission of guilt. Her defence barrister, Ben Myers KC, previously argued that the prosecution's case was "riddled with guilt" and that everything Letby said or did was interpreted as evidence of her guilt.</p>

<p>Despite this, no expert forensic psychologists were called to testify on how the notes should be interpreted. The Countess of Chester Hospital declined to comment on the case while the inquiry and further investigations are ongoing.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-08/br77oh3s_lucy-letby-afp_625x300_19_August_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Some experts have dismissed Letby's notes as "meaningless"]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gunfire-reported-at-high-school-in-us-georgia-currently-under-hard-lockdown-news-agency-afp-6491595]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[At Least 4 Dead In School Shooting In US's Georgia, Suspect, 14, Arrested]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gunfire-reported-at-high-school-in-us-georgia-currently-under-hard-lockdown-news-agency-afp-6491595]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Sep 2024 22:01:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[At least four people have died after a gunman opened fire at a high school in US's Georgia. Police and medics rushed to the school and the neighbourhood was put under "a hard lockdown". The suspect is now arrested.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At least four people have died after a gunman opened fire at a high school in US's Georgia. Police and medics rushed to the school and the neighbourhood was put under "a hard lockdown". The suspect is now arrested.</p>

<p>Local news reports suggest that there are some who have been injured and at least one person has been evacuated in an air ambulance.</p>

<p>The Georgia Bureau of Investigation or GBI said it responded to the "shooting" at the high school.</p>

<p>"At approximately 10:23 a.m., officers from multiple law enforcement agencies and Fire/EMS personnel were dispatched to the high school in reference to a reported active shooting," the Barrow County Sheriff's office said in a statement.</p>

<p>Students were evacuated from the scene of the shooting and several were seen huddled at a field near the school. The Barrow County Sheriff's Office said in a statement that the suspect has been taken into custody.</p>

<p>The shooter who opened fire inside Apalachee High school is believed to be a 14-year-old boy, a law enforcement source told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://edition.cnn.com/us/live-news/apalachee-high-school-shooting-georgia-09-04-24/index.html" rel="No follow, no index" target="_top">CNN</a>, adding that it is not yet known whether the teen attended that school.</p>

<p>CNN also confirmed that at least four people have died in today's shooting incident. In addition to the four killed, over a dozen people are injured, it reported. It further said that not all injuries were gunshot wounds. Several were injuried while trying to take cover or flee the scene.</p>

<p>The Apalachee High School in Barrow County, Georgia, sent out a message to parents saying it was "currently in a hard lockdown after reports of gunfire."</p>

<p>The school is located in the town of Winder, about 45 miles (70 kilometers) northeast of Atlanta, the state capital.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en"><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/HappeningNow?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#HappeningNow</a> shooting at Apalachee High School in Barrow Co. GA. Hearing reports of injuries. <a href="https://t.co/t4xgv8Ibaq">pic.twitter.com/t4xgv8Ibaq</a></p>
— DAP (insert blue check here) (@Deetroit_Dave) <a href="https://twitter.com/Deetroit_Dave/status/1831351931933212900?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 4, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>"We have agents on site assisting local, state, and federal law enforcement w/ the investigation. One suspect in custody," the GBI said in a post on social media.</p>

<p>"Law enforcement has arrived. Please do not attempt to come to the school at this time while officers work to secure the area," it added.</p>

<p>ABC News quoted a witness, student Sergio Caldera, as saying he was in chemistry class when he heard gunshots. Caldera, 17, told ABC his teacher opened the door and another teacher ran in to tell her to shut the door "because there's an active shooter."</p>

<p>As students and teachers huddled in the room, someone pounded on his classroom door and shouted several times for it to be opened. When the knocking stopped, Caldera heard more gunshots and screams. He said his class later evacuated to the school's football field, reported Reuters.</p>

<p>"What we see behind us is an evil thing today," Sheriff Jud Smith said during a brief news conference on school grounds.</p>

<p>Georgia Governor Brian Kemp said on social media website X that state agencies were responding to the incident.</p>

<p>The White House said in a statement that President Joe Biden had been briefed on the shooting "and his administration will continue coordinating with federal, state, and local officials as we receive more information."</p>

<p>The U.S. has seen hundreds of shootings inside of schools and colleges in the past two decades, with the deadliest resulting in over 30 deaths at Virginia Tech in 2007. The carnage has sparked pitched debate over the U.S. gun laws and the U.S. Constitution's Second Amendment, which enshrines the right "to keep and bear arms."</p>

<p><em><strong>(Inputs from AFP and Reuters)</strong></em><br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/1qr42hno_school-shooting_625x300_04_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[4 people have died in a shooting incident at the Apalachee High School in Barrow County, Georgia]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>