<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Sep 2024 22:48:50 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/truly-sorry-french-mayor-for-no-one-died-remark-on-mass-rape-case-6611968]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Truly Sorry": French Mayor For "No One Died" Remark On Mass Rape Case]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/truly-sorry-french-mayor-for-no-one-died-remark-on-mass-rape-case-6611968]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Sep 2024 21:19:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The mayor of the French town where a man for over a decade brought strangers to rape his wife apologised on Friday for remarks that were criticised for playing down the ordeal of the victim.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The mayor of the French town where a man for over a decade brought strangers to rape his wife apologised on Friday for remarks that were criticised for playing down the ordeal of the victim.</p>

<p>Louis Bonnet, 74, mayor of Mazan in southern France, told broadcaster BBC in an interview that "after all, no one died" about the mass rape for which dozens of men are on trial.</p>

<p>They are accused of raping Gisele Pelicot at the invitation of her then-husband Dominique Pelicot who drugged her first.</p>

<p>"It could have been far more serious," Bonnet told the BBC. "There were no kids involved. No women were killed."</p>

<p>Bonnet's remark caused a storm of indignation on social media in France and beyond.</p>

<p>"People say I minimised the serious nature of the abject crimes of which the defendants are accused," Bonnet said in a statement posted on Facebook.</p>

<p>"I understand that people are shocked by these remarks and I am truly sorry."</p>

<p>The mayor said his apologies were addressed "notably to women who were hurt by the clumsy words that were pronounced under the pressure felt in front of the microphone of a foreign media".</p>

<p>Mazan and its 6,000 residents had been under "constant media pressure" since the start of the mass rape trial this month, he said.</p>

<p>Dominique Pelicot has admitted to drugging Gisele Pelicot into unconsciousness and inviting strangers to rape her.</p>

<p>She has become a feminist icon since demanding a public trial.</p>

<p>The trial has horrified France, partly because 71-year-old Dominique Pelicot's co-defendants include apparently ordinary men such as a fireman, a nurse and a journalist, many of them with families.</p>

<p>Forty-nine co-defendants are accused of raping or attempting to rape Gisele Pelicot, and one is accused of imitating Dominique Pelicot to sexually assault his own wife.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/5m5tlorg_gisele-pelicot-french-mass-rape-survivor-afp_625x300_14_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Forty-nine co-defendants are accused of raping or attempting to rape Gisele Pelicot (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/lebanon-pager-blasts-walkie-talkie-blasts-a-modern-trojan-horse-how-hezbollah-faced-2-days-of-mayhem-in-lebanon-6611177]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[A Modern 'Trojan Horse': How Hezbollah Faced 2 Days Of Mayhem In Lebanon]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/lebanon-pager-blasts-walkie-talkie-blasts-a-modern-trojan-horse-how-hezbollah-faced-2-days-of-mayhem-in-lebanon-6611177]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Sep 2024 19:26:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[It's around 3:30 in the afternoon on September 17. People in Lebanon are going about their daily business, doing the shopping, having a haircut, conducting meetings.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It's around 3:30 in the afternoon on September 17. People in Lebanon are going about their daily business, doing the shopping, having a haircut, conducting meetings.</p>

<p>Hundreds of pagers across the country, and even outside its borders, then simultaneously bleep with a message and explode, wounding and killing their owners and also bystanders.</p>

<p>The communications devices were used by members of the Iran-backed Lebanese Shiite group Hezbollah, which swiftly blamed Israel for the operation, as did several international media organisations.</p>

<p>Israel, according to its convention for operations outside its borders, neither confirmed nor denied the charge.</p>

<p>But observers say that the simultaneous explosions bear all the hallmarks of an operation by Israel, which appears to have infiltrated the supply chain of the pager production and inserted tiny but potent explosives inside.</p>

<p>Israel may have even set up a shell company to supply the devices to Hezbollah in a years-long project that would seem fantastical even in an espionage thriller, according to analysts.</p>

<p>But that was not the end. A day later, on September 18, around the same time in the afternoon, another low-fi gadget, the walkie-talkies used by Hezbollah cadres, exploded, even amid the funerals for those killed in the pager attacks.</p>

<p>The subsequent day, Hezbollah chief Hassan Nasrallah, who himself had told group members to use low-fi devices so as not to be targeted by Israel through the positioning of their smartphones, made his first public comments, admitting an "unprecedented blow" but also vowing "tough retribution and just punishment" for Israel.</p>

<p>Even though there is next to no doubt Israel was behind the operation, questions abounded. Why now? Is this the start of the widely-feared Israeli offensive into southern Lebanon? Or has Israel simply activated the explosives now simply because it feared the whole operation risked being compromised?</p>

<h2><strong>'IN THE MIDST OF THEIR ORDINARY LIVES'</strong></h2>

<p>The explosions were felt Hezbollah's strongholds throughout Lebanon: the southern Beirut suburbs, the south of the country and the Bekaa Valley in the east, as well as in Syria.</p>

<p>At least 37 people were killed in the two attacks and thousands injured.</p>

<p>The wounded included Iran's ambassador to Lebanon. But those killed also included a 10-year-old girl and another child. As the hospitals filled up the most common wounds were mutilated hands and eyes.</p>

<p>"Hezbollah suffered a very serious blow on a tactical level, a very impressive and comprehensive one that affects the operational side, the cognitive side," said Yoram Schweitzer, a former intelligence officer now at the The Institute for National Security Studies at Tel Aviv University.</p>

<p>Peter Harling, founder of the Synaps Lab think tank added: "The targets may have been Hezbollah members, but many were caught in the midst of their ordinary lives, and in the heart of their communities."</p>

<p>"This is also a breach that is extraordinarily hard to explain."</p>

<p>UN rights chief Volker Turk warned that the simultaneous targeting of thousands of individuals "whether civilians or members of armed groups" without knowledge as to who was around them at the time "violates international human rights law".</p>

<p>International humanitarian law prohibits the use of "booby traps" precisely to avoid putting civilians at grave risk and "produce the devastating scenes that continue to unfold across Lebanon", said Lama Fakih, Middle East and North Africa Director at Human Rights Watch.</p>

<h3><strong>'ISRAELI FRONT'</strong></h3>

<p>Espionage professionals have meanwhile expressed their admiration for how the operation was put together.</p>

<p>"It's not a technological feat," said a person working for a European intelligence service, asking not to be named. But "it's the result of human intelligence and heavy logistics."</p>

<p>The small devices, bearing the name of the firm Gold Apollo in Taiwan, were intercepted by Israeli services before their arrival in Lebanon, according to multiple security sources who spoke to AFP, asking not to be named.</p>

<p>But the Taiwanese company denied having manufactured them and pointed to its Hungarian partner BAC.</p>

<p>Founded in 2022, the company is registered in Budapest. Its CEO, Cristiana Barsony-Arcidiacono, appears there as the only employee.</p>

<p>The devices in question have never been on Hungarian soil, according to the Hungarian authorities.</p>

<p>The New York Times, citing three intelligence sources, said BAC was "part of an Israeli front" with at least two other shell companies were created as well to mask the real identities of the people creating the pagers who were Israeli intelligence officers.</p>

<p>It described the pagers as a "modern day Trojan Horse" after the wooden horse said to have been used by the Greeks to enter the city of Troy in the Trojan War.</p>

<h3><strong>'IMPRESSIVE OPERATION'</strong></h3>

<p>The attack comes nearly a year after Hezbollah ally Hamas carried out its October 7 attack on Israel, sparking the war in Gaza.</p>

<p>The focus of Israel's firepower has since been on the Palestinian territory, but Hezbollah fighters and Israeli troops have exchanged fire almost daily across the border region since October, forcing thousands on both sides to flee their homes.</p>

<p>Israel's Defence Minister Yoav Gallant said the focus of the war was shifting towards Lebanon, while the government said securing the northern front was a key objective, in order to allow Israelis evacuated from the area to return home.</p>

<p>Schweitzer said that despite the spectacular nature of the device operation it did not represent the end of Israel's work to degrade Hezbollah.</p>

<p>"I don't think this impressive operation that has its tactical gains... is getting into the strategic layers yet.</p>

<p>"It does not change the equation, it is not a decisive victory. But it sends another signal to Hezbollah, Iran and others," he said.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/5g8d25mc_lebanon-pager-blasts-reuters_625x300_20_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Pager and walkie-talkie blasts targetting Hezbollah militants caused mayhem across Lebanon.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/sunita-williams-celebrates-59th-birthday-her-second-in-space-6611006]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Sunita Williams Celebrates Birthday In Space. Not Her 1st Time]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/sunita-williams-celebrates-59th-birthday-her-second-in-space-6611006]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Sep 2024 19:03:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Indian-Origin astronaut Sunita Williams has celebrated her 59th birthday -- the second in space.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p>

<p>Indian-Origin astronaut Sunita Williams has celebrated her 59th birthday -- the second in space.</p>

<p>SunitaWilliams is currently stranded at the International Space Station (ISS) after Boeing's faulty Starliner spacecraft was declared unfit for human travel by NASA. While Starliner is back on Earth unharmed, SunitaWilliams is expected to return on SpaceX's capsule in February next year.</p>

<p>SunitaWilliams marked her 59th birthday aboard the ISS on September 19. She dedicated her day to vital maintenance tasks and scientific research on the orbiting lab.</p>

<p>Along with fellow astronaut Don Pettit, she worked on maintaining life support systems on the ISS.</p>

<p>The astronaut duo then replaced filters in the station's waste and hygiene compartment -- called the space bathroom.</p>

<p>The 59-year-old created history by becoming the first woman to fly on the maiden mission of the Starliner. The Starliner flight is SunitaWilliams's third to space -- the first being in 2006 and the second in 2012.</p>

<p>According to NASA, "Sunita has spent a cumulative total of 322 days in space", and she is the second woman astronaut with the highest number of spacewalks.</p>

<p>On her birthday, Sunita Williams received a rendition of legendary singer Mohd Rafi's birthday song 'Bar bar din ye aaye' from Indian music company Saregama.</p>

<p>In a post on Instagram, Saregama shared: "Come on India let's sing #HappyBirthdaySunita along with India's biggest icons and send our collective wishes to Astronaut Sunita Williams up in space. Use #HappyBirthdaySunita to post your videos and Tag @saregama_official".</p>

<p>In the video shared along with the post, film director Karan Johar, and iconic singers Sonu Nigam, Shaan, Hariharan, and Neeti Mohan sang the song to wish her birthday.</p>

<p>The post also called for people to make videos wishing Sunita Williams and share them with #HappyBirthdaySunita.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Sunita Williams is expected to cast her votes in the 2024 US presidential elections, scheduled for November 5, from space.</p>

<p>Originally slated for an eight-day mission, Sunita William's stay in space has now stretched to eight months.</p>

<p>Commenting on being stuck in space, the Indian-origin astronaut in a recent video press conference said, "That's how things go in this business."</p>

<p>She added that the transition to station life was "not that hard" since both astronauts had prior experience on the ISS.</p>

<p>Reflecting on her extended mission, Sunita Williams shared, "This is my happy place. I love being up here in space."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/00gim5tg_sunita-williams-butch-wilmore_625x300_14_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sunita William's stay in space has now stretched to eight months. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-army-says-conducted-targeted-strike-in-beirut-6610855]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Top Hezbollah Commander Killed As Israeli Strike Rattles Beirut]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-army-says-conducted-targeted-strike-in-beirut-6610855]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Sep 2024 18:42:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A strike on Hezbollah's stronghold in Lebanon's capital Beirut on Friday killed eight people and wounded dozens of others, with a source close to the movement saying a top military leader was dead.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A strike on Hezbollah's stronghold in Lebanon's capital Beirut on Friday killed eight people and wounded dozens of others, with a source close to the movement saying a top military leader was dead.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said it had conducted a "targeted strike", while the Lebanese health ministry said the attack had killed eight people and wounded 59 more.</p>

<p>Requesting anonymity to discuss sensitive matters, the source close to Hezbollah said the strike on the militant group's stronghold in south Beirut had killed the head of its elite Radwan unit, Ibrahim Aqil.</p>

<p>The air strike is the third to hit the southern suburbs of Beirut since the start of the Israel-Hamas war on October 7, with the focus of the violence shifting dramatically this week from Gaza to Lebanon.</p>

<p>Earlier this year, strikes blamed on Israel killed a top commander of Hezbollah, Fuad Shukr, and a leader of its allied Palestinian militant group Hamas, Saleh al-Aruri.</p>

<p>"The Israeli air strike killed Radwan Force commander Ibrahim Aqil, its armed force's second-in-command after Fuad Shukr," the source close to Hezbollah said.</p>

<p>Hezbollah has not officially confirmed his death, but it said after the strike that it had hit an Israeli intelligence base it claimed was responsible for unspecified "assassinations".</p>

<p>The United States had offered a $7 million reward for information on Aqil, describing him as a "principal member" of the organisation that claimed the bombing of the US embassy in Beirut in 1983 that killed 63 people.</p>

<p>Footage posted on social media and verified by AFP showed smoke rising over southern Beirut on Friday.</p>

<p><strong>Communication device explosions</strong></p>

<p>Israeli troops and Hezbollah fighters have battled each other along the Israel-Lebanon border since Hamas sparked the war in Gaza with its October 7 attack.</p>

<p>The focus of Israel's firepower for nearly a year has been on Gaza, but with Hamas much weakened, the focus of the war has shifted dramatically to Israel's northern border.</p>

<p>Months of near-daily border clashes have killed hundreds in Lebanon, most of them fighters, and dozens in Israel, and forced thousands on both sides to flee their homes.</p>

<p>On Tuesday and Wednesday, Hezbollah was hit by an unprecedented attack that it has blamed on Israel, though Israel has yet to comment.</p>

<p>The attack saw thousands of Hezbollah operatives' communication devices explode across two days, killing 37 people and wounding thousands more.</p>

<p>Hezbollah chief Hassan Nasrallah vowed on Thursday that Israel would face retribution for the blasts.</p>

<p>Earlier Friday, Israel said Hezbollah had fired dozens of rockets from Lebanon following air strikes which destroyed dozens of the militant group's launchers.</p>

<p>Israel announced this week it was shifting its war objectives to its northern border with Lebanon.</p>

<p>Speaking to troops on Wednesday, Israeli Defence Minister Yoav Gallant said: "Hezbollah will pay an increasing price" as Israel tries to "ensure the safe return" of its citizens to border areas.</p>

<p>"We are at the start of a new phase in the war," he said.</p>

<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu meanwhile delayed his scheduled departure to the United States, where he is due to address the UN General Assembly, by a day, with an official citing the situation on the northern front.</p>

<p>Earlier Friday, Hezbollah said it targeted at least six Israeli military bases with salvos of rockets after overnight bombardment that people in south Lebanon described as among the fiercest so far.</p>

<p><strong>'Fear of wider war'</strong></p>

<p>Residents of Marjayoun, a Lebanese town close to the border, said the overnight bombardment was among the heaviest since the border clashes began last October.</p>

<p>"We were very scared, especially for my grandchildren," said Nuha Abdo, 62. "We were moving them from one room to another."</p>

<p>Clothing store owner Elie Rmeih, 45, counted more than 50 strikes.</p>

<p>"It was a terrifying scene and unlike anything we have experienced since the escalation began.</p>

<p>"We live in fear of a wider war, you don't know where to go."</p>

<p><strong>Calls for restraint</strong></p>

<p>International mediators have been scrambling to stop the Gaza war from turning into an all-out regional conflict.</p>

<p>US Secretary of State Antony Blinken, who has been scrambling to salvage efforts for a Gaza ceasefire and hostage release deal, called for restraint on all sides.</p>

<p>"We don't want to see any escalatory actions by any party" that would endanger the goal of a Gaza ceasefire, he said.</p>

<p>Hamas's October 7 attacks that sparked the Gaza war resulted in the deaths of 1,205 people, mostly civilians, on the Israeli side, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli official figures that include hostages killed in captivity.</p>

<p>Out of 251 hostages seized by militants, 97 are still held in Gaza, including 33 the Israeli military says are dead.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory military offensive has killed at least 41,272 people in Gaza, most of them civilians, according to figures provided by the Hamas-run territory's health ministry. The United Nations has acknowledged the figures as reliable.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/46stftj_israel-strikes-beirut_625x300_20_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hezbollah has not officially confirmed Ibrahim Aqil's death]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uns-summit-of-the-future-has-arrived-heres-all-you-need-to-know-6610401]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UN's Summit Of The Future Has Arrived. Here's All You Need To Know]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uns-summit-of-the-future-has-arrived-heres-all-you-need-to-know-6610401]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Sep 2024 17:48:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[With just six years left to meet the deadline for the United Nations' Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs), the world is not on track to meet those targets.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With just six years left to meet the deadline for the United Nations' Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs), the world is not on track to meet those targets.</p>

<p>The COVID-19 pandemic, escalating conflicts and growing climate chaos have severely hindered progress.</p>

<p>To get back on track, the world needs massive investment in sustainable development, as well as accelerated action in several critical areas, including climate change, peace and security, and inequalities among and between countries, as the recent <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://dashboards.sdgindex.org/" rel="No follow, no index" target="_blank">Sustainable Development Report 2024</a> found.</p>

<p>To address these acute challenges, UN Secretary-General Antonio Guterres has called for a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.un.org/en/summit-of-the-future" rel="No follow, no index" target="_blank">Summit of the Future</a> at the United Nations in New York on September 22-23.</p>

<p>With the theme "Multilateral solutions for a better tomorrow", the summit will bring together UN member states and agencies, academic institutions, non-governmental organisations, civil society organisations, the private sector and young people.</p>

<p>Humanity is facing a set of unprecedented challenges that can only be solved through global cooperation, also known as multilateralism. During the summit, attendees will collectively forge a new global consensus on what our future should look like - and what we can do today to secure it.</p>

<p>The summit will focus on five core areas: sustainable development and financing; international peace and security; fostering digital cooperation and the control of new technologies, such as artificial intelligence; the empowerment of young people and future generations; and reform of the UN architecture.</p>

<p>Within sustainable development, the core challenge is securing global financing. After all, achieving the Sustainable Development Goals will require sizeable public investment.</p>

<p>With low-income and lower-middle-income countries, in particular, lacking the access to financing they need to achieve those goals, the global system will need to work out a way to provide access to long-term, low-cost financing to these countries.</p>

<p>To achieve global peace, one of the core challenges today is great-power competition, including between the US, Russia and China. The world will need to move toward a UN-led system in which this great-power competition is governed and restrained by the UN Charter rather than by militarism and power politics.</p>

<p>To support this goal, countries must be truly committed to global cooperation - and a new index on UN-based multilateralism could play a part in monitoring just how committed to that goal UN member states are.</p>

<p>For digital cooperation and new technologies, the main challenge is to ensure that they are transparently and responsibly governed.</p>

<p>For youth and future generations, high-quality education plays an essential role in their empowerment and progress. The world will need to work toward a new global financial arrangement to ensure that every child, even in the poorest countries, is given the opportunity for a decent education.</p>

<p>All of these objectives cannot be achieved without reform of the UN system, ensuring that more power is given to UN institutions and ensuring that they are more representative. To make the UN as representative as possible, boosting diverse representation, including women's representation, at leadership levels is essential.</p>

<p>Furthermore, approaching decarbonisation and other sustainability efforts with a gender lens and boosting women's representation in this area is critical for making progress on all of the above challenges.</p>

<p>Published to coincide with the UN's Summit of the Future, this special report, a collaboration between 360info and the UN Sustainable Development Solutions Network (SDSN), tables solutions to some of the world's most pressing issues.</p>

<p><em>(<strong>Authors:</strong> Alyson Marks, the UN Sustainable Development Solutions Network (SDSN), and 360info editorial team)</em></p>

<p><em><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> Originally published under <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/" rel="No follow, no index" target="_top">Creative Commons</a> by <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://360info.org/" rel="No follow, no index" target="_blank">360info</a></em><br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/grpvqmo_summit-of-the-future-illustration-image-360info_625x300_20_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Summit of the Future is being held in the United States next week. (Illustration Image)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-handed-out-pagers-hours-before-blasts-even-after-checks-6610247]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hezbollah Handed Out Pagers Hours Before Blasts - Even After Checks]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-handed-out-pagers-hours-before-blasts-even-after-checks-6610247]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Sep 2024 17:28:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hezbollah was handing its members new Gold Apollo branded pagers hours before thousands blew up this week, two security sources said, indicating they were confident the devices were safe despite an ongoing sweep of electronic kit to identify threats.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lebanon's Hezbollah was still handing its members new Gold Apollo branded pagers hours before thousands blew up this week, two security sources said, indicating the group was confident the devices were safe despite an ongoing sweep of electronic kit to identify threats.</p>

<p>One member of the Iranian-backed militia received a new pager on Monday that exploded the next day while it was still in its box, said one of the sources.</p>

<p>A pager given to a senior member just days earlier injured a subordinate when it detonated, the second source said.</p>

<p>In an apparently coordinated attack the Gold Apollo branded devices detonated on Tuesday across Hezbollah's strongholds of south Lebanon, Beirut's suburbs and the eastern Bekaa valley.</p>

<p>On Wednesday, hundreds of Hezbollah walkie-talkies exploded. The consecutive attacks killed 37 people, including at least two children, and injured more than 3,000 people.</p>

<p>The batteries of the walkie-talkies were laced with a highly explosive compound known as PETN, another Lebanese source familiar with the device's components told Reuters on Friday. Up to three grams of explosives hidden in the pagers had gone undetected for months by Hezbollah, Reuters reported earlier this week.</p>

<p>One of the security sources said it was very hard to detect the explosives "with any device or scanner." The source did not specify what type of scanners Hezbollah had run the pagers through.</p>

<p>Hezbollah examined the pagers after they were delivered to Lebanon, starting in 2022, including by travelling through airports with them to ensure they would not trigger alarms, two additional sources told Reuters. In total, Reuters spoke to six sources familiar with the details of the exploding devices for this story.</p>

<p>The sources did not specify the name of the airports where they conducted the tests.</p>

<p>Lebanon, Hezbollah and Western security sources say Israel was behind the attacks. Israel, which has since stepped up airstrikes on Lebanon, has neither denied or confirmed involvement.</p>

<p>Rather than a specific suspicion of the pagers, the checks had been part of a routine "sweep" of its equipment, including communications devices, to find any indications that they were laced with explosives or surveillance mechanisms, one of the security sources said.</p>

<p>The attacks, and the distribution of the devices despite the routine sweep and checks for breaches, have struck at Hezbollah's reputation as the most formidable of Iran's allied 'Axis of Resistance' umbrella of anti-Israel irregular forces across the Middle East.</p>

<p>In a televised speech on Thursday, Hezbollah Secretary-General Hassan Nasrallah said the attacks were "unprecedented in the history" of the group.</p>

<p>Hezbollah's media office and Israel's armed forces did not immediately respond to requests for comment for this story.</p>

<p>Taiwan-based Gold Apollo has said it did not manufacture the devices used in the attack, saying they were made by a company in Europe licensed to use the firm's brand. Reuters has not been able to establish where they were made or at what point they were tampered with.&nbsp;</p>

<p>A batch of 5,000 of the pagers were brought into Lebanon earlier this year. Reuters previously reported that Hezbollah turned to pagers in an attempt to evade Israeli surveillance of its mobile phones, following the killing of senior commanders in targeted airstrikes over the past year.</p>

<p>Hezbollah's conflict with Israel dates back decades but has flared up in the past year in parallel with the Gaza war, heightening worries of a full-blown regional war.</p>

<p><strong>TOO LITTLE, TOO LATE</strong></p>

<p>After the pagers detonated on Tuesday, Hezbollah suspected more of its devices may have been compromised, two of the security sources, as well as an intelligence source, told Reuters.</p>

<p>In response, it intensified the sweep of its communications systems, carrying out careful examinations of all devices. It also began investigating the supply chains through which the pagers were brought in, the two security sources said.</p>

<p>But the review had not been concluded by Wednesday afternoon, when the hand-held radios exploded.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Hezbollah believes that Israel opted to detonate the group's hand-held radios because it feared Hezbollah would soon find that the walkie-talkies were also rigged with explosives, one of the sources told Reuters.</p>

<p>The walkie-talkie explosions left 25 people dead and at least 650 injured, according to Lebanon's health ministry - a much higher fatality rate than the previous day's pager blasts, which killed 12 and wounded nearly 3,000.&nbsp;</p>

<p>That is because they carried a higher payload of explosives than the beepers, one of the security sources and the intelligence source said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The group's probe into precisely where, when and how the devices were laced with explosives is ongoing, three of the sources said. Nasrallah later said the same in the speech on Thursday.</p>

<p>One of the security sources said Hezbollah had foiled previous Israeli operations targeting devices imported from abroad by the group - from its private landline telephones to ventilation units in the group's offices.&nbsp;</p>

<p>That includes suspected breaches in the past year.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"There are several electronic issues that we were able to discover - but not the pagers," the source said. "They tricked us, hats off to the enemy."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/944ak7j_pagers_625x300_19_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A security source said it was very hard to detect the explosives "with any device or scanner." (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/4-key-obstacles-to-india-joining-un-security-council-with-veto-power-6610212]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[4 Key Obstacles To India Joining UN Security Council With Veto Power]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/4-key-obstacles-to-india-joining-un-security-council-with-veto-power-6610212]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Sep 2024 17:21:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Indian politicians have argued for decades that the nation deserves to be a member of the United Nations Security Council (UNSC).]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Indian politicians have argued for decades that the nation deserves to be a member of the United Nations Security Council (UNSC).</p>

<p>An aspirational superpower, India believes that it has been unfairly denied a seat at the high table.</p>

<p>Several visiting foreign political dignitaries and international coalitions that have pushed for UNSC reforms have also voiced support for India's candidacy for permanent membership of the Security Council.</p>

<p>However, despite persistent lobbying by India, experts are not hopeful of change in the near future.</p>

<p>There are four key challenges India must overcome before it secures veto power in the United Nations.</p>

<h2><strong>CHINA'S OPPOSITION</strong></h2>

<p>Among the five permanent security council members all except China - the US, the UK, France, and Russia - have categorically supported India's candidature in the past.</p>

<p>As a close competitor of India in regional and international politics, China - the only Asian country with a security council seat - is unwilling to endorse New Delhi's position.</p>

<p>This adds to its power and international prestige and China is unlikely to want to share this space with India. What's more, particularly amid an ongoing border dispute with India, China will resist any attempt by any of the four members to change the composition of the UNSC.</p>

<p>China is also uncomfortable with Japan, a close US ally that, like India, is a strong contender for a permanent seat.</p>

<p>China has unofficially dropped hints that it may back India, provided New Delhi doesn't endorse Japan's bid. China knows that New Delhi will not break the unity of the G-4 (comprising Brazil, Germany, India, and Japan, are four countries which support each other's bids for permanent seats on the security council) and thus, considers it is a safe bet to pit India against Japan.</p>

<h3><strong>DISAGREEMENT ON MEMBERSHIP WITHOUT VETO POWER</strong></h3>

<p>Some parties have raised the prospect of India gaining UNSC membership without veto power.</p>

<p>Groups including Uniting for Consensus (UfC) - a powerful coalition led by Italy, with other members including Canada, Mexico, Spain, Pakistan, South Korea and Turkey - have advocated reinforcing the working of the General Assembly and increasing the number of non-permanent members.</p>

<p>Its argument is that the addition of non-permanent members will make the UN more accountable and representative by accommodating relevant regional voices in the decision-making process. In doing so, the group argues, this solution would mean there are more than a few select chief custodians of the international system.</p>

<p>But there are questions about what happens if India gets a high seat without veto power. Could this be considered a piecemeal approach towards achieving the larger objective?</p>

<p>Despite some parties saying they prefer this kind of arrangement, New Delhi is not comfortable with this proposition. India's position is that all new permanent members to the security council must possess a veto. Thus, it is unlikely this outcome will unfold.</p>

<h3><strong>WESTERN CONCERNS THAT INDIA MAY NOT ALIGN WITH US PRIORITIES</strong></h3>

<p>The US has, in principle, endorsed India gaining a permanent seat on the security council. But not everyone believes US policymakers will actually support such a reform in practice.</p>

<p>Indeed, in the past, P-5 countries have displayed "a habit of being non-commital" when it comes to actual decision-making on veto powers. As former US Under Secretary of State for Political Affairs Nicholas Burns said in 2008: "We want to preserve the veto, and we do not want to extend a veto to new permanent members."</p>

<p>Prominent US-based South Asian expert Ashley Tellis recently penned a piece in <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.foreignaffairs.com/india/americas-bad-bet-india-modi" rel="No follow, no index" target="_blank">Foreign Affairs magazine</a> arguing that the US cannot be sure of India's support on significant strategic matters. Ashley later defended this position in an interview, saying "the current war in Ukraine is a good example... India defines its interest in ways that are not always identical to our own".</p>

<p>It is true that India has not always voted with the West in the UN and has maintained an independent position on several critical subjects (e.g., India abstaining on the Russian invasion of Ukraine). Due to this, many think India is a fence-sitter and see it as an unreliable partner.</p>

<p>The West, particularly after the Russian-Ukraine war, is more watchful of new geopolitical reality. The understanding that Russia may fail to secure any support in the world for its war has changed.</p>

<p>Despite developing closer strategic ties with the West, India remained uncommitted on supporting sanctions on Russia. While China's response was anticipated, for the West, foot dragging by New Delhi in criticising Russia was no less than a shock.</p>

<p>In these changed circumstances, it is difficult to imagine that the West, particularly the US, will go ahead with a reformed security council where India has veto power.</p>

<h3><strong>THE REGIONAL CONUNDRUM</strong></h3>

<p>India also faces formidable challenges to its leadership emanating from its own region. India influences the region, but not in absolute terms. Indeed, as instability in the region has increased, so too have New Delhi's troubles.</p>

<p>South Asia has become a battleground of India-China competition.</p>

<p>And while the India-Pakistan rivalry captures most attention, there are major India-related issues that agitate people in Nepal, Bangladesh, Sri Lanka, Maldives and even in Bhutan.</p>

<p>With its recent change of government, Bangladeshis no longer on the same page. Queries over India's regional leadership raises questions over its claims to be a global power.</p>

<h3><strong>NEXT STEP FOR INDIA</strong></h3>

<p>There are convincing arguments that the UN is in desperate need of reform, particularly the Security Council. Expanding the Security Council's membership to include developing countries like India would benefit the UN and the international community.</p>

<p>However, New Delhi must make more concerted efforts to address criticisms to further legitimise its demand for permanent membership.</p>

<p>India's geographical, political, and social influence in South Asia cannot be ignored. Recent criticism around its increasing political intolerance - which is directly linked to the state of democracy in India - must be addressed and resolved.</p>

<p>India's failure to improve its ranking in the Human Development Index, the issue of economic inequality, and its lack of world-class infrastructure all contribute to the nation's global image.</p>

<p>Therefore, there are structural and more prominent geopolitical factors that overshadow India's chances to acquire security council permanent membership.</p>

<p>Additionally, India needs better engagement with the region and much more internal work to strengthen its claim further.</p>

<p><em>(<strong>Author:</strong> Dhananjay Tripathi is Associate Professor in the Department of International Relations at South Asian University, New Delhi)</em></p>

<p><em><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> Originally published under <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/" rel="No follow, no index" target="_blank">Creative Commons</a> by <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://360info.org/" rel="No follow, no index" target="_blank">360info</a></em><br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-08/gg6u123_india-at-un-security-council-un-security-council-un-security-council-president_625x300_01_August_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[There are 4 key challenges India must overcome before it secures veto power in UN Security Council]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/so-dumb-melinda-french-gates-slams-ceos-who-brag-about-sleep-deprivation-6609740]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["So Dumb": Melinda French Gates Slams CEOs Who Brag About Sleep Deprivation]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/so-dumb-melinda-french-gates-slams-ceos-who-brag-about-sleep-deprivation-6609740]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Sep 2024 16:27:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In a recent interview, Melinda French Gates criticised CEOs and tech entrepreneurs who boast about functioning on minimal sleep, calling the trend "so dumb."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Billionaire philanthropist Melinda French Gates has taken CEOs and tech entrepreneurs to task for bragging about getting minimal sleep, claiming it maximises productivity. An interview with <em>Vanity Fair</em> ended with her calling the approach "so dumb." She confided that she gets between seven and eight hours of sleep at night.</p>

<p>In the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.vanityfair.com/style/story/melinda-gates-interview-politics?_sp=3adf1d39-eefb-4f9c-992b-2070941c5bd7.1726583518652"><em>interview,</em></a> French Gates identified the negative side of sleep deprivation, adding that "some of us didn't want to be around them! Let's be honest!" referring to CEOs, in her opinion, who advocate for a destructive and performative deprivation of sleep.</p>

<p>Physicians support this, highlighting the need for sufficient rest for optimal health. <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.cdc.gov/mmwr/volumes/65/wr/mm6506a1.htm#:~:text=To%20promote%20optimal%20health%20and,mortality%20(2%E2%80%934).">The Centre for Disease Control and Prevention</a> recommends that adults aged 18 to 60 years should sleep for at least seven hours in a day.</p>

<p>Extreme sleep deprivation causes critical health conditions such as diseases of the heart and kidneys, high blood pressure, diabetes, stroke, obesity, and depression.</p>

<p>French Gates' comments come as a growing number of prominent figures, including Elon Musk, Jeff Bezos, and Bill Gates, have acknowledged the importance of sleep and are prioritising it in their own lives.</p>

<p>"I've tried [to sleep] less... Even though I'm awake more hours, I get less done," Musk told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.cnbc.com/2023/05/18/elon-musk-sacrificing-sleep-for-productivity-gave-me-brain-pain.html"><em>CNBC </em></a>last year. "And the brain pain level is bad if I get less than six hours [of sleep]."</p>

<p>Research shows that getting enough sleep is essential for peak physical and mental performance, and sleep deprivation can even mimic the effects of being intoxicated.</p>

<p>According to CDC, insufficient sleep impairs cognitive performance, which can increase the likelihood of motor vehicle and other transportation accidents, industrial accidents, medical errors, and loss of work productivity that could affect the wider community.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/5sr78lb_melinda-french-gates_625x300_20_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Melinda highlighted the negative impacts of sleep deprivation and the importance of rest.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-chief-hassan-nasrallah-admits-group-suffered-major-blow-in-lebanon-device-blasts-6609568]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hezbollah Chief Admits Group Suffered "Major" Blow In Lebanon Device Blasts]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-chief-hassan-nasrallah-admits-group-suffered-major-blow-in-lebanon-device-blasts-6609568]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Sep 2024 16:07:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hezbollah chief Hassan Nasrallah has acknowledged that his powerful group had suffered an "unprecedented" blow when thousands of operatives' communication devices exploded in attacks it blamed on Israel.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hezbollah chief Hassan Nasrallah has acknowledged that his powerful group had suffered an "unprecedented" blow when thousands of operatives' communication devices exploded in attacks it blamed on Israel.</p>

<p>Israel has not commented on the attacks that killed 37 people and wounded nearly 3,000 across Lebanon over two days but has said it will widen the scope of its war in Gaza to include the Lebanon front.</p>

<p>Delivering a speech after the attacks on Tuesday and Wednesday, which plunged Lebanon into panic, Nasrallah struck a defiant tone and warned of retaliation.</p>

<p>Describing the attacks as a possible "act of war", he said Israel would face "tough retribution and just punishment, where it expects it and where it does not".</p>

<p>The attacks were a "massacre" that "could be a war crime or a declaration of war," he said, accusing Israel of having wanted to "kill no less than 5,000 people in two minutes".</p>

<p>Nasrallah also vowed to keep up Hezbollah's fight against Israel until a ceasefire in Gaza is reached.</p>

<p>"The Lebanese front will not stop until the aggression on Gaza stops" despite "all this blood spilt," he said.</p>

<h2><strong>'STOP' GAZA WAR</strong></h2>

<p>Nasrallah addressed Israeli officials' promises to return to their homes thousands of Israelis displaced by exchanges of fire across the border with Lebanon.</p>

<p>"You will not be able to return the people of the north to the north," he said, warning that "no military escalation, no killings, no assassinations and no all-out war can return residents to the border".</p>

<p>The "only way" to return the displaced to the north is to "stop the war on Gaza," he said.</p>

<p>Hezbollah is an ally of Palestinian militant group Hamas, which on October 7 launched an unprecedented attack on Israel that sparked Gaza's deadliest ever war.</p>

<p>Up until now, the focus of Israel's firepower had been on Gaza.</p>

<p>But Israel's northern border with Lebanon has seen exchanges of fire between Israeli troops and Hezbollah militants almost every day since October 8.</p>

<p>The violence has killed hundreds of people, mostly fighters, on the Lebanese side, and dozens on the Israeli side.</p>

<p>Israeli warplanes broke the sound barrier over Beirut as Nasrallah spoke, Lebanon's state-run National News Agency said, with AFP correspondents in Beirut reporting loud booms.</p>

<p>Nasrallah announced the launch of an internal probe into the attacks, which experts and some Israeli media have said bear all the hallmarks of Israeli intelligence agency Mossad.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/m54d096s_hezbollah-chief-hassan-nasrallah_625x300_20_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hassan Nasrallah also vowed to keep up Hezbollah's fight against Israel until a ceasefire in Gaza]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/he-makes-us-feel-confident-modis-us-visit-has-desi-fans-thrilled-6609553]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: "He Makes Us Feel Confident": Modi's US Visit Has Desi Fans Thrilled]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/he-makes-us-feel-confident-modis-us-visit-has-desi-fans-thrilled-6609553]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Sep 2024 16:03:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Like her Indian immigrant parents, Agrima Agnihotri is convinced that PM Modi thinks "futuristically" and has "put India in a good light". "Modiji is not only an inspiration in India. I like to think that he inspires us across the oceans. He is my ro]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/5q0rarlo_modi_625x300_20_September_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Amidst the cacophony of US Presidential election campaigns, many Indian American youth are rallying for the Indian Prime Minister, Narendra Modi. Eager little dancers are fine-tuning their steps to be at their coordinated best when they perform for him on September 22 at the Nassau Coliseum in Long Island, New York. Thirteen-year-old Mahita Pendota is one of over 80 performers who will showcase their talent in traditional and popular pan-India performing arts. Beats of<i>&nbsp;Dhol baje'&nbsp;</i>will reverberate across the venue as her group from East Coast's Shivaay Dance Academy will present traditional garba in a Bollywood twist style' to a soundtrack custom-produced in India. Rohan Virdi, the co-founder of the academy, describes the enthusiasm among Indian American families thus: They are willing to do anything possible to be a part of this show. Even if the parents will not get to attend, they don't want their kids to miss seeing Modiji.</p>

<p>The enthusiasm among Indian American youngsters springs from the cultural milieu they are being raised in. For instance, Sandeep Shetty, a former Bollywood choreographer who runs New Jersey-based Rudra Dance Academy, not only focuses on technical skills but also teaches culture'. We educate them about cultural, current and historical things from India like festivals. Students know a lot about Modi. When they got to know the Prime Minister was coming to New York, they were so excited to participate! he says. Shetty's group will also be presenting a Bollywood-style performance.</p>

<p>US-raised graduate Agrima Agnihotri finds herself fortunate to be one of the volunteers. She and many young second-generation immigrant peers who speak highly of Modi will be attending the event. We finally get to see him! she exclaims. Like her Indian immigrant parents, Agnihotri is convinced that PM Modi thinks futuristically and has put India in a good light. Modiji is not only an inspiration in India. I like to think that he inspires us across the oceans. He is my role model personally. My parents are huge supporters, and I've learned to be a supporter as well, she says. Calling him a "guiding light" for youth, she says Modi even makes Indian American youth feel cool about their identity and background socially. After he became the PM, India is much more respected than earlier which makes us feel confident and validated when we talk to our non-Indian peers. The narrative has switched in our favour.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>Indian Americans Are A Diverse Lot</strong></h2>

<p>The largest Asian immigrant community in the US, Indian Americans are a diverse lot, representing various Indian cultures and political leanings. Their population has more than doubled in the last two decades. The ideological leanings of recent immigrants reflect home country politics, evident in their affinity for Indian political leaders. It is well-known that Modi is very popular among a large chunk of Hindu Americans. Temple University's Dr Sanjoy Chakravorty, co-author of<i>&nbsp;The Other One Percent: Indians in America</i>, is sceptical of generalising for most Indian Americans but recognises that the affinity for PM Modi among those from Gujarat is strong. By and large, the second-generation children have very little political knowledge of India. In Gujarati families, there's a worship of Modi and you know how Gujaratis are well-represented in certain parts of the US, particularly in New Jersey, New York and Chicago.&nbsp;</p>

<p>At the same time, for those growing up in the US, the dominant culture for a majority of Indian American youth remains American. The American political horse race is kind of fascinating and it's constantly in your face. They constantly talk about it as it's always on TV, always in the news, and they get caught up in it. India is a distant thing and a good chunk of them have rarely been to India, Dr Chakravorty explains. And thus, while some second-generation immigrants reject their parents' politics, there are others who follow it, he adds.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>"A Bubble"</strong></h2>

<p>You're seeing a particular bubble which I don't think is representative. It really doesn't strike me in any shape or fashion as something that's representative of the second-generation Indians in the US, Chakravorty points out. Even so, within the bubble that's enthusiastic about Modi's visit, culture and politics seem to transcend continents and generations. The sign-ups for the event, dubbed as Modi and US, Progress Together', crossed 29,700 according to a lead organiser. It was not open to the public and only well-recognised cultural and philanthropic US-based organisations could apply. The 600 selected, including sponsors, had to trim their member lists to be accommodated into the 13,500-capacity at the Nassau Coliseum.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Wanting to be seen and recognised, this is a grand stage for aspirational Indian diaspora members. It's networking at the highest level. Being at a Prime Minister event is high visibility. Getting a picture taken with the Prime Minister is something they'll hang on the walls, show everywhere, put on their websites. It's not just Indians, everybody does it, says Dr Chakravorty.&nbsp;</p>

<p>A group of US-based Welcome Partner Organizations' have come together as the Indo American Community of USA' to steer the effort. Participants will be taking long flights and drives from over 42 states to Long Island on the US East Coast. One of those attending from the West Coast is California-based Vijaya Aasuri, President of the Association of Indo-Americans, a conglomeration of 48 Indian cultural and charity organisations. She has been part of Modi's past meetings at The White House and diaspora events, including the 2014 Madison Square Garden summit and the 2019 Howdy Modi rally in Texas. Aasuri says she is looking forward to his latest address. Every day, every minute you see growth in India. Getting those updates from the media is one thing but hearing about the progress directly from our honourable Prime Minister is very reassuring.</p>

<h2><strong>Hindu Indian-Americans Biggest Supporters</strong></h2>

<p>In line with the religious demographics of the Indian American community, the rally will largely consist of Hindu Indian-Americans but will also have a smattering of other religions. Nikunj Trivedi, president of the Coalition of Hindus of North America, says, I do know that there are Sikh groups, there's an Indian Christian group and a Muslim group. Ismaili Bohra Muslims from Gujarat maintain a strong affinity to the state. I know that as I am from Gujarat. Meanwhile, two large Sikh-American groups as well as the Indian American Muslim Council say they will not be participating in the rally.</p>

<p>According to a lead organiser, the rally is being funded by participating groups and sponsors. One of the gold sponsors, Indiaspora, is an influential organisation whose mission is to build bridges among diaspora leaders in several countries and professions with leaders residing in India. They have close ties with US and Indian administrations and corporate leaders and are an example of the role the Indian diaspora plays in enhancing synergy between the two countries. Their Executive Director, Sanjeev Joshipura, says Indiaspora, a secular and non-partisan organisation, has been part of the Indian Prime Minister's earlier US visits too. It makes sense for an organisation to work with the sitting Prime Minister of India regardless of political party. A lot of Indiaspora network and members are going to be part of the VIP seating and backstage opportunities with Foreign Minister Jaishankar, and a possible meet-and-greet with the PM.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>No Political Leanings</strong></h2>

<p>A clear directive being followed by the organisers is not to lean towards any one US political party. A few prominent Indian American politicians might be in attendance, but organisers say they will be at the event in their personal capacity. This would be unlike the 2019 Howdy Modi' event, which saw addresses by both PM Modi and then US President Donald Trump. San Francisco Bay Area-based Democrat Ajay Bhutoria, member of National Finance Committee 2024, Harris for President', is one of the attendants at the rally. He says, During the planning stages, organisers had thought to extend invitations to both Trump and Harris, but they were unsure, just in case one accepts and the other doesn't for some reason. To avoid that, they decided against it, and are not inviting any members of Congress or elected officials.</p>

<p>As preparations for the Long Island rally continue in full swing, Joshipura points out that though it is only natural that a mass rally would generate conversation and grab headlines, Modi's US visit will also be defined by several other non-public aspects. There is the UNGA assembly going on, climate week is also at the same time, there is a QUAD meeting that will occur just before Modi's big speech in Nassau County and meetings with corporate leaders. In addition to what one sees on TV, there is a lot of substance to this visit, sometimes bilateral, in some cases even multilateral, he says.&nbsp;</p>

<p><em>(Savita Patel is a San Francisco Bay Area-based journalist and producer. She reports on the Indian diaspora, India-US ties, geopolitics, technology, public health, and the environment. She tweets at @SsavitaPatel.)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/r5u6deno_modi_625x300_20_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/how-elliott-hill-went-from-being-an-intern-to-nikes-chief-executive-officer-6608703]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How Elliott Hill Went From Being An Intern To Nike's CEO]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/how-elliott-hill-went-from-being-an-intern-to-nikes-chief-executive-officer-6608703]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Sep 2024 14:36:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Nike has announced the return of Elliott Hill as president and CEO, succeeding John Donahoe.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Nike has announced the return of <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/elliott-hill-4bb3331b6/">Elliott Hill</a> as president and CEO, succeeding John Donahoe. The leadership shake-up comes amid the sportswear giant's efforts to revive its sales and combat increasing competition in the industry. Mr Hill, who boasts an impressive 32-year career at Nike, held numerous roles and has been instrumental in shaping the company's trajectory. His endeavours have contributed significantly to the brand's growth, propelling it to an impressive revenue of over $39 billion. As Mr Hill comes to the helm, employees and industry observers are eager to see how his deep expertise influences Nike's future.</p>

<p><strong>Homecoming for Elliott Hill</strong></p>

<p>Effective October 14, 2024, Mr Hill will not only step into the role of CEO but also join the NIKE, Inc. Board of Directors and the Executive Committee. While he may be relatively unknown to the broader public, within Nike, he is a respected figure. Many employees hold him in high regard, recognising his commitment and contributions to the brand.</p>

<p>Mr Hill is a graduate of Texas Christian University (TCU) and Ohio University, currently serving on TCU's Board of Trustees. His journey at Nike began as an intern in 1988, and over the years, he has navigated through 19 different roles, culminating in his retirement in 2020 as President of Consumer and Marketplace.</p>

<p><strong>A successful track record</strong><br />
<br />
Throughout his career at Nike, Mr Hill was in various senior leadership positions across Europe and North America, expanding the company's footprint and boosting its revenue. As President of Consumer and Marketplace, he was responsible for managing Nike's largest brands and driving the company's commercial and marketing strategies across its global markets.<br />
<br />
On his LinkedIn profile, Mr Hill stated, In my previous role at NIKE as President  Consumer and Marketplace, I was running the largest brands in the sports industry and responsible for helping to grow NIKE, Inc. to $39 billion. I was also responsible for the NIKE business, which included the Jordan Brand and marketing operations and all four of Nike's geographies.<br />
<br />
His passion for sports extends beyond his professional life. In his free time, he enjoys running, hiking, cycling, and skiing and even founded a baseball team in Austin called the Austin Moontowers. He balances his active lifestyle with family time, spending quality moments with his wife, Gina, and their two children, Peyton and Austin.</p>

<p><strong>Looking ahead</strong></p>

<p>In his return to Nike, Mr Hill is eager to reconnect with his colleagues and foster new relationships. NIKE has always been a core part of who I am, and I'm ready to help lead it to an even brighter future, he <a href="https://about.nike.com/en/newsroom/releases/nike-inc-announces-return-of-long-time-nike-veteran-elliott-hill-as-president-and-ceo">said</a>, adding For 32 years, I've had the privilege of working with the best in the industry, helping to shape our company into the magical place it is today.<br />
<br />
Mr Hill is eager to reconnect with the many employees and trusted partners he's worked with over the years, and is just as excited to build new, impactful relationships that will move them ahead, he said. "Together with our talented teams, I look forward to delivering bold, innovative products that set us apart in the marketplace and captivate consumers for years to come," he added.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/83s6for_elliott-hill-nike-linkedin_625x300_20_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Elliott Hill was in various senior leadership positions across Europe and North America.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/all-about-greeces-golden-visa-scheme-popular-among-wealthy-indians-6607859]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[All About Greece's Golden Visa Scheme, Popular Among Wealthy Indians]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/all-about-greeces-golden-visa-scheme-popular-among-wealthy-indians-6607859]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Sep 2024 13:34:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Indian investors snapped up Greek properties at a record pace in July and August to secure permanent residency before the country's Golden Visa Programme underwent significant changes on September 1.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Indian investors snapped up Greek properties at a record pace in July and August to secure permanent residency before the country's Golden Visa Programme underwent significant changes on September 1. <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-investors-rush-to-buy-greek-properties-ahead-of-golden-visa-rule-changes-6601066">Property purchases by Indian investors</a> in Greece saw a remarkable 37 per cent increase between July and August, data show. The surge was led by buyers seeking to capitalise on the existing minimum investment requirements.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Now the changes in the Golden Visa Programme have doubled the minimum investment required to qualify for a visa through real estate purchases. In Tier I cities, including Athens, Thessaloniki, Mykonos, and Santorini, the threshold has increased 800,000 800,000 (approximately Rs 7 crore).&nbsp;</p>

<p>In Tier II regions, covering all other parts of Greece, the minimum investment has risen to 400,000 from 250,000.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>Greece Golden Visa Programme</strong></h2>

<p>The Greece Golden Visa programme is a premier residency-by-investment initiative designed to attract non-EU nationals to invest in Greece.</p>

<p>In 2024, the programme was updated to better align with Greece's economic strategies, introducing new investment thresholds and conditions.</p>

<h2><strong>Eligibility criteria</strong></h2>

<ul>
	<li>Non-EU/EEA citizenship</li>
	<li>Age 18+</li>
	<li>Clean criminal record</li>
	<li>Medical insurance</li>
	<li>Good character</li>
</ul>

<h2><strong>Benefits</strong></h2>

<ul>
	<li>Residency Rights: Right to reside in Greece without mandatory stay requirements.</li>
	<li>Schengen Area Access: Visa-free travel within the Schengen Zone.</li>
	<li>Family Inclusion: Eligibility for family members to obtain residency.</li>
	<li>Pathway to Citizenship: Potential to apply for Greek citizenship after seven years of residency, subject to conditions.</li>
</ul>

<h2><strong>Application Process and legal requirements</strong></h2>

<h3><strong>Required Documentation</strong></h3>

<ul>
	<li>Valid Passport: Current and any previous visas.</li>
	<li>Proof of Investment: Property contracts, bank statements, etc.</li>
	<li>Biometric Data: Required for the application.</li>
	<li>Health Insurance: Policy valid in Greece.</li>
	<li>Criminal Record: Clean criminal record from the applicant's country of residence, officially translated into Greek.</li>
</ul>

<h3><strong>Legal Representation</strong></h3>

<ul>
	<li>Mandatory Lawyer: Licensed to practise in Greece.&nbsp;</li>
	<li>Role of Lawyer: Facilitates document preparation, and submission, and ensures compliance with Greek immigration laws.</li>
	<li>Power of Attorney: Often required for the lawyer to act on the applicant's behalf.</li>
</ul>

<h3><strong>Renewal and Permanent Residency</strong></h3>

<ul>
	<li>Initial Permit: Issued for five years, renewable as long as the investment is maintained.</li>
	<li>Permanent Residency: Eligible after seven years of continuous residency in Greece.</li>
</ul>

<h3><strong>Dependents</strong></h3>

<ul>
	<li>Spouse and Partner: Including legally recognised cohabitation agreements.</li>
	<li>Children: Under 21, or older if financially dependent and studying.</li>
	<li>Parents: Dependent parents of the primary applicant or spouse.</li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/i648nt9g_parthenon-temple-greece_625x300_13_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Greece Golden Visa programme is a premier residency-by-investment initiative.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/titanic-ex-oceangate-employee-says-titan-sub-had-to-abort-a-dive-days-before-fatal-implosion-6607726]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ex Employee Says Titan Sub Had To Abort A Dive Days Before Fatal Implosion]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/titanic-ex-oceangate-employee-says-titan-sub-had-to-abort-a-dive-days-before-fatal-implosion-6607726]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Sep 2024 12:05:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Titan submersible had to abort a dive just days before the implosion that killed its five passengers as they explored the wreck of the Titanic, an ex-employee of the company that operated the vessel testified on Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Titan submersible had to abort a dive just days before the implosion that killed its five passengers as they explored the wreck of the Titanic, an ex-employee of the company that operated the vessel testified on Thursday. The testimony from former OceanGate scientific director Steven Ross came as the US Coast Guard began a two-week hearing on Monday into the 2023 catastrophe, which will feature evidence as to what went wrong and whether physical or design failure contributed to the accident, which garnered worldwide attention.</p>

<p>Ross told the hearing that the earlier dive had to be aborted due to a valve malfunction that left at least one passenger hanging upside down and took "considerable time" to correct.</p>

<p>He said that when the privately-owned and operated submersible surfaced during that dive, it tilted so its bow was pointing upwards at a 45-degree angle.</p>

<p>Ross, who was inside along with four other passengers, explained that "there's nothing to hold on to inside this submersible."</p>

<p>The pilot that day -- OceanGate CEO Stockton Rush, who died in the implosion days later -- "crashed into the rear bulkhead," Ross said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The rest of the passengers tumbled about. I ended up standing on the rear bulkhead," he continued.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"One passenger was hanging upside down, and the other two managed to wedge themselves into the bow end cap."</p>

<p>He said no one was injured in the incident, but that inside the cramped and confined space "it was uncomfortable and unpleasant, and it took considerable time to correct the problem" -- at least an hour, by his reckoning.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Rush, he said, was "upset" by the incident.</p>

<p>Rush and four passengers descended in the submersible on June 18, 2023, to observe the wreck of the Titanic.</p>

<p>But contact was lost less than two hours after their departure. A vast rescue operation was launched in the hope that the passengers had simply lost power and were drifting helplessly in the ocean's depths.</p>

<p>However, within days it became clear that the sub had been destroyed in a cataclysmic implosion.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Victims are presumed to have died instantly in the disaster, which occurred under the crushing pressure of the North Atlantic at a depth of more than two miles (nearly four kilometers).</p>

<p>Apart from Rush, the four others on the Titan were British explorer Hamish Harding, French submarine expert Paul-Henri Nargeolet, Pakistani-British tycoon Shahzada Dawood and his son Suleman.</p>

<p>The family of Nargeolet has taken OceanGate to court, claiming $50 million for negligence.&nbsp;</p>

<p>A debris field was found 1,600 feet (500 meters) from the bow of the Titanic, which sits 400 miles off the coast of Newfoundland, Canada.</p>

<p>The Titanic hit an iceberg and sank in 1912 during its maiden voyage from England to New York, with 2,224 passengers and crew on board. More than 1,500 people died.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/epo97r78_oceangate-titan-sub_625x300_20_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Five people had descended in the submersible on June 18, 2023, to observe the wreck of the Titanic]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/generous-gesture-maldives-as-india-sends-crucial-budgetary-support-6607501]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Generous Gesture": Maldives As India Sends "Crucial Budgetary Support"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/generous-gesture-maldives-as-india-sends-crucial-budgetary-support-6607501]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Sep 2024 11:35:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Maldives Foreign Minister Moosa Zameer has expressed gratitude to External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar as the Indian government extended budgetary support to the Maldives with the rollover of the USD 50 million Treasury Bill.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Maldives Foreign Minister Moosa Zameer has expressed gratitude to External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar as the Indian government extended budgetary support to the Maldives with the rollover of the USD 50 million Treasury Bill. He said the Indian government's announcement demonstrates "enduring bonds of friendship between the Maldives and India."</p>

<p>In a post on X, Mr Zameer stated, "Sincere gratitude to External Affairs Minister @DrSJaishankar and the Government of #India for extending crucial budgetary support to the Maldives with the rollover of USD 50 million Treasury Bill. This generous gesture reflects the enduring bonds of friendship between #Maldives and #India."</p>

<p>At the request of the Maldivian government, the State Bank of India (SBI) has subscribed the USD 50 million government Treasury Bills (T-bills) issued by the Ministry of Finance of the Maldives for a period of one more year upon the maturity of the previous subscription on September 19, the Indian High Commission in the Maldives said in a press release.</p>

<p>This is the second rollover granted by the Indian government this year, following the first rollover of a USD 50 million Treasury Bill on May 13.</p>

<p>According to the press release, the Maldivian government is "highly appreciative" of the support announced by India following the request made by Moosa Zameer during his meeting with Mr Jaishankar in August.</p>

<p>In a press release, the Maldives Ministry of Foreign Affairs stated, "Government of India's decision to grant this extension came following a request to that effect made by Foreign Minister Moosa Zameer during the discussions held between the two governments at the recent visit of the Minister of External Affairs of India, S Jaishankar, to the Maldives from 9-11 August 2024."</p>

<p>"The Government of the Maldives is highly appreciative of the generous support that the Government of India has been providing to the Maldives in the form of budgetary support. This extension comes at a pivotal moment as the Government of the Maldives is implementing a strong fiscal consolidation program to address the pressing economic challenges," it added.</p>

<p>Maldivian Ministry of Foreign Affairs noted that India has once again showcased the high value it places on the enduring partnership between the two nations.</p>

<p>The press release stated, "The Government of India has once again demonstrated the high value it places on this enduring partnership. The Government of Maldives looks forward to continuing this collaborative partnership for the mutual benefit and prosperity of the people of both nations."</p>

<p>In the press release, the Indian High Commission called the Maldives India's key maritime neighbour and important partner under India's 'Neighbourhood First' policy.</p>

<p>The Indian High Commission in Maldives stated, "Maldives is India's key maritime neighbour and an important partner under India's 'Neighbourhood First' policy and Vision SAGAR i.e. Security and Growth for All in the Region."</p>

<p>"India has assisted the Maldives in times of need, and the current subscription of T-bills along with the Government of India's decision earlier this year, of extending special quota for export of essential commodities for Maldives by one more year reflect India's continued support to the Government and the people of the Maldives," it added.</p>

<p>It noted that SBI had similarly subscribed a USD 50 mn T-bills under the same mechanism in May 2024, at the request of the Maldives government. These subscriptions have been made at the special request of the Maldives government as emergency financial assistance.</p>

<p>India's ties with the Maldives were strained after Maldives President Mohamed Muizzu took office. Shortly after he was sworn in, Mr Muizzu stirred bilateral tensions by demanding the removal of approximately 88 Indian military personnel from the Maldives. These personnel were repatriated from three aviation platforms and replaced by Indian civilians by the May 10 deadline set by President Muizzu.</p>

<p>Recently, Mr Muizzu's government in the Maldives took a reconciliatory tone after ties between the two nations soured, leading to a diplomatic row in January after three Maldivian deputy ministers made derogatory comments against Prime Minister Narendra Modi over his pictures from the visit to Lakshadweep.</p>

<p>Since January, many efforts have been undertaken by the Muizzu-led government in order to restore the relationship, which includes several high-level visits, including the President himself coming to India for the swearing-in ceremony of PM Narendra Modi or the visit of the Maldivian Foreign Minister.</p>

<p>Earlier in August, External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar visited Maldives. During his visit to Male, Mr Jaishankar signed MoUs on capacity building and inaugurated six High Impact Community Development Projects (HICDPs), according to a Ministry of External Affairs (MEA) release.</p>

<p>Mr Jaishankar also called on Mr Muizzu and reviewed bilateral relations with his Maldives counterpart Moosa Zameer.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/726io9h8_s-jaishankar-moosa-zameer_625x300_20_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[File photo]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/wrath-of-god-to-the-angel-6-times-mossad-ops-inspired-hollywood-6607430]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA['Wrath Of God' To 'The Angel': 6 Times Mossad Ops Inspired Hollywood]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/wrath-of-god-to-the-angel-6-times-mossad-ops-inspired-hollywood-6607430]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Sep 2024 11:21:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel's spy intelligence agency Mossad has long been synonymous with daring and covert operations.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">Israel's spy intelligence agency Mossad has long been synonymous with daring and covert operations. The recent explosions in Lebanon  where thousands of pagers and walkie talkies, allegedly triggered remotely by Israel, killed 32  have once again brought the agency's capabilities to focus.&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">Mossad's real-life missions have inspired filmmakers worldwide, bringing these dramatic and dangerous operations to the screen. Here are some films and series based on actual Mossad operations:</p>

<h2 dir="ltr"><strong>Munich (2005)</strong></h2>

<p dir="ltr">Directed by Steven Spielberg, <em>Munich</em> follows Avner Kaufman (played by Eric Bana), a Mossad agent tasked with leading a secret mission, "Wrath of God," to assassinate Palestinian militants responsible for the 1972 Olympics terror attack. The film explores the moral complexities of revenge and counter-terrorism.</p>

<h2 dir="ltr"><strong>Kidon (2011)</strong></h2>

<p dir="ltr">Loosely based on the 2010 assassination of Hamas commander Mahmoud Al-Mabhouh in Dubai, Kidon combines spy action and comedy. The film follows a Mossad team as they execute a high-stakes mission.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 dir="ltr"><strong>Operation Finale (2018)</strong></h2>

<p dir="ltr">This film recreates the 1960 Mossad mission to capture Adolf Eichmann, a key architect of the Holocaust, in Argentina. Peter Malkin (played by Oscar Isaac) leads the team of agents who track down Eichmann and bring him to Israel to face justice.</p>

<h2 dir="ltr"><strong>The Angel (2018)</strong></h2>

<p dir="ltr">Based on the book The Angel: The Egyptian Spy Who Saved Israel', this film tells the story of Ashraf Marwan (played by Marwan Kenzari), an Egyptian diplomat who becomes a double agent for Mossad. Marwan provides crucial intelligence to Israel, including a warning about the 1973 Yom Kippur War.</p>

<h2 dir="ltr"><strong>The Spy (Netflix series, 2019)</strong></h2>

<p dir="ltr">Based on true events, <em>The Spy</em> tells the story of Eli Cohen (played by Sacha Baron Cohen), an Israeli Mossad agent who infiltrates Syrian high society in the 1960s. Cohen, posing as Kamel Amin Thaabet, gains the trust of military officials and politicians, becoming a close confidant of future Syrian President Amin al-Hafiz. His mission provides vital intelligence for Israel's victory in the 1967 Six-Day War. However, his daring mission comes at a great personal cost when his cover is blown and he is captured by Syrian forces.</p>

<h2 dir="ltr"><strong>The Red Sea Diving Resort (2019)</strong></h2>

<p dir="ltr"><em>The Red Sea Diving Resort</em> is based on one of Mossad's most audacious humanitarian operations, Operation Brothers, in the early 1980s. The mission aimed to rescue Ethiopian Jews fleeing civil war and famine. Thousands had crossed the border into Sudan making it extremely difficult for Mossad to operate. The solution was Israeli agents setting up a fake diving resort on the Sudanese coast as a front for taking refugees to safety. The resort was fully operational, with tourists and diving activities masking the covert mission.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/at93cihs_munich_625x300_20_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/traslados-argentinas-death-flights-when-people-were-thrown-out-of-planes-6607191]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Argentina's "Death Flights": When People Were Thrown Out Of Planes]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/traslados-argentinas-death-flights-when-people-were-thrown-out-of-planes-6607191]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Sep 2024 10:44:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A documentary, "Traslados", explores the grim legacy of Argentina's death flights, where thousands of dissidents were rounded up and thrown out of planes, often alive.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A chilling reminder of Argentina's violent military dictatorship between 1976 and 1983 has resurfaced on the big screen with the documentary Traslados' (Transferred). The film sheds light on the haunting practice of death flights,' where thousands of dissidents were rounded up and thrown out of planes, often alive, into the River Plate and the Atlantic Ocean.<br />
<br />
This week, a packed crowd at a theatre in Buenos Aires, the capital city of Argentina, saw one of the first screenings of the film, which brought both survivors and younger generations face to face with a past many would prefer to forget.</p>

<h3><strong>What were the death flights'?</strong></h3>

<p>The term death flights' refers to brutal executions by Argentina's military dictatorship. Those considered enemies, including activists and intellectuals, of the regime were told they were being transferred to another location. Instead, they were tortured and taken aboard military aircraft.<br />
<br />
Mid-flight, they were thrown from the planes, many still alive, into the sea or the River Plate, where they would drown or die due to the impact. The fate of thousands remains a mystery; their bodies were never recovered. What's been described by many as "state-sponsored terrorism" was a key tactic in silencing dissent during Argentina's Dirty War.</p>

<h3><strong>Traslados' documentary</strong></h3>

<p>Directed by Nicolas Gil Lavedra, Traslados'  the 90-minute documentary  brings together testimonies from survivors, archived material and dramatised reenactments to present the horrors of the death flights. According to Lavedra, Traslados' puts evidence on the table, brings together all the pieces and everything known...about the death flights.<br />
<br />
There are no partisan or subjective opinions, there are facts and there is evidence, Lavedra told AFP.<br />
<br />
He aimed to present a clear and unbiased account of the atrocities committed during the dictatorship, an era when 30,000 people were killed or disappeared, according to human rights organisations. One of the central stories featured in Traslados' is that of Esther Ballestrino, Azucena Villaflor, and Maria Ponce, founders of the Mothers of the Plaza de Mayo  a group that continues to fight for justice for the disappeared. Along with French nuns Alice Domon and Leonie Duquet, and seven other activists, they were abducted and killed in one of the death flights on December 14, 1977.</p>

<p>The documentary comes while Argentina is still grappling with its dark history. Controversy erupted earlier this year when lawmakers from President Javier Milei's party visited former military officers convicted of crimes against humanity, including Alfredo Astiz, the man who infiltrated the Mothers of the Plaza de Mayo' and identified the women who were later killed.<br />
<br />
The documentary's release has reignited calls for justice and remembrance. For Lavedra, this is more than revisiting history  it's about shaping the present. He said, The only way we have to heal that wound is with justice, truth and memory.<br />
<br />
His connection to the subject runs deep, as his father presided over post-dictatorship trials, and he has previously directed a film on human rights activist Estela de Carlotto, president of the Mothers' group.</p>

<h3><strong>Argentina's military dictatorship</strong></h3>

<p>Argentina's military dictatorship remains one of the most brutal in Latin American history. Torture, forced disappearances, and state-sanctioned murders were used to suppress any form of dissent. As the military sought to maintain power, the people of Argentina lived in constant fear, unsure of who among them might vanish next.<br />
The death flights' represent one of the most horrific tactics of this regime, and many of the victims were never identified.<br />
<br />
For younger Argentines, many of whom were born long after the dictatorship, Traslados' provides a stark reminder of the country's brutal past.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/rp5646s8_traslados_625x300_20_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A packed crowd at a theatre in Buenos Aires saw one of the first screenings of the film]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-us-elections-2024-if-somebody-breaks-into-my-house-theyre-getting-shot-6606918]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["If Somebody Breaks Into My House, They're Getting Shot": Kamala Harris]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-us-elections-2024-if-somebody-breaks-into-my-house-theyre-getting-shot-6606918]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Sep 2024 09:58:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kamala Harris' remarks came during a star-studded rally hosted by talk show legend Oprah Winfrey.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kamala Harris held a star-studded rally hosted by talk show legend Oprah Winfrey on Thursday in a bid to bedazzle voters, as rival Donald Trump criticized Jewish Americans for not voting for him. Hollywood stars including Jennifer Lopez, Meryl Streep, Julia Roberts, Chris Rock, and Ben Stiller beamed in remotely to lavish praise via screens on the Democratic vice president.</p>

<p>Sitting on a chat-show style stage, Winfrey started by asking Harris about what seemed a sudden burst in confidence -- "a veil or something dropped" -- after she replaced President Joe Biden as nominee.</p>

<p>"We each have those moments in our lives when you have to step up," the 59-year-old Harris replied at the livestreamed "Unite for America" event</p>

<p>The pair hugged as Harris arrived on stage at the rally in Michigan, one of the seven crucial battleground states that will decide the knife-edge November 5 election.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">It is so good to be with <a href="https://twitter.com/Oprah?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Oprah</a> for a town hall to speak directly with Americans about the issues on their minds in this election.<br />
<br />
Our campaign is about who we are as Americansand making clear that we stand for freedom, independence, and dignity. <a href="https://t.co/5k8h5Ra7Uk">pic.twitter.com/5k8h5Ra7Uk</a></p>
 Kamala Harris (@KamalaHarris) <a href="https://twitter.com/KamalaHarris/status/1836934301453099356?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 20, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Harris urged Americans to unite against the "powerful forces that would try to divide us", represented by Republican former president Trump.</p>

<p>The Democrat then talked through her key campaign points, ranging from abortion to economy and immigration and gun control, as audience members told stories about their experiences.</p>

<p>Former prosecutor Harris also made a pitch to gun owners, a key part of the electorate in a country with more firearms than people, even as she called for an end to high-powered assault weapons used in a string of school shootings.</p>

<p>"I'm a gun owner too, if somebody breaks in my house they're getting shot," Harris said with a laugh, before adding: &nbsp;"I probably shouldn't have said that... &nbsp;my staff will deal with that later."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Watch Live: Livestream event with Vice President Kamala Harris and Oprah Winfrey <a href="https://t.co/P8Rax1dAGk">https://t.co/P8Rax1dAGk</a></p>
 Kamala HQ (@KamalaHQ) <a href="https://twitter.com/KamalaHQ/status/1836914885587828940?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 19, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>TV superstar Winfrey, who also spoke at the Democratic National Convention in Chicago in August, said as she introduced Harris that she felt "hope and joy rising."</p>

<p>Groups including "Swifties for Harris" (made up of fans of Harris-backing pop star Taylor Swift) and "Cat Ladies for Kamala" (women mocking comments by Trump's running mate J.D. Vance on childless people) tuned in remotely.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The US election is effectively neck-and-neck as Harris and Trump try to eke out every vote with 47 days left until polling day.</p>

<p>Harris got a boost from a New York Times/Siena poll showing her marginally ahead in Pennsylvania, perhaps the most crucial of all the swing states, but the survey also put her and Trump level nationwide.</p>

<p>Her glitzy event contrasted with the darker tone taken by Trump at an anti-Semitism event in the capital, Washington.</p>

<p>Trump spent much of time repeating his grievance over the fact that Jewish voters in the United States have historically leant towards the Democrats.</p>

<p>"If I don't win this election... in my opinion the Jewish people would have a lot to do with a loss," Trump said.</p>

<p>Accusing Harris of failing to back Israel after the October 7 attacks by Hamas, Trump said that "more than any other people on Earth, Israel, I believe, has to defeat her."</p>

<p>Trump added that "any Jewish person that votes for her... should have their head examined."</p>

<p>The Gaza war could be a crucial one in the election.</p>

<p>The US "Uncommitted" movement, which opposes the Biden-Harris administration's military and political support for Israel's war on Gaza, said on Thursday it would not be backing Harris in the election.</p>

<p>It also threatens Harris's narrow margins in Michigan, where there is a large Arab-American community against the war.</p>

<p>Harris's running mate Tim Walz meanwhile on Thursday met with the families of Americans held hostage by Hamas since the attack.</p>

<p>He said after the meeting that Biden and Harris would "continue doing everything possible to bring them home."</p>

<p>Trump and Harris are also battling for support from US unions.</p>

<p>The powerful Teamsters union on Wednesday declined to endorse a presidential candidate, in a blow for Harris as it had a quarter century tradition of endorsing Democrats.</p>

<p>But Harris's campaign said however that local Teamsters branches representing one million people had since said they endorsed her.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/mjjmrfoo_kamala-harris_625x300_20_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[File photo]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/want-to-buy-iphone-16-heres-the-number-days-you-need-to-work-to-afford-it-6606865]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How Many Days Do People In Various Countries Need To Work To Buy iPhone 16]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/want-to-buy-iphone-16-heres-the-number-days-you-need-to-work-to-afford-it-6606865]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Sep 2024 09:48:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The new iPhone is now officially being sold in India. The brand new iPhone 16 may not completely fit into every budget, and a new study tells us exactly how many days of work will it take to save up for one, in any country.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The new iPhone is now officially being sold in India. The brand new iPhone 16 may not completely fit into every budget, and a new study tells us exactly how many days of work will it take to save up for one, in any country. The research shows there are countries where people need to work for more than three months in order to afford the iPhone 16.</p>

<p>According to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.picodi.com/us/bargain-hunting/iphone-index-2024">iPhone Index</a>, a person in Switzerland needs to work only 4 days to afford the iPhone 16. In contrast, an average American requires 5.1 days, while Australians and Singaporeans need 5.7 days.</p>

<p>In India, one needs to work 47.6 days to afford the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.gadgets360.com/mobiles/news/iphone-16-pro-max-plus-price-india-sale-date-specifications-features-6526758">new iPhone 16</a>.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/hed1bqho_iphone-index-2024_625x300_20_September_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>The iPhone Index, calculated based on the official prices of the iPhone 16 Pro (128 GB), is an annual index of iPhone price-to-wage ratios since 2018.</p>

<p>In India, iPhone 16 pricing starts at Rs 79,900, iPhone 16 Plus at Rs 89,900, iPhone 16 Pro at Rs 119,900, and iPhone 16 Pro Max at Rs 144,900.</p>

<p>The new iPhones are available at Apple retail and online stores in India, including Apple BKC (Mumbai) and Apple Saket (New Delhi), and through authorized sellers.</p>

<p>The company will roll out the US English version of the Apple Intelligence feature on the iPhone 16 series devices next month through a software update. Apple Intelligence will enable users to rewrite, proofread, and summarise text.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/6qceprbg_iphone-16-reuters_625x300_20_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The new iPhones are available at Apple retail and online stores in India.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-lebanon-hezbollah-pagers-walkie-talkies-banned-on-flights-from-lebanon-after-deadly-blasts-6606808]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Pagers, Walkie-Talkies Banned On Flights From Lebanon After Deadly Blasts]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-lebanon-hezbollah-pagers-walkie-talkies-banned-on-flights-from-lebanon-after-deadly-blasts-6606808]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Sep 2024 09:36:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Lebanon has banned walkie-talkies and pagers from flights departing Beirut airport. The decision, announced on Thursday, was made after walkie-talkies and pagers, reportedly used by Hezbollah members, detonated in a deadly attack.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lebanon has banned walkie-talkies and pagers from flights departing Beirut airport. The decision, announced on Thursday, was made after walkie-talkies and pagers, reportedly used by Hezbollah members, detonated in a deadly attack earlier this week, killing at least 37 people and injured thousands</p>

<p>According to Lebanon's National News Agency, the Civil Aviation Directorate instructed airlines operating out of Beirut Rafic Hariri International Airport (BEY) to inform passengers about the new restrictions. Both walkie-talkies and pagers are now prohibited in carry-on and checked luggage, as well as cargo shipments. The ban will remain in place until further notice, the agency reported.</p>

<p><strong>READ </strong>| <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-bombs-targets-in-lebanon-hours-after-hezbollahs-revenge-vow-6606329#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll">Hours After Hezbollah Chief's "Revenge" Vow, Israel Bombs Lebanon: 10 Facts</a></p>

<p>Two waves of explosions occurred on Tuesday and Wednesday, killing 37 and wounding more than 3,000 people, according to Lebanese health authorities. The explosions involved large caches of walkie-talkies and pagers, which Hezbollah, the Iran-backed militant group, reportedly used in their operations.</p>

<p>Lebanese officials have claimed that Israel was responsible for the attack, although Israel has yet to officially take credit. Hezbollah and Israel have been locked in an ongoing conflict, exchanging fire across the Lebanese-Israeli border for nearly a year.</p>

<p>Qatar Airways responded to the new directive, announcing it would enforce the ban on pagers and walkie-talkies for all flights from Beirut.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>READ </strong>|<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hezbollah-inside-lebanon-politics-hezbollah-iran-and-a-larger-battle-for-hegemony-6588884"> Inside Lebanon Politics: Hezbollah, Iran And A Larger Battle For Hegemony</a></p>

<p>"Effective immediately: Following the directive received from the Directorate General of Civil Aviation of the Republic of Lebanon, all passengers flying from Beirut Rafic Hariri International Airport (BEY) are prohibited from carrying pagers and walkie-talkies on board flights," the airline wrote. "The ban applies to both checked and carry-on luggage, as well as cargo, and will be enforced until further notice."</p>

<p>As tensions escalate between Hezbollah and Israel, the Israel Defense Forces (IDF) launched new airstrikes targeting Hezbollah strongholds in Lebanon on Thursday. In a statement posted on X, the IDF said it aimed to degrade Hezbollah's military capabilities and infrastructure. The Israeli military has been focusing on Hezbollah's network of tunnels and civilian homes in southern Lebanon, which the group allegedly uses for military operations.</p>

<p>"The IDF is currently striking Hezbollah targets in Lebanon to degrade Hezbollah's terrorist capabilities and infrastructure," the IDF said in the post. "For decades, Hezbollah has weaponized civilian homes, dug tunnels beneath them, and used civilians as human shields-having turned southern Lebanon into a war zone."</p>

<p>In an address on Thursday, Israeli Defense Minister Yoav Gallant declared the start of a "new phase" in Israel's ongoing conflict with Hezbollah. Gallant said that Israel is shifting resources and attention to the northern arena, aiming to bring security to the region and allow displaced residents to return to their homes.</p>

<p>"We are at the start of a new phase in the war," Gallant said in a social media post. "We are allocating resources and forces to the northern arena, and our mission is clear: ensuring the safe return of Israel's northern communities to their homes. To do so, the security situation must be changed."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/8va96iko_beirut-reuters_625x300_20_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Qatar Airways responded to the new directive, announcing it would enforce the ban.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mohamed-al-fayed-billionaire-whose-son-died-with-princess-diana-accused-of-multiple-rapes-6606526]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Mohamed Al-Fayed, Whose Son Died With Princess Diana, Accused Of Rape]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mohamed-al-fayed-billionaire-whose-son-died-with-princess-diana-accused-of-multiple-rapes-6606526]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Sep 2024 08:21:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former Harrods boss Mohamed Al-Fayed, whose son Emad El-Din "Dodi" Mohamed Fayed was killed in a 1997 Paris car crash alongside Princess Diana, has been accused of multiple rapes.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former Harrods boss Mohamed Al-Fayed, whose son Emad El-Din "Dodi" Mohamed Fayed was killed in a 1997 Paris car crash alongside Princess Diana, has been accused of multiple rapes. According to <em>The BBC</em>, five women have claimed that they were raped by the billionaire, who died last year aged 94, when they worked at the luxury London department store Harrods, which Al-Fayed owned from 1985 to 2010. The outlet revealed that it had heard testimonies from more than 20 former female staff members who claim the billionaire businessman sexually assaulted them, with the incidents allegedly taking place in London, St. Tropez, Abu Dhabi and Paris.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The allegations were laid out in a <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cz6x635wpjxo">BBC </a></em>documentary, titled <em>'Al-Fayed: Predator at Harrods'</em>. The documentary revealed that during Fayed's ownership, Harrods not only failed to intervene but helped cover up abuse allegations.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.harrods.com/en-gb/press">statement</a>, Harrods' current owners said they were "utterly appalled" by the allegations and that his victims had been failed - for which the store apologised.</p>

<p>"These were the actions of an individual who was intent on abusing his power wherever he operated and we condemn them in the strongest terms," the statement read. "We also acknowledge that during this time as a business, we failed our employees who were his victims and for this we sincerely apologise," it added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to <em>The BBC</em>, one woman has alleged that the billionaire raped her at his London apartment. "I made it obvious that I didn't want that to happen. I did not give consent. I just wanted it to be over," she told the outlet.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Another woman claimed that she was raped at the apartment in Mayfair when she was a teenager. "We were all scared. He actively cultivated fear," she said. "If he said 'jump' employees would ask 'how high'."</p>

<p>A woman named Sophia, who worked as Fayed's personal assistant from 1988 to 1991, says the billionaire tried to rape her more than once. "I couldn't leave. I didn't have a [family] home to go back to, I had to pay rent," she said. "I knew I had to go through this and I didn't want to. It was horrible and my head was scrambled," she added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Another of his personal assistants, Gemma, who worked for Fayed from 2007 to 2009, claimed he raped her at Villa Windsor in Paris, a former home of King Edward VIII and his wife Wallis Simpson. She said that as part of the agreement for her leaving the job, she had to shred all evidence and sign a non-disclosure agreement (NDA) in return for a sum of money. Ms Gemma told the outlet that a shredding truck came to her lawyer's office and a member of HR from Harrods was present.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-pm-accepted-132-000-in-gifts-including-taylor-swift-and-football-tickets-6603625">UK PM Accepted $132,000 In Gifts, Including Taylor Swift And Football Tickets</a></strong></p>

<p>Tony Leeming, a former Harrods department manager of 10 years, said that he was aware of the abuse of women on the shop floor, but claimed he did not know about the allegations of assault or rape. Mr Leeming's testimony is backed by former members of Fayed's security team.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"We were aware that he had this very strong interest in young girls," said Eamon Coyle, who joined Harrods in 1979 as a store detective, then became deputy director of security from 1989-95.</p>

<p>Many women told the <em>BBC </em>that when they began working directly for Fayed they underwent medicals - including invasive sexual health tests carried out by doctors. The outlet also reported that before his death, the billionaire faced a number of sexual assault claims in 1997, 2008 and 2017.</p>

<p>Of the women the outlet spoke to for the investigation, a total of 14 have brought civil claims against Harrods for damages. The department store's current owners started settling these in July 2023, according to the outlet.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Notably, Fayed, born in Egypt, moved to the United Kingdom in 1974 and was already a well-known public figure when he took over Harrods in 1985. His son Dodi was killed in a car crash alongside Princess Diana in 1997. He has become known to a new generation through the two most recent Netflix series of 'The Crown'.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-09/cd3l3p0o_mohamed-alfayed-afp_625x300_02_September_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The allegations were laid out in a BBC documentary, titled 'Al-Fayed: Predator at Harrods'.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>