<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Mon, 26 Aug 2024 01:27:25 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-rejects-new-conditions-in-us-led-gaza-ceasefire-talks-6417199]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hamas Rejects "New Conditions" In US-Led Gaza Ceasefire Talks]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-rejects-new-conditions-in-us-led-gaza-ceasefire-talks-6417199]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 26 Aug 2024 00:03:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hamas said Friday it rejected "new conditions" in a Gaza ceasefire proposal that US-led mediators presented during two days of talks in Qatar.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hamas said Friday it rejected "new conditions" in a Gaza ceasefire proposal that US-led mediators presented during two days of talks in Qatar.</p>

<p>Diplomatic efforts have so far failed to alleviate the suffering endured over more than 10 months of war, but US President Joe Biden insisted after the latest round of talks that "we are closer than we have ever been".</p>

<p>He is sending US Secretary of State Antony Blinken to Israel this weekend to push the latest proposal, the State Department said.</p>

<p>Egyptian, Qatari and US mediators have been seeking to finalise details of a framework initially outlined by Biden in May, which he said Israel had proposed.</p>

<p>In a joint statement, the mediators said they had presented both sides with a proposal that "bridges remaining gaps" and will continue working in the coming days to hash out the specifics on humanitarian provisions and the hostage-prisoners swap.</p>

<p>Talks aiming to secure a rapid deal are set to resume in Cairo "before the end of next week".</p>

<p>Hamas, which did not attend the Doha talks, swiftly announced its opposition to what it called "new conditions" from Israel in the latest plan.</p>

<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu called on mediators to "pressure" Hamas to accept Biden's framework.</p>

<p>Threats by Iran and its proxies to attack Israel have added renewed urgency to the efforts to hammer out a Gaza ceasefire, with mediators seeking a deal in the hopes of dousing a wider regional conflict.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"No one in the region should take actions to undermine this process," Biden warned, later telling reporters, "There's just a couple more issues, I think we've got a shot."</p>

<p>- 'Cataclysmic' consequences -<br />
An informed source told AFP Hamas had objected to conditions about keeping Israeli troops on Gaza's border with Egypt and terms related to the release of Palestinian prisoners in exchange for Israeli hostages.</p>

<p>Western ally Jordan, however, put the blame squarely on Netanyahu for blocking a deal, with Foreign Minister Ayman Safadi urging pressure "by everyone who wishes to see this through to completion".</p>

<p>British Foreign Secretary David Lammy and his French counterpart Stephane Sejourne held talks in Israel on Friday to press the deal.</p>

<p>Israeli Foreign Minister Israel Katz told his visiting counterparts he expects foreign support if Iran seeks to avenge the assassination of Hamas leader Ismail Haniyeh in Tehran.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Sejourne replied that it would be "inappropriate" to discuss responding to any attack while diplomacy to stop it from happening is in high gear.</p>

<p>A senior US official, speaking to reporters on condition of anonymity, said Iran would face "cataclysmic" consequences if it strikes Israel.</p>

<p>A deadly attack by Israeli settlers in the occupied West Bank late Thursday drew international condemnation and calls for sanctions, including against government ministers, over the surge in settler violence against Palestinians since the Gaza war began.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said "dozens of Israeli civilians, some of them masked", entered the village of Jit and "set fire to vehicles and structures in the area, hurled rocks and Molotov cocktails". A Palestinian man was shot dead.</p>

<p>The West Bank-based Palestinian foreign ministry described the attack as "organised state terrorism".</p>

<p>The European Union's top diplomat, Josep Borrell, said he would propose sanctions against Israeli government "enablers" of Jewish settler violence.</p>

<p>Israeli far-right Finance Minister Bezalel Smotrich, a proponent of West Bank settlements, was quick to join other Israeli leaders in condemning Thursday's attack by "criminals".</p>

<p>First polio case recorded</p>

<p><br />
Hamas's unprecedented October 7 attack on Israel that triggered the war resulted in the deaths of 1,198 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally of Israeli official figures.</p>

<p>Militants also seized 251 hostages, 111 of whom are still held in Gaza, including 39 the military says are dead. More than 100 were freed during a one-week truce in November.</p>

<p>On Thursday, the toll from Israel's retaliatory military campaign topped 40,000, according to the health ministry in Hamas-run Gaza, which does not provide a breakdown of civilian and militant casualties.</p>

<p>The war has devastated the besieged territory's healthcare infrastructure, prompting repeated warnings from the World Health Organization about the risk of preventable diseases.</p>

<p>On Friday, the Palestinian health ministry reported an unvaccinated 10-month-old child in Gaza had been diagnosed with polio, the territory's first case in 25 years, according to the WHO.</p>

<p>The announcement came hours after UN chief Antonio Guterres called for two seven-day breaks in the Gaza war to vaccinate more than 640,000 children against type 2 poliovirus, which was first detected in the territory's wastewater in June.</p>

<p>As truce talks were underway, thousands of civilians were on the move again inside the Palestinian territory after the Israeli military issued fresh evacuation orders ahead of imminent military action.</p>

<p>The UN estimated the orders affect more than 170,000 people, forcing them to pack into the shrinking remnants of an area declared a humanitarian safe zone.</p>

<p>The area where people have been told to relocate to makes up just 11 percent of Gaza, according to the UN.</p>

<p>"During each round of negotiations, they exert pressure by forcing evacuations and committing massacres," Issa Murad, a Palestinian displaced to Deir al-Balah, said of the Israeli forces.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/4dmff0tg_israel-hamas-war_625x300_31_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hamas did not attend the ceasefire talks that took place in Doha, Qatar. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/102-year-old-woman-becomes-uks-oldest-skydiver-6417089]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[102-Year-Old Woman Becomes UK's Oldest Skydiver]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/102-year-old-woman-becomes-uks-oldest-skydiver-6417089]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 25 Aug 2024 23:35:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A British woman on Sunday celebrated her 102nd birthday by skydiving out of a plane and said she hoped her daredevil antics might inspire other elderly people to stay active.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A British woman on Sunday celebrated her 102nd birthday by skydiving out of a plane and said she hoped her daredevil antics might inspire other elderly people to stay active.</p>

<p>Manette Baillie said it was "a bit scary", adding "I must admit I shut my eyes very firmly."</p>

<p>Baillie told BBC radio she just wanted "other people who are getting towards 80 and 90 not to give up anything. Just keep going".</p>

<p>It's not the first time the centenarian from the village of Benhall Green in eastern England has taken on a daredevil challenge.</p>

<p>She drove around the Silverstone motor racing circuit in a Ferrari at 210 kilometres per hour (130 miles per hour) to mark her 100th birthday two years ago.</p>

<p>The skydive at Beccles Airfield involved Baillie jumping from a height of more than 2,100 metres (6,900 feet), with an assistant strapped into the harness with her.</p>

<p>Baillie said earlier she had been spurred into action after hearing about a friend's 85-year-old father who had done a skydive.</p>

<p>"If an 85-year-old man can do it, so can I," she said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/0k2gthpg_uk-woman-skydiving_625x300_25_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["If an 85-year-old man can do it, so can I," Manette Baillie said.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/dont-give-smartphones-to-kids-under-11-uk-network-operator-warns-parents-6417033]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Don't Give Smartphones To Kids Under 11, UK Network Operator Warns Parents]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/dont-give-smartphones-to-kids-under-11-uk-network-operator-warns-parents-6417033]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 25 Aug 2024 23:23:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[One of Britain's biggest mobile network operators said on Sunday it will warn parents they should not give smartphones to children under the age of 11.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>One of Britain's biggest mobile network operators said on Sunday it will warn parents they should not give smartphones to children under the age of 11.</p>

<p>The new guidance comes after growing concern from parents about the potential pitfalls of smartphone access for young people.</p>

<p>A recent study by the UK communications regulator found around a quarter of British children aged between five and seven-years-old now had a smartphone.</p>

<p>EE will say in new guidance that children should only be given phones with "limited capability devices" allowing them only to text and call.</p>

<p>It will also advise enabling parental control features for teens under the age of 16 and restrictions on social media for the under-13s.</p>

<p>UK parents have increasingly started to push back against the trend of giving children one of the devices when they transfer from primary to secondary school at the age of 11.</p>

<p>Widely justified on safety grounds in case of an emergency on the way to or from school, parents fear the phones also potentially open children up to online predators, bullying, social pressure and harmful content.</p>

<p>"While technology and connectivity have the power to transform lives, we recognise the growing complexity of smartphones can be challenging for parents and caregivers," said Mat Sears, EE corporate affairs director.</p>

<p>"They need support, which is why we are launching new guidelines on smartphone usage for under 11s, 11 to 13-year-olds, and 13 to 16-year-olds to help them make the best choices for their children through these formative years."</p>

<p>US author Jonathan Haidt -- whose recent book "The Anxious Generation" argued that smartphones have rewired children's brains -- has urged parents to act together on smartphone access so it becomes the norm for children not to have one.</p>

<p>A child "breaks our heart" by telling us they are excluded from their peer group by being the only one without a phone, he said earlier this year.</p>

<p>Mr Haidt advocates for no smart phones before the age of 14 or social media before 16.</p>

<p>"These things are hard to do as one parent. But if we all do it together -- if even half of us do it together -- then it becomes much easier for our kids," he added.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-03/qnsv9sm8_smartphone_625x300_12_March_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A study found that 25% of British children aged between 5 and 7 now had a smartphone. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/attacker-armed-with-boxcutter-goes-on-stabbing-spree-in-australia-4-injured-police-6416360]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Attacker Goes On Stabbing Spree In Australia, 4 Injured: Police]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/attacker-armed-with-boxcutter-goes-on-stabbing-spree-in-australia-4-injured-police-6416360]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 25 Aug 2024 21:10:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Four people including a police officer were injured in a stabbing attack in Sydney early on Sunday, police said, the latest in a series of knife assaults in Australia's biggest city this year.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Four people including a police officer were injured in a stabbing attack in Sydney early on Sunday, police said, the latest in a series of knife assaults in Australia's biggest city this year.</p>

<p>A man who ran from the scene has been taken into custody, police said in a statement. There is no ongoing threat to people in Sydney, said New South Wales state Police Minister Yasmin Catley.</p>

<p>Police said no one was killed in the attack, which came after a "domestic-related" incident in a car that collided with another vehicle in the southern suburb of Engadine.</p>

<p>The attacker "was armed with what we believe to be a boxcutter," police superintendent Donald Faulds said in a televised press conference.</p>

<p>Aerial footage of the scene by the Australian Broadcasting Corp showed two crashed cars cordoned off with police tape.</p>

<p>Sydney, a city of 5 million, has seen a spate of knife attacks this year, prompting the New South Wales government to toughen its knife laws. The state parliament passed laws in June giving police electronic metal-detecting scanners to check people without a warrant at shopping centres, sporting venues and public transport stations.</p>

<p>In April, six people were killed and 12 injured in a knife attack at a mall in Sydney's Bondi area.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-12/jfqvbh78_sydney-harbour-bridge-bloomberg_625x300_22_December_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sydney has seen a spate of knife attacks this year. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/famous-indian-origin-doctor-ramesh-babu-peramsetty-shot-dead-in-us-tuscaloosa-6416304]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Famous Indian-Origin Doctor Shot Dead In US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/famous-indian-origin-doctor-ramesh-babu-peramsetty-shot-dead-in-us-tuscaloosa-6416304]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 25 Aug 2024 20:59:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An Indian-origin doctor was shot in US in Tuscaloosa on Friday. The victim, identified as Dr Ramesh Babu Peramsetty, died on the spot.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An Indian-origin doctor was shot in US in Tuscaloosa, a city in Alabama, on Friday. The victim, identified as Dr Ramesh Babu Peramsetty, died on the spot. He was a renowned physician who operated several hospitals in America.</p>

<p>Dr Ramesh, who was from Andhra Pradesh's Tirupati district, was one of the founders and medical director of a group of local medical officers operating as the Crimson Network. He was known for his contributions in the field of healthcare and also practiced as a physician in Tuscaloosa.</p>

<p>"As many are aware at this moment, we have been informed of Dr. Ramesh Peramsetty's passing. The Peramsetty family ask for us to give them privacy as they grieve his passing. They have received abundant outpouring of love and faith. We will continue to honor him as he would want us to do. Thank you for your understanding," the Crimson Care Network Team said in a Facebook post. (sic)</p>

<p>The Crimson Care Network said its team "is prepared to make more statements within the next few days."</p>

<h3><strong>Who Was Dr Ramesh Babu Peramsetty?</strong></h3>

<p>Dr Peramsetty graduated from the Medical College of Wisconsin, Sri Venkateswara Medical College in 1986, according to his Wedmd page. He had 38 years of experience.</p>

<p>He worked in Tuscaloosa and four other locations and was specialised in Emergency Medicine and Family Medicine, it says. He was also affiliated with Diploma in Child Health (DCH) Regional Medical Center.</p>

<p>As per local reports, a street in Tuscaloosa was named after him due to his significant contributions in the medical profession. He also did extensive work during the Covid-19 pandemic and also received awards for the same, reports suggest. He is survived by his wife, two sons and two daughters and all are settled in the US, as per reports.</p>

<p>He donated Rs 14 lakh to Menakuru High School in Andhra Pradesh where he studied and also for the construction of a Sai temple in his village, according to reports.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/hktfeugo_dr-ramesh-babu-peramsetty_625x300_25_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Dr Ramesh Babu Peramsetty had 38 years of experience]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-solidarity-with-sudan-us-rapper-macklemore-cancels-dubai-show-over-uae-role-in-sudan-war-6416286]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Rapper Macklemore Cancels Dubai Show Over UAE Role In Sudan War]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-solidarity-with-sudan-us-rapper-macklemore-cancels-dubai-show-over-uae-role-in-sudan-war-6416286]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 25 Aug 2024 20:55:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US rapper Macklemore has announced he is cancelling an upcoming show in Dubai over the UAE's involvement in the conflict in Sudan, charges the Gulf state has denied.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US rapper Macklemore has announced he is cancelling an upcoming show in Dubai over the UAE's involvement in the conflict in Sudan, charges the Gulf state has denied.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The rapper best known for hits like 2012's "Thrift Shop" made the announcement in a post on social media on Saturday.</p>

<p>"I have decided to cancel my upcoming show in Dubai this October," he said.</p>

<p>"Over the last several months I've had a number of people reach out to me, sharing resources and asking me to cancel the show in solidarity with the people of Sudan," he said.</p>

<p>"Until the UAE stops arming and funding the RSF I will not perform there," Macklemore added, referring to the paramilitary Rapid Support Forces that have been battling the Sundanese army.</p>

<p>War has raged since April 2023 between the Sudanese army, under the country's de facto ruler Abdel Fattah al-Burhan, and the RSF, which is commanded by Burhan's former deputy Mohamed Hamdan Daglo.&nbsp;</p>

<p>For months, the army has accused the UAE of supporting the RSF.</p>

<p>In June, Sudan's ambassador to the United Nations Al-Harith Idriss al-Harith Mohamed called Abu Dhabi's financial and military support for the RSF the "main reason behind this protracted war".</p>

<p>The UAE has denied allegations of RSF support as "disinformation", saying that it's efforts are focused exclusively towards de-escalation and alleviating Sudan's humanitarian suffering.</p>

<p>Macklemore has released socially aware music in the past, supporting LGBTQ+ rights while also criticising ills including poverty and consumerism.</p>

<p>In his latest track released in May, Macklemore voices support for Palestinians and also praises students across the United States protesting against Israel's war in Gaza.</p>

<p>The song, "Hind's Hall", is named after a building at Columbia University that students recently occupied and renamed after Hind Rajab, a six-year-old Palestinian girl killed in Gaza.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/1co8gsf_macklemore-reuters_625x300_25_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[In his latest song, Macklemore voiced support for Palestinians.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hezbollah-israeli-prime-minister-benjamin-netanyahu-warns-strikes-in-lebanon-are-not-final-word-6415892]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel PM Warns Strikes In Lebanon Are Not "Final Word"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hezbollah-israeli-prime-minister-benjamin-netanyahu-warns-strikes-in-lebanon-are-not-final-word-6415892]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 25 Aug 2024 19:46:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu warned that Sunday's strikes in Lebanon were "not the final word" in his country's military campaign against Lebanese armed group Hezbollah.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu warned that Sunday's strikes in Lebanon were "not the final word" in his country's military campaign against Lebanese armed group Hezbollah.</p>

<p>"We are striking Hezbollah with surprising, crushing blows... This is another step towards changing the situation in the north and safely returning our residents to their homes. And, I repeat, this is not the final word," Netanyahu told a cabinet meeting.</p>

<p>He said the military destroyed thousands of "short-range rockets, all of which were intended to harm our civilians and forces in the Galilee".</p>

<p>"Additionally, the IDF (Israeli military) intercepted all the drones that Hezbollah launched at a strategic target in central Israel," he said, without identifying what the target was.</p>

<p>Israeli media however reported the target Hezbollah aimed to strike was the headquarters of the Israeli Mossad spy agency near Tel Aviv.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/435p3ito_benjamin-netanyahu_625x300_21_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israeli military intercepted all the drones that Hezbollah launched, Benjamin Netanyahu said.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-strikes-a-slap-in-the-face-for-israel-says-hamas-6415836]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hezbollah Strikes "A Slap In The Face" For Israel, Says Hamas]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-strikes-a-slap-in-the-face-for-israel-says-hamas-6415836]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 25 Aug 2024 19:34:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Palestinian Islamist movement Hamas on Sunday hailed strikes by Lebanon's Hezbollah against Israel, calling it a "strong and focused response".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Palestinian Islamist movement Hamas on Sunday hailed strikes by Lebanon's Hezbollah against Israel, calling it a "strong and focused response".</p>

<p>"We emphasize that this strong and focused response, which struck deep inside the Zionist entity, is a slap in the face" for the Israeli government, Hamas said in a statement after Hezbollah said it launched a large-scale operation using rockets and drones.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/j0g60nng_israel-hezbollah-afp_625x300_25_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel launched a pre-emptive strike on Lebanon on Sunday]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/zuckerberg-should-be-arrested-for-massive-child-exploitation-on-instagram-musk-6415730]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["But No Arrest For Zuckerberg...": Elon Musk Wants Telegram CEO Freed]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/zuckerberg-should-be-arrested-for-massive-child-exploitation-on-instagram-musk-6415730]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 25 Aug 2024 19:18:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Tesla and SpaceX CEO Elon Musk on Sunday came out in support of Telegram Founder Pavel Durov, saying Mark Zuckerberg should instead be arrested for "massive child exploitation" problem on his Meta-owned Instagram.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Tesla and SpaceX CEO Elon Musk on Sunday came out in support of Telegram Founder Pavel Durov, saying Mark Zuckerberg should instead be arrested for "massive child exploitation" problem on his Meta-owned Instagram.</p>

<p>The billionaire reacted after Russian-born Pavel Durov, founder and owner of the popular encrypted messaging app Telegram, was arrested in France over numerous charges related to his platform, and faces up to 20 years in prison if convicted.</p>

<p>Mr Musk said that Meta Founder Mark Zuckerberg has "already caved into censorship pressure".</p>

<p>"Instagram has a massive child exploitation problem, but no arrest for Zuck, as he censors free speech and gives governments backdoor access to user data," the X owner posted.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Because he already caved into censorship pressure.<br />
<br />
Instagram has a massive child exploitation problem, but no arrest for Zuck, as he censors free speech and gives governments backdoor access to user data. <a href="https://t.co/RTTGIaD0gA">https://t.co/RTTGIaD0gA</a> <a href="https://t.co/iPb5NIxIJN">https://t.co/iPb5NIxIJN</a></p>
— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1827647414020211016?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 25, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>He further said that "It's 2030 in Europe and you're being executed for liking a meme".</p>

<p>"It is vital to the support of free speech that you forward X posts to people you know, especially in censorship-heavy countries," the tech billionaire mentioned.</p>

<p>In February this year, Mr Zuckerberg apologised to the families of victims of online child sex abuse during a Senate hearing on Capitol Hill.</p>

<p>The billionaire entrepreneur told parents that "I'm sorry for everything you have all been through. No one should go through the things that your families have suffered".</p>

<p>"And this is why we invest so much and we are going to continue doing industry-wide efforts to make sure no one has to go through the things your families have had to suffer," he added.</p>

<p>In May this year, Mr Musk said that Zuckerberg-run Meta is "super greedy" at taking credit for advertisers who run campaigns on its platform.</p>

<p>The X owner replied that "we are terrible at claiming credit, and Meta is super greedy at claiming credit."</p>

<p>The rivalry between Mr Musk and Mr Zuckerberg is well known. They were apparently set for a "cage fight' some time back -- dubbed as the fight of the century. However, the much-anticipated showdown between the duo was cancelled.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-07/fi20bt2k_elon-musk-mark-zuckerberg_625x300_07_July_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Elon Musk said that Mark Zuckerberg has "already caved into censorship pressure".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/syrian-man-confesses-to-killing-3-in-germany-stabbing-attack-6415186]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Syrian Man Confesses To Killing 3 In Germany Stabbing Attack]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/syrian-man-confesses-to-killing-3-in-germany-stabbing-attack-6415186]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 25 Aug 2024 17:33:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[German police said Sunday that a Syrian man has given himself up and confessed to killing three people and wounding eight others in a knife rampage at a street festival.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>German police said Sunday that a Syrian man has given himself up and confessed to killing three people and wounding eight others in a knife rampage at a street festival.</p>

<p>The random attack as thousands of people gathered on Friday night in the western city of Solingen has stunned Germany.</p>

<p>Two men aged 56 and 67 and a 56-year-old woman were killed, officials said. Four of the wounded remained in a serious condition. All of the victims were stabbed in the neck, according to police.</p>

<p>Police said in a statement that the suspect was a 26-year-old Syrian who had "given himself up to authorities... and declared himself responsible for the attack".</p>

<p>Officers arrested a suspect in a raid at a hostel for asylum seekers on Saturday, not far from the scene of the attack, a police spokesman told AFP.</p>

<p>Police have evidence linking the man to the knife attacks, according to North Rhine-Westphalia state interior minister Herbert Reul. Federal prosecutors have launched an investigation into charges of "participating in a terrorist organisation", a spokesman said.</p>

<p>According to the Bild and Spiegel newspapers, the suspect arrived in Germany in December 2022 and had a protected immigration status often given to those fleeing war-torn Syria.</p>

<p>He was not known to the security services as an extremist, the newspapers reported.</p>

<p><strong>Teen arrested&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p>Police have also arrested a 15-year-old suspected of failing to report a criminal act. Witnesses allegedly saw the teen discussing the attack, said Markus Caspers, prosecutor of Duesseldorf, just west of Solingen.</p>

<p>The attack took place as thousands of people gathered for the first night of a "Festival of Diversity", part of a series of events to mark Solingen's 650th anniversary. The whole festival has now been cancelled.</p>

<p>Germany has been on high alert for extremist attacks since the Gaza war erupted on October 7 with the Hamas attacks on Israel.</p>

<p>German street festivals and markets have previously been hit.</p>

<p>A truck rampage at a Berlin Christmas market in 2016 killed 12 people. In May, a police officer was killed and five people were wounded in a knife attack at a far-right rally in Mannheim, with an Islamist motive suspected.</p>

<p>The jihadist Islamic State group's Amaq propaganda arm said "the perpetrator of the attack on a gathering of Christians" in Solingen "was a soldier of the Islamic State".</p>

<p>IS said the attack was carried out as "revenge for Muslims in Palestine and everywhere", in an apparent reference to the Gaza conflict.</p>

<p>The claim could not be immediately verified, though German officials had said "a terrorist motive cannot be excluded".</p>

<p>Interior Minister Nancy Faeser had warned this month that Germany was in "the firing line" of Islamist groups.</p>

<p>National and local leaders, including Chancellor Olaf Scholz, said the country had been "deeply shocked" by the deaths in Solingen, a city of 160,000 people.</p>

<p>Witness Lars Breitzke told the Solinger Tageblatt newspaper he was near the attack, close to the main stage, and "understood from the expression on the singer's face that something was wrong".</p>

<p>"And then, a metre away from me, a person fell," said Breitzke, who at first thought it was someone who had had too much to drink.&nbsp;</p>

<p>When he turned around, he saw other people on the ground in pools of blood.</p>

<p>During a visit to the site of the tragedy Faeser called for the country to "remain united" as she denounced "those who want to stir up hatred".&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Let us not be divided," she said.</p>

<p>Scholz's centre-left coalition faces regional elections next week in the east of the country, where the far-right AfD is leading in polls.</p>

<p>Germany took in more than a million asylum seekers in 2015-2016 at the height of Europe's migrant crisis.</p>

<p>The influx was deeply divisive in Germany and fuelled the popularity of the AfD.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/irump6t_germany-festival-stabbing-victims_625x300_25_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Police said in a statement that the suspect was a 26-year-old Syrian]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/haunting-titanic-newspaper-discovered-in-wardrobe-after-112-years-6415076]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Haunting Titanic Newspaper Discovered In Wardrobe After 112 Years]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/haunting-titanic-newspaper-discovered-in-wardrobe-after-112-years-6415076]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 25 Aug 2024 17:15:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Titanic, famously touted as "practically unsinkable" before its maiden voyage, remains one of the deadliest maritime disasters in history.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A newspaper chronicling the devastating human toll of the Titanic sinking has been uncovered after 112 years in a wardrobe. The edition of the <em>Daily Mirror</em>, dated April 20, 1912-five days after the tragedy-was discovered in a home in Lichfield, Staffordshire. Its front-page story depicts the anguish of passengers' relatives in Southampton, anxiously awaiting news of their loved ones from the list of survivors, the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/home-news/titanic-sink-newspaper-wardrobe-auction-how-much-b2600091.html"><em>Independent </em></a>reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://hansonsauctioneers.co.uk/suffering-of-british-families-with-loved-ones-on-titanic-revealed-by-newspaper-found-in-wardrobe-after-112-years/"><em>Hanson's Auctioneers</em></a>, who sold the newspaper this week, described the find as a "valuable piece of social history."</p>

<p>Charles Hanson, the auction house's owner, remarked, "The sinking of the Titanic has been extensively documented in films, TV shows, and books, and we know much about the lives lost. This discovery serves as a poignant reminder of the many bereaved families and friends-heartbroken mothers, fathers, and wives."</p>

<p>The Titanic, famously touted as "practically unsinkable" before its maiden voyage, remains one of the deadliest maritime disasters in history. Over 1,500 people perished when the ship struck an iceberg in the North Atlantic, with only around 700 survivors. Although the ship was equipped with too few lifeboats, many were launched half-empty due to the widespread belief that the Titanic could not sink.</p>

<p>Southampton, home to the majority of the ship's crew, was particularly hard hit by the disaster. The Daily Mirror described the scene outside the White Star Line's offices, where lists of survivors were posted: "A list of the saved was posted outside the White Star offices, and mothers and wives who had been hoping against hope eagerly read the names, only to find their worst fears were realized. By this appalling disaster, mothers have been robbed of sons, wives of husbands, and young girls of sweethearts."</p>

<p>The newspaper called the publication of the survivors' list "a terrible day in the history of the town, though it put an end to all suspense." The cover story was supplemented by a two-page spread featuring photographs of victims, including Titanic's captain, Edward Smith.</p>

<p>This piece of maritime and social history sold at auction for 34 pounds on Tuesday, August 20. The auctioneer noted that while accounts of the sinking often focus on the victims, the newspaper's emphasis on the families left behind is what makes it so compelling. "When you see the faces of those affected, it's very moving," Mr. Hanson added.</p>

<p>The newspaper was found alongside other historical documents, including those covering King George V's coronation in 1911.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/dnhsudc8_titanic-newspaper-article_625x300_25_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[This piece of maritime and social history sold at auction for 34 pounds on Tuesday, August 20.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hezbollah-missile-exchange-how-israel-vs-hezbollah-unfolded-in-the-skies-6414952]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Video: How Israel vs Hezbollah Unfolded In The Skies]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hezbollah-missile-exchange-how-israel-vs-hezbollah-unfolded-in-the-skies-6414952]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 25 Aug 2024 16:50:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Lebanon-based armed group Hezbollah launched hundreds of rockets and drones at Israel today after Israel's military said it initiated pre-emptive strikes on targets in Lebanon.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lebanon-based armed group Hezbollah launched hundreds of rockets and drones at Israel today after Israel's military said it initiated pre-emptive strikes on targets in Lebanon, stating that they had detected preparations by Hezbollah for "large-scale" attacks on Israeli territory.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Israel said its military deployed fighter jets that destroyed "thousands" of Hezbollah rocket launchers in south Lebanon that were aimed at northern and central Israel.</p>

<p>"Approximately 100 IAF fighter jets struck and eliminated thousands of Hezbollah rocket launcher barrels, aimed for immediate fire toward northern and central Israel. More than 40 Hezbollah launch areas were struck. We will do whatever is needed to defend our civilians and the State of Israel," the Israel Defense Forces (IDF) posted on X.</p>

<p>Pictures emerged of an Israeli fighter jet firing flares as it tried to intercept a hostile aircraft that was launched from Lebanon over the border area with south Lebanon.&nbsp;Israel conducted an airstrike on the town of Zibqin in south Lebanon. Visuals showed smoke billowing from the site of the airstrike.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/6fq9u22_israel-hezbollah-afp_625x300_25_August_24.jpeg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" />
<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/j0g60nng_israel-hezbollah-afp_625x300_25_August_24.jpeg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" />
<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/5vbccfmg_israel-hezbollah-afp_625x300_25_August_24.jpeg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>

<p>"We are still operating to thwart real-time threats. IDF fighter jets have just struck additional Hezbollah launchers in several areas in southern Lebanon and a terrorist cell operating in the area of Khiam in southern Lebanon," IDF wrote on X.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">We are still operating to thwart real-time threats.<br />
<br />
IDF fighter jets have just struck additional Hezbollah launchers in several areas in southern Lebanon and a terrorist cell operating in the area of Khiam in southern Lebanon. <a href="https://t.co/j6E1WNwb4d">pic.twitter.com/j6E1WNwb4d</a></p>
— Israel Defense Forces (@IDF) <a href="https://twitter.com/IDF/status/1827621989852311685?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 25, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>Israeli aircraft were seen intercepting Hezbollah drones over north Israel early Sunday morning. Hezbollah, an Iran-backed group, said its militants "began an air attack with a large number of drones" sent across the border, followed by "more than 320" Katyusha rockets that hit 11 military targets.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/dfacgns8_israel-hezbollah-afp_625x300_25_August_24.jpeg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" />
<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/icpttt8o_israel-hezbollah-afp_625x300_25_August_24.jpeg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>

<p>The Lebanese movement said its attack was an "initial response" to the assassination of its military commander Fuad Shukr last month, adding the attack &nbsp;had "ended with total success".</p>

<p>Israel's Defense Minister Yoav Gallant declared a state of emergency and Foreign Minister Israel Katz said Israel would respond to developments on the ground but did not seek a full-scale war.</p>

<p>As a precautionary measure, flights to and from Ben Gurion International Airport in Tel Aviv were suspended for around 90 minutes.</p>

<p>The United Nations peacekeeping force in Lebanon and the UN's special coordinator's office in the country called on all sides to cease fire, calling the developments overnight "worrying".</p>

<p>Responding to the developments, the US said it "will keep supporting Israel's right to defend itself". National Security Council spokesperson Sean Savett said, "At President Joe Biden's direction, senior US officials have been communicating continuously with their Israeli counterparts. We will keep supporting Israel's right to defend itself, and we will keep working for regional stability."</p>

<p>Today's escalation is one of many between Israel and Hezbollah that began after Hamas's unprecedented attack on southern Israel on October 7 last year, which led to the outbreak of the Gaza war.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/891mr9b_israel-hezbollah-afp_625x300_25_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hezbollah said its attack was an "initial response" to the killing of its military commander Fuad Shukr]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/indians-abroad/andhra-woman-swept-away-in-malaysia-sewage-drain-after-footpath-collapses-6414411]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Andhra Woman Swept Away In Malaysia Sewage Drain After Footpath Collapses]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/indians-abroad/andhra-woman-swept-away-in-malaysia-sewage-drain-after-footpath-collapses-6414411]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 25 Aug 2024 15:09:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 45-year-old woman from Andhra Pradesh has gone missing in Malaysia's capital Kuala Lumpur after being swept away into a sewage drain after the footpath she was walking on collapsed suddenly.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 45-year-old woman from Andhra Pradesh has gone missing in Malaysia's capital Kuala Lumpur after being swept away into a sewage drain after the footpath she was walking on collapsed suddenly.</p>

<p>The woman, identified as Vijayalakshmi from Chittoor district's &nbsp;Animiganipalle village, was reportedly walking along a footpath when the ground collapsed. While her husband and son managed to escape the collapse, she was swept into the underground sewer.</p>

<p>Rescue operations were launched immediately by the civic authorities in Kuala Lumpur and are ongoing. Despite their efforts, there was no sign of Vijayalakshmi as of Saturday evening.</p>

<p>Vijayalakshmi was known for frequently travelling to Malaysia and Singapore as part of her business.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In response to the incident, Andhra Pradesh Chief Minister N Chandrababu Naidu has directed officials from the Andhra Pradesh Non-Resident Telugu (APNRT) Society to ensure that the search operations are conducted effectively.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Chief Minister, along with Minister for Human Resource Development (HRD) Nara Lokesh, has been closely monitoring the situation.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/emfs17ao_andhra-woman_625x300_25_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The woman was swept into the underground sewer (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-the-iran-backed-group-that-once-went-to-month-long-war-with-israel-6414342]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hezbollah: The Iran-Backed Group That Once Went To Month-Long War With Israel]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-the-iran-backed-group-that-once-went-to-month-long-war-with-israel-6414342]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 25 Aug 2024 14:55:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hezbollah, which has exchanged fire with Israeli forces since October, last went to war with Israel in 2006 and has since expanded its domestic and regional influence, politically and militarily.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hezbollah, which has exchanged fire with Israeli forces since October, last went to war with Israel in 2006 and has since expanded its domestic and regional influence, politically and militarily.</p>

<p>Financed and armed by Iran, Hezbollah is the most prominent actor in the so-called axis of resistance -- regional pro-Tehran armed groups opposed to Israel that also include Palestinian group Hamas, Iraqi movements, and Yemen's Huthi rebels.</p>

<p>Since the day after Hamas's October 7 attack on Israel that triggered war in the Gaza Strip, Hezbollah has launched cross-border attacks from Lebanon seeking to tie up Israeli military resources in support of its Palestinian ally.</p>

<p>Fears of all-out war have spiked after Hezbollah vowed to avenge an Israeli strike on Beirut's southern suburbs last month that killed a key commander, Fuad Shukr, and Iran pledged retaliation for the killing in Tehran, blamed on Israel, of Hamas's political chief Ismail Haniyeh.</p>

<h3><strong>Hezbollah-Israel War</strong></h3>

<p>Hezbollah, whose name means "Party of God" in Arabic, was founded during the Lebanese civil war after Israel besieged the capital Beirut in 1982, and has since become a key domestic political player.</p>

<p>Created at the initiative of Iran's Revolutionary Guards, the Shiite Muslim movement gained its moniker as "the Resistance" by fighting Israeli troops who occupied southern Lebanon until 2000.</p>

<p>Israel and Hezbollah fought a month-long war in July-August 2006 that killed some 1,200 people in Lebanon, mostly civilians, and 160 in Israel, mostly soldiers, after the group kidnapped two Israeli troops in a cross-border raid.</p>

<p>United Nations Security Council Resolution 1701 ended that conflict and called for the Lebanese army and United Nations peacekeepers to be the only armed forces deployed in south Lebanon.</p>

<p>But Hezbollah has maintained a discreet presence there, where it enjoys broad support and where experts say it likely has a network of underground tunnels.</p>

<p>On August 16, the group released a video showing what appeared to be underground tunnels and large missile launchers, without revealing their location.</p>

<p>The group also has a strong presence in the Bekaa valley in east Lebanon near the border with Syria.</p>

<p>Hezbollah has bolstered its powerful arsenal, including with guided missiles, and says it can count on more than 100,000 fighters.</p>

<p>Hezbollah chief Hassan Nasrallah was elected secretary-general in 1992 after Israel assassinated his predecessor, and he rarely appears in public.&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>Hezbollah's Regional Influence</strong></h3>

<p>Hezbollah is a key actor in the Middle East, where it plays a central role in the "axis of resistance". It has supported and trained Iran-backed groups in Iraq and Huthi rebels in Yemen, who since October have claimed attacks on Israel and Israeli-linked shipping interests.</p>

<p>Hezbollah is also present in Syria, where many of its members have fought in support of President Bashar al-Assad in his country's civil war, with Damascus also an ally of Tehran.</p>

<p>Domestically, Hezbollah is the only Lebanese faction to have retained its weapons after the country's 1975-1990 civil conflict, doing so in the name of "resistance" against Israel.</p>

<p>It is now a key political player, though detractors have accused it of being a "state within a state".</p>

<p>Political deadlock between Hezbollah allies and their adversaries since late 2022 has prevented the election of a new president, in a country experiencing a grinding economic crisis.</p>

<h3><strong>Hezbollah's Services</strong></h3>

<p>Founded in Lebanon's Bekaa Valley, Hezbollah has become predominant in all Shiite Muslim areas of Lebanon, while its key religious and financial institutions are based in Beirut's southern suburbs.</p>

<p>The movement runs an extensive social services network, complete with schools, hospitals, emergency responders and a wide range of charitable organisations serving its supporters.</p>

<p>Its trademark yellow flags and huge portraits of Nasrallah, along with pictures of dead commanders, fighters and "axis of resistance" figures, adorn areas of the country where it is popular.</p>

<p>The United States has considered Hezbollah a "terrorist" organisation for years, blaming it for a series of bombings and hijackings in the 1980s, including one targeting US Marines in Beirut. The European Union applies the classification to the group's armed wing.</p>

<p>In 2022, a UN-backed court sentenced two Hezbollah members in absentia to life imprisonment for a huge Beirut bombing in 2005 that killed Lebanon's former premier Rafic Hariri.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/43e3nv2o_hassan-nasrallah_625x300_25_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hezbollah chief Hassan Nasrallah rarely appears in public.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nasa-decides-to-bring-back-empty-starliner-capsule-boeing-suffers-1-billion-blow-6414064]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[As Starliner Returns Without Sunita Williams, Boeing Faces $1 Billion Loss]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nasa-decides-to-bring-back-empty-starliner-capsule-boeing-suffers-1-billion-blow-6414064]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 25 Aug 2024 14:45:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[NASA, on Saturday, announcedthat Boeing's Starliner capsule will return empty from the International Space Station (ISS), citing ongoing propulsion system problems.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>NASA, on Saturday, announced&nbsp;that Boeing's Starliner capsule will return empty from the International Space Station (ISS), citing ongoing propulsion system problems. This latest development adds to Boeing's woes, with estimated losses in the Starliner program exceeding $1 billion, reported <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2024/08/24/nasa-boeing-starliner-decision-return-empty-spacex-astronauts-iss.html ">CNBC</a>.</p>

<p>Astronauts Butch Wilmore and Sunita Williams will now return on Elon Musk's SpaceX's Crew-9 vehicle in February 2025, after a six-month extended stay on the ISS. The original nine-day test flight was delayed due to issues with Starliner's thrusters.</p>

<p>A "technical disagreement" between NASA and Boeing led to the decision, with NASA prioritising safety and choosing SpaceX for the return mission.</p>

<p>"Boeing has worked very hard with NASA to get the necessary data to make this decision," NASA Administrator Bill Nelson said on Saturday. "We want to further understand the root causes and understand the design improvements so that the Boeing Starliner will serve as an important part of our assured crew access to the ISS." Mr Nelson stressed that test flights like the Starliner mission are "neither safe, nor routine."</p>

<p>Following the decision, NASA will conduct an additional phase of its Flight Readiness Review to determine the optimal time to bring the empty Starliner capsule back to Earth.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Despite Boeing's assurances that Starliner was safe for emergency crew return, NASA disagreed. Mr Nelson expressed support for Boeing, stating he was "100% certain" that Starliner would launch with a crew again in the future. Boeing also reaffirmed its commitment to safety, saying it would execute the mission as determined by NASA and prepare for a safe uncrewed return.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In a <a href="https://x.com/boeingspace/status/1827396444959002966?s=46 ">statement on X</a>, Boeing said, "We continue to focus, first and foremost, on the safety of the crew and spacecraft. We are executing the mission as determined by NASA, and we are preparing the spacecraft for a safe and successful uncrewed return."</p>

<p>Ken Bowersox, NASA associate administrator, said NASA officials were unanimous in their decision to choose SpaceX to bring the crew home. Meanwhile, SpaceX will bring two astronauts along on its Crew-9 vehicle - instead of the four who were originally planned to go - to make room for Wilmore and Williams.</p>

<p>Boeing's Starliner capsule, 'Calypso', has been docked at the International Space Station since June, with its mission extended indefinitely due to ongoing thruster failures. The Starliner crew flight test, intended to be a final milestone for Boeing, has instead become a major setback.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/dlpu640o_sunita-williams-butch-wilmore_625x300_25_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A "technical disagreement" between NASA and Boeing led to the decision.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/journalist-missing-2-others-injured-after-missile-strike-on-ukraine-hotel-6414230]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Journalist Missing, 2 Others Injured After Missile Strike On Ukraine Hotel]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/journalist-missing-2-others-injured-after-missile-strike-on-ukraine-hotel-6414230]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 25 Aug 2024 14:35:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A member of the Reuters team covering the war in Ukraine was missing and two others were hospitalised after a strike on a hotel in the eastern Ukrainian city of Kramatorsk.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A member of the Reuters team covering the war in Ukraine was missing and two others were hospitalised after a strike on a hotel in the eastern Ukrainian city of Kramatorsk. In a statement, the news agency said that the Hotel Sapphire, where a six-person Reuters crew was staying, was hit "by an apparent missile strike" on Saturday.</p>

<p>"One of our colleagues is unaccounted for, while another two have been taken to hospital for treatment," the agency said.</p>

<p>"Three other colleagues have been accounted for. We are urgently seeking more information, working with the authorities in Kramatorsk, and supporting our colleagues and their families. We will give an update when we have more information," it added.</p>

<p>Vadym Filashkin, governor of Donetsk region, said in a post on Telegram on Sunday morning that "the Russians hit Kramatorsk", and that two journalists were injured, while one was missing after a strike on a hotel.</p>

<p>"Authorities, police and rescuers are working on the spot. Debris clearance and rescue operations are ongoing," he said.</p>

<p>The Russian Defence Ministry did not immediately respond to a request for comment.</p>

<p>Ukraine's General Prosecutor's Office said in a statement on Telegram that it had opened a "pre-trial investigation" into the strike, which it said happened at 10:35 p.m. local time (1935 GMT) on Saturday.</p>

<p>"Russian troops struck the city of Kramatorsk, probably with an Iskander-M missile," it said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/h1b0ouag_russia-ukraine-war_625x300_25_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[File photo]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/circus-performer-in-uk-falls-from-tightrope-in-front-of-horrified-audience-hospitalised-6414187]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Circus Performer In UK Falls From Tightrope In Front Of Horrified Audience]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/circus-performer-in-uk-falls-from-tightrope-in-front-of-horrified-audience-hospitalised-6414187]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 25 Aug 2024 14:29:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The performer was seated on a chair balanced on a pole held by two men as they navigated a tightrope 16 feet in the air.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A heart-stopping incident occurred at Gravity Circus in East Sussex when a&nbsp;female circus performer&nbsp;fell off a tightrope 16 feet in the air in front of a horrified audience. According to <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://metro.co.uk/2024/08/23/circus-performer-seriously-injured-falling-tightrope-front-crowd-21479970/">Metro</a></em>, a performer was seated on a chair balanced on a pole held by two men as they navigated a tightrope 16 feet in the air. As she adjusted her position, the pole wobbled, causing her foot to slip. She fell from the apparatus, and the chair struck a wire, sending her into a freefalling backflip. The performer hit the ground knees first, spinning until she landed in a fetal position on the metal floor.</p>

<p>The horrific accident, captured on video, has left onlookers shocked and concerned for the performer's well-being.</p>

<p>According to South East Coast Ambulance Service (Seacamb), the woman sustained non-life-threatening injuries and was taken to the Royal Sussex County Hospital in Brighton.&nbsp;Seacamb said she suffered from ''facial and other injuries consistent with a fall.''</p>

<p>Witness Hayley Walsh told the&nbsp;<em><a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/czx6wql53n4o" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">BBC</a>,</em> ''It looked like she gave way. She lost her balance and went flying down wrapped around the wire. She smashed down onto the metal floor.''</p>

<p>After the incident, Gravity Circus informed on Facebook that the performer was ''doing well and is in safe hands''.</p>

<p>They said, ''We can confirm that an accident occurred last night involving one of our tightrope performers during the show. In live entertainment and high-risk performances, accidents can unfortunately happen despite stringent safety measures. Our emergency protocols were immediately enacted, and the performer was promptly taken to the hospital. Our primary concern is the well-being of the performers, their families, the high-wire troupe, and our entire circus family. We are closely monitoring the situation and conducting a thorough investigation.''</p>

<section data-context="{&quot;section&quot;:&quot;permalink&quot;,&quot;name&quot;:&quot;text_block&quot;}" id="cb-4c24f5967d2898fff60f0cabd1f542f3">
<p>The female circus performer was part of a highwire troupe act from Colombia, performing with Gravity Circus at Glyne Gap Field in East Sussex, England.</p>
</section>

<section data-context="{&quot;section&quot;:&quot;permalink&quot;,&quot;name&quot;:&quot;text_block&quot;}" id="cb-a10004156cfb1477a0ad04394bd787ad"></section>

<aside data-nosnippet="" data-track-module="trending-post-strip_article" data-vars-type="trending-post-strip-personalised"></aside>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/mnp7fms_circus-performer-_625x300_25_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The video left onlookers shocked and concerned for the performer's well-being]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sunita-williams-and-butch-wilmore-the-two-astronauts-stuck-in-space-6414168]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Sunita Williams And Butch Wilmore: The Two Astronauts Stuck In Space]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sunita-williams-and-butch-wilmore-the-two-astronauts-stuck-in-space-6414168]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 25 Aug 2024 14:20:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Two veteran NASA astronauts with a combined 500 days of previous spaceflight were the first crew launched into space on Boeing's Starliner space capsule, in a June 5 test flight from Florida. They had been scheduled to return in about eight days.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Two veteran NASA astronauts with a combined 500 days of previous spaceflight were the first crew launched into space on Boeing's Starliner space capsule, in a June 5 test flight from Florida. They had been scheduled to return in about eight days. Now Barry "Butch" Wilmore and Sunita "Suni" Williams, both former military test pilots, will not return to Earth until early next year on a SpaceX vehicle. NASA has deemed issues with Starliner's propulsion system too risky to carry its first crew home as planned.</p>

<p>The Starliner capsule sprang leaks and some of its thrusters failed, so their mission at the International Space Station has been extended by months.</p>

<h3><strong>Barry "Butch" Wilmore</strong></h3>

<p>Barry "Butch" Wilmore, 61, a retired U.S. Navy captain, completed four operational deployments flying fighter jets off the decks of aircraft carriers, including 21 combat missions during the first U.S. Gulf War in the 1990s. He also served as a Navy test pilot and flight instructor before joining the NASA astronaut corps in 2000.</p>

<p>He first flew to the space station as a NASA space shuttle pilot in 2009, and returned to the orbiting laboratory in 2014 - launched aboard a Russian Soyuz spacecraft with two cosmonauts - for a long-duration mission, including several months as station commander.</p>

<p>Before his Starliner mission, Wilmore had logged 178 days in space and completed four spacewalks.</p>

<p>A Tennessee native who played college football while attending Tennessee Tech University, Wilmore holds advanced degrees in electrical engineering and aviation systems. He is married with two daughters.</p>

<h3><strong>Sunita "Suni" Williams</strong></h3>

<p>Sunita "Suni" Williams, 58, a former Navy helicopter pilot with experience flying more than 30 different rotary aircraft, was deployed as part of a helicopter combat support squadron during the first Gulf War. She later flew in support of Navy disaster relief operations in Florida following Hurricane Andrew.</p>

<p>She returned to the naval test pilot school as a rotary aircraft instructor before being selected for the NASA astronaut program in 1998.</p>

<p>Like Wilmore, Williams first flew to the space station aboard a space shuttle and made a return visit as a Soyuz passenger riding along with two cosmonauts. Both her ISS tours - in 2006-2007 and in 2012 - were long-duration science expeditions.</p>

<p>After two stays aboard the outpost, Williams had set a world record for the most time spent by a woman in orbit outside a spacecraft, logging a total of 50 hours and 40 minutes combined during seven spacewalks. Her record has since been surpassed by fellow astronaut Peggy Whitson.</p>

<p>During her second ISS mission in 2012, Williams became only the second woman designated as commander of the station.</p>

<p>An avid athlete, Williams in 2007 became the first person to complete a marathon in space, competing virtually in the Boston Marathon from orbit on the space station's treadmill to go the distance in four hours and 24 minutes.</p>

<p>Taking the concept to the next level, Williams in 2012 completed the first triathlon in space, again using the treadmill and a stationary bicycle, then performing a mix of weight-lifting and resistance exercises on a fitness machine that approximated swimming in microgravity.</p>

<p>Before her Starliner mission to ISS, Williams had spent a total of 322 days in space. She also made history as the first woman on the inaugural crewed flight of a new orbital spacecraft.</p>

<p>Born in Massachusetts, Williams currently resides in Houston with her husband, a federal police officer who also flew helicopters earlier in his career.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/dlpu640o_sunita-williams-butch-wilmore_625x300_25_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Barry "Butch" Wilmore and Sunita "Suni" Williams are both former military test pilots]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/22-killed-as-bus-falls-into-valley-in-pakistan-6413847]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[35 Killed In 2 Separate Bus Accidents In Pakistan]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/22-killed-as-bus-falls-into-valley-in-pakistan-6413847]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 25 Aug 2024 13:22:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[At least 35 people were killed in two separate bus accidents in Pakistan on Sunday, including 12 pilgrims who had been trying to reach Iran, rescue and hospital officials said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At least 35 people were killed in two separate bus accidents in Pakistan on Sunday, including 12 pilgrims who had been trying to reach Iran, rescue and hospital officials said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Twenty-three people were killed when the bus they were travelling in plunged into a ravine near the town of Azad Pattan on the border between Punjab province and Pakistan-administered Kashmir.</p>

<p>Sameena Khan, the head of Tehsil Headquarter Hospital in the town of Kahuta, told AFP that twenty-three bodies had been recovered from the crash site.</p>

<p>"I have lost three members of my family," Tara Zafar, who travelled to the hospital after hearing about the accident, told AFP.</p>

<p>Her father, sister and one-year-old nephew were among the dead.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"I hoped that at least one of them had survived. It's doomsday for my family."</p>

<p>Umar Farooq, a senior government official from Sudhanoti district, where the bus started its journey, confirmed the number of deaths in a phone call with AFP from the crash site.</p>

<p>In a separate incident, 12 men died when their bus crashed into a ravine on the Makran Coastal Highway in Balochistan, after being prevented from crossing into Iran.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"An army crane is on its way to help lift the bus from the ravine to check if passengers are pinned underneath the vehicle. Therefore the death count may rise," police official Aslam Bangulzai, who was at the scene, told AFP.</p>

<p>"This is a particularly treacherous tract of road, with many twists and turns. The driver was speeding and the bus fell into a deep ravine," he added.</p>

<p>The accident occurred in a mountainous area, around 100 kilometres (62 miles) from the nearest town of Uthal and 500 kilometres from the Iran border town of Pishin.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The bus was carrying pilgrims on its way to Arbaeen (pilgrimage) but was turned back at the Iran border because their documents had some problems," said Hamood Ur Rehman, a senior government official in the nearby district of Gwadar.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Road accidents with high fatalities are common in Pakistan, where safety measures are lax, driver training is poor and transport infrastructure often decrepit.</p>

<p>On Saturday, the bodies of 28 pilgrims who died in a bus crash in Iran were returned to Pakistan.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The bus was carrying 51 Pakistani pilgrims who were passing through Iran to attend the Arbaeen commemoration in Iraq, one of the biggest events of the Shiite calendar, when it overturned and caught fire in front of a checkpoint in Yazd province on Tuesday night, Iranian state TV reported.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/scdg8ne8_pakistan-hospital_625x300_25_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[In a separate incident, 12 men died when their bus crashed into a ravine in Balochistan]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladeshs-ex-textile-and-jute-minister-golam-dastagir-gazi-arrested-6413594]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ex Bangladesh Minister Arrested Amid Crackdown On Awami League Leaders]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladeshs-ex-textile-and-jute-minister-golam-dastagir-gazi-arrested-6413594]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 25 Aug 2024 12:39:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Bangladesh's former textile and jute minister Golam Dastagir Gazi has been arrested as the police take stern measures against officials and ministers of the ousted prime minister Sheikh Hasina's Awami League government, according to media reports.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bangladesh's former textile and jute minister Golam Dastagir Gazi has been arrested as the police take stern measures against officials and ministers of the ousted prime minister Sheikh Hasina's Awami League government, according to media reports on Sunday.</p>

<p>The 76-year-old leader was detained late Saturday night from a house in the Piergoli area of the capital Dhaka around 3 am, The Daily Star newspaper quoted Paltan police station officer-in-charge Mollah Mohammad Khalid Hussain as saying.</p>

<p>The Dhaka Metropolitan Police detained him and brought him to the Detective Branch (DB) office, according to The Dhaka Tribune.</p>

<p>Gazi was kept at the DB office as the police station is badly damaged following recent violence, Hussain said, adding that a group of people besieged the house after knowing his location there.</p>

<p>However, the police officer did not provide any details regarding the case for which he was arrested.</p>

<p>Earlier, a case of murder was filed against 105 individuals, including Hasina and Gazi, at Rupganj police station in Narayanganj.</p>

<p>Gazi was elected MP from Rupganj-1 constituency in Narayanganj in the 12th parliamentary elections held in January with Awami League's boat symbol.</p>

<p>On Saturday, a Dhaka court placed Salman F Rahman, private industry affairs adviser to Hasina, former law minister Anisul Huq, former social welfare minister Dipu Moni and two others on different terms of remand for interrogation in four murder cases.</p>

<p>Apart from the three, former chief whip ASM Feroz and former army officer Major General Ziaul Ahsan were also placed on remand in murder cases.</p>

<p>Cases have been filed against many officials or ministers of the ousted Hasina-led government after she resigned and fled to India on August 5 following massive protests against the quota reform system in Bangladesh.</p>

<p>Most leaders of the Awami League have gone into hiding since Hasina's resignation.</p>

<p>Many Hasina-led Awami League party members are in jail after the new interim government led by Nobel Laureate Muhammad Yunus took charge on August 8 following the fall of the previous government.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/qfne501_golam-dastagir-gazi-bangladesh-minister_625x300_25_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The police did not provide any details regarding the case for which Golam Dastagir Gazi was arrested.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>