<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Wed, 28 Aug 2024 14:56:21 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-election-2024-over-200-former-republican-presidential-staffers-endorse-kamala-harris-over-donald-trump-6433303]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Over 200 Former Republican Presidential Staffers Endorse Harris Over Trump]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-election-2024-over-200-former-republican-presidential-staffers-endorse-kamala-harris-over-donald-trump-6433303]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 28 Aug 2024 14:38:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump has faced a jolt from within the Republican party. More than 200 Republicans who previously worked for former US President George W Bush have written an open letter endorsing Kamala Harris for the top post instead of Donald Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump has faced a jolt from within the Republican party. More than 200 Republicans who previously worked for former US President George W Bush have written an open letter endorsing Kamala Harris for the top post instead of their own party candidate Donald Trump.</p>

<p>This comes weeks ahead of the US Presidential election scheduled in early November.</p>

<p>According to Fox News, a group of Republican officials, including several former aides to George HW Bush, has endorsed Kamala Harris, a Democrat and current Vice President, urging "moderate Republicans and conservative independents" to support her.</p>

<p>However, this is not the first time this has happened. In the previous US election, held in 2020, the same group had opposed Donald Trump.</p>

<p>"Four years ago, President George W Bush, the late Sen John McCain, and then-Gov Mitt Romney alumni came together to warn fellow Republicans that re-electing President Trump would be a disaster for our nation. In those declarations we stated the plain truth, each predicting that another four years of a Trump presidency would irreparably damage our beloved democracy," the letter said, which was published on Monday by US-based news organisation USA Today.</p>

<p>"We reunite today, joined by new George HW Bush alumni, to reinforce our 2020 statements and, for the first time, jointly declare that we're voting for Vice President Kamala Harris and Gov Tim Walz this November," the letter added.</p>

<p>While acknowledging significant policy disagreements with Kamala Harris, the Republican officials emphasised that the alternative is untenable. "Of course, we have plenty of honest, ideological disagreements with Vice President Harris and Gov. Walz. That's to be expected. The alternative, however, is simply untenable," the letter said.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/qp4pb238_kamala-harris-afp-_625x300_23_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US Election: Kamala Harris now has the support of over 200 former Republican presidential staffers.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/deadpool-killer-wade-wilson-gets-death-for-cruelly-slaughtering-2-6435579]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA['Deadpool Killer' Wade Wilson Gets Death For "Cruelly" Slaughtering 2]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/deadpool-killer-wade-wilson-gets-death-for-cruelly-slaughtering-2-6435579]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 28 Aug 2024 13:50:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Florida man, who was convicted of killing two women earlier this year, has been sentenced to death. Wade Wilson, known as the "Deadpool Killer", strangled and killed the women in 2019.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Florida man, who was convicted of killing two women earlier this year, has been sentenced to death. Wade Wilson, known as the "Deadpool Killer", strangled and killed the women in 2019. The 30-year-old showed no emotion as Lee Circuit Judge Nicholas Thompson delivered the capital punishment.</p>

<p>Wilson, who shares&nbsp;his name with the Marvel antihero, was convicted in June for the deaths of Kristine Melton, 35, and Diane Ruiz, 43, reported the <a href="https://nypost.com/2024/08/27/us-news/deadpool-killer-wade-wilson-who-slaughtered-2-women-for-the-sake-of-killing-sentenced-to-death/ ">NY Post</a>.</p>

<p>On the night of the murders, Wilson first attacked Ms Melton in her home after a drug-induced sexual encounter. He strangled her, stole her car, and used her phone to call his girlfriend, Melissa Montanez, whom he later assaulted when she refused to get into the car.</p>

<p>Wilson then encountered Ms Ruiz in Cape Coral, who was asking for directions. He invited her into his vehicle, strangled her and dumped her body. He then ran over Ms Ruiz repeatedly with his car "until she looked like spaghetti," as described during the trial.</p>

<p>Judge Thompson described the murders as "heinous, atrocious, and cruel," as per the NY Post, noting the second killing was "cold, calculated, and premeditated."</p>

<p>Assistant State Attorney Andreas Gardiner slammed Wilson's actions as being driven purely by a desire to kill, calling strangulation "the epitome of life slipping through someone's hands.</p>

<p>Despite the severity of his crimes, Wade Wilson received thousands of fan mail, love letters and X-rated photos from admirers during his time in jail. Some even wrote to the judge, asking for leniency and claiming that Wilson's behaviour changed when he was on medication. His attorneys argued that he suffered from brain damage and abandonment issues, stemming from his drug addiction and his being adopted as a child.</p>

<p>Wilson's adoptive parents also pleaded for mercy, stating they believed "the human is still in there" and asking the court not to impose the death penalty. In addition to his murder convictions, Wilson was found guilty of several other charges, including grand theft, burglary, battery, and petit theft.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/pnqae3og_deadpool-killer-wade-wilson_625x300_28_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rare-mosquito-disease-where-1-in-3-people-die-has-us-state-on-alert-6435331]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Rare Mosquito Disease Where 1 In 3 People Die Has US State On Alert]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rare-mosquito-disease-where-1-in-3-people-die-has-us-state-on-alert-6435331]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 28 Aug 2024 13:14:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A person in the northeastern US state of New Hampshire has died after contracting the very rare mosquito-borne eastern equine encephalitis (EEE) virus, health authorities have announced.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A person in the northeastern US state of New Hampshire has died after contracting the very rare mosquito-borne eastern equine encephalitis (EEE) virus, health authorities have announced.</p>

<p>The patient, identified only as an adult from the town of Hampstead, was hospitalised with severe central nervous system disease and later succumbed to the illness, the New Hampshire Department of Health and Human Services (DHHS) said in a statement.</p>

<p>"The last reported human EEEV infection in New Hampshire was in 2014, when DHHS identified three human infections, including two fatalities," the department said.</p>

<p>The new infection and death comes amid rising concerns from state officials across New England about the increasing risk of EEE, a threat believed to be exacerbated by climate change.</p>

<p>Earlier this month, Massachusetts announced the year's first human case of EEE in the state - a man in his 80s - and officials have asked the public to observe voluntary outdoor curfews, closed public parks, and initiated aerial and ground spraying to control the mosquito population.</p>

<p>According to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, symptoms of eastern equine encephalitis include fever, headache, vomiting, diarrhea, seizures, behavioral changes and drowsiness.</p>

<p>It can also cause severe neurological disease, such as inflammation of the brain and membranes around the spinal cord, known as encephalitis and meningitis.</p>

<p>Approximately 30 per cent of those infected die, and many survivors suffer ongoing physical or mental impacts. Individuals under 15 and over 50 are considered at higher risk.</p>

<p>There are currently no vaccines or treatments available.</p>

<p>Health officials advise using insect repellent, wearing protective clothing outdoors and eliminating standing water around homes to reduce mosquito breeding sites.</p>

<p>A 2023 report by Climate Central highlighted that the number of "mosquito days" - warm, humid conditions ideal for mosquito activity - has increased across much of the U.S. over the past four decades due to human-caused climate change.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-11/5eh3qh9_mosquito-home-remedies_625x300_08_November_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The last reported human EEEV infection in New Hampshire was in 2014. (Representational Image)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-vs-kamala-harris-the-battle-over-hot-mics-heats-up-ahead-of-key-debate-6435273]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Vs Harris: The Battle Over Hot Mics Heats Up Ahead Of Key Debate]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-vs-kamala-harris-the-battle-over-hot-mics-heats-up-ahead-of-key-debate-6435273]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 28 Aug 2024 13:05:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The use of "hot mics" has been a topic of debate in previous presidential debates, with some arguing for more authentic and spontaneous discussion.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In just under two weeks, Republican candidate Donald Trump and his Democratic rival Kamala Harris will participate in the first Presidential debate. Ahead of the September 10 face-off, the two campaigns are already at loggerheads over the issue of "hot mics".&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Harris Campaign demands an open mic</strong></p>

<p>The Harris campaign is pushing for an open microphone policy, meaning both candidates will have their mics on throughout the debate. This approach, they argue, ensures transparency and spontaneous interactions, giving the audience a complete picture of each candidate's responses and reactions in real time.</p>

<p>According to Brian Fallon, spokesperson for US Vice President Kamala Harris, the Democratic nominee is fully prepared to handle Donald Trump's tactics that often entail interruptions and offhand remarks. However, the Harris campaign insists the microphones remain live for the entire debate, ensuring neither "hides behind the mic" or avoids direct responses.</p>

<p><strong>Trump wants mics muted</strong></p>

<p>The Trump campaign, however, is advocating for the same rules as previous debates held in June. For the CNN debate, microphones were muted when it was the other candidate's turn to speak. The Trump team argues that this rule prevents interruptions and maintains order during the debate, allowing each candidate to present their points without disruption.</p>

<p>US President Joe Biden, before stepping down as the Democratic party nominee, had agreed with Donald Trump's campaign on the controversial microphone policy.&nbsp;</p>

<p></p>

<p>The differences over debate rules escalated when Trump implied that the ABC network, which is hosting the September 10 debate, was biased. In a <a href="https://x.com/TrumpDailyPosts/status/1827891929256018092 ">social media post</a>, Trump indicated he had reached an agreement for the microphones to be closed, similar to the rules from the previous CNN debate.</p>

<p>The Trump campaign proposed an additional debate on September 4 on Fox News, which the Harris team rejected.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The use of "hot mics" has been a topic of debate in previous presidential debates, with some arguing for more authentic and spontaneous discussion, while others saying it only leads to candidates speaking over each other and avoiding direct answers.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/lqgn5nn_donald-trump-kamala-harris_625x300_28_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump and Kamala Harris will face off on September 10]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-man-dies-from-rare-mosquito-borne-eee-virus-officials-alarmed-6435101]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Man Dies From Rare Mosquito Borne Virus, Officials Alarmed]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-man-dies-from-rare-mosquito-borne-eee-virus-officials-alarmed-6435101]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 28 Aug 2024 12:40:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A person in the northeastern US state of New Hampshire has died after contracting the rare mosquito-borne eastern equine encephalitis (EEE) virus, health authorities announced.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A person in the northeastern US state of New Hampshire has died after contracting the rare mosquito-borne eastern equine encephalitis (EEE) virus, health authorities announced Tuesday.</p>

<p>The patient, identified only as an adult from the town of Hampstead, was hospitalized with severe central nervous system disease and later succumbed to the illness, the New Hampshire Department of Health and Human Services (DHHS) said in a statement.</p>

<p>"The last reported human EEEV infection in New Hampshire was in 2014, when DHHS identified three human infections, including two fatalities," the department said.</p>

<p>The new infection and death come amid rising concerns from state officials across New England about the increasing risk of EEE, a threat believed to be exacerbated by climate change.</p>

<p>Earlier this month, Massachusetts announced the year's first human case of EEE in the state -- a man in his 80s -- and officials have asked the public to observe voluntary outdoor curfews, closed public parks, and initiated aerial and ground spraying to control the mosquito population.</p>

<p>According to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, symptoms of eastern equine encephalitis include fever, headache, vomiting, diarrhoea, seizures, behavioural changes and drowsiness.</p>

<p>It can also cause severe neurological diseases, such as inflammation of the brain and membranes around the spinal cord, known as encephalitis and meningitis.</p>

<p>Approximately 30 per cent of those infected die, and many survivors suffer ongoing physical or mental impacts. Individuals under 15 and over 50 are considered at higher risk.</p>

<p>There are currently no vaccines or treatments available.</p>

<p>Health officials advise using insect repellent, wearing protective clothing outdoors and eliminating standing water around homes to reduce mosquito breeding sites.</p>

<p>A 2023 report by Climate Central highlighted that the number of "<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/world-mosquito-day-date-theme-history-and-significance-6374914" target="_blank">mosquito days</a>"-warm, humid conditions ideal for mosquito activity increased across much of the US over the past four decades due to human-caused climate change.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/ndpa50jo_mosquito_625x300_20_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[There are currently no vaccines or treatments available (Representational).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-or-donald-trump-why-one-us-county-matters-most-in-us-polls-6435084]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris Or Donald Trump? Why One US County Matters Most In US Polls]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-or-donald-trump-why-one-us-county-matters-most-in-us-polls-6435084]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 28 Aug 2024 12:39:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Voters in Maricopa County, the largest in the US swing state of Arizona, will play a key role in deciding whether Kamala Harris or Donald Trump wins the White House in November.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Voters in Maricopa County, the largest in the US swing state of Arizona, will play a key role in deciding whether Kamala Harris or Donald Trump wins the White House in November.</p>

<p><strong>Here are five key facts about the county:</strong></p>

<p><strong>America's hottest big city</strong></p>

<p>Maricopa County is home to Phoenix, Arizona's state capital, where the average high temperature exceeds 100 degrees Fahrenheit (37.7 Celsius) for four months of the year.</p>

<p>The sun-drenched metropolis was named in the late 19th century after being founded on the ruins of an ancient native civilization. The small settlement, located in the northern Sonoran Desert, was worth just $550 after the US Civil War.</p>

<p>Irrigation helped Phoenix grow from a sleepy frontier town dotted with saguaro cacti into a center for citrus, cattle and cotton. Its hot, arid climate later made it an attraction for tuberculosis patients.</p>

<p>After World War II, immigrants, retirees and young families seeking warm weather and low costs flocked to the area, dramatically increasing the population thanks in part to the advent of air conditioning.</p>

<p>Phoenix is now the nation's fifth-largest by population, surpassing Philadelphia. More than 1.6 million Americans live in the financial services and manufacturing hub, according to the latest US Census.</p>

<p><strong>Historically Republican</strong></p>

<p>The county -- home to about 4.5 million people, or 62 percent of Arizona's population -- is the second-largest voting jurisdiction in the country, and was until recently a reliable Republican stronghold.</p>

<p>"The real significant election, I think, was in 2016 when Trump took the county just by three percentage points. Four years earlier, it was taken by Mitt Romney by 11 points," said David Berman, professor emeritus of political science at Arizona State University.</p>

<p>President Joe Biden beat Trump in Maricopa County by more than 45,000 votes in 2020, helping him break a nearly eight-decade winning streak for Republican presidential candidates in Arizona.</p>

<p>Berman said Trump's right-wing agenda has alienated some Arizonans who prefer more centrist Republicans, such as late US senator John McCain.</p>

<p><strong>Hispanic population growing</strong></p>

<p>The Hispanic population in Maricopa County has grown to account for nearly a third of all residents, according to the latest census.</p>

<p>That change is part of a larger trend spurred in part by rising immigration. Between 2010 and 2020, Arizona's Hispanic residents increased by 16 percent -- faster than the state's overall population growth.</p>

<p>"There has been a concentrated effort to bring out the Hispanic vote as well as the Native American vote," Berman said of the groups, which tend to vote Democratic.</p>

<p>He added that there have also been "some gains for Democrats" as people seeking cheaper housing and better job opportunities continue to move to Arizona from more traditionally liberal states such as California.</p>

<p><strong>Increasingly independent</strong></p>

<p>Despite Arizona's Republican voting history and recent Democratic inroads, more than a third of Maricopa County residents are not affiliated with either party.</p>

<p>Roughly 34 percent of active voters are registered as "other," according to the county's most recent data -- rivaling Republicans at 35 percent and surpassing Democrats at 28 percent.</p>

<p>That proportion has grown steadily over the past few years, making the county's election results more unpredictable.</p>

<p>"Maricopa County still has quite a bit of red in it, and these swing voters will generally opt for more traditional Republicans," rather than Trump's hard-right brand, said Paul Bentz, senior vice president at Phoenix-based public affairs firm Highground.</p>

<p>"We are not a purple state," he said, referring to an area evenly mixed between Republican red and Democratic blue.</p>

<p>"We are a red state with purple spots."</p>

<p><strong>Early voting dominates</strong></p>

<p>About 80 percent of the county's voters cast early ballots in 2020 and 2022, mirroring a statewide trend that predates the coronavirus pandemic.</p>

<p>"We've been doing it for over three decades. Republicans are really the ones that brought early voting to the state of Arizona," Bentz said.</p>

<p>In 1991, the state legislature allowed voters to request an absentee ballot for any reason, making the practice widely available. More than a decade later, Arizona created a program that automatically sends voters a ballot for each upcoming election.</p>

<p>The growth of mail ballots since the pandemic has made vote verification and counting a days-long process. Most US news networks took more than a week to call the state for Biden in 2020.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/kqs5e0o4_kamala-harris-donald-trump_625x300_27_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kamala Harris or Donald Trump - Voters in Maricopa County will play a key role in deciding who wins]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-a-44-year-old-cold-case-murder-in-us-was-solved-with-a-cigarette-butt-6435013]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How A 44-Year-Old Cold Case Murder In US Was Solved With A Cigarette Butt]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-a-44-year-old-cold-case-murder-in-us-was-solved-with-a-cigarette-butt-6435013]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 28 Aug 2024 12:30:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 30-year-old Boeing instructor and part-time pizza worker was found raped and strangled in her Kent, Washington condo in February 1980.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A decades-old cold case murder has finally been cracked thanks to a discarded cigarette butt, leading to the arrest of 65-year-old Kenneth Kundert in connection with the brutal killing of Dorothy Silzel. According to <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/08/27/us-news/kenneth-kundert-arrested-in-cold-case-murder-of-boeing-instructor-dorothy-silzel/" rel="nofollow, noindex">New York Post,</a></em>&nbsp;the 30-year-old Boeing instructor and part-time pizza worker was found raped and strangled in her Kent, Washington condo in February 1980. Her body was discovered during a welfare check on February 26, three days after she was last seen alive on February 23. Authorities have now linked Kundert to the crime scene through DNA evidence from the cigarette butt, bringing closure to a case that had gone unsolved for 44 years.</p>

<p>According to the charging documents, Ms Silzel's body was found with signs of a violent struggle, having been brutally beaten, strangled, and sexually assaulted. She was left partially naked in her home.&nbsp;At the time of the murder, investigators collected sperm samples from the crime scene using swabs, but the DNA technology available in 1980 was not advanced enough to identify the perpetrator.</p>

<p>The samples were preserved, awaiting future breakthroughs in forensic science.</p>

<p>However, the case remained dormant for over 40 years until March 2022, when a forensic genealogist uploaded the DNA profile to two databases, reigniting the investigation. The search yielded 11 potential suspects, all first cousins, according to court documents. Kent authorities narrowed their focus to Kenneth Kundert in September and reached out to the Van Buren County Sheriff's Office in Arkansas, seeking his DNA.</p>

<p>Coincidentally, Kundert was already under investigation for a separate assault case. During an interview with the sheriff's office, Kundert exhibited a peculiar behaviour - he carefully collected every cigarette butt he smoked and stored them in his pocket.</p>

<p id="mntl-sc-block_28-0">While smoking in a Walmart parking lot earlier this year, he carelessly discarded a cigarette butt into a receptacle. Alert detectives retrieved the butt from the bin and sent it to a lab for analysis. The results revealed showed that the DNA from the cigarette butt was identical to the DNA evidence collected from the 1980 crime scene, finally linking Kundert to the murder of Dorothy Silzel.</p>

<p>Although there was no apparent direct connection between them, investigators discovered that a relative of Kundert resided in an apartment near Silzel's home at the time of the murder. Furthermore, Kundert, then 20 years old, had worked in Washington state around 1987, approximately seven years after the crime.&nbsp;</p>

<p>He was arrested on August 20 by deputies from the Van Buren County Sheriff's Office and is currently being held on a bail of $3 million.&nbsp;He is expected to be extradited to Washington at a later date.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/e3kqje8o_cigarette_625x300_28_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Authorities linked Kundert to the crime scene through DNA evidence from the cigarette butt,]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-sunita-williams-butch-wilmore-will-spend-another-7-months-in-space-6435012]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Will Sunita Williams Run Out Of Food, Oxygen? Astronaut's Survival Plan]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-sunita-williams-butch-wilmore-will-spend-another-7-months-in-space-6435012]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 28 Aug 2024 12:30:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Astronauts Sunita Williams and Butch Wilmore will return to Earth in February 2025, six months later than initially planned, NASA has revealed.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Astronauts Sunita Williams and Butch Wilmore will return to Earth in February 2025, six months later than initially planned, NASA has revealed. The duo will depart from the International Space Station (ISS) aboard a SpaceX Crew Dragon spacecraft, instead of the originally intended Boeing Starliner. However, their extended stay has raised concerns about their survival, particularly regarding food and oxygen supply.</p>

<p>NASA has assured that there is no immediate danger to the astronauts and the ISS has sufficient provisions to support the crew for the additional time.</p>

<p>"The space station is well-stocked with everything the crew needs, including food, water, clothing and oxygen," NASA stated. The agency stressed that regular resupply missions will ensure the astronauts' needs are met, citing regular arrivals of cargo spacecraft carrying food, fuel and supplies.</p>

<p>The space station revealed that two spacecraft - one carrying "8,200 pounds of food, fuel, supplies" and another carrying "three tons of cargo" - arrived at the ISS recently.</p>

<p>Living in space for an extended period requires unique arrangements. On the ISS, astronauts can sleep anywhere - floor, ceiling or walls - thanks to zero gravity. They use sleeping stations, similar to phone booths, with sleeping bags and pillows attached to the floor, wall, or ceiling. Astronauts can also make video calls, audio calls or send emails through NASA.</p>

<p>The ISS has a gym, called the Advanced Resistive Exercise Device (ARED), where astronauts can work out using vacuum cylinders to simulate weights. They can perform exercises like squats, deadlifts and bench presses to maintain muscle mass and bone density until they return to Earth.</p>

<p>Aboard the ISS, Sunita Williams and Butch Wilmore also have access to the Vegetable Production System (Veggie garden) which allows them to grow fresh produce and even flowers in space. During their extended stay, the duo has been experimenting with various techniques to improve crop growth in space.</p>

<p>Williams and Wilmore are scheduled to return to Earth in late February aboard a SpaceX spacecraft. Meanwhile, their original ride, the Boeing Starliner, will undock in early September and attempt an uncrewed return journey.</p>

<p>NASA Administrator Bill Nelson talked about the agency's commitment to safety, explaining the decision to keep the astronauts on the ISS and return the Starliner uncrewed, "Spaceflight is risky, even at its safest and most routine. A test flight, by nature, is neither safe nor routine."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/j537v0c_sunita-williams_625x300_25_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/officials-warn-against-panic-amidst-unprecedented-shortage-of-rice-in-japan-6435005]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Japan Is Grappling With Unprecedented Rice Shortage. Here's What Led To This]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/officials-warn-against-panic-amidst-unprecedented-shortage-of-rice-in-japan-6435005]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 28 Aug 2024 12:27:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The threat of a "megaquake", a series of typhoons, and a week-long national holiday have some Japanese scrambling to buy rice -- the nation's cherished staple food -- with the government warning Tuesday against panic buying.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The threat of a "megaquake", a series of typhoons, and a week-long national holiday have some Japanese scrambling to buy rice -- the nation's cherished staple food -- with the government warning Tuesday against panic buying.</p>

<p>"We could only procure half the usual amount of rice this summer and bags of rice get quickly sold out," a clerk at a branch of the popular Fresco supermarket chain told AFP in the Japanese capital.</p>

<p>Rice shelves in some stores emptied or stocks were rationed after a government warning this month -- since lifted -- of a possible "megaquake", as well as several typhoons and the annual Obon holiday.</p>

<p>Other factors include lower harvests caused by hot weather and water shortages, as well as increased demand related to record numbers of foreign tourists.</p>

<p>At one food store in Tokyo, a sign seen by AFP read: "In order for many customers to be able to buy, we ask you to purchase one (bag of rice) a day per family."</p>

<h3><strong>'No prospects'</strong></h3>

<p>A worker at another store in Tokyo said: "We can't purchase any rice at all, and there's no prospect of buying anytime soon".</p>

<p>The Fresco worker told AFP that daily stocks ran out by midday.</p>

<p>"Customers queue up before the store opens but piles of bags, each of which contains 10 kilograms (22 pounds), are always sold out during the morning," he said.</p>

<p>Farm minister Tetsushi Sakamoto appealed for calm Tuesday.</p>

<p>"Please be cool-headed in your purchase activity by buying only the amount of rice you need," Sakamoto said, stressing "the supply shortage situation will be gradually resolved."</p>

<p>Rice is deeply ingrained in Japanese culture and its harvesting has shaped the nation's landscape -- even being used as a currency in the 7th century.</p>

<p>With an annual consumption of seven million tons per year, it is by far the most consumed food staple in the country.</p>

<p>Demand has been falling for some time, however, because of a declining population and changing eating habits by many Japanese as they opt for alternatives.</p>

<p>The nation's stockpile in June was the lowest since 1999 when comparable data was first collected, but officials believe the inventory is sufficient.</p>

<p>A new harvesting season has started with 40 percent of the crop available by the end of September, a farm ministry official told AFP.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/6h86qd4_rice-japan_625x300_28_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The sign says that the customers are requested to purchase one bag a day per family.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-woman-sues-american-airlines-after-fellow-passenger-sexually-assaults-her-6434816]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Woman Sues American Airlines After Passenger Sexually Assaults Her]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-woman-sues-american-airlines-after-fellow-passenger-sexually-assaults-her-6434816]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 28 Aug 2024 11:54:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The woman, who wishes to remain anonymous, claims that American Airlines bears responsibility for not ensuring her safety and well-being on board.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A New Jersey woman has filed a lawsuit against American Airlines, alleging that the carrier failed to prevent or stop a sexual assault she experienced at the hands of a stranger seated next to her on a flight. According to the <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.independent.co.uk/news/world/americas/american-airlines-assault-flight-new-jersey-b2602014.html" rel="nofollow, noindex">Independent</a></em>, the incident occurred on August 26, 2022, during a nighttime flight from Charlotte, North Carolina, to Newark Liberty International Airport. The woman, who wishes to remain anonymous, claims that American Airlines bears responsibility for not ensuring her safety and well-being on board.</p>

<p>According to the lawsuit, shortly after takeoff, the woman fell asleep, only to awaken to a horrific discovery. She found the stranger's arm inside her pants and his hand forcing hers onto his p***s. The man had covered them both with his black puffer jacket, "digitally penetrating" her while she slept. The woman was left paralysed in shock and panic upon waking.</p>

<p>The stranger then climbed on top of her, ''attempting to penetrate her with his p***s, which he was partially able to do,'' according to the lawsuit. The woman mustered the strength to push him away, and he promptly returned to his seat, ending the assault.</p>

<p>Later, the attacker attempted to downplay the assault by offering the victim water while forcibly holding her hand, only stopping when he noticed a flight attendant approaching. The victim then woke her friend and reported the incident to a flight attendant, who relocated her to a different seat for the remainder of the flight.</p>

<p>Upon landing, the perpetrator was escorted off the plane, and authorities collected statements from the victim and witnesses. But it is ''unknown whether the Perpetrator was taken into custody and/or ever charged with the sexual assault of Plaintiff,'' the lawsuit claimed.</p>

<p>''As alleged in the complaint, we look forward to seeking justice on behalf of our client to remedy this terrible injustice for all that she has suffered,'' the woman's attorney, Brian Andris, told&nbsp;<em>The Independent.</em></p>

<p></p>

<p>In an email, an American Airlines spokesperson said, “We are reviewing the lawsuit and the details of the flight. The safety and comfort of our customers is a top priority for Americans.”</p>

<p>The lawsuit alleged that the airline industry has been aware of the alarming increase in in-flight sexual assaults, with the FBI reporting 96 related cases in the previous year alone. The suit further emphasised that the victim bore no responsibility for the assault and that American Airlines had a clear duty to ensure her safety during the flight.&nbsp;</p>

<p>''American Airlines breached its duty of care by failing to properly monitor the cabin, failing to prevent the sexual assault, and failing to promptly intervene when the assault occurred,'' the lawsuit claims.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/evtl94dg_american-airlines-flight_625x300_28_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The incident occurred on August 26, 2022, during a nighttime flight]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/dartmouth-ai-conference-1956-ai-was-born-at-this-us-summer-camp-68-years-ago-heres-why-it-matters-6434716]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[AI Was Born At This US Summer Camp 68 Years Ago. Here's Why It Matters]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/dartmouth-ai-conference-1956-ai-was-born-at-this-us-summer-camp-68-years-ago-heres-why-it-matters-6434716]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 28 Aug 2024 11:40:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Imagine a group of young men gathered at a picturesque college campus in New England, in the United States, during the northern summer of 1956. Its a small casual gathering. But the men are not here for campfires and nature hikes.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="theconversation-article-title">Imagine a group of young men gathered at a picturesque college campus in New England, in the United States, during the northern summer of 1956.</p>

<div class="theconversation-article-body">
<p>It's a small casual gathering. But the men are not here for campfires and nature hikes in the surrounding mountains and woods. Instead, these pioneers are about to embark on an experimental journey that will spark countless debates for decades to come and change not just the course of technology – but the course of humanity.</p>

<p>Welcome to the Dartmouth Conference – the birthplace of artificial intelligence (AI) as we know it today.</p>

<p>What transpired here would ultimately lead to ChatGPT and the many other kinds of AI which now help us diagnose disease, detect fraud, put together playlists and write articles (well, not this one). But it would also create some of the many problems the field is still trying to overcome. Perhaps by looking back, we can find a better way forward.</p>

<h3><strong>The summer that changed everything</strong></h3>

<p>In the mid-1950s, rock'n'roll was taking the world by storm. Elvis's Heartbreak Hotel was topping the charts, and teenagers started embracing James Dean's rebellious legacy.</p>

<p>But in 1956, in a quiet corner of New Hampshire, a different kind of revolution was happening.</p>

<p>The <a href="https://dl.acm.org/doi/10.1609/aimag.v27i4.1904">Dartmouth Summer Research Project on Artificial Intelligence</a>, often remembered as the Dartmouth Conference, kicked off on June 18 and lasted for about eight weeks. It was the brainchild of four American computer scientists – John McCarthy, Marvin Minsky, Nathaniel Rochester and Claude Shannon – and brought together some of the brightest minds in computer science, mathematics and cognitive psychology at the time.</p>

<p>These scientists, along with some of the 47 people they invited, set out to tackle an ambitious goal: to make intelligent machines.</p>

<p>As <a href="https://dl.acm.org/doi/10.1609/aimag.v27i4.1904">McCarthy put it in the conference proposal</a>, they aimed to find out “how to make machines use language, form abstractions and concepts, solve kinds of problems now reserved for humans”.</p>

<p><strong>The birth of a field – and a problematic name</strong></p>

<p>The Dartmouth Conference didn't just coin the term “artificial intelligence”; it coalesced an entire field of study. It's like a mythical Big Bang of AI – everything we know about machine learning, neural networks and deep learning now traces its origins back to that summer in New Hampshire.</p>

<p>But the legacy of that summer is complicated.</p>

<p>Artificial intelligence won out as a name over others proposed or in use at the time. Shannon preferred the term “automata studies”, while two other conference participants (and the soon-to-be creators of the first AI program), Allen Newell and Herbert Simon, continued to use “complex information processing” for a few years still.</p>

<p>But here's the thing: having settled on AI, no matter how much we try, today we can't seem to get away from comparing AI to human intelligence.</p>

<p>This comparison is both a blessing and a curse.</p>

<p>On the one hand, it drives us to create AI systems that can match or exceed human performance in specific tasks. We celebrate when AI outperforms humans in games such as chess or Go, or when it can detect cancer in medical images with greater accuracy than human doctors.</p>

<p>On the other hand, this constant comparison leads to misconceptions.</p>

<p>When a <a href="https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/computer-beats-go-champion-for-first-time/">computer beats a human at Go</a>, it is easy to jump to the conclusion that machines are now smarter than us in all aspects – or that we are at least well on our way to creating such intelligence. But AlphaGo is no closer to writing poetry than a calculator.</p>

<p>And when a large language model sounds human, <a href="https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/google-engineer-claims-ai-chatbot-is-sentient-why-that-matters/">we start wondering if it is sentient</a>.</p>

<p>But ChatGPT is no more alive than a talking ventriloquist's dummy.</p>

<h3><strong>The overconfidence trap</strong></h3>

<p>The scientists at the Dartmouth Conference were incredibly optimistic about the future of AI. They were convinced they could solve the problem of machine intelligence in a single summer.</p>

<p>This overconfidence has been a recurring theme in AI development, and it has led to several cycles of hype and disappointment.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/20124494">Simon stated in 1965</a> that “machines will be capable, within 20 years, of doing any work a man can do”. <a href="https://dl.acm.org/doi/10.5555/151188">Minsky predicted in 1967</a> that “within a generation, […] the problem of creating ‘artificial intelligence' will substantially be solved”.</p>

<p>Popular futurist <a href="https://www.independent.co.uk/tech/ai-singularity-date-ray-kurzweil-google-b2511847.html">Ray Kurzweil now predicts</a> it's only five years away: “We're not quite there, but we will be there, and by 2029 it will match any person”.</p>

<h3><strong>Reframing our thinking: new lessons from Dartmouth</strong></h3>

<p>So, how can AI researchers, AI users, governments, employers and the broader public move forward in a more balanced way?</p>

<p>A key step is embracing the differences and utility of machine systems. Instead of focusing on the race to “artificial general intelligence”, we can focus on <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0268401224000720">the unique strengths of the systems we have built</a> – for example, the enormous creative capacity of image models.</p>

<p>Shifting the conversation from automation to augmentation is also important. Rather than pitting humans against machines, let's focus on <a href="https://theconversation.com/ai-chatbots-are-coming-to-your-workplace-but-are-not-necessarily-coming-for-your-job-216433">how AI can assist and augment human capabilities</a>.</p>

<p>Let's also emphasise ethical considerations. The Dartmouth participants didn't spend much time discussing the ethical implications of AI. Today, we know better, and must do better.</p>

<p>We must also refocus research directions. Let's emphasise research into AI interpretability and robustness, interdisciplinary AI research and explore new paradigms of intelligence that aren't modelled on human cognition.</p>

<p>Finally, we must manage our expectations about AI. Sure, we can be excited about its potential. But we must also have realistic expectations so that we can avoid the disappointment cycles of the past.</p>

<p>As we look back at that summer camp 68 years ago, we can celebrate the vision and ambition of the Dartmouth Conference participants. Their work laid the foundation for the AI revolution we're experiencing today.</p>

<p>By reframing our approach to AI – emphasising utility, augmentation, ethics and realistic expectations – we can honour the legacy of Dartmouth while charting a more balanced and beneficial course for the future of AI.</p>

<p>After all, real intelligence lies not just in creating smart machines, but in how wisely we choose to use and develop them.<!-- Below is The Conversation's page counter tag. Please DO NOT REMOVE. --><img alt="The Conversation" height="1" referrerpolicy="no-referrer-when-downgrade" src="https://counter.theconversation.com/content/237205/count.gif?distributor=republish-lightbox-basic" style="border: none !important; box-shadow: none !important; margin: 0 !important; max-height: 1px !important; max-width: 1px !important; min-height: 1px !important; min-width: 1px !important; opacity: 0 !important; outline: none !important; padding: 0 !important" width="1" /><!-- End of code. If you don't see any code above, please get new code from the Advanced tab after you click the republish button. The page counter does not collect any personal data. More info: https://theconversation.com/republishing-guidelines --></p>

<p><em><span><a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/sandra-peter-385460">Sandra Peter</a>, Director of Sydney Executive Plus, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/university-of-sydney-841">University of Sydney</a></span></em></p>

<p><em>This article is republished from <a href="https://theconversation.com">The Conversation</a> under a Creative Commons license. Read the <a href="https://theconversation.com/ai-was-born-at-a-us-summer-camp-68-years-ago-heres-why-that-event-still-matters-today-237205">original article</a>.</em></p>
</div><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/tlt8rrqo_dartmouth-ai-conference-1956-_625x300_28_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[These scientists, along with some of the 47 people they invited, set out to make intelligent machines.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-jared-isaacman-the-billionaire-who-is-set-to-become-first-private-citizen-to-complete-spacewalk-6434616]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[This US Billionaire Is Heading To Space For First-Ever Private Spacewalk]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-jared-isaacman-the-billionaire-who-is-set-to-become-first-private-citizen-to-complete-spacewalk-6434616]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 28 Aug 2024 11:25:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Billionaire Jared Isaacman is set to embark on his second space trip in three years on Wednesday on the Polaris Dawn mission backed by Elon Musk's SpaceX.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Billionaire Jared Isaacman is set to embark on his second space trip in three years on Wednesday on the Polaris Dawn mission backed by Elon Musk's SpaceX. Leaving Cape Canaveral in Florida, the 41-year-old is part of a four-person crew attempting to go further from the planet Earth than any space tourist before them in a SpaceX Crew Dragon capsule, the <em>New York Post </em>reported. During the course of the five-day journey, he is also poised to become the first private citizen to complete a "spacewalk".&nbsp;</p>

<p>Joining Mr Isaacman on Polaris Dawn will be two SpaceX engineers, Sarah Gillis and Anna Menon, the first from the company to join a mission to orbit. After takeoff today, the four-person team is expected to travel into an oval-shaped orbit that extends as far as 1,400 kilometres from Earth. The space mission will aim to reach the highest orbit around Earth for a crewed mission. Ms Gillis and Ms Menon would also become the first women to make such a journey.&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>Polaris Dawn space mission is expected to last about five days. Here's everything about the billionaire who is set to become the first private citizen to complete a spacewalk.&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Jared Isaacman is the founder and chief executive officer of Shift4 Payments, a firm that provides payment processing services and point-of-sale software businesses. According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/conormurray/2024/08/26/what-to-know-about-jared-isaacman-billionaire-heading-to-space-tomorrow-for-first-ever-private-spacewalk/" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>Forbes</em></a>, he is worth about $1.9 billion.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The 41-year-old took up aviation as a hobby, learning how to fly fighter jets and completing a flight around the world in 61 hours, 51 minutes and 15 seconds. According to the outlet, he also co-founded Draken International, which now owns the world's largest private fleet of military jets and trains Air Force pilots. Mr Isaacman sold his majority stake in Draken for a nine-figure sum to Blackstone in 2019, and became a billionaire the following year after he took Shift4 Payments public.</p>

<p>The 41-year-old is now set to take flight in a SpaceX Crew Dragon spacecraft. The mission will be the first of three planned Polaris missions funded and executed by Mr Isaacman and SpaceX for space technology development purposes.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The upcoming mission will be Mr Isaacman's second trip to space. He first travelled to space in 2021 on a self-funded mission launched by SpaceX called Inspiration4.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>About Polaris Dawn space mission&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p>Polaris Dawn space mission stands out not just for its duration but also for its scientific goals and the risks involved. Mr Isaacman and his three crewmates will travel farther from Earth than any space mission conducted since NASA's Apollo flights in the 1970s. According to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/08/26/us-news/billionaire-jared-isaacman-blasting-off-on-five-day-space-mission/" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>New York Post</em></a>, the crew will also conduct research on radiation exposure in space, and valuable data for future missions to the moon and Mars.</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/science/astronomers-discover-object-500-trillion-times-brighter-than-the-sun-6430389">Astronomers Discover Object 500 Trillion Times Brighter Than The Sun</a></strong></p>

<p>On the third day of their journey, Mr Isaacman and Ms Gillis will perform space tourism first by opening the hatch of their SpaceX Crew Dragon capsule. Although described as a spacewalk, this involves leaning out of the capsule while tethered, exposing them to the harsh environment of outer space. The two will each spend about 15 minutes outside the spacecraft to test the spacesuits, connected to the ship by 12-foot long umbilical cords that will provide oxygen.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The crew will pass through Earth's Van Allen radiation belts, where dangerous amounts of radiation will be present, and they will conduct an experiment to determine whether the radiation in space can take X-ray images without an X-ray machine, the Forbes reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Notably, the mission is expected to take off from NASA's Kennedy Space Center in Florida between 3:38 and 7:09 am ET Wednesday - a 24-hour delay from the company's previous launch target.&nbsp;</p>

<p>SpaceX said in a social media post Monday that it pushed the launch time back in order to take "a closer look at a ground-side helium leak" on a piece a equipment designed to detach from the rocket during takeoff.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/m8532vv_jared-isaacman_625x300_28_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Jared Isaacman is the founder and chief executive officer of Shift4 Payments.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-natasha-danish-ali-the-pakistani-woman-behind-the-deadly-land-cruiser-crash-6434510]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Who Is Natasha Danish Ali, Pak Industrialist's Wife Accused Of Killing 2]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-natasha-danish-ali-the-pakistani-woman-behind-the-deadly-land-cruiser-crash-6434510]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 28 Aug 2024 11:08:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Natasha Danish Ali, the wife of a prominent businessman, was driving a Toyota Land Cruiser when she mowed down a father-daughter duo.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A video of a Pakistani woman smiling and appearing unremorseful after allegedly killing two people with her car&nbsp;has sparked outrage on social media. Natasha Danish Ali, the wife of prominent businessman Danish Iqbal, was driving a Toyota Land Cruiser on Karsaz Road on August 19 when she attempted to turn.&nbsp;Seconds later, she rammed multiple vehicles, including motorcycles and a parked car, resulting in the deaths of a father and daughter on the spot. At least four others were injured and rushed to nearby hospitals for treatment.</p>

<p>Despite being involved in a car crash that killed two people, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/on-camera-pakistani-woman-shocking-behaviour-after-deadly-accident-6434311#pfrom=home-ndtv_topstories" target="_blank">Natasha Danish Ali</a> was caught on camera smiling and showing no signs of remorse.</p>

<p>In one clip, she boasts about her family's influence, saying "<em>Tum mere baap ko nahi jantay </em>(You don't know who my father is)."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Shameless woman Natasha Iqbal killed a father &amp; his daughter on road, is the wife of Danish Iqbal, current Chairman of Gul Ahmed Energy Limited.<br />
<br />
Two killed, four injured in accident at Karachi's Karsaz Road <a href="https://t.co/BJ2DNPK55k">pic.twitter.com/BJ2DNPK55k</a></p>
— Sumit (@SumitHansd) <a href="https://twitter.com/SumitHansd/status/1826160937105240208?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 21, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<h3><strong>Who Is Natasha Danish Ali?</strong></h3>

<ul>
	<li>
	<p>Natasha Danish was born in Karachi, Pakistan. She is 32.</p>
	</li>
	<li>Natasha is the wife of Danish Iqbal, a well-known businessman from Pakistan. Danish Iqbal is the Chairman of Gul Ahmed Energy Limited and its affiliated companies, as well as at Metro Power Group.</li>
	<li>They live in Karachi's upscale KDA Scheme-I area.&nbsp;</li>
	<li>Her lawyer has claimed she is mentally "not stable", is on medication for mental stress, and is not fully aware of her actions.&nbsp;</li>
</ul>

<p>According to reports, she is currently behind bars on a 14-day judicial remand.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/pa7a5bko_natasha-danish-ali_625x300_28_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/taylor-swift-on-kamala-harris-us-elections-2024-taylor-swift-is-yet-to-back-kamala-harris-fans-start-campaign-without-her-6434388]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Taylor Swift Is Yet To Back Kamala Harris, Fans Start Campaign Without Her]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/taylor-swift-on-kamala-harris-us-elections-2024-taylor-swift-is-yet-to-back-kamala-harris-fans-start-campaign-without-her-6434388]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 28 Aug 2024 10:47:00 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Pop star Taylor Swift has yet to endorse a candidate for president this election season, but some of her fans are entering their political era by organizing for Vice President Kamala Harris.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pop star Taylor Swift has yet to endorse a candidate for president this election season, but some of her fans are entering their political era by organizing for Vice President Kamala Harris.</p>

<p>Senators Elizabeth Warren and Kirsten Gillibrand, both Democrats, joined singer-songwriter Carole King and about 15,000 others on a video conference Tuesday to kickstart Swifties for Kamala's organizing efforts. All of the speakers mentioned their favourite Swift song on the call, including Senator Ed Markey of Massachusetts, who said "Snow on the Beach" was his.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The call on Zoom raked in more than $113,000, organizers said. Swift said in July that 113 was her "favorite number" at an Eras Tour concert in Zurich. Donations continued to roll in after the call concluded.</p>

<p>The Swifties for Kamala call is the latest example of affinity and identity-based groups organizing online for the vice president in what has turned out to be a truncated campaign period after President Joe Biden dropped out of the race late last month.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Harris campaign and allies have embraced virtual gatherings to quickly mobilize volunteers and raise money.</p>

<p>Harris entered August with $377 million cash on hand compared to $327 million for former President Donald Trump, whose fundraising has lagged behind his Democratic opponents - whether Biden or Harris - for most of the campaign.</p>

<p>King serenaded attendees Tuesday with a brief rendition of "Shake it Off," her favorite Swift song, and she offered some tips for how to effectively knock on doors to convince voters to support Harris.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"I've been a political activist for years. I've been a volunteer and I've been a door-knocker, even as a famous person," King said.</p>

<p>"You are resilient and you know how to take on bullies," Warren said on the call. "That's what the Harris campaign is all about. Sticking up to bullies like Donald Trump."&nbsp;</p>

<p>Other speakers on Tuesday's call included Representative Chris Deluzio of Pennsylvnia, Representative Becca Balint of Vermont, and North Carolina Democratic Party chair Anderson Clayton.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Swift is not affiliated with the group and she did not attend the call, but the organizers said on social media that she was "always welcome to show up to our party."</p>

<p>Swift's massive following has grown over the past year as she has toured across the country and internationally, playing to sold-out sports stadiums, and as she began a romantic relationship with Kansas City Chiefs football player Travis Kelce.</p>

<p>The Democratic ticket had been eager to secure Swift's backing. Biden's campaign privately hoped for months to land her endorsement before he stood aside and backed Harris for the top of the ticket. Rumours circulated heavily last week that Swift or Beyonce could perform at the Democratic National Convention, though neither ended up making an appearance.</p>

<p>Trump openly sought Swift's support, earlier this year in a post on Truth Social, the social media platform he owns. Earlier this month, he posted an artificial intelligence-created image of her offering her endorsement, which she never gave.</p>

<p>Swift has signalled she may get politically active this cycle. Last September, the tortured poet of the Millennial generation posted a short message on Instagram encouraging her hundreds of millions of followers to register to vote. Afterwards, the website Swift directed her fans to - the nonpartisan nonprofit Vote.org - recorded more than 35,000 voter registrations, according to the organization.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In 2020, Swift endorsed Biden for president.</p>

<p>The Democratic National Convention last week showcased an array of other pop culture icons - including television executive Oprah Winfrey, musician Stevie Wonder, actress Mindy Kaling and singer John Legend.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/smeukbng_taylor-swift-placard-bloomberg-_625x300_28_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Taylor Swift has signalled she may get politically active this cycle (representational).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/on-camera-pakistani-woman-shocking-behaviour-after-deadly-accident-6434311]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[On Camera, Pakistani Woman's Shocking Behaviour After Deadly Accident]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/on-camera-pakistani-woman-shocking-behaviour-after-deadly-accident-6434311]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 28 Aug 2024 10:31:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A video of a Pakistani woman smiling and appearing unremorseful after being involved in a car accident, killing two people, has sparked outrage on social media.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A video of a Pakistani woman smiling and appearing unremorseful after being involved in a car accident, killing two people, has sparked outrage on social media. On August 19, Natasha Danish, the wife of prominent businessman Danish Iqbal, was driving a Toyota Land Cruiser on Karsaz Road when she attempted to turn.</p>

<p>The next moment, she rammed multiple vehicles, including motorcycles and a parked car, resulting in the deaths of a father and daughter on the spot. At least four others were injured and rushed to nearby hospitals for treatment. One of the victims is now on a ventilator, his family said, as per <a href="https://mmnews.tv/natasha-danish-iqbals-friends-defend-her-after-deadly-karsaz-accident/ ">MM News</a>.</p>

<p>However, Natasha's behaviour after the accident, captured on videos that have since gone viral on social media, was even more shocking. Footage shared on X shows Natasha, surrounded by an angry mob, smiling and boasting about her family's influence. "Tum mere baap ko nahi jantay (you don't know who my father is)," she's heard saying. &nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/reel/C_Fcd7sIlKv/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/C_Fcd7sIlKv/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/C_Fcd7sIlKv/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/C_Fcd7sIlKv/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by @aroob_jattoii</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Natasha Iqbal's crushing poor father his daughter in the drunkenness of wealth,this smile is spitting on the face of Pakistan's law,courts,justice system and government.This is slander in the name of the elite above the law.There are prisons punishments,detentions, fines for poor <a href="https://t.co/iBNl3ZqgcE">pic.twitter.com/iBNl3ZqgcE</a></p>
— Zain Tareen (@Zaintareen_) <a href="https://twitter.com/Zaintareen_/status/1827316928806850755?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 24, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>"Zero regrets," a user commented on X.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none">
<p dir="ltr" lang="pt">Zero regrets.</p>
— Shahzebkhan666 Khan (@shahzebkhan666) <a href="https://twitter.com/shahzebkhan666/status/1826933610437312524?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 23, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Another user wrote, "Throw her behind bars and treat her like any other prisoner."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Throw her behind bars and treat her like any other prisoner</p>
— U I (@UI8838063189376) <a href="https://twitter.com/UI8838063189376/status/1826950804344877162?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 23, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Someone stated, "Driving and killing poor and innocent father and daughter under the influence of drugs, the evil smile on her face says, hey common and poor Pakistani 'You Know Who I Am'."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Driving and killing poor and innocent father and daughter under the influence of drugs, the evil smile on her face says, hey common and poor Pakistani<br />
“ You Know Who I Am”</p>
— Khan (@mutual323) <a href="https://twitter.com/mutual323/status/1826938416082137192?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 23, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>"It's shameful how #Natasha flaunts her wealth &amp; arrogance while mocking #Pakistan's laws &amp; justice system. This is the elite's disregard for accountability, where the poor face prisons, punishments, detentions, and fines," a comment read.&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">It's shameful how <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Natasha?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Natasha</a> flaunts her wealth &amp; arrogance while mocking <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Pakistan?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Pakistan</a>'s laws &amp; justice system. This is the elite's disregard for accountability, where the poor face prisons, punishments, detentions, and fines. <a href="https://twitter.com/YousufNazar?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@YousufNazar</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/AsadAToor?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@AsadAToor</a> <a href="https://t.co/L53WkjFUEr">pic.twitter.com/L53WkjFUEr</a></p>
— Zohar Amin (@ZoharAmin2) <a href="https://twitter.com/ZoharAmin2/status/1827678648318513411?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 25, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Another demanded she be "tried as an alleged criminal." "Otherwise the farcical nature of this system simply multiplies."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">She should be tried as an alleged criminal. Otherwise the farcical nature of this system simply multiplies</p>
— alison@wonderlab (@numbpolitics) <a href="https://twitter.com/numbpolitics/status/1826241435353657402?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 21, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Natasha Danish avoided court appearance after the fatal car accident, citing mental health concerns. Her advocate Amir Mansub claimed Natasha's mental health was "not stable", and that she was receiving treatment at Jinnah Hospital. However, hospital records contradicted this claim, showing Natasha was discharged as fit after medical evaluations. Doctors found no need for immediate psychiatric intervention, as per MM News.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/eispjf98_pakistan-woman_625x300_28_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/this-airline-mistakenly-sold-hundreds-of-first-class-tickets-at-huge-discount-6434160]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[This Airline Mistakenly Sold First Class Tickets At Huge Discount]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/this-airline-mistakenly-sold-hundreds-of-first-class-tickets-at-huge-discount-6434160]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 28 Aug 2024 10:07:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The first-class tickets include access to airport lounges, champagne, a large seat and bedding, a chance to "peruse a pillow menu" and other amenities.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a shocking incident, Qantas Airways mistakenly sold hundreds of first-class flight tickets at a huge discount due to a coding error, as per a report in the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.independent.co.uk/travel/news-and-advice/qantas-mistake-fare-first-class-business-tickets-b2602150.html"><em>Independent</em></a>. They are now planning to offer refunds or downgrade the passengers.</p>

<p>On Thursday, the airline posted flights from Australia to the US on its website, however, due to an error, the flights seemed to be up to 85 per cent less expensive than the regular first-class rates. The cost of a return flight was listed at less than $5,000 (Rs 4 lakh), roughly $15,000 (Rs 12 lakh) cheaper than usual. The exceptionally low costs were on offer for around eight hours, during which time over 300 customers were able to reserve the return flights between Australia and the US.</p>

<p>Notably, the first-class tickets include access to airport lounges, champagne, a large seat and bedding, a chance to "peruse a pillow menu" and other amenities.</p>

<p>However, the cheap first-class tickets ended up being a mistake. According to Qantas' terms and conditions on its website, they are entitled to cancel a booking, issue a refund, or issue a new ticket at the proper fare price if mistakes are made and wrong fares are presented that are "reasonably obvious."</p>

<p>Qantas stated that they would still allow passengers to choose a higher class, but not the first-class experience. According to the airline, a business class passenger would still receive a ticket that is 65 per cent less expensive than usual.</p>

<p>A spokesperson for the Australian airline said, "Unfortunately, this is a case where the fare was actually too good to be true." "As a gesture of goodwill, we're rebooking customers in business class at no additional cost. Customers also have the option of a full refund," they added.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-03/8souj528_airplane_625x300_21_March_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The exceptionally low costs were on offer for around eight hours.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/what-is-atlantic-nina-la-ninas-cousin-that-could-affect-hurricane-season-6434148]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What Is Atlantic Nina, La Nina's Cousin That Could Affect Hurricane Season]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/what-is-atlantic-nina-la-ninas-cousin-that-could-affect-hurricane-season-6434148]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 28 Aug 2024 10:02:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[It's rare to see both Ninas at the same time, yet in August 2024, both appeared to be developing.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The North Atlantic Ocean has been running a fever for months, with surface temperatures <a href="https://climatereanalyzer.org/clim/sst_daily/" style="font-size: 13px;">at or near record highs</a><span style="font-size: 13px;">. But cooling along the equator in both the Atlantic and eastern Pacific may </span><a href="https://coralreefwatch.noaa.gov/product/5km/index_5km_baa-max-ytd.php" style="font-size: 13px;">finally be starting to bring some relief</a><span style="font-size: 13px;">, particularly for vulnerable coral reef ecosystems.</span></p>

<div class="theconversation-article-body">
<p>This cooling comes from two climate phenomena with similar names: La Nina, which forms in the tropical Pacific, and the less well-known Atlantic Nina.</p>

<p>Both can affect the Atlantic hurricane season. While La Nina&nbsp;<a href="https://www.weather.gov/jan/el_nino_and_la_nina">tends to bring conditions ideal for Atlantic hurricanes</a>, the less powerful Atlantic Nina has the potential to reduce some of the hurricane risk.</p>

<figure class="align-center "><img alt="A map shows a cool spot along the equator while temperatures just to the north are well above average." sizes="(min-width: 1466px) 754px, (max-width: 599px) 100vw, (min-width: 600px) 600px, 237px" src="https://images.theconversation.com/files/615694/original/file-20240827-16-tv9yxc.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;fit=clip" srcset="https://images.theconversation.com/files/615694/original/file-20240827-16-tv9yxc.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=426&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=1 600w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/615694/original/file-20240827-16-tv9yxc.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=30&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=426&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=2 1200w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/615694/original/file-20240827-16-tv9yxc.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=15&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=426&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=3 1800w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/615694/original/file-20240827-16-tv9yxc.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=535&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=1 754w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/615694/original/file-20240827-16-tv9yxc.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=30&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=535&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=2 1508w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/615694/original/file-20240827-16-tv9yxc.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=15&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=535&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=3 2262w" />
<figcaption><span class="caption">Cooling in the tropical Atlantic along the equator is a sign an Atlantic Nina may be forming.</span></figcaption>
</figure>

<p>We're <a href="https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=6jEKlrQAAAAJ&amp;hl=en">ocean</a> and <a href="https://handlos.eas.gatech.edu/research/">atmospheric scientists</a> who study this type of climate phenomenon. It's rare to see both Ninas at the same time, yet in August 2024, <a href="https://www.climate.gov/news-features/event-tracker/atlantic-nina-verge-developing-heres-why-we-should-pay-attention">both appeared to be developing</a>. Let's take a closer look at what that means.</p>

<h2><strong>La Nina and its cousin, Atlantic Nina</strong></h2>

<p>La Nina is part of the <a href="https://www.climate.gov/enso">El Nino–Southern Oscillation</a>, a well-known climate phenomenon that has widespread effects on climate and weather around the world.</p>

<p>During La Nina, sea surface temperatures in the tropical Pacific dip below normal. Easterly trade winds then strengthen, allowing more cool water to well up along the equator off South America. That cooling <a href="https://theconversation.com/la-nina-is-coming-raising-the-chances-of-a-dangerous-atlantic-hurricane-season-an-atmospheric-scientist-explains-this-climate-phenomenon-228595">affects the atmosphere in ways that reverberate</a> across the planet. Some areas become stormier and others drier during La Nina, and the wind shear that can tear apart Atlantic hurricanes tends to weaken.</p>

<p>La Nina and its warmer opposite, <a href="https://oceanservice.noaa.gov/facts/ninonina.html">El Nino</a>, oscillate <a href="https://www.pmel.noaa.gov/elnino/lanina-faq">every three to four years or so</a>.</p>

<figure><iframe allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="260" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wVlfyhs64IY?wmode=transparent&amp;start=0" width="440"></iframe>

<figcaption><span class="caption">La </span>Nina&nbsp;<span class="caption">and its opposite, El Niño, explained. NOAA.</span></figcaption>
</figure>

<p>A similar climate phenomenon, <a href="https://www.aoml.noaa.gov/atlantic-nina-on-the-verge-of-developing-heres-why-we-should-pay-attention/">Atlantic Nina</a>, occurs in the Atlantic Ocean but at a much smaller scale and amplitude. It typically peaks around July or August and tends to have a shorter duration than its Pacific cousin and much more modest and local impacts. Atlantic Ninas generally have the <a href="https://cpaess.ucar.edu/sites/default/files/meetings/2020/presentations/kim-presentation.pdf">opposite effect</a> of <a href="https://www.climate.gov/news-features/event-tracker/atlantic-nina-verge-developing-heres-why-we-should-pay-attention">Atlantic Ninos, which tend to</a> reduce <a href="https://www.aoml.noaa.gov/the-atlantic-nino-el-ninos-little-brother/">rainfall over Africa's Sahel</a> region and increase rainfall in Brazil and the countries that surround the Gulf of Guinea, such as Ghana, Nigeria, and Cameroon.</p>

<p>While much weaker than their Pacific counterpart, Atlantic Ninas can, however, partially counteract La Ninas by weakening summer winds that help drive the upwelling that cools the eastern Pacific.</p>

<h2><strong>Why are both happening now?</strong></h2>

<p>In July and August 2024, meteorologists <a href="https://www.aoml.noaa.gov/atlantic-nina-on-the-verge-of-developing-heres-why-we-should-pay-attention/">noted cooling</a> that appeared to be the development of an Atlantic Nina along the equator. The winds at the ocean surface had been weak through most of the summer, and sea surface temperatures there were <a href="https://coralreefwatch.noaa.gov/product/5km/index_5km_ssta.php">quite warm until early June</a>, so signs of an Atlantic Nina emerging were a surprise.</p>

<p>At the same time, waters along the equator in the eastern Pacific were also cooling, with <a href="https://www.cpc.ncep.noaa.gov/products/analysis_monitoring/enso_advisory/ensodisc.shtml">La Nina&nbsp;conditions expected</a> there by October or November.</p>

<figure class="align-center "><img alt="" sizes="(min-width: 1466px) 754px, (max-width: 599px) 100vw, (min-width: 600px) 600px, 237px" src="https://images.theconversation.com/files/615698/original/file-20240827-18-el3bdp.png?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;fit=clip" srcset="https://images.theconversation.com/files/615698/original/file-20240827-18-el3bdp.png?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=347&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=1 600w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/615698/original/file-20240827-18-el3bdp.png?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=30&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=347&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=2 1200w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/615698/original/file-20240827-18-el3bdp.png?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=15&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=347&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=3 1800w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/615698/original/file-20240827-18-el3bdp.png?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=436&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=1 754w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/615698/original/file-20240827-18-el3bdp.png?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=30&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=436&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=2 1508w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/615698/original/file-20240827-18-el3bdp.png?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=15&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=436&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=3 2262w" />
<figcaption><span class="caption">A map of sea surface temperature anomalies shows cooling along the tropical Atlantic and eastern Pacific regions, but much warmer than average temperatures in the Caribbean.</span></figcaption>
</figure>

<p>Getting a Pacific-Atlantic Nina combination is <a href="https://www.climate.gov/news-features/event-tracker/atlantic-nina-verge-developing-heres-why-we-should-pay-attention">rare but not impossible</a>. It's like finding two different pendulums that are weakly coupled to swing in opposite directions moving together in time. The combinations of La Nina and Atlantic Niño, or El Niño and Atlantic Nina are more common.</p>

<h2><strong>Good news or bad for hurricane season?</strong></h2>

<p>An Atlantic Nina may initially suggest good news for those living in hurricane-prone areas.</p>

<p>Cooler than average waters off the coast of Africa can suppress the formation of African easterly waves. These are <a href="https://glossarytest.ametsoc.net/wiki/African_Easterly_Wave">clusters of thunderstorm activity</a> that can form into tropical disturbances and eventually tropical storms or hurricanes.</p>

<p>Tropical storms <a href="https://oceanexplorer.noaa.gov/facts/hurricanes.html">draw energy from the process of evaporating water</a> associated with warm sea surface temperatures. So, cooling in the tropical Atlantic could weaken this process. That would leave less energy for the thunderstorms, which would reduce the probability of a tropical cyclone forming.</p>

<p>However, NOAA takes all factors into account when <a href="https://www.cpc.ncep.noaa.gov/products/outlooks/hurricane.shtml">it updates its Atlantic hurricane season outlook</a>, released in early August, and it still anticipates an extremely active 2024 season. <a href="https://climatecenter.fsu.edu/topics/hurricanes">Tropical storm season typically peaks</a> in early to mid-September.</p>

<p><iframe class="tc-infographic-datawrapper" frameborder="0" height="400px" id="lcaEc" scrolling="no" src="https://datawrapper.dwcdn.net/lcaEc/2/" style="border: 0;" width="100%"></iframe></p>

<p>Two reasons are behind the busy forecast: The <a href="https://www.cpc.ncep.noaa.gov/products/outlooks/Slide4.JPG">near record-breaking warm</a> sea surface temperatures in much of the North Atlantic can strengthen hurricanes. And the expected development of a La Nina in the Pacific tends to weaken <a href="https://theconversation.com/what-is-wind-shear-an-atmospheric-scientist-explains-how-it-can-disrupt-air-travel-and-tear-apart-hurricanes-213527">wind shear</a> – the change in wind speed with height that can tear apart hurricanes. La Nina's much stronger effects can override any impacts associated with the Atlantic Nina.</p>

<h2><strong>Exacerbating the problem: Global warming</strong></h2>

<p>The past two years have seen <a href="https://climatereanalyzer.org/clim/sst_daily/">exceptionally high ocean temperatures</a> in the Atlantic and around much of the world's oceans. The two Ninas are likely to contribute some cooling relief for certain regions, but it may not last long.</p>

<p>In addition to these cycles, the global warming trend caused by rising greenhouse gas emissions is raising the baseline temperatures and can <a href="https://science.nasa.gov/earth/climate-change/a-force-of-nature-hurricanes-in-a-changing-climate/">fuel major hurricanes</a>.<!-- Below is The Conversation's page counter tag. Please DO NOT REMOVE. --><img alt="The Conversation" height="1" referrerpolicy="no-referrer-when-downgrade" src="https://counter.theconversation.com/content/237425/count.gif?distributor=republish-lightbox-basic" style="border: none !important; box-shadow: none !important; margin: 0 !important; max-height: 1px !important; max-width: 1px !important; min-height: 1px !important; min-width: 1px !important; opacity: 0 !important; outline: none !important; padding: 0 !important" width="1" /><!-- End of code. If you don't see any code above, please get new code from the Advanced tab after you click the republish button. The page counter does not collect any personal data. More info: https://theconversation.com/republishing-guidelines --></p>

<p><em><span>(<strong>Authors:&nbsp;</strong><a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/annalisa-bracco-1447820">Annalisa Bracco</a>, Professor of Ocean and Climate Dynamics, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/georgia-institute-of-technology-1310">Georgia Institute of Technology</a> and <a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/zachary-handlos-1470948">Zachary Handlos</a>, Atmospheric Science Educator, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/georgia-institute-of-technology-1310">Georgia Institute of Technology</a>)</span></em></p>

<p><em>(This article is republished from <a href="https://theconversation.com">The Conversation</a> under a Creative Commons license. Read the <a href="https://theconversation.com/what-is-an-atlantic-nina-how-la-ninas-smaller-cousin-could-affect-hurricane-season-237425">original article</a>.)</em></p>

<p></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/oclfu018_la-nina_625x300_28_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Representational Image]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/indians-abroad/pm-modi-us-visit-over-24-000-indian-americans-sign-up-for-pm-modis-community-event-in-new-york-6433838]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Over 24,000 Indian-Americans Sign Up For PM Modi's Community Event]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/indians-abroad/pm-modi-us-visit-over-24-000-indian-americans-sign-up-for-pm-modis-community-event-in-new-york-6433838]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 28 Aug 2024 09:42:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[More than 24,000 members of the Indian diaspora have signed up to attend a mega community event that will be addressed by Prime Minister Narendra Modi here next month.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>More than 24,000 members of the Indian diaspora have signed up to attend a mega community event that will be addressed by Prime Minister Narendra Modi here next month.</p>

<p>The ‘Modi &amp; US' Progress Together' event will be held on September 22 at the Nassau Veterans Memorial Coliseum, which has a capacity of 15,000.</p>

<p>The Indo-American Community of USA (IACU) said Tuesday that over 24,000 Indian-Americans have signed up to attend the mega event, a community gathering that will be addressed by Modi.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Modi is scheduled to address the high-level UN General Assembly session here on September 26, according to a provisional list of speakers issued by the UN.</p>

<p>The IACU said in a statement that registrations for the event in Uniondale, Long Island have come through 590 community organisations, all of whom have signed up as ‘Welcome Partners', from across the United States.</p>

<p>While Indian Americans from at least 42 states are expected to attend, the response has been particularly strong from the tri-state area, it said.</p>

<p>"We're committed to ensuring as many people as possible can participate in this historic event," said a key organiser of the event.</p>

<p>"We're going to do our best to expand seating arrangements and coordinate with our Welcome Partners to prioritise final seat allocations to those who will confirm they expect to attend." The IACU said the 'Modi &amp; US' event “promises to be a significant gathering celebrating the interconnected diversity of the Indian-American community.” Attendees and participating organisations will include a wide range of religious communities, including members of the Jewish, Zoroastrian, Jain, Christian, Sikh, Muslim, and Hindu communities. They also represent a significant cross-section of India's diverse languages, including Hindi, Telugu, Punjabi, Tamil, Bengali, Malayalam, Gujarati, and others, IACU said.</p>

<p>In addition to an address by Prime Minister Modi, the event will showcase cultural performances and appearances by prominent Indian-Americans in business, science, entertainment, and the arts.</p>

<p>A not-for-profit organisation, the Indo-American Community of USA (IACU) fosters understanding of and unity within the Indo-American community through cultural events and public programmes.</p>

<p>Earlier this month, sources told PTI that preparations are in full swing for the community event in Long Island, coming 10 years after Modi addressed a massive community gathering at the famed Madison Square Garden in New York in September 2014 just months after he had first taken charge as Prime Minister and visited the city to attend the high-level annual General Assembly session.</p>

<p>In 2019, Modi addressed the mega community event ‘Howdy Modi' at the NRG Stadium in Houston, Texas, where he was joined by former President Donald Trump. This year's visit to the US comes just weeks before the country goes to the presidential polls in November with a race to the top office between Trump and Democratic Presidential nominee Kamala Harris, the first woman of Black and Indian heritage.</p>

<p>This year, the high-level General Debate of the 79th session of the UN General Assembly will take place from September 24-30. As per the provisional list of speakers for the General Debate issued by the UN on Monday, India's “Head of Government” is scheduled to address the high-level session in the afternoon of September 26.</p>

<p>The list is not final and the UN releases updated provisional lists of speakers in the weeks leading up to the high-level session to reflect any modifications in attendance, schedules and speaking slots of leaders, ministers and ambassadors.</p>

<p>Modi took oath in June as India's Prime Minister for a historic third term and last addressed the annual high-level UNGA session in September 2021.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Modi also visited the UN headquarters on June 21 last year, leading the historic Yoga Day commemoration at the North Lawn of the world body's headquarters before heading to Washington DC for a State Visit hosted by former President Joe Biden.</p>

<p>UN Secretary-General Antonio Guterres will present his report before the start of the General Debate, followed by an address by the President of the 79th session of the General Assembly.</p>

<p>Guterres is also convening the ambitious Summit of the Future at UN Headquarters during the high-level week, with the action days slated for September 20-21 and the Summit scheduled on September 22-23.</p>

<p>World leaders will convene at the United Nations to adopt the Pact for the Future, which will include a Global Digital Compact and a Declaration on Future Generations as annexes.</p>

<p>“The Summit is a high-level event, bringing world leaders together to forge a new international consensus on how we deliver a better present and safeguard the future,” the UN has said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2016-06/pm-modi-us-reuters_650x400_61465394623.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Indo-American Community of USA said over 24,000 Indian-Americans have signed up to attend the mega event.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hunters-conservationists-design-safer-traps-to-protect-formosan-bears-6433792]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hunters, Conservationists Design Safer Traps To Protect Formosan Bears]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hunters-conservationists-design-safer-traps-to-protect-formosan-bears-6433792]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 28 Aug 2024 08:43:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[As the cage holding an endangered Formosan black bear swung open conservationists blasted gunshots and air horns to ensure the frightened young bear disappeared quickly into the mountains of central Taiwan, hopefully far from human contact.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As the cage holding an endangered Formosan black bear swung open conservationists blasted gunshots and air horns to ensure the frightened young bear disappeared quickly into the mountains of central Taiwan, hopefully far from human contact.</p>

<p>Ziman, a one-and-a-half-year-old bear, had finally recovered from the amputation of a paw caused by a hunter's steel noose and now had a second chance in life.</p>

<p>"Please take care of him and help him find his parents safely," Pihao Payen, the leader of a nearby ethnic Atayal community, said in a prayer as Ziman disappeared from sight.</p>

<p>Wearing a traditional tribal tunic and headgear decorated with animal horns, the 74-year-old chief and an experienced hunter also prayed for his ancestors' help to keep Ziman away from traps.</p>

<p>Taiwanese hunters and conservationists are teaming up to protect the Formosan black bear, with only a few hundred estimated still in the wild, by designing new traps which will not amputate limbs if they are accidentally caught in a snare.</p>

<p>While bears are not a target for Indigenous Taiwanese hunters, people in Pihao Payen's village accidentally caught bears twice in recent years when laying traps for prey such as deer and boars, a traditional practice in Indigenous culture.</p>

<p>Since 2014, 18 bears have been captured in traps, with six found dead, according to the non-governmental organisation, the Taiwan Black Bear Conservation Association.</p>

<p>While most of the bears were released, some suffered major injuries caused by old-fashioned hunting tools such as metal snares, which can break bones or sever paws or toes as the bear struggles to break free.</p>

<p>"Steel snares bounce off from the ground and tighten up their limbs when triggered by animals," said Liu Li-wen, an animal caretaker who oversaw Ziman's recovery in a government-run bear shelter in the mountains of Taichung.</p>

<p>"The snares turned tighter and tighter as the animal struggled. When blood circulation stopped, his entire paw turned necrotic," she said, showing pictures of Ziman's swollen left paw. Vets had to cut most of the paw off to save the cub's life after two months of treatment.</p>

<p>"That's why we are seeing many bears with broken paws or toes in the wild. It's likely that they were entangled by traps, broke free by themselves and survived," she said.</p>

<h3><strong>NEW SNARES</strong></h3>

<p>The Formosan black bear is one of seven subspecies of Asiatic black bear which is considered vulnerable to extinction by the International Union for Conservation of Nature.</p>

<p>Indigenous to sub-tropical Taiwan with an iconic V-shaped white mark on the chest, the Formosan black bear is seen as a symbol of Taiwanese identity that champions its diverse culture and freedom. Democratic Taiwan was previously better known internationally as Formosa.</p>

<p>To reduce death or injuries of wildlife, the Forestry and Nature Conservation Agency is now urging hunters and farmers to adopt a new type of animal snare designed to only trap smaller prey and which does not tighten to the point of amputation.</p>

<p>More than 5,600 such traps have been given to hunters and farmers for free across mountainous Taiwan which is 60% covered by forest, while monetary rewards are given to those who report cases of bears caught by traps.</p>

<p>"Because of its small size, and because the bear's palm is very wide, you see that it (the bear paw) will not fall in completely when stepped on like this," explained Pan Wen-ming, an ethnic Amis hunter and guava farmer in central Taiwan, as he demonstrated how to set up the new trap to Reuters reporters.</p>

<p>"It tries to minimise (bear injuries) while letting the elders and hunters of our tribe still hunt for prey," he said.</p>

<p>Chen Yen-long, chief of the Wushikeng Research Centre bear shelter in Taichung, said some hunters killed snared bears for fear of being prosecuted for trapping a protected animal.</p>

<p>Sadly, Ziman, the cub with the amputated paw, was found dead in the central mountains only weeks after his release, with authorities unable to determine the cause of death.</p>

<p>"This is not the end of the story. We will not stop what we are doing," said Lai Chiao Ling, one of Ziman's caretakers. "At least there are still bears in the wild for us to save."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/kh3gqt58_formosan-black-bear-reuters-_625x300_28_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Formosan black bear is one of seven subspecies of Asiatic black bear, vulnerable to extinction.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/no-modis-ukraine-visit-wasnt-about-ditching-russia-6433766]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: No, Modi's Ukraine Visit Wasn't About 'Ditching' Russia]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/no-modis-ukraine-visit-wasnt-about-ditching-russia-6433766]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 28 Aug 2024 08:40:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India is not in a position to either alienate the West or Russia, as it needs both to protect and advance its larger national interest.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/kkihncj_pm-modi-and-zelensky_625x300_23_August_24.jpeg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi's visit to Poland and Ukraine is being construed by pro-West lobbies in India as a new thrust of Indian foreign policy towards Central and East Europe, to re-balance and de-hyphenate its engagement with Russia and Central Europe, and more particularly, its ties with Russia and Ukraine.</p>

<p>The view of this lobby is that India, in deference to its Russia sensitivities, did not engage Ukraine and the erstwhile Warsaw Pact countries so far. Modi's visit to Ukraine is therefore seen in these pro-Western circles as a long overdue correction of India's approach to the Russian invasion of Ukraine.</p>

<p>India, it is argued, has all along stayed silent on Russia's unacceptable actions even when they challenged the core principles of India's worldview - the sanctity of national sovereignty and territorial integrity. The political costs of this silence on Russian aggressions have been mounting and ergo the change in India's approach that we see.</p>

<h2><strong>A Shallow Analysis</strong></h2>

<p>This kind of analysis of India's foreign policy is ill-informed, shallow and ideological. Take the Czech Republic as an example of India's supposed lack of engagement with Central and East Europe. Look at the reality: India's former President, Ram Nath Kovind, made a visit there in 2018; the Czech PM visited India in 2019, when the Czech Republic was a partner country at the Vibrant Gujarat Summit; its Defence Minister came in February 2019, its Foreign Minister in January 2020; former CDS General Rawat visited the Czech Republic in November 2021; India's External Affairs Minister (EAM) went there in June 2022; the Czech Foreign Minister came to India in February 2023; the Czech Prime Minister came to India in January 2024 when the India-Czechia Strategic Partnership On Innovation was adopted. The Czech Foreign Minister visited India again in February 2024. Similarly, Prime Minister Orban of Hungary visited India in 2013, the Hungarian Foreign Minister has visited India three times - in 2020, 2022 and 2024 - while India's EAM visited Hungary in 2019. High-level visits have been exchanged with Slovakia too, as well as Poland.</p>

<p>The Russia-Ukraine conflict has posed serious problems for not only India but the international community as a whole. The US, Europe and the G7 are pitted against Russia. China, which has intensive ties with the West, is supporting Russia, bearing in mind that Beijing is now seen by the US as its biggest adversary. It therefore sees the value of Russia as a partner. India has deepening ties with the West but also has close historical ties with Russia. India is not in a position to either alienate the West or Russia, as it needs both to protect and advance its larger national interest.</p>

<h2><strong>The Russia-Ukraine Issue Is Multilayered</strong></h2>

<p>If Russia has committed aggression against Ukraine, the list of aggressions that the US and its partners in NATO have committed against other countries is incomparably longer. If this has not deterred India from forging close ties with the US and NATO countries, why would it be wrong to preserve our ties with Russia? Should we have double standards too?</p>

<p>More pertinently, an objective analysis of the Ukraine conflict would show that the responsibility for it does not lie on one side only. It is not a simple case of violation of the sovereignty and territorial integrity of one country. Much larger and complex issues of historical legacies, geopolitics, national security, balance of power, ethnic rights, external interference, regime change, etc., are involved.</p>

<p>India cannot take a simplistic view of the conflict. More so as those who want to promote the interests of the West should recall that on issues of our own sovereignty and territorial integrity, the record of the West has been adverse to our interests, and is not supportive even now.</p>

<h2><strong>Multilateralism Has Collapsed</strong></h2>

<p>Modi's visit to Ukraine should not be seen as India de-hyphenating its engagement with Russia and Ukraine. India, as well as the global south in general, has been impacted by the Russia-Ukraine conflict in many ways. Europe, too, has been hit by this conflict, which is also against our interest at a time when we seek to deepen our ties with Europe, especially on the trade and technology front, not to mention the larger issues of energy security, climate change, critical technologies, etc., which require constructive cooperation with Europe.</p>

<p>The complete breakdown of a dialogue between the US and Russia is against our interests too. The liberal use of sanctions as a political and economic tool disrupts our ties with Russia as well as with others, like Iran. Multilateralism has virtually collapsed. This prevents much-needed international cooperation to address problems that are global in nature. Viewing Modi's visit to Ukraine only in the context of balancing our ties with Russia is missing the larger point.</p>

<p>All the more so as Russia had been taken into confidence about the visit and no doubt felt assured that India would do nothing to harm its interests. Russia has never counselled us not to engage Ukraine, or, for that matter, forge closer relations with the US, including defence ties, an area of prime interest for Moscow in ties with India. The US, on the contrary, openly asks us to dilute ties with Russia, especially in the defence area.</p>

<h2><strong>A Range Of Reasons</strong></h2>

<p>The reasons for Modi visiting Ukraine are diverse. They flow from a developing willingness to play whatever role is feasible in resolving the conflict peacefully. Modi has been saying in many fora that India is willing to be helpful. India's rising stature under Modi's leadership, the success of India's G-20 presidency, the Indian discourse that we seek friendship with all, that we are in a position to talk to countries that may be adversaries of each other, the belief promoted by our Western interlocutors that Modi, after his homily to Putin that "today is not an era of war", could talk peace to the Russian persuasively, may explain why Modi may have felt it was time to carry his message of dialogue and diplomacy to Kyiv.</p>

<p>Beyond this, Modi may have wanted to defuse rising criticism in the US and Ukraine after his visit to Moscow where he embraced Putin in his signature greeting style that Putin too has adopted, by making a balancing visit to Kyiv. During the visit, he consciously embraced Zelenskyy on three occasions, put his arm around his shoulders and held his hand in a gesture of personal empathy and fellow-feeling. The Ukrainian side, keeping in mind that while in Moscow Modi had expressed great anguish to Putin at the killing of children in war, organised a visit to the exhibition in Kyiv on children killed in the ongoing conflict to expose Modi to Russian brutalities. The Ukrainian side had also wanted Modi to visit the hospital allegedly bombed by Russia, but the Indian side would have resisted being drawn into too many anti-Russia elements in the programme.</p>

<h2><strong>India's Position Is Clear</strong></h2>

<p>On substance, India yielded nothing during the visit on the fundamentals of its position on the conflict. India did not endorse Zelenskyy's 10-point peace plan that the Ukrainian president lobbied for. EAM Jaishankar declared in his press briefing that there were multiple ways of approaching the issue of peace talks. India's position is clearly reflected in the joint statement, to the effect that all stakeholders should be engaged to develop innovative solutions that should have broad acceptability. Jaishankar made it a point to draw attention to this para in the joint statement in his press briefing.</p>

<p>It is noteworthy that in the joint statement with Poland and Ukraine, the paragraphs on the Ukraine issue make no mention of Russia by name, just as in the case of the G-20 Delhi Declaration. But there, neither Ukraine nor Poland were present. This was a notable success of Indian diplomacy.<br />
India preserved its equities with Russia while engaging Zelenskyy in Ukraine.</p>

<p>Perhaps the failure to draw India to his side and drive some wedge between India and Russia would explain Zelenskyy's remarks to the Indian press in Kyiv that conveyed his differences with India on substance and altogether lacked diplomatic propriety.</p>

<p><em>(Kanwal Sibal was Foreign Secretary and Ambassador to Turkey, Egypt, France and Russia, and Deputy Chief Of Mission in Washington.)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/kkihncj_pm-modi-and-zelensky_625x300_23_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>