<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Sep 2024 13:54:04 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/campaign-launched-to-increase-participation-of-indian-americans-in-us-polls-6487668]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Campaign Launched To Increase Participation Of Indian-Americans In US Polls]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/campaign-launched-to-increase-participation-of-indian-americans-in-us-polls-6487668]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Sep 2024 13:33:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ahead of the November 5 US presidential elections, an Indian diaspora group has launched a campaign to increase the policy impact and participation of Indian-American voters in the polls.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ahead of the November 5 US presidential elections, an Indian diaspora group has launched a campaign to increase the policy impact and participation of Indian-American voters in the polls.</p>

<p>Launched by the non-profit institution Foundation for India and Indian Diaspora Studies (FIIDS), the "Indo American Votes Matter" campaign underscores the critical role the community can play in shaping the nation's future, a statement issued on Tuesday said.</p>

<p>"As a vibrant and growing immigrant minority, Indo-Americans-- numbering approximately 4.5 million across the United States -- have a unique opportunity to make a significant impact in the 2024 elections. Concentrated in key swing states such as Florida, Georgia, Arizona, Virginia, New Jersey, and Pennsylvania, the Indo-American vote could be decisive in determining the outcome of crucial races," the FIIDS said.</p>

<p>A comprehensive survey of Indian-Americans will gather their views on both domestic and global policy matters of the US important to them, it said.</p>

<p>"With a sizable population in swing states crucial to the presidential elections, Indian-Americans have a unique opportunity to make an impact," said Khanderao Kand, chief of policy and strategy at FIIDS.</p>

<p>"Therefore, their policy issues and preferences should be seriously considered by both the Republican National Committee (RNC) and the Democratic National Committee (DNC). With the voters registration campaign, we want to have at least a million plus Indian American voters in this election," Kand said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ugf3uu1g_trump-harris-_625x300_22_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The "Indo American Votes Matter" campaign marks the the critical role the Indian diaspora can play (file)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-luck-often-trumps-justice-in-us-immigration-system-6487571]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How Luck Often Trumps Justice In US Immigration System]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-luck-often-trumps-justice-in-us-immigration-system-6487571]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Sep 2024 13:21:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The US asylum process is meant to offer a fair shot at safe haven. But new reporting from Bloomberg uncovers how the difference between those who are granted asylum and those who are denied often boils down to chance.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The US asylum process is meant to offer a fair shot at safe haven. But new reporting from Bloomberg uncovers how the difference between those who are granted asylum and those who are denied often boils down to chance.</p>

<p>On today's Big Take podcast, Bloomberg investigative reporter Monte Reel joins host David Gura to trace the arc of one man's journey and discuss new data analysis that reveals the flaws at the core of the US asylum system.</p>

<h3><strong>Here is a lightly edited transcript of the conversation:</strong></h3>

<p><strong>David Gura</strong>: In 2018, 29-year-old Yerandy Valdes fled Cuba, where he was born and raised. He'd been targeted by the police, put in prison, and he feared for his life. Monte Reel, a senior investigative reporter at Bloomberg, says Valdes made it, months later, to the US-Mexico border:</p>

<p><strong>Monte Reel</strong>: He crossed a bridge across the Rio Grande to McAllen, Texas. And there's a border patrol station on the US side of that bridge. And he turned himself in to Border Patrol officers, and announced that he wanted to apply for asylum.</p>

<p><strong>Gura</strong>: Valdes was one of tens of thousands of people that year, who hoped the US government would agree with them, that life in their home countries had become too dangerous. Monte says that, as soon as Valdes told Border Patrol he wanted to apply for asylum, an agent peppered him with questions. He was given what's known as a "credible fear interview."</p>

<p><strong>Reel:</strong> And so, they ask him the nature of his fears in Cuba, and so he really, you know, started to think about this, and he wasn't sure where to start.</p>

<p><strong>Gura</strong>: Because there was so much to say. There was the story of what had happened to his dad. At the time, it had been illegal to operate a private business in Cuba - but Valdes' dad defied those rules. He ran an auto shop, and owned a food cart. He was arrested and found guilty of "enrichment at the expense of the state."</p>

<p><strong>Reel</strong>: And so, when Valdes was a kid, his father was in jail for almost 15 years.</p>

<p><strong>Gura</strong>: His dad escaped the country and was legally admitted to the US. But then, Monte says, Valdes became a target.</p>

<p><strong>Reel</strong>: He himself had a churro cart, you know, selling snacks. Those carts were confiscated by the government. He was thrown in jail. He, in fact, became so disenchanted with the Cuban government that he actually got a tattoo on his forearm, and the tattoo said that Cuba is a prison of the living dead.</p>

<p><strong>Gura</strong>: And that small act of protest made things worse. He believes someone saw that tattoo, and reported him.</p>

<p><strong>Reel</strong>: The jail authorities threatened to burn it off. And in fact, they singed his arm by the tattoo with a hot spoon.</p>

<p><strong>Gura</strong>: Valdes tried to leave Cuba over and over again, but he was caught and arrested. So, in 2018, he felt some relief. He'd made it to US soil, he had an opportunity to make his case, and that border patrol agent found Valdes' fear of persecution credible. But this was just the first step in what became a years-long process, and what happened next shows how capricious - and, Monte says, how broken - the US asylum process is. This is "The Big Take," from Bloomberg News. I'm David Gura, and today on the show, a story about one person who applied for asylum in the US in the last decade - one of hundreds of thousands, and what his experience tells us about how arbitrary and unjust that system is.</p>

<p><strong>Gura</strong>: After Yerandy Valdes made it through that first interview at the border, the agent had to decide whether to let Valdes live with his dad, before a court hearing or if he should be detained. And Bloomberg's Monte Reels says he chose the latter.</p>

<p><strong>Reel</strong>: If you talk to immigration lawyers, they will say that these decisions to detain or to parole often feel arbitrary. That there's no real reason behind them. Technically, the reason given for Valdes becoming a detainee was that he was a flight risk.</p>

<p><strong>Gura</strong>: In the US, more than 80% of asylum seekers get parole. But Valdes was not one of them. And according to Monte, that denial made it less likely Valdes' application for asylum would be approved. The next question then, was where he would be detained? And Monte says the answer was, as it often is with asylum cases: "Wherever there's space."</p>

<p><strong>Reel</strong>: So, he is transferred to a detention facility in rural Louisiana.</p>

<p><strong>Gura</strong>: Back then, around 2018, ICE opened up several new detention centers in the American South. Valdes was sent to one of them. It's in the small town of Pine Prairie. And getting sent there Monte says made his odds of getting asylum even tougher:</p>

<p><strong>Reel</strong>: It just so happens that, when you get assigned to a detention center, your case travels to that location. So, if he had been, for example, sent to New York City, about 29% of asylum cases in New York City are denied, and those people are ordered deported. In Louisiana, where he was sent, more than 80% are denied. So that was, you know, a pretty fateful circumstance.</p>

<p><strong>Gura</strong>: Valdes, like many others, would learn that, in the asylum process, geography matters. And something else that can make a huge difference, Monte says, is which immigration judge gets your case. His was assigned to Agnelis Reese.</p>

<p><strong>Reel</strong>: He got a judge who, in the past 11 years before his case, had heard hundreds of asylum cases and hadn't granted asylum to a single one of them.</p>

<p><strong>Gura</strong>: About six months later, Valdes got his day in court.</p>

<p><strong>Reel</strong>: He was there, his father was there as a supporting witness. And the proceeding is held essentially like a trial. There's a government attorney who's acting sort of as a prosecutor. And this is an attorney with the Department of Homeland Security who essentially is arguing for deportation. The judge is overseeing all of this and throwing in questions of her own, and so it becomes a hearing that will serve as sort of a one-day trial. This is his chance to present his case.</p>

<p><strong>Gura</strong>: Now, one of the key differences between immigration courts and civil courts, or criminal courts, is that immigration courts fall under the executive branch, not the judicial branch.</p>

<p><strong>Reel</strong>: So the person who's overseeing the immigration courts is actually the attorney general, which is a political appointee. So one of the reasons a lot of people want reform in this system is they say that these immigration courts are more susceptible to political meddling, political influence, because of that structure.</p>

<p><strong>Gura</strong>: Four months before Valdes' hearing, Jeff Sessions, who was the US attorney general at the time, put in place a quota system that required every immigration court judge to make at least 700 rulings every year. All of a sudden, everyone had a busy docket, and Monte says that's reflected in the court records:</p>

<p><strong>Reel</strong>: There was pressure on judges to move cases through their courtrooms quickly. And in the transcripts, you can definitely see that come through with the judge in Valdes' case. She's- the judge was definitely in a hurry. Valdes was presenting his evidence through a translator, and there were several times in the hearing where the translation was imprecise.</p>

<p><strong>Gura</strong>: At one point, the immigration judge asked Valdes about what happened when Cuban police gave him trouble for having that snack cart:</p>

<p><strong>Reel</strong>: He used the verb decomisar, which in Spanish means confiscated. They were confiscated. The translator, she said, "de-commiserated." And the judge had a problem understanding what she meant, and really kind of, took out that misunderstanding on Valdes. She ruled that he was being unresponsive.</p>

<p><strong>Gura</strong>: But that wasn't the only thing that stood out to Monte, when he read the transcript of Valdes' court hearing. The judge believed there were inconsistencies in Valdes' story.</p>

<p><strong>Reel</strong>: He had told her in the courtroom that, during one of the periods where he was jailed, that the officers had beaten him with a club, hit him in the head and had fractured his skull. And she went back and looked at the credible fear interview, and the credible fear interview, keep in mind, it's not a verbatim transcript. These are just notes that are taken- summary notes by the interviewing officer. And in that interview, he said that he had been hit in the head with a police stick, and that it had broken open his head and created a wound.</p>

<p><strong>Gura</strong>: The judge seized on that difference - how Valdes described something as a "fracture" in her courtroom, and as a "wound" in that first conversation with border patrol. "In his interview with asylum officers," she wrote, "he did not mention his head being fractured." This was something at "the heart of the claim," she said, and rendered his testimony "non-credible." Judge Reese denied Valdes' request for asylum. She retired in 2022. And she did not respond to Bloomberg's requests for comment.</p>

<p><strong>Gura</strong>: How common is it to have a proceeding go this way? As you just kind of look at, look at others, for there to be difficulties with translation or cultural misunderstanding?</p>

<p><strong>Reel</strong>: Yeah, if you talk to immigration lawyers who've had a lot of experience in these courts, they are full of stories about mistranslations, about misinterpretations of testimony, of judges who are hurried and who, in some cases, display a sort of callousness towards the people who are testifying. And you know, in some cases, sure, there are people who are entering the asylum system with claims that are invalid - that just don't hold up. But there are people who have gone through trauma, and who enter these courtrooms, and who face judges that oftentimes are hurried and don't give their cases the hearing that they might deserve.</p>

<p><strong>Gura</strong>: Under the current system, judges are routinely required to deliver an oral decision at the conclusion of a hearing immediately after the testimony is given without adjourning. One former immigration judge told Monte that means two similar cases can have very different outcomes, depending on the judge. In an Ohio case, for example, a 22-year old woman testified she had been raped by military officers. They were looking for her relatives, who were activists. That asylum applicant said they'd found her alone, at home, early one morning. The immigration judge in Ohio, overseeing that case, denied her request, saying the assault could not be considered "state-sanctioned violence," because, in Cameroon, quote, "police officers are not allowed to enter a private home at night in search of a criminal suspect" end quote. Valdes pressed on. He took the decision in his case to the Board of Immigration Appeals, which is the appellate body of US immigration courts. But Monte says Valdes recognized his odds were getting even worse.</p>

<p><strong>Reel</strong>: That body sustains the vast majority of cases that they hear. So, whenever it came time for his appeal, it was a last-ditch effort, and one he knew he probably wasn't going to win.</p>

<p><strong>Gura</strong>: Valdes was sent back to Pine Prairie, Louisiana, to that ICE detention center. Six months later after Valdes submitted his appeal, the board denied his request.</p>

<p><strong>Reel</strong>: He was put on a deportation flight to Havana and the plane lands in Havana at the airport and even before he gets off the plane, the police are waiting for him.</p>

<p><strong>Gura</strong>: After the break, another turn in the story of Yerandy Valdes, and what his story says about who is - and who isn't - being granted asylum in the US today.</p>

<p><strong>Gura</strong>: Yerandy Valdes spent more than a year in an ICE detention facility in Pine Prairie, Louisiana, after an immigration judge rejected his application for asylum, and before a board denied his appeal. I asked Bloomberg's Monte Reel how the asylum system in the US is supposed to work - if it's supposed to take this long.</p>

<p><strong>Reel</strong>: Someone who is being persecuted by their home government, they apply for asylum, and then their case goes before a judge and the person is supposed to present their case to the judge. The judge hears it and makes a ruling quickly and that person either then is on the path for citizenship in the United States or they're deported. And it's supposed to be a pretty quick process. But the reality is that these cases now drag on for years.</p>

<p><strong>Gura</strong>: And that's partly because of how many cases there are - how many migrants are asking for asylum.</p>

<p><strong>Reel</strong>: Well, the court system has just become increasingly overwhelmed with cases and a backlog of cases. So since 2016, that backlog of immigration court cases has grown from about 500,000 to about 3.7 million. And asylum cases alone, they're a part of that backlog. They account for about 1.3 million of those cases.</p>

<p><strong>Gura</strong>: Monte says asylum seekers and lawyers alike - and even some immigration judges themselves - argue the system is in sore need of reform.</p>

<p><strong>Reel</strong>: One of the things that the judges themselves say is that there's too much political influence in the system. There are also a lot of judges in especially rural immigration courts, places like rural Louisiana, where there, there's not a huge pool of people who qualify, who are living near those courtrooms. 62% of the people who end up being appointed judges there had previously served as staff attorneys for the Department of Homeland Security. In other words, they were prosecutors. And if you look at the judges overall, you know, there are those judges who deny almost all cases. You can find other judges in other jurisdictions, for example, in San Francisco, who deny only, say, 20% of the cases. Critics of the immigration court system say that the variances between judges are so extreme that that ends up becoming the most important part of a case. It's not the merits of the case. It's actually the luck of the draw.</p>

<p><strong>Gura</strong>: And Yerandy Valdes? He got a series of bad draws - when he was detained, when he was sent to Louisiana to await trial and when he was sent back to Cuba, where he was put in prison.</p>

<p><strong>Reel</strong>: When he was released in 2022, at this time, he began sort of documenting abuses that he would see by the Cuban government.</p>

<p><strong>Gura</strong>: He made videos about his own experiences</p>

<p>Yerandy Valdes (in Spanish): Hello, my name is Yerandy Valdes Ruiz.</p>

<p><strong>Gura</strong>: In one, he introduces himself as a human rights activist.</p>

<p>Valdes (in Spanish): I am an activist for human rights.</p>

<p><strong>Gura</strong>: He also recorded protests and videos of what he saw as examples of government failures. Like this one, after Hurricane Ian decimated western Cuba in late September 2022. You see him walking through the wreckage, pointing out damage, and asking residents if they're getting the help they need.</p>

<p><strong>Reel</strong>: And he sent those videos to video bloggers in the United States anti-Cuban bloggers who had programs on YouTube and that sort of thing out of Miami. And he became something of, like, a citizen journalist correspondent, trying to detail abuses in the Cuban regime.</p>

<p><strong>Gura</strong>: And Valdes decided he would try again - to leave Cuba. In 2023, he boarded a raft made out of a car frame, and kept afloat by plastic containers, and floated for two days across the Caribbean, before he came ashore on Mexico's Yucatan Peninsula. He worked odd jobs there for eight months before he once again made his way through Mexico, to its border with the US.</p>

<p><strong>Reel</strong>: And, you know, the way it works is you generally pay coyotes to help you across the border. He did that, and this time, they didn't cross at a bridge like he did the last time. This time they crossed in ranchland in Arizona. He was picked up by the border patrol, and now for a second time, he entered the asylum system.</p>

<p><strong>Gura</strong>: Valdes was in a different state. The US had a different president. And the process had changed. Border Patrol gave him a new form to fill out, one called an I-220A.</p>

<p><strong>Reel</strong>: What it meant for Valdes at the time was that he was allowed to go and live with his father. So he joined his father in Missouri. In 2023, and he's there now, and he's awaiting his first court hearing in the immigration courts, which will happen in Missouri, not in Louisiana this time</p>

<p><strong>Gura</strong>: That hearing is scheduled for January 2026. And Monte says Valdes is more optimistic. This time, he's going to go before another judge, and he has a cell phone full of videos to support his case. But the odds are not in his favor. In the Missouri court where his hearing will take place the denial rate for asylum seekers is 76%</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/bmu0c3n8_us-immigration-_625x300_04_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The difference between those who are granted asylum and those who are denied often boils down to chance.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nasa-images-show-construction-of-egypts-brand-new-capital-city-6487510]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[NASA Images Show Construction Of Egypt's Brand-New Capital City]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nasa-images-show-construction-of-egypts-brand-new-capital-city-6487510]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Sep 2024 13:10:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The city dubbed as The New Administrative Capital (NAC) will be a sprawling metropolis, comparable in size to Singapore, and designed to accommodate over 6 million residents.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Cairo, Egypt's capital, boasts a history spanning over 1,000 years, earning its reputation as one of the world's most iconic cities. However, the country has decided to relocate its capital, and recent images from NASA have captured the rapid development of the brand-new capital city being built in the desert 45 kilometres (28 miles) east of Cairo. According to <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.newsweek.com/egypt-new-capital-cairo-nasa-satellite-images-1946656#:~:text=Egypt's%20historic%20capital%2C%20Cairo%2C%20is,28%20miles%20to%20its%20east." rel="nofollow, noindex">Newsweek,</a></em> the plan to move the new capital was first announced back in 2015, driven by the need to address Cairo's swelling population, traffic congestion and pollution.</p>

<p>Images of the new capital were acquired by the OLI (Operational Land Imager) on Landsat 8 and the OLI-2 on Landsat 9 in August 2017 and August 2024 respectively. In the earlier image, traces of the city are visible as the work on the megaproject had begun by this time. The second image&nbsp;shows the progress of the construction of the new city in 2024.</p>

<p>"Egypt is relocating its capital to a brand new city in the desert outside of Cario. #Landsat captured these images of the new capital in August 2017 and 2024, showing the expansion of the city and several prominent landmarks," NASA Earth wrote on X.</p>

<p><strong>See the image here:</strong></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Egypt is relocating its capital to a brand new city in the desert outside of Cario. <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Landsat?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Landsat</a> captured these images of the new capital in August 2017 and 2024, showing the expansion of the city and several prominent landmarks. <a href="https://t.co/jvJhqrEuvA">https://t.co/jvJhqrEuvA</a> <a href="https://t.co/hDgPRSZFpG">pic.twitter.com/hDgPRSZFpG</a></p>
— NASA Earth (@NASAEarth) <a href="https://twitter.com/NASAEarth/status/1829887894254666210?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 31, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Notably, the city dubbed as The New Administrative Capital (NAC) will be a sprawling metropolis, comparable in size to Singapore, and designed to accommodate over six million residents. This futuristic city will feature sleek skyscrapers, including a 77-storey tower, as well as Egyptian government offices, major financial hubs, and other impressive infrastructure. It is estimated to cost over $58 billion.</p>

<p>The images by NASA reveal the impressive landmarks of Egypt's new capital city, including a&nbsp;10-kilometre-long Green River Park, offering walking and biking paths.&nbsp;Many government ministry offices also comprise the dense development to the east of the park, while the Ministry of Defense occupies a sizeable facility called The Octagon. The images also feature a massive sports complex featuring Africa's second-largest stadium aimed at catching the attention of the Olympic committee.</p>

<p>More than 1,500 families have moved to the new capital, with the population expected to reach 10,000 by the end of the year.</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/4ictnh0o_egypts-new-capital_625x300_04_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The city is set to become the new hub for government and business operations.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/beware-of-handsome-men-beautiful-women-chinas-spy-warning-to-students-6487421]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA['Beware Of Handsome Men, Beautiful Women': China's Spy Warning to Students]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/beware-of-handsome-men-beautiful-women-chinas-spy-warning-to-students-6487421]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Sep 2024 13:00:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[China's state security agency on Wednesday warned students with access to sensitive information against falling for "handsome men" or "beautiful women" that might entice them to spy for foreign powers.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>China's state security agency on Wednesday warned students with access to sensitive information against falling for "handsome men" or "beautiful women" that might entice them to spy for foreign powers.</p>

<p>Beijing's Ministry of State Security (MSS) has promoted claims that foreign spies are working to lure loyal Chinese to betray their country -- often in lurid and unusual ways -- since opening a WeChat account last year.</p>

<p>It has warned that foreign spies "have countless disguises, and can even change their gender" and called on citizens to "build 1.4 billion lines of defence" against threats to the country.</p>

<p>And it accused on Wednesday foreign intelligence agencies of deploying "romance traps" to lure Chinese students.</p>

<p>It said foreign spies were using job ads and even online dating to "lure and coerce" young students, especially those with access to "sensitive scientific research data", to hand over confidential information.</p>

<p>"They may even disguise themselves as 'handsome men' or 'beautiful women'... and drag young students into 'romance trap'," it warned.</p>

<p>The MSS did not name which countries were behind the alleged scheme.</p>

<p>But it warned that spies might be disguising themselves as university scholars, scientific researchers or consultants, luring students short of cash in what it called "targeted infiltration".</p>

<p>In another lurid tale this month, the MSS warned the public to beware "wolves in sheep's clothing" -- foreign agents pretending to be "good Samaritans".</p>

<p>In June, it accused Britain's MI6 intelligence agency of recruiting a couple who worked for the central government to spy for the UK.</p>

<p>Under Xi Jinping, China's most powerful and authoritarian leader in decades, Beijing has stepped up dark warnings that foreign powers are seeking to clip the country's rise.</p>

<p>China and Western powers have long traded accusations of spying but only recently started to disclose details of alleged individual cases.</p>

<p>In May, investigators searched the Brussels office of a German MEP suspected of spying for China.</p>

<p>And on Tuesday, a former official who worked as an aide to the governor of New York state was arrested and charged with working as an agent of China in return for millions of dollars.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-05/nkud288s_china-flag_625x300_20_May_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[China and Western powers have long traded accusations of spying (representational).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-man-70-died-after-doctor-removed-wrong-organ-during-surgery-lawsuit-6487372]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Man, 70, Died After Doctor Removed Wrong Organ During Surgery: Lawsuit]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-man-70-died-after-doctor-removed-wrong-organ-during-surgery-lawsuit-6487372]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Sep 2024 12:52:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 70-year-old man in the United States died on an operating table after the doctor mistakenly removed the wrong organ during surgery.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 70-year-old man in the United States died on an operating table after the doctor mistakenly removed the wrong organ during surgery, the <em>New York Post</em> reported. William Bryan and his wife Beverly were visiting their rental property in Florida last month when he suddenly began experiencing lower left abdominal pain. They immediately went to Ascension Sacred Heart Emerald Coast Hospital, where the 70-year-old was admitted for further tests over concerns about an abnormality of the spleen. The doctors then convinced the man to undergo surgery at the hospital. However, the operation led to the death of the man after the doctor mistakenly removed the man's liver during surgery before the surgeon attempted to pass off the organ as an "enlarged spleen," according to a lawyer representing the man's widow.</p>

<p>In a Facebook post, the law firm claimed that General Surgeon Dr Thomas Shaknovsky and the hospital's Chief Medical Officer Dr Christopher Bacani persuaded the reluctant family for the 70-year-old to undergo surgery at the hospital or he "could experience serious complications if he left the hospital". Mr Bryan agreed with the doctors and underwent a hand-assisted laparoscopic splenectomy procedure in August. "From the records it appears, both physicians were involved in the discussion as to the appropriateness of the planned procedure and the capabilities of the facility to accommodate such," the law firm wrote.&nbsp;</p>

<p><iframe allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="true" frameborder="0" height="476" scrolling="no" src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/video.php?height=476&amp;href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2Fzarzaurlaw%2Fvideos%2F382732311330894%2F&amp;show_text=false&amp;width=267&amp;t=0" style="border:none;overflow:hidden" width="267"></iframe></p>

<p>In the middle of the surgery, Mr Shaknovsky removed Mr Bryan's liver by transecting the major vasculature supplying the liver. The surgical cut resulted in "immediate and catastrophic blood loss resulting in death," the Facebook post read.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The law firm claimed that after the doctors mistakenly removed Mr Bryan's liver, the general surgeon labelled the organ as a "spleen," which was only identified as a liver after the man's death. The surgeons meanwhile explained to Mr Bryan's wife that her husband's "spleen" was so diseased that it was four times bigger than usual and had migrated to the other side of his body. "The family was informed that Mr. Bryan's spleen, the root of his original symptom profile upon presentation to the hospital, was still in his body and appeared with a small cyst on its surface," the law firm said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Notably, inside the human body, the liver is located on the upper right side of the abdominal cavity, just below the diaphragm, and above the stomach, right kidney, and intestines. The spleen, on the other hand, is located on the upper left side of the abdomen next to the stomach and is significantly smaller and lighter than the liver.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/feature/neuralinks-first-patient-names-his-brain-chip-eve-uses-it-to-learn-math-and-new-languages-6487096">Neuralink's First Patient Names His Brain Chip "Eve", Uses It To Learn Math And Languages</a></strong></p>

<p>In the Facebook post, Zarzaur Law claimed that Dr Shaknovsky had a previous "wrong-site surgery" back in 2023 where he supposedly removed a portion of a patient's pancreas instead of performing the intended adrenal gland resection.</p>

<p>Beverly Brayns retained the law firm to get "justice" for her husband and is hoping the general surgeon no longer treats other patients. "My husband died while helpless on the operating room table by Dr. Shaknovsky. I don't want anyone else to die due to his incompetence at a hospital that should have known or knew he had previously made drastic, life-altering surgical mistakes," the widow said in a statement through the law firm. She also added that she is pushing for both civil and criminal proceedings related to her husband's death.&nbsp;</p>

<p>North Walton Doctor's Hospital "disassociated" itself from Shaknovsky and has removed all photos and references to the doctor from its website, according to the law firm. Ascension Sacred Heart Emerald Coast Hospital said it was investigating the man's death.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/09/04/us-news/alabama-husband-william-bryan-dies-on-florida-hospital-operating-table-after-dr-thomas-shaknovsky-removes-liver/" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>Post</em></a>, an apparent small cyst was discovered later on Mr Bryan's spleen which is believed to be the cause of the pain he was hospitalized for.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ibqkel4o_doctor-generic_625x300_20_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The incident took place in August. (Representaive pic)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/x-investors-have-lost-24-billion-since-elon-musk-takeover-in-2022-report-6487295]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[X Investors Have Lost $24 Billion Since Elon Musk Takeover In 2022: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/x-investors-have-lost-24-billion-since-elon-musk-takeover-in-2022-report-6487295]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Sep 2024 12:42:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[When Elon Musk acquired X (then Twitter) in 2022 for $44 billion, he did so with the backing of a formidable group of investors, including Saudi Prince Alwaleed bin Talal, Twitter co-founder Jack Dorsey and leading Silicon Valley venture capital firm]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When Elon Musk acquired X (then Twitter) in 2022 for $44 billion, he did so with the backing of a formidable group of investors, including Saudi Prince Alwaleed bin Talal, Twitter co-founder Jack Dorsey and leading Silicon Valley venture capital firms. However, under Mr Musk's leadership, Twitter's valuation has nosedived, leaving these investors with substantial financial losses.</p>

<p>Mr Musk and his group of investors have reportedly lost over $24 billion in paper value on their investment, the Washington Post reported. The value of the company has plummeted by 72 per cent since October 2022.</p>

<p>https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2024/09/01/musk-twitter-investors-underwater/</p>

<p>According to a Washington Post analysis,&nbsp; the eight largest initial investments have collectively lost approximately $5 billion in value since Mr Musk's takeover. The overall stake has shed $24 billion in value, with investors like Jack Dorsey, Larry Ellison and Sequoia Capital facing significant losses.</p>

<p>Prince Alwaleed bin Talal, the second-largest investor in X after Mr Musk, insists on valuing his stake at $1.9 billion despite external assessments pointing to significant devaluation. The Prince attributes this confidence to X's investments in Musk's artificial intelligence startup, xAI, and stresses prioritising revenue growth in the platform's future.</p>

<p>The deal has faced scrutiny, with the SEC investigating Mr Musk's purchase for potential fraud. Advertisers have fled the platform due to controversies, and some investors have received subpoenas as part of the probe.</p>

<p>Here's a breakdown of the largest initial investors and their losses:</p>

<ul>
	<li>Elon Musk: -$24.12 billion</li>
	<li>Prince Alwaleed bin Talal (and Kingdom Holding Co.): -$1.36 billion</li>
	<li>Jack Dorsey: -$720 million</li>
	<li>Larry Ellison: -$720 million</li>
	<li>Sequoia Capital: -$576 million</li>
	<li>Vy Capital: -$504 million</li>
	<li>Binance: -$360 million</li>
	<li>Andreessen Horowitz: -$288 million</li>
	<li>Qatar Investment Authority: -$270 million</li>
</ul>

<p>One of the major factors contributing to X's financial troubles is the exodus of advertisers. Many companies have grown wary of Elon Musk's approach to content moderation, which prioritises a more relaxed stance on free speech. However, this approach has put X at odds with regulatory bodies, leading to a suspension in Brazil over the platform's refusal to censor certain political content.</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/ofh8h8ro_elon-musk_625x300_27_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Elon Musk had taken over Twitter in 2022.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-were-the-4-indians-killed-in-the-us-car-crash-6487112]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Who Were The 4 Indians Killed In The US Car Crash?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-were-the-4-indians-killed-in-the-us-car-crash-6487112]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Sep 2024 12:17:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Four Indians were charred to death in a massive car crash in Texas, US, on Friday. The victims, who were carpooling to Arkansas, were identified as Aryan Raghunath Orampati, Farooq Shaik, Lokesh Palacharla and Dharshini Vasudevan.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Four Indians were charred to death in a massive car crash in Texas, US, on Friday. The victims, who were carpooling to Arkansas, were identified as Aryan Raghunath Orampati, Farooq Shaik, Lokesh Palacharla and Dharshini Vasudevan.</p>

<p>A speeding truck rear-ended the SUV they were travelling in, causing it to explode and burst into flames. The authorities are relying on DNA testing to confirm their identities.&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>Aryan Raghunath Orampati</strong></h3>

<p>Aryan Raghunath Orampati, a resident of Hyderabad, loved music, travelling, and sports, and had an "unbending fascination" for Finance. He had a degree in Electrical, Electronics, and Communications Engineering from Amrita Vishwa Vidyapeetham, Tamil Nadu and a Master's in Finance from the University of Texas at Dallas. His father Subhash Chandra Reddy owns a Hyderabad-based firm named Max Agri Genetics Private Limited.</p>

<p>Mr Orampati worked as an Accounting Intern at Max Agri-Genetics Pvt Ltd. in India before he earned a full-time position at the company for over a year. He was returning from visiting his cousin in Dallas when the tragedy struck.&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>Farooq Shaik</strong></h3>

<p>Farooq Shaik, also a Hyderabad resident, was travelling to Bentonville to meet his friend when he met with the fatal car accident. He had gone to the US three years ago to pursue his MS degree, which he completed recently, revealed his father. His father, Masthan Vali is a retired private employee.&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>Lokesh Palacharla</strong></h3>

<p>Lokesh Palacharla, from Andhra Pradesh, was a banker in the Bank of America in Allen, Texas. He was travelling to Bentonville to meet his wife.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Mr Palacharla held a Master's degree in Informatics from Northeastern University. He worked at Tech Mahindra in Hyderabad. Before that, he worked at BrainVita Pvt Ltd in Kakinada, Andhra Pradesh.</p>

<h3><strong>Dharshini Vasudevan</strong></h3>

<p>Dharshini Vasudevan completed her Master's degree from the University of Texas and was working in the US. She was on her way to visit her uncle in Bentonville, Arkansas, when the car she was travelling in got rear-ended. Ms Vasudevan's father sought help locating her through an X post, tagging External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar, after she became unreachable following the accident.</p>

<p>In his emotional post, he shared details about his daughter's stay in the US, mentioning her Indian passport number, address in Frisco, Texas, and her activities on the day of the accident. He explained that Ms Vasudevan had taken a carpool ride with three others around 3 pm and was actively messaging until 4 pm, after which all contact was lost with her.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/g5v6fgt_indians-who-died-in-texas-crash-_625x300_04_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The victims were carpooling to Arkansas when the accident occurred.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/ai-chip-nvidia-ceo-us-antitrust-nvidia-gets-doj-subpoena-in-escalating-antitrust-probe-6487088]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Nvidia Gets DOJ Subpoena In Escalating Antitrust Probe]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/ai-chip-nvidia-ceo-us-antitrust-nvidia-gets-doj-subpoena-in-escalating-antitrust-probe-6487088]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Sep 2024 12:10:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The DOJ, which had previously delivered questionnaires to companies, is now sending legally binding requests that oblige recipients to provide information]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The US Justice Department sent subpoenas to Nvidia Corp. and other companies as it seeks evidence that the chipmaker violated antitrust laws, an escalation of its investigation into the dominant provider of AI processors.</p>

<p>The DOJ, which had previously delivered questionnaires to companies, is now sending legally binding requests that oblige recipients to provide information, according to people familiar with the investigation. That takes the government a step closer to launching a formal complaint.</p>

<p>Antitrust officials are concerned that Nvidia is making it harder to switch to other suppliers and penalizes buyers that don't exclusively use its artificial intelligence chips, according to the people, who asked not to be identified because the discussions are private.</p>

<p>Nvidia shares, which suffered a record-setting $279 billion rout on Tuesday, fell further in late trading after Bloomberg reported on the subpoenas. Still, the stock has more than doubled this year - fueled by explosive sales growth at the Santa Clara, California-based chipmaker.</p>

<p>As part of the probe, which Bloomberg previously reported in June, investigators have been contacting other technology companies to gather information. The DOJ's San Francisco office is taking the lead running the inquiry, the people said. A representative for the DOJ declined to comment.</p>

<p>In response to questions about the probe, Nvidia said that its market dominance stems from the quality of its products, which deliver faster performance.</p>

<p>"Nvidia wins on merit, as reflected in our benchmark results and value to customers, who can choose whatever solution is best for them," the company said in an emailed statement.</p>

<p>Nvidia has drawn regulatory scrutiny since becoming the world's most valuable chipmaker and a key beneficiary of the AI spending boom. Sales have been more than doubling each quarter, and it's eclipsed onetime chip leaders such as Intel Corp.</p>

<p>In the DOJ probe, regulators have been investigating Nvidia's acquisition of RunAI, a deal announced in April. That company makes software for managing AI computing, and there are concerns that the tie-up will make it more difficult for customers to switch away from Nvidia chips. Regulators also are inquiring whether Nvidia gives preferential supply and pricing to customers who use its technology exclusively or buy its complete systems, according to the people.</p>

<p>Nvidia, founded in 1993, made its name by selling graphics cards to computer gamers. But its approach to chipmaking ultimately proved useful for building AI models, a process that involves bombarding the software with data. The company also has rapidly expanded its lineup with a range of software, servers, networking and services - all aimed, Nvidia argues, at speeding up the deployment of AI.</p>

<p>Nvidia Chief Executive Officer Jensen Huang said he prioritizes customers who can make use of his products in ready-to-go data centers as soon as he provides them, a policy designed to prevent stockpiling and speed up the broader adoption of AI.</p>

<p>The success of its products - along with struggles by rivals to field alternative chips - has made Nvidia a crucial part of the supply chain for some of the biggest companies in the world. Microsoft Corp. and Meta Platforms Inc., for example, spend more than 40% of their budget for hardware on the chipmaker's gear. During the peak of shortages of Nvidia's H100 accelerator, individual components were retailing for as much as $90,000 each.</p>

<p>Analysts project that Nvidia will chalk up $120.8 billion of revenue in calendar 2024, up from $16 billion in 2020, with most of that money coming from its data center unit. In fact, Nvidia is set to bring in more profit this year than the total sales of its nearest rival, Advanced Micro Devices Inc.</p>

<p>There also are broader regulatory questions about Nvidia's practices. Access to AI capabilities has become a key focus for governments around the world, with the technology becoming increasingly vital to economic strength and national security.</p>

<p>Nvidia CEO Jensen Huang is expected to visit India in October for Nvidia AI Summit at the Jio World Convention Centre in Mumbai.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/7kk4lmqo_jensen-huang_625x300_04_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Nvidia CEO Jensen Huang is expected to visit India in October for Nvidia AI Summit in Mumbai.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/7-000-and-counting-a-look-at-sultan-of-bruneis-5-billion-car-collection-6487015]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[7,000 And Counting: A Look At Sultan Of Brunei's $5 Billion Car Collection]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/7-000-and-counting-a-look-at-sultan-of-bruneis-5-billion-car-collection-6487015]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Sep 2024 12:00:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Sultan Of Brunei's car collection boasts more than 7,000 vehicles and is worth an estimated $5 billion.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi is currently on a diplomatic visit to Brunei and Singapore, aiming to strengthen India's relationships with the Southeast Asian countries. His first stop was Brunei, where he held a meeting with the country's monarch, Sultan Haji Hassanal Bolkiah, at his lavish palace.</p>

<p>The Sultan of Brunei, the second-longest reigning monarch in history, is known for his extravagant lifestyle. One of his most notable possessions is the world's largest private car collection. Valued at $5 billion, his collection features over 7,000 luxury cars, reported Fox News.</p>

<p>The collection was put together with the help of Hassanal's brother, Jefri Bolkiah (also known as Prince Jefri), and other members of the royal family. Since it's impossible to talk about every car he owns, we'll focus on a select few luxury vehicles.</p>

<h3><strong>The Bentleys</strong></h3>

<p>Sultan's car collection includes approximately $80 million worth of classic Bentleys from the 1980s and 1990s, mostly Azure and Continental models. The Bentley Dominator SUV is among the most unique among the selection. Other Bentley cars in the collection include the Continental R Superfast, the Buccaneer GT coupe, and the Java, which has a twin-turbo V8 engine.</p>

<h3><strong>The Ferraris</strong></h3>

<p>There's no shortage of Italian exotica in the largest vehicle collection in the world. He owns a rare Ferrari F50, two 250 GTOs, an F40, several Ferrari 456s, a Ferrari FX and a Testarossa F90 Speciale.</p>

<h3><strong>The Porsches</strong></h3>

<p>The Sultan's collection also includes 55 Porsche 928s, 32 of which are S4 variants. This demonstrates how Porsche has successfully branched out from its classic 911 model. The monarch also got a Porsche 959s, a Daur 962 Le Mans and a Carrera GT as well.</p>

<h3><strong>The Rolls-Royces</strong></h3>

<p>In 2011, Sultan Hassanal Bolkiah broke the record for having the world's largest private Rolls-Royce collection. Though the precise number is unknown, estimations indicate that there are more than 600 distinct models.</p>

<h3><strong>The Aston Martins</strong></h3>

<p>The Sultan is no stranger to ordering custom Aston Martin vehicles. The unique AM3, a one-of-a-kind grand tourer inspired by the Vantage and created in association with Pininfarina, is one noteworthy example.</p>

<p>Additionally, the Sultan's opulent collection features several McLaren, Bugatti, BMW, Mercedes-Benz, Brabus, Jaguar and a Koenigsegg CCXR.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/mhl4nkig_sultan-hassanal-bolkiah_625x300_03_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-lenders-wont-have-a-say-on-who-runs-byjus-amid-bankruptcy-concerns-6486982]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Lenders Won't Have A Say On Who Runs Byju's Amid Bankruptcy Concerns]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-lenders-wont-have-a-say-on-who-runs-byjus-amid-bankruptcy-concerns-6486982]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Sep 2024 11:54:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US lenders to Byju's were removed from an influential creditors committee by a court-appointed arbitrator in India, a potential boon for the struggling online-education company seeking to avert bankruptcy.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US lenders to Byju's were removed from an influential creditors committee by a court-appointed arbitrator in India, a potential boon for the struggling online-education company seeking to avert bankruptcy.</p>

<p>The decision by the official, who is overseeing an insolvency case against Byju's, means that the lenders won't get a say on who should run the startup and steer a restructuring plan.</p>

<p>The removal is a setback for the lenders, represented by investment firm Glas Trust, and their effort to collect more than $1.2 billion from the troubled startup. Glas Trust has been the most vocal opponent of a settlement agreement Byju's struck with an Indian creditor - the country's cricket governing body - to escape insolvency. The investment firm has filed a petition to void the agreement with the cricket body, arguing that it deserves to be paid first - the arbitrator's decision means technically that the court may allow the settlement to proceed.</p>

<p>The lenders said they didn't get a chance to vote on who should run Byju's while a plan to repay creditors is put together. The lenders accused the official - Byju's Interim Resolution Professional Pankaj Srivastava - of "secretly plotting to reject" their claims and of manipulating the creditor's vote by excluding them.</p>

<p>Before the US lenders even learned that they had been removed, Srivastava held a meeting of the creditors committee and was selected as a "permanent resolution professional," the lenders alleged in an emailed statement. Srivastava didn't respond to an email sent after business hours in India.</p>

<p>"Pankaj Srivastava's actions are unprecedented and entirely illegitimate as no interim resolution professional in the history of the Insolvency and Bankruptcy Code of India has ever attempted to unlawfully strip financial creditors of claims of this magnitude," the lenders said.</p>

<p>Lenders have been trying to force Byju's into an insolvency proceeding in a court in India for months but with limited success. One part of that court fight is now before India's Supreme Court.</p>

<p>In the US, the lenders have been trying to track down $533 million that Byju's founder, Byju Raveendran, allegedly said was so well hidden, that no one would ever find it, according to court documents.</p>

<p>Byju's faces a fraudulent transfer lawsuit in a US bankruptcy court. That case involves Byju's Alpha, a shell company created by Byju's in order to tap US capital markets. After Byju's defaulted, lenders seized control of the shell company, put it under court protection and sued to get $533 million they claim should go to them.</p>

<p>In India, Byju's had a deal to end the main insolvency case against it, filed by the cricket governing body. The lenders have asked the Supreme Court of India to block that deal, arguing money that should go to them was wrongly being used to pay off the cricket board instead. The court hasn't yet ruled on that appeal.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/rvvruu_byjus-generic-bloomberg-_625x300_04_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Byju's faces a fraudulent transfer lawsuit in a US bankruptcy court.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/man-who-designed-nigerias-flag-to-get-burial-a-year-after-death-6486972]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Man Who Designed Nigeria's Flag To Get Burial A Year After Death]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/man-who-designed-nigerias-flag-to-get-burial-a-year-after-death-6486972]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Sep 2024 11:52:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A year after the man who designed the Nigerian flag died at 87, his family has decided to bury his body. The family had been waiting for the government to fulfill its promise to arranging a state burial for him, but the promise never materialised.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A year after the man who designed the Nigerian flag died at 87, his family has decided to bury his body. The family had been waiting for the government to fulfill its promise to arranging a state burial for him, but the promise never materialised.</p>

<p>Pa Taiwo Michael Akinkunmi, who died on August 29, 2023, designed the green and white flag while studying in London in the late 1950s. In his design, he evoked Nigeria's agricultural wealth and the peace and unity among its diverse ethnic groups.</p>

<p>The design won a national competition and the new flag unveiled on Nigeria's Independence Day on October 1. Despite his significant contribution, very few people knew about his work and Mr Akinkunmi lived a relatively quiet life, working for the Ministry of Agriculture.</p>

<p>Recognition came later in life, when he was given the Officer of the Order of the Federal Republic (OFR) award in 2014, one of the highest civilian awards in Nigeria.</p>

<p>After his death, a motion was proposed to give him a state burial, but no plans were made, leaving his family to pay for his body to be kept in a mortuary for over a year.</p>

<p>Despite public outcry and a directive from the Ministry of Art, Culture, and the Creative Economy for the National Institute for Cultural Orientation (NICO) to ensure he received a state funeral, there was little follow-through.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Ultimately, the Oyo state government stepped in to support the family to give him a befitting burial in early September, just after the one-year anniversary of his passing.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/q5k1jdc8_-pa-taiwo-michael-akinkunmi_625x300_04_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kim-jong-un-executes-30-officials-for-failing-to-prevent-deaths-during-floods-report-6486649]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kim Jong Un Executes 30 Officials For Failing To Prevent Floods: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kim-jong-un-executes-30-officials-for-failing-to-prevent-deaths-during-floods-report-6486649]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Sep 2024 10:57:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In July, severe rainfall triggered landslides and flooding in North Korea, affecting over 4,000 homes and leaving 15,000 residents displaced.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Several South Korean media reports suggest that North Korean leader Kim Jong Un ordered the execution of up to 30 officials, allegedly due to their failure to prevent devastating flooding and landslides.&nbsp;The disasters reportedly resulted in approximately 1,000 deaths. According to a report by South Korea's <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://news.tvchosun.com/site/data/html_dir/2024/09/03/2024090390229.html" rel="nofollow, noindex">Chosun TV</a></em>, citing a North Korean official, Kim Jong Un called for ''strict punishment'' to be meted out to those deemed responsible for the ''unacceptable loss'' of life caused by the recent flooding.&nbsp;Officials were also charged with corruption and dereliction of duty.&nbsp;The executions reportedly took place late last month.</p>

<p>''It has been determined that 20 to 30 cadres in the flood-stricken area were executed at the same time late last month,'' the official was quoted as saying.</p>

<p>Although the identities of the executed officials remain undisclosed, the North Korean Central News Agency (KCNA) reported that Kang Bong-hoon, the secretary of the Chagang Province Provincial Party Committee since 2019, was among the leaders removed from their positions by Kim Jong-un.</p>

<p>In July, severe rainfall triggered landslides and flooding in North Korea, affecting over 4,000 homes and leaving 15,000 residents displaced. Kim Jong Un himself visited the affected areas and stated that it would take several months to rebuild and restore the neighbourhoods that were completely inundated by the floods. The government also provided shelter in Pyongyang facilities for 15,400 people, including vulnerable groups such as mothers, children, the elderly, and disabled soldiers.</p>

<p>However, the North Korean leader denied reports of a high death toll from the flooding, dismissing the claims as "false rumours." He accused South Korea of spreading these rumours as part of a deliberate "smear campaign" designed to damage North Korea's international reputation.</p>

<p>Lee Il-gyu, a former North Korean diplomat at the International Korean Peninsula Forum remarked, "Even though there was recent flood damage, they were dismissed for social security reasons, and the executives themselves are so anxious that they don't know when their necks will fall off."</p>

<p>According to the <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.koreatimes.co.kr/www/nation/2024/09/103_361356.html" rel="nofollow, noindex">Korea Times</a></em>, North Korea's public executions have surged dramatically since the COVID-19 pandemic. Before the pandemic, the country typically saw around 10 public executions per year. However, that number has skyrocketed to approximately 100 annual public executions, representing a tenfold increase.</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/2885brr4_kim-jong-un_625x300_11_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The executions reportedly took place late last month.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/head-of-mossads-financial-network-arrested-in-turkey-6486504]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Head of Mossad's Financial Network Arrested In Turkey]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/head-of-mossads-financial-network-arrested-in-turkey-6486504]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Sep 2024 10:30:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Turkish authorities have arrested Liridon Rexhepi, the head of Israel's Mossad intelligence agency's financial network in Turkey, according to a report by state media.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Turkish authorities have arrested Liridon Rexhepi, the head of Israel's Mossad intelligence agency's financial network in Turkey, according to a report by state media.</p>

<p>On August 30, Istanbul police detained Rexhepi in connection with the allegations of transferring money on behalf of Mossad during an operation, Xinhua news agency reported.</p>

<p>Rexhepi was formally arrested after a court hearing, during which he admitted to the charges, the state-run Anadolu Agency reported.</p>

<p>The Turkish intelligence agency, MIT, had been monitoring Rexhepi since his entry into the country on August 25.</p>

<p>MIT's investigation revealed that Rexhepi managed financial operations for Mossad and transferred significant amounts of money repeatedly via Western Union to field agents in Turkey.</p>

<p>Rexhepi was also found to have conducted drone surveillance and psychological operations targeting Palestinian politicians.</p>

<p>MIT discovered that Mossad was transferring funds to its field agents in Turkey, primarily from Kosovo and other Eastern European countries, according to Anadolu.</p>

<p>The financial tracking revealed that the funds from Kosovo were being transferred by Mossad's field agents in Turkey to sources in Syria via Western Union and cryptocurrency.</p>

<p>Since January, Turkish authorities have detained dozens of people, among them private investigators, on charges of collecting data on individuals, for Israeli intelligence.</p>

<p>Since the start of the Israel-Hamas war in Gaza, sparked by the terror group's slaughter of 1,200 people and kidnapping of 251 in southern Israel on October 7, Turkish President Recep Tayyip Erdogan has been one of the strongest critics of the Jewish state. He has also praised the Hamas terror group as a liberation group.</p>

<p>Turkish police arrested a suspect last week believed to have been transferring money to operatives of Israel's Mossad intelligence agency, Turkish security sources said on Tuesday.</p>

<p>In December, the head of Israel's Shin Bet security agency said that his organisation was prepared to target Hamas anywhere, including in Lebanon, Turkey and Qatar.</p>

<p>Turkey warned Israel of "serious consequences" if it tries to hunt down members of the terror group living outside Palestinian territories, including in Turkey.</p>

<p>Since then, Turkish authorities have detained dozens of people, among them private investigators, on charges of collecting data on individuals, mostly Palestinians residing in Turkey, for Israeli intelligence.</p>

<p>In January, Turkey arrested 33 individuals suspected of spying for Israel, according to the country's Interior Minister. The suspects were arrested in eight provinces across the country in what Ankara called Operation Mole.</p>

<p>In February, Turkish police arrested seven suspects on suspicion of selling information to Mossad through private detectives, the state-run Anadolu news agency said. Seven more people, including a private detective, were arrested in March - also for selling information to Mossad. Another two were arrested in April.</p>

<p>Israel has not commented on the arrests.</p>

<p>In May, Turkey halted all trade with Israel, and in August, it filed a request with a UN court to join South Africa's lawsuit accusing Israel of genocide in Gaza.</p>

<p>Erdogan has accused Israel of committing genocide in Gaza, called for it to be punished in international courts and criticised Western nations for backing Israel. He has compared Israel to Nazi Germany, and Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu to Nazi leader Adolf Hitler.</p>

<p>Turkey and Israel normalised ties in 2022 by reappointing ambassadors following years of tensions. But those links quickly deteriorated after Hamas's October 7 invasion.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/00sgsnkg_police-turkey-raid_625x300_30_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Liridon Rexhepi was detained in connection with the allegations of transferring money on behalf of Mossad]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-to-revise-nuclear-doctrine-over-actions-of-the-collective-west-6486460]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russia To Revise Nuclear Doctrine Over Actions Of The "Collective West"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-to-revise-nuclear-doctrine-over-actions-of-the-collective-west-6486460]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Sep 2024 10:26:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russia says it has become necessary for Moscow to revise its nuclear doctrine because of Washington's escalation of the war in Ukraine. The Kremlin has blamed the "collective actions of the West" for such a move, spokesperson Dmitry Peskov has said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russia says it has become necessary for Moscow to revise its nuclear doctrine because of Washington's escalation of the war in Ukraine. The Kremlin has blamed the "collective actions of the West" in Ukraine for such a move, spokesperson Dmitry Peskov has reportedly said.</p>

<p>Without revealing what the changes will be to Russia's nuclear doctrine, Moscow has said that certain changes are required to be made on the policy over the circumstances for the use of its nukes.</p>

<p>President Vladimir Putin had set the current nuclear doctrine in place four years ago. According to that, Russia may use nuclear weapons in the scenario where it comes under a nuclear attack or if a conventional attack threatens the existence of the state.</p>

<p>An update to the Russian nuclear doctrine is now necessary "against the backdrop of the challenges and threats provoked by the countries of the so-called collective West", Kremlin spokesperson Dmitry Peskov has said.</p>

<p>Moscow foresees the likelihood of Ukraine using long-range missiles and other weapons supplied by the United States to attack deep inside Russian territory, Mr Peskov said.</p>

<p>Ukraine has reportedly been negotiating with its allies for Kyiv to use weapons supplied by the West to target deep inside Russian territory. Ukraine's appeals have grown louder and more frequent as Russia has increased its airstrikes to target Ukraine's energy and other infrastructure.</p>

<p>"Ukraine will obviously do this, and we are taking that into account," Mr Peskov reportedly said, according to a Reuters report.</p>

<p>Russia has stepped up its airstrikes on Ukraine. At least 50 people were killed and more than 270 wounded when Russia hit a military institute in Ukraine's central town of Poltava with two ballistic missiles on Tuesday, in the year's single-deadliest attack of the war.</p>

<p>Writing on social media website X, Ukraine's President Zelenskyy vowed that Russia will "surely pay for this strike".</p>

<p>Calling it a "terror attack", Me Zelenskyy wrote, "We continue to urge everyone in the world who has the power to stop this terror: Ukraine needs air defense systems and missiles now, not sitting in storage. Long-range strikes that can protect us from Russian terror are needed now, not later. Every day of delay, unfortunately, means more lost lives."<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/2ak8srak_russia-missile-russia-missiles-ians_625x300_04_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Russia says it has become necessary for Moscow to revise its nuclear doctrine.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/texas-car-crash-dharshini-vasudevan-no-contact-after-indian-womans-fathers-sos-to-centre-she-was-dead-6486447]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["No Contact After...": Indian Woman's Father's SOS To Centre. She Was Dead]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/texas-car-crash-dharshini-vasudevan-no-contact-after-indian-womans-fathers-sos-to-centre-she-was-dead-6486447]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Sep 2024 10:21:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Before he learnt of the multi-level car crash that killed his daughter Dharshini Vasudevan, an exasperated father had tagged External Affairs Minister Dr S Jaishankar in a social media post, informing that he can't reach his daughter and seeking the]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Before learning of the multi-level car crash that killed his daughter Dharshini Vasudevan, a desperate father had tagged External Affairs Minister Dr S Jaishankar in a social media post, requesting the government's help in locating her.</p>

<p>In the post, Chennai-based Mr Vasudevan said his daughter had been in the US for the past three years and lived at Frisco in Texas. She completed her MS studies a year back and was working for the past year, he wrote.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en"><a href="https://twitter.com/DrSJaishankar?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@DrSJaishankar</a> Dear Sir, My daughter Dharshini Vasudevan holding Indian passport No-T6215559 have been in USA for the last 3 years, 2 years of MS studies and later 1 year of Employment and stays 3150 Avenue of the stars Apt 1110-Frisco,Texas-75034.</p>
— Vasudevan (@VasuV1970) <a href="https://twitter.com/VasuV1970/status/1829830395434803649?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 31, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>"Yesterday evening she took a car pooling along with 3 others around 3pm till 4pm she was actively messaging and reachable on phone after 4pm no further contacts could be established with her as well other 3 people who were travelling with her," he said in the post.</p>

<p>NDTV cannot verify the authenticity of the post on X.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The travel was from Frisco to Bentonville (her uncle home) since it's a long weekend she pre booked for the travel. We parents are really worried and it's almost 12 hours we don't the status of our daughter. Please help," the post stated.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">The travel was from Frisco to Bentonville (her uncle home) since it's a long weekend she pre booked for the travel. We parents are really worried and it's almost 12 hours we don't the status of our daughter. Please help</p>
— Vasudevan (@VasuV1970) <a href="https://twitter.com/VasuV1970/status/1829830476158169569?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 31, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>Dharshini Vasudevan is among four Indian nationals killed in a multi-car crash in Texas. The four, also comprising Aryan Raghunath Orampati, Farooq Shaik and Lokesh Palacharla had connected through a carpooling app and were travelling to Bentonville in Arkansas. While Dharshini was on her way to meet her uncle, Orampati and Shaik were returning from Texas to their homes in Bentonville. Lokesh Palacharla was going to Bentonville to meet his wife. The authorities managed to identify them through the carpooling app they had used.</p>

<p>According to reports, a speeding truck rear-ended the SUV the victims were in. The car burst into flames and all the occupants burnt to death. The authorities are now relying on DNA fingerprinting and teeth and bone remains to confirm the identities. "DNA fingerprinting will be done to identify the bodies, and the samples will be matched with the parents," a local authority said.</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/b4r5o2so_dharshini-vasudevan_625x300_04_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Dharshini Vasudevan and three other Indians were killed in the car crash in Texas]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/young-chinese-women-hire-female-cosplayers-to-play-dream-men-6486314]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Young Chinese Women Hire Female Cosplayers To Play Dream Men]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/young-chinese-women-hire-female-cosplayers-to-play-dream-men-6486314]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Sep 2024 10:00:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[During her final years of high school, Chinese teenager Xu Yunting found an unusual way to make some pocket money -- transforming herself into male video game characters and taking their female devotees on dates.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>During her final years of high school, Chinese teenager Xu Yunting found an unusual way to make some pocket money -- transforming herself into male video game characters and taking their female devotees on dates.</p>

<p>The trend, called "cos commissioning", has gained traction in China recently, with social media posts garnering millions of views as an increasing number of young women use their purchasing power to engineer a meeting with their dream man in real life.</p>

<p>One early morning in Shanghai last month, Xu carefully inserted contacts to enlarge her irises and adjusted a tangerine wig to transform into "Jesse", a character from the romance quest mobile game "Light and Night".&nbsp;</p>

<p>A tall and sensitive musician, he is one of five characters that woo players throughout the game -- and for client Feng Xinyu, a vivacious 19-year-old, the ideal partner.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"I don't have a boyfriend because I'm not interested in 3D men," Feng told AFP, using a term for real-life men as opposed to those on the page or screen.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"I like anime characters a little bit more, they're more appealing to me."</p>

<p>"Light and Night", made by tech giant Tencent and aimed squarely at young women, promises a "brand-new interactive experience of highly immersive love".</p>

<p>Players like Feng, who form strong emotional connections with characters in such games, are known as "dream girls" -- and cos commissioning takes the immersion to the next level by dragging those 2D beaus off the screen and into the real world.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Feng has commissioned Xu twice before, for a fee of around $70.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Last month, she spent $2,800 on a multi-day trip with another Jesse cosplayer to a different province.</p>

<p>But she decided she preferred Xu's portrayal and hired her for a third date.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"We really click," Feng said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"She's just like the character from the game, it feels like we were meant to be together."</p>

<p><strong>'Reconstructing gender rules'</strong></p>

<p>Feng was waiting for Xu at a metro station, and grinned in unabashed delight when she spotted her.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The two appeared relaxed, holding hands and chatting happily as they headed to their first activity.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Their date -- all planned and paid for entirely by Feng -- lasted all day, beginning with tea and ending with a hotpot meal and a romantic stroll.&nbsp;</p>

<p>At both a doll-painting workshop and cake-decorating class they attended, they were one of many cos commission pairs.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Staff at the latter business told AFP they had noticed more and more couples coming in over the past year -- sometimes dozens on busy days.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Part of the appeal, experts studying the phenomenon say, is that it gives young women a way to perform an idealised heteronormative relationship.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Conservative social attitudes towards women remain widespread in China, often reinforced by state media and popular culture.</p>

<p>Aside from assuaging safety concerns, hiring a female cosplayer ensures a level of equality and understanding not necessarily guaranteed in a real-life relationship.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"I don't think it's important what gender the person being commissioned is," Fudan University's Tian Qian told AFP.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"What is important is that (the cosplayer) is a vessel, because the client needs a vehicle for their emotions."&nbsp;</p>

<p>Another academic, Zhou Zixing, wrote that cos commissioning allows women "to gain a voice that is fully respected by the opposite sex... responding to, breaking, and reconstructing the gender rules of the real world".</p>

<p><strong>'Low-quality guys'</strong></p>

<p>At the cake-decorating class, Feng leaned over the table, fondly watching Xu pipe generous amounts of icing onto a sponge cake.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Afterwards, Xu gently helped Feng remove her apron, modelling Jesse's gentlemanly behaviour. &nbsp;</p>

<p>"The guys in the games are all quality guys," said Xu.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"I think (clients) will be able to improve their requirements in real life in terms of what they want from a man, so that they don't settle for low-quality guys."&nbsp;</p>

<p>Her mother Fang Xiuqing admitted her initial reaction when she learned what Xu was doing was: "How could this happen to my daughter?"&nbsp;</p>

<p>But she has since come around to the idea.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"I don't think it's a profession, it's a hobby," said Fang.</p>

<p>"She gets enjoyment from it, and she also brings joy to others."&nbsp;</p>

<p>Fudan University's Tian said cos commissions can act as "emotional sustenance".&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Although this is a paid interaction, it still gives a sense of being seen, which has a certain healing effect to it."&nbsp;</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/j1l37jcg_chinese-female-cosplayers_625x300_04_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/vladimir-putin-orders-russian-scientists-to-urgently-develop-an-anti-ageing-cure-report-6486307]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Putin Orders Russian Scientists To Develop 'Anti-Aging' Cure: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/vladimir-putin-orders-russian-scientists-to-urgently-develop-an-anti-ageing-cure-report-6486307]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Sep 2024 09:58:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russian Health Ministry senta letter to research institutes, asking doctors to urgently develop proposals aimed at preserving the health and well-being of Russian citizens.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>President Vladimir Putin has ordered Russian scientists to fast-track the development of a revolutionary anti-ageing treatment,&nbsp;that could help tackle the country's declining life expectancy.&nbsp;The health ministry's June directive, which came to light through investigative reporting by <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://meduza.io/en/feature/2024/09/03/who-wants-to-live-forever">Meduza</a></em> and <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.currenttime.tv/a/prichudy-politbyuro-systema/33102242.html" rel="nofollow, noindex">Sistema</a>, has taken leading medical researchers by surprise. The outlets reported that the Russian Health Ministry sent&nbsp;a letter to research institutes, asking doctors to urgently develop and submit proposals aimed at preserving and promoting the health and well-being of Russian citizens. The goal is to "save 175,000 lives" by 2030, according to the investigation.</p>

<p>At the '<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://meduza.io/en/feature/2024/07/09/a-future-alternative">Rossiya' exhibition</a> in Moscow, Russian Deputy Prime Minister Tatyana Golikova unveiled the government's plan to invest in cutting-edge technologies&nbsp;aimed at promoting longevity and healthy ageing.&nbsp;Physicians were then requested to submit 'development proposals' focusing on several key areas, including:</p>

<ul>
	<li>Mitigating the effects of cellular ageing</li>
	<li>Innovative technologies to prevent cognitive decline and sensory impairment</li>
	<li>Methods for modulating and correcting the immune system</li>
	<li>4Cutting-edge medical technologies leveraging bioprinting</li>
</ul>

<p>A Russian doctor who received the letter in June expressed surprise at the sudden urgency with which physicians were asked to develop proposals, saying it was unusual to be given such a tight deadline for a project of this scope.&nbsp;</p>

<p>''They asked us to fast-track all of our proposals —&nbsp;it felt like the letter had just arrived today and the deadline was yesterday. To be honest, it was the first time I'd seen anything like it —&nbsp;usually, any national project or federal program is preceded by several meetings involving various specialists and some sort of public discussion'', he said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>''When we got this letter, honestly, I was stunned. The whole premise baffled me. Oh sure, let's work on restoring the health of these old fogies —&nbsp;it's not like there's anyone else who needs our attention. Right in the middle of the war, we're just supposed to drop everything. The level of cynicism is bewildering,'' another researcher said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Other researchers and experts are also concerned about the high costs of the research. A source close to the Kremlin stated, ''All the modern research discussed in the national project is quite expensive—developing new drugs costs billions. No single national project can handle that, especially now. I don't think they will be able to put together anything meaningful quickly''</p>

<p>Mikhail Kovalchuk, a close associate of President Putin and director of the prestigious Kurchatov Institute, Russia's premier nuclear research facility, has been actively lobbying for the initiative.&nbsp;He "raves about eternal life and the 'Russian genome,' a Kremlin source said.</p>

<p>According to data released by the Federal State Statistics Service of Russia (Rosstat) in July, the country's average life expectancy experienced a decline between July 2023 and June 2024, dropping to 73.24 years.&nbsp;</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/etden2mo_vladimir-putin_625x300_13_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The goal is to "save 175,000 lives" by 2030, according to the investigation.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/woman-40-killed-in-front-of-father-for-refusing-marriage-proposal-6486208]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Pak Woman Killed In Front Of Father For Refusing Marriage Proposal: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/woman-40-killed-in-front-of-father-for-refusing-marriage-proposal-6486208]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Sep 2024 09:39:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 40-year-old female school teacher was allegedly shot and killed in front of her father after she refused a marriage proposal, ARY News reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 40-year-old female school teacher was allegedly shot and killed in front of her father after she refused a marriage proposal, ARY News reported.</p>

<p>The incident occurred in the Jangdara Totalai area of Buner in the Khyber Pakhtunkhwa province, where the suspect opened fire on the teacher and fled the scene.</p>

<p>The local police have registered a first information report (FIR) and launched an investigation, as reported by ARY News.</p>

<p>According to the victim's father, the suspect had previously attacked his daughter, and despite reporting the incident to the police, no action was taken.</p>

<p>This comes amid rising crime cases across different parts of Pakistan.</p>

<p>Similar incidents were reported in the month of June as well.</p>

<p>In a similar incident in the Mardan district of Khyber Pakhtunkhwa on June 8, a female school teacher, who contracted free-will marriage was killed in the name of 'honour.'</p>

<p>The incident occurred in the Tazagram area of Mardan district in which the 22-year-old woman was killed after being dragged out of a car, according to details.</p>

<p>Further, as per the police information, the teacher was killed in the name of honour, nine months after she had a court marriage.</p>

<p>The police started the investigation as evidence from the crime scene had been collected. The woman's dead body has been sent to the hospital for medico-legal formalities, according to ARY News.</p>

<p>The attackers managed to escape after the murder and are still at large.</p>

<p>On June 4, two sisters, who contracted free will marriages, were killed in the name of 'honour'.</p>

<p>According to the District Police Officer (DPO), the two sisters had married boys they loved against the wishes of their family. They were brought back due to a decision made by a "Panchayat."</p>

<p>The police said that the sisters were killed by their father, brother, and uncle.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-11/iof8givc_arrest-generic_625x300_30_November_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[This incident comes amid rising crime cases across different parts of Pakistan (representational).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/teenage-bodybuilder-with-brilliant-future-ahead-dies-aged-19-6486154]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Brazil Bodybuilder, Whose Fight Against Obesity Went Viral, Dies At 19]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/teenage-bodybuilder-with-brilliant-future-ahead-dies-aged-19-6486154]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Sep 2024 09:24:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 19-year-old bodybuilder from Brazil was found dead at his home on Sunday afternoon, allegedly due to a heart attack, according to various reports.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 19-year-old bodybuilder from Brazil was found dead at his home on Sunday afternoon, allegedly due to a heart attack, according to various reports.</p>

<p>Matheus Pavlak had transformed his body in just five years after taking up the sport to overcome obesity. He was a regular competitor and a rising star in the bodybuilding community, particularly in the southern Brazilian state of Santa Catarina, where he lived. According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.tmz.com/2024/09/03/bodybuilder-matheus-pavlak-dead/" rel="No follow, No index ">TMZ</a>, he recently placed fourth and sixth in regional competitions and won the U23 contest in 2023, becoming "Mr. Blumenau" in his hometown.</p>

<p>Pavlak's untimely death has sparked speculation about the role of anabolic steroids in triggering health issues. Critics on social media have highlighted his impressive physique at such a young age, suggesting that the use of performance-enhancing drugs may have contributed to his heart attack.</p>

<p>One acquaintance of Pavlak responded to these accusations on social media, stating, "How can human beings exist who are capable of offending the memory of a boy who is no longer here to defend himself!!"</p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/reel/ChSIwFKDc9g/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/ChSIwFKDc9g/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/ChSIwFKDc9g/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/ChSIwFKDc9g/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by Matheus Pavlak | Atleta (@matheus.pavlak)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p></p>

<p>Pavlak had previously posted pictures of his incredible body transformation, accompanied by the caption, "No matter how difficult or impossible your dream is, if you really want it, you will get there. I DID."</p>

<p>Pavlak's former trainer, Lucas Chegatti, expressed his grief over the loss of his protégé. On Instagram, Chegatti wrote, "Today ends in a sad day with the loss of a great friend, a spectacular young man who leaves us far too soon, a tragedy that has taken us by surprise. He had a brilliant future ahead of him as a respected athlete. God has his plans, but it's hard to understand; I don't have the words to explain the weight I feel in my heart."</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/C_Y7lrvSUY5/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C_Y7lrvSUY5/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C_Y7lrvSUY5/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C_Y7lrvSUY5/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by Lucas Chegatti (@chegatti_treinador)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p></p>

<p>Chegatti continued, "I was Matheus' first coach, and I'm very proud to have had the opportunity to care for him like a son. I promised him that one day he would beat me, and said and done, the first time we competed against each other, he ended up winning." Chegatti met Pavlak in 2022.</p>

<p>Pavlak's death comes amid a series of high-profile tragedies involving bodybuilders, raising concerns about the long-term health implications of the sport. In April, Brazilian bodybuilder and fitness instructor <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.thesun.co.uk/sport/27437839/bodybuilder-fitness-influencer-jonas-filho-dies/" rel="No Follow, No Index ">Jonas Filho</a> died aged 29 after losing his battle with Covid. In May, a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.thesun.co.uk/sport/27958048/bodybuilding-champion-xisco-serra-dies/" rel="No Follow, No Index ">Majorcan bodybuilder</a>, who was also a cancer survivor, passed away aged 50.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/mqjup9pg_brazil-bodybuilder-_625x300_04_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Matheus Pavlak had transformed his body in just five years after taking up the sport to overcome obesity.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistan-government-bars-public-servants-from-using-social-media-without-permission-6486041]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Pak Restricts Public Servants From Using Social Media Without Permission]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistan-government-bars-public-servants-from-using-social-media-without-permission-6486041]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Sep 2024 09:15:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Pakistan government has issued an order barring all government employees from using social media without permission to stop disclosure of official information and documents, The News International reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Pakistan government has issued an order barring all government employees from using social media without permission to stop disclosure of official information and documents, The News International reported.</p>

<p>According to an office memorandum issued by the Establishment Division, government employees have been asked to adhere to the instruction under the Government Servants (Conduct) Rules, 1964. As per the order, the government employees will not be allowed to use any social media platform without permission, The News International reported.</p>

<p>The memorandum stated, "Government employees cannot express opinions or facts that affect the reputation of the government," adding that employees are not permitted to speak against government policy, decisions, national sovereignty and dignity.</p>

<p>It further stated that public servants cannot share their opinions or rhetoric on social media platforms without permission. Strict action would be taken against government employees for violating the directives issued in the order, according to The News International report.</p>

<p>According to the memorandum, a government employee cannot share official documents and information with unrelated persons. It stated that employees cannot speak to the media in a way that impacts Pakistan's ties with other nations.</p>

<p>The memorandum stated, "Civil servants have often been seen debating on social media. The guidelines are not intended to ban the positive use of social media." According to the memorandum, institutions have been asked to monitor their social media platforms to remove objectionable content.</p>

<p>The memorandum stated, "Government servants of all services and groups are bound to follow the instructions. Violation may lead to misconduct proceedings against the employees concerned," according to the report. It asked federal secretaries, additional secretaries, heads of departments, and chief secretaries to execute the memorandum.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/6s4542g8_computer-generic_625x300_02_June_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Pak government has issued an order barring all government employees from using social media.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>