<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Wed, 26 Jun 2024 08:27:17 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/wikileaks-founder-julian-assange-freed-in-us-plea-deal-hearing-5971114]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Julian Assange Walks Free After Pleading Guilty In Deal With US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/wikileaks-founder-julian-assange-freed-in-us-plea-deal-hearing-5971114]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 26 Jun 2024 08:02:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[WikiLeaks founder Julian Assange was freed by a court on the U.S. Pacific island territory of Saipan on Wednesday after pleading guilty to violating U.S. espionage law, in a deal that will see him return home to Australia.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>WikiLeaks founder Julian Assange was freed by a court on the U.S. Pacific island territory of Saipan on Wednesday after pleading guilty to violating U.S. espionage law, in a deal that will see him return home to Australia.</p>

<p>During the three-hour hearing, Assange pled guilty to one criminal count of conspiring to obtain and disclose classified U.S. national defence documents but said he had believed the Constitution's First Amendment, which protects free speech, shielded his activities.</p>

<p>"Working as a journalist I encouraged my source to provide information that was said to be classified in order to publish that information," he told the court.</p>

<p>"I believed the First Amendment protected that activity but I accept that it was ... a violation of the espionage statute."</p>

<p>Chief U.S. District Judge Ramona V. Manglona accepted his guilty plea and released him due to time already served in a British jail.</p>

<p>Assange, 52, is set to leave Saipan shortly after noon local time (0200 GMT) on a private jet accompanied by Australia's ambassadors to the U.S. and UK, according to flight logs. They will then travel to Canberra, landing just before 7 p.m. (0900 GMT).</p>

<p>Assange had agreed to plead guilty to a single criminal count, according to filings in the U.S. District Court for the Northern Mariana Islands.</p>

<p>The U.S. territory in the western Pacific was chosen due to his opposition to travelling to the mainland U.S. and for its proximity to Australia, prosecutors said.</p>

<p>Dozens of media from around the world attended the hearing, with more gathered outside the courtroom to cover the proceedings. Media were not allowed inside the courtroom to film the hearing.</p>

<p>"I watch this and think how overloaded his senses must be, walking through the press scrum after years of sensory depravation and the four walls of his high-security Belmarsh prison cell," Stella Assange, the wife of WikiLeaks founder said on social media platform X.</p>

<h3><strong>LONG SAGA</strong></h3>

<p>Australian-born Assange spent more than five years in a British high-security jail and seven holed up in the Ecuadorean embassy in London as he fought accusations of sex crimes in Sweden and battled extradition to the U.S., where he faced 18 criminal charges.</p>

<p>Assange's supporters view him as a victim because he exposed U.S. wrongdoing and potential crimes, including in conflicts in Afghanistan and Iraq. Washington has said the release of the secret documents put lives in danger.</p>

<p>The Australian government has been advocating for his release and has raised the issue with the United States several times.</p>

<p>"This isn't something that has happened in the last 24 hours," Prime Minister Anthony Albanese told a news conference on Wednesday.</p>

<p>"This is something that has been considered, patient, worked through in a calibrated way, which is how Australia conducts ourselves."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/hvu6cddo_assange-freed-reuters-_625x300_26_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Australian government has been advocating for his release with the United States several times.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nepalese-spiritual-leader-buddha-boy-found-guilty-of-sexually-assaulting-minor-5971076]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Nepalese Spiritual Leader 'Buddha Boy' Convicted Of Sexual Assault On Minor]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nepalese-spiritual-leader-buddha-boy-found-guilty-of-sexually-assaulting-minor-5971076]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 26 Jun 2024 07:53:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A judge at the Sarlahi District Court found him guilty of sexually assaulting an underage girl and said sentencing would be on July 1.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A controversial spiritual leader known as ''Buddha Boy''&nbsp;was convicted by a court in Nepal on charges of sexually assaulting a minor. The leader whose real name is Ram Bahadur Bomjan was <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nepal-spiritual-leader-ram-bahadur-bomjan-buddha-boy-arrested-over-alleged-rape-of-a-minor-4836676">arrested in January </a>for the sexual assault of a minor as well as suspicion of involvement in the disappearance of at least four of his devotees.</p>

<p>A judge at the Sarlahi District Court found him guilty of sexually assaulting an underage girl and said sentencing would be on July 1. He could face at least 12 years in jail but can still appeal against his conviction.</p>

<p><a id="more-section-display-name"></a></p>

<aside>
<p>The 33-year-old guru, whom his followers believe to be the reincarnation of Gautam Buddha, became famous as a teenager after followers said he could meditate motionless for months without water, food, or sleep. However, some reporters filmed him eating, and he was also spotted sleeping when his followers said he was meditating in private.</p>
</aside>

<p>Accusations of abuse and misconduct against Bomjan stretch back more than a decade. Dozens of assault complaints were filed against him in 2010. At the time he said he had beaten followers because they had disturbed his meditation.</p>

<p>On the run for years, the 33-year-old was arrested by officials from Nepal's Central Investigation Bureau this January on the outskirts of Kathmandu in January this year. During the arrest, police also seized Nepalese banknotes worth $227,000 and other foreign currencies amounting to $23,000.</p>

<p>Before he went on the run, Bomjan still commanded a legion of followers as the allegations against him mounted. At one point tens of thousands of people had gathered to witness his reputed miracles of meditation deep in the jungle.</p>

<p>While aged 16, Bomjan disappeared for nine months to wander the wilderness of eastern Nepal, prompting a round-the-clock vigil by Buddhist monks who prayed for his safe return.</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/emf93dhg_buddha-boy_625x300_26_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[He could face at least 12 years in jail, but can still appeal his conviction.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/australian-pm-calls-assanges-us-plea-deal-hearing-welcome-development-5971045]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Welcome Development": Australian PM On Julian Assange's US Plea Deal]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/australian-pm-calls-assanges-us-plea-deal-hearing-welcome-development-5971045]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 26 Jun 2024 07:41:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Australia's prime minister hailed WikiLeaks founder Julian Assange's US plea deal hearing Wednesday as a "welcome development".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Australia's prime minister hailed WikiLeaks founder Julian Assange's US plea deal hearing Wednesday as a "welcome development".</p>

<p>Assange, 52, pleaded guilty to a single count of conspiracy to obtain and disseminate US national defence information at a court in the US Pacific territory of the Northern Mariana Islands.</p>

<p>The plea is part of an agreement that is expected to free Assange to return to his native Australia within hours.</p>

<p>"This is a welcome development, but we recognise as well that these proceedings are sensitive and should be respected," Prime Minister Anthony Albanese told reporters in Canberra.</p>

<p>"Given those proceedings that are happening literally in real-time, it isn't appropriate to provide further commentary," Albanese said.</p>

<p>Australia had used "all appropriate channels" to support a "positive outcome" in the case, he said, noting that Australia's ambassador to the United States, Kevin Rudd, was accompanying Assange.</p>

<p>"Regardless of your views about Mr Assange, his case has dragged on for too long. There is nothing to be gained from his continued incarceration and we want him brought home to Australia," the Australian leader said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-11/7moee0go_anthony-albanese-_625x300_05_November_23.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese called Assange's US plea deal hearing a "welcome development".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/princess-dianas-finery-from-handbag-to-ball-gown-to-go-up-for-auction-5971018]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Princess Diana's Handbags, Hats, Gowns To Go Up For Auction]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/princess-dianas-finery-from-handbag-to-ball-gown-to-go-up-for-auction-5971018]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 26 Jun 2024 07:28:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The biggest auction of Diana memorabilia since the late British princess sold dozens of outfits months before her death gets underway in California this week, featuring a midnight blue tulle dress and a flamenco-style lace-up number.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The biggest auction of Diana memorabilia since the late British princess sold dozens of outfits months before her death gets underway in California this week, featuring a midnight blue tulle dress and a flamenco-style lace-up number.</p>

<p>Nearly fifty pieces, including gowns, shoes, handbags and hats, will go under the hammer in Beverly Hills.</p>

<p>"Princess Diana's Elegance &amp; A Royal Collection," brings together some of the style maven's favourite designers, including Victor Edelstein, Murray Arbeid and Catherine Walker.</p>

<p>Highlights include Arbeid's blue diamante ball gown, which the princess wore in 1986 to the London premiere of Andrew Lloyd Webber's "The Phantom of the Opera," and a magenta lace dress by Edelstein.</p>

<p>Both pieces are expected to fetch up to $400,000, according to Julien's Auctions, which is running the sale.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Explore the elegance of Princess Diana through the eyes of designer Victor Edelstein – his voice and vision come to life in our Royal Collection auction where his best creations for Lady Di grace the auction block at last.<br />
<br />
Register &amp; Bid<a href="https://t.co/Twkk8gZFpO">https://t.co/Twkk8gZFpO</a> <a href="https://t.co/4CgMbf5u3u">pic.twitter.com/4CgMbf5u3u</a></p>
— Julien's Auctions (@JuliensAuctions) <a href="https://twitter.com/JuliensAuctions/status/1805653834280194463?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 25, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>"We are here celebrating Princess Diana's elegance," said Gabriela Schwartz, of the auction house.</p>

<p>"We have some really standout pieces... that Diana wore with a lot of pride and (which are) really emblematic of her style."</p>

<p>Diana married Britain's now-King Charles in 1981 in an opulent ceremony watched by tens of millions around the globe.</p>

<p>The fairy tale soured over the following years and their tempestuous relationship became fodder for newspapers and gossip magazines, feeding a growing celebrity culture that exploded in the 1990s.</p>

<p>The couple had two children -- Princes William and Harry -- but divorced in 1996 in a tabloid frenzy and amid mutual infidelities.</p>

<p>Diana died in a car crash in Paris the following year as she and her lover tried to outrun paparazzi.</p>

<p>More than a quarter of a century on, the woman dubbed "The People's Princess" remains unmatched as a celebrity and style icon, whose allure continues to fascinate millions.</p>

<p>A dress worn by the princess that was auctioned last year fetched a staggering $1.14 million.</p>

<p>The collection, which has toured the globe for months, is expected to generate huge interest by the time bidding closes on Thursday.</p>

<p>As well as items of high couture, the sale will also include shoes by Salvatore Ferragamo, Kurt Geiger and Rayne, as well as letters in Diana's own handwriting, along with a number of other items connected to the British royal family.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/0mn4ck5_princess-diana-blue-ball-gown-x_625x300_26_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The princess wore this blue ball gown to the London premiere of "The Phantom of the Opera," in 1986.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-set-to-roll-out-plan-to-replace-hamas-government-in-gaza-5970920]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Set To Roll Out Plan To Replace Hamas Government In Gaza]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-set-to-roll-out-plan-to-replace-hamas-government-in-gaza-5970920]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 26 Jun 2024 06:54:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel will "soon" roll out a plan to replace Hamas governance in northern Gaza, Israeli National Security Advisor Tzachi Hanegbi said on Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel will "soon" roll out a plan to replace Hamas governance in northern Gaza, Israeli National Security Advisor Tzachi Hanegbi said on Tuesday.</p>

<p>Speaking at Reichman University's annual Herzliya Conference, Hanegbi said that the collapse of Hamas's military ability to rule will open opportunities "for countries that want to see a governing alternative to Hamas in Gaza, with local leadership in Gaza, to join this process."</p>

<p>He explained that Gaza's new leadership will include Israel's Abraham Accords partners, the United States, the European Union and the United Nations, while the Israeli military continues "cleansing the area" of Hamas's presence.</p>

<p>"We've been talking about this notion of 'the day after' for many months and the main thing that we've tried to emphasize throughout is that it's mainly the day after Hamas in the sense that we don't need to wait for it to disappear, because that process could take a long time."</p>

<p>"The idea is, and this is what the Americans agree on, including in the conversations this week and also in the conversation that the minister of defense [Yoav Gallant] is conducting right now [in Washington], is that there will be a so-called top-down leadership, and not only bottom-up," he continued.</p>

<p>Said Hanegbi, "You cannot completely get Hamas to disappear because it's an idea, a concept."</p>

<p>The US has pressed Israeli officials to clarify a vision for Gaza's governance after the war. The Biden administration opposes Israel occupying Gaza or allowing the Strip to descend into chaos. Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu has stressed that Israel's three war aims are the destruction of Hamas's military and governing capabilities, the return of all hostages, and ensuring that Gaza no longer poses a threat to Israel.</p>

<p>In an interview with the US-based Punchbowl News on Friday, Netanyahu said a demilitarized post-war Gaza will be overseen by a civilian-run administration with the assistance of Arab countries. He also referred to a "deradicalization process."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/dci79qa_benjamin-netanyahu-_625x300_08_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/as-israel-iran-backed-hezbollah-exchange-fire-us-warns-of-terrible-consequences-5970919]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[As Israel, Hezbollah Exchange Fire, US Warns Of "Terrible Consequences"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/as-israel-iran-backed-hezbollah-exchange-fire-us-warns-of-terrible-consequences-5970919]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 26 Jun 2024 06:54:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US Defense Secretary Lloyd Austin met his Israeli counterpart Yoav Gallant at the Pentagon on Tuesday, warning that a conflict between Israel and Hezbollah could spark a regional war and urging a diplomatic solution.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US Defense Secretary Lloyd Austin met his Israeli counterpart Yoav Gallant at the Pentagon on Tuesday, warning that a conflict between Israel and Hezbollah could spark a regional war and urging a diplomatic solution.</p>

<p>More than eight months of war in Gaza has heightened tensions across the region, with Israeli forces and Lebanon's Iran-backed Hezbollah exchanging fire on a near-daily basis.</p>

<p>"Another war between Israel and Hezbollah could easily become a regional war, with terrible consequences for the Middle East," Austin said. "Diplomacy is by far the best way to prevent more escalation."</p>

<p>Gallant, speaking at the opening of the meeting with Austin, said "we are working closely together to achieve an agreement but we must also discuss readiness on every possible scenario.</p>

<p>The Israeli army said last week that plans for an offensive in Lebanon were "approved and validated" amid escalating cross-border clashes, but Washington is seeking to lower the temperature and head off another major conflict in the Middle East.</p>

<p>Gallant is on a visit to Washington seeking to reaffirm the value of ties with Israel's top ally after Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu publicly chastised the United States for what he said was a delay in weapons deliveries.</p>

<p>The US government insists that only one shipment of bombs has been held up over concerns about their use in populated areas and that other arms deliveries are proceeding as usual.</p>

<p>The United States is Israel's main supplier of weapons but the growing death count from the Gaza conflict has piled pressure on President Joe Biden to take action and fueled tensions between his administration and Netanyahu.</p>

<p>Gallant met with Secretary of State Antony Blinken in Washington the previous day, with the top US diplomat calling on Israel to avoid escalation in Lebanon.</p>

<p>The Israeli minister also held talks with CIA chief Bill Burns, the key US point man in negotiations to free hostages from Hamas, which launched an unprecedented attack on Israel in October that sparked a devastating conflict in Gaza.</p>

<p>Netanyahu has said Israeli forces are winding up the most intense part of the Gaza war and will redeploy to the northern border, although he has cast the move as defensive.</p>

<p>Israel and Hezbollah last fought a full-scale war in 2006 when a cross-border Hezbollah attack sparked 34 days of fighting that took a heavy toll on Lebanon, especially the country's south.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/p1emcm18_usisrael-defense-meet-afp_625x300_26_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US Defense Secretary Lloyd Austin met his Israeli counterpart Yoav Gallant at the Pentagon on Tuesday.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/indians-in-kenya-asked-to-limit-non-essential-movement-amid-violent-protests-5970688]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Indians In Kenya Asked To Limit "Non-Essential" Movement Amid Protests]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/indians-in-kenya-asked-to-limit-non-essential-movement-amid-violent-protests-5970688]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 26 Jun 2024 06:39:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India has advised its citizens in Kenya to exercise utmost caution and restrict non-essential movement amid violent protests in the East African nation against the government's proposed tax hikes.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India has advised its citizens in Kenya to exercise utmost caution and restrict non-essential movement amid violent protests in the East African nation against the government's proposed tax hikes.</p>

<p>"In view of the prevailing tense situation, all Indians in Kenya are advised to exercise utmost caution, restrict non-essential movement and avoid the areas affected by the protests and violence till the situation clears up," the Indian consulate in Kenya said in an advisory posted on social media platform X.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">ADVISORY FOR INDIAN NATIONALS IN KENYA<br />
<br />
In view of the prevailing tense situation, all Indians in Kenya are advised to exercise utmost caution, restrict non-essential movement and avoid the areas affected by the protests and violence till the situation clears up.</p>
— India in Kenya (@IndiainKenya) <a href="https://twitter.com/IndiainKenya/status/1805698054550331419?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 25, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p></p>

<p>"Please follow local news and Mission's website and social media handles for updates," it added.</p>

<p>At least five protestors were shot dead and more than 150 others injured in Nairobi as police used tear gas and live rounds after thousands stormed into Kenya's Parliament and set part of it on fire.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/flna2alo_kenya-protests_625x300_25_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[At least five protestors were shot dead and more than 150 others injured in Nairobi. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/wikileaks-says-julian-assange-to-fly-to-australia-within-hours-5970715]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[WikiLeaks Says Julian Assange To Fly To Australia Within Hours]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/wikileaks-says-julian-assange-to-fly-to-australia-within-hours-5970715]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 26 Jun 2024 05:48:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[WikiLeaks founder Julian Assange will fly to the Australian capital Canberra within hours following a plea deal to set him free, the whistleblower website said Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>WikiLeaks founder Julian Assange will fly to the Australian capital Canberra within hours following a plea deal to set him free, the whistleblower website said Wednesday.</p>

<p>"Expected to depart in 2 hours, 58 minutes. To Canberra, Australia," WikiLeaks said in a social media post, as Assange faced court in the Pacific US territory of the Northern Mariana Islands.</p>

<p>Assange, 52, pleaded guilty at the US court in Saipan to a single count of conspiracy to obtain and disseminate US national defence information.</p>

<p>"Guilty to the information," Assange said in court, later joking to the judge that whether he is satisfied "depends on the outcome of the hearing".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2018-02/wikileaks-founder-julian-assange-reuters_650x400_71518491860.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Julian Assange expected to depart within 3 hours, WikiLeaks said.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-voters-prefer-trump-on-economy-biden-for-democracy-survey-5970662]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Voters Prefer Trump On Economy, Biden For Democracy: Survey]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-voters-prefer-trump-on-economy-biden-for-democracy-survey-5970662]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 26 Jun 2024 05:27:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[several years of fast-rising consumer prices, though inflation has slowed considerably in recent months and the jobless rate has been below 4% for more than two years.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>several years of fast-rising consumer prices, though inflation has slowed considerably in recent months and the jobless rate has been below 4% for more than two years.</p>

<p>The Republican had a more significant edge - 44% to 31% - on immigration. Immigrants made up 13.9% of the country in 2022, the highest share in over a century. Trump has taken aim at immigrants in the country illegally. Trump was favored 40% to 35% on foreign conflicts and terrorism.</p>

<p>But Biden had the edge over Trump on responding to political extremism and threats to democracy, respondents' No. 2 concern, with registered voters picking the Democrat over Trump by 39% to 33%.</p>

<p>Trump, who was convicted last month on criminal charges he falsified business records, is awaiting three more criminal trials, two of which are tied to his efforts to overturn his 2020 election loss to Biden. Trump, who falsely claims his 2020 election defeat resulted from fraud, included the claim in a fiery speech shortly before hundreds of his supporters stormed the U.S. Capitol on Jan. 6, 2021.</p>

<p>Biden also had an edge over Trump on healthcare policy - 40% to 29%. Biden was vice president in 2010 when then-President Barack Obama pushed a landmark health reform through Congress that dramatically increased access to health insurance.</p>

<p>Previous Reuters/Ipsos polls have shown Biden and Trump neck-and-neck in the presidential race, though a number of polls in battleground states have shown Trump ahead in recent months.</p>

<p>The Reuters/Ipsos poll, conducted nationwide and online, collected responses from 1,019 U.S. adults, including 856 registered voters. It had a margin of error of 3.2 percentage points for all respondents and 3.5 percentage points for registered voters.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-11/sd77uu9g_biden-trump-split-image_625x300_04_November_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump was favored 40% to 35% on foreign conflicts and terrorism.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/wikileaks-julian-assange-plea-bargain-hearing-begins-at-us-court-5970631]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[WikiLeaks Founder Julian Assange Pleads Guilty In US Court]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/wikileaks-julian-assange-plea-bargain-hearing-begins-at-us-court-5970631]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 26 Jun 2024 05:14:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A plea bargain hearing for Julian Assange began at a US court in Saipan on Wednesday, AFP reporters said, in a final legal step expected to leave the WikiLeaks founder a free man.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>WikiLeaks founder Julian Assange pleaded guilty in a US court in Saipan on Wednesday, AFP reporters said, in a plea bargain that will leave him a free man after years of legal drama.</p>

<p>The 52-year-old admitted to a single count of conspiracy to obtain and disseminate national defence information in the courtroom in the Northern Mariana Islands, a Pacific US territory.</p>

<p>"Guilty to the information," Assange said, later joking to the judge during the proceedings that whether he is satisfied "depends on the outcome of the hearing".</p>

<p>Assange has long been wanted by Washington for releasing hundreds of thousands of secret US documents from 2010 as head of the whistleblowing website WikiLeaks.</p>

<p>He was released Monday from a high-security British prison where he had been held for five years while he fought extradition to the United States.</p>

<p>On Wednesday, he is expected to be sentenced to five years and two months in prison, with credit for the same amount of time he spent behind bars in Britain.</p>

<p>Assange's wife Stella said he would be a "free man", thanking supporters who have campaigned for his release.</p>

<p>"We weren't really sure until the last 24 hours that it was actually happening," she told BBC radio, saying she was "just elated".</p>

<p>The Northern Mariana Islands was chosen because of Assange's unwillingness to go to the continental United States and because of its proximity to Australia, a court filing said.</p>

<p>After the hearing is done, Assange will fly to Canberra in Australia, WikiLeaks said on social media platform X, adding that the plea bargain "should never have had to happen."</p>

<p>The Australian government said his case had "dragged on for too long" and there was "nothing to be gained by his continued incarceration".</p>

<p><strong>- End of an ordeal -</strong></p>

<p>Since 2010 Assange has become a hero to free speech campaigners and a villain to those who thought he had endangered US security and intelligence sources.</p>

<p>US authorities wanted to put Assange on trial for divulging military secrets about the wars in Iraq and Afghanistan.</p>

<p>He was indicted by a US federal grand jury in 2019 on 18 counts stemming from WikiLeaks' publication of a trove of national security documents.</p>

<p>The United Nations hailed Assange's release, saying the case had raised "a series of human rights concerns".</p>

<p>Assange's mother Christine Assange said in a statement carried by Australian media that she was "grateful that my son's ordeal is finally coming to an end."</p>

<p>But former US vice president Mike Pence slammed the plea deal on X as a "miscarriage of justice" that "dishonors the service and sacrifice of the men and women of our Armed Forces."</p>

<p>The announcement of the deal came two weeks before Assange was scheduled to appear in court in Britain to appeal against a ruling that approved his extradition to the United States.</p>

<p><strong>- Extradition battle -</strong></p>

<p>Assange had been detained in the high-security Belmarsh prison in London since April 2019.</p>

<p>He was arrested after spending seven years in Ecuador's London embassy to avoid extradition to Sweden, where he faced accusations of sexual assault that were eventually dropped.</p>

<p>The material he released through WikiLeaks included video showing civilians being killed by fire from a US helicopter gunship in Iraq in 2007. The victims included a photographer and a driver from Reuters.</p>

<p>The United States accused Assange under the 1917 Espionage Act and supporters warned he risked being sentenced to 175 years in prison.</p>

<p>The British government approved his extradition in June 2022 but, in a recent twist, two British judges said in May that he could appeal against the transfer.</p>

<p>The plea deal was not entirely unexpected. US President Joe Biden had been under growing pressure to drop the long-running case against Assange.</p>

<p>The Australian government made an official request to that effect in February and Biden said he would consider it, raising hopes among Assange supporters that his ordeal might end.</p>

<p>In the first official US reax to the plea deal, State Department spokesman Matthew Miller said that as the case is about to go before a judge, "I think it's appropriate for me to not comment on the matter at this time."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/4ingcj8_julian-assange_625x300_26_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[WikiLeaks' Julian Assange landed in Saipan for US plea-deal court hearing on Wednesday.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukraine-russia-exchange-90-prisoners-of-war-5970517]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ukraine, Russia Exchange 90 Prisoners Of War]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukraine-russia-exchange-90-prisoners-of-war-5970517]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 26 Jun 2024 04:33:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ukraine and Russia have exchanged 90 prisoners of war each in the biggest swap between the two warring sides in almost five months, officials said Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ukraine and Russia have exchanged 90 prisoners of war each in the biggest swap between the two warring sides in almost five months, officials said Tuesday.</p>

<p>Moscow and Kyiv have carried out over 50 prisoner exchanges since Russia invaded Ukraine more than two years ago, despite ongoing hostilities and both sides accusing each other of derailing talks.</p>

<p>The United Arab Emirates mediated the deal announced on Tuesday.</p>

<p>"Today, 90 more of our people have returned home from Russian captivity," Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky said on social media.</p>

<p>"We remember all our people in Russian captivity. We continue to work for the release of each and every one of them," he said.</p>

<p>Russia said that 90 of its servicemen "who were in mortal danger in captivity have been returned from territory controlled by the Kyiv regime."</p>

<p>The freed servicemen will be airlifted to Moscow "for treatment and rehabilitation," its defence ministry said, confirming it had released 90 Ukrainian soldiers in return</p>

<p>The last swap between the two warring sides was at the end of May, when they exchanged 75 prisoners each, also with the UAE's mediation.</p>

<p>In February, both sides said they swapped 100 prisoners each, their first exchange since Moscow accused Kyiv of downing a plane carrying captured Ukrainian soldiers.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-02/af2nr57_russia-ukraine-war-avdiivka_625x300_17_February_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Moscow and Kyiv have carried out over 50 prisoner exchanges since Russia invaded Ukraine.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-court-partially-lifts-donald-trump-hush-money-gag-order-ahead-of-first-us-presidential-debate-5970404]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Court Partially Lifts Trump Gag Order Ahead Of 1st Presidential Debate]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-court-partially-lifts-donald-trump-hush-money-gag-order-ahead-of-first-us-presidential-debate-5970404]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 26 Jun 2024 03:57:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A New York judge partially lifted a gag order imposed on former President Donald Trump in his hush money criminal case on Tuesday, The Hill reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A judge eased a gag order on Tuesday that was imposed on Donald Trump during his criminal trial which saw him convicted of 34 counts, according to a court filing.</p>

<p>Judge Juan Merchan imposed the limited gag order ahead of the trial, restricting Trump from commenting publicly on jurors, witnesses, prosecutors and court staff, later expanding it to include his own family and that of the prosecutor.</p>

<p>Merchan, who will sentence the presidential hopeful on July 11, said that "circumstances have now changed. The trial portion of these proceedings ended when the verdict was rendered, and the jury discharged."</p>

<p>The order means Trump, the first ever former US president to be convicted of a felony, can now comment publicly about witnesses who testified at his trial, as well as discuss the jury and their verdict.</p>

<p>But Merchan said that measures barring the disclosure of jurors' identities would remain in place.</p>

<p>Trump was fined $10,000 by the Manhattan court for breaking the order on 10 occasions -- and threatened with jail for openly flouting the judge's ruling.</p>

<p>Before the gag order was imposed ahead of Trump's trial, the ex-president repeatedly attacked likely witnesses and the prosecutors via posts on his Truth Social platform.</p>

<p>On May 30 jurors found Trump, who is seeking to retake the presidency in this year's election, guilty of falsifying business records to cover up a sex scandal in the final stages of the 2016 presidential campaign.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/7un4ctq8_donald-trump_625x300_31_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The partial lift will allow Trump to address the jury that convicted him last month in hush money case.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korea-fires-ballistic-missile-into-sea-says-south-korea-5970376]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[North Korea Fires Ballistic Missile Into Sea, Says South Korea]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korea-fires-ballistic-missile-into-sea-says-south-korea-5970376]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 26 Jun 2024 03:45:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[North Korea fired a ballistic missile toward the sea on Wednesday, the South Korean military said, according to the Yonhap news agency.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>North Korea fired a ballistic missile toward the sea on Wednesday, the South Korean military said, according to the Yonhap news agency.</p>

<p>South Korea's Joint Chiefs of Staff said it detected the launch but gave no details, saying an analysis is under way.</p>

<p>The office of Japanese Prime Minister Fumio Kishida confirmed on X that North Korea launched a suspected ballistic missile.</p>

<p>"The suspected ballistic missile from North Korea is not expected to reach Japan," it said of the projectile filed toward the East Sea, also known as the Sea of Japan.</p>

<p>This launch came amid increased cross-border tension as the reclusive communist state has been sending balloons carrying garbage into South Korea.</p>

<p>North Korea's last missile launch prior to this one came on May 30, when Seoul accused Pyongyang of firing a volley of around 10 short-range ballistic missiles.</p>

<p>One day later North Korean state media released images of leader Kim Jong Un supervising tests of a multiple rocket launcher system.</p>

<p>Analysts have suggested the nuclear-armed North could be testing and ramping up production of artillery and cruise missiles before sending them to Russia for use in Ukraine.</p>

<p>In a report last month the Pentagon said it had confirmed this behaviour.</p>

<p>North Korea has sent more trash-filled balloons southward this week, Seoul's military said Tuesday, the latest in a series of border barrages that have sparked a tit-for-tat propaganda campaign.</p>

<p>Pyongyang has already sent more than a thousand balloons carrying trash in what it says is retaliation for balloons carrying propaganda criticising Kim's rule floated north by activists.</p>

<p>In response, Seoul has fully suspended a tension-reducing military deal and restarted some propaganda broadcasts from loudspeakers along the border.</p>

<p>Kim Jong Un's sister and key government spokeswoman Kim Yo Jong warned this month that Seoul would "undoubtedly witness the new counteraction of the DPRK" if the leaflet drops and loudspeaker broadcasts continued.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/bcqk7j4_north-korea-missile-launch-afp-_625x300_30_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[North Korea's last missile launch prior to this one came on May 30.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/possession-of-marijuana-not-a-crime-says-top-brazil-court-5970190]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Possession Of Marijuana Not A Crime, Says Top Brazil Court]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/possession-of-marijuana-not-a-crime-says-top-brazil-court-5970190]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 26 Jun 2024 02:46:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A majority of the justices on Brazil's Supreme Court are in favor of decriminalizing the possession of marijuana for personal consumption, following a crucial vote on Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;A majority of the justices on Brazil's Supreme Court are in favor of decriminalizing the possession of marijuana for personal consumption, following a crucial vote on Tuesday.</p>

<p>"The position is clear that no user of any drug can be considered a criminal," said Justice Dias Toffoli, the sixth judge on the 11-member top court to vote for decriminalization.</p>

<p>So far, three justices have opposed a decision to no longer make possession of cannabis a crime, including its most recent member, Cristiano Zanin, who was appointed by leftist President Luiz Inacio Lula da Silva.</p>

<p>The consumption of marijuana in public will continue to be prohibited and cannabis remains illegal in Brazil.</p>

<p>Decriminalizing its use has been discussed by the Supreme Court since 2015 and the justices reached a majority at a time when politicians are proposing a constitutional ban on the use of illegal drugs.</p>

<p>A bill advancing in Congress, with the support of conservative and evangelical lawmakers, proposes amending the Constitution to make the use and possession of any kind of narcotics a criminal offense.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/e7hnnr0g_marijuana-brazil_625x300_26_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The court, however, ruled that the consumption of marijuana in public will continue to be prohibited.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/brazil-floods-a-climate-warning-to-world-says-un-5970099]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Ghost Town": Brazil Floods A Climate Warning To World, Says UN]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/brazil-floods-a-climate-warning-to-world-says-un-5970099]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 26 Jun 2024 02:15:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Record floods that killed over 170 people and displaced half a million in southern Brazil are a warning sign of more disasters to come throughout the Americas because of climate change, an official at the UN' refugee agency said on Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Record floods that killed over 170 people and displaced half a million in southern Brazil are a warning sign of more disasters to come throughout the Americas because of climate change, an official at the United Nations' refugee agency said on Tuesday.</p>

<p>Roughly 389,000 people in the state of Rio Grande do Sul remain displaced from their homes because of the intense rain and flooding, which local officials say was the worst disaster in the region's history. Scientists say climate change made the flooding twice as likely to happen.</p>

<p>Andrew Harper, special advisor on climate action to the refugee agency UNHCR, visited a flooded neighborhood in state capital Porto Alegre over the weekend and called it "a ghost town."</p>

<p>"It was underwater for almost 40 days. There wasn't even any rats running around. Everything had died," Harper said in an interview on Tuesday.</p>

<p>Even after the flood waters subsided, residents have not returned to the neighborhood where streets are piled high with water-logged garbage and debris. Many are still living in shelters, including Venezuelan refugees who had resettled in Porto Alegre.</p>

<p>UNHCR is helping the local government to build temporary housing.</p>

<p>Residents of some hard hit areas may never return, having been forced to move by repeated flooding, Harper said. But how many would become so-called climate migrants will only be known years after the disaster.</p>

<p>The floods surpassed all expectations that local authorities had for climate disasters, and governments need to do more to prepare for these events, Harper said.</p>

<p>"We're seeing the emergence in Brazil of what we may be seeing throughout the Americas. So to ignore this, they do it at their own peril," Harper said.</p>

<p>Governments need to understand where the people most vulnerable to climate change live, like the neighborhood he visited in Porto Alegre, and include those people in their climate plans, he said.</p>

<p>"It's a warning signal, but we've been seeing warning signals now for five, ten years," Harper added. "At what point do you basically have to slap somebody in the face and say, 'Wake up, you're not going to ignore this.'"</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/elrcis3s_brazil-flood_625x300_26_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[UN official visited a flooded neighborhood in state capital Porto Alegre over the weekend.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kenya-protest-kenyan-president-vows-full-response-as-anti-tax-protests-intensify-5969973]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kenyan President Vows "Full Response" As Anti-Tax Protests Intensify]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kenya-protest-kenyan-president-vows-full-response-as-anti-tax-protests-intensify-5969973]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 26 Jun 2024 01:40:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kenya's President William Ruto vowed to take a tough line against "violence and anarchy" on Tuesday, after protests against his government's proposed tax hikes turned deadly and demonstrators ransacked parliament.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kenya's President William Ruto vowed to take a tough line against "violence and anarchy" on Tuesday, after protests against his government's proposed tax hikes turned deadly and demonstrators ransacked parliament.</p>

<p>The youth-led protests, which have steadily grown over the past two weeks, had been largely peaceful but chaos erupted in the capital on Tuesday, with crowds throwing stones at police, pushing past barricades and ultimately entering the grounds of Kenya's parliament.</p>

<p>The military has been deployed to support police who fired tear gas, water cannon, rubber bullets and -- according to a rights group -- live ammunition against protesters.</p>

<p>Five people were shot dead and 31 wounded, several NGOs including Amnesty Kenya reported in a joint statement.</p>

<p>"We shall provide a full, effective and expeditious response to today's treasonous events," Ruto told a press briefing in Nairobi, saying the demonstrations were "hijacked by dangerous people".</p>

<p>"It is not in order or even conceivable that criminals pretending to be peaceful protesters can reign terror against the people, their elected representatives and the institutions established under our constitution and expect to go scot-free," Ruto added.</p>

<p>"I hereby put on notice the planners, financiers, orchestrators, abetters of violence and anarchy."</p>

<p>The White House appealed for calm and 13 Western nations -- including Canada, Germany and Britain -- said they were "especially shocked" by the scenes outside parliament.</p>

<p>Mainly youth-led rallies have galvanised outrage over proposed tax hikes and simmering anger over a cost-of-living crisis to fuel rapidly growing demonstrations that have caught the government off guard.</p>

<p>"This is the voice of the young people of Kenya," said Elizabeth Nyaberi, 26, a lawyer at a protest. "They are tear gassing us, but we don't care."</p>

<p>"We are here to speak for our generations and the generations to come," she added.</p>

<p><strong>- 'Unleashed brute force' -</strong></p>

<p>Amid the clashes, global web monitor NetBlocks reported that a "major disruption" had hit the country's internet service.</p>

<p>In the aftermath of the parliament compound breach, local TV showed images of ransacked rooms with smashed windows, while cars parked outside were vandalised and flags destroyed, according to an AFP reporter.</p>

<p>The governor's office in Nairobi City Hall -- just a few hundred metres from parliament -- was set alight, footage on privately owned Citizen TV showed, with a water cannon attempting to douse the fire.</p>

<p>After reports that live ammunition was fired at protesters, Kenya's main opposition coalition, Azimio, said the government had "unleashed brute force on our country's children".</p>

<p>"Kenya cannot afford to kill its children just because the children are asking for food, jobs and a listening ear," it said in a statement.</p>

<p>The military's deployment was "in response to the security emergency" across Kenya, Defence Minister Aden Bare Duale said in a statement.</p>

<p>Despite the heavy police presence, thousands of protesters had earlier marched peacefully through Nairobi's business district, many livestreaming the action as they sang and beat drums in their push towards parliament.</p>

<p>Crowds also marched in the port city of Mombasa, the opposition bastion of Kisumu, and Ruto's stronghold of Eldoret, images on Kenyan TV channels showed.</p>

<p><strong>- Protesters 'abducted' -</strong></p>

<p>The Independent Policing Oversight Authority watchdog and rights groups said two people had died following last week's rallies in Nairobi.</p>

<p>Several organisations, including Amnesty International Kenya, said at least 200 people were wounded in last week's protests in Nairobi.</p>

<p>Amnesty's Kenya chapter posted on X Tuesday that "the pattern of policing protests is deteriorating fast", urging the government to respect demonstrators' right to assembly.</p>

<p>Rights watchdogs have also accused the authorities of abducting protesters.</p>

<p>The Kenya Human Rights Commission said the abductions had mostly occurred at night and were "conducted by police officers in civilian clothes and unmarked cars", calling for the "unconditional release of all abductees".</p>

<p>Police have not responded to AFP requests for comment on the allegations.</p>

<p><strong>- Fuel price hikes -</strong></p>

<p>The cash-strapped government agreed last week to roll back several tax increases.</p>

<p>But it still intends to raise other taxes to fill the void left by the changes, including on fuel prices and export taxes, saying they are necessary for filling the state coffers and cutting reliance on external borrowing.</p>

<p>Critics say the move will make life more expensive in a country already saddled with high inflation and where well-paid jobs are out-of-reach for many young Kenyans.</p>

<p>Kenya has one of the most dynamic economies in East Africa but a third of its 52 million people live in poverty.</p>

<p>The country has a huge debt mountain whose servicing costs have ballooned because of a fall in the value of the local currency over the last two years, making interest payments on foreign-currency loans more expensive.</p>

<p>After the government agreed to scrap levies on bread purchases, car ownership and financial and mobile services, the treasury warned of a budget shortfall of 200 billion shillings ($1.56 billion).</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/five-killed-in-las-vegas-shooting-suspect-arrested-report-5969903]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Five Killed In Las Vegas Shooting, Suspect Arrested: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/five-killed-in-las-vegas-shooting-suspect-arrested-report-5969903]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 26 Jun 2024 01:12:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Police in North Las Vegas on Tuesday captured a man they suspect shot and killed five people in an apartment complex, according to local media reports.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Police in North Las Vegas on Tuesday captured a man they suspect shot and killed five people in an apartment complex, according to local media reports.</p>

<p>The Las Vegas Review-Journal newspaper, citing a police statement, said that in addition to the five dead, a 13-year-old girl was also shot and is in critical condition at a nearby hospital.</p>

<p>North Las Vegas police did not return requests for comment.</p>

<p>Police identified the suspect as Eric Adams, 57, according to the Review-Journal. He is suspected of carrying out the shooting late on Monday in two different apartments within the same apartment complex.</p>

<p>Police did not provide details on any possible motive for the shooting, nor did they say when or how they arrested Adams.</p>

<p>Names of the victims have not been released, though police said that four women and one man were among those killed, according to the newspaper.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-07/6835sp0g_us-police-generic_625x300_27_July_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Police said that four women and one man were among those killed in shooting. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-pm-sheikh-hasina-says-will-gauge-india-china-proposals-on-teesta-project-5967879]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh PM Says Will Gauge India, China Proposals On Teesta Project]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-pm-sheikh-hasina-says-will-gauge-india-china-proposals-on-teesta-project-5967879]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 26 Jun 2024 00:01:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina said on Tuesday that Bangladesh would gauge proposals from both India and China to build a mega project on the cross-border Teesta River involving a reservoir and accept the better one for her country.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina said on Tuesday that Bangladesh would gauge proposals from both India and China to build a mega project on the cross-border Teesta River involving a reservoir and accept the better one for her country.</p>

<p>PM Hasina, who visited India last week at the invitation of Prime Minister Narendra Modi, described her trip as "very fruitful" and said the outcome of her talks with India's top leadership will play a "pivotal role" in strengthening the existing bilateral relations and opening new avenues of cooperation.</p>

<p>"We undertook the Teesta projects. China has proposed, and so has India. We will evaluate both proposals and accept the one that is most beneficial and acceptable in terms of the interests of our people," the 76-year-old leader said while addressing a press conference here.</p>

<p>Asked which side she favoured more as far as India and China were concerned regarding the Teesta Project, PM Hasina said, "We maintain our friendships based on the developmental needs of our country”.</p>

<p>"When we receive a proposal, we consider factors such as its suitability for us, our capacity to repay any loans, the returns we will enjoy after project completion, and how it will benefit the people of our country," she said.</p>

<p>China has completed a physical survey on the project while India expressed its willingness to do another study regarding the implementation of the Teesta project.</p>

<p>India is presumed to have a reservation over China's involvement in a major project near its strategic Siliguri Corridor, also known as the Chicken's Neck, while Bangladesh's foreign ministry earlier said Dhaka would "take into cognizance the geopolitical issues" in proceeding with the proposal.</p>

<p>According to Bangladesh officials, China in 2020 proposed a major dredging work on the Teesta River and building reservoirs and embankments without India having to play any role, but Bangladesh has kept the billion-dollar project on hold.</p>

<p>Several analysts said the Chinese involvement in the project could complicate the India-Bangladesh dispute over the major common river.</p>

<p>The Teesta water sharing agreement has been in the talks since the Awami League government returned to power in 2009 while PM Hasina today said “Bangladesh has a longstanding issue over Teesta River water sharing with India”.</p>

<p>"So, it will be easy for Bangladesh if India does the Teesta project. In that case, we won't need to talk about the Teesta water sharing always," she added.</p>

<p>PM Hasina simultaneously said Bangladesh has a longstanding issue with India over water sharing of the 54 common rivers but added that “if there are problems, there are solutions as well".</p>

<p>"India has agreed to cooperate with us on the Teesta project. A joint committee will be formed to decide not only how the water will be shared but also how to revive the river, use it for cultivation in the northern region, and enhance its navigation," she said.</p>

<p>She said the water-sharing discussion included river dredging, constructing embankments and water conservation measures as well.</p>

<p>"India will send a technical team after the 1996 Ganges water treaty expires in 2026. The team (with their Bangladesh counterparts) will explore options and negotiate the terms," she added.</p>

<p>Dhaka and New Delhi were set to ink the Teesta Agreement during former Prime Minister Manmohan Singh's Bangladesh visit in 2011 when West Bengal Chief Minister Mamata Banerjee was also supposed to be his entourage member.</p>

<p>But Ms Banerjee precluded her from his entourage at the last minute, opposing the treaty.</p>

<p>India and Bangladesh agreed to sign the deal but it could not be materialised due to opposition from the West Bengal government.</p>

<p>Indian media reports have suggested that the West Bengal government decided in principle to dig two new canals to divert the Teesta waters for irrigation purposes in the Jalpaiguri and Cooch Behar districts.</p>

<p>Replying to another query about Ms Banerjee's objection to the Indian government's move over the Teesta and Ganges rivers water sharing with Bangladesh, PM Hasina said she doesn't want to make any comment over the issue as it is solely their internal matter.</p>

<p>But PM Hasina said she has a good relationship with all the political parties in India, including PM Modi and Ms Banerjee.</p>

<p>Asked how she wanted to strike a balance regarding ties between India and China in her fifth term, four in a row, the premier said there was nothing to balance as her government was following a foreign policy principle that suggests -- "Friendship to all, malice to none".</p>

<p>Mr Hasina said India is very important for Dhaka as they along with the Freedom Fighters shed blood for the independence of Bangladesh during the 1971 Liberation War.</p>

<p>Simultaneously, she said, there were many things to learn from China about how the country could be developed.</p>

<p>"We maintain the relations considering all these aspects," she said, adding that she never interfered with what relations the two countries have.</p>

<p>"I work for the welfare and development of the country and people maintaining friendly relations with all." She also said she didn't see any problem with maintaining relations with India and China.</p>

<p>The premier said she went to New Delhi as she was first invited to visit India to attend the swearing-in ceremony of Prime Minister Modi and later invited for a state visit to India and now, she would visit China as that country has also invited her.</p>

<p>Replying to a question about rail transit to India, she said Bangladesh and India decided to resume the rail connectivity considering their trade and commerce and socio-economic development.</p>

<p>The premier said Bangladesh is an independent country and “we liberated the country through the Liberation War”.</p>

<p>She said everyone should keep in mind that India was the only force in the world which left a country after helping in its liberation and referred to the American troops of allied forces which were still staying in Japan and Russian troops in Germany.</p>

<p>"Even then, some talk about the rail issue that Bangladesh will be sold to India. How do they say this? Those who talk like this are themselves sold to India," she said.</p>

<p>They criticise India publicly and flatter secretly, she added.</p>

<p>"Look at Europe where there are no borders. Is one country selling itself to another country there? …will we keep our doors shut in Bangladesh?" she added.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-01/ndjlqm4_sheikh-hasina_625x300_11_January_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[PM Hasina had visited India last week at the invitation of PM Modi. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/setback-for-canadas-trudeau-liberals-lose-stronghold-in-key-polls-5969262]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Setback For Canada's Trudeau, Liberals Lose Stronghold In Key Polls]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/setback-for-canadas-trudeau-liberals-lose-stronghold-in-key-polls-5969262]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 23:50:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In a stunning blow to Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau, his Liberal Party lost a closely-watched federal by-election on Tuesday to the Conservatives from a longtime Liberal stronghold.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a stunning blow to Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau, his Liberal Party lost a closely-watched federal by-election on Tuesday to the Conservatives from a longtime Liberal stronghold, prompting opposition leader Pierre Poilievre to demand a snap election.</p>

<p>In a nail-biting finish, Conservative candidate Don Stewart won the Liberal stronghold of Toronto-St. Paul's by defeating Liberal Party's Leslie Church by 590 votes. The contest also featured Amrit Parhar, an Indian-origin candidate from the New Democratic Party.</p>

<p>Toronto-St. Paul's is a federal electoral district in Toronto, Ontario province. The Liberal Party had held Toronto-St Paul's since 1993. It is one of 338 seats in the House of Commons.</p>

<p>Stewart's victory over Church is shocking because the seat has been held by the Liberals for more than 30 years, Canadian media commented.</p>

<p>Before Monday, the seat was held by the Liberals for 10 successive elections. Former MP Carolyn Bennett — whose appointment as ambassador to Denmark triggered the byelection — had been the local representative for over 25 years.</p>

<p>"Thank you, Toronto-St. Paul's! I am beyond humbled for the trust you have put in me and I will never take it for granted. I promise to be YOUR voice on Parliament Hill," Stewart posted on X.</p>

<p>His rival, Church in her remarks after she lost the race, noted that the Liberals have got 16 months until the next election. "I plan to be the Liberal candidate in St. Paul's. We start working to earn back the trust of voters...," she posted on X.</p>

<p>"Congratulations to Don Stewart on a well run campaign. We look forward to the rematch," she wrote.</p>

<p>According to the preliminary results, Stewart won 42.1 per cent of the vote with 15,555 votes cast for him, while Church received 40.5 per cent of the vote, with 14,965 ballots cast for her. The NDP candidate Parhar came a distant third with 10.9 per cent of the votes. Christian Cullis, who ran for the Green Party, received 2.9 per cent of the votes.</p>

<p>Losing the historic stronghold is likely to pile pressure on Prime Minister Trudeau, Global News reported.</p>

<p>"The Liberals' poor showing in a stronghold like this could prompt some soul-searching for Trudeau, who has seen his popularity plummet as inflation, the cost of living crisis, high home prices and surging immigration levels drive voter discontent," CBC News commented.</p>

<p>This Conservative upset is likely to lead to some anxiety in the Liberal caucus because such a dramatic vote swing could put other supposedly "safe" seats in play for the Conservatives in the next general election, expected to be in 2025, it said.</p>

<p>Conservative Leader Poilievre demanded Prime Minister Trudeau call a snap election after what he described as a “shocking upset” on social media Tuesday.</p>

<p>“Here is the verdict: Trudeau can't go on like this. He must call a carbon tax election now,” Poilievre wrote on X.</p>

<p>Voters in Toronto-St. Paul's told CBC News throughout the campaign that the government's handling of the housing crisis, inflation and the Israel-Hamas conflict were sore spots.</p>

<p>But it wasn't just about the issues - several voters expressed a desire for change and fatigue with Trudeau.</p>

<p>Even past and present Liberal supporters told CBC News Trudeau should resign as leader if the party loses this one-time ruby-red Liberal seat.</p>

<p>Trudeau, whose allegations in September last year of "potential" involvement of Indian agents in the killing of a Sikh terrorist in Canada caused a severe strain in Ottawa's relations with New Delhi, has given no indication he's stepping down.</p>

<p>The 52-year-old prime minister has repeatedly said he will lead the Liberal Party into the federal election that is expected sometime next year.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, national polling shows Trudeau's Liberal Party struggling to attract and retain support, with Conservative support growing.&nbsp; A poll conducted by Ipsos for Global News suggested Trudeau's waning popularity appears to be “dragging” the Liberals' fortunes down.</p>

<p>A majority of voters (68 per cent) want him to step down, with Ipsos CEO Darrell Bricker describing the numbers as “close to rock bottom,” while Conservative Leader Poilievre, 45, is gaining ground.</p>

<p>That poll put the Conservatives at 42 per cent of the decided vote, with the Liberals at 24 per cent.&nbsp;Almost half - 44 per cent - said they felt Conservative Leader Poilievre would make the best prime minister, while 75 per cent of Canadians want another party to take government from the Liberals.</p>

<p>Just 25 per cent think the Liberals “deserve reelection,” Global News reported.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/cvt02ck8_justin-trudeau_625x300_09_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Opposition leader Pierre Poilievre has demanded that Trudeau call a snap election. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gun-violence-a-public-health-crisis-in-us-declares-surgeon-general-5969055]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Gun Violence A Public Health Crisis In US, Declares Surgeon General]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gun-violence-a-public-health-crisis-in-us-declares-surgeon-general-5969055]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 23:14:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In a new advisory released on Tuesday, US Surgeon General Dr Vivek Murthy said that gun violence in the country is an urgent public health crisis that demands the "collective commitment of the nation" to put an end to it, reported CNN.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a new advisory released on Tuesday, US Surgeon General Dr Vivek Murthy said that gun violence in the country is an urgent public health crisis that demands the "collective commitment of the nation" to put an end to it, reported CNN.</p>

<p>This is the first Office of the Surgeon General publication that specifically addresses gun violence and its "deep consequences" for victims, communities, and mental health.</p>

<p>The US Department of Health and Human Services states that a surgeon general's advice is usually used to highlight important public health issues.</p>

<p>The advise released on Tuesday outlines the terrible effects of gun violence in the US and provides information on how public health initiatives can be helpful.</p>

<p>Provisional data indicates that over 48,000 US citizens lost their lives as a result of firearm-related injuries in 2022 alone. Homicides, suicides, and accidental deaths were all included in that total. The recommendation states that the number of firearm-related deaths in the US has been increasing and will peak in 2021 at three decades, reported CNN.</p>

<p>According to the advice, since then, there has been a decline in gun-related killings but the number of gun-related suicides has remained relatively constant. The caution states that although mass shootings are still uncommon--they account for only 1 per cent of gun fatalities--the frequency of these events has been increasing.</p>

<p>The Surgeon General's advisory underlined, how people of colour are "disproportionately impacted" by gun violence, reported CNN.</p>

<p>The recommendation states that firearm violence can have a negative impact on mental health in addition to the physical issues it can cause.</p>

<p>According to the advisory, youngsters are especially prone to fearing gun violence, with many of them believing that their school will be the scene of such carnage. It states that in order to understand how to lower and prevent firearm violence in the US, additional funding for guns research is required. Investments should be made with a focus on improving data gathering and preventative tactics, CNN reported.</p>

<p>The guideline calls on healthcare providers and communities to take proactive measures to support populations that are most at risk of this type of violence.</p>

<p>"There are no federal standards or regulations regarding the safety of firearms produced in the US," the advisory says.</p>

<p>In the past few weeks, the US has witnessed several shooting incidents, with at least 21 other mass shootings recorded by the Gun Violence Archive since last Friday. According to CNN report, the Gun Violence Archive regards mass shootings as ones in which four or more people are shot, excluding the shooter.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-05/qn6uc1s8_gun-violence_625x300_21_May_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Provisional data indicates that over 48,000 US citizens died due to gun-related injuries in 2022. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>