<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Sun, 28 Jul 2024 04:19:32 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-says-underdog-campaign-will-overcome-trumps-wild-lies-6204455]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris Says "Underdog" Campaign Will Overcome Trump's "Wild Lies"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-says-underdog-campaign-will-overcome-trumps-wild-lies-6204455]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 28 Jul 2024 03:30:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US Vice President Kamala Harris on Saturday acknowledged the uphill climb to defeating Donald Trump in November, but said her freshly-minted presidential campaign would prevail over the "wild lies" of her Republican rival.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US Vice President Kamala Harris on Saturday acknowledged the uphill climb to defeating Donald Trump in November, but said her freshly-minted presidential campaign would prevail over the "wild lies" of her Republican rival.</p>

<p>As Trump prepared to address a bitcoin conference in Tennessee, Harris was speaking at a fundraising event in Massachusetts with celebrity guests including singer-songwriter James Taylor and cellist Yoyo Ma.</p>

<p>"We are the underdogs in this race, but this is a people-powered campaign," she told the crowd at the event, which her campaign said would net $1.4 million.</p>

<p>"You may have noticed, Donald Trump has been resorting to some wild lies about my record. And some of what he and his running mate are saying, well, it's just plain weird," she said, the latest quip adopted by Democrats in describing the Republicans' attacks.</p>

<p>The latest among them included Trump's remarks to a religious convention Friday night, where he accused Harris of being an anti-Semite who plans to allow the murder of newborn babies.</p>

<p>"She doesn't like Jewish people. She doesn't like Israel. That's the way it is," he said of the vice president, whose husband is Jewish.</p>

<p>In perhaps his most outrageous statement of the night, he claimed Harris wanted to enshrine in federal law the right to "rip the baby out of the womb in the eighth, ninth month and even after birth -- execute the baby after birth."</p>

<p>Trump, who at age 78 is now the oldest major-party nominee in history, is scrambling to reorient an election against someone two decades his junior, having expected to face an 81-year-old incumbent Joe Biden beset by concerns over infirmity.</p>

<p>Seeking to become the first female president in US history, Harris is tasked with rapidly assembling a campaign against an opponent who has been in near permanent reelection mode since he became president in 2016.</p>

<p>Her late-starting White House bid has enjoyed early momentum. Polls that had shown Biden steadily slipping against Trump now show Harris in a race too close to call.</p>

<p>She's garnered support from Democratic heavyweights, including Biden himself and most recently Barack and Michelle Obama.</p>

<p>Torianna Parrish, 34, was among the crowd greeting Harris upon her arrival Saturday afternoon at the airport in Westfield, Massachusetts.</p>

<p>"I wanted to show there's power in numbers. I wanted to show my support," she said.</p>

<p>"We're rooting for her and we want to see her make this country what it needs to be."</p>

<p>Harris was introduced at the Colonial Theater in Pittsfield by Taylor, who said: "Let us honor the woman and the moment and may our ardent support be the wind in her sails. Our hopes go with her and she stands for us all."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/kqs5e0o4_kamala-harris-donald-trump_625x300_27_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/will-pay-heavy-price-netanyahu-warns-hezbollah-after-air-strike-kills-11-6204151]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Will Pay Heavy Price": Netanyahu Warns Hezbollah After Air Strike Kills 11]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/will-pay-heavy-price-netanyahu-warns-hezbollah-after-air-strike-kills-11-6204151]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 28 Jul 2024 01:57:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A rocket fired from Lebanon hit a football pitch in an Arab town in the Israeli-annexed Golan Heights Saturday, killing 11 youngsters in what the army described as the "deadliest attack on Israeli civilians since October 7".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A rocket fired from Lebanon hit a football pitch in an Arab town in the Israeli-annexed Golan Heights Saturday, killing 11 youngsters in what the army described as the "deadliest attack on Israeli civilians since October 7".</p>

<p>The army said Lebanese group Hezbollah fired the deadly rocket that killed the youngsters aged between 10 and 20 years when they were hit on the pitch in the town of Majdal Shams.</p>

<p>Many residents of the town retain Syrian nationality decades after the territory's occupation in the 1967 Arab-Israeli war.</p>

<p>The rocket fire came after an Israeli strike killed four Hezbollah fighters in south Lebanon prompting the Iran-backed militant group to announce a flurry of retaliatory rocket attacks against the Golan and northern Israel.</p>

<p>Military spokesman Daniel Hagari said on X that 11 youngsters were killed in the attack, while the emergency service Magen David Adom said 19 others were wounded when the rocket hit Majdal Shams.</p>

<p>"We will prepare for a response against Hezbollah... we will act," Rear Admiral Hagari said in a video statement, adding the rocket fire was the "deadliest attack on Israeli civilians since October 7" when Hamas militants attacked southern Israel sparking war in Gaza.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu, who was returning early from a visit to the United States, vowed that "Israel will not let this murderous attack go unanswered".</p>

<p>"Hezbollah will pay a heavy price for it, a price it has not paid before," he warned in a statement released by his office.</p>

<p>- 'Only crime' playing soccer -</p>

<p>Israeli President Isaac Herzog charged that Hezbollah had "brutally attacked and murdered children today, whose only crime was going out to play soccer".</p>

<p>Hezbollah denied it was responsible for the deadly strike.</p>

<p>"The Islamic Resistance has no connection to this incident," it said, referring to its military wing.</p>

<p>The police and the army said the rocket fired at Majdal Shams was part of a barrage of rockets fired from Lebanon which struck multiple locations in the Golan.</p>

<p>Ambulances, helicopters and mobile intensive care units were deployed to the scene, the army said.</p>

<p>"We arrived at a football pitch and saw destruction and objects on fire. Injured people were lying on the grass," paramedic Idan Avshalom said in a statement issued by Magen David Adom.</p>

<p>An AFP correspondent saw medics carrying away the wounded for treatment.</p>

<p>"Officers and police bomb disposal experts from the northern district police are currently securing the area and searching for additional (rocket) remnants to eliminate any further risk to the public," the police said in a separate statement.</p>

<p>The rocket fire came after a Lebanese security source said an Israeli strike killed four Hezbollah fighters in the southern village of Kfar Kila.</p>

<p>Hezbollah, which has exchanged near-daily cross-border fire with the Israeli army since the Gaza war erupted last October, confirmed the deaths of four of its fighters.</p>

<p>It said it carried out a dozen retaliatory attacks on Israeli targets, nine in the space of two hours.</p>

<p>The violence since October has killed at least 527 people in Lebanon, according to an AFP tally. Most of the dead have been fighters, but they have included at least 104 civilians.</p>

<p>On the Israeli side, 18 soldiers and 24 civilians have been killed, according to Israeli authorities.</p>

<p>The war in Gaza broke out after Hamas's October 7 attack resulted in the deaths of 1,197 people in Israel, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on official Israeli figures.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory military campaign in Gaza has killed at least 39,258 people, according to the health ministry in the Hamas-run territory, which does not provide details on civilian and militant deaths.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/s3tapnio_netanyahu_625x300_24_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/will-pay-heavy-price-netanyahu-warns-hezbollah-after-air-strike-kills-10-6204150]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Will Pay Heavy Price": Netanyahu Warns Hezbollah After Strike Kills 10]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/will-pay-heavy-price-netanyahu-warns-hezbollah-after-air-strike-kills-10-6204150]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 28 Jul 2024 01:57:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A rocket fired from Lebanon hit a football pitch in an Arab town in the Israeli-annexed Golan Heights Saturday, killing 11 youngsters in what the army described as the "deadliest attack on Israeli civilians since October 7".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A rocket fired from Lebanon hit a football pitch in an Arab town in the Israeli-annexed Golan Heights Saturday, killing 11 youngsters in what the army described as the "deadliest attack on Israeli civilians since October 7".</p>

<p>The army said Lebanese group Hezbollah fired the deadly rocket that killed the youngsters aged between 10 and 20 years when they were hit on the pitch in the town of Majdal Shams.</p>

<p>Many residents of the town retain Syrian nationality decades after the territory's occupation in the 1967 Arab-Israeli war.</p>

<p>The rocket fire came after an Israeli strike killed four Hezbollah fighters in south Lebanon prompting the Iran-backed militant group to announce a flurry of retaliatory rocket attacks against the Golan and northern Israel.</p>

<p>Military spokesman Daniel Hagari said on X that 11 youngsters were killed in the attack, while the emergency service Magen David Adom said 19 others were wounded when the rocket hit Majdal Shams.</p>

<p>"We will prepare for a response against Hezbollah... we will act," Rear Admiral Hagari said in a video statement, adding the rocket fire was the "deadliest attack on Israeli civilians since October 7" when Hamas militants attacked southern Israel sparking war in Gaza.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu, who was returning early from a visit to the United States, vowed that "Israel will not let this murderous attack go unanswered".</p>

<p>"Hezbollah will pay a heavy price for it, a price it has not paid before," he warned in a statement released by his office.</p>

<p>- 'Only crime' playing soccer -</p>

<p>Israeli President Isaac Herzog charged that Hezbollah had "brutally attacked and murdered children today, whose only crime was going out to play soccer".</p>

<p>Hezbollah denied it was responsible for the deadly strike.</p>

<p>"The Islamic Resistance has no connection to this incident," it said, referring to its military wing.</p>

<p>The police and the army said the rocket fired at Majdal Shams was part of a barrage of rockets fired from Lebanon which struck multiple locations in the Golan.</p>

<p>Ambulances, helicopters and mobile intensive care units were deployed to the scene, the army said.</p>

<p>"We arrived at a football pitch and saw destruction and objects on fire. Injured people were lying on the grass," paramedic Idan Avshalom said in a statement issued by Magen David Adom.</p>

<p>An AFP correspondent saw medics carrying away the wounded for treatment.</p>

<p>"Officers and police bomb disposal experts from the northern district police are currently securing the area and searching for additional (rocket) remnants to eliminate any further risk to the public," the police said in a separate statement.</p>

<p>The rocket fire came after a Lebanese security source said an Israeli strike killed four Hezbollah fighters in the southern village of Kfar Kila.</p>

<p>Hezbollah, which has exchanged near-daily cross-border fire with the Israeli army since the Gaza war erupted last October, confirmed the deaths of four of its fighters.</p>

<p>It said it carried out a dozen retaliatory attacks on Israeli targets, nine in the space of two hours.</p>

<p>The violence since October has killed at least 527 people in Lebanon, according to an AFP tally. Most of the dead have been fighters, but they have included at least 104 civilians.</p>

<p>On the Israeli side, 18 soldiers and 24 civilians have been killed, according to Israeli authorities.</p>

<p>The war in Gaza broke out after Hamas's October 7 attack resulted in the deaths of 1,197 people in Israel, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on official Israeli figures.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory military campaign in Gaza has killed at least 39,258 people, according to the health ministry in the Hamas-run territory, which does not provide details on civilian and militant deaths.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/s3tapnio_netanyahu_625x300_24_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/its-british-were-used-to-rain-uk-pm-shrugs-off-paris-olympics-photo-6204149]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["It's British. We're Used To Rain": UK PM Shrugs Off Paris Olympics Photo]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/its-british-were-used-to-rain-uk-pm-shrugs-off-paris-olympics-photo-6204149]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 28 Jul 2024 01:55:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[British Prime Minister Keir Starmer Saturday brushed off the fascination with a viral image taken at the Paris Olympic Games opening ceremony showing him as the only dignitary not wearing a protective plastic poncho during driving rain.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>British Prime Minister Keir Starmer Saturday brushed off the fascination with a viral image taken at the Paris Olympic Games opening ceremony showing him as the only dignitary not wearing a protective plastic poncho during driving rain.</p>

<p>Starmer was pictured as the only person bare-headed as other VIPs opted to encase themselves in plastic hand-out ponchos to protect themselves from the rain that blighted Friday's opening ceremony on the River Seine.</p>

<p>The image was widely shared on social media, with users seeing the picture as a classic example of a very British stiff upper lip in the face of the inclement weather all to familiar to residents of the famously drizzly country.</p>

<p>"It's British! We are used to the rain," Starmer told French channel LCI in an interview.</p>

<p>"But it (the rain) didn't dampen the spirits," he added, describing the opening ceremony as a "spectacular" and "fantastic" event that made "the whole use of the river (and) of Paris."</p>

<p>Starmer, elected earlier this month in a landslide election victory for the centre-left Labour Party that ended 14 years of right-wing Conservative rule, was making his first official visit to Paris as premier.</p>

<p>"Nothing more British than absolutely refusing to wear one of those plastic poncho things," wrote one user on X, formerly Twitter.</p>

<p>Rain has had considerable symbolism in British politics in recent weeks.</p>

<p>When he called the general election, Conservative former prime minister Rishi Sunak was widely mocked for delivering his address outside 10 Downing Street in pouring rain without a coat or an umbrella.</p>

<p>Starmer was however wearing a navy blue Team GB rain-proof jacket and in other images could also be seen using its hood to protect his hair from the rain.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Preparation is the key to success," the Labour Party wrote on X as it posted one of these images.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/nr0lrb98_keir-starmer-rain_625x300_28_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The image was seen as a classic example of a very British stiff upper lip.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/9-killed-as-rocket-hits-football-pitch-in-israel-occupied-golan-report-6203464]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Army Says Hezbollah Fired Rocket That Killed 10 In Annexed Golan]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/9-killed-as-rocket-hits-football-pitch-in-israel-occupied-golan-report-6203464]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 27 Jul 2024 23:08:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ten people, including children, were killed in a rocket attack on a football ground in the Israeli-occupied Golan Heights on Saturday, Israel's N12 News reported, the worst incident yet in months of violence between Israel and armed groups in Lebanon]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ten people, including children, were killed in a rocket attack on a football ground in the Israeli-occupied Golan Heights on Saturday, Israel's N12 News reported, the worst incident yet in months of violence between Israel and armed groups in Lebanon.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said the rocket was fired by Lebanese group Hezbollah. The Iran-backed group denied any involvement in the attack, which looked likely to draw a fierce response from Israel.</p>

<p>The Israeli emergency service said earlier that nine people were critically wounded by a rocket fired from Lebanon that hit a village football pitch in the Druze village of Majdal Shams. A medic described great destruction and fire at the scene.</p>

<p>"We witnessed great destruction when we arrived at the soccer field, as well as items that were on fire. There were casualties on the grass and the scene was gruesome," said Magen David Adom medic Idan Avshalom.</p>

<p>A witness told Reuters: "It landed in the soccer pitch, all of them are children ... many bodies and remains are in field we don't know who they are." She asked not to be named.</p>

<p>The attack on the soccer pitch followed an Israeli strike in Lebanon that killed four operatives on Saturday. Two security sources in Lebanon said the four fighters killed in the Israeli strike on Kfarkila in southern Lebanon were members of different armed groups, with at least one of them belonging to Hezbollah.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said its aircraft had targeted a military structure belonging to Hezbollah, after identifying a militant cell entering the building.</p>

<p>At least 30 rockets were then fired from Lebanon across the border, the military said.</p>

<p>"According to an IDF situational assessment and the intelligence in our possession, the rocket launch toward Majdal Shams was carried out by the Hezbollah terrorist organization," the military said.</p>

<p>Hezbollah claimed at least four attacks, including with Katyusha rockets, in retaliation for the Kfarkila attacks. However senior Hezbollah media representative Mohammad Afif denied responsibility for the strike on Majdal Shams.</p>

<p>In a written statement, but group said "the Islamic Resistance has absolutely nothing to do with the incident, and categorically denies all false allegations in this regard".</p>

<p>Hezbollah and Israel have been trading fire since October, after Hamas' attack on southern Israel triggered the Gaza war, in their worst escalation since 2006.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/16nkdeig_golan-attack_625x300_27_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/4-hezbollah-fighters-killed-in-israeli-strike-as-tensions-flare-up-report-6203385]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[4 Hezbollah Fighters Killed In Israeli Strike As Tensions Flare-Up: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/4-hezbollah-fighters-killed-in-israeli-strike-as-tensions-flare-up-report-6203385]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 27 Jul 2024 22:51:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An Israeli strike on south Lebanon killed four fighters of Iran-backed operative group Hezbollah on Saturday, a security source told AFP.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An Israeli strike on south Lebanon killed four fighters of Iran-backed operative group Hezbollah on Saturday, a security source told AFP.</p>

<p>"Four Hezbollah fighters were killed in an Israeli strike on the village of Kfar Kila," the source said, speaking on condition of anonymity.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Hezbollah, which has exchanged near-daily cross-border fire with the Israeli army since the Gaza war erupted last October, confirmed the deaths of four of its fighters.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-10/6e8i71v_missile-generic_650x400_17_October_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hezbollah has exchanged near-daily cross-border fire with the Israeli army (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-police-arrest-two-men-after-assault-on-anti-facism-protester-6203183]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK Police Arrest Two Men After Assault On Anti-Fascism Protester]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-police-arrest-two-men-after-assault-on-anti-facism-protester-6203183]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 27 Jul 2024 22:19:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[UK police arrested two men on Saturday following an assault on a participant in an anti-fascism protest, held to counter another nearby demonstration organised by far-right agitator Tommy Robinson.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>UK police arrested two men on Saturday following an assault on a participant in an anti-fascism protest, held to counter another nearby demonstration organised by far-right agitator Tommy Robinson.</p>

<p>London's Metropolitan Police said the pair were arrested on suspicion of assaulting a "Stand Up To Racism" protester in Victoria Embankment Gardens in the city centre.</p>

<p>Officers gave the victim first aid after he sustained a head injury in the incident, and he will be taken to hospital to be checked, according to the force.</p>

<p>It noted that, contrary to social media reports, the arrests were not related to the carrying of any flags.</p>

<p>The Met, as the London force is known, said around 1,000 officers were on duty Saturday as part of the policing operation to deal with the two rallies, as well as another protest.</p>

<p>Thousands gathered in the heart of the British capital from late morning for the demonstration organised by Robinson, a far-right firebrand and founder of the now defunct Islamophobic English Defence League organisation.</p>

<p>Meanwhile the counter-protest staged by Stand Up To Racism and others also rallied in the heart of London, with the Met imposing so-called conditions on the two marches "with the aim of preventing serious disruption".</p>

<p>They included requiring participants to stick to certain areas and streets and disperse by stipulated times.</p>

<p>"Our first priority is to keep the peace to ensure that those exercising their right to lawful protest can do so safely," Chief Superintendent Colin Wingrove said ahead of the weekend events.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/2hmhj068_uk-police_625x300_12_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-vows-to-hold-outdoor-rallies-with-more-security-despite-assassination-attempt-6203014]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Vows To Hold Rallies With More Security Despite Assassination Attempt]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-vows-to-hold-outdoor-rallies-with-more-security-despite-assassination-attempt-6203014]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 27 Jul 2024 21:43:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Presidential candidate Donald Trump said Saturday he will return to holding outdoor rallies with additional Secret Service protection, two weeks after he was injured in an assassination attempt at an open-air campaign event.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Presidential candidate Donald Trump said Saturday he will return to holding outdoor rallies with additional Secret Service protection, two weeks after he was injured in an assassination attempt at an open-air campaign event.</p>

<p>"I will continue to do outdoor rallies, and the Secret Service has agreed to substantially step up their operation. They are very capable of doing so," Trump said on his Truth Social platform.</p>

<p>"No one can ever be allowed to stop or impede free speech or gathering," he added.</p>

<p>His remarks came after the Secret Service reportedly encouraged Trump's campaign to stop scheduling outdoor campaign events following his assassination attempt, opting instead for large indoor arenas.</p>

<p>Trump was wounded when a 20-year-old gunman shot at him during an outdoor rally in Butler, Pennsylvania on July 13, killing one person and injuring two others.</p>

<p>The FBI confirmed on Friday that Trump was hit by a bullet, or a fragment of one -- putting to rest questions over the nature of the injury to his right ear.</p>

<p>Investigators are still working to establish a motive for the attack, which marked another stunning chapter in the US election race and sparked heavy criticism of the Secret Service.</p>

<p>Director Kimberly Cheatle resigned on Tuesday after acknowledging that the agency had failed in its mission of protecting high-profile politicians.</p>

<p>She told a congressional committee that the Secret Service was alerted "two to five times" ahead of the attack about a "suspicious individual" at the rally, but was unable to locate him before he opened fire.</p>

<p>Perched on the roof of a nearby building, he was shot dead by a Secret Service sniper less than 30 seconds after firing the first of eight shots.</p>

<p>Trump has made the shooting a key part of his campaign pitch, telling supporters that he "took a bullet for democracy" and vowing to return to Butler for a "big and beautiful rally."</p>

<p>On Saturday, the Republican and his running mate JD Vance were scheduled to hold a campaign event at an indoor, 6,000-seat hockey arena in the midwestern US state of Minnesota.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Vice President Kamala Harris -- who is on track to become the Democratic nominee -- was set to attend a fundraising event in Pittsfield, Massachusetts.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/pigc5cvo_donald-trump-_625x300_21_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The FBI confirmed on Friday that Trump was hit by a bullet (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/tourists-duped-into-eating-dog-meat-in-bali-authorities-launch-crackdown-6202972]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Tourists Duped Into Eating Dog Meat In Bali, Authorities Launch Crackdown]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/tourists-duped-into-eating-dog-meat-in-bali-authorities-launch-crackdown-6202972]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 27 Jul 2024 21:36:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[On Thursday, Bali officials seized hundreds of kilograms of raw dog meat and numerous skewers from vendors.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A recent investigation has revealed that Australian tourists were being tricked into eating dog meat skewers during their holidays on an Indonesian island.&nbsp;On Thursday, Bali officials seized hundreds of kilograms of raw dog meat and numerous skewers from vendors, despite a comprehensive ban on the trade of such meat on the popular resort island, the <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.independent.co.uk/asia/southeast-asia/bali-dog-meat-arrests-skewers-illegal-b2586314.html">Independent</a></em> reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to AFP, public order officers in Bali's Jembrana district seized at least 500 dog meat skewers and 56 kilograms of raw dog meat from various sellers following a series of inspections.&nbsp;Dewa Nyoman Rai Dharmadi, head of the Bali Public Order Agency, said that inspections conducted this week found three vendors still peddling dog meat, defying local regulations that prohibit its sale.</p>

<p>Two of the vendors had previously received warnings from Bali Police regarding their engagement in the trade of dog meat.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"We won't suddenly take legal action, but we are giving them the chance to know the ban and why it was banned. But we will process recurrent (sellers) for deterrent effect. We're not playing around,'' Mr Dharmadi said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>''Dog meat is not food and can also potentially cause disease. Don't believe in the superstitions that dog meat is healthy. That's misleading,'' he added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Two of the vendors are reportedly set to attend court in August.</p>

<p>Notably, Bali has enacted a stringent ban on the dog meat trade, imposing severe penalties on offenders, including a maximum prison sentence of three months and a hefty fine of up to 50 million rupiah (approximately 2,300 pounds), serving as a strong deterrent to those who would engage in this illicit activity.</p>

<p>Unlike regulated agricultural practices, the dog meat trade often relies on the inhumane seizure of dogs that are not raised for food, including stolen pets, community-owned dogs, and street dogs.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Animal welfare organizations, including Animals International, have condemned the sale and consumption of dog and cat meat, citing the inherent cruelty of the trade. They argue that the dog meat trade not only subjects dogs to immense suffering but also poses serious health and safety risks to both tourists and local communities.&nbsp;</p>

<p>However, dog meat is considered a part of traditional cuisine and consumed in certain regions of Southeast and East Asia, including China, Vietnam, and North Korea.&nbsp;<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/8il4cb48_dogs_625x300_27_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Dog meat trade often relies on the inhumane seizure of dogs]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/11-year-old-chinese-boy-writes-600-lines-of-code-to-build-rocket-6202767]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[11-Year-Old Chinese Boy Writes 600 Lines Of Code To Build Rocket]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/11-year-old-chinese-boy-writes-600-lines-of-code-to-build-rocket-6202767]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 27 Jul 2024 20:58:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Yan's interest in rockets began when he witnessed the Long March-2 liftoff at the age of four.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yan Hongsen, an 11-year-old from Zhejiang, China, has become an online sensation after writing 600 lines of code to build a rocket. According to the <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3271669/china-boy-11-writes-600-lines-code-build-rocket-after-mastering-physics-chemistry">South China Morning Post</a></em>, Yan's interest in rockets began when he witnessed the Long March-2 liftoff at the age of four. He has since taken online courses and self-studied physics and chemistry.&nbsp;</p>

<p data-qa="Component-Component" datatype="p">Starting in August 2022, Yan spent 10 months building his first homemade solid-fuel rocket. He launched the rocket named Sen Xing, in June 2023. Although it crashed due to a parachute malfunction, Yan remained calm and analysed the cause of the failure.</p>

<p data-qa="Component-Component" datatype="p">''The nitrocellulose didn't explode as expected, the spring and lithium battery were also damaged. Maybe there is still an issue with the rocket's body connection,'' Yan said.</p>

<p>He now plans to launch his second rocket and hopes to get into one of China's seven prestigious civilian defence universities. His ultimate dream is to build a real rocket for China to explore the universe.</p>

<p>The young prodigy has been documenting his rocket development journey on social media, gaining over 440,000 followers. His parents also have been supportive, converting their living room into a rocket research studio.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The boy's father shared his pride and excitement with <em>SCMP</em> recalling the maiden launch, ''Although the rocket crashed, I considered its first flight a triumph. I was over the moon with excitement, but my son took it in stride, remaining remarkably calm and composed.''</p>

<p data-qa="Component-Component" datatype="p">“I don't understand aerospace, but I will always accompany my son As parents, we fully support our child's dreams. If he encounters technical difficulties that he can't solve, he always contacts me, and I try my best to reach out to experts for help,” his father added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>His accomplishment has captured the attention of educators, tech enthusiasts, and space aficionados worldwide. His feats have gone viral on mainland Chinese social media as well, captivating the attention of millions and earning him a reputation as a prodigious talent.&nbsp;</p>

<p>''His parents are remarkable for unconditionally supporting their child's dreams,'' wrote one user, while another commented, ''This must be the youngest person to build a rocket in China. I'm so proud of him.''</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/stai7i2_code_625x300_27_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The young prodigy has been documenting his rocket development journey on social media]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-el-chapos-son-helped-us-arrest-famous-narco-chief-el-mayo-6202689]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How El Chapo's Son Helped US Arrest Famous Narco Chief El Mayo]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-el-chapos-son-helped-us-arrest-famous-narco-chief-el-mayo-6202689]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 27 Jul 2024 20:44:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[As a propeller plane on Thursday whirred towards the U.S.-Mexico border to cross illegally, U.S. agents raced to meet it at a small municipal airport near El Paso, Texas, and arrest two men who were part of Mexican drug trafficking royalty.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As a propeller plane on Thursday whirred towards the U.S.-Mexico border to cross illegally, U.S. agents raced to meet it at a small municipal airport near El Paso, Texas, and arrest two men who were part of Mexican drug trafficking royalty.</p>

<p>The son of jailed former Sinaloa Cartel kingpin Joaquin "El Chapo" Guzman planned to give himself up upon landing. The other passenger - legendary septuagenarian trafficker Ismael "El Mayo" Zambada - did not and was duped into getting on the plane by the younger man, according to two current and two former U.S. officials familiar with the situation.</p>

<p>Zambada's arrest followed lengthy surrender talks between U.S. authorities and El Chapo's son, Joaquin Guzman Lopez, the sources said. But many American officials had given up hope on Joaquin turning himself in, and were caught unaware when he sent a last-minute message that he would arrive with a kingpin U.S. authorities had been chasing for four decades.</p>

<p>"El Mayo was the cherry on top," said one U.S. official, who declined to be identified because he was not authorized to speak publicly about the arrests. "It wasn't expected at all."</p>

<p>Guzman Lopez had convinced Zambada to board the plane by telling him that they were flying to see real estate in northern Mexico, according to the two current and one former U.S. officials.</p>

<p>Reuters was the first news organization to report the arrests, ahead of a Department of Justice statement on Thursday evening that confirmed the two men had been detained in El Paso. The news agency spoke to current and former officials to piece together a detailed account of the operation.</p>

<p>The U.S. Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) and the Homeland Security Investigations (HSI), the two agencies who carried out the operation, scrambled agents from their local El Paso offices and barely reached the airport by the time the private plane was landing, according to a fifth source, a U.S. official who declined to give further details on the arrests.</p>

<p>One worker at the Dona Ana County International Jetport, near El Paso, told Reuters he saw a Beechcraft King Air plane land on Thursday afternoon on the runway, where federal agents were already waiting.</p>

<p>"Two individuals got off the plane ... and were calmly taken into custody," said the man, who declined to share his name out of concern for his safety.</p>

<p>The unexpected arrest of El Mayo, in his late 70s, and the way he appears to have been betrayed by Guzman Lopez, who is about 38 years old, has jolted the Mexican drug trafficking world, triggering fears of a bloody fissure in the Sinaloa Cartel between the two families that control the group's biggest power bases.</p>

<p>Zambada is accused of being one of the most consequential traffickers in Mexico's history, having co-founded the Sinaloa Cartel with "El Chapo" Guzman, who was extradited to the U.S. in 2017 and is serving a life sentence in a maximum security prison in Colorado.</p>

<p>Reuters could not determine why Guzman Lopez betrayed his father's long-time partner, though the four current and former sources said it was likely due to his desire to obtain a more favourable plea bargain deal from U.S. authorities and help his brother, Ovidio, who was arrested and extradited to the United States in 2023.</p>

<p>U.S. authorities have made drug bosses key targets, frequently striking plea bargain deals with them in exchange for information that leads to the capture of other high-ranking cartel figures.</p>

<p>The back-channel communication between American officials and Guzman Lopez was carried out through lawyers, the first official said. Jeffrey Lichtman, who represents both Guzman brothers, declined to comment.</p>

<p>Zambada, who was in a wheelchair, pleaded not guilty on Friday in a Texas courtroom to drug charges, including continuing criminal enterprise, narcotics importation conspiracy and money laundering. His lawyer, Frank Perez, said Zambada did not come to the U.S. voluntarily.</p>

<p>Guzman Lopez is due to appear in court next week in Chicago, where he was first indicted on drugs charges around 6 years ago.</p>

<p>Guzman Lopez is one of four sons of El Chapo - known as Los Chapitos, or Little Chapos - who inherited their father's faction of the cartel. Joaquin and Ovidio have the same mother, while the other two siblings - Ivan and Jesus Alfredo - hail from El Chapo's first marriage.</p>

<p>The brothers have in recent years come under ferocious pressure from U.S. authorities, who have made them their main anti-narcotics targets, portraying them and the Sinaloa Cartel as the biggest traffickers of fentanyl into the United States. Fentanyl overdoses have surged to become the leading cause of death for Americans between the ages of 18 and 45.</p>

<p>Ray Donovan, a former high-ranking U.S. Drug Enforcement Administration (DEA) official, said the defeats suffered by key Sinaloa Cartel bosses in recent past are mainly down to their embrace of fentanyl, which has risen up the political agenda in Washington as the death told has mounted on U.S. streets.</p>

<p>"The number of Americans dying has put a lot more pressure," Donovan said. "Fentanyl brought them down."</p>

<p>On Friday, U.S. President Joe Biden heralded the arrests and vowed to continue combating "the scourge of fentanyl".</p>

<h3><strong>New Generation Of Narcos</strong></h3>

<p>El Chapo's sons are known to be more violent and hot-headed than Zambada, who had a reputation as a shrewd operator that liked to stay in the shadows. Guzman Lopez was also seen as less important than his other three brothers.</p>

<p>The U.S. authorities had a $15 million reward for the capture of Zambada, who co-founded the Sinaloa Cartel in the late 1980s with El Chapo. Guzman Lopez had a $5 million bounty on his head. Both men face multiple indictments in the United States.</p>

<p>The first U.S. official cautioned that there are still many questions unanswered about how or why Zambada, an ultra-cautious and experienced cartel chieftain, found himself on that plane.</p>

<p>Mexican Security Minister Rosa Rodriguez said that Mexico was informed of the detentions by the U.S. government, but that Mexican authorities did not participate in the operation.</p>

<p>Outgoing Mexican President Andres Manuel Lopez Obrador has taken a cautious approach to tackling the powerful cartels, curbing security cooperation with U.S. authorities on fears that the previous U.S.-Mexico strategy of targeting powerful kingpins was triggering more nationwide violence.</p>

<p>In Oct. 2019, Mexico's military arrested Ovidio but were forced to release him after hundreds of Sinaloa Cartel foot soldiers blocked roads and fought running gun battles with soldiers as they to lay siege to the city of Culiacan, the capital of Sinaloa. The military arrested Ovidio again in Jan. 2023 and he was extradited in September last year.</p>

<p>Matthew Allen, a former Special Agent in Charge of HSI's Arizona division that built indictments against Guzman Lopez and other Sinaloa Cartel figures, said both Zambada and Guzman Lopez had had periodic conversations with U.S. officials about surrendering over the years.</p>

<p>Allen, who maintains regular contact with former colleagues at HSI, said many traffickers, especially those from the younger generation, realize that giving themselves up, serving some time in jail and then spending their wealth is a better option than risking death from rivals in Mexico or capture by authorities that can lead to lifelong prison terms. Some informants are allowed to enter witness protection programs.</p>

<p>"They're seeing that this way you can do your time and do not have to look over your shoulder for the rest of your life," he said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/gg6p3imo_el-chapo-and-el-mayo_625x300_27_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-tells-christians-they-wont-have-to-vote-after-this-election-6202477]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump Tells Christians They Won't Have To Vote After This Election]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-tells-christians-they-wont-have-to-vote-after-this-election-6202477]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 27 Jul 2024 20:10:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump told Christians on Friday that if they vote for him this November, "in four years, you don't have to vote again. We'll have it fixed so good, you're not gonna have to vote."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump told Christians on Friday that if they vote for him this November, "in four years, you don't have to vote again. We'll have it fixed so good, you're not gonna have to vote."</p>

<p>It was not clear what the former president meant by his remarks, in an election campaign where his Democratic opponents accuse him of being a threat to democracy, and after his attempt to overturn his 2020 defeat to President Joe Biden, an effort that led to the deadly insurrection at the U.S. Capitol on Jan. 6, 2021.</p>

<p>The Trump campaign did not immediately respond to a request for clarification of his comments.</p>

<p>Trump was speaking at an event organized by the conservative group Turning Point Action in West Palm Beach, Florida.</p>

<p>Trump said: "Christians, get out and vote, just this time. "You won't have to do it anymore. Four more years, you know what, it will be fixed, it will be fine, you won't have to vote anymore, my beautiful Christians."</p>

<p>He added: "I love you Christians. I'm a Christian. I love you, get out, you gotta get out and vote. In four years, you don't have to vote again, we'll have it fixed so good you're not going to have to vote," Trump said.</p>

<p>In an interview with Fox News in December, Trump said that if he won the Nov. 5 election he would be a dictator, but only on "day one", to close the southern border with Mexico and expand oil drilling.</p>

<p>Democrats have seized on that comment. Trump has since said the remarks were a joke.</p>

<p>If Trump wins a second term in the White House, he can serve only four more years as president. U.S. presidents are limited to two terms, consecutive or not, under the U.S. Constitution.</p>

<p>In May, speaking at a National Rifle Association gathering, Trump quipped about serving more than two terms as president.</p>

<p>He referred to the presidency of Franklin D. Roosevelt, a Democrat, the only president to serve more than two terms. The two-term limit was added after Roosevelt's presidency.</p>

<p>"You know, FDR, 16 years - almost 16 years - he was four terms. I don't know, are we going to be considered three-term? Or two-term?" Trump asked the NRA crowd.</p>

<p>Trump's remarks on Friday pointed to the need for both parties to energize their base voters ahead of what will likely be a closely fought election. Trump has enjoyed loyal support from evangelicals in the past two elections.</p>

<p>The race has abruptly tightened after the decision by Biden to end his reelection bid and with his vice president, Kamala Harris, becoming the presumptive Democratic nominee.</p>

<p>Recent opinion polls show Trump's significant lead over Biden has been largely erased since the torch was passed to Harris.</p>

<p>Jason Singer, a Harris campaign spokesperson, in a statement did not directly address Trump's remarks about Christians not having to vote again.</p>

<p>Singer described Trump's overall speech as "bizarre" and "backward looking".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/vqggd4j8_donald-trump-florida_625x300_27_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["I love you, get out, you gotta get out and vote," Donald Trump said]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/170-killed-hundreds-wounded-in-days-long-israeli-operation-in-gaza-6202313]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[170 Killed, Hundreds Wounded In Days-Long Israeli Operation In Gaza]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/170-killed-hundreds-wounded-in-days-long-israeli-operation-in-gaza-6202313]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 27 Jul 2024 19:41:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Gaza's civil defence agency said Saturday that Israel's military operation around Khan Yunis has killed about 170 people and wounded hundreds since it started on Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Gaza's civil defence agency said Saturday that Israel's military operation around Khan Yunis has killed about 170 people and wounded hundreds since it started on Monday.</p>

<p>"Since the beginning of the Israeli military operation in the Khan Yunis area, we are talking of approximately 170 martyrs and hundreds of wounded," agency spokesman Mahmud Bassal told AFP.</p>

<p>He said many people had been displaced again on Saturday as the Israeli operation continued.</p>

<p>"The questions is where will these residents go?" Basal said.</p>

<p>"Anyone who sees the situation in Khan Yunis will witness thousands of people spread out on the ground, on the roads, in areas that unfortunately are not suitable for living.</p>

<p>"With no other options available, they are exposing themselves to death."</p>

<p>Earlier on Saturday the military issued new evacuation orders for residents of the southern city, after retrieving the bodies of five Israelis and warning of new operations.</p>

<p>The United Nations said more than 180,000 Palestinians have fled Khan Yunis since the Israeli operation began on Monday.</p>

<p>The evacuation orders and "intensified hostilities" have "significantly destabilised aid operations", it added, reporting "dire water, hygiene and sanitation conditions" across the Palestinian territory.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said it launched the operation to halt rocket fire from the area, which already saw heavy fighting earlier this year.</p>

<p>On Wednesday, it said troops had retrieved the bodies of five Israelis from the area.</p>

<p>They had been killed during the Hamas attacks of October 7 and their bodies taken back to Gaza, the military said.</p>

<p>On Saturday, it ordered residents from more parts of Khan Yunis "to temporarily evacuate to the adjusted humanitarian area in Al-Mawasi" -- the second such adjustment made to the safe zone within a week.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/vtksln98_khan-younis_625x300_27_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The United Nations said more than 180,000 Palestinians have fled Khan Yunis]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/antony-blinken-raises-concern-over-chinas-provocative-actions-around-taiwan-6202074]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Blinken Raises Concern Over China's "Provocative" Actions Around Taiwan]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/antony-blinken-raises-concern-over-chinas-provocative-actions-around-taiwan-6202074]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 27 Jul 2024 19:02:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United States hailed "open and productive" discussions between China's foreign minister and Secretary of State Antony Blinken in Laos on Saturday in which Blinken raised US concerns over Beijing's "provocative actions" around Taiwan.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United States hailed "open and productive" discussions between China's foreign minister and Secretary of State Antony Blinken in Laos on Saturday in which Blinken raised US concerns over Beijing's "provocative actions" around Taiwan.</p>

<p>Blinken's stop in Laos is part of a multi-nation Asia visit aimed at reinforcing regional ties in the face of Beijing's growing assertiveness, including in the South China Sea, and its deepening ties with Moscow.</p>

<p>The talks on the sidelines of a foreign ministers meeting of the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) lasted for one hour and twenty minutes, according to a senior State Department official.</p>

<p>Blinken raised "US concerns about provocative actions" by China, including a simulated blockade of Taiwan following the May inauguration of its new president Lai Ching-te, the official said.</p>

<p>China claims the democratic island as its territory and slammed Lai's inauguration speech as "confession of independence."</p>

<p>China's foreign ministry was yet to release a statement on the meeting.</p>

<p>Shortly before the meeting Blinken hit out at Beijing's "escalatory and unlawful actions" in the South China Sea, where China and the Philippines are locked in a territorial dispute.</p>

<p>Beijing claims the waterway -- through which trillions of dollars of trade passes annually -- almost in its entirety despite an international court ruling that its assertion has no legal basis.</p>

<p>A Filipino sailor lost a thumb in the latest June 17 confrontation when Chinese coast guard members wielding knives, sticks and an axe foiled a Philippine Navy attempt to resupply its troops.</p>

<p>The clashes have fuelled fears of a conflict that could drag in the United States due to its mutual defence treaty with Manila.</p>

<p>On Saturday Manila said it had successfully resupplied troops on the Second Thomas Shoal -- the focus of clashes in recent months -- under a deal agreed with Beijing.</p>

<p>On Friday Wang called on the Philippines to "honour its commitments" under the deal rather than "backtracking or creating complications", warning Beijing would "respond resolutely" to any violation.</p>

<p>Wang also warned the Philippines over deploying a US medium-range missile system on its soil, saying it would "create tension and confrontation in the region and trigger an arms race."</p>

<p>The US Army said in April it had deployed the Mid-Range Capability missile system in the northern Philippines for annual joint military exercises.</p>

<p>Philippines military officials later said the system would be removed from the country.</p>

<p>- China, Russia talk security -</p>

<p>Blinken arrived in Laos two days after the foreign ministers of China and Russia met with the 10-nation ASEAN bloc -- and each other on the sidelines of the meeting.</p>

<p>On Thursday, Wang met Russia foreign minister Sergei Lavrov in Vientiane and discussed "building a new security architecture for Eurasia", according to Moscow's foreign ministry.</p>

<p>The pair also agreed to jointly "counter any attempts by extra-regional forces to interfere in Southeast Asian affairs", it said.</p>

<p>China has a strong political and economic partnership with Russia, with NATO members labelling Beijing as a "key facilitator" of Moscow's involvement in the war in Ukraine.</p>

<h3><strong>Myanmar</strong></h3>

<p>A joint communique released by ASEAN on Saturday expressed the bloc's "deep concern over the escalation of conflicts" in member-state Myanmar.</p>

<p>The country has been ravaged by violence since the military seized power in 2021, sparking renewed fighting with established ethnic minority armed groups and dozens of newer "People's Defence Forces".</p>

<p>ASEAN has spearheaded so far unsuccessful diplomatic efforts to resolve the crisis, with a five-point peace plan agreed between the junta and the bloc now moribund.</p>

<p>The five-point consensus "remains our main reference to address the political crisis," the joint communique said.</p>

<p>Myanmar's junta has been banned from high-level ASEAN summits over its coup and crackdown on dissent, in which rights groups say it may have committed war crimes.</p>

<p>Two senior bureaucrats represented Myanmar at the Laos talks.</p>

<p>The military's readiness to re-engage with ASEAN diplomatically was a "sign of the junta's weakened position", a Southeast Asian diplomat told AFP earlier this week.</p>

<p></p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/tlr2l40g_antony-blinken_625x300_27_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Blinken raised "US concerns about provocative actions" by China, the official said (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/passengers-struggle-as-france-suffers-second-day-of-sabotage-train-delays-6202011]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Passengers Struggle As France Suffers Second Day Of Sabotage Train Delays]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/passengers-struggle-as-france-suffers-second-day-of-sabotage-train-delays-6202011]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 27 Jul 2024 18:53:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Tens of thousands of rail passengers struggled through a second day of cancelled trains Saturday as investigators tracked saboteurs who paralysed the network just ahead of the Paris Olympics opening ceremony.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Tens of thousands of rail passengers struggled through a second day of cancelled trains Saturday as investigators tracked saboteurs who paralysed the network just ahead of the Paris Olympics opening ceremony.</p>

<p>The SNCF rail company chief Jean-Pierre Farandou said services would be back to normal by Monday. But deputy transport minister authorities acknowledged that 160,000 of the 800,000 people due to travel this weekend still faced cancellations.</p>

<p>Nearly one third of trains were cancelled in northern, western and eastern France. About a quarter of Eurostar high speed trains between London and Paris also failed to leave.</p>

<p>No claim of responsibility has been made for the meticulously planned night-time attacks on cabling boxes at junctions north, southwest and east of the French capital, just ahead of Friday's Olympics opening ceremony in Paris. Maintenance workers thwarted a fourth attack.</p>

<p>But Interior Minister Gerald Darmanin said the investigation was progressing.</p>

<p>"We have uncovered a certain number of elements that allow us to think that we will soon know who is responsible for what clearly did not sabotage the Olympic Games but did sabotage part of the holidays of the French people," Darmanin told France 2 television.</p>

<p>French authorities are on high alert for a terrorist attack during the Games, which run through August 11. Tens of thousands of police and troops are on Olympics security duties.</p>

<p>Some 250,000 people missed their train on Friday, according to SNCF, because of the attacks that dozens of investigators are now working on.</p>

<p>About three out of every 10 trains were cancelled Saturday in the three regions affected by the attacks, with most trains still operating delayed by between one and two hours, SNCF said.</p>

<p>Kathleen Cuvellier, speaking in the northern city of Lille, said her journey to Avignon in the south was going to be "hell".</p>

<p>Cuvellier, travelling with her two-year-old son, said she now had to take a slow train to Paris and then switch to another for Avignon. "The travel time was four hours and now it's going to be seven".</p>

<p>"One doesn't have any choice," commented Cecile Bonnefond, whose train from Lille to the western city of Nantes was cancelled.</p>

<p>Trains to eastern France have largely returned to normal. But traffic will remain disrupted into Sunday in northern France and into Britain and Belgium, while services to western France would slowly improve, SNCF said.</p>

<p>The company said its staff worked through the night "in difficult conditions in the rain" to get the affected lines working again.</p>

<p>The coordinated attacks staged at 4:00 am early Friday cut fibre optic cables running along the tracks that transmit safety information to train drivers. The attackers also set fire to the cables.</p>

<p>"Everything will be back to normal for Monday morning," SNCF president Farandou told reporters at Paris Montparnasse station. "We will be ready".</p>

<p>Most passengers at the station remained patience. But they were given regular loudspeaker reminders that "a malicious act" meant trains would be cancelled or delayed.</p>

<p></p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/qgjtbsko_france-railways-afp-_625x300_27_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/as-racist-sexist-attacks-fly-republicans-grapple-with-how-to-take-on-kamala-harris-6201977]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[As Racist Attacks Fly, Republicans Grapple With How To Take On Harris]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/as-racist-sexist-attacks-fly-republicans-grapple-with-how-to-take-on-kamala-harris-6201977]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 27 Jul 2024 18:48:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Republican nominee Donald Trump has called her "crazy," "nuts" and "dumb as a rock." Republicans in Congress disparage her as a diversity hire.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Republican nominee Donald Trump has called her "crazy," "nuts" and "dumb as a rock." Republicans in Congress disparage her as a diversity hire. Right-wing activists and trolls have smeared her online with racist, sexist and sexualized barbs.</p>

<p>The attacks on Kamala Harris, the first woman and first Black and South Asian person to serve as U.S. vice president, have intensified in the days since she consolidated support to become Democrats' likely presidential nominee.</p>

<p>The demeaning racist and sexist attacks threaten to distract from the Republican Party's concerted effort to focus on Harris' policies. Trump allies, including some members of the "Black Americans for Trump" coalition, warn that disparaging Harris could hurt him in his outreach to Black voters, a crucial demographic in the Nov. 5 presidential election.</p>

<p>In interviews with nine Republican lawmakers and 11 Black Republican women who back Trump, eight said personal attacks on Harris should be avoided. While guarded in their comments and emphasizing their continued support for Trump, several expressed worry over the tenor of the attacks and whether the onslaught could harm Republicans at the ballot box.</p>

<p>"I think there is a way to critique her without going underneath her clothes," said P Rae Easley, a Black conservative radio show host in Chicago and a member of the "Black Americans for Trump" coalition, a loosely organized group of Black allies backing Trump.</p>

<p>Several members of Congress echoed her sentiments.</p>

<p>"I'm going to oppose Vice President Harris because of what she's done, not who she is," said Representative Dusty Johnson, who chairs the 75-member Republican Main Street Caucus. "Some of this ugliness is unbecoming of a great country."</p>

<p>Others said the attacks on Harris' personal life were no different than Democrats attacking Trump over his personal and family life.</p>

<p>"It's a nasty fight. Democrats have a tendency to play victim," said Madgie Nicolas, co-chair of Haitians for Trump and the Faith and Freedom Coalition's national director of African American voices.</p>

<p>The tension suggests Trump campaign efforts to tie Harris to President Joe Biden's record - particularly on immigration, crime and the economy - risk being overshadowed by personal attacks that show no signs of slowing.</p>

<p>"Going after Kamala Harris as a 'DEI hire' is breathtakingly stupid," said Republican pollster Whit Ayres, who has worked on campaigns for U.S. Senator Marco Rubio, Florida Governor Ron DeSantis and others. "It's going to backfire," Ayres said, adding that Harris had an "incredible array of far left-wing policies" that could be targeted.</p>

<p>DEI stands for "diversity, equity and inclusion" initiatives aimed at increasing representation of women and people of color in the workforce to address longstanding inequities and discrimination. The term "DEI hire" is now used to suggest a person is not qualified for their role and has been chosen on the basis of their race or gender.</p>

<p>Ayres said the disparaging rhetoric would alienate women and "anyone who isn't far-right."</p>

<p>The Trump campaign did not directly respond to questions about whether it had discussed trying to tone down personal attacks on Harris.</p>

<p>Trump's inflammatory rhetoric has emboldened people with racist beliefs to express them, according to rhetoric experts, critics and past public opinion polling.</p>

<p>The former president has a history of attacking political opponents, including other Black women in power such as Fulton County District Attorney Fani Willis, who is prosecuting his election interference case in Georgia, and U.S. District Judge Tanya Chutkan, the judge assigned to the federal case against him for attempting to overturn the results of the 2020 election.</p>

<p>At a rally in North Carolina on Wednesday, Trump did not go after Harris on gender or racial grounds. Instead, he painted a potential Harris presidency in apocalyptic terms.</p>

<p>"She is a radical left lunatic who will destroy our country," Trump said.</p>

<p>Trump spokesperson Karoline Leavitt said voters would reject Harris not because of her race and gender, but because of her failed policies.</p>

<p>A spokesperson for Harris, whose nascent campaign has generated a groundswell of grassroots fundraising and activism, said she is staying focused on her work.</p>

<p>"These attacks are backfiring and even Republicans know it," said Sarafina Chitika.</p>

<h3><strong>Lewd Comments</strong></h3>

<p>Online attacks against Harris were ramping up even before Biden dropped out on Sunday, according to researchers and a Reuters review of posts on the X platform, although exact data is hard to come by.</p>

<p>Some of the recent posts refer to sexual acts and speak of Harris' past relationships in lewd terms. Others disparage her for not having biological children, echoing a comment Trump running mate JD Vance made in 2021, when he criticized Harris and other Democrats as "a bunch of childless cat ladies who are miserable at their own lives."</p>

<p>Harris has two stepchildren with her husband, lawyer Doug Emhoff. Emhoff's ex-wife on Wednesday called such attacks "baseless" and described Harris as a "loving, nurturing, fiercely protective" co-parent.</p>

<p>Disinformation researchers say the online attacks do not appear to be coming from a specific epicenter and are now so prevalent that most accounts are merely "amplifiers" of already-existing narratives.</p>

<p>U.S. Representative Michael Cloud, a member of the ultraconservative House Freedom Caucus, defended Republicans who have disparaged Harris as a "DEI hire."</p>

<p>"Those were Biden's words, actually," Cloud said.</p>

<p>Biden has not called Harris a "DEI hire." At a campaign appearance with Harris in May, he spoke of the values of DEI and having a diverse administration. "And it starts at the top with the vice president," Biden said.</p>

<p>Trump has nicknamed Harris "Laffin' Kamala," mocking her laugh, and "Lyin' Kamala," claiming she tried to hide Biden's aging from the public. At a Sunday rally in Grand Rapids, Michigan, the former president called her "crazy" and "nuts."</p>

<p>Kelly Dittmar, a political science professor at Rutgers University, said the nicknames appeared to be playing into stereotypes about women's voices and emotions, as well as seeking to emulate African American pronunciation.</p>

<p>"The actual laughing and cackling goes back to tropes about not wanting to hear women's voices," Dittmar said. "It's not the laugh itself. It's to characterize her as annoying. I think the nicknames are trying to cue the fact she's Black."</p>

<p>Republican House Speaker Mike Johnson, who attended a closed-door meeting this week where party leaders urged members to concentrate on policy issues, told Reuters on Thursday that he had not spoken to Trump or the Trump campaign about how to message regarding Harris.</p>

<p>"This campaign will be about policies," Johnson said. "And I think everybody will be discussing that in detail, and I think we'll win on that basis."&nbsp;</p>

<p>Easley, the radio show host, said she suggested to Trump campaign officials they engage Black allies more to counter Harris "without the veil of racism being attached to it."</p>

<p>She and several other Black Republican women who spoke to Reuters said they did not like the personal attacks, with some noting their own experiences confronting higher standards and expectations as Black women, or having their qualifications questioned.</p>

<p>"As a Black woman myself, I don't appreciate when people start saying because of the color of your skin, that makes you a DEI hire. I don't think that's fair to anyone," said Corrin Rankin, vice chair of the California Republican Party, who said she met Harris when they both worked in San Francisco.</p>

<p>However, Rankin said she felt Biden's vow to pick a woman or person of color as his running mate in 2020 had allowed that term to take hold.</p>

<p>Other Trump allies warned that his attacks could alienate some voters.</p>

<p>"I am hoping that his advisers will encourage Trump to pull it back," said Camilla Moore, chair of the Georgia Black Republican Council. "Because it could hurt in the long run."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/bg80adm8_kamala-harris-reuters-_625x300_24_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Trump has nicknamed Harris "Laffin' Kamala," mocking her laugh (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/killer-whales-sink-128-000-yacht-in-mediterranean-sea-in-harrowing-2-hour-attack-6201510]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Killer Whales Sink Yacht In Mediterranean Sea In Harrowing 2-Hour Attack]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/killer-whales-sink-128-000-yacht-in-mediterranean-sea-in-harrowing-2-hour-attack-6201510]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 27 Jul 2024 17:38:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The pod of five first targeted the rudder, rendering the sailboat unable to steer after approximately 15 strikes.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A $128,000 yacht was attacked and sunk by a group of killer whales in the Mediterranean Sea, leaving the crew in shock. According to <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/07/26/world-news/killer-whales-sink-128k-yacht-in-2-hour-mediterranean-sea-attack/">New York Post</a></em>,&nbsp;Robert Powell, 59, and his crew were just 22 hours into their 10-day trip from Vilamoura, Portugal, to Greece on Wednesday when they saw killer whales approaching them.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The orcas, typically known for their intelligence and curiosity, began to exhibit aggressive behaviour, ramming the yacht with incredible force.&nbsp;The five orcas circled the 39-foot sailing boat and, in a coordinated assault, took turns ramming it to pieces around 8 p.m.</p>

<p>''To me, they were not playing at all, they knew exactly what they were doing. They knew the weak points of the boat, and they knew how to sink it. Their sole intention was to sink the boat, and that was it,'' Mr Powell, who was meant to be celebrating his birthday aboard the boat, said.</p>

<p>The pod of five first targeted the rudder, rendering the sailboat unable to steer after approximately 15 strikes. The orcas then broke apart and systematically attacked distinct parts of the boat's exterior, with one concentrating on the keel, another on the stern, and the others targeting other vulnerable areas.</p>

<p>''They were circling. It was like watching wolves hunt. They were taking it in turns to come in — sometimes two would come in at the same time and hit it. So obviously pretty terrifying,'' Mr Powell added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The crew, caught off guard by the ferocity of the assault, attempted to steer the vessel away from the whales, but their efforts were in vain. The orcas seemed determined to sink the yacht, displaying an unusual level of aggression.</p>

<p>Fortunately, a Spanish salvage vessel intervened, evacuating the crew just moments before the sailboat plunged 130 feet into the Mediterranean, disappearing beneath the waves.</p>

<p>Killer whales are known for their complex social structures and typically do not exhibit unprovoked aggression towards human vessels. While there have been reports of orcas interacting with boats, such extreme behaviour is rare. Some experts speculate that the attack could have been triggered by environmental stressors, changes in their habitat, or even previous negative encounters with boats.</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/kunbhvcg_killer-whales_625x300_27_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The five orcas circled the boat and, in a coordinated assault, took turns ramming it to pieces]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/french-rail-chief-says-trains-to-run-normally-from-monday-after-sabotage-6201502]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[French Rail Chief Says Trains To Run Normally From Monday After Sabotage]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/french-rail-chief-says-trains-to-run-normally-from-monday-after-sabotage-6201502]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 27 Jul 2024 17:36:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Traffic on France's high-speed rail network should be back to normal by Monday, Transport Minister Patrice Vergriete said after sabotaged signal stations and cables caused travel chaos on Friday, the opening day of the Olympic Games.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Traffic on France's high-speed rail network should be back to normal by Monday, Transport Minister Patrice Vergriete said after sabotaged signal stations and cables caused travel chaos on Friday, the opening day of the Olympic Games.</p>

<p>French rail operator SNCF reiterated that transport plans for teams competing in the Paris 2024 Olympics would be guaranteed.</p>

<p>Friday's pre-dawn attacks on the high-speed rail network damaged infrastructure along the lines connecting Paris with cities such as Lille in the north, Bordeaux in the west and Strasbourg in the east. Another attack on the Paris-Marseille line was foiled, SNCF has said.</p>

<p>There has been no immediate claim of responsibility.</p>

<p>Speaking to reporters at Paris' Montparnasse train station, Vergriete and SNCF chief Jean-Pierre Farandou said train services would continue to experience disruption throughout the weekend as they gradually return to normal.</p>

<p>On Friday, 100,000 people could not take their trains, and another 150,000 faced delays but eventually got to their destinations, Vergriete said.</p>

<p>"There will still be disruptions tomorrow," Vergriete told reporters. "From Monday, there is no need to worry."</p>

<p>Farandou confirmed this, adding that investigations were ongoing and they did not yet know who was behind the attack.</p>

<p>SNCF said in a statement that traffic would remain disrupted on Sunday on the North axis but should improve on the Atlantic axis for weekend returns.</p>

<p>"On the Eastern high-speed line, traffic resumed normally this morning at 6:30 a.m. (0530 GMT) while on the North, Brittany and South-West high-speed lines, 7 out of 10 trains on average will run with delays of 1 to 2 hours," it said.</p>

<p>Two security sources have said the modus operandi meant initial suspicions fell on leftist militants or environmental activists, but they said there was not yet any evidence.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Gabriel Attal on Friday said it was too early to say who could be behind the sabotage.</p>

<p>"What we know, what we see, is that this operation was prepared, coordinated, that nerve centres were targeted, which shows a certain knowledge of the network to know where to strike," he said.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/joe8rf28_french-rail-sabotage_625x300_27_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[There has been no immediate claim of responsibility]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-neck-and-neck-with-donald-trump-show-latest-polls-6201284]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris Cuts Down Donald Trump's Lead Sharply, Show Latest Polls]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-neck-and-neck-with-donald-trump-show-latest-polls-6201284]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 27 Jul 2024 17:01:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US Vice President Kamala Harris, the most likely candidate to replace Joe Biden as the Democratic Party nominee for the November 5 presidential elections, has narrowed the margin against Donald Trump, according to latest polls.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US Vice President Kamala Harris, the most likely candidate to replace Joe Biden as the Democratic Party nominee for the November 5 presidential elections, has narrowed the margin against Donald Trump, according to latest polls. There's been a significant rise in support for her among non-white voters and within her party.</p>

<p><b>What polls say</b></p>

<p>The latest <a href="https://www.wsj.com/politics/elections/harris-erases-trumps-lead-wsj-poll-finds-e286144d">Wall Street Journal </a>poll shows Harris and Trump neck-and-neck at 49% to 47% in a two-person matchup. However, the report states this was within the margin of error of plus or minus 3.1 percentage points.</p>

<p>Earlier this month, Trump was in a six-point lead against Biden before he quit the race.</p>

<p>According to a New York Times/Siena College poll of 1,142 voters nationwide conducted between July 22-24, Trump leads Harris 48% to 47% among likely voters in a head-to-head match.</p>

<p>This is a significant improvement for the Democrats after numbers earlier this month showed Biden behind by six percentage points.</p>

<p>Besides this, the polls further state that Trump currently leads Harris 48% to 46% among the registered voters. Earlier, he led among registered voters by nine percentage points over Biden.</p>

<p>Harris' gain primarily comes from parts of the Democratic coalition that earlier soured on Biden.</p>

<p>The US President was getting only 59% of Black registered voters in the <a href="http://https://www.nytimes.com/2024/07/25/us/politics/poll-kamala-harris-donald-trump.html">New York Times</a> poll a month ago. However, now Harris is expected to get 69% of these votes. Apart from that, Harris has also increased her party's share of Hispanic voters from 45% to 57% and under 30 voters from 46% to 56%.</p>

<p>According to <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-07-26/kamala-harris-polls-show-trump-lead-narrowing-in-2024-election?srnd=homepage-asia">Bloomberg</a>, an unweighted average of the polls conducted after Biden left the presidential race shows Harris trailing Trump by 1.6 percentage points.</p>

<p><b>Kamala Harris declares her candidacy</b></p>

<p>Harris, on Saturday, signed the forms officially declaring her candidacy for President of the United States. "I will work hard to earn every vote. And in November, our people-powered campaign will win," she wrote on X.</p>

<p>This came after US President Joe Biden, 81, on July 21 announced his exit from the presidential race and endorsed Harris as the nominee of the party. Harris has further received support from former US President Barack Obama and ex-First Lady Michelle Obama.</p>

<p>The US vice president has secured the support of a majority of Democratic delegates and seems all set to be the official nominee at the party convention next month.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/kqs5e0o4_kamala-harris-donald-trump_625x300_27_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/at-least-30-killed-over-100-wounded-in-israeli-strike-school-in-gaza-6201196]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[At Least 30 Killed, Over 100 Wounded In Israeli Strike School In Gaza]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/at-least-30-killed-over-100-wounded-in-israeli-strike-school-in-gaza-6201196]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 27 Jul 2024 16:47:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[At least 30 Palestinians were killed in an Israeli strike on a school in Deir al Balah in central Gaza, Palestinian health officials said, and the Israeli military said it had struck a Hamas command centre.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At least 30 Palestinians were killed in an Israeli strike on a school in Deir al Balah in central Gaza, Palestinian health officials said, and the Israeli military said it had struck a Hamas command centre.</p>

<p>The Gaza health ministry and the Hamas-run government media office gave the toll for those killed in the strike on the school in Deir Al-Balah, one of the areas most populated with displaced families, and said over 100 others were wounded.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said in a statement it had targeted a "Hamas command and control center inside the Khadija school compound in central Gaza".</p>

<p>The statement said the school was being used to launch attacks against troops and as a weapons cache and that it warned civilians before the strike.</p>

<p>At Al-Aqsa Hospital in Deir Al-Balah, ambulances raced wounded Palestinians into the medical facility. Some of the wounded also arrived on foot, with their clothes stained with blood.</p>

<p>In previous such strikes that have hit civilian infrastructure, Israel's military has blamed the Islamist group Hamas for putting civilians in harm's way, accusing it of operating within densely populated neighbourhoods, schools and hospitals as cover. Hamas denies this.</p>

<p>Earlier on Saturday, Palestinian official media said that at least 14 Palestinians were killed by Israeli attacks since dawn in the southern city of Khan Younis and that their bodies were brought to Nasser Medical Complex.</p>

<p>The Israeli military told Palestinians to temporarily evacuate southern neighborhoods of Khan Younis so it could "forcefully operate" there, telling them to relocate to a humanitarian area in Al-Mawasi, a military statement said.</p>

<p>The military said its calls to evacuate were communicated to the population via several mediums in order to mitigate danger to civilians.</p>

<p>In Al-Bureij refugee camp, five Palestinians were killed earlier in an Israeli air strike on a house, while four others were killed in another strike on a house in Rafah, near the border with Egypt, medics said.</p>

<p>U.N. and humanitarian officials accuse Israel of using disproportionate force in the war and of failing to ensure civilians have safe places to go, which it denies.</p>

<p>On Friday the military said troops battled Palestinian fighters in Khan Younis, and destroyed tunnels and other infrastructure, as they sought to suppress small operative units that have continued to hit troops with mortar fire.</p>

<p>The fighting, more than nine months after the start of Israel's invasion of Gaza following the Hamas-led Oct. 7 attack, underlined the difficulty the Israeli Defence Forces (IDF) has in eliminating fighters of the group amid continued resistance.</p>

<p>On Friday the military said troops battled Palestinian fighters in Khan Younis, and destroyed tunnels and other infrastructure, as they sought to suppress small operative units that have continued to hit troops with mortar fire.</p>

<p>More than 39,000 Palestinians have been killed by Israeli strikes in the enclave, according to Gaza health authorities, who do not distinguish between fighters and non-combatants.</p>

<p>Israeli officials estimate that some 14,000 fighters from groups including Hamas and Islamic Jihad have been killed or taken prisoner, out of a force they estimated to number more than 25,000 at the start of the war.</p>

<p>Around 1,200 people were killed and 250 were taken hostage in the Oct. 7 raid on southern Israel, according to Israeli tallies.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/8oobe958_gaza-school-attack_625x300_27_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[U.N. and humanitarian officials accuse Israel of using disproportionate force in the war]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>