<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Thu, 27 Jun 2024 12:34:31 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ahead-of-uk-polls-all-you-need-to-know-about-british-pm-rishi-sunak-5979987]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ahead Of UK Polls, All You Need To Know About British PM Rishi Sunak]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ahead-of-uk-polls-all-you-need-to-know-about-british-pm-rishi-sunak-5979987]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 27 Jun 2024 11:51:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[UK will vote on July 4 in a snap general election called by PM  Rishi Sunak. With his Conservative Party trailing the Labour Party by 21 points in the latest polls, Mr Sunak faces an uphill task to retain his party's 14-year grip on power.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United Kingdom will vote on July 4 in a snap general election called by Prime Minister Rishi Sunak. With his Conservative Party trailing the Labour Party by 21 points in the latest polls, Mr Sunak faces an uphill task to retain his party's 14-year grip on power and own position as Prime Minister.<br />
<br />
<strong>Here are a few facts about the current British Prime Minister:</strong><br />
<br />
1. Rishi Sunak was born on May 12, 1980, in Southampton, England. His grandparents were all born in India but migrated to East Africa for work and eventually settled in the UK. Mr Sunak went to Winchester College, a private boarding school in England and later graduated from Oxford University. He pursued an MBA at Stanford University, where he met his wife, Akshata Murty, daughter of Infosys co-founder N R Narayana Murthy. They got married in 2009 and have two daughters together.<br />
<br />
2. Before he forayed into politics, Mr Sunak had a successful career in finance. He worked as an analyst at Goldman Sachs from 2001 to 2004 before becoming a partner at The Children's Investment Fund Management in 2006. In 2010, he moved to Theleme Partners, another hedge fund management firm. He also served as the director of Catamaran Ventures, an investment firm owned by his father-in-law.<br />
<br />
3. Mr Sunak's political career took off in 2014 when he was chosen as the Conservative candidate for Richmond (Yorks). In 2015, he was elected a Member of Parliament for Richmond (Yorks), receiving 36.2% votes. His political ascension continued as he held various government positions, including Minister for Local Government in 2018, Chief Secretary to the Treasury in 2019 and Chancellor of the Exchequer from 2020 to 2022.<br />
<br />
4. In October 2022, Mr Sunak made history when King Charles III appointed him as Britain's first Hindu and Indian-origin Prime Minister. Elected unopposed as the leader of the Conservative Party on Diwali, he became the youngest British Prime Minister in 210 years at 42.<br />
&nbsp;<br />
5. As UK PM, Mr Sunak has courted controversies. In May 2024, he proposed restricting the UK's post-study visa, which drew opposition from cabinet members. In 2022, Mr Sunak faced a tax scandal surrounding his wife's non-domicile status. The same year, he was involved in another controversy over holding a US green card while serving as a British government minister. Mr Sunak also faced criticism for his role in the Partygate scandal, receiving a fixed-penalty notice for attending a birthday party for Boris Johnson during the lockdown in 2020.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/3srb65a8_rishi-sunak-reuters_625x300_20_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-zealand-woman-who-sued-ex-boyfriend-over-airport-ride-loses-claim-5979781]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[New Zealand Woman Who Sued Ex Boyfriend Over Airport Ride Loses Claim]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-zealand-woman-who-sued-ex-boyfriend-over-airport-ride-loses-claim-5979781]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 27 Jun 2024 11:21:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The promise of a ride to the airport is not legally binding, a woman in New Zealand has discovered after seeking compensation from her ex-boyfriend because she missed her flight.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The promise of a ride to the airport is not legally binding, a woman in New Zealand has discovered after seeking compensation from her ex-boyfriend because she missed her flight.</p>

<p>The woman was so annoyed about failing to catch her plane when her partner reneged on an airport ride that she ended the relationship and took him to a dispute tribunal for small claims.</p>

<p>Her ex-partner's pledge to give her a lift and look after her pets while she was away was a verbal contract, the unnamed woman claimed, according to tribunal documents released last week.</p>

<p>The woman requested compensation because she had to kennel her dogs, which she claimed her ex had also verbally agreed to look after when she ended up taking a replacement flight to watch a concert with friends.</p>

<p>As well as seeking money for a new plane ticket, kennel costs and alternative transport to the airport, the woman also wanted the cash back for a ferry ticket she bought her ex-partner for a holiday last December.</p>

<p>The tribunal dismissed her claim when it was heard in March.</p>

<p>A law academic told AFP the woman would have had to show a legally binding contract for her claim to succeed.</p>

<p>"If the arrangement had been entered into by text message, I don't think it would have made a difference here," said Associate Professor Simon Connell from Otago University's law faculty.</p>

<p>"What's missing is a clear signal that the parties wanted to create a legally bringing contract."</p>

<p>Connell said it is unusual for someone to try and legally enforce what many people would see as a social agreement, "so when it does happen, it can attract some attention."</p>

<p>He cited the reported 2015 example of a five-year-old boy in Britain, who was sent an invoice and his parents threatened with legal action because he failed to attend a child's birthday party.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2019-05/soicn89g_airport-generic_625x300_10_May_19.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/astronaut-sunita-williams-return-to-earth-delayed-again-what-nasa-said-5979727]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Astronaut Sunita Williams' Return To Earth Delayed Again. What NASA Said]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/astronaut-sunita-williams-return-to-earth-delayed-again-what-nasa-said-5979727]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 27 Jun 2024 11:15:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Indian-origin astronaut Sunita Williams' scheduled return to Earth has been delayed once again after the spacecraft in which she travelled to space, the Boeing Starliner, faced a series of technical glitches.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Indian-origin astronaut Sunita Williams' scheduled return to Earth has been delayed once again after the spacecraft in which she travelled to space, the Boeing Starliner, faced a series of technical glitches.</p>

<p>The astronaut, who left Earth on June 5 was set to return on June 14, after a week in space. However, her return was delayed to June 26. Now, no new date for her return has been disclosed by NASA.</p>

<p>NDTV had reported that the space agency had extended Ms Williams' stay on the space station after five helium leaks were detected on the Starliner spaceship and five of its 28 thrusters faced issues. At least 14 thrusters are needed for a safe return.</p>

<p>For now, Ms Williams and her crewmate Butch Wilmore are both safe on the International Space Station along with the seven other crew members. The ISS is a "mini city in space" about the size of a football field that astronauts from multiple space agencies use for research.</p>

<p>In a press briefing, NASA said it is taking "our time and following our standard mission management team process", adding that the spacecraft is clear for return in case of an emergency on the space station that requires the crew to come back to Earth.</p>

<p>The space agency said mission managers are evaluating future return opportunities following a planned spacewalk on July 2.</p>

<p>“Starliner is performing well in orbit while docked to the space station. We are strategically using the extra time to clear a path for some critical station activities while completing readiness for Butch and Suni's return on Starliner and gaining valuable insight into the system upgrades we will want to make for post-certification missions," it said</p>

<p>Before the veteran astronaut returned to space, her flight was marred with several delays as the launch of the Boeing Starliner spacecraft was repeatedly postponed by NASA. On June 7, the Indian-origin astronaut broke into a dance as she entered the space station.</p>

<p>While Ms Williams has described the Boeing Starliner as a "fantastic spacecraft", several whistleblowers have accused Boeing and NASA of neglect.</p>

<p>They have alleged that both Boeing and NASA managers knew of the technical faults with the spaceship but went ahead with the launch to avoid further delay. So far 20 whistleblowers, have accused NASA of ignoring their concerns.</p>

<p>On the other hand, aircraft maker Boeing has faced several allegations of technical failures as several of its aircrafts have suffered serious snags during flights across the globe.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/66j5ea08_sunita-williams_625x300_27_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/free-from-prison-wikileaks-founder-julian-assange-plans-to-rediscover-life-enjoy-freedom-5979655]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Free From Prison, Julian Assange Plans To "Rediscover Life", Enjoy Freedom]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/free-from-prison-wikileaks-founder-julian-assange-plans-to-rediscover-life-enjoy-freedom-5979655]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 27 Jun 2024 11:03:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[WikiLeaks founder Julian Assange is "rediscovering" life as he tastes freedom in Australia after a five-year stretch in a London high-security prison, his wife said Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>WikiLeaks founder Julian Assange is "rediscovering" life as he tastes freedom in Australia after a five-year stretch in a London high-security prison, his wife said Thursday.</p>

<p>The 52-year-old landed in Canberra the night before, hours after pleading guilty in a US Pacific island court to a single count of revealing military secrets.</p>

<p>Under a plea deal, he was sentenced to time already served and allowed to walk free, ending a 14-year legal struggle with the US Department of Justice.</p>

<p>But the jail time has taken a toll.</p>

<p>Assange did not attend a news conference after he touched down, with his wife near tears as she pleaded for family privacy and time for him to recuperate.</p>

<p>"He's just savouring freedom for the first time in 14 years. He needs time to rest and recover. And he is just rediscovering normal life. And he needs space to do that," Stella Assange told reporters Thursday.</p>

<p>"Julian plans to swim in the ocean every day. He plans to sleep in a real bed. He plans to taste real food. And he plans to enjoy his freedom."</p>

<h3><strong>&nbsp;'Jumping on the sofa'&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>The WikiLeaks publisher had yet to see his two children, who were staying elsewhere and asleep when his plane landed, she said.</p>

<p>Stella Assange said she sent her husband a video on the day of his US court hearing showing their children "jumping on the sofa" at the prospect of their father's return.</p>

<p>Assange spent more than five years in London's Belmarsh prison fighting extradition to the United States on charges under the 1917 Espionage Act.</p>

<p>He had already lived for seven years in Ecuador's London embassy to escape extradition to Sweden over sexual assault charges, which were eventually dropped.</p>

<p>The couple have not had time to discuss how their lives will play out since his release, said Stella, who met Assange while he was still in the Ecuadorian embassy and married him in the London prison.</p>

<p>Assange's legal team argues that the US Justice Department's legal pursuit of their client will have a chilling effect on journalism.</p>

<p>They have called for US President Joe Biden to grant him a pardon following his plea deal in Saipan, capital of the US territory of Northern Mariana Islands.</p>

<p>"The president of the United States has absolute pardon power. President Biden or any subsequent president can, and in my mind should, issue a pardon to Julian Assange," said his US trial lawyer Barry Pollack.</p>

<h3><strong>People put in 'danger'&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Stella Assange said her husband had pleaded "guilty to committing journalism -- this case criminalises journalism".</p>

<p>Assange had published hundreds of thousands of confidential US documents on the WikiLeaks whistleblowing website from 2010.</p>

<p>He became a hero to free speech campaigners but a villain to those who thought he had endangered US security and intelligence sources.</p>

<p>The Australian citizen was indicted by a US federal grand jury in 2019 on 18 counts stemming from WikiLeaks' publication of a trove of national security documents.</p>

<p>The material he released through WikiLeaks included video showing civilians being killed by fire from a US helicopter gunship in Iraq in 2007. The victims included a photographer and a driver from Reuters.</p>

<p>On Wednesday, the US State Department renewed its allegation that he put people at risk.</p>

<p>"The documents they published gave identifying information of individuals who were in contact with the State Department," State Department spokesman Matthew Miller told reporters in Washington.</p>

<p>"That included opposition leaders, human rights activists around the world -- whose positions were put in some danger."</p>

<p>The US Justice Department has banned Assange from returning to the United States without permission.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/v7ajaupg_assange-afp_625x300_27_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Julian Assange spent more than five years in London's Belmarsh prison.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bolivia-president-luis-arce-faces-coup-attempt-amid-political-tensions-5979653]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bolivia President Luis Arce Faces Coup Attempt Amid Political Tensions]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bolivia-president-luis-arce-faces-coup-attempt-amid-political-tensions-5979653]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 27 Jun 2024 11:02:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Bolivian President Luis Arce, a mild-mannered and bespectacled former economy minister, faced down a coup attempt on Wednesday, as the armed forces withdrew after occupying the central square in La Paz and entering the presidential palace.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bolivian President Luis Arce, a mild-mannered and bespectacled former economy minister, faced down a coup attempt on Wednesday, as the armed forces withdrew after occupying the central square in La Paz and entering the presidential palace.</p>

<p>Arce, 60, won election in 2020 after a period of deep political turmoil. A ballot the year before was marred by allegations of fraud, which sparked widespread protests and the eventual resignation of then-President Evo Morales.</p>

<p>Former allies and colleagues, Arce and Morales have since become political rivals. Both are eyeing a presidential run in an election next year, and each leads a faction of the dominant Movement to Socialism (MAS) political party.</p>

<p>A court ruling against Morales' running again fueled protests this year that blocked the country's main highway and hurt the economy. Shortages of dollars and fuel have also caused damage as the landlocked country's gas output and exports fell.</p>

<p>Arce, a former economist known for keeping a low personal profile, was at one time Morales' protégé and crafted the economic plan for Morales' successful 2005 presidential run.</p>

<p>Morales then appointed Arce as economy minister in 2006, and he steered the Andean country's economy for well over a decade. Supporters said he was the architect of Bolivia's growth "miracle" in the 2000s that lifted many in one of South America's poorest nations out of poverty. Commodities including gas, metals, and soybeans boomed.</p>

<p>He also angered investors by pushing for the nationalization of sectors including oil and gas.</p>

<p>Towards the end of Morales' nearly 14-year rule, growth slowed and opposition grew to his seeking an unprecedented fourth term.</p>

<p>The voided 2019 election marked a political crisis. It was followed by Morales' resignation, bloody violence, and the year-long interim presidency of Jeanine Anez, a right-wing congresswoman who assumed power after Morales left the country.</p>

<p>Arce's election in 2020 appeared to bring political stability. Morales returned from nearly a year in exile when Arce won the presidency.</p>

<p>As president, Arce has struggled to manage a U.S. dollar shortage that has strained the economy and led credit-ratings agencies to downgrade Bolivia's debt to "junk" status.</p>

<p>The general behind Wednesday's coup effort, Juan Jose Zuniga, said the government was "impoverishing" the country.</p>

<p>Arce's government has signed agreements with Russian and Chinese firms to develop Bolivia's huge untapped reserves of lithium, a metal used in batteries for electric vehicles, cell phones, and laptops. However, lawmakers in the divided legislature have yet to approve any contracts.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/dci9035_luis-arce_625x300_27_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Luis Arce, 60, won election in 2020 after a period of deep political turmoil.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/larry-the-cat-awaits-for-sixth-prime-minister-as-uk-election-nears-5979425]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Larry The Cat Awaits Sixth Prime Minister As UK Election Nears]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/larry-the-cat-awaits-for-sixth-prime-minister-as-uk-election-nears-5979425]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 27 Jun 2024 10:43:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[There has been one figure of stability in the last 14 years of political turmoil in the UK -- Larry the Downing Street cat.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There has been one figure of stability in the last 14 years of political turmoil in the UK -- Larry the Downing Street cat.</p>

<p>Now, with a general election fast approaching on July 4, the ageing tabby could be in line for his sixth prime minister.</p>

<p>He has already had five Conservative prime ministers serve under him but if polls are correct, he will soon get his first from the Labour party.</p>

<p>Incumbent Rishi Sunak's departure would see him take his fox-red labrador retriever Nova too. Not that Larry would mind.</p>

<p>According to Sunak's wife, Akshata Murty, the pair have had some "heated exchanges". But Larry has always prevailed.</p>

<p>Labour leader Keir Starmer recently told the BBC that his family has a cat, Jojo, that his children spoil more than him.</p>

<p>They also have a hamster, Bear, he told the Metro newspaper. But it's uncertain if either would move with him if he wins.</p>

<p>Larry has been fiercely protective of his territory, frequently fighting to be the top cat with his counterpart at the foreign ministry, Palmerston.</p>

<p>His rival eventually retired to the countryside.</p>

<p>Urban foxes and unsuspecting pigeons have also been chased away, although one feathered interloper narrowly avoided his clutches, as the media looked on.</p>

<h3><strong>Longevity&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Larry made his first appearance in Downing Street on February 15, 2011, after being adopted from the Battersea shelter in south London.</p>

<p>He was recruited under then prime minister David Cameron to get rid of mice and even given an official title: "Chief Mouser".</p>

<p>But his performance in that department left much to be desired, despite a few early successes.</p>

<p>Cameron himself tried to quash rumours that he and Larry did not get along, while reporters on the politics beat have said he is friendly with journalists.</p>

<p>"He's interested," the appropriately named BBC political correspondent Helen Catt said in a recent item on Larry.</p>

<p>"He tends to come up and have a look when you're there with the camera crew, he likes to see what the press are up to."</p>

<p>But that has its downsides, she added.</p>

<p>"When you're in Downing Street and you're doing lives, you're always very aware that if he pops out behind you, a lot of people really aren't going to be listening to what you're saying anymore," she said.</p>

<p>For the general election, Larry has set out his campaign manifesto on his official @Number10cat social media account.</p>

<p>"I don't get to vote in the general election but I do have to live with whoever you elect. No pressure," one post read after Sunak announced the election on May 22.</p>

<p>"Whatever the result of the election, I'll be here to keep an eye on things," read another.</p>

<p>Interviewed by AFP on the 10th anniversary of his arrival in power, Larry, via the human running his social media account, revealed the secret to his longevity.</p>

<p>"The key thing to remember is that I live here permanently, the politicians just lodge with me for a bit until they're fired," he said.</p>

<p>"They all work out sooner or later that it's me that runs the place.".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2016-04/larry-the-cat_650x400_71460473935.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[He has already had five Conservative prime ministers serve under him.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/climate-change-and-thinning-ice-exposes-bodies-of-mountaineers-on-everest-5979386]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Climate Change And Thinning Ice Exposes Bodies Of Mountaineers On Everest]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/climate-change-and-thinning-ice-exposes-bodies-of-mountaineers-on-everest-5979386]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 27 Jun 2024 10:42:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[On Everest's sacred slopes, climate change is thinning snow and ice, increasingly exposing the bodies of hundreds of mountaineers who died chasing their dream to summit the world's highest mountain.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On Everest's sacred slopes, climate change is thinning snow and ice, increasingly exposing the bodies of hundreds of mountaineers who died chasing their dream to summit the world's highest mountain.</p>

<p>Among those scaling the soaring Himalayan mountain this year was a team not aiming for the 8,849-metre (29,032-foot) peak, but risking their own lives to bring some of the corpses down.</p>

<p>Five as yet unnamed frozen bodies were retrieved -- including one that was just skeletal remains -- as part of Nepal's mountain clean-up campaign on Everest and adjoining peaks Lhotse and Nuptse.</p>

<p>It is a grim, tough and dangerous task.</p>

<p>Rescuers took hours to chip away the ice with axes, with the team sometimes using boiling water to release its frozen grip.</p>

<p>"Because of the effects of global warming, (the bodies and trash) are becoming more visible as the snow cover thins," said Aditya Karki, a major in Nepal's army, who led the team of 12 military personnel and 18 climbers.</p>

<p>More than 300 people have perished on the mountain since expeditions started in the 1920s, eight this season alone.</p>

<p>Many bodies remain. Some are hidden by snow or swallowed down deep crevasses.</p>

<p>Others, still in their colourful climbing gear, have become landmarks en route to the summit.</p>

<p>Nicknames include "Green Boots" and "Sleeping Beauty".</p>

<h3><strong>'Death zone'&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>"There is a psychological effect," Karki told AFP.</p>

<p>"People believe that they are entering a divine space when they climb mountains, but if they see dead bodies on the way up, it can have a negative effect."</p>

<p>Many are inside the "death zone", where thin air and low oxygen levels raise the risk of altitude sickness.</p>

<p>Climbers must have insurance, but any rescue or recovery mission is fraught with danger.</p>

<p>One body, encased in ice up to its torso, took the climbers 11 hours to free.</p>

<p>The team had to use hot water to loosen it, prising it out with their axes.</p>

<p>"It is extremely difficult," said Tshiring Jangbu Sherpa, who led the body retrieval expedition.</p>

<p>"Getting the body out is one part, bringing it down is another challenge".</p>

<p>Sherpa said some of the bodies still appeared almost as they had at the moment of death -- dressed in full gear, along with their crampons and harnesses.</p>

<p>One seemed untouched, only missing a glove.</p>

<p>The retrieval of corpses at high altitudes is a controversial topic for the climbing community.</p>

<p>It costs thousands of dollars, and up to eight rescuers are needed for each body.</p>

<p>A body can weigh over 100 kilogrammes (220 pounds), and at high altitudes, a person's ability to carry heavy loads is severely affected.</p>

<h3><strong>'Turn into a graveyard'</strong></h3>

<p>But Karki said the rescue effort was necessary.</p>

<p>"We have to bring them back as much as possible," he said. "If we keep leaving them behind, our mountains will turn into a graveyard."</p>

<p>Bodies are often wrapped in a bag then put on a plastic sled to drag down.</p>

<p>Sherpa said that bringing one body down from close to Lhotse's 8,516 metre peak -- the world's fourth-highest mountain -- had been among the hardest challenges so far.</p>

<p>"The body was frozen with hands and legs spread," he said.</p>

<p>"We had to carry it down to Camp Three as it was, and only then could it be moved to be put in a sled to be dragged."</p>

<p>Rakesh Gurung, from Nepal's tourism department, said two bodies had been preliminarily identified and authorities were awaiting "detailed tests" for the final confirmation.</p>

<p>The retrieved bodies are now in the capital Kathmandu, with those not identified likely to be eventually cremated.</p>

<h3><strong>Missing mountaineers&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Despite the recovery efforts, the mountain still holds its secrets.</p>

<p>The body of George Mallory, the British climber who went missing during a 1924 attempt on the summit, was only found in 1999.</p>

<p>His climbing partner, Andrew Irvine, has never been found -- nor has their camera, which could provide evidence of a successful summit that would rewrite mountaineering history.</p>

<p>The clean-up campaign, with a budget of over $600,000, also employed 171 Nepali guides and porters to bring back 11 tonnes of rubbish.</p>

<p>Fluorescent tents, discarded climbing equipment, empty gas canisters and even human excreta litter the well-trodden route to the summit.</p>

<p>"The mountains have given us mountaineers so many opportunities," Sherpa said.</p>

<p>"I feel that we have to give back to them, we have to remove the trash and bodies to clean the mountains."</p>

<p>Today, expeditions are under pressure to remove the waste that they create, but historic rubbish remains.</p>

<p>"This year's trash might be brought back by the mountaineers," said Karki. "But who will bring the old ones?</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/ipn5ukl_everest-cleanup-afp_625x300_27_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The clean-up campaign employed 171 Nepali guides and porters to bring back 11 tonnes of rubbish.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/juan-orlando-hernandez-cocaine-worth-10-billion-130-murders-ex-honduran-presidents-drug-empire-5979422]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How An Ex President Helped Traffic Cocaine Worth $10 Billion Into US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/juan-orlando-hernandez-cocaine-worth-10-billion-130-murders-ex-honduran-presidents-drug-empire-5979422]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 27 Jun 2024 10:22:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Juan Orlando Hernandez was convicted in a US federal court on three counts, including cocaine importation and weapons offences. ]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former Honduran president <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-jails-honduran-ex-president-for-45-years-on-drug-trafficking-charges-5978213" target="_blank">Juan Orlando Hernandez</a>&nbsp;was on Wednesday sentenced to 45 years in a United States prison and fined $8 million for his role in drug trafficking.&nbsp;US prosecutors accused him of running a "narco-state" that smuggled over 400 tons of South American cocaine to the US while he was president from 2014 to 2022.</p>

<p>US District Judge Kevin Castel said Hernandez provided police and military support and helped to send drugs worth $10 billion to the United States.</p>

<p>Hernandez, 55, was found guilty of federal drug and weapons charges in March. He was convicted in a US federal court on three counts, including cocaine importation and weapons offences.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
Prosecutors said he built his political career on bribes from traffickers and protected them from extradition and prosecution.<br />
<br />
<strong>Early involvement</strong><br />
<br />
Juan Orlando Hernandez's involvement in the drug trade dates back to at least 2004, when he was a congressman in Honduras.</p>

<p>He allegedly accepted bribes from drug traffickers in Honduras, Mexico and beyond, in exchange for political favours and protection, stated a <a href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/juan-orlando-hernandez-former-president-honduras-convicted-manhattan-federal-court ">press release</a>&nbsp;by the US Department of Justice.<br />
<br />
<strong>Rise to power</strong><br />
<br />
As Hernandez's political career advanced, so did his involvement in the drug trade. He became the President of Honduras in 2014 and used his position to expand his drug empire. He allegedly worked with some of the world's largest drug traffickers, including the Sinaloa Cartel, to transport tons of cocaine through Honduras and into the US.<br />
<br />
<strong>Abuse of power</strong><br />
<br />
Juan Orlando Hernandez presented himself as an advocate against drug trafficking in public, but in reality, he colluded with and protected the interests of drug traffickers who supported him.<br />
<br />
He selectively upheld extraditions, allowing certain drug traffickers to remain in Honduras while others were extradited to the US. Hernandez also used Honduran institutions, including the police and military, to protect his drug trafficking operation, as per the press release.<br />
<br />
<strong>Violence and murder</strong><br />
<br />
According to reports, Hernandez's drug empire was responsible for more than 130 murders, including the killings of rival traffickers and those who threatened his operation. His brother, Juan Antonio "Tony" Hernandez, was also involved in the drug trade and was convicted in the US for cocaine trafficking. Countless others disappeared or were tortured; their fates unknown.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
<strong>Sentence</strong><br />
<br />
Hernandez was convicted on three counts of importing cocaine into the US (10 years to life in prison), using machine guns and destructive devices in the drug trade (additional 30 years in prison) and conspiring to use and carry machine guns and destructive devices in the drug trade (up to life in prison).&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/2eqisb88_juan-orlando-hernandez_625x300_27_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Former Honduran president Juan Orlando Hernandez has been jailed for 45 years (File photo)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-and-biden-to-have-their-1st-debate-of-2024-without-studio-audience-5979267]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump And Biden To Have Their 1st Debate Of 2024 Without Studio Audience]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-and-biden-to-have-their-1st-debate-of-2024-without-studio-audience-5979267]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 27 Jun 2024 09:53:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[There will be no studio audience, depriving candidates of the momentum that comes from ginning up supporters. Microphones will cut out when a candidate's speaking time is over. Thursday night's presidential debate will not be business as usual.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There will be no studio audience, depriving candidates of the momentum that comes from ginning up supporters. Microphones will cut out when a candidate's speaking time is over. Thursday night's presidential debate will not be business as usual.</p>

<p>CNN, which is hosting President Joe Biden and his predecessor Donald Trump for their first debate of the 2024 campaign in Atlanta, wants to avoid the chaos seen when the two men squared off in 2020.</p>

<p>Here are some facts about the 90-minute debate, a key moment in the race for the White House, but one whose impact is difficult to predict.</p>

<h3><strong>&nbsp;Averting mayhem&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>In their first war of words four years ago, Trump repeatedly cut off the veteran Democrat, launched into lengthy diatribes and taunted his rival, who ended up shouting at one point: "Will you shut up, man?"</p>

<p>It was hardly the height of presidential decorum.</p>

<p>To cut down on the hijinks, CNN has set up a series of rules, to which both campaigns agreed.</p>

<p>Among the most notable: When the candidates take the stage at the network's Atlanta studios at 9:00 pm (0100 GMT Friday), there will be no one in the audience.</p>

<p>Microphones will be muted except for the candidate asked to speak. There will be two commercial breaks during the showdown between 78-year-old Trump and 81-year-old Biden, the two oldest presumptive White House nominees in history.</p>

<p>Moderators Jake Tapper and Dana Bash, both regular CNN on-air presenters, will "use all tools at their disposal to enforce timing and ensure a civilized discussion," the network said.</p>

<h3><strong>Trump gets last word&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Biden won the coin toss, allowing him to choose either his podium position or whether he preferred to speak first or second in final statements.</p>

<p>The incumbent chose the podium on the viewers' right, and Trump opted to have the last word.</p>

<h3><strong>No live fact-checking&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>CNN has not revealed the debate themes and does not plan to fact-check candidate statements in real time -- even if Trump repeats the baseless charge that the 2020 election was stolen from him.</p>

<p>For Kathleen Hall Jamieson, a professor of communication at the University of Pennsylvania, "one problem with a debate that features Donald Trump is that the moderators don't fact check in real-time, nor should they."</p>

<p>"It's highly risky to try to do that and it would be disruptive of the debate if they did," she told AFP. "The danger is instead of informing, a debate could actually increase the amount of inaccurate knowledge."</p>

<p>Biden and Trump will not have teleprompters and they cannot bring pre-written notes to the stage, although they will be provided with paper and pen. Consulting with campaign staff during commercial breaks will not be allowed.</p>

<h3><strong>Debate airs on all networks&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Both candidates rejected the oversight of the nonpartisan Commission on Presidential Debates formed in 1987 to manage such events.</p>

<p>Instead, they made a direct deal with CNN. The news network, now owned by media conglomerate Warner Bros Discovery, afforded its rivals the opportunity to broadcast the debate live in the name of public service, under certain conditions.</p>

<p>The screen must bear the CNN logo and outside commentary is forbidden.</p>

<p>Fox News -- which regularly attacks CNN as biased against Trump -- plans to hit the airwaves two hours before the event, with talk show hosts Jesse Watters and Sean Hannity providing pre-game insights.</p>

<p>In the past, Hannity has called Tapper a "radical left-wing partisan talk show host masquerading as a journalist."</p>

<h3><strong>&nbsp;Impact on campaign?&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>The debate will certainly be a key moment in the campaign, watched by tens of millions: a record 84 million tuned in to watch Trump's first battle with Hillary Clinton in 2016, and 73 million saw Trump and Biden duke it out in 2020.</p>

<p>But it will not necessarily be a game-changer.</p>

<p>This is the first time a debate has been organized so early in the race, more than four months before Election Day, and even before the candidates have been formally nominated by their respective parties.</p>

<p>"The worry is that the public in the United States doesn't pay much attention to news in summer," said Jamieson.</p>

<p>"In general, presidential debates don't affect a sufficient number of votes to decide the outcome of an election. But when an election is close, as this one may be, debates can play an important role."</p>

<p>ABC is scheduled to host a second debate on September 10.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-10/9d8qmao8_us-presidential-debate-2020-trump-biden-afp-650_650x400_23_October_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[CNN is hosting President Biden and Donald Trump for their 1st debate of the 2024 campaign (file).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-election-from-chaos-to-scandals-moments-from-us-presidential-debates-over-the-years-5979162]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[From Chaos To Scandals: Moments From US Presidential Debates Over The Years]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-election-from-chaos-to-scandals-moments-from-us-presidential-debates-over-the-years-5979162]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 27 Jun 2024 09:35:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[From Gerald Ford's catastrophic Soviet gaffe to Ronald Reagan's witty remark about his age and Joe Biden asking Donald Trump to "shut up," US presidential debates have been funny, vicious and everything in between.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>From Gerald Ford's catastrophic Soviet gaffe to Ronald Reagan's witty remark about his age and Joe Biden asking Donald Trump to "shut up," US presidential debates have been funny, vicious and everything in between.</p>

<p>Here are some of the most memorable moments from more than 60 years of modern American debates.</p>

<h3><strong>Kennedy-Nixon, September 26, 1960&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>It was the first televised debate of its kind, when everything was still broadcast in black-and-white, and it established the importance of a politician's public image. Republican Richard Nixon looked poised to win the election, having served two terms as vice president under Dwight Eisenhower.</p>

<p>But the debate did not go well for him. Nixon refused to wear makeup and appeared pale and sweaty in front of more than 66 million viewers, while the young Massachusetts senator John F. Kennedy looked tanned and relaxed. While Nixon addressed the moderator, Kennedy looked at the camera, speaking directly to his voters.</p>

<p>How much the debate visuals pushed the needle is disputed, but Kennedy went on to defeat Nixon at the polls.</p>

<h3><strong>Ford-Carter, October 6, 1976&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>The first debate between Republican president Gerald Ford and Democratic challenger Jimmy Carter was marked by a 27-minute loss of audio. The second debate didn't go well for Ford either, when he made a gaffe that arguably cost him the presidency.</p>

<p>At the height of the Cold War, Ford uttered that "there is no Soviet domination of Eastern Europe, and there never will be under a Ford administration," even though the Soviet Union had troops deployed across the Eastern bloc.</p>

<p>Six days passed before Ford explained himself, saying that he spoke not of the literal military presence but meant that people's spirits there hadn't been crushed.</p>

<h3><strong>&nbsp;Reagan-Mondale, October 21, 1984&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Republican president Ronald Reagan was 73 when he ran for a second term against 56-year-old Walter Mondale. But he managed to turn his age into his strength with a witty answer that went down in history.</p>

<p>"I will not make age an issue of this campaign," Reagan said when asked whether he was fit for office. "I am not going to exploit, for political purposes, my opponent's youth and inexperience."</p>

<h3><strong>Bush-Clinton-Perot, October 15, 1992&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>The second presidential debate in the 1992 race pitted incumbent president George Bush against both his future successor Bill Clinton and Ross Perot, an independent candidate.</p>

<p>Bush was caught on camera looking at his watch while Clinton talked to an audience member during a town hall debate, a move that cost Bush dearly.</p>

<p>Years later, Bush admitted he hated the debates. "Maybe that's why I was looking at it, 'only 10 more minutes of this crap.'"</p>

<h3><strong>&nbsp;Obama-Romney, October 22, 2012&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>During a debate against president Barack Obama, Republican challenger Mitt Romney lamented that the US Navy had fewer ships presently than it did in 1916.</p>

<p>"Governor, we also have fewer horses and bayonets, because the nature of our military's changed," Obama retorted.</p>

<p>"We have these things called aircraft carriers, where planes land on them. We have these ships that go under water, nuclear submarines."</p>

<p>Obama's comments went viral online.</p>

<h3><strong>Trump-Clinton, October 9, 2016&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>The second debate of the 2016 US presidential election pitting Hillary Clinton and Donald Trump was particularly vicious.</p>

<p>Coming shortly after the release of a video in which Trump was heard boasting that his fame allowed him to grope women, the Republican billionaire went after his opponent's husband, former president Bill Clinton, accusing him of being "so abusive to women."</p>

<p>Trump also vowed to have Hillary Clinton investigated over her use of a private email account when she was secretary of state.</p>

<p>"It's just awfully good that someone with the temperament of Donald Trump is not in charge of the law in our country," Clinton said.</p>

<p>Trump shot back: "Because you'd be in jail."</p>

<h3><strong>&nbsp;Trump-Biden, September 29, 2020&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>The first debate of the 2020 presidential election, featuring Trump and Democrat Joe Biden, devolved into shouting and insults.</p>

<p>With Trump constantly interrupting him, Biden snapped, saying, "Will you shut up, man?"</p>

<p>The Democrat also called his opponent a "clown" and "Putin's puppy."</p>

<p>Trump for his part kept evading the question of whether he would recognize the results of the election.</p>

<p>Powerless to control the two candidates, the debate moderator, Fox News journalist Chris Wallace, later described feeling "desperation."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/m45iqmp_us-debates-afp-_625x300_27_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The 2016 US presidential election debate which had Trump against Clinton, was particularly vicious.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/boeing-whistleblower-richard-cuevas-claims-i-was-fired-after-raising-safety-concerns-5978871]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[I Was "Fired" After Raising Safety Concerns, Claims Boeing Whistleblower]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/boeing-whistleblower-richard-cuevas-claims-i-was-fired-after-raising-safety-concerns-5978871]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 27 Jun 2024 09:23:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Another whistleblower stepped forward Wednesday alleging he was retaliated against after flagging potentially dangerous manufacturing problems on the Boeing 787 Dreamliner.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Another whistleblower stepped forward Wednesday alleging he was retaliated against after flagging potentially dangerous manufacturing problems on the Boeing 787 Dreamliner.</p>

<p>Richard Cuevas filed complaints with two US agencies alleging he was dismissed suddenly in March 2024 after raising concerns over manufacturing deviations in the forward pressure bulkhead, which is critical to managing pressure during flights, according to attorneys Katz Banks Kumin.</p>

<p>Cuevas is the latest whistleblower to come forward from Boeing's operations, adding to scrutiny of the plane maker following a January inflight incident on a 737 MAX operated by Alaska Airlines that required an emergency landing.</p>

<p>Cuevas worked as a contractor for Strom, who assigned him to Spirit AeroSystems, which builds fuselages for the Dreamliner.</p>

<p>In October 2023, Cuevas filed an ethics complaint with Boeing, alleging Spirit had made unauthorized changes to fastener hole dimensions in the forward pressure bulkhead on 787 aircraft without notifying Boeing.</p>

<p>"Our client witnessed critical issues with the forward pressure bulkhead assembly on multiple planes that deviated from Boeing's specifications," said a statement from Katz Banks Kumin.</p>

<p>"He recognized the substandard work and expressed concern about his safety concerns, but Spirit and Boeing failed to stop the faulty manufacturing processes. Mr. Cuevas was fired when his manager found out that an employee complained about these issues, and suspected that employee was Mr. Cuevas."</p>

<p>The attorneys filed complaints with the Federal Aviation Administration and the Occupational Health and Safety Administration, saying in the latter submission that Cuevas believes that "based on his direct observations of glaring safety issues, that Boeing's and Spirit's statements to the public and investors about the safety of 787 Dreamliners are fraudulent."</p>

<p>The attorneys also represent Sam Salehpour, a Boeing engineer who testified in April in the Senate about concerns over 787 manufacturing practices and that he was retaliated against for speaking.</p>

<p>Boeing said it is not involved in personnel decisions of subcontracts.</p>

<p>"A subcontractor's employee previously reported concerns to us that we thoroughly investigated as we take seriously any safety-related matter. Engineering analysis determined that the issues raised did not present a safety concern and were addressed," Boeing said. "We are reviewing the documents released today and will thoroughly investigate any new claim."</p>

<p>Spirit "leadership is aware of the allegations and looking into the matter," said company spokesperson Joe Buccino. "We encourage all Spirit employees with concerns to come forward, safe in knowing they will be protected."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/007a2he8_boeing-787-afp_625x300_18_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Boeing said it is not involved in personnel decisions of subcontracts (file).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/broken-healthcare-a-key-issue-for-uk-voters-ahead-of-elections-5978584]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Broken" Healthcare A Key Issue For UK Voters Ahead Of Elections]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/broken-healthcare-a-key-issue-for-uk-voters-ahead-of-elections-5978584]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 27 Jun 2024 08:58:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The NHS, created after World War II to provide free healthcare to all, is a shadow of its former self, weakened by years of underfunding and the Covid-19 pandemic.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Fatme Ibryanova, 36, will travel from Britain to Turkey next month, not to holiday but for a medical appointment about surgery she is struggling to get on the UK's "broken" state-run health service.</p>

<p>The NHS, created after World War II to provide free healthcare to all, is a shadow of its former self, weakened by years of underfunding and the Covid-19 pandemic.</p>

<p>Getting an appointment with a doctor or a dentist is often an ordeal. Emergency rooms are usually overwhelmed, and waiting times for hospital treatment regularly hit new highs.</p>

<p>But the institution remains beloved by Britons, and the malaise afflicting it is one of their primary concerns going into the country's general election on July 4.</p>

<p>Ibryanova has just seen her local doctor in Chelmsford, a London commuter town in Essex, southeast England, for an ear infection that has been causing her severe pain for months.</p>

<p>It has stopped her working and she needs an operation, quickly.</p>

<p>"I'm on a waiting list. I have to wait three or four months. That's long," she told AFP.</p>

<p>So she decided to go to Turkey, her home country, where she can receive treatment sooner.</p>

<p>"If you need operation, they are doing it like this," she said, snapping her fingers.</p>

<p><strong>- 'Broken' -</strong></p>

<p>Ibryanova is not alone. More than 7.5 million people in England were waiting for treatment in April, a new peak despite recent investment by the Conservative government.</p>

<p>A recent survey suggested that less than a quarter of Britons were satisfied with the NHS, an unprecedented level.</p>

<p>"We have to wait three weeks for a blood test. We often have to queue to buy medications when you can buy them," lamented 71-year-old retiree Christine Knight.</p>

<p>The crisis is particularly acute in south Essex, with one doctor for more than 2,300 patients at the end of last year, much worse than the national average, according to the Nuffield Trust health think-tank.</p>

<p>Two doctors' surgeries have closed in Chelmsford in recent years, explained Marie Goldman, the candidate for the Liberal Democrats party in the constituency, which has a sitting Conservative MP.</p>

<p>"What is left is a hole. It is so frustrating for people," Goldman added. Voters always asked her about the NHS, she said.</p>

<p>The opening ceremony of the 2012 London Olympic Games celebrated the health service as the "pride" of the UK, she pointed out. But today, she said, it's "broken".</p>

<p>Hospitals here are among the worst in the country for cancer care, with more than three-quarters of patients having to wait more than a month to start treatment once diagnosed.</p>

<p>The local health body declined to comment when contacted by AFP.</p>

<p>Bobby Jacobs, a 30-year-old construction worker, recently had hand surgery at the town's Broomfield Hospital.</p>

<p>He noted a lack of resources in a system that already relies heavily on caregivers from abroad.</p>

<p>"You can see on every nurse's face that they are so overworked and overstressed. They are working long hours. There is not enough of them," he told AFP.</p>

<p><strong>- Funding needed -</strong></p>

<p>Long and frequent strikes over pay and conditions, including a historic first walkout by nurses, have plagued the NHS over the past two years.</p>

<p>Low morale is leading professionals to leave the service or try to cut back on hours.</p>

<p>"It was not unusual to see 45 to 50 patients a day, sometimes more than that," said James Booth, a doctor for more than 20 years who quit one workplace to go part-time at another.</p>

<p>He cited an ageing population, less time with patients, and a shortage of staff.</p>

<p>"We're seeing worrying numbers of doctors, nurses and other professionals leaving early into their careers or not joining the NHS at all," said Billy Palmer, of the Nuffield Trust.</p>

<p>Booth noted that two private clinics have opened in Chelmsford in recent years and are doing "very well".</p>

<p>All parties, including Labour -- which is tipped to form the next government -- are promising to fix the NHS through massive recruitment, innovation and reorganisation.</p>

<p>Experts remain unconvinced, however, saying what the system really needs is a massive injection of cash currently not available.</p>

<p><br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/gnu2sdn8_rishi-sunak-afp_625x300_23_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Low morale is leading professionals to leave the service or try to cut back on hours.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/man-suffers-heart-attack-after-winning-rs-33-crore-jackpot-at-singapore-casino-5978835]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Man Suffers Heart Attack After Winning Rs 33 Crore Jackpot In Singapore]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/man-suffers-heart-attack-after-winning-rs-33-crore-jackpot-at-singapore-casino-5978835]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 27 Jun 2024 08:15:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[He was quickly rushed to the hospital where he is still recovering.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Panic ensued at a casino in Singapore after a man suffered a heart attack while celebrating his 3.2 million pound (Rs 33,76,45,600) jackpot. According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.news.com.au/finance/money/wealth/man-wins-6m-jackpot-at-marina-bay-sands-casino-in-singapore-collapses-immediately-after-suffering-heart-attack/news-story/17485409921ad4dc1744f3500166c1d1">news.com.au</a>, the incident happened&nbsp;at the Marina Bay Sands Casino in Singapore on June 22.&nbsp;The unnamed man, a regular visitor&nbsp;to the casino, was left overjoyed after he won the life-changing amount.&nbsp;As he was celebrating and punching the air in sheer joy., he suddenly fell to the ground having a cardiac arrest.&nbsp;</p>

<p>As he collapsed,&nbsp;horrified bystanders gathered around him as the staff rushed to help him. A woman accompanying the man became increasingly worried and was heard pleading with the staff as they tried to administer medical assistance. He was&nbsp;quickly rushed to the hospital where he is recovering from cardiac arrest.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, many social media reports suggested the man died, however, industry insiders said that the man is alive and still in recovery at the hospital.&nbsp;</p>

<p>A spokesperson for the casino condemned the false reporting, highlighting the distress it has caused the man's family. ''Unfortunately, the fake news has spread, and the video still circulating online is causing some distress to the guest's family,'' he said.&nbsp;Some sources&nbsp;have also disputed the amount that the gambler won, however, there is no official clarification of it yet.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The casino is owned and operated by Las Vegas Sands, a Nevada-based company pulling revenues of $10.4 billion last year.</p>

<p>In a similar incident in 2021, a man in Michigan in the US was found washed up dead on a beach with the winning ticket in his pocket.&nbsp;A similar unfortunate incident happened in the US in April after a man fell into cardiac arrest while sitting at a Las Vegas blackjack table.</p>

<p></p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/c86qh18_casino_625x300_27_June_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Marina Bay Sands Casino is owned and operated by Las Vegas Sands.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/musks-space-x-to-help-discard-nasas-international-space-station-by-2030-5978659]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Musk's Space X To Help Discard NASA's International Space Station By 2030]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/musks-space-x-to-help-discard-nasas-international-space-station-by-2030-5978659]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 27 Jun 2024 07:39:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[NASA on Tuesday said it had picked SpaceX to build a vessel to carry the International Space Station back through Earth's atmosphere and on to a final resting place in the Pacific Ocean after it is retired in 2030.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>NASA on Tuesday said it had picked SpaceX to build a vessel to carry the International Space Station back through Earth's atmosphere and on to a final resting place in the Pacific Ocean after it is retired in 2030.</p>

<p>Elon Musk's company has been awarded a contract with a potential value of $843 million to develop and deliver the spaceship, dubbed the US Deorbit Vehicle.</p>

<p>"Selecting a US Deorbit Vehicle for the International Space Station will help NASA and its international partners ensure a safe and responsible transition in low Earth orbit at the end of station operations," said NASA's Ken Bowersox in a statement.</p>

<p>NASA plans to take ownership of the spacecraft after SpaceX builds it, and control operations throughout the mission.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">We have selected <a href="https://twitter.com/SpaceX?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@SpaceX</a> to develop and deliver the U.S. Deorbit Vehicle and prepare for a safe and responsible deorbit of the <a href="https://twitter.com/Space_Station?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Space_Station</a> after the end of its operational life in 2030. Learn more: <a href="https://t.co/ogAhEazBpt">https://t.co/ogAhEazBpt</a> <a href="https://t.co/5pyBPfobkp">pic.twitter.com/5pyBPfobkp</a></p>
— NASA (@NASA) <a href="https://twitter.com/NASA/status/1806077416525185486?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 26, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Weighing 430,000 kilograms (950,000) pounds, the ISS is by far the largest single structure ever built in space.</p>

<p>Based on past observations of how other stations such as Mir and Skylab disintegrated on atmospheric re-entry, NASA engineers expect the orbital outpost to break up in three stages.</p>

<p>First, the massive solar arrays and the radiators that keep the orbital lab cool will come off, then individual modules will break off from the truss, or the station's backbone structure. Finally, the truss and the modules themselves will tear apart.</p>

<p>Much of the material will be vaporized, but large pieces are expected to survive. For this reason, NASA is aiming for an area of the Pacific Ocean called Point Nemo, one of the most remote areas of the world and known as the graveyard of satellites and spaceships.</p>

<p>The first segment of the ISS was launched in 1998, and it has been continuously inhabited by an international crew since 2001.</p>

<p>The US, Japan, Canada, and participating countries of the European Space Agency (ESA) have committed to operate the microgravity lab through 2030 -- though Russia, the fifth partner, has only committed to operations through 2028.</p>

<p>NASA chief Bill Nelson told Congress in April that given the dire state of US-Russia ties, it would be prudent to begin work on a US deorbit vehicle to "get the whole station down safely, so it won't hit anybody or anything."</p>

<p>Several companies are working on commercial successors to the ISS, including notably Axiom Space and Jeff Bezos' Blue Origin.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/aehc65pg_musk-space-x-reuters-_625x300_27_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Elon Musk's company has been awarded a contract of $843 million to develop and deliver the spaceship.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/australian-prime-minister-anthony-albanese-hails-julian-assanges-return-opposition-says-he-is-no-martyr-5978543]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Australian PM Hails Assange's Return, Opposition Says He Is "No Martyr"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/australian-prime-minister-anthony-albanese-hails-julian-assanges-return-opposition-says-he-is-no-martyr-5978543]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 27 Jun 2024 06:55:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Julian Assange spent his first night in 14 years as a free man back at home in Australia as the conservative opposition on Thursday cautioned the government against hailing the WikiLeaks founder as a hero.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Julian Assange spent his first night in 14 years as a free man back at home in Australia as the conservative opposition on Thursday cautioned the government against hailing the WikiLeaks founder as a hero.</p>

<p>Assange landed in Australia to an ecstatic welcome on Wednesday evening after spending more than five years in a British high-security jail and seven years in asylum at the Ecuadorean embassy in London.</p>

<p>He had battled extradition to Sweden on sexual assault allegations and to the U.S., where he faced 18 criminal charges tied to WikiLeaks' release in 2010 of hundreds of thousands of U.S. classified military documents and diplomatic cables.</p>

<p>Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese, who has been calling for Assange's release for several years, welcomed him home in a phone call saying he "had a very warm discussion" with Assange.</p>

<p>However, the conservative opposition raised concerns about portraying Assange as a hero after he spent more than a decade trying to avoid prosecution and then pleaded guilty to one criminal count of conspiring to obtain and disclose classified national defence documents.</p>

<p>The opposition leader in the Senate, Simon Birmingham, welcomed Assange's release but posted on X that "he's no martyr and was never a political prisoner denied access to justice."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">This call is neither necessary nor appropriate. Julian Assange was not wrongfully detained like Cheng Lei, Sean Turnell or Kylie Moore-Gilbert.<br />
<br />
For 12 years Assange chose to avoid facing justice in countries with fair judicial systems. He is underserving of this treatment. <a href="https://t.co/I8zDNFZ66V">https://t.co/I8zDNFZ66V</a></p>
— Simon Birmingham (@Birmo) <a href="https://twitter.com/Birmo/status/1805921152352788885?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 26, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>He cautioned Albanese against meeting Assange and said the release could strain Australia's ties with the United States, but that was rejected by Foreign Minister Penny Wong.</p>

<p>Wong told ABC Radio on Thursday that Assange's release posed no threat to Australia-U.S. ties.</p>

<p>James Paterson, the opposition's home affairs spokesperson, told Sky News Assange had evaded lawful extradition requests by hiding in the Ecuadorean embassy and used his legal rights in the UK to challenge it over many years.</p>

<p>"He is now someone who's pled guilty to very serious national security offences, which are not just offences against the United States. They're offences against the Five Eyes intelligence gathering alliance, including Australia," he said.</p>

<p>The U.S. State Department on Wednesday said its involvement in the resolution of Assange's case was very limited and reiterated its position that his actions had put lives at risk, although the U.S. judge who accepted his guilty plea said there had been no personal victim.</p>

<p>The White House was not in any way involved in the case, national security spokesman John Kirby said, adding it was a Department of Justice matter.</p>

<p>Assange's supporters and free speech advocates view him as a victim because he exposed U.S. wrongdoing and potential crimes, including in conflicts in Afghanistan and Iraq.</p>

<p>However, the U.S. government has long said his actions were reckless and by publishing the names of government sources he had put agents' lives at risk.</p>

<p>Assange has not spoken publicly since being released. His wife, Stella, said it was too soon to say what her husband would do next and requested privacy for him.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/98l2elo_assange-homecoming-reuters-_625x300_27_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Julian Assange landed in Australia to an ecstatic welcome on Wednesday evening.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russian-pranksters-release-hoax-video-call-with-uks-david-cameron-about-ukraine-5978477]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russian Pranksters Release Hoax Video Call With David Cameron About Ukraine]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russian-pranksters-release-hoax-video-call-with-uks-david-cameron-about-ukraine-5978477]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 27 Jun 2024 06:32:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russian pranksters who often target people the Russian state is interested in released footage on Wednesday of a video call with British Foreign Secretary David Cameron after tricking him into thinking he was speaking to a former Ukrainian president.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;Russian pranksters who often target people the Russian state is interested in released footage on Wednesday of a video call with British Foreign Secretary David Cameron after tricking him into thinking he was speaking to a former Ukrainian president.</p>

<p>London's Foreign Office said earlier this month that Cameron had held a video call with someone purporting to be former Ukrainian president Petro Poroshenko before realising he was the victim of a hoax.</p>

<p>The call, which appears to have lasted around 15 minutes and in which Cameron is shown talking on his mobile phone dressed casually somewhere outside, was carried out by Russian pranksters who use the aliases "Vovan and Lexus."</p>

<p>The duo is well-known inside Russia having duped a string of Western politicians over the years, including Italian Prime Minister Giorgia Meloni, Turkish President Recep Tayyip Erdogan, and, in 2022, then British defence minister Ben Wallace.</p>

<p>The Foreign Office said on Wednesday that the call looked like a Russian information operation designed to distract attention from Moscow's war in Ukraine. It did not answer a question about the video's authenticity.</p>

<p>Vovan and Lexus have in the past denied Western accusations that they have links to Russia's intelligence services, though they often ask their victims questions that would be of interest to the Russian state.</p>

<p>In Wednesday's video, the authenticity of which Reuters could not independently verify, Cameron is seen and heard talking about sensitive Ukraine-related topics.</p>

<p><strong>LOBBYING TRUMP</strong></p>

<p>In particular, he is heard talking about a private dinner he had with U.S. presidential candidate Donald Trump in April during which he lobbied Trump to allow Republicans to vote in favour of U.S. military aid for Ukraine.</p>

<p>Cameron is heard saying that the Republican party is split on Ukraine and that he had told Trump that he was wrong if he thought Putin just wanted Crimea and Donbas, two of five Ukrainian regions Moscow now says are part of Russia.</p>

<p>The Washington Post reported in April that Trump had privately spoken about the option of allowing Putin to keep Crimea and Donbas in return for peace, something Trump's campaign has not confirmed.</p>

<p>Cameron is heard saying such an idea is flawed.</p>

<p>"Trump is convinced there's a deal to be made and that's not the case because Putin wants so much more," says Cameron, adding that he thinks Trump, if he wins the presidency, will support the winning side on the battlefield and that is why this summer's fighting is so important.</p>

<p>Cameron is also heard saying Ukraine will not be invited to join the NATO military alliance at a summit next month because Washington is opposed to the idea. Cameron also says he does not think a potential French plan to send troops to Ukraine is the right approach because they would become a target for Putin.</p>

<p>In another segment, he is heard recounting a conversation with the foreign minister of Kazakhstan who he said had told him the Central Asian nation feared Russia "wanted a slice" of northern Kazakhstan where many ethnic Russians live.</p>

<p>A spokesperson for Britain's Foreign Office said in a statement:</p>

<p>"...We made public the fact that this call happened weeks ago, to do the right thing and make sure others were warned of the risk at the earliest opportunity. The Foreign Secretary understood this was a private call with a Ukrainian politician.</p>

<p>"This is clearly Russian, and is standard practice for information operations. Disinformation is a tactic straight from the Kremlin playbook to try to distract from their illegal activities in Ukraine and the human rights abuses being committed there."</p>

<p>Russia denies committing war crimes in Ukraine.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-04/hmf6fkm_david-cameron_625x300_12_April_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[In the call, David Cameron is shown talking on his mobile phone dressed casually somewhere outside.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-says-doesnt-want-war-but-warns-hezbollah-5978357]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Says Doesn't Want War But Warns Hezbollah]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-says-doesnt-want-war-but-warns-hezbollah-5978357]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 27 Jun 2024 05:56:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli Defense Minister Yoav Gallant said on a visit to Washington that his country does not want war in Lebanon but was ready to inflict "massive damage" on Hezbollah if diplomacy fails.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli Defense Minister Yoav Gallant said on a visit to Washington that his country does not want war in Lebanon but was ready to inflict "massive damage" on Hezbollah if diplomacy fails.</p>

<p>"We do not want war, but we are preparing for every scenario," Gallant told reporters during the visit that ended Wednesday.</p>

<p>"Hezbollah understands very well that we can inflict massive damage in Lebanon if a war is launched," he said.</p>

<p>Tensions have been rising, with growing skirmishes along the border between Israel and the Iranian-backed militia, since the October 7 attack by Hamas that prompted a relentless Israeli retaliatory campaign in Gaza.</p>

<p>Gallant said that Israel has killed more than 400 Hezbollah "terrorists" in recent months.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-10/g7dminco_yoav-gallant-_625x300_08_October_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israeli Defense Minister said that Israel has killed over 400 Hezbollah "terrorists" in recent months.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bolivias-army-general-arrested-for-coup-attempt-5978266]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bolivia's Army General Arrested For Coup Attempt]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bolivias-army-general-arrested-for-coup-attempt-5978266]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 27 Jun 2024 05:24:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Bolivian authorities arrested General Juan Jose Zuniga on Wednesday afternoon, a Reuters witness saw, hours after troops stormed into the presidential palace amid a military coup attempt.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bolivian authorities arrested General Juan Jose Zuniga on Wednesday afternoon, a Reuters witness saw, hours after troops stormed into the presidential palace amid a military coup attempt.</p>

<p>Bolivia's government and international leaders denounced</p>

<p>Bolivian armed forces pulled back from the presidential palace in La Paz on Wednesday evening and a general was arrested after President Luis Arce slammed a "coup" attempt against the government and called for international support.</p>

<p>Earlier in the day, military units led by General Juan Jose Zuniga, recently stripped of his military command, had gathered in the central Plaza Murillo square, home to the presidential palace and Congress. A Reuters witness saw an armored vehicle ram a door of the presidential palace and soldiers rush in.</p>

<p>"Today the country is facing an attempted coup d'état. Today the country faces once again interests so that democracy in Bolivia is cut short," Arce said in comments from the presidential palace, with armed soldiers outside.</p>

<p>"The Bolivian people are summoned today. We need the Bolivian people to organize and mobilize against the coup d'état in favor of democracy."</p>

<p>A few hours later, a Reuters witness saw soldiers withdraw from the square and police take control of the plaza. Bolivian authorities arrested Zuniga and took him away, though their destination was unclear.</p>

<p>Inside the presidential palace, Arce swore in José Wilson Sanchez as the military commander, Zuniga's former role. He called for calm and order to be restored.</p>

<p>"I order that all personnel mobilized on the streets return to their units," Sanchez said. "We entreat that the blood of our soldiers not be spilled."</p>

<p>The United States said it was closely monitoring the situation and urged calm and restraint.</p>

<p>Tensions have been building in Bolivia ahead of general elections in 2025, with leftist ex-President Evo Morales planning to run against former ally Arce, creating a major rift in the ruling socialist party and wider political uncertainty.</p>

<p>Many do not want a return of Morales, who governed from 2006-2019 when he was ousted amid widespread protests and replaced by an interim conservative government. Arce then won election in 2020.</p>

<p>Zuniga said recently that Morales should not be able to return as president and threatened to block him if he attempted to, which led Arce to remove Zuniga from his post.</p>

<p>Ahead of the attack on the presidential palace, Zuniga had addressed reporters in the square and cited growing anger in the landlocked country, which has been battling an economic slump with depleted central bank reserves and pressure on the boliviano currency as gas exports have dried up.</p>

<p>"The three chiefs of the armed forces have come to express our dismay," Zuniga told a local TV station, calling for a new cabinet of ministers.</p>

<p>"Stop destroying, stop impoverishing our country, stop humiliating our army," he said in full uniform, flanked by soldiers, insisting the action being taken was supported by the public.</p>

<p><strong>'STRONGEST CONDEMNATION'</strong></p>

<p>Morales, head of the ruling MAS socialist party, said that his supporters would mobilize in support of democracy.</p>

<p>"We will not allow the armed forces to violate democracy and intimidate people," Morales said.</p>

<p>Bolivia's public prosecutor's office said it would launch a criminal investigation against Zuniga and others involved in the attempted coup.</p>

<p>Public support for Arce and Bolivia's democracy has poured in from regional leaders and beyond.</p>

<p>"We express the strongest condemnation of the attempted coup d'état in Bolivia. Our total support and support for President Luis Alberto Arce Catacora," Mexican President Andres Manuel Lopez Obrador said on X.</p>

<p>Even conservative political opponents of the government in Bolivia condemned the military action, including ex-President Jeanine Anez, who was imprisoned in 2022 amid political turmoil.</p>

<p>"I fully reject of the mobilization of the military in the Plaza Murillo attempting to destroy constitutional order," she wrote on X. "The MAS with Arce and Evo must be got out through the vote in 2025. We Bolivians will defend democracy."</p>

<p>the attempted coup. It is unclear where Zuniga is being taken.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/2b05k12k_bolivia-coup-attempt_625x300_27_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Military police officers stand guard outside Quemado Palace at Plaza Murillo in La Paz on June 26, 2024.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-jails-honduran-ex-president-for-45-years-on-drug-trafficking-charges-5978213]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Jails Honduran Ex-President For 45 Years On Drug Trafficking Charges]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-jails-honduran-ex-president-for-45-years-on-drug-trafficking-charges-5978213]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 27 Jun 2024 05:08:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A court in New York on Wednesday sentenced former Honduran president Juan Orlando Hernandez to 45 years in prison after he was convicted of trafficking hundreds of tons of cocaine into the United States.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A court in New York on Wednesday sentenced former Honduran president Juan Orlando Hernandez to 45 years in prison after he was convicted of trafficking hundreds of tons of cocaine into the United States.</p>

<p>Anti-Hernandez protesters gathered outside the Manhattan courthouse ahead of sentencing brandishing placards decrying the former head of state's crimes with one declaring "Narco government -- makes the people emigrate."</p>

<p>"The role of Mr Hernandez was to use his political power as president of Congress and president of Honduras to limit the risks of drug traffickers in exchange of money," said Judge Kevin Castel as the disgraced statesman stood impassively.</p>

<p>He said Hernandez provided police and military support and helped to send 400 tons of drugs -- worth $10 billion at market prices -- to the United States.</p>

<p>In a speech ahead of sentencing, Hernandez, who wore prison garb and used a walking stick to enter court, was interrupted by the judge for contesting the trial's outcome and insisting he was wrongly charged.</p>

<p>The sentence, which also included an $8 million fine, was less than the life imprisonment that prosecutors had sought -- although Hernandez's age, 55, means he may die behind bars.</p>

<p>"He's going to pursue every single possible legal remedy that he can pursue," Hernandez's lawyer Renato Stabile told reporters outside court.</p>

<p><strong>- War on drugs -</strong></p>

<p>Hernandez, who US federal prosecutors said turned his Central American country into a "narco-state" during his 2014-2022 presidency, has previously indicated through his legal team he would appeal his conviction.</p>

<p>He was convicted in March of having facilitated the smuggling of hundreds of tons of cocaine -- mainly from Colombia and Venezuela -- to the United States via Honduras since 2004, starting long before he became president.</p>

<p>Hernandez used the drug money to enrich himself and finance his political campaign, and commit electoral fraud in the 2013 and 2017 elections, prosecutors said.</p>

<p>He had presented himself as a champion of the war on drugs and was initially seen by Washington as an ally in the fight.</p>

<p>In 2017, the United States was one of the first countries to recognize his re-election, while the opposition denounced fraud against a backdrop of violent protests that left some 30 people dead.</p>

<p>He was extradited to the United States in 2022 using a law he had himself helped to pass as Congress president under pressure from Washington, accused of aiding drug smugglers in return for millions of dollars in bribes.</p>

<p>US Attorney General Merrick Garland said Hernandez "abused his power to support one of the largest and most violent drug trafficking conspiracies in the world, and the people of Honduras and the United States bore the consequences."</p>

<p>The fall of Hernandez, who is known in his country as "JOH," was abrupt.</p>

<p>No sooner had he handed over power to the new left-wing president Xiomara Castro, the outgoing leader was shackled and paraded in front of journalists.</p>

<p>Hernandez follows in the footsteps of other former Latin American heads of state convicted in the United States, including Panama's Manuel Noriega in 1992 and Guatemala's Alfonso Portillo in 2014.</p>

<p>The short, athletic leader was known for his military haircut, having served as an officer before training as a lawyer, completing a masters degree in New York in 1995.</p>

<p>His legal woes began in earnest in 2018 when his brother, Juan Antonio Hernandez, was arrested in Miami and sentenced in March 2021 to life imprisonment for "large-scale" drug trafficking.</p>

<p>After his arrest in Honduras in February 2022, Hernandez said he was a victim of "revenge" by the drug lords, many of whom testified against him in New York.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2015-06/juan-orlando-hernandez_650x400_81434577361.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Juan Orlando Hernandez used the drug money to enrich himself and finance his political campaign.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korea-says-successfully-conducted-multiple-warhead-missile-test-5978154]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[North Korea Says Successfully Conducted Multiple-Warhead Missile Test]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korea-says-successfully-conducted-multiple-warhead-missile-test-5978154]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 27 Jun 2024 04:46:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[North Korea claimed to have successfully tested its multiple-warhead missile capability, according to state-run KCNA news agency Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>North Korea claimed to have successfully tested its multiple-warhead missile capability, according to state-run KCNA news agency Thursday.</p>

<p>Pyongyang "successfully conducted the separation and guidance control test of individual mobile warheads" on Wednesday," KCNA reported, adding that the "separated mobile warheads were guided correctly to the three coordinate targets."</p>

<p>"The test is aimed at securing the MIRV capability," it said, referring to multiple independently targetable reentry vehicle technology -- or, the ability to fire multiple warheads on a single ballistic missile.</p>

<p>The statement came a day after South Korea's military said the North had test-fired what appeared to be a hypersonic missile on Wednesday, but the launch ended in a mid-air explosion.</p>

<p>The missile took off from an area in or around Pyongyang at about 5:30 am (2030 GMT) and South Korean and US intelligence agencies were conducting a detailed analysis, Seoul's Joint Chiefs of Staff said in a statement.</p>

<p>The JCS official said the test of what appeared to be a hypersonic missile ended in failure after a journey of some 250 kilometres (155 miles).</p>

<p>More smoke than usual appeared to emanate from the missile, raising the possibility of combustion issues, the official said, adding it may have been powered by solid propellants.</p>

<p>Japan also confirmed the launch, with its coast guard saying the missile splashed down in the Sea of Japan, also known as the East Sea.</p>

<p>According to KCNA, the test "was carried out by use of the first-stage engine of an intermediate-range solid-fuel ballistic missile within a 170-200 km radius."</p>

<p>"The effectiveness of a decoy separated from the missile was also verified by anti-air radar," it said.</p>

<p>The test follows North Korea launching hundreds more trash-carrying balloons southward on Monday and Tuesday, the latest in a series of border barrages that have sparked a tit-for-tat propaganda campaign.</p>

<p>Late Wednesday, South Korea's military said the North has again floated another round of trash-carrying balloons southward for the third consecutive day, advising the public to report the balloons if spotted and refrain from touching them.</p>

<p>In response, Seoul has fully suspended a tension-reducing military deal and restarted some propaganda broadcasts from loudspeakers along the border.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, South Korea's Marine Corps resumed live-fire exercises on islands near the western inter-Korean border on Wednesday, marking the first such exercises since a 2018 tension-reducing military deal with the North was suspended earlier this month over the balloon-borne propaganda.</p>

<p>South Korea and the US also staged joint air drills Wednesday involving around 30 aircraft, including Washington's advanced stealth fighter jet, F-22 Raptor.</p>

<p>On Tuesday, President Yoon Suk Yeol visited a US aircraft carrier that arrived in South Korea at the weekend for joint military drills aimed at countering North Korean threats.</p>

<p>The drills, which include Japan, are set to go ahead later this month.</p>

<p>Pyongyang has routinely criticised such exercises as rehearsals for an invasion.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2016-06/north-korea-missile-afp-650_650x400_41466719050.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[This came a day after North Korea had test-fired what appeared to be a hypersonic missile on Wednesday.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>