<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Mon, 07 Oct 2024 04:17:32 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-calls-october-7-attack-glorious-ahead-of-anniversary-6731348]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hamas Calls October 7 Attack "Glorious" Ahead Of Anniversary]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-calls-october-7-attack-glorious-ahead-of-anniversary-6731348]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:12:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Palestinian group Hamas on Sunday praised its October 7 attack on Israel in a video message ahead of the first anniversary of the deadly storming of southern Israel which sparked the war in Gaza.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Palestinian group Hamas on Sunday praised its October 7 attack on Israel in a video message ahead of the first anniversary of the deadly storming of southern Israel which sparked the war in Gaza.</p>

<p>"The crossing of the glorious 7th of October shattered the illusions the enemy had created for itself, convincing the world and the region of its supposed superiority and capabilities," Qatar-based Hamas member Khalil al-Hayya said in a video statement.</p>

<p>Last year's October 7 attack resulted in the deaths of 1,205 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli official figures that include hostages killed in captivity.</p>

<p>At least 41,870 Palestinians, a majority of them civilians, have been killed in Israel's military campaign in the Gaza Strip since the war began, according to data provided by the health ministry in Hamas-run Gaza. The UN has acknowledged these figures as reliable.</p>

<p>Al-Hayya, said a year after the October 7 attack, "all of Palestine, particularly Gaza, and our Palestinian people are writing a new history with their resistance, blood, and steadfastness".</p>

<p>The Hamas member, who has emerged as the Islamist group's public face following the killing of its former leader Ismail Haniyeh in July, said Gazans had remained "resilient to all attempts at displacement... despite the kinds of torture and terrorism you have endured, and the horrific genocide and daily massacre".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-11/5dd8htho_hamas-attacks-israel_625x300_05_November_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Last year's October 7 attack resulted in the deaths of 1,205 people in Israel (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chinese-hackers-breached-us-court-wiretap-systems-report-6731225]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Chinese Hackers Breached US Court Wiretap Systems: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chinese-hackers-breached-us-court-wiretap-systems-report-6731225]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 06 Oct 2024 23:41:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Chinese hackers accessed the networks of US broadband providers and obtained information from systems the federal government uses for court-authorized wiretapping, the Wall Street Journal reported on Saturday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Chinese hackers accessed the networks of US broadband providers and obtained information from systems the federal government uses for court-authorized wiretapping, the Wall Street Journal reported on Saturday.</p>

<p>Verizon Communications, AT&amp;T and Lumen Technologies are among the telecoms companies whose networks were breached by the recently discovered intrusion, the newspaper said, citing people familiar with the matter.</p>

<p>The hackers might have held access for months to network infrastructure used by the companies to cooperate with court-authorized US requests for communications data, the Journal said. It said the hackers had also accessed other tranches of internet traffic.</p>

<p>China's foreign ministry responded on Sunday that it was not aware of the attack described in the report but said the United States had "concocted a false narrative" to "frame" China in the past.</p>

<p>"At a time when cybersecurity has become a common challenge for all countries around the world, this erroneous approach will only hinder the efforts of the international community to jointly address the challenge through dialogue and cooperation," the ministry said in a statement to Reuters.</p>

<p>Beijing has previously denied claims by the US government and others that it has used hackers to break into foreign computer systems.</p>

<p>Lumen Technologies declined to comment, while Verizon and AT&amp;T did not immediately respond to requests for comment.</p>

<p>The Journal said the attack was carried out by a Chinese hacking group with the aim of collecting intelligence. US investigators have dubbed it "Salt Typhoon."</p>

<p>Earlier this year, US law enforcement disrupted a major Chinese hacking group nicknamed "Flax Typhoon," months after confronting Beijing about sweeping cyber espionage under a campaign named "Volt Typhoon."</p>

<p>China's foreign ministry said in its statement that Beijing's cybersecurity agencies had found and published evidence to show Volt Typhoon was staged by "an international ransomware organization."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/el6jo8cg_us-china-generic_625x300_06_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[China responded on Sunday that it was not aware of the attack described in the report (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/flights-from-all-irans-airports-cancelled-until-tomorrow-morning-report-6731176]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Flights From All Iran's Airports Cancelled Until Tomorrow Morning: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/flights-from-all-irans-airports-cancelled-until-tomorrow-morning-report-6731176]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 06 Oct 2024 23:32:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Flights from all Iran's airports will be cancelled until 6 a.m. local time (0230 GMT) on Monday from 9 p.m. on Sunday, Iran's state media said, citing a spokesperson for Iran's Civil Aviation Organisation.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Flights from all Iran's airports will be cancelled until 6 a.m. local time (0230 GMT) on Monday from 9 p.m. on Sunday, Iran's state media said, citing a spokesperson for Iran's Civil Aviation Organisation.</p>

<p>The flights have been cancelled due to operational restrictions, state media cited the spokesperson as saying without providing further details.</p>

<p>Iran implemented restrictions on flights on Tuesday when it launched missiles at Israel, in an attack to which Israel vowed to respond.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/f4mjirv_iran-generic-afp_625x300_21_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The flights have reportedly been cancelled due to operational restrictions (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-deploys-more-troops-near-gaza-ahead-of-oct-7-attack-anniversary-6731132]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Deploys More Troops Near Gaza Ahead Of Oct 7 Attack Anniversary]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-deploys-more-troops-near-gaza-ahead-of-oct-7-attack-anniversary-6731132]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 06 Oct 2024 23:25:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Israeli military said Sunday it deployed more troops to defend southern communities and areas bordering Gaza, ahead of the anniversary of the October 7 attack by Hamas.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Israeli military said Sunday it deployed more troops to defend southern communities and areas bordering Gaza, ahead of the anniversary of the October 7 attack by Hamas.</p>

<p>"The IDF's (army) Gaza Division has been reinforced with several platoons, with forces stationed to defend both the communities and the border area," the military said.</p>

<p>"The soldiers are fully equipped to defend the region in coordination with local security forces," it said in a statement.</p>

<p>Inside Gaza, the military said three divisions were working to "dismantle terrorist infrastructure and degrade Hamas's capabilities".</p>

<p>"The Southern Command remains at a heightened state of vigilance and readiness for the coming days," commanding officer Major General Yaron Finkelman was quoted as saying.</p>

<p>Earlier, the military said its forces had surrounded the area of Jabaliya in central Gaza where Hamas was trying to rebuild its operational capabilities.</p>

<p>On October 7 last year, Hamas militants broke through the border from Gaza into Israel in what would become the deadliest attack in Israel's history.</p>

<p>At the end of the Jewish holiday of Sukkot, the militants launched their assault by land, air, and sea.</p>

<p>A year later, the confirmed death count from the attack, including hostages killed in captivity, has reached 1,205 on the Israeli side, most of them civilians, according to an AFP tally based on official Israeli figures.</p>

<p>Militants abducted 251 hostages, 97 of whom are still captive in Gaza, including 33 the Israeli military has said are dead.</p>

<p>Hours after the attack Israel launched a lightning military offensive on Gaza, which has reduced large swathes of the territory to rubble, and nearly all of the 2.4 million residents have been displaced at least once as a humanitarian crisis worsened.</p>

<p>Israel's relentless offensive on Gaza has so far killed at least 41,870 people, a majority of them civilians, according to the health ministry in the Hamas-run Palestinian territory.</p>

<p>The figures have been found to be reliable by the United Nations.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/8a6ntim8_israel-army-reuters_625x300_30_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[On October 7 last year, Hamas militants attacked Israel which triggered this war (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-gaza-war-gaza-mothers-struggle-to-care-for-newborns-say-wouldnt-have-given-birth-6731027]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Wouldn't Have Given Birth...": Gaza Mothers Struggle To Care For Newborns]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-gaza-war-gaza-mothers-struggle-to-care-for-newborns-say-wouldnt-have-given-birth-6731027]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 06 Oct 2024 23:07:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Gazan mother Rana Salah cradles her one-month-old daughter Milana in her arms in a sweltering tent for the displaced, and speaks of the guilt she feels for bringing her child into a world of war and suffering.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Gazan mother Rana Salah cradles her one-month-old daughter Milana in her arms in a sweltering tent for the displaced, and speaks of the guilt she feels for bringing her child into a world of war and suffering.</p>

<p>"If it were up to me, I wouldn't have gotten pregnant or given birth during the war because life is completely different; we've never lived this life before," she said, speaking at a camp in Deir al-Balah in the central Gaza Strip.</p>

<p>"I gave birth twice before, and life was better and easier for me and the child. Now, I feel like I've wronged both myself and the child because we deserve to live better than this."</p>

<p>Milana was born in a hospital tent by caesarean owing to complications with Salah's pregnancy. The family have not been able to return home due to the conflict, moving instead from one tent to another.</p>

<p>Milana is one of around 20,000 babies to have been born in Gaza in the last year, according to UNICEF statistics.</p>

<p>The current war, a particularly deadly episode in the decades-old Israeli-Palestinian conflict, was triggered on October 7, 2023, when Hamas militants attacked Israel, killing 1,200 people and taking about 250 hostages, according to Israeli tallies.</p>

<p>Israeli air and artillery strikes in response have reduced much of the Palestinian enclave to rubble and more than 41,500 Palestinians have been killed in the Israeli assault, according to the Gaza health ministry. Most of Gaza's 2.3 million residents have been displaced.</p>

<p><strong>INFECTION RISK</strong></p>

<p>Salah fans Milana with cardboard and says the heat is bad for the baby's skin.</p>

<p>"Instead of returning to our house, we keep moving from one tent to another... where diseases are widespread and the water is contaminated."</p>

<p>The World Health Organization (WHO) has said postnatal services have decreased significantly in Gaza, so women who have complications have less access to the care they need, as do their babies.</p>

<p>Rick Brennan, the WHO's Eastern Mediterranean Regional emergency director, said malnutrition was a threat to newborns, particularly if their mothers were unable to breastfeed, as there was no access to breast milk substitutes.</p>

<p>Displacement and being constantly on the move are disruptive for a newborn and expose them to risks of infection, he said.</p>

<p>Manar Abu Jarad is staying in a school shelter run by the UN Palestinian refugee agency (UNRWA). Her youngest daughter Sahar was born on Sept. 4th, also by caesarean section. Her husband was killed in the war.</p>

<p>On hearing she would need a caesarean for the birth, she worried about how she would care for her other children.</p>

<p>"I already have three girls. I started shouting... How can I carry (water) buckets? How can I bathe my daughters? How can I help them and my husband is not with me, he was martyred."</p>

<p>Children rock baby Sahar, who is swaddled in a crib, next to Jarad.</p>

<p>"I've reached the point where I cannot carry the responsibility for this girl ... Thank God I found some help here," she said. She has borrowed what she can from family and uses one diaper a day for the baby as she can't afford more.</p>

<p>"I don't have the money to provide diapers or milk for her."</p>

<p>Jarad longs for an end to the war and a return to her home, even if it is just a tent next to her former home.</p>

<p>"The important thing is to go home. Enough of all the exhaustion we are experiencing here, enough carrying buckets, enough of the dirt in the bathrooms. It's really, really hard and really tiring for us. Diseases are everywhere."<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/aur1vdk_gaza-babies_625x300_06_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel-Gaza war has been going on since October 7 last year]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/s-jaishankar-meets-maldives-president-mohamed-muizzu-says-appreciate-his-commitment-to-6730800]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Appreciate His Commitment To...": S Jaishankar Meets Maldives President]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/s-jaishankar-meets-maldives-president-mohamed-muizzu-says-appreciate-his-commitment-to-6730800]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 06 Oct 2024 22:22:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar on Sunday greeted Maldives President Mohamed Muizzu, who arrived in New Delhi for his first bilateral visit to India.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar on Sunday greeted Maldives President Mohamed Muizzu, who arrived in New Delhi for his first bilateral visit to India.</p>

<p>S Jaishankar expressed appreciation for Mr Muizzu's commitment to strengthening the India-Maldives relationship. He also expressed confidence that Mr Muizzu's talks with Prime Minister Narendra Modi will bring a new boost to their friendly ties.</p>

<p>Sharing pictures with Mr Muizzu, S Jaishankar on X wrote, "Pleased to call on President Mohamed Muizzu today at the start of his State Visit to India."</p>

<p>He added, "Appreciate his commitment to enhance India-Maldives relationship. Confident that his talks with PM Narendra Modi tomorrow will give a new impetus to our friendly ties."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Pleased to call on President <a href="https://twitter.com/MMuizzu?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@MMuizzu</a> today at the start of his State Visit to India.<br />
<br />
Appreciate his commitment to enhance ?? ?? relationship. Confident that his talks with PM <a href="https://twitter.com/narendramodi?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@narendramodi</a> tomorrow will give a new impetus to our friendly ties. <a href="https://t.co/UwDjnCZ0t6">pic.twitter.com/UwDjnCZ0t6</a></p>
— Dr. S. Jaishankar (@DrSJaishankar) <a href="https://twitter.com/DrSJaishankar/status/1842914260860760303?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 6, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>President Muizzu along with First Lady of Maldives, Sajidha Mohamed arrived in India on Sunday, for his first bilateral visit to India.</p>

<p>He was welcomed by Union Minister of State for External Affairs, Kiriti Vardhan Singh. Mr Muizzu's visit to India, from October 6-10, has come upon the official invitation of President Droupadi Murmu.</p>

<p>Ministry of External Affairs spokesperson, Randhir Jaiswal, announced the arrival of Maldives President in New Delhi. Sharing a post on X, he wrote, "A warm welcome to President Mohamed Muizzu of Maldives as he arrives in New Delhi on a State Visit to India."</p>

<p>"Received by MoS Kirti Vardhan Singh at the airport. The visit will provide further boost to this long-standing India-Maldives comprehensive bilateral partnership," the post further said.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">A warm welcome to President <a href="https://twitter.com/MMuizzu?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@MMuizzu</a> of Maldives as he arrives in New Delhi on a State Visit to India.<br />
<br />
Received by MoS <a href="https://twitter.com/KVSinghMPGonda?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@KVSinghMPGonda</a> at the airport.<br />
<br />
The visit will provide further boost to this long-standing ??-?? comprehensive bilateral partnership.<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/NeighbourhoodFirst?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#NeighbourhoodFirst</a> <a href="https://t.co/FHoNN4C0U3">pic.twitter.com/FHoNN4C0U3</a></p>
— Randhir Jaiswal (@MEAIndia) <a href="https://twitter.com/MEAIndia/status/1842894613499011237?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 6, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>During this visit, President Muizzu will hold meetings with President Droupadi Murmu, Prime Minister Narendra Modi and other senior officials.</p>

<p>Notably, this is Mr Muizzu's second visit to India this year after attending the swearing-in ceremony of Prime Minister Narendra Modi earlier this June.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/okgjncg_s-jaishankar-muizzu-_625x300_06_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[This is Mr Muizzu's second visit to India this year]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/teen-stabbed-50-times-then-burned-alive-in-france-6730744]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Teen "Stabbed 50 Times" Then Burned Alive In France]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/teen-stabbed-50-times-then-burned-alive-in-france-6730744]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 06 Oct 2024 22:11:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA["He was stabbed 50 times and taken to the Fonscolombes housing estate, where, according to the results of the autopsy, he was burned alive," said Bessone. His friend, also aged 15, was able to escape, Bessone added.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The southern French city of Marseille was this week shaken by two apparently drug-related killings, including the murder of a 15-year-old boy who was "stabbed 50 times" and burned alive, prosecutors said on Sunday.</p>

<p>Marseille, France's second-largest city but also one of its poorest, is plagued by drug-related violence.</p>

<p>The historic port city on the Mediterranean coast has in recent years witnessed a turf war for control of the highly profitable drug market between various clans including DZ Mafia and Yoda.</p>

<p>The problem was once again thrust into public eye this week, with Marseille prosecutor Nicolas Bessone telling a news conference on Sunday that victims and perpetrators of such violence were getting increasingly younger.</p>

<p>The 15-year-old teenager was murdered on Wednesday in a case Bessone described as one of "unprecedented savagery".</p>

<p>On Friday, a 36-year-old football player, Nessim Ramdane, was shot and killed "in cold blood" by a 14-year-old in a case linked to Wednesday's murder.</p>

<p>The two latest cases mean that the number of drug-related killings in Marseille has risen to 17 since the start of the year.</p>

<p>Marseille's drug lords have been recruiting foot soldiers with ads on social media, "outsourcing" street dealing to youngsters known as "jobbeurs".</p>

<p>Bessone said on Sunday that now young boys were responding to ads not only to sell cannabis resin but also to kill "without any remorse or reflection".</p>

<p>The teenager had been hired via social networks by a 23-year-old prisoner to intimidate a competitor by setting fire to his door, the prosecutor said, adding the youth had been promised 2,000 euros.</p>

<p>The detainee of the Luynes prison south of Aix-en-Provence had described himself as a member of DZ Mafia.</p>

<p><strong>Shot in the head</strong></p>

<p>During his mission, the teenager was spotted by members of a rival gang who searched him and discovered that he was carrying a gun. To punish the minor, they repeatedly stabbed him then set him on fire.</p>

<p>"He was stabbed 50 times and taken to the Fonscolombes housing estate, where, according to the results of the autopsy, he was burned alive," said Bessone. His friend, also aged 15, was able to escape, Bessone added.</p>

<p>The same prisoner then again turned to social media, recruiting a 14-year-old minor to carry out a revenge attack and kill a member of the Blacks gang, promising to pay him 50,000 euros.</p>

<p>The 14-year-old for his part hired Ramdane, a football player who also worked as a chauffeur to support his family, the prosecutor said.</p>

<p>The minor, accompanied by a friend, asked the driver "to drop them off and wait for them, but he apparently "didn't comply", Bessone said.</p>

<p>The teenager then "shot him in the back of the head", he added.</p>

<p>The minor was taken into custody and admitted shooting the driver, but insisted that the shot had "gone off accidentally".</p>

<p>In September, Franck Rastoul, public prosecutor at the Aix-en-Provence court of appeal, warned of the scourge of drug-related violence.</p>

<p>"It is imperative that we fully understand the ravages of drug trafficking, which undermines the very foundations of our society," he said.</p>

<p>Rastoul said young people were "intoxicated by easy drug money" to the point of "total disregard for human life."</p>

<p>Drug-related violence caused a record number of 49 deaths in Marseille last year.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-12/sg8ktf4g_france-police-generic_625x300_23_December_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The 15-year-old teenager was murdered on Wednesday (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/pontus-plate-long-lost-part-of-earth-believed-to-120-million-years-old-discovered-in-borneo-6730246]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Long-Lost Part Of Earth Believed To Be 120-Million-Year-Old Found In Borneo]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/pontus-plate-long-lost-part-of-earth-believed-to-120-million-years-old-discovered-in-borneo-6730246]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 06 Oct 2024 20:46:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Researchers have reconstructed the ancient Pontus plate, estimating it covered an area roughly one-quarter the size of the Pacific Ocean.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a groundbreaking discovery, experts have identified ancient remnants of a long-lost tectonic plate, dubbed Pontus, dating back an astonishing 120 million years. This finding sheds new light on Earth's history and underscores the ongoing quest for knowledge about our planet. According to<em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.indy100.com/science-tech/lost-earth-crust-northern-borneo-2669278686"> Indy100.com</a></em>, researchers Suzanna van de Lagemaat and Douwe van Hinsbergen from Utrecht University made the breakthrough by analysing geological data from the Asia-Pacific region. Their prediction has now been confirmed, revealing the existence of Pontus, a previously unknown part of Earth's crust in Borneo.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Geologist Suzanna van de Lagemaat said, "We thought we were dealing with relics of a lost plate that we already knew about. But our magnetic lab research on those rocks indicated that our finds were originally from much farther north, and had to be remnants of a different, previously unknown plate."</p>

<p>She continued, ''But our magnetic lab research on those rocks indicated that our finds were originally from much farther north, and had to be remnants of a different, previously unknown plate.''</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Press release!<a href="https://twitter.com/Suzannavdl?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Suzannavdl</a>'s PhD research yielded a nice surprise: the reconstruction of the Pontus Plate that we predicted 11 years ago based on tomography. And now it rolled out of her reconstruction ?.<a href="https://t.co/rNUOM8oazK">https://t.co/rNUOM8oazK</a><a href="https://twitter.com/UUGeo?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@UUGeo</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/UUEarthSciences?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@UUEarthSciences</a> <a href="https://t.co/3hXVeSx334">pic.twitter.com/3hXVeSx334</a></p>
— Douwe van Hinsbergen (@vanHinsbergen) <a href="https://twitter.com/vanHinsbergen/status/1711278537699676541?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 9, 2023</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>Researchers reconstructed the ancient Pontus plate, estimating it covered an area roughly one-quarter the size of the Pacific Ocean. Formed during the supercontinent Pangaea, Pontus lay beneath the vast ocean separating Eurasia and Australia 160 million years ago. As Pangaea broke apart, the Pontus plate was gradually subducted or swallowed by neighbouring plates. This geological process carried countries like the Philippines and Borneo to their present-day locations.</p>

<p>Notably, van de Lagemaat focussed her research on the intricate Junction Region, where tectonic plates converge between Japan, Borneo, the Philippines, New Guinea, and New Zealand. Her groundbreaking research enabled the creation of a stunning visual reconstruction.</p>

<p>This 3D clip revealed 160 million years of tectonic plate movements, from the dinosaur era to the present day.&nbsp;</p>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/fggkl61o_pontus-plate_625x300_06_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[This finding sheds new light on Earth's history]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/un-like-old-company-not-entirely-keeping-up-with-market-s-jaishankar-6729989]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["UN Like Old Company, Not Entirely Keeping Up With Market": S Jaishankar]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/un-like-old-company-not-entirely-keeping-up-with-market-s-jaishankar-6729989]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 06 Oct 2024 19:58:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar on Sunday took a critical view of the United Nations, saying it was "like an old company", not entirely keeping up with the market but occupying the space.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar on Sunday took a critical view of the United Nations, saying it was "like an old company", not entirely keeping up with the market but occupying the space.</p>

<p>During an interaction at the Kautilya Economic Conclave here, he also said that two very serious conflicts are going on in the world. "And where is the UN on them, essentially a bystander," the minister said.</p>

<p>In response to a query on the possible outcome of the US elections, he said the US actually has "made a shift", geopolitically and in its economic outlook, and irrespective of the outcomes in November, many of these trends will "intensify" in the days to come.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en"><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/WATCH?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#WATCH</a> | Delhi: At Kautilya Economic Conclave, EAM Dr S Jaishankar says "The United Nations is like an old company, not entirely keeping up with the market, but occupying the space...What you have today is, yes, there is a UN. At the end of the day, however suboptimal it is in… <a href="https://t.co/AFFTf9ScHo">pic.twitter.com/AFFTf9ScHo</a></p>
— ANI (@ANI) <a href="https://twitter.com/ANI/status/1842852176911372755?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 6, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>S Jaishankar took part in the interactive session on 'India and the Globe' and spoke of India's role and challenges amid changing global dynamics.</p>

<p>"So, we are both a lifting tide and a bit of paradoxical one, a ballast as well," S Jaishankar said as he enumerated some of the steps India has taken to help other countries, including its neighbours such as Sri Lanka.</p>

<p>Asked about his upcoming visit to Pakistan to attend a summit of the Shanghai Cooperation Organisation (SCO), he again sought to rule out any bilateral talks with his Pakistani counterpart.</p>

<p>"I am going there for a certain job, a certain responsibility. And, I take my responsibilities seriously. So, I am going there to represent India at the SCO meeting, and that is what I am going to do," S Jaishankar said.</p>

<p>At an event on Saturday, the external affairs minister said that he was going to Islamabad for a "multilateral event" and not to discuss India-Pakistan relations.</p>

<p>In his response to a query on the United Nations' role amid the changing global scenario, he took a rather critical view of the world body that was born in 1945 after the Second World War. Initially, it had 50 countries, which has grown over these years to nearly four times.</p>

<p>"The UN is in a way like an old company, not entirely keeping up with the market, but occupying the space. And, when it's behind times, in this world you have start-ups and innovations, so different people start doing their own things," S Jaishankar said.</p>

<p>"So, what you have today is that yes you have a UN at the end, however suboptimal in functioning, it is still the only multilateral game in town," he added.</p>

<p>"But, when it doesn't step up on key issues, countries figure out their own ways of doing it. For example, let's take the last five-10 years, probably the biggest thing that happened in our life was Covid. Now, what did the UN do on Covid? I think the answer is -- not very much," the minister said.</p>

<p>S Jaishankar said, "Now, you have two conflicts going on in the world today, two very serious conflicts, where is the UN on them, essentially a bystander," he said.</p>

<p>So, what is happening, as it did during Covid also, countries did their own thing such as the initiative like Covax that was done by a group of countries, the minister said. "When it comes to big issues of the day, you have an increasing combination of countries coming together to agree to do something." He cited the examples of connectivity initiatives like the India-MiddleEast-Europe Economic Corridor (IMEC), QUAD in Indo-Pacific to look after the global commons, the International Solar Alliance (ISA) and the Coalition for Disaster Resilient Infrastructure (CDRI), saying all these bodies came outside the UN framework.</p>

<p>"Today, the UN will continue, but increasingly there is a non-UN space which is the active space and I think it's telling on the UN," Jaishankar added.</p>

<p>More than 75 years after its inception, the United Nations is still working to maintain international peace and security, give humanitarian assistance to those in need, protect human rights, and uphold international law, according to the UN website.</p>

<p>India has been demanding reforms in the world body and its UN Security Council in sync with the changed times.</p>

<p>Earlier this year, S Jaishankar suggested that the "short-sighted" approach of the five permanent members of the UNSC is holding back forward movement in the long-pending reform of the global body.</p>

<p>The five permanent members are Russia, the UK, China, France and the US and these countries can veto any substantive resolution.</p>

<p>S Jaishankar was asked about a possible outcome of the US elections and how will India engage with the new administration.</p>

<p>"You spoke of one possibility of the two in the American elections. I stress to you, look back over the last five years, how many of the policies which in 2020 people thought were the Trump administration's policies actually not just carried over by Biden but they doubled down on those policies," he said.</p>

<p>So, this is not just a politician, it's not just a fashion, just one administration. "I think there are very deep shifts happening," the minister added.</p>

<p>"This is... America which actually has made a shift, geopolitically and in its economic outlook and has come to the conclusion that the order which itself devised many years ago no longer works to its benefit to that degree," he said.</p>

<p>"So, I would argue, irrespective of the outcomes in November, many of these trends will intensify in the days to come. And, you are going to get, I would call it a more fractured world, but I would say, in some ways, reliability and transparency are going to be two very key factors which will become a metric for countries to have enterprises and domains to have dealings with each other," he said.</p>

<p>On a question on the Global South, S Jaishankar said that it itself has a "great value".</p>

<p>"It is a collective. We don't expect to be the leader. We are seen as a trusted member, an articulate member... So, I am not really comfortable with the idea that you walk away from the Global South. On the contrary, I see value," the minister said.</p>

<p>He also spoke on the role and impact of artificial intelligence in shaping the world going forward.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/n2g27oq_s-jaishankar-ani_625x300_06_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[S Jaishankar was speaking on India's role and challenges amid changing global dynamics.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rockets-fired-from-gaza-cross-into-south-israel-6729786]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Rockets From Gaza Cross Into Israel Day Before Hamas Attack Anniversary]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rockets-fired-from-gaza-cross-into-south-israel-6729786]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 06 Oct 2024 19:19:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Israeli military said that rockets fired from northern Gaza crossed into southern Israel on Sunday, a day ahead of the first anniversary of Hamas's October 7 attack.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Israeli military said that rockets fired from northern Gaza crossed into southern Israel on Sunday, a day ahead of the first anniversary of Hamas's October 7 attack.</p>

<p>"Several projectiles were identified crossing from the northern Gaza Strip into Israeli territory. One projectile was intercepted, and the rest fell in open areas," the military said in a statement, with Israeli forces on alert for attacks ahead of the grim anniversary of Palestinian militants' unprecedented attack.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-10/6e8i71v_missile-generic_650x400_17_October_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israeli forces are on alert for attacks ahead of Hamas' Oct 7 attack anniversary (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/1-dead-10-injured-in-shooting-attack-in-southern-israel-cops-6729468]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Cop Dead, 10 Injured In Shooting Attack In Southern Israel: Cops]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/1-dead-10-injured-in-shooting-attack-in-southern-israel-cops-6729468]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 06 Oct 2024 18:18:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli police on Sunday said a female border officer was killed in a shooting attack on a bus station that first responders say injured 10 others.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli police on Sunday said a female border officer was killed in a shooting attack on a bus station that first responders say injured 10 others.</p>

<p>The incident took place a day before the first anniversary of the October 7 Hamas attack.</p>

<p>"Paramedics have pronounced a 25-year-old female deceased, and are evacuating 10 casualties," emergency service provider Magen David Adom said in a statement.</p>

<p>Police identified the victim as Sergeant Shira Haya Suslik, a member of the border police, and said she "fell during an encounter with a terrorist in an attack that occurred today at the central bus station in Beersheba."</p>

<p>Police said the incident was being treated as a "suspected terrorist attack".</p>

<p>"A number of injured on the scene. The terrorist was neutralised at the scene and many police forces of the southern district are at the scene," said a police spokesman in a statement.</p>

<p>Hamas praised the "heroic" attack, saying it "came in defence of our people, our land, and our holy sites".</p>

<p>The incident comes just days after a Hamas-claimed shooting attack last week in which seven people were killed in Israel's commercial hub of Tel Aviv.</p>

<p>The Tel Aviv attack -- one of the deadliest in the country since the October 7 Hamas attack -- came as Iran fired about 200 missiles at Israel, sending hundreds of thousands of people into public shelters.</p>

<p>Israel and Hamas have been at war in Gaza since the October 7 attack on Israel that resulted in the deaths of 1,205 people, most of them civilians, according to an AFP tally based on official Israeli figures.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory military campaign has killed at least 41,870 people in Gaza, the majority of them civilians, according to the Hamas-run territory's health ministry. The United Nations has said the figures are reliable.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/qp7q40s8_israel-shooting-beersheva_625x300_06_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A 25-year-old woman has been reportedly killed in the shooting incident.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/easyjet-flight-makes-emergency-landing-in-athens-after-passengers-brawl-mid-air-6728716]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[EasyJet Flight Makes Emergency Landing After Passengers Brawl Mid-Air]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/easyjet-flight-makes-emergency-landing-in-athens-after-passengers-brawl-mid-air-6728716]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 06 Oct 2024 15:59:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Despite cabin crew and passengers' efforts to calm the situation, the disruptive man refused to comply.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Chaos erupted on an easyJet flight from Turkey to London Gatwick after a reportedly intoxicated passenger caused a disturbance, prompting an emergency landing in Athens. According to <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://metro.co.uk/2024/10/05/easyjet-captain-pleads-drunk-passengers-midair-brawl-21741849/">Metro</a></em>, the topless man had been arguing with fellow travellers, leading the captain to issue a stern warning over the intercom.&nbsp;The captain was heard saying: "This is the captain speaking. To the people fighting, the police are waiting for you at the gate. You're only making things worse for yourself. Please sit down."</p>

<p>Despite cabin crew and passengers' efforts to calm the situation, the disruptive man refused to comply. Passengers grew increasingly frustrated, shouting insults at the delay. A woman exclaimed, "You've messed us all up, you silly fool!"</p>

<p>It is unclear what started the fight, but the original TikTok post was captioned: "POV your flight back from Turkey gets diverted to Athens because boys can't handle their drink."</p>

<p>Later, staff attempted to dress the man and guide him off the plane, but he continued to provoke others, including a passenger in a white jacket who sarcastically applauded the captain's announcement. As tensions escalated, the captain's warning proved ineffective, and the man was eventually escorted off the flight by authorities.</p>

<p>A spokesperson for EasyJet stated, ''Flight EZY8558 from Antalya to London Gatwick on 1 October diverted to Athens and was met by police after landing due to two passengers behaving disruptively onboard. easyJet's cabin crew are trained to assess and evaluate all situations and to act quickly and appropriately to ensure that the flight's and other passengers' safety is not compromised at any time. Whilst such incidents are rare, we take them very seriously and do not tolerate disruptive behaviour onboard. The safety and wellbeing of passengers and crew is always EasyJet's highest priority.''</p>

<p>The footage has elicited strong reactions from internet users, who called for severe consequences, including billing the disruptive passengers thousands of dollars for the diversion and imposing lifetime bans on flying. Others suggested prohibiting alcohol on flights, citing the excessive drinking culture among some travellers.</p>

<p>One user wrote, ''It's only a matter of time before they ban drinking because of people like these who can't handle their drink. Jail them and they may think twice.''&nbsp;Another commented, ''Why do Brits revolve their life around drink, drink, drink? This is what ends up happening. I'm not generalizing, but this is why alcohol is not the way.''</p>

<aside></aside>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2016-08/easyjet-flight_650x400_51472040707.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The footage has elicited strong reactions from internet users, who called for severe consequences.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/a-year-of-devastation-and-tonnes-of-rubble-to-deal-with-gazas-continued-struggle-6728537]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[A Year Of Devastation And Tonnes Of Rubble To Deal With, Gaza's Struggle]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/a-year-of-devastation-and-tonnes-of-rubble-to-deal-with-gazas-continued-struggle-6728537]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 06 Oct 2024 15:20:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United Nations estimates there is over 42 million tonnes of debris, including both shattered edifices that are still standing and flattened buildings.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In the ruins of his two-storey home, 11-year-old Mohammed gathers chunks of the fallen roof into a broken pail and pounds them into gravel which his father will use to make gravestones for victims of the Gaza war.</p>

<p>"We get the rubble not to build houses, no, but for tombstones and graves - from one misery to another," his father, former construction worker Jihad Shamali, 42, says as he cuts through metal salvaged from their home in the southern city of Khan Younis, damaged during an Israeli raid in April.</p>

<p>The work is hard, and at times grim. In March, the family built a tomb for one of Shamali's sons, Ismail, killed while running household errands.</p>

<p>But it is also a tiny part of the efforts starting to take shape to deal with the rubble left by Israel's military campaign to eliminate Palestinian militant group Hamas.</p>

<p>The United Nations estimates there is over 42 million tonnes of debris, including both shattered edifices that are still standing and flattened buildings.</p>

<p>That is 14 times the amount of rubble accumulated in Gaza between 2008 and the war's start a year ago, and over five times the amount left by the 2016-17 Battle of Mosul in Iraq, the U.N. said.</p>

<p>Piled up, it would fill the Great Pyramid of Giza - Egypt's largest - 11 times. And it is growing daily.</p>

<p>The U.N. is trying to help as Gazan authorities consider how to deal with the rubble, three U.N. officials said.</p>

<p>A U.N.-led Debris Management Working Group plans a pilot project with Palestinian authorities in Khan Younis and the central Gazan city of Deir El-Balah to start clearing roadside debris this month.</p>

<p>"The challenges are huge," said Alessandro Mrakic, the Gaza Office head for the United Nations' Development Programme (UNDP) which is co-chairing the working group. "It's going to be a massive operation, but at the same time, it's important that we start now."</p>

<p>Israel's military has said Hamas fighters hide among civilians and that it will strike them wherever they emerge, while also trying to avoid harming civilians.</p>

<p>Asked about the debris, Israel's military unit COGAT said it aimed to improve waste-handling and would work with the U.N. to expand those efforts. Mrakic said coordination with Israel was excellent but detailed discussions on future plans were yet to take place.</p>

<p>Tent Amid The Ruins</p>

<p>Israel began its offensive after Hamas militants entered Israel on Oct. 7 last year, killed about 1,200 Israelis and took over 250 people hostage.</p>

<p>Nearly 42,000 Palestinians have been killed in a year of conflict, Palestinian health authorities say.</p>

<p>On the ground, wreckage is piled high above pedestrians and donkey carts on dusty narrow paths that were once busy roads.</p>

<p>"Who is going to come here and clear the rubble for us? No-one. Therefore, we did that ourselves," taxi driver Yusri Abu Shabab said, having cleared enough debris from his Khan Younis home to erect a tent.</p>

<p>Two-thirds of Gaza's pre-war structures - over 163,000 buildings - have been damaged or flattened, according to U.N. satellite data. Around a third were high-rise buildings.</p>

<p>After a seven-week war in Gaza in 2014, UNDP and its partners cleared 3 million tonnes of debris - 7% of the total now. Mrakic cited an unpublished preliminary estimate that it would cost $280 million to clear 10 million tonnes, implying around $1.2 billion if the war stopped now.</p>

<p>A U.N. estimate from April suggested it would take 14 years to clear the rubble.</p>

<p>Concealed Bodies</p>

<p>The debris contains unrecovered bodies, as many as 10,000 according to the Palestinian health ministry, and unexploded bombs, Mrakic said.</p>

<p>The International Committee of the Red Cross says the threat is "pervasive" and U.N. officials say some of the debris poses a big injury risk.</p>

<p>Nizar Zurub, from Khan Younis, lives with his son in a home where only a roof remains, hanging at a precarious angle.</p>

<p>The United Nations Environment Programme said an estimated 2.3 million tonnes of debris might be contaminated, citing an assessment of Gaza's eight refugee camps, some of which have been hit.</p>

<p>Asbestos fibres can cause larynx, ovarian and lung cancer when inhaled.</p>

<p>The World Health Organization has recorded nearly a million cases of acute respiratory infections in Gaza in the past year, without saying how many are linked to dust.</p>

<p>WHO spokesperson Bisma Akbar said dust was a "significant concern", and could contaminate water and soil and lead to lung disease.</p>

<p>Doctors fear a rise in cancers and birth defects from leaking metals in coming decades. Snake and scorpion bites and skin infections from sandflies are a concern, a UNEP spokesperson said.</p>

<p>Land And Equipment Shortages</p>

<p>Gaza's rubble has previously been used to help build seaports. The U.N. hopes now to recycle a portion for road networks and bolstering the shoreline.</p>

<p>Gaza, which had a pre-war population of 2.3 million crammed into an area 45 km (28 miles) long and 10 km wide, lacks the space needed for disposal, the UNDP says.</p>

<p>Landfills are now in an Israeli military zone. Israel's COGAT said they were in a restricted area but that access would be granted.</p>

<p>More recycling means more money to fund equipment such as industrial crushers, Mrakic said. They would have to enter via crossing points controlled by Israel.</p>

<p>Government officials report fuel and machinery shortages because of Israeli restrictions that slow clear-up efforts. The UNEP spokesperson said prolonged approval processes were a "major bottleneck".</p>

<p>Israel did not specifically comment on allegations it was restricting machinery.</p>

<p>The UNEP says it needs owners' permission to remove debris, yet the scale of destruction has blurred property boundaries, and some property records have been lost during the war.</p>

<p>Several donors have expressed interest in helping since a Palestinian government-hosted meeting in the West Bank on Aug. 12, Mrakic said, without naming them.</p>

<p>A U.N. official, requesting anonymity to avoid undermining ongoing efforts, said: "Everybody's concerned whether to invest in rebuilding Gaza if there is no political solution in place."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/bm36f4ng_israel-hamas-war-gaza-rubble_625x300_06_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Piled up, rubble in Gaza would fill the Great Pyramid of Giza - Egypt's largest - 11 times.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-airstrike-on-mosque-in-gaza-kills-26-6728447]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israeli Airstrike On Mosque In Gaza Kills 26]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-airstrike-on-mosque-in-gaza-kills-26-6728447]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 06 Oct 2024 15:01:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The health ministry in Hamas-run Gaza said on Sunday an Israeli strike on a mosque-turned-shelter in central Deir al-Balah killed 26 people, while Israel's military said it had targeted Hamas militants.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The health ministry in Hamas-run Gaza said on Sunday an Israeli strike on a mosque-turned-shelter in central Deir al-Balah killed 26 people, while Israel's military said it had targeted Hamas militants.</p>

<p>"The number of martyrs brought to hospitals as a result of the occupation's targeting of displaced people in the Ibn Rushd school and Al Aqsa Martyrs mosque reached 26, with several more wounded," the health ministry said in a statement.</p>

<p>The Gaza civil defence agency had earlier said 21 people had been killed in the pre-dawn strike in central Gaza's Deir El-Balah area.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said in a statement that it had "conducted a precise strike on Hamas terrorists who were operating within a command and control centre" at the mosque. It did not give any specific toll.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/i78fm3ko_israeli-airstrike-on-mosque_625x300_06_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Palestinian women react upon identifying the bodies of victims of an Israeli strike on mosque.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/frances-golden-owl-treasure-hunt-ends-after-31-years-6728408]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Three-decade Long Treasure Hunt For 'Golden Owl' Finally Over]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/frances-golden-owl-treasure-hunt-ends-after-31-years-6728408]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 06 Oct 2024 14:56:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 31-year-long treasure hunt that attracted thousands of enthusiasts across France has come to an end.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 31-year-long treasure hunt that attracted thousands of enthusiasts across France has come to an end.&nbsp;The hunt, called “On the Trail of the Golden Owl,” was based on a book of riddles published in 1993. Participants had to solve 11 puzzles in the book, along with a 12th hidden puzzle, to discover the exact location of the replica of the golden owl.&nbsp;The official website of the search announced on Thursday that the token needed to claim the grand prize had been found.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The hunt's <a href="https://goldenowlhunt.com/the-golden-owl-is-won-after-31-years/">official chat line</a> announced, "We confirm that the replica of the golden owl was dug up last night and that simultaneously a solution has been sent on the online verification system."</p>

<p>The book, published in 1993 by author Regis Hauser and artist Michel Becker, gained a cult-like following with over 2 lakh players, known as ‘owlers,' from France and beyond, according to the hunt's official website. In a documentary posted on YouTube, Mr Becker mentioned that he oversaw and financed the creation of the prize, which is an owl made of 3 kg of gold and 7 kg of silver with diamond chips on its face.</p>

<p>Regis Hauser, the riddle maker, initially used the pen name Max Valentin to prevent the most determined treasure hunters from seeking him out. He died in 2009, French newspaper Le Monde reported.</p>

<p>According to a 2021 documentary, the concept was inspired by The Masquerade, a 1979 book of riddles by Kit Williams, where hunters also had to solve several puzzles to find a golden rabbit.</p>

<p>The writer of the treasure search was Michel Becker, a French artist who illustrated "Sur la Trace de la Chouette d'Or" ("On the Trail of the Golden Owl"), a picture book published in 1993, and sculpted the gold-and-silver owl promised to whoever could first solve the clues hidden in its pages. He and Hauser decided to bury a replica of the owl while keeping the valuable original in a safe place. Its value is estimated at £126,000 (Rs 1.39 crore), fans of the treasure hunt have said online.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the world's longest-running treasure hunt is believed to be The Secret, by Byron Preiss, published in 1982. It involves a search for 12 boxes of treasure buried at secret locations in the US and Canada, of which only three have been found.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/ah1ls0p8_golden-owl-treasure-hunt_625x300_06_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The book, published in 1993, gained a cult-like following.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/keep-praying-and-be-your-beautiful-self-british-hostage-s-mother-writes-to-daughter-held-in-gaza-6721579]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["I Promise...": UK Woman Writes Letter To Daughter Held By Hamas In Gaza]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/keep-praying-and-be-your-beautiful-self-british-hostage-s-mother-writes-to-daughter-held-in-gaza-6721579]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 06 Oct 2024 14:39:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The mother of a British woman, who was among those taken hostage by Hamas on October 7, has written a heartfelt letter to her daughter and urged UK Prime Minister Keir Starmer to ensure it's delivered in Gaza.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The mother of a British woman, who was among those taken hostage by Hamas on October 7, has written a heartfelt letter to her daughter and urged UK Prime Minister Keir Starmer to ensure it's delivered in Gaza. Emily Damari, 28, is a British-Israeli dual citizen and was taken hostage from her home in Kibbutz Kfar Aza, near the Gaza border, where she was born and raised, <a href="https://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-13926257/mother-missing-British-hostage-hamas-Gaza-letter-daughter.html">Daily Mail </a>reported.</p>

<p>Mandy Damari, Emily's mother, travelled to Downing Street earlier this week and handed over the note for her daughter to Mr Starmer. She also urged the UK government to do more to bring Emily back home.</p>

<p>"It is breaking my heart a little more, day by day... Soon there will be nothing left of my heart - or Emily," Mandy, 63, was quoted as saying by the news outlet.</p>

<p>She said that most of the British people were still unaware that a UK citizen was still held hostage in Gaza. Hence, she urged Starmer to mention her daughter whenever the UK government talks about the hostages.</p>

<p>Requesting Starmer to use &nbsp;"every ounce of his influence" to get Emily back, Mandy said, "Diplomatic pressure, negotiations, humanitarian efforts — whatever it takes... We cannot let another day pass."</p>

<p>She said that the country can't afford to lose any more lives to the nightmare, adding, "We don't need tea and sympathy, we need actions, not words."</p>

<p><strong>Here's Mandy's heartfelt letter for her daughter:</strong></p>

<p>"Dear Emily,</p>

<p>I hope this note gets to you when you are alive and home with me, abba and all your family. And you'll see that we are all alive.</p>

<p>If it gets to you in Gaza know that we all love you and miss you and are sick with worry about what is happening to you every day and we are praying and meeting whoever we can to get you back home.</p>

<p>Please keep strong, keep praying and just be your beautiful self that I love to the moon and back. You will come home. And I promise that I'll never complain again about your perfume sticking to me when you're home.</p>

<p>Love you so much</p>

<p>Your Mum (who is always right!)"</p>

<p>In January this year, Dafna Elyakim, a released hostage, said in an interview with an Israeli TV channel that she and her sister were taken into underground tunnels by the Hamas militants where they met five other hostages. Besides Emily Damari, the other four mentioned by her are Liri Albag, Naama Levy, Romy Gonen and Agam Berger.</p>

<p>It is believed that Emily, kidnapped alongside twin brothers Ziv and Gali Berman, is still somewhere in the Gaza Strip, held hostage inside a deep underground tunnel. On Monday, it will be a year since the October 7 attack by Hamas militants in southern Israeli communities, killing at least 1,200 people and kidnapping over 250 others.</p>

<p>The report further said that Emily's beloved dog Choocha, a golden cockapoo, was shot dead by the Hamas militants in her arms, while she too suffered a gunshot wound to the hand.</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/udsulgho_emily-damari-_625x300_06_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[It is believed that Emily is still in the Gaza Strip.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/pan-pacific-orchard-hotel-this-singapore-hotel-has-been-named-as-worlds-new-best-skyscraper-6728187]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[This Singapore Hotel Has Been Named As World's New Best Skyscraper]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/pan-pacific-orchard-hotel-this-singapore-hotel-has-been-named-as-worlds-new-best-skyscraper-6728187]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 06 Oct 2024 14:23:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Singapore's Pan Pacific Orchard hotel has been crowned the world's best new skyscraper, as recognised by The Council on Tall Buildings and Urban Habitat (CTBUH).]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Singapore's Pan Pacific Orchard hotel has been crowned the world's best new skyscraper, as recognised by The Council on Tall Buildings and Urban Habitat (CTBUH). The 23-storey, 140-metre-tall structure located in the heart of Singapore's iconic shopping district opened in June 2023 and has quickly gained global recognition.</p>

<p>The hotel, designed by Woha Architects, also won three other prestigious awards, including “Best Tall Building” in the 100m-199m category. The CTBUH, an esteemed global authority on skyscrapers, announced the awards during its recent conference held from September 23-27 across London and Paris.&nbsp;</p>

<p>CTBUH CEO, Javier Quintana de Una, praised Pan Pacific Orchard, saying that the hotel “represents the best of responsible vertical urbanism today,” as per the <a href="https://www.straitstimes.com/singapore/singapore-s-pan-pacific-orchard-hotel-crowned-world-s-best-new-skyscraper">Straits Times</a>. Vertical urbanism is a concept that promotes the sustainable use of urban spaces by building upwards, maximising land use while incorporating greenery into the design.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Pan Pacific Orchard is celebrated for integrating eco-friendly elements into its design. It features solar panels, rainwater harvesting for irrigation and an on-site biodigester to manage food waste. The hotel's lush greenery mirrors Singapore's focus on sustainable development, with high trees, gardens, and pools enveloping the guest experience. It achieved a green plot ratio of over 300 per cent, meaning it has more than three times the landscaped surface area of its footprint.</p>

<p>The hotel is divided into four distinct environments: the Forest Terrace, Beach Terrace, Garden Terrace and Cloud Terrace. Each zone offers unique experiences, from a high-ceiling lobby with towering trees to a sandy beachfront and meandering pools. The Cloud Terrace hosts a pillarless ballroom, one of the highest in Singapore, ideal for exclusive events.</p>

<p>This recognition further strengthens Woha Architects' standing, following past accolades for projects like Kampung Admiralty and Oasia Hotel Downtown. The Pan Pacific Orchard hotel also earned Singapore's Green Mark Platinum award – the nation's highest environmental certification – in 2020.&nbsp;</p>

<p>At the same CTBUH event, other Asian skyscrapers also received recognition. Malaysia's Petronas Towers won the Global Icon award, while China's Greenland Hangzhou Century Centre was named Asia's best tall building.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/tn4g2oog_pan-pacific-orchard-sinagpore-facebook_625x300_06_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Pan Pacific Orchard is celebrated for integrating eco-friendly elements into its design.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-man-brandon-barnes-kills-wife-jessica-barnes-dumps-body-in-forest-with-roommates-help-police-6728090]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Man Kills Wife, Dumps Body In Forest With Roommates' Help: Police]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-man-brandon-barnes-kills-wife-jessica-barnes-dumps-body-in-forest-with-roommates-help-police-6728090]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 06 Oct 2024 14:00:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 21-year-old man has been arrested and charged with the murder of his 20-year-old wife who disappeared from their home in Pendleton, South Carolina, on August 1.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 21-year-old man has been arrested and charged with the murder of his 20-year-old wife who disappeared from their home in Pendleton, South Carolina, on August 1. Brandon Barnes was arrested and charged with one count of murder in connection to the death of his wife, Jessica Barnes, reported <a href="https://www.wyff4.com/article/missing-woman-pendleton-jessica-barnes-home-search/62300209 ">WYFF4</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to authorities, Brandon allegedly enlisted the help of their two roommates, Kendall Mims and Victoria Tippett, in moving Jessica's body after her death. They were charged with “accessory after the fact, Obstruction of Justice and Misprision of a Felony.”</p>

<p>Jessica Barnes was last seen on August 1 at her home in Pendleton, South Carolina, which she shared with her husband, Brandon, and two roommates, Mims and Tippett.&nbsp;</p>

<p>She was not reported missing until September 10, when her mother, Cecilia Varvara, contacted the Pendleton Police Department. Her body was discovered kilometres away in a woody area near Twin Lakes in Pickens County on September 20.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Pickens County Coroner's Office determined the cause of death to be “asphyxiation by strangulation”.&nbsp;</p>

<p>During a press conference on Wednesday, Pendleton Police Chief Robert Crosby said, "Details surrounding the disappearance were vague and material and personnel from the South Carolina Law Enforcement Division (SLED) were required and needed for this continued investigation."</p>

<p>Chief Crosby confirmed that Jessica Barnes' mother had claimed several times that she received text messages from an account in Jessica's name after her disappearance, but she didn't believe they were sent by her daughter. On September 20, police searched the home where the couple lived with their roommates, the <a href="https://nypost.com/2024/10/05/us-news/south-carolina-wife-jessica-barnes-allegedly-murdered-by-husband-brandon-and-two-roommates/ ">NY Post</a> reported.</p>

<p>Pendleton Police collected "clues, articles of clothing and electronic devices" from the residence. Their investigation also led police to the car of one of the couple's roommates at a location regularly visited by both Jessica and Brandon Barnes. Phone records allegedly showed that Brandon Barnes had driven the vehicle to the location, though it wasn't immediately clear which roommate's car the police traced.</p>

<p>During their investigation, authorities discovered remains in nearby Pickens County, which were not immediately identified, according to a statement from Pendleton Police this week. On October 1, a Pickens County coroner confirmed that the remains belonged to Jessica.</p>

<p>After the remains were found, Pendleton Police, along with SLED, interviewed Jessica's husband, Brandon Barnes, and the couple's two roommates, Kendall Mims and Victoria Tippett, according to an official statement. Following these interviews, police charged the three with several offences including a murder charge for Brandon. Both women allegedly confessed to their involvement, according to their affidavits.</p>

<p>Victoria Tippett is also accused of failing to report a crime, despite "witnessing" the killing and having several opportunities to inform the police, as outlined in the affidavits. Police further alleged that Mims failed to report the crime, even though she had been told about the killing.</p>

<p>"There were some issues with her and her husband. They were having the typical marital disputes, argumentative, and then, she just left,” Chief Crosby said earlier.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/fnn3m0c8_jessica-barnes_625x300_06_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Jessica Barnes was last seen on August 1 at her home in Pendleton.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/1-000-year-old-seed-revived-in-israeli-desert-grows-into-10-foot-tree-6727925]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[1,000-Year-Old Seed Revived In Israeli Desert, Grows Into 10-Foot Tree]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/1-000-year-old-seed-revived-in-israeli-desert-grows-into-10-foot-tree-6727925]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 06 Oct 2024 13:28:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The tree, linked to Biblical times, shows medicinal properties, including anti-cancer compounds. ]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An ancient 1,000-year-old seed has grown into a tree named "Sheba" in Israel. The tree, linked to Biblical times, shows medicinal properties, including anti-cancer compounds. Scientists believe it could be linked to historical resins mentioned in religious texts.</p>

<p>This remarkable development began when archaeologists unearthed the pristine seed in the 1980s. Years later, Dr Sarah Sallon, from the Louis L Borick Natural Medicine Research Centre in Jerusalem, initiated a study to plant the seed, which was remarkably dated to be 1,000 years old.&nbsp;</p>

<p>To the researchers' surprise, a tiny shoot emerged just five weeks after planting, leading scientists to identify the tree as part of the Commiphora genus, although its exact species remains unknown and is likely extinct.</p>

<p>Now it has grown into a 10-feet-tall tree. Despite thriving in height, the tree has yet to flower or produce fruit. Researchers believe it could be linked to a healing plant mentioned in the Bible. This project is part of a broader effort to bring back extinct species, like the woolly mammoth and dodo, using hybrid techniques.</p>

<p>Beyond plants, scientists are also studying ancient DNA for new drugs and insights into genetic diversity, which could benefit modern medicine. These efforts show how exploring the past can help us understand and improve our future.</p>

<p>In parallel, Mount Everest is rising more rapidly than previously thought, growing at a rate of about 0.08 inches (2 millimetres) per year due to geological processes dating back millions of years. A recent phenomenon known as “river piracy” is contributing to this unexpected growth.</p>

<p>In Denmark, archaeologists found a Viking-era burial ground with over 50 well-preserved skeletons, including a woman buried in a wagon. They plan to extract DNA from the remains to learn more about the people buried there.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the northern bald ibis population has rebounded thanks to dedicated efforts, growing from just 59 pairs in the 1990s to over 500 today. Other reintroduction programs, including teaching zoo-raised ibises their migration routes using ultralight aircraft, have helped these distinctive birds return to Europe for the first time since the 1600s.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/jucsq52o_tree-from-ancient-seed_625x300_06_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[An ancient 1,000-year-old seed has grown into a tree named "Sheba" in Israel. (Representational Image)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/dog-saves-injured-owner-84-by-leading-cop-to-her-home-in-us-6727762]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["True Hero": Dog Saves Injured Owner, 84, By Leading Cop To Her Home In US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/dog-saves-injured-owner-84-by-leading-cop-to-her-home-in-us-6727762]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 06 Oct 2024 13:03:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The dog, named Gita, was first seen sitting in the middle of the road in a remote wooded area in Washington's Stevens County by a deputy.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A loyal rescue dog named Gita has been hailed as a "hero" after she saved&nbsp;her 84-year-old owner's life by guiding an officer to his location following a severe fall in the woods. The incident occurred on September 25, when Deputy Dean Jones of the Stevens County Sheriff's Office found Gita sitting in the middle of a remote wooded road.</p>

<p>The deputy tried to get Gita into his vehicle, but she refused to go in. Deputy Jones searched nearby homes but couldn't find the dog's owner. Growing worried, Jones returned to Gita, lying on the road's centerline, said the Sheriff's Office.</p>

<p><iframe allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="true" frameborder="0" height="250" scrolling="no" src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/post.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2Fstevenscountysheriff%2Fposts%2Fpfbid0m3KKRvaeJ2zacE9j1BE5xwByYhYro3m7LwrRGXm5YRBpyFs3ErsTHpQQc2DbA5RJl&amp;show_text=true&amp;width=500" style="border:none;overflow:hidden" width="500"></iframe></p>

<p>When Jones tried to move Gita to safety, she darted down a nearby unmarked path. The deputy followed her, and she eventually led him to a small summer cabin. Near the cabin, Jones heard an elderly man's faint voice calling for help. The 84-year-old man had fallen hours earlier, injuring his leg and unable to take his medication.</p>

<p>He had fallen and injured his leg, which could have led to serious consequences if he wasn't found. Authorities added that he had been injured for three hours and also had other medical conditions that required attention.</p>

<p>“It turns out the dog, Gita, is a 13-year-old rescue dog and best friend of the gentleman in trouble,” said the Sheriff's Office. “We credit Gita for saving his life that day. The loyalty and heroism of our furry friends never cease to amaze us,”&nbsp; the Sheriff's Office added. The sheriff's office did not provide details about how Gita's owner was treated or where he was taken. "Thank you Gita for being a good girl and true hero," the statement concluded.</p>

<p>This comes four months after another dog ran six kilometres to find help for his owner, who had crashed his car into a ravine in Oregon. That owner was eventually rescued.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/2qvenptg_dog-saves-injures-owner_625x300_06_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The cop found the dog, Gita, sitting in the middle of a remote wooded road.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>