<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Sep 2024 13:19:12 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-to-soon-top-china-among-emerging-global-markets-morgan-stanley-6495638]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India To Soon Top China Among Emerging Global Markets: Morgan Stanley]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-to-soon-top-china-among-emerging-global-markets-morgan-stanley-6495638]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Sep 2024 13:22:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India is likely to soon overtake China as the most influential in a key emerging markets index, pulling in more foreign funds and adding fuel to a stock market rally that is "only past the halfway mark", Morgan Stanley said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India is likely to soon overtake China as the most influential in a key emerging markets index, pulling in more foreign funds and adding fuel to a stock market rally that, though already among the best globally, is "only past the halfway mark", Morgan Stanley said.</p>

<p>India's weightage in the MSCI emerging markets index rose to 19.8% after a rejig in August, closing in on China's 24.2%. India's weightage has steadily increased from 9.2% in December 2020, while China's has dropped from 39.1%.</p>

<p>"A rising weight essentially means more absolute foreign flows," analysts led by Ridham Desai said in a note on Wednesday.</p>

<p>"In the context of India being underweight in the average emerging markets portfolio, this is even better for foreign portfolio flows."</p>

<p>Foreign portfolio investors (FPIs) have bought shares worth 531.78 billion rupees ($6.33 billion) so far in 2024, and have remained net buyers since June, bolstered by policy continuity after the country's elections and an imminent start to global interest rate cuts.</p>

<p>So far, the sustained inflows from domestic institutional investors, mutual funds and retail traders have helped power the benchmark Nifty 50 to record highs. Its 16% jump this year is more than most other markets, including China.</p>

<p>Mr Desai expects the rally to continue as fiscal consolidation allows private borrowing and spending to fuel the next leg of earnings growth and as higher FII inflows will keep liquidity in surplus, lending resilience.</p>

<p>"We think we are only past the halfway mark in the current bull market. A bull market peak for India is possibly still in the future and the weight in the EM index could have some more distance to travel before it peaks."</p>

<p>Morgan Stanley retained India as its top pick among emerging markets and second favourite, behind Japan, in the Indo-Pacific region.</p>

<p>Among stocks, it prefers cyclicals over defensives and large-caps over small-caps. And among sectors, it is 'overweight' on financials, technology, consumer discretionary and industrials, and is 'underweight' on others. ($1 = 83.9690 Indian rupees)<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/dtdmdblg_bombay-stock-exchange-bse-generic-reuters_625x300_05_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[BSE: India to soon overtake China as the most influential in a key emerging markets index.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/new-york-man-says-he-pays-over-rs-1-5-lakh-a-month-in-rent-to-live-with-23-roommates-6495585]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Man Pays Over Rs 1.5 Lakh A Month In Rent To Live With 23 Roommates]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/new-york-man-says-he-pays-over-rs-1-5-lakh-a-month-in-rent-to-live-with-23-roommates-6495585]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Sep 2024 13:16:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 33-year-old Sri Lankan native, who moved to New York from London in 2022, recently opened up about his living situation in Brooklyn's communal building, where he shares his home with more than two dozen people and pays a staggering $2,100 per month]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>New York City has a reputation of being one of the most expensive cities in the world. While the city is known for its character and charm, it's not exactly considered budget-friendly. It is common to see people in their late 20s and early 30s living with roommates to help manage the high cost of living. Amid this, a 33-year-old man, who moved to New York from London in 2022, recently opened up about his living situation in Brooklyn's communal building, where he shares his home with more than two dozen people and pays a staggering $2,100 (approximately Rs 176,000) in rent each month.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In an interview with <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.cnbc.com/2024/08/24/33-year-old-pays-2100/month-to-live-with-23-roommates-in-brooklyn.html" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>CNBC Make It,</em></a> Ishan Abeysekera, an engineer by profession, lifted the lid on what life is like in his "cohab" home. He revealed that he lives with 23 housemates and it costs him a whopping $2,100 in rent each month. He has a shared bathroom and kitchen. His monthly payment covers WiFi, utilities, household supplies, a weekly cleaning service and a monthly communal breakfast.&nbsp;</p>

<p>His living situation might have similarities to college housing and might sound wild, but he says that "it's quite nice".&nbsp;</p>

<p>Mr Abeysekera lives in a space operated by Cohabs, a company that offers fully furnished bedrooms and communal living spaces for stays as short as 6 months or as long as a year or more. When he first moved to New York, his company put him up in a one-bedroom apartment in the Financial District for a few months. However, when it came time for him to look for his own space, he said that the high cost of living in the city forced him to consider alternatives to a traditional renter setup.&nbsp;</p>

<p>After a Google search, the 33-year-old then came across Cohabs. His budget was between $2,000 to $3,000, which more than covered the cost of one of the rooms in the company's Crown Heights property. He also thought that the shared living experience would give him an opportunity to make friends.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"How do you really meet people when you're new to a city? This seemed like a great way to do that," he said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>As a result, Mr Abeysekera decided to move into the Cohab space. The building has four floors and 24 bedrooms. The tenants are all in their 20s and 30s. His bedroom is furnished with a bed, storage space, a desk, a desk light and a walk-in closet. He does, however, have to share his bathroom with not just one person, rather than all 23 of his roommates.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/feature/all-about-alaska-triangle-where-over-20-000-people-have-mysteriously-disappeared-6494421">All About "Alaska Triangle" Where Over 20,000 People Have Mysteriously Disappeared</a></strong></p>

<p>The building is complete with co-working spaces, an outdoor patio and a finished basement with a massive couch that can fit all the residents at once. There's even some gym equipment and a number of ongoing building-wide exercise challenges.</p>

<p>"There's so much shared amenities and space that you're never really in each other's way," Mr Abeysekera said. "And everyone has their own space in terms of their own room," he added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>However, he admitted that his current living situation is similar to living in a college dorm. But he insisted that it hadn't been a problem. "Everyone's a lot more respectful because they're more of an adult and more mature," he said. "Being here has really helped me build a community and make friends. It's really enriched my life," he told the outlet.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/n2elov88_brooklyn-generic_625x300_05_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The man admitted that his living situation is similar to living in a college dorm.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/artificial-intelligence/openai-co-founder-sutskevers-new-safety-focused-ai-startup-ssi-raises-1-billion-6495451]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[OpenAI Co-Founder Sutskever's New Safety-Focused AI Startup SSI Raises $1 billion]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/artificial-intelligence/openai-co-founder-sutskevers-new-safety-focused-ai-startup-ssi-raises-1-billion-6495451]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Sep 2024 12:59:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Company currently has 10 employees and plans to use funds to acquire computing power and hire top talent. It will focus on building a small highly trusted team of researchers and engineers split between Palo Alto, California and Tel Aviv, Israe]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Safe Superintelligence (SSI), newly co-founded by OpenAI's former chief scientist Ilya Sutskever, has raised $1 billion in cash to help develop safe artificial intelligence systems that far surpass human capabilities, company executives told Reuters.</p>

<p>SSI, which currently has 10 employees, plans to use the funds to acquire computing power and hire top talent. It will focus on building a small highly trusted team of researchers and engineers split between Palo Alto, California and Tel Aviv, Israel.</p>

<p>The company declined to share its valuation but sources close to the matter said it was valued at $5 billion. The funding underlines how some investors are still willing to make outsized bets on exceptional talent focused on foundational AI research. That's despite a general waning in interest towards funding such companies which can be unprofitable for some time, and which has caused several startup founders to leave their posts for tech giants.</p>

<p>Investors included top venture capital firms Andreessen Horowitz, Sequoia Capital, DST Global and SV Angel. NFDG, an investment partnership run by Nat Friedman and SSI's Chief Executive Daniel Gross, also participated.</p>

<p>"It's important for us to be surrounded by investors who understand, respect and support our mission, which is to make a straight shot to safe superintelligence and in particular to spend a couple of years doing R&amp;D on our product before bringing it to market," Gross said in an interview.</p>

<p>AI safety, which refers to preventing AI from causing harm, is a hot topic amid fears that rogue AI could act against the interests of humanity or even cause human extinction.</p>

<p>A California bill seeking to impose safety regulations on companies has split the industry. It is opposed by companies like OpenAI and Google, and supported by Anthropic and Elon Musk's xAI.</p>

<p>Sutskever, 37, is one of the most influential technologists in AI. He co-founded SSI in June with Gross, who previously led AI initiatives at Apple, and Daniel Levy, a former OpenAI researcher.</p>

<p>Sutskever is chief scientist and Levy is principal scientist, while Gross is responsible for computing power and fundraising.</p>

<p>NEW MOUNTAIN</p>

<p>Sutskever said his new venture made sense because he "identified a mountain that's a bit different from what I was working on."</p>

<p>Last year, he was a part of the board of OpenAI's non-profit parent which voted to oust OpenAI CEO Sam Altman over a "breakdown of communications."</p>

<p>Within days, he reversed his decision and joined nearly all of OpenAI's employees in signing a letter demanding Altman's return and the board's resignation. But the turn of events diminished his role at OpenAI. He was removed from the board and left the company in May.</p>

<p>After Sutskever's departure, the company dismantled his "Superalignment" team, which worked to ensure AI stays aligned with human values to prepare for a day when AI exceeds human intelligence.</p>

<p>Unlike OpenAI's unorthodox corporate structure, implemented for AI safety reasons but which made Altman's ouster possible, SSI has a regular for-profit structure.</p>

<p>SSI is currently very much focused on hiring people who will fit in with its culture.</p>

<p>Gross said they spend hours vetting if candidates have "good character", and are looking for people with extraordinary capabilities rather than overemphasizing credentials and experience in the field.</p>

<p>"One thing that excites us is when you find people that are interested in the work, that are not interested in the scene, in the hype," he added.</p>

<p>SSI says it plans to partner with cloud providers and chip companies to fund its computing power needs but hasn't yet decided which firms it will work with. AI startups often work with companies such as Microsoft and Nvidia to address their infrastructure needs.</p>

<p>Sutskever was an early advocate of scaling, a hypothesis that AI models would improve in performance given vast amounts of computing power. The idea and its execution kicked off a wave of AI investment in chips, data centers and energy, laying the groundwork for generative AI advances like ChatGPT.</p>

<p>Sutskever said he will approach scaling in a different way than his former employer, without sharing details.</p>

<p>"Everyone just says scaling hypothesis. Everyone neglects to ask, what are we scaling?" he said.</p>

<p>"Some people can work really long hours and they'll just go down the same path faster. It's not so much our style. But if you do something different, then it becomes possible for you to do something special."</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/dl0ik8pg_openai-competition_625x300_05_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Daniel Gross, Ilya Sutskever and Daniel Levy cofounders of AI Company Safe Superintelligence]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/nvidia-did-not-receive-a-us-justice-department-subpoena-spokesperson-says-6495299]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Nvidia Did Not Receive A US Justice Department Subpoena, Spokesperson Says]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/nvidia-did-not-receive-a-us-justice-department-subpoena-spokesperson-says-6495299]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Sep 2024 12:35:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Bloomberg News reported on Tuesday the Justice Department had sent a subpoena related to a potential antitrust investigation. The Justice Department did not immediately respond to a request for comment.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Nvidia did not receive a U.S. Justice Department subpoena, a spokesperson said in a statement on Wednesday.</p>

<p>"We have inquired with the U.S. Department of Justice and have not been subpoenaed. Nonetheless, we are happy to answer any questions regulators may have about our business."</p>

<p>Bloomberg News reported on Tuesday the Justice Department had sent a subpoena related to a potential antitrust investigation, which would signal an escalation in the probe. Bloomberg News said subpoenas had been sent to other companies in addition to Nvidia.</p>

<p>The Justice Department has been asking tech companies about Nvidia's business practices in recent weeks, including questions about the company's hardware bundling practices, two sources familiar with the questions investigators are asking told Reuters.</p>

<p>The Justice Department did not immediately respond to a request for comment.</p>

<p>In addition to questions about bundling, Justice Department officials are examining a recent acquisition of the Israel-based Run:AI for a reported $700 million in April, the sources also told Reuters. Officials are probing whether the purchase could further increase Nvidia's grip on the artificial intelligence computing market.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/eeo6b19g_nvidia-_625x300_05_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Shares of AI heavyweight Nvidia tumbled 9.5% on Tuesday in the deepest ever single-day decline]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-research-proves-cats-to-be-as-playful-companions-as-dogs-6495286]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[New Research Proves Cats To Be As Playful Companions As Dogs]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-research-proves-cats-to-be-as-playful-companions-as-dogs-6495286]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Sep 2024 12:32:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Many people have seen dogs fetch, but cats like to get into the game too. Despite their very different hunting and play styles, fetching appears to combine elements of predatory and social behaviour for both species.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="theconversation-article-title"><span style="font-size: 13px;">Many people have seen dogs fetch, but cats like to get into the game too. Despite their very different hunting and play styles, fetching appears to combine elements of predatory and social behaviour for both species.</span></p>

<div class="theconversation-article-body">
<p>Although their domestication histories and natural behaviours are very different, cats and dogs share many similarities. Both species are predators, live closely with humans and are capable of enjoying rich social experiences with us.</p>

<p>In our <a href="https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0309068">newly published study</a>, we found that more than 40% of cats described in our survey data played fetch, compared with almost 80% of dogs. We also outlined several possible reasons for fetching, including play, selection during domestication, and learning effects.</p>

<h3><strong>Scant research</strong></h3>

<p><a href="https://vet.purdue.edu/discovery/croney/index.php">Our research group</a> sat up and took note when British researchers published a study in 2023 that explored some <a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-023-47409-w">key characteristics of fetching in cats</a>. The scientists surveyed 924 owners of cats that fetched, and they found that the cats would retrieve a wide variety of objects, from pet toys and balls of paper to pens, bottle caps <a href="https://people.com/pets/cat-steals-shoes-owner-made-facebook-group-to-return-shoes/">and even shoes</a>.</p>

<p>Perhaps most intriguing was the fact that the cats generally were not trained to fetch – they offered the behaviour spontaneously. Cats also preferred to be the ones to start the fetch game and were more likely to play when they brought a toy to their human, rather than the human tossing a toy.</p>

<p>Prior to this study, fetching behaviour in cats hadn't received much scientific attention. However, because this review surveyed only owners of cats that fetched, there was no way to compare those animals with cats that didn't. We wondered whether there was something about the cats themselves that made some more likely to fetch than others.</p>

<p>And what about dogs? Fetching is one of the <a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/S0168-1591(99)00078-7">most common forms of play between dogs and humans</a>. Many dogs have been bred and selected specifically to assist human hunts by <a href="https://www.akc.org/expert-advice/dog-breeds/best-dog-breeds-for-hunting/">retrieving prey</a>. We expected to find abundant research about fetching behaviour in dogs, but we learned that it was rarely addressed in dog behaviour studies.</p>

<h3><strong>Fluffy, get the ball!</strong></h3>

<p>To help fill this gap, our group teamed with <a href="https://www.vet.upenn.edu/people/faculty-clinician-search/JAMESSERPELL">University of Pennsylvania researcher James Serpell</a>, who developed two survey-based tools to assess dog and cat behaviour. The surveys include basic questions about each animal's breed, age and living environment, followed by dozens of questions about their behaviour, including traits such as predatory behaviour, sociability with humans, activity level and fearfulness. Both surveys also included questions about fetching.</p>

<p>Using these survey results, we analyzed data from thousands of cat and dog owners to explore just how common fetching is and what characteristics of a cat or dog and their environment are likely to predict fetching.</p>

<p>We found that fetching was much more common in cats than we anticipated. Over 40% of cat owners had a cat that “sometimes, usually, or always” fetched. For comparison, we also provided the first estimate of the prevalence of fetching behaviour in dogs. Almost 78% of dogs represented in the data were reported to fetch.</p>

<p>Interestingly, being male was associated with increased fetching in both species. Being older and having health problems decreased the likelihood that either cats or dogs would be fetchers. And for both species, sharing a home with a dog also made the animal represented in the survey less likely to fetch.</p>

<p>There were breed differences too, especially among dogs. Breeds known for being responsive to human instructions and taking interest in toys, such as <a href="https://www.akc.org/dog-breeds/german-shepherd-dog/">German shepherd dogs</a>, <a href="https://www.akc.org/dog-breeds/golden-retriever/">golden retrievers</a> and <a href="https://www.akc.org/dog-breeds/labrador-retriever/">Labrador retrievers</a>, were among the most likely breeds to fetch. In contrast, hounds and livestock guard dogs were among those least likely to fetch.</p>

<p>Fetching was correlated with trainability in dogs, regardless of breed, pointing to the potential importance of early selection of dogs to be human helpers, <a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.24272/j.issn.2095-8137.2020.002">long before we started developing dog breeds</a>.</p>

<p>There are far fewer breeds of cats than dogs and fewer purebred cats were represented in our study compared with dogs. Still, we also found breed differences among cats. <a href="https://cfa.org/breed/siamese/">Siamese</a>, <a href="https://cfa.org/tonkinese-article/">Tonkinese</a>, <a href="https://cfa.org/burmese-article/">Burmese</a> and <a href="https://cfa.org/breed/bengal/">Bengals</a> were the most likely cats to fetch.</p>

<p>Fetching was correlated with activity level: Cats that were more likely to run, jump, engage with new items in the home and initiate play with their owners were also more likely to fetch.</p>

<h3><strong>From hunting to playing catch</strong></h3>

<p>The roots of fetching behaviour lie in both species' hunting practices. Cats are known as stalk-and-rush hunters, meaning that they sneak up on their prey and <a href="https://www.felidae.org/KNOWELLPUBL/Prelims.pdf">pounce at an opportune moment</a>. Dogs are believed to be pursuit predators that <a href="https://doi.org/10.1080/08927014.1995.9522969">chase prey over longer distances</a>.</p>

<p>The development of breeds has altered dogs' typical predatory behaviour sequence, which goes like this: orient, eye, stalk, chase, grab-bite, kill-bite. Dog breeds that have been bred for exaggerated or increased “chase and/or grab-bite” behaviour – such as pointers and retrievers – are more likely to fetch and less likely to complete the predatory sequence and “kill-bite.”</p>

<p>But both cats and dogs will carry prey items away from the kill site, which may also partially explain how a behaviour such as a fetch could arise.</p>

<p>Although cats often are viewed as independent and aloof, recent studies have found that cats can <a href="http://dx.doi.org/%2010.1016/j.cub.2019.08.036">show attachment to humans</a>, <a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/s10071-014-0832-2">pick up social cues from humans</a> and even <a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/s10071-013-0620-4">recognize their owner's voice</a>. We hope that our study further encourages people to understand that cats are capable of loving relationships with humans, especially when these popular pets are well-socialized and provided with an enriched and safe environment. Including fetching, if your cat is so inclined.</p>

<p>For all of the differences between dogs and cats, we think it's charming that they have converged on a similar behaviour – fetching. Fetching also highlights the effect of the human-animal relationship. Humans clearly play an important role in fetching behaviour, even if dogs and cats simply perceive us as the thing that makes the toy move so they can chase it.<!-- Below is The Conversation's page counter tag. Please DO NOT REMOVE. --><img alt="The Conversation" height="1" referrerpolicy="no-referrer-when-downgrade" src="https://counter.theconversation.com/content/237926/count.gif?distributor=republish-lightbox-basic" style="border: none !important; box-shadow: none !important; margin: 0 !important; max-height: 1px !important; max-width: 1px !important; min-height: 1px !important; min-width: 1px !important; opacity: 0 !important; outline: none !important; padding: 0 !important" width="1" /><!-- End of code. If you don't see any code above, please get new code from the Advanced tab after you click the republish button. The page counter does not collect any personal data. More info: https://theconversation.com/republishing-guidelines --></p>

<p><em><span><a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/mikel-delgado-261351">Mikel Delgado</a>, Senior Research Scientist, College of Veterinary Medicine, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/purdue-university-1827">Purdue University</a> and <a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/judith-stella-1647756">Judith Stella</a>, Senior Research Scientist, College of Veterinary Medicine, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/purdue-university-1827">Purdue University</a></span></em></p>

<p><em>This article is republished from <a href="https://theconversation.com">The Conversation</a> under a Creative Commons license. Read the <a href="https://theconversation.com/cats-and-dogs-both-like-to-play-fetch-its-rooted-in-their-hunting-instincts-237926">original article</a>.</em></p>
</div>

<h1 class="theconversation-article-title"></h1><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/m532ipqo_lazy-cat-generic-_625x300_05_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Fetching was correlated with trainability in dogs, regardless of breed (representational).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/ai-safety-ai-regulation-ai-policy-australia-plans-ai-rules-on-human-oversight-transparency-6495216]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Australia Plans AI Rules On Human Oversight, Transparency]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/ai-safety-ai-regulation-ai-policy-australia-plans-ai-rules-on-human-oversight-transparency-6495216]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Sep 2024 12:22:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The report containing the guidelines said it was critical to enable human control as required across an AI system's lifecycle.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p>

<p>Australia's centre-left government said on Thursday it planned to introduce targeted artificial intelligence rules including human intervention and transparency amid a rapid rollout of AI tools by businesses and in everyday life.</p>

<p>Industry and Science Minister Ed Husic unveiled 10 new voluntary guidelines on AI systems and said the government has opened a month-long consultation over whether to make them mandatory in the future in high-risk settings.</p>

<p>"Australians know AI can do great things but people want to know there are protections in place if things go off the rails," Husic said in a statement. "Australians want stronger protections on AI, we've heard that, we've listened."</p>

<p>The report containing the guidelines said it was critical to enable human control as required across an AI system's lifecycle.</p>

<p>"Meaningful human oversight will let you intervene if you need to and reduce the potential for unintended consequences and harms," the report said. Companies must be transparent to disclose AI's role when generating content, it added.</p>

<p>Regulators around the world have raised concerns about misinformation and fake news contributed by AI tools amid the rising popularity of generative AI systems such as Microsoft-backed OpenAI's ChatGPT and Google's Gemini.</p>

<p>As a result, the European Union in May passed landmark AI laws, imposing strict transparency obligations on high-risk AI systems that are more comprehensive than a light-touch voluntary compliance approach in several countries.</p>

<p>"We don't think that there is a right to self-regulation any more. I think we've passed that threshold," Husic told ABC News.</p>

<p>Australia has no specific laws to regulate AI, though in 2019 it introduced eight voluntary principles for its responsible use. A government report published this year said the current settings were not adequate enough to tackle high-risk scenarios.</p>

<p>Husic said only one-third of businesses using AI were implementing it responsibly on metrics such as safety, fairness, accountability and transparency.</p>

<p>"Artificial intelligence is expected to create up to 200,000 jobs in Australia by 2030 ... so it's crucial that Australian businesses are equipped to properly develop and use the technology," he said.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/5bt8baag_ai-reuters_625x300_05_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Australia has no specific laws to regulate AI, though in 2019 it introduced eight voluntary principles.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-new-zealand-s-new-maori-queen-5-points-on-nga-wai-hono-i-te-po-paki-6495087]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Know About New Zealand's Second-Ever Maori Queen ]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-new-zealand-s-new-maori-queen-5-points-on-nga-wai-hono-i-te-po-paki-6495087]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Sep 2024 12:20:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Nga Wai Hono i te po Paki was anointed as the new Maori Queen, succeeding her father, King Tuheitia Pootatau Te Wherowhero VII, who died last week.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">Nga Wai Hono i te po Paki was anointed as the new Maori Queen, succeeding her father, King Tuheitia Pootatau Te Wherowhero VII, who died last week. Thousands gathered at New Zealand's Tuurangawaewae, the meeting place of the King movement, to bid farewell to the late king and witness the anointment of his daughter.&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">The ceremony, known as Te Whakawahinga, involved the placement of a sacred bible on the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-zealands-maori-crowned-new-queen-after-fathers-death-6494926">queen's head</a> and the use of sacred oils to bestow prestige, power and spiritual essence upon her, as per AFP.&nbsp;During her coronation, she wore traditional Maori attire including a headdress of fern leaves, a light brown cloak and a carved whalebone necklace.&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr"><strong>Here are some facts on the new Maori queen:</strong></p>

<ol>
	<li dir="ltr">
	<p dir="ltr" role="presentation">Nga Wai Hono i te po Paki is the youngest child and only daughter of King Tuheitia and Queen Te Atawhai Makau Ariki. She is 27.</p>
	</li>
	<li dir="ltr">
	<p dir="ltr" role="presentation">She holds a Master of Arts in Tikanga (Maori societal lore) and has served on the board of the Te Kohanga Reo National Trust, which focuses on strenghtening the Maori language, as per AFP.</p>
	</li>
	<li dir="ltr">
	<p dir="ltr" role="presentation">She was chosen as successor at the Te Whakawahinga ceremony where a group of 12 elders from various Maori tribes, known as the Kiingitanga advisory council, chose her to become the Maori queen. Despite having two older brothers, NNga Wai Hono i te po Paki was selected to lead, which the Maori people called a “new dawn”. The late Maori King'sfuneral took place shortly before her ascension.</p>
	</li>
	<li dir="ltr">
	<p dir="ltr" role="presentation">She is the eighth Maori monarch and the second queen. Her grandmother, Queen Te Arikinui Dame Te Atairangikaahu, was the first queen and served for four decades until 2006.</p>
	</li>
	<li dir="ltr">
	<p dir="ltr" role="presentation">She has a traditional chin tattoo (“moko kauae”), received at age 19, which honours her father and the time he dedicated to his role as king.&nbsp;</p>
	</li>
</ol>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/67jovae8_new-zealands-new-maori-queen-afp_625x300_05_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Nga Wai Hono i te po Paki is the youngest child and only daughter of King Tuheitia.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/us-britain-eu-to-sign-first-international-treaty-on-ai-standards-ft-reports-6495036]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[AI Safety, AI Regulation, AI Standards: US, Britain, EU To Sign First International Treaty On AI Standards, FT Reports]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/us-britain-eu-to-sign-first-international-treaty-on-ai-standards-ft-reports-6495036]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Sep 2024 11:56:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The three would sign the Council of Europe's convention on AI on Thursday, the newspaper said, adding that the convention was drafted for over two years by more than 50 countries]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The U.S., Britain and the EU are expected to sign the first international treaty on the use of AI that is legally binding, the Financial Times reported on Thursday.</p>

<p>The three would sign the Council of Europe's convention on AI on Thursday, the newspaper said, adding that the convention was drafted for over two years by more than 50 countries including Canada, Israel, Japan and Australia.</p>

<p>The U.S. was "committed to ensuring that AI technologies support respect for human rights and democratic values" and saw "the key value-add of the Council of Europe in this space," a senior Biden administration official told the newspaper.</p>

<p>"It's the first [agreement] with real teeth globally, and it's bringing together a very disparate set of nations as well," Britain's technology minister Peter Kyle said, according to the report.</p>

<p>The Council of Europe's framework convention on AI, which addresses human rights, democracy, and the rule of law, was drafted by the Committee on Artificial Intelligence (CAI).</p>

<p>The CAI finalised the draft of the convention in March. Following this, the convention was adopted by the Committee of Ministers of the Council of Europe on May 17 and will be opened for signature in Vilnius on September 5.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/bu1pp5go_ai-reuters_625x300_05_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-zealands-maori-crowned-new-queen-after-fathers-death-6494926]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[New Zealand's Maori Crowned Queen After Father's Death]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-zealands-maori-crowned-new-queen-after-fathers-death-6494926]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Sep 2024 11:40:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Twenty-seven-year-old Nga Wai hono i te po was Thursday anointed as the new monarch by Maori chiefs in New Zealand. The decision came after the death of King Kiingi Tuheitia Ptatau Te Wherowhero VII.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Twenty-seven-year-old Nga Wai hono i te po was Thursday anointed as the new monarch by Maori chiefs in New Zealand. The decision came after the death of <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-zealands-maori-king-dies-after-18-year-reign-world-leaders-mourn-6451320">King Kiingi Tuheitia Pōtatau Te Wherowhero VII</a>. Nga Wai was chosen as Kuini in a formal ceremony held on the North Island by a council of the Indigenous Māori chiefs, reported AFP.<br />
<br />
With this, Nga Wai became the second-ever <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-zealands-maori-king-wants-whales-to-be-granted-personhood-heres-why-5329988">Maori</a> queen in the eight-dynasty reign of the Kingitanga movement to ascend the throne. Her father died last week at the age of 69, following heart surgery.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
“The new monarch was raised in a ceremony known as Te Whakawahinga, in front of thousands of people gathered for the tangihanga (funeral and burial) of Kiingi Tuheitia,” a spokesperson for the Kiingitanga or royal family said.<br />
<br />
Instead of crowning the queen, Archbishop Don Tamihere placed a bible, that has been in use since 1858, on her head and used holy oils to bestow dignity, sacredness, strength, and spiritual essence upon her.<br />
<br />
Thousands flocked to Turangawaewae, the King movement's meeting spot, to bid farewell to him in a traditional funeral ceremony. After his daughter's anointment, the King's coffin was transported by hearse to the Waikato River. From there, it was floated in a flotilla of traditional Maori waka, or canoes, to Taupiri Mountain, where he was to be buried with other royals and high-profile Maori.<br />
<br />
The Maori <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/all-you-need-to-know-about-sultan-hassanal-bolkiah-and-bruneis-royal-family-6480250">monarchy </a>was established back in 1858 to fight colonisation and protect Māori culture and land from intruders. Although the monarch is primarily ceremonial and has little official authority, it is nevertheless regarded by many tribes as the supreme chief.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
With a master's degree in Māori cultural studies from Waikato University, Nga Wai has served on several boards, including the Te Kohanga Reo National Trust, an organisation charged with revitalising the Maori language, according to 1News.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
Her anointment comes amid strained racial relations in New Zealand. Since assuming power last year, the centre-right coalition in New Zealand has begun to roll back the policies of the previous administration, especially those that supported the official use of the Maori language, improved living conditions and rights for Indigenous people, and attempts to right some of the wrongs committed during colonisation.</p>

<p><br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/1l0a67eo_new-zealand-maori-queen-_625x300_05_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[At 27, Nga Wai hono i te po is the second-youngest monarch in Maoridom.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/im-going-to-let-her-talk-donald-trump-on-debate-with-kamala-harris-6494910]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["I'm Going To Let Her Talk": Donald Trump On Debate With Kamala Harris]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/im-going-to-let-her-talk-donald-trump-on-debate-with-kamala-harris-6494910]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Sep 2024 11:40:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump said he plans to allow his opponent, Kamala Harris, to speak without interruption during their presidential debate next week, a shift for the reality-television-star-turned-politician who built a career on combative exchanges.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump said he plans to allow his opponent, Kamala Harris, to speak without interruption during their presidential debate next week, a shift for the reality-television-star-turned-politician who built a career on combative exchanges. &nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p>"I'm going to let her talk," Trump said Wednesday at a taping of a town hall in Harrisburg, Pennsylvania, with Fox News' Sean Hannity. "Debates are interesting, you can go in with all the strategy you want, but you have to sort of feel it out."</p>

<p>The Sept. 10 debate hosted by ABC News is the next big test for the two candidates. That forum has already been the centre of a row over the rules for microphones, and with Trump claiming the network is biased in favour of Harris.</p>

<p>ABC News released the rules of the debate on Wednesday and said they had been accepted by both campaigns.</p>

<p>Trump left a little room to change his plan for the event, adding Wednesday: "Mike Tyson made the statement, 'Everyone has a plan until you're punched in the face.'"</p>

<p>Trump in the past has resisted the traditional debate planning employed by presidential campaigns, involving detailed policy briefings and mock exchanges. Instead, he preferred to have less formal preparation from his team and rely more on his own intuition. He refused to debate his Republican rivals during the 2024 primary battle.</p>

<p>The high-stakes confrontation is the first - and potentially only - opportunity for the two candidates to spar in person in a very close contest. With only two months until Election Day, they have few opportunities to sway the small sliver of persuadable voters.</p>

<p>The debate presents risks for both Harris and Trump. The former president has been chastised by both allies and critics for attacks on Harris that criticize her intelligence, gender and racial identity that could alienate key voters. The vice president has largely been untested as a presidential candidate in unscripted settings, only doing one television interview since she became the Democratic nominee.</p>

<h3><strong>Debate About Debates</strong></h3>

<p>Trump had originally agreed to the ABC News debate with President Joe Biden, then the Democratic candidate. For weeks, he suggested he might not show up for the debate with Harris, before saying he would participate after all. Trump and Biden held one debate, a calamitous performance for the sitting president that led members of his own party to push him out of the race.</p>

<p>For weeks, the campaigns have clashed over the rules for the microphones. Harris' camp has sought to keep both candidates' microphones live throughout the broadcast, while Trump's team has pushed for them to be muted when they were not answering questions, as they were during the June Biden-Trump debate on CNN.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In the rules released on Wednesday, ABC said the microphones would be "live only for the candidate whose turn it is to speak and muted when the time belongs to another candidate." Candidates have two minutes to answer questions, two minutes to rebut and one minute for follow-ups or clarifications, according to the network.</p>

<p>The Harris campaign in a letter to ABC said that the muted microphones would disadvantage Harris and shield Trump from having to directly engage with the vice president, according to a campaign official. Harris' team was concerned that Trump would skip the debate if they didn't agree to having the mics silenced, and said that if there is significant cross-talk, the network might unmute the candidates, so that the audience can understand what's happening, the official said.</p>

<p>Trump has floated other debates, including with Fox News. The Harris campaign has ruled out participating in a forum on that network but has proposed a second debate, with the details to be resolved if Trump takes part in the ABC event.</p>

<h3><strong>Swing States</strong></h3>

<p>The debate will take place in Philadelphia, the largest city in Pennsylvania, one of the most critical swing states. Trump's town hall appearance Wednesday marks his second visit there in as many weeks. The two nominees are in a pitched fight for the state's working-class voters, some of them uneasy with Biden's economic agenda and drawn to Trump's populist appeals.</p>

<p>Harris campaigned in the western part of the state on Labor Day with Biden and is returning on Thursday for the 10th time this year, according to her campaign. The state is the most populous of the seven core battlegrounds, offering 19 Electoral College votes.</p>

<p>Trump's team has acknowledged polls showing the race has grown more competitive. A Bloomberg News/Morning Consult poll released late August found Harris overtaking Trump in Pennsylvania by 51% to 47%. Republican National Committee co-chair Lara Trump, on Bloomberg Television's Balance of Power last week, said the party would consider putting more money and attention into "must-win" battlegrounds such as Pennsylvania.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ugf3uu1g_trump-harris-_625x300_22_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump in the past has resisted the traditional debate planning by presidential campaigns (file)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/scientists-propose-licking-ice-lollies-in-primary-school-science-curriculum-6494738]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Scientists Propose Licking Ice Lollies In Primary School Science Curriculum]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/scientists-propose-licking-ice-lollies-in-primary-school-science-curriculum-6494738]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Sep 2024 11:16:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A group of scientists, including people from the Royal Society of Chemistry, recently proposed that experiences such as licking an ice lolly should be part of the science curriculum.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="theconversation-article-title">A <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/newsround/articles/c984wz29xexo">group of scientists</a>, including people from the Royal Society of Chemistry, recently proposed that experiences such as <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/education/article/2024/aug/20/add-ice-lolly-licking-to-england-primary-school-curriculum-urge-scientists">licking an ice lolly</a> should be part of the science curriculum. By licking a lolly and seeing how it melts – the idea goes – children would better learn about melting, and therefore about chemistry and physics.</p>

<div class="theconversation-article-body">
<p>But does licking a lolly, or experiences such as kneading dough, playing with shadows or digging in soil, actually help pupils learn science? Deploying examples and demonstrations in the classroom can be a helpful gateway towards deeper understanding, but it's not a shortcut to knowledge.</p>

<p>The idea of learning through experiences has a long history. It's perhaps most closely associated with the work of educator <a href="https://plato.stanford.edu/ENTRIES/dewey/">John Dewey</a> in the early 20th century. Dewey and other educators of the time were concerned that an emphasis on rote learning would lead to “inert knowledge”: facts that students wouldn't be able to apply <a href="https://www.taylorfrancis.com/chapters/edit/10.4324/9780203056646-5/cognitive-coping-strategies-problem-inert-knowledge-carl-bereiter-marlene-scardamalia">to the real world</a>.</p>

<p>An experience like licking a lolly may at least be memorable – especially if you've never done it before. Licking a lolly or seeing it melt in class would lead to what psychologists call an episodic memory: a memory of an event in your life.</p>

<h3><strong>Experience and understanding</strong></h3>

<p>However, there <a href="https://psycnet.apa.org/record/2007-08951-001">is a difference</a> between having memories for events and having knowledge. There is a difference, for example, between having personally lived through the French Revolution and knowing what happened.</p>

<p>The latter involves a different type of memories – semantic memories. These are based on understanding how things work and what they mean. It is the type of memory that is at play when you use a word such as “heavy”, unconnected to a specific heavy object. Such understandings are essential to both scientific learning and our use of language.</p>

<p>If you stop to think about it, most of your knowledge can't be clearly tied to one particular experience. Learning is usually not a one-shot process – think of how much experience a gardener needs before they “know” how plants grow and thrive, for example.</p>

<p>These semantic memories derive from an amalgam of lots of experiences, and sometimes, from comparing and contrasting different things: the difference between two types of plants, or between an ice lolly and an ice cream.</p>

<p>Learning about melting is similar. We don't just demonstrate melting one time, and boom (or squelch), the students have learned it.</p>

<h3><strong>Importance of context</strong></h3>

<p>Understanding science or anything else is also not just about remembering experiences. Learners need to <a href="https://www.taylorfrancis.com/chapters/edit/10.4324/9781410603784-7/teaching-learning-understanding-david-perkins-chris-unger">understand the encounter</a>, to have their attention directed towards similar and different processes, and to experience <a href="https://www.frontiersin.org/journals/psychology/articles/10.3389/fpsyg.2015.00505/full">multiple examples</a>.</p>

<p>To profit most from this, learners need sufficient prior knowledge to understand what is happening when they observe something in class. This is one reason that leaving students to discover things entirely by themselves is a <a href="https://doi.org/10.1037/0003-066X.59.1.14">flawed strategy</a>.</p>

<p>It's also another reason why relying on one-off experiences doesn't work. Students need to revisit ideas periodically, each time bringing more knowledge and understanding to the table.</p>

<p>Without a basic understanding of science, there is a risk that a learner will fail to connect a classroom observation to its wider context. Knowing about melting, for example, is a lot more than knowing that a lolly melts – it involves knowing why, and under what circumstances. It involves knowing that other everyday substances would melt in higher temperatures.</p>

<p>This foundational understanding is also important to stop students from coming up with scientific misconceptions. In the lolly example, students might <a href="https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/00461520.2012.695709">overgeneralise surface features</a> such as how quickly the lolly melts or how sticky it is, seeing these as characteristics of melting in general.</p>

<p>In short, understanding science or anything else is not just about remembering things. It's about understanding what an experience connects to, what category it is an example of, and how it differs from other concepts.</p>

<h3><strong>Personal learning</strong></h3>

<p>Another notable claim in the ice lolly story was the suggestion that it is valuable to promote learning <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/newsround/articles/c984wz29xexo">“on a personal level”</a>. There is research on this, too.</p>

<p>Imagine you were asked to remember a list of random words such as “music, broccoli, dancing, plastic bottles, baby sharks”. <a href="https://psycnet.apa.org/record/1970-03138-001">A study</a> looking at memory found that people better recalled words from lists like this if they were asked “do you like this?” compared to a blander, information-processing question, such as “does the word contain a letter ‘e'?”. We also <a href="https://doi.org/10.1080/17470211003770938">remember our own possessions</a> better than generic objects.</p>

<p>So, yes – there is some evidence that we might retain experiences better if we are personally invested in them. However, it's worth noting that such experiments are rather short-term. In everyday life, we can really enjoy and engage with something on a personal level (such as a book or a conversation) yet forget the details within a few weeks or months.</p>

<p>This is partly why people write diaries. Memories of our lives are ephemeral, easily lost over time. Sometimes such memories are distorted, or even <a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/S0079-7421(08)60124-3">entirely imagined</a> – false memories. It's risky to base science learning upon this type of memory.</p>

<p>If we want students to build up their knowledge of science and be able to use it in future, it's vital that the focus is on strategies that build deep understanding of concepts and how they are structured, rather than relying on gimmicks or one-off experiences.</p>

<p>All of this is to say nothing of the practicality of storing an ice lolly for every school pupil, handing them out in class – or cleaning up afterwards.<!-- Below is The Conversation's page counter tag. Please DO NOT REMOVE. --><img alt="The Conversation" height="1" referrerpolicy="no-referrer-when-downgrade" src="https://counter.theconversation.com/content/237806/count.gif?distributor=republish-lightbox-basic" style="border: none !important; box-shadow: none !important; margin: 0 !important; max-height: 1px !important; max-width: 1px !important; min-height: 1px !important; min-width: 1px !important; opacity: 0 !important; outline: none !important; padding: 0 !important" width="1" /><!-- End of code. If you don't see any code above, please get new code from the Advanced tab after you click the republish button. The page counter does not collect any personal data. More info: https://theconversation.com/republishing-guidelines --></p>

<p><em><span><a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/jonathan-firth-889115">Jonathan Firth</a>, Senior Teaching Fellow in Education, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/university-of-strathclyde-1287">University of Strathclyde </a></span></em></p>

<p><em>This article is republished from <a href="https://theconversation.com">The Conversation</a> under a Creative Commons license. Read the <a href="https://theconversation.com/licking-an-ice-lolly-at-school-might-make-a-good-memory-but-this-isnt-the-secret-to-learning-science-237806">original article</a>.</em></p>
</div><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/29e74om_ice-lollies-unsplash_625x300_05_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Licking a lolly in class would lead to what psychologists call an episodic memory (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/setback-for-canadas-trudeau-as-key-ally-jagmeet-singh-pulls-out-support-6494668]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Setback For Canada's Trudeau As Key Ally Jagmeet Singh Pulls Support]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/setback-for-canadas-trudeau-as-key-ally-jagmeet-singh-pulls-out-support-6494668]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Sep 2024 11:05:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In a major setback to Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau, key ally Jagmeet Singh's New Democratic Party has pulled out support for his minority Liberal government ahead of the general election next year.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a major setback to Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau, key ally Jagmeet Singh's New Democratic Party has pulled out support for his minority Liberal government ahead of the general election next year.</p>

<p>In a video message shared on social media, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/justin-trudeau-weakened-after-key-sikh-ally-withdraws-support-6492183">Jagmeet Singh </a>said Mr Trudeau will not be able to take on the opposition Conservatives amid recent polls showing them securing an easy win in elections.</p>

<p>"<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/canada-to-reduce-number-of-temporary-foreign-workers-6424021">Justin Trudeau</a> has proven again and again he will always cave to corporate greed. The Liberals have let people down. They don't deserve another chance from Canadians," Mr Singh said in the video.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">The deal is done.<br />
<br />
The Liberals are too weak, too selfish and too beholden to corporate interests to stop the Conservatives and their plans to cut. But the NDP can.<br />
<br />
Big corporations and CEOs have had their governments. It's the people's time. <a href="https://t.co/BsE9zT0CwF">pic.twitter.com/BsE9zT0CwF</a></p>
— Jagmeet Singh (@theJagmeetSingh) <a href="https://twitter.com/theJagmeetSingh/status/1831375557507850740?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 4, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>The leader said that the "big battle" now is defeating the Conservatives to stop them from choosing big corporations over the young people and Canadian families.</p>

<p>"There is another, even bigger battle ahead. The threat of Pierre Poilievre and Conservative cuts. From workers, from retirees, from young people, from patients, from families -- he will cut in order to give more to big corporations and wealthy CEOs," he said.</p>

<p>The two leaders had struck in 2022 to come together to boost the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/setback-for-canadas-trudeau-liberals-lose-stronghold-in-key-polls-5969262">Liberal </a>party's minority government. The deal was supposed to go on till October next year but an NDP spokesperson said the plan to end the agreement was in the works for the past two weeks.</p>

<p>Reports suggest the sudden social media post was a surprise for the Canadian PM's party as within minutes of informing them of their decision to withdraw Mr Singh posted the video on social media.</p>

<p>Mr Singh said "the NDP is ready for an election, and voting non-confidence will be on the table with each and every confidence measure."</p>

<p>Reacting to Mr Singh's announcement, Mr Trudeau said his government will continue to focuse on tackling the affordability crisis in the country.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"These are the things that we're focused on. I'll let others focus on politics.I really hope the NDP stays focused on how we can deliver for Canadians, as we have over the past years, rather than focusing on politics," he said.</p>

<p>The Canadian prime minister also said he remained hopeful that the next election will not happen "until next fall" so that his government can also work on pharmacare, dental care, and school food programmes.</p>

<p>Mr Singh's NDP kept the Mr Trudeau's Liberal government in power through a confidence-and-supply agreement. In exchange for its support, the government agreed to address key priorities, including introducing dental care benefits, providing one-time rental supplements for low-income tenants, and temporarily doubling the GST rebate.</p>

<p>But some of the promises made to Mr Singh's party are yet to be fulfilled.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/b6nb7k98_trudeau-jagmeet-singh_625x300_05_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/4-killed-by-teen-shooter-at-us-school-what-we-know-so-far-6494423]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[4 Killed By Teen Shooter At US School: What We Know So Far]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/4-killed-by-teen-shooter-at-us-school-what-we-know-so-far-6494423]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Sep 2024 10:28:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The shooter was armed with an AR-15, a semi-automatic rifle commonly used in many mass shootings across the US.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 14-year-old <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gunfire-reported-at-high-school-in-us-georgia-currently-under-hard-lockdown-news-agency-afp-6491595 ">opened fire on fellow students and teachers</a> at the Apalachee High School in Georgia, USA, killing four and injuring nine others. The shooter, Colt Gray, surrendered to school resource officers shortly after the attack and now faces charges of murder.<br />
<br />
<strong>The shooter: Colt Gray</strong><br />
<br />
Colt Gray, 14, a student at Apalachee High School, was described as a “pretty quiet” individual by classmates, not known for socialising much and often skipped classes. He exhibited behaviour that, in hindsight, some peers say fit the "stereotype" of a potential shooter.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
<strong>The timeline</strong></p>

<p>The shooting started during an algebra class Gray attended earlier in the day. According to student Lyela Sayarath, Gray left the classroom at the beginning of the period, only to return near the end of the class, attempting to re-enter.<br />
<br />
Due to the school's security protocol, the classroom doors automatically locked once closed, meaning someone inside had to manually let him in. However, a fellow student reportedly noticed that Gray was carrying a gun and made the life-saving decision of not unlocking the door. Moments later, gunshots rang through the hallways of the high school.<br />
<br />
<strong>The attack&nbsp;</strong><br />
<br />
After being denied entry into the algebra class, Gray moved to another classroom, where he opened fire on students and teachers.<br />
<br />
The shooting occurred just before 10:30 am on Wednesday. Initial reports suggest that students and teachers thought it was a drill when a lockdown was announced. However, panic quickly set in as gunfire echoed through the halls. Students scrambled to barricade themselves with desks inside classrooms, while others fled to the school's football field.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
<strong>Aftermath</strong><br />
<br />
In a matter of minutes, four people – two students and two teachers – were dead, and nine others were injured. He was armed with an AR-15, a semi-automatic rifle commonly used in many mass shootings across the US.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
<strong>Law enforcement's response</strong><br />
<br />
Officers arrived at the scene quickly, and Gray was taken into custody just minutes after the shooting began.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
Sheriff Jud Smith described the scene as "pure evil." Gray surrendered without resistance, laying down his weapon and complying with officers.<br />
<br />
The Georgia Bureau of Investigation (GBI) confirmed that Gray was on their radar over a year ago after local law enforcement received anonymous tips about online threats of a potential school shooting. At the time, both Gray and his father were interviewed by the FBI but no arrests were made due to the lack of probable cause.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
<strong>Shooter's behaviour before the shooting</strong><br />
<br />
According to classmates, Colt Gray showed signs of social withdrawal and isolation. While not explicitly violent, his quiet demeanour and tendency to skip classes made him stand out. Lyela Sayarath, who sat beside him in algebra class, wasn't particularly shocked that Gray carried out the attack. His behaviour fit the unsettling "quiet kid" stereotype, often associated with school shooters.<br />
<br />
Colt Gray is being charged as an adult in connection with the shooting, though a motive has yet to be identified.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/hu6t8m4_georgia-shooting_625x300_05_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/all-about-alaska-triangle-where-over-20-000-people-have-mysteriously-disappeared-6494421]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[All About "Alaska Triangle" Where Over 20,000 People Mysteriously Vanished]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/all-about-alaska-triangle-where-over-20-000-people-have-mysteriously-disappeared-6494421]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Sep 2024 10:26:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Bermuda Triangle is a region in the Atlantic Ocean notorious for mysterious disappearance. However, did you know about the so-called "Alaska Triangle", an area that has more unsolved missing person cases than anywhere else in the world?]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Bermuda Triangle is a region in the Atlantic Ocean notorious for mysterious disappearance. However, did you know about the so-called "Alaska Triangle", an area that has more unsolved missing person cases than anywhere else in the world? Located roughly around three points of Anchorage and Juneau in the south, and Utqiagvik, a northern coastal city, the Alaska Triangle has remained a mystery after the disappearance of more than 20,000 people. According to <em>IFL Science</em>, this area first came to the public's attention in October 1972, when a small plane carrying two US politicians suddenly disappeared en route from Anchorage to Juneau.</p>

<p>According to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.iflscience.com/why-over-20000-people-have-vanished-in-the-alaska-triangle-69957" rel="noindex, nofollow">outlet</a>, US House Majority Leader Thomas Hale Boggs Sr and Alaska Congressman Nick Begich disappeared when flying in a light aircraft from Anchorage to Juneau alongside Mr Begich's aide, Russell Brown, and the pilot, Don Jonz. A massive search effort was launched to find the four missing people, however, the bodies nor the plane were ever discovered.&nbsp;</p>

<p>This incident sparked several conspiracy theories as to what could've happened - particularly since Mr Boggs was a Warren Commission member (the official body created to investigate John F. Kennedy's assassination) and apparently did not agree with the findings the group had made, per <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.indy100.com/science-tech/alaska-triangle-people-disappeared" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>Indy100</em></a>.</p>

<p>Another prominent case was Gary Frank Sotherden, a 25-year-old New Yorker who travelled to the Alaskan wilderness in the mid-1970s to go hunting but never returned home. Two decades later in 1997, a human skull was found along the Porcupine River in northeastern Alaska and DNA was later received in 2022. It was concluded the skull belonged to Mr Sotherden and believed he most probably died after being mauled by a bear.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/feature/greek-woman-44-intentionally-starts-2-wildfires-to-watch-firefighters-and-flirt-with-them-6494024">Greek Woman, 44, Intentionally Starts 2 Wildfires To "Watch Firefighters" And "Flirt With Them": Report</a></strong></p>

<p>Many have offered various explanations for the disappearances. While some have suggested that there is unusual magnetic activity in the Alaska Triangle, others believe a lot of extraterrestrial aliens have been visiting the area.&nbsp;</p>

<p>However, some simpler explanations have been that it is vast land which is full of wilderness and natural dangers which can be the reason why people have gone missing and never been found again.&nbsp;</p>

<p>But perhaps, like the Bermuda Triangle, this mystery will never be solved.</p>

<p><em>IFLScience</em> says that the area is full of "untouched wilderness", "ragged mountain ranges" and horrifically cold weather, as well as "lots of bears".&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/3m38kbmo_alaska-generic_625x300_05_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Since 1970s, over 20,000 people have vanished in Alaska Triangle. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-teen-who-shot-dead-4-was-questioned-by-cops-over-threats-in-2023-6494163]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[FBI Had Alerted Cops Of Teen Who Shot Dead 4 At US School]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-teen-who-shot-dead-4-was-questioned-by-cops-over-threats-in-2023-6494163]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Sep 2024 09:31:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The 14-year-old student who killed four of his schoolmates in US's Georgia was questioned last year by police about online threats, the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The 14-year-old student who killed four of his schoolmates in US's Georgia was questioned last year by police about online threats, the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) said.</p>

<p>In May 2023, Colt Gray was questioned by police who believed he was behind internet posts that contained images of guns, warning of a school shooting.</p>

<p>The FBI said its National Threat Operations Center had alerted local law enforcement after receiving tips about "online threats to commit a school shooting at an unidentified location and time".</p>

<p>After the location of the threats were determined, the police interviewed the teen and his father.</p>

<p>While the teen denied sending the threats, his father told police that he had hunting guns in the house but the then 13-year-old "did not have unsupervised access to them".</p>

<p>"At the time, there was no probable cause for an arrest or to take any additional law enforcement action on the local, state or federal levels," the FBI said in a statement.</p>

<p>On Wednesday, the boy used an assault rifle to open fire in Apalachee High School, killing two teachers and two student, investigators say.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Eight other students and one teacher were injured in the attack. Gray was arrested from the school premises and will be tried as an adult.</p>

<p>The school sent out a message to parents saying it was "currently in a hard lockdown after reports of gunfire."</p>

<p>Survivors recounted the moment when Gray began attacking the students. One student told BBC that she saw him leave a class after a maths lesson and when he returned he had a gun in his hand. One of her classmates saw the gun and refused to open the door for Gray even as he continued to pound on it.</p>

<p>Gray then moved to the next classroom and opened fire.</p>

<p>According to the BBC, this was the 23rd US school shooting of 2024. So far 11 people have died and 38 have been injured in such attacks this year.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/enra0qjg_georgia-shooting_625x300_05_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/made-by-astronauts-for-astronauts-boeing-starliner-to-return-without-them-6494023]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Made By Astronauts For Astronauts, Boeing Starliner To Return Without Them]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/made-by-astronauts-for-astronauts-boeing-starliner-to-return-without-them-6494023]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Sep 2024 09:02:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Boeing Starliner on which Indian-origin NASA astronaut Sunita Williams flew to ISS on June 5 was touted as a space capsule made by astronauts for astronauts but, much to the embarrassment of Boeing, is now set to return without any humans.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Boeing Starliner on which Indian-origin NASA astronaut Sunita Williams flew to the International Space Station (ISS) on June 5 was touted as a space capsule made by astronauts for astronauts but, much to the embarrassment of Boeing, is now set to return without any human spacefarers. The return journey, in autonomous mode, is slated for September 6 and the Starliner is expected to land about six hours after it undocks.</p>

<p>The Starliner, whose development was plagued by delays, was on its first crewed test flight, carrying Sunita Williams and Barry "Butch" Wilmore for what was meant to be an eight-day mission. The two astronauts have been at the International Space Station since June 6 and their stay kept getting extended because of propulsion issues on the Starliner. NASA announced on August 24 that the astronauts would return to Earth in February 2025 and the Boeing spacecraft would come back without its crew. &nbsp;</p>

<p>The uncrewed return allows NASA and Boeing to continue gathering testing data on the Starliner during its flight home while also allowing it not to accept more risk than is necessary for its crew. NASA officials said the decision was "unanimous" on its part, while Boeing asserted it could return the Starliner both with or without crew.</p>

<p><strong>'Tense Meeting'</strong></p>

<p>The space agency has confirmed that the decision to get the spacecraft to return without crew was taken at a "tense" meeting between NASA and Boeing officials.</p>

<p>Explaining the decision, NASA chief Senator Bill Nelson, who is also a former astronaut, said, "Spaceflight is risky, even at its safest and most routine. A test flight, by nature, is neither safe nor routine.</p>

<p>The decision to keep Butch and Suni (Sunita Williams) aboard the International Space Station and bring Boeing's Starliner home without crew is the result of our commitment to safety - our core value and our North Star."</p>

<p>Boeing, on its part, said it remains confident in the Starliner spacecraft and its ability to return safely with crew. "We continue to support NASA's requests for additional testing, data, analysis and reviews to affirm the spacecraft's safe undocking and landing capabilities. Our confidence is based on this abundance of valuable testing from Boeing and NASA. The testing has confirmed that 27 of 28 RCS (reaction control system) thrusters are healthy and back to full operational capability," the company said in a statement.<br />
"Starliner's propulsion system also maintains redundancy and the helium levels remain stable. The data also supports root cause assessments for the helium and thruster issues and flight rationale for Starliner and its crew's return to Earth," it added. &nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Requirements Unmet</strong></p>

<p>But NASA, having burnt its fingers after the twin accidents of the Challenger and Columbia space shuttles, did not want to take any risks.</p>

<p>In a statement, NASA said the "uncertainty and lack of expert concurrence does not meet the agency's safety and performance requirements for human spaceflight".</p>

<p>Experts said the space capsule which Indian origin astronaut Sunita Williams had piloted to the International Space Station (ISS) is the most modern crew module and has been designed to ensure that astronauts who fly in it are safe and comfortable. Ms Williams herself has her imprint on almost all aspects of the spacecraft as she has been involved in its making for a long time.</p>

<p><strong>Calypso</strong></p>

<p>According to data released by Boeing, the Starliner has a height of 5 metres with both the crew module and service module, a diameter of 4.6 metres, and weighs 13,000 kg at lift-off. The Starliner is designed to accommodate a maximum crew of seven, but NASA missions will carry a crew of four to five. Each crew module is designed to fly up to 10 missions, so it is partially reusable. The service modules, however, are made for each mission as they get jettisoned in space.</p>

<p>The Crew Space Transportation (CST)-100 Starliner spacecraft was designed for a mix of crew and cargo for missions to low-Earth orbit.</p>

<p>Ms Williams, who had also called the Starliner a 'fantastic spacecraft', was given the opportunity to name the spacecraft she would fly in and decided to call it 'Calypso' - after the famous ship on which the French oceanographer and legendary filmmaker Jacques-Yves Cousteau explored the oceans when she was still a student.</p>

<p>The making of the Starliner was much delayed and went way over the budget, and some say the same problems which have beset the Boeing Company in its aviation business may be plaguing the space side as well.</p>

<p>In 2014, NASA had awarded a $ 4.2 billion contract to Boeing for making the Starliner from scratch and it managed to go on its first human spaceflight only this June - ten years later. In comparison, Space X, which was given a similar contract for the development of Crew Dragon,&nbsp; delivered it at an estimated cost of $ 2.6 billion and has been ferrying astronauts since 2020. Ms Williams and Mr Wilmore will also be returning to Earth aboard the Crew Dragon.</p>

<p><strong>Development To Continue</strong></p>

<p>On August 24, the NASA chief said he had 100% confidence that the Boeing Starliner would continue to be developed but asserted that the agency had awarded a fixed-price contract to Boeing, meaning that the company will have to bear the extra costs for its full certification as a human space flight-worthy vehicle at its own expense.</p>

<p>The Starliner had also been making headlines recently for "strange noises" emanating from it, which have now been identified as feedback from a speaker.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/al1jc96g_boeing-starliner_625x300_05_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nasa-says-there-was-tension-with-boeing-over-astronauts-space-rescue-6493860]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[NASA Says There Was "Tension" With Boeing Over Astronauts Space Rescue]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nasa-says-there-was-tension-with-boeing-over-astronauts-space-rescue-6493860]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Sep 2024 08:29:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[NASA admitted on Wednesday there was "tension" during meetings with Boeing executives about how to bring home two astronauts stranded on the International Space Station, but denied reports of shouting matches.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>NASA admitted on Wednesday there was "tension" during meetings with Boeing executives about how to bring home two astronauts stranded on the International Space Station, but denied reports of shouting matches.</p>

<p>The US space agency is enlisting SpaceX to rescue the astronauts because of safety concerns with Boeing's Starliner capsule, which encountered thruster malfunctions and helium leaks on its way to the orbital outpost.</p>

<p>Butch Wilmore and Suni Williams launched in June for what was meant to be around a weeklong stay, but they now aren't expected back until February 2025 when the SpaceX Crew-9 mission returns.</p>

<p>Boeing had publicly insisted it was confident in its spaceship, but the absence of its executives from recent NASA press briefings had fueled speculation of a rift.</p>

<p>According to sources cited by the New York Post, meetings between the two sides often descended into yelling and arguments.</p>

<p>Asked to address the claims, Steve Stich, program manager for NASA's Commercial Crew Program, said "anytime you're in a meeting of this magnitude where there's this kind of decision, there is some tension in the room."</p>

<p>"Boeing believed in the model that they had created that tried to predict the thruster degradation for the rest of the flight," he added, but "the NASA team, due to the uncertainty in the modeling, could not get comfortable with that."</p>

<p>"I wouldn't say it was a yelling, screaming kind of meeting," Stich told reporters. "It was a tense technical discussion where we had both sides listening intently to all the data."</p>

<h2>Fresh clothes</h2>

<p>Despite their extended stay, Wilmore and Williams remain in good spirits and are in touch with their families.</p>

<p>They are no longer dependent on borrowed clothes having been sent better fitting suits during a recent resupply mission, the NASA officials reported.</p>

<p>Starliner is set to depart the ISS on Friday evening US Eastern Time before making a parachute and airbag assisted landing in the western United States early on Saturday morning.</p>

<p>Shortly after undocking, the spaceship will execute a "breakout burn" with its thrusters to ensure it shoots clear of the research station before it continues its onward journey to Earth.</p>

<p>Had the flight been crewed, the ship would have flown closer to the station to capture exterior views, but NASA deemed the risk of collision too great without astronauts on board to manually pilot Starliner if required.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/fev0vbs8_sunita-williams_625x300_25_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-condemns-shooting-incident-in-georgia-school-6493805]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Joe Biden Condemns Shooting Incident In Georgia School]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-condemns-shooting-incident-in-georgia-school-6493805]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Sep 2024 08:11:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Expressing condolences for the victims of a shooting incident at a school in Georgia, President Joe Biden has called on Republicans to work with Democrats in the US Congress to pass gun safety legislation.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Expressing condolences for the victims of a shooting incident at a school in Georgia, President Joe Biden has called on Republicans to work with Democrats in the US Congress to pass gun safety legislation to help prevent future gun violence in the United States.</p>

<p>At least four people, including two students, have been killed and nine others were injured when a fellow student opened fire in a high school in the US state of Georgia on Wednesday, CNN reported.</p>

<p>Biden described the shooting incident as "another horrific reminder of how gun violence continues to tear our communities apart."</p>

<p>"Jill (Biden) and I are mourning the deaths of those whose lives were cut short due to more senseless gun violence and thinking of all of the survivors whose lives are forever changed. What should have been a joyous back-to-school season in Winder, Georgia, has now turned into another horrific reminder of how gun violence continues to tear our communities apart," Biden said in a statement released by the White House.</p>

<p>The US president lamented that students across the country are "learning how to duck and cover instead of how to read and write."</p>

<p>"We cannot continue to accept this as normal. We are closely coordinating with officials at the federal, state and local levels and are grateful for the first responders who brought the suspect into custody and prevented further loss of life," Biden said.</p>

<p>Further, Biden reaffirmed his commitment to tackling the gun violence epidemic in the US and highlighted his efforts to address the issue, including the signing of the Bipartisan Safer Communities Act.</p>

<p>"Ending this gun violence epidemic is personal to me. It's why I signed into law the Bipartisan Safer Communities Act--the most meaningful gun safety bill in decades--and have announced dozens of gun safety executive actions. I also established the first-ever White House Office of Gun Violence Prevention, overseen by Vice President Harris. We've made significant progress, but this crisis requires even more," the US president said.</p>

<p>Biden called on Republicans to work with Democrats in Congress to pass gun safety legislation to help prevent future gun violence and stated that 'enough is enough.'</p>

<p>"After decades of inaction, Republicans in Congress must finally say 'enough is enough' and work with Democrats to pass common-sense gun safety legislation. We must ban assault weapons and high-capacity magazines once again, require safe storage of firearms, enact universal background checks, and end immunity for gun manufacturers. These measures will not bring those who were tragically killed today back, but they will help prevent more tragic gun violence from ripping more families apart," Biden said.</p>

<p>US Vice President Kamala Harris also took to X and expressed condolences for the people who are impacted by this shooting and described it as a "senseless tragedy."</p>

<p>"Today, Doug and I are mourning the deaths of those whose lives were cut short by gun violence at Apalachee High School in Georgia. Our hearts are with the students, teachers, and families impacted by this shooting, and we are grateful to the first responders and law enforcement on the scene. This is a senseless tragedy -- and it does not have to be this way. We must end the epidemic of gun violence in our country once and for," said Kamala Harris.</p>

<p>Georgia Governor Brian P Kemp also posted on X and stated "I have directed all available state resources to respond to the incident at Apalachee High School and urge all Georgians to join my family in praying for the safety of those in our classrooms, both in Barrow County and across the state."</p>

<p>"We will continue to work with local, state, and federal partners as we gather information and further respond to this situation," he added.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the suspected gunman is in custody and was identified as 14-year-old Colt Cray, a student of Apalachee High School in Winder, Georgia, about an hour outside of Atlanta. Two of those killed were students and two were teachers. Law enforcement agencies are still investigating the shooting and the motive behind it.</p>

<p>The high school had received an earlier phone threat, multiple law enforcement officials told CNN.</p>

<p>The phone call Wednesday morning warned there would be shootings at five schools, and that Apalachee would be the first. It is not known who placed the call. Officials tell CNN they are investigating the call and where it originated.</p>

<p>The US has suffered at least 385 mass shootings so far this year, according to the Gun Violence Archive, which, like CNN, defines mass shootings as those in which four or more victims are shot. That's an average of more than 1.5 mass shootings every day.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/ro6ijdvo_joe-biden_625x300_11_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Joe Biden called the shooting incident another horrific reminder of gun violence which tears communities]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/british-hiker-found-dead-another-missing-in-spains-mallorca-after-storm-6493772]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[British Hiker Found Dead, Another Missing In Spain's Mallorca After Storm]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/british-hiker-found-dead-another-missing-in-spains-mallorca-after-storm-6493772]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Sep 2024 08:05:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A British hiker has been found dead and another is missing on the Spanish island of Mallorca after heavy rains swept over the popular tourist destination, emergency services said on Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A British hiker has been found dead and another is missing on the Spanish island of Mallorca after heavy rains swept over the popular tourist destination, emergency services said on Wednesday.</p>

<p>Emergency services had been looking for the two hikers since Monday night in an area of mountains in Mallorca where the Torrent de Pareis canyon descends to the Mediterranean, a police spokeswoman told AFP.</p>

<p>The search was called off on Wednesday at around 1900 GMT as dusk fell, with emergency services saying it would resume on Thursday.</p>

<p>"The body found is that of a woman and the missing person is a man," police said in a statement, adding that the search for the man had been suspended because of poor weather but would resume when conditions improved.</p>

<p>Juan Carlos Rodriguez, the head of the Mountain Rescue Group brigade in the Balearic islands, told reporters they had rescued 10 people who were hiking in the canyon and "were surprised by the storm".</p>

<p>"They were the ones who told us that they had seen two people who had been swept away by the water," he said.</p>

<p>"When you don't look at the weather before, and you are in a foreign country doing sport tourism, or sun and beach tourism, that leads to people having accidents," he added.</p>

<p>Local authorities had called for people to be careful due to the "very intense storms" that were expected.</p>

<p>"Avoid outdoor activities (going to the beach, hiking, water sports)," the archipelago's emergency services warned on X.</p>

<p>Mallorca remained on alert on Wednesday for heavy rains and strong winds, with the national weather office Aemet warning that gusts of over 120 kilometres (75 miles) per hour were possible.</p>

<p>The Mediterranean island, known for its picturesque beaches and sunny weather, is one of Europe's most visited destinations. It is especially popular with German and British tourists.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2015-09/spanish-police_650x400_81441914061.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The search was called off as dusk fell, with emergency services to resume on Thursday (representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/polio-first-phase-vaccination-campaign-in-gaza-successful-who-6493713]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Polio First Phase Vaccination Campaign In Gaza Successful: WHO]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/polio-first-phase-vaccination-campaign-in-gaza-successful-who-6493713]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Sep 2024 07:50:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The first phase of a large-scale polio vaccination campaign in Gaza has concluded successfully, the World Health Organization said on Wednesday, providing nearly 200,000 children in the centre of the Palestinian territory with their initial dose.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The first phase of a large-scale polio vaccination campaign in Gaza has concluded successfully, the World Health Organization said on Wednesday, providing nearly 200,000 children in the centre of the Palestinian territory with their initial dose.</p>

<p>With Gaza lying in ruins and the majority of its 2.4 million residents forced to flee their homes due to Israel's military assault -- often taking refuge in cramped and unsanitary conditions -- disease has spread.</p>

<p>After the first confirmed polio case in 25 years, a massive vaccination effort began on Sunday, aided by localised "humanitarian pauses" in fighting.</p>

<p>The campaign aims to fully vaccinate more than 640,000 children in the besieged territory, devastated by almost 11 months of war.</p>

<p>During the first phase of the campaign, conducted between September 1 and 3 in central Gaza, more than 187,000 children under the age of 10 were reached, the WHO said in a statement.</p>

<p>"We are grateful for the dedication of all the families, health workers and vaccinators who made this part of the campaign a success despite the dire conditions in the Gaza Strip," WHO chief Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus said on X, formerly Twitter.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">The first phase of <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/polio?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#polio</a> vaccination in central <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Gaza?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Gaza</a> is complete. Over 187,000 children under the age of ten were vaccinated, well over the target of 156,500. The numbers are being finalised.<br />
<br />
Four fixed sites will continue to offer polio vaccination for the next three days in… <a href="https://t.co/QB0MHCSltF">pic.twitter.com/QB0MHCSltF</a></p>
— Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus (@DrTedros) <a href="https://twitter.com/DrTedros/status/1831251117935595998?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 4, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>"We ask for the humanitarian pauses to continue to be respected. We continue to call for a ceasefire."</p>

<p>The WHO had estimated that vaccines would be needed for nearly 157,000 children below the age of 10 in central Gaza but acknowledged that that was an underestimate.</p>

<p>This it said was "due to population movement towards central Gaza, and expanded coverage in areas outside the humanitarian pause zone". &nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>No child left behind&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>More than 500 teams, consisting of nearly 2,200 health and community outreach workers, took part in the campaign in central Gaza, with vaccinations provided at 143 fixed sites across the area.</p>

<p>In addition, mobile teams visited tents and hard-to-reach areas, including those outside the agreed humanitarian pause zone.</p>

<p>While the large-scale campaign in central Gaza is over, the WHO said that vaccinations would continue at four large health facilities there over the next few days "to ensure no child is missed in the area".</p>

<p>The main focus is meanwhile set to move to southern Gaza, where an estimated 340,000 children over the next four days will receive their first dose.</p>

<p>And finally, the campaign will be concentrated in northern Gaza between September 9 and 11, targeting around 150,000 children, the WHO said.</p>

<p>A fresh campaign to provide a needed second dose is due to begin in about four weeks time.</p>

<p>The WHO has stressed that it is vital to reach at least 90 per cent coverage to avoid the spread of the disease both within Gaza's borders and beyond.</p>

<p>"We want to ensure... there will be no other Gaza children who actually will suffer from polio," Rik Peeperkorn, the WHO's representative for the Palestinian territories, told reporters on Wednesday.</p>

<p>"But we also want to make sure that we prevent the spread of polio to neighbouring countries."</p>

<p>The October 7 Hamas attack that sparked the war resulted in the deaths of 1,205 people, mostly civilians and including hostages killed in captivity, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli official figures.</p>

<p>Israel's campaign against Hamas since October 7 has killed at least 40,861 people in Gaza, according to the territory's health ministry. The UN rights office says most of the dead are women and children.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/h72e6gno_gaza-vaccination-x_625x300_05_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A fresh campaign to provide a needed second dose is due to begin in about four weeks time.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>