<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Sun, 13 Oct 2024 10:54:09 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/woman-dies-after-falling-overboard-from-luxury-cruise-ship-off-channel-islands-6778113]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Woman Dies After Falling Overboard From Cruise Ship Off Channel Islands]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/woman-dies-after-falling-overboard-from-luxury-cruise-ship-off-channel-islands-6778113]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 13 Oct 2024 10:49:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Though rescuers retrieved her from the water and rushed her to the hospital, she was pronounced dead.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A woman in her 20s has died after falling from the MSC Virtuosa cruise ship into the English Channel. According to a report by <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c8j7v22d40eo">BBC,&nbsp;</a></em>a&nbsp;distress signal was issued by the 18-deck cruise ship, after the woman went overboard near Les Casquets rocks, west of Alderney, around midnight on Saturday.&nbsp;One passenger told the <em>BBC</em> an alarm rang three times to signal a person had gone overboard.</p>

<p>A plane from Channel Islands Air Search was dispatched from Guernsey to scour the area, while lifeboat crews from both Alderney and France rushed to the scene. Additionally, a French helicopter crew based near Cherbourg joined the search and rescue operation, working in tandem to locate and retrieve the woman.&nbsp;</p>

<p><iframe allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="true" frameborder="0" height="773" scrolling="no" src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/post.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2Fchannelislandsairsearch%2Fposts%2Fpfbid02KE3p4UfMK5bSnBD4dQqHmteMZWTb3gVx3U3DCrt6sUb52u9ApTCDdhMnY6ib8fQKl&amp;show_text=true&amp;width=500" style="border:none;overflow:hidden" width="500"></iframe></p>

<p></p>

<p>Though rescuers retrieved her from the water and rushed her to the hospital, she was pronounced dead despite medical efforts.&nbsp;The woman's identity and nationality have not been publicly released.</p>

<p>A French coastguard spokesman said, ''The H160 helicopter finds the person in its search area and hoists them out. The helicopter lands at the Tourlaville rescue centre where a medical team declared the dead.''</p>

<p>The ship's owner MSC Cruises said: "A guest on board MSC Virtuosa went overboard on 12 October, while the ship was sailing to Southampton.&nbsp; The body was later recovered with the involvement of the authorities. We are deeply saddened by this tragic event, and our thoughts are with the family during this difficult time. Out of respect for their privacy, we will not be providing further details.''</p>

<p>British and French police are now probing the woman's death.</p>

<p>The MSC Virtuosa, a Maltese-flagged cruise ship, is 331 meters (1,086 feet) in length and 43 meters (141 feet) in width. With 19 decks, this mega-ship can accommodate up to 6,334 passengers and 1,704 crew members. Currently, it is docked at Southampton, having arrived at 08:00 from Cartagena Port in Spain, according to MarineTraffic.<br />
&nbsp;</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/1g7r8elo_msc_625x300_13_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[British and French police are now probing the womans death.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/covid-19-infections-from-1st-wave-linked-to-elevated-risks-of-heart-attack-study-finds-6777938]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[First Wave Covid Infections Linked To Higher Heart Attack Risks: Study]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/covid-19-infections-from-1st-wave-linked-to-elevated-risks-of-heart-attack-study-finds-6777938]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 13 Oct 2024 10:03:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[As per the research, unvaccinated individuals infected with the virus in 2019 and 2020 are at a notably higher risk of experiencing a heart attack or stroke, with this risk lasting for up to three years after infection.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Individuals diagnosed with severe Covid-19 infections during the initial wave of the pandemic may face twice the risk of experiencing heart attacks and strokes, according to a new study. The research, published this week in the journal Arteriosclerosis, Thrombosis, and Vascular Biology and backed by the National Institutes of Health, revealed that the increased risk could persist for as long as three years.</p>

<p>The study found that those who have ever contracted Covid-19 are twice as likely to experience heart attacks, strokes, and mortality compared to those who have never been infected. Furthermore, for those who were hospitalised due to the virus, the risk increases to four times higher.</p>

<p>According to Dr Hooman Allayee, the study's principal investigator, the cardiovascular threats posed by severe Covid-19 are comparable to those associated with type 2 diabetes. "Cardiovascular mortality trends from 2010 to 2019 were steadily declining. Then, all of a sudden, between 2020 and 2022, ten years of progress were completely wiped out because of Covid-19,"<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://abcnews.go.com/Health/covid-19-infections-1st-wave-linked-higher-risk/story?id=114734406" rel="NoFollowNoIndex"> ABC News quoted</a> Dr Allayee as saying.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ahajournals.org/doi/10.1161/ATVBAHA.124.321001">The findings </a>particularly underscore the risks associated with different blood types, revealing that individuals with blood types A, B, and AB are more vulnerable to increased cardiovascular complications from Covid-19, whereas those with type O blood exhibit a lower risk.</p>

<p>The research utilized data from the UK Biobank, which predominantly includes older, wealthier, and mostly white participants. However, similar studies in other demographics have yielded comparable results, according to Dr Allayee.</p>

<p>Emphasising the critical role of vaccinations, Dr Allayee stated, "No matter what vaccine you received, just six months after the vaccination or booster, the chance of heart attack and stroke decreased. But immunity wanes over time, which is why you need boosters."</p>

<p>Individuals who have had severe Covid-19, particularly those requiring hospitalisation, are urged to consult their healthcare providers about the potential long-term health implications of the virus. "It's not going away, so we have to start talking about it. Stay on top of your vaccinations and boosters and get regular check-ups," Dr Allayee advised.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-01/d31ktkno_covid-19-_625x300_11_January_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[For those who were hospitalised due to the virus, the risk increases to four times higher.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korea-leader-kim-jong-uns-sister-warns-of-horrible-disaster-as-a-response-to-drones-6777856]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kim Jong Un's Sister Warns Of "Horrible Disaster" As A Response To Drones]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korea-leader-kim-jong-uns-sister-warns-of-horrible-disaster-as-a-response-to-drones-6777856]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 13 Oct 2024 09:48:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The powerful sister of North Korean leader Kim Jong Un warned Saturday that Seoul would face a "horrible disaster" if unmanned drones reached Pyongyang again, a day after accusing the South of launching such aircraft at the capital.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The powerful sister of North Korean leader Kim Jong Un warned Saturday that Seoul would face a "horrible disaster" if unmanned drones reached Pyongyang again, a day after accusing the South of launching such aircraft at the capital.</p>

<p>North Korea on Friday said the South had sent drones carrying propaganda leaflets into Pyongyang's airspace on October 3, and then again on Wednesday and Thursday this week.</p>

<p>South Korea's Defense Minister Kim Yong-Hyun initially denied the claim, but the Joint Chiefs of Staff later amended that position, saying in a statement that they "cannot confirm whether the North Korean allegations are true or not."</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kim-jong-uns-sister-kim-yo-jong-denies-north-korea-exporting-weapons-to-russia-5681555">Kim Yo Jong</a>, the sister of Pyongyang's leader and a key regime spokesperson, said Seoul's refusal to confirm the allegations meant that the drones were sent by "the military gangsters", referring to Seoul's forces.</p>

<p>"The moment that a drone of the ROK is discovered in the sky over our capital city once again will certainly lead to a horrible disaster," she added in a statement released late Saturday, using the acronym for South Korea's official name.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The drones allegedly sent by the South had dropped anti-regime propaganda, and the leaflets were filled with "inflammatory rumours and rubbish", the North's official Korean Central News Agency (KCNA) reported on Friday.</p>

<p>KCNA described the incident as a "wanton violation of the international law and a grave military attack".</p>

<p>Despite official efforts to prevent them from doing so, South Korean activists have long flown <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korea-sends-more-balloons-as-kim-jong-uns-sister-warns-of-new-counteraction-5863483">balloons</a> with anti-Kim propaganda leaflets and other materials, including USB sticks containing K-pop and South Korean television dramas, over the border, a tactic that the North has protested against.</p>

<p>In response, the North -- where the government is extremely sensitive about its people gaining access to South Korean pop culture products -- has launched more than 6,000 trash-carrying balloons southward since May.</p>

<p>Relations between the two Koreas are at their lowest point in years, after a military agreement meant to reduce tensions was fully suspended over the balloon incidents in June.&nbsp;</p>

<p>North Korean leader Kim recently said that his country would use nuclear weapons "without hesitation" if attacked by the South.</p>

<p>In 2022, five North Korean drones crossed into the South, the first such incident in five years, prompting the South Korean military to fire warning shots and deploy fighter jets.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The jets failed to shoot down any of the North Korean drones.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-07/p0rtvip8_kim-yo-jong-koreausa_625x300_17_July_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Relations between the two Koreas are at their lowest point in years. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-israeli-strikes-outside-hezbollah-strongholds-kill-15-says-lebanon-6777659]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[New Israeli Strikes Outside Hezbollah Strongholds Kill 15, Says Lebanon]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-israeli-strikes-outside-hezbollah-strongholds-kill-15-says-lebanon-6777659]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 13 Oct 2024 08:58:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Lebanon's health ministry said Israeli strikes on three villages outside traditional Hezbollah strongholds had killed at least 15 people Saturday, as state media reported further strikes elsewhere]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lebanon's health ministry said Israeli strikes on three villages outside traditional Hezbollah strongholds had killed at least 15 people Saturday, as state media reported further strikes elsewhere.</p>

<p>An "Israeli enemy strike on Maaysra", a Shiite Muslim majority village in a mostly Christian mountain area north of Beirut, left "nine dead and 15 wounded", the ministry said in a statement, updating an earlier toll.</p>

<p>An AFP correspondent in Maaysra saw excavators trying to remove chunks of a destroyed building. Emergency workers, one using a manual sledgehammer, tried to break through a huge slab of concrete.</p>

<p>Separately, the ministry said four people had been killed and 18 others wounded in an "Israeli enemy strike" on Barja in the Shouf district south of the capital.</p>

<p>The ministry reported two dead, four wounded and "body parts" in an Israeli strike on Deir Billa, some 15 kilometres (nine miles) from the town of Batroun on Lebanon's north coast.</p>

<p>DNA tests were being carried out to determine the identity of the remains, the statement added.</p>

<p>The official National News Agency (NNA) had said an "Israeli strike" targeted a house in Deir Billa where families from <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/more-israeli-strikes-pound-beirut-after-fresh-warning-from-iran-10-points-6719624">south Lebanon</a> had taken refuge.</p>

<p>Another AFP correspondent in Deir Billa saw a mattress, pillows, bed covers, a washing basket and clothes among the wreckage, as people sifted through the rubble by hand and smoke rose from a smouldering pile.</p>

<p>In east Lebanon, the management of the Tal Chiha hospital said in a statement that the facility had sustained "light material damage" due to "strikes that targeted the vicinity" of the mainly Christian town of Zahle.</p>

<p>No patients or staff had been injured and the hospital was still operating, it added.</p>

<p>Since September 23, Israel has been <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-carries-out-new-strikes-in-lebanon-minutes-after-netanyahus-speech-at-un-6664911">heavily bombarding</a> south and east Lebanon, as well as Beirut's southern suburbs, saying it is targeting Hezbollah sites.</p>

<p>The mountain area near Maaysra as well as Barja, Deir Billa and Zahle are not areas usually considered Hezbollah strongholds.</p>

<h3><strong>'Huge damage'&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Later Saturday, the NNA said "Israeli warplanes... carried out a strike that targeted the centre of the marketplace" in Nabatiyeh, a major city in south Lebanon around 12 kilometres from the border with Israel.</p>

<p>The health ministry reported eight wounded in a "provisional toll" for that strike, adding that rescue workers were still removing rubble.</p>

<p>Israel's army last week told residents to evacuate the city, which is home to public institutions, hospitals and a branch of the Lebanese University.</p>

<p>The ministry also said two people had been wounded in an "Israeli enemy strike on the civil defence centre" belonging to the<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hezbollah-carrying-out-fresh-strikes-on-hezbollah-targets-in-lebanon-says-israel-army-6677154"> Hezbollah-affiliated</a> Islamic Health Committee in the south Lebanon village of Aiteet.</p>

<p>And in the eastern Bekaa Valley, the NNA also reported that "enemy aircraft carried out a series of strikes".</p>

<p>The health ministry said the Tal Chiha hospital and two others in the Bekaa Valley had sustained "material damage" in the strikes. The NNA reported "huge damage to houses and property and institutions" and to a university in nearby Riyaq.</p>

<p>Almost a year of cross-border exchanges between Israel and Hezbollah escalated into an all-out war on September 23.</p>

<p>The health ministry said Saturday that 26 people had been killed the previous day, reporting 2,255 dead in a year of violence.</p>

<p>More than half of those have been since September 23, according to an AFP tally.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/gf9scarg_israel-strike-on-lebanon-_625x300_13_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Almost a year of cross-border Israel-Hezbollah exchanges escalated into an all-out war on September 23.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/egyptair-passenger-severely-injured-after-overhead-luggage-falls-on-his-face-6777472]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[EgyptAir Passenger Severely Injured After Overhead Luggage Falls On Him]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/egyptair-passenger-severely-injured-after-overhead-luggage-falls-on-his-face-6777472]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 13 Oct 2024 08:00:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The bag's impact caused significant harm, including a cracked upper incisor tooth and severe facial injuries.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Connecticut man, Jarek Neczypor, 31, has filed a federal lawsuit against EgyptAir, alleging he suffered severe physical and mental injuries during a flight from Cairo to John F. Kennedy Airport in New York. According to the Manhattan federal court filing, the incident occurred on August 17 aboard Flight 985 when a rolling bag fell from the overhead compartment above his assigned seat, striking him in the face.</p>

<p>The bag's impact caused significant harm, including a cracked upper incisor tooth and severe facial injuries, the <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/10/12/us-news/egyptair-flight-to-jfk-left-man-with-severe-injuries-suit/">New York Post</a></em> reported. To compound the situation, the cabin crew relocated Neczypor to another seat, which was allegedly damaged and not secured to the floor. For the remainder of the 11.5-hour flight, Mr Neczypor endured neck and back injuries due to the defective seat.</p>

<p>Mr Neczypor's lawsuit seeks unspecified damages from EgyptAir, citing pain, anguish, and mental suffering. The incident has reportedly left him with lasting physical and emotional trauma. The lawsuit alleges EgyptAir's negligence and failure to ensure passenger safety led to Mr Neczypor's injuries.</p>

<p>A similar incident happened in July when an <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/cathay-pacific-passenger-76-hospitalised-after-hand-baggage-falls-on-her-head-6084766">elderly woman on a Cathay Pacific flight</a> bound for London was hurt when a piece of luggage fell from an overhead compartment and hit her on the head. According to the&nbsp;<em><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/society/article/3269682/passenger-hong-kong-london-cathay-flight-injured-after-hand-baggage-falls-and-hits-her-head">South China Morning Post</a></em>, the incident happened when the flight left Hong Kong International Airport for London Heathrow Airport. The woman received medical assistance at the airport before being transferred to North Lantau Hospital for further treatment.</p>

<p>A spokesperson for Cathay Pacific said: ''The reason for the injury could be down to a misplaced item of luggage in the overhead storage compartment. Our cabin crew and ground staff immediately called for assistance, sent the passenger to a nearby hospital for further medical care, cancelled the flight for the passenger and her family members, and arranged for the family members to stay at an airport hotel.''</p>

<p>Notably, airlines are usually liable for injuries sustained by passengers, unless they can demonstrate that the injury resulted from the passenger's own negligence.</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/md0ldnfg_egyptair_625x300_13_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[His lawsuit seeks unspecified damages from EgyptAir, citing pain, anguish, and mental suffering.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/champion-of-india-israel-friendship-israeli-pm-benjamin-netanyahu-condoles-ratan-tatas-death-6776238]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Champion Of India-Israel Friendship": Netanyahu Condoles Ratan Tata's Death]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/champion-of-india-israel-friendship-israeli-pm-benjamin-netanyahu-condoles-ratan-tatas-death-6776238]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 13 Oct 2024 00:43:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister of Israel Benjamin Netanyahu wrote to Narendra Modi today condoling the death of industrialist and global icon Ratan Tata. He said many people in his country are mourning Mr Tata's death.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister of Israel Benjamin Netanyahu wrote to Narendra Modi today condoling the death of industrialist and global icon Ratan Tata. He said many people in his country are mourning Mr Tata's death.</p>

<p>Ratan Tata died on October 9 at Mumbai's Breach Candy Hospital, where he was admitted for a routine health check due to his age.</p>

<p>With words of appreciation for Mr Tata's contribution in bridging India-Israel ties, Mr Netanyahu wrote, "I and many in Israel mourn the loss of Ratan Naval Tata, a proud son of India and a champion of the friendship between our two countries."</p>

<p>He also asked the prime minister to "convey my condolences to Ratan's family."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">To my friend, Prime Minister <a href="https://twitter.com/narendramodi?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@narendramodi</a>.<br />
I and many in Israel mourn the loss of Ratan Naval Tata, a proud son of India and a champion of the friendship between our two countries. ????<br />
<br />
Please convey my condolences to Ratan's family.<br />
<br />
In sympathy,<br />
Benjamin Netanyahu</p>
— Prime Minister of Israel (@IsraeliPM) <a href="https://twitter.com/IsraeliPM/status/1845157094384660628?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 12, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>Mr Netanyahu joined several world leaders in paying a tribute to Mr Tata, who was one of the most respected industrial titans in India. He is credited for his <span jsslot=""><span class="JgzqYd">philanthropic </span></span>work and for expanding the Tata Group to more than 100 countries.</p>

<p>"India and the world have lost a giant with a giant heart," said Eric Garcetti, US Ambassador to India, in his condolence message. He went on to say "When I was nominated to serve as ambassador, the first congratulations from India came from Ratan Tata."</p>

<p>Mr Garcetti also mentioned how Mr Tata "gave so much in service to my hometown, serving on the board of the University of Southern California. He saw a future of greater prosperity and equality for his country and did so much for our world," adding that "May his memory be a blessing."</p>

<p>Remembering Ratan Tata's "visionary contribution", French President Emmanuel Macron said, "France has lost a dear friend from India. Ratan Tata's visionary helmsmanship contributed to boosting industries in Indiaand France, in the fields of innovation and manufacturing. Beyond this, his legacy will be marked by his humanist vision, immense philanthropic achievements and his humility."</p>

<p>"I convey my deepest condolences to his near and dear ones as well as to the people of India. We will remember your lifelong commitment to the betterment of society with admiration and respect," President Macron said in post on Facebook.</p>

<p>Several prominent business leaders also sent their tributes, with Google CEO Sundar Pichai and Microsoft founder Bill Gates being among the first to do so.</p>

<p>Mr Pichai recalled his last meeting with Mr Tata, saying "My last meeting with Ratan Tata at Google, we talked about the progress of Waymo and his vision was inspiring to hear. He leaves an extraordinary business and philanthropic legacy and was instrumental in mentoring and developing the modern business leadership in India."</p>

<p>He also said that Mr Tata "deeply cared about making India better. Deep condolences to his loved ones and Rest in Peace Shri Ratan Tata Ji".</p>

<p>Bill Gates too expressed his condolences on the death of Ratan Tata, a "visionary leader whose dedication to improving lives left an indelible mark on India - and the world".</p>

<p>In a LinkedIn Post, Bill Gates recalled meeting Mr Tata on multiple occasions and expressed his admiration for the business tycoon's commitment to improving lives. "I was always moved by his strong sense of purpose and service to humanity," Mr Gates wrote in his post. He also recalled collaborating with Mr Tata on several initiatives and said that his legacy will inspire generations.</p>

<p>"Ratan Tata was a visionary leader whose dedication to improving lives left an indelible mark on India-and the world. I had the privilege of meeting him on several occasions, and I was always moved by his strong sense of purpose and service to humanity," Mr Gates wrote.</p>

<p>"Together, we partnered on numerous initiatives to help people lead healthier, more prosperous lives. His loss will be felt around the world for years to come, but I know the legacy he left and example he set will continue to inspire generations," he added.</p>

<p>Mr Tata's death has drawn an outpouring of grief and tributes from across the world. Prime Minister Narendra Modi remembered Mr Tata as a visionary business leader and a compassionate soul.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/d39lsmd8_ratan-tata_625x300_11_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israeli PM Benjamin Netanyahu wrote to Narendra Modi today condoling Ratan Tata's death.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-makes-medical-report-public-claims-donald-trump-refuses-to-do-so-6775361]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris Makes Medical Report Public, Claims Trump Refuses To Do So]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-makes-medical-report-public-claims-donald-trump-refuses-to-do-so-6775361]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 12 Oct 2024 21:43:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Vice President Kamala Harris, the Democratic presidential nominee, released a letter from her doctor on Saturday that pronounced her in good health and fit for high office, in an effort to draw a contrast with her counterpart, Donald Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Vice President Kamala Harris, the Democratic presidential nominee, released a letter from her doctor today that pronounced her in good health and fit for high office, in an effort to draw a contrast with her counterpart, Donald Trump.</p>

<p>In a memo distributed by the White House, the vice president's physician, Joshua Simmons, said Harris's most recent physical exam in April was "unremarkable," that she maintains an active lifestyle and "very healthy diet" despite a busy schedule, suffers from seasonal allergies and sporadic hives, does not use tobacco and drinks alcohol only in moderation.</p>

<p>"She possesses the physical and mental resiliency required to successfully execute the duties of the Presidency, to include those as Chief Executive, Head of State and Commander in Chief," the doctor wrote.</p>

<p>Harris, 59, is running against Republican Trump, 78, for the White House. She made her medical information public today in an effort to draw attention to his refusal to do so, a Harris campaign aide said.</p>

<p>The Harris campaign is eager to highlight the former president's age since he became the oldest candidate in the race after President Joe Biden, 81, stepped aside as the Democratic standard bearer following a poor debate performance against Trump.</p>

<p>Locked in a very tight race. Harris' campaign hopes that contrasting her comparative youth and mental acuity with Trump's more advanced age and tendency to meander, along with the differences in transparency between the two, will help convince undecided voters that she is more fit for office than he.</p>

<p>A White House doctor said in 2018 when Trump was in office that he was in overall excellent health then but needed to shed weight and start a daily exercise routine.</p>

<p>Simmons said Harris's allergies had been well-managed with over-the-counter and prescription medications.</p>

<p>Her urticaria or hives were "sporadic and transient and do not seem to be triggered by any particular exposure nor are they associated with other symptoms" and respond well to antihistamine treatment.</p>

<p>Harris has been on allergen immunotherapy for the last three years, dramatically improving her allergy and urticaria symptoms and negating her need for medication other than occasional nasal spray, he said.</p>

<p>Harris wears contact lenses. Her family history includes her mother's colon cancer. Harris was up to date on preventative health procedures including colonoscopy and annual mammograms, he said.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/if09613_kamala-harris_625x300_25_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kamala Harris released a letter from her doctor declaring her in good health and fit for high office]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-conflict-update-un-warns-of-regional-conflict-as-israeli-forces-battle-hezbollah-hamas-6775221]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UN Warns of Regional Conflict As Israeli Forces Battle Hezbollah, Hamas]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-conflict-update-un-warns-of-regional-conflict-as-israeli-forces-battle-hezbollah-hamas-6775221]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 12 Oct 2024 21:11:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[UN peacekeepers in Lebanon warned Saturday against a "catastrophic" regional conflict as Israeli forces battled Hezbollah and Hamas militants on two fronts, on the holiest day of the Jewish calendar.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>UN peacekeepers in Lebanon warned Saturday against a "catastrophic" regional conflict as Israeli forces battled Hezbollah and Hamas militants on two fronts, on the holiest day of the Jewish calendar.</p>

<p>Israel has faced a fierce diplomatic backlash over incidents in south Lebanon that saw five Blue Helmets wounded.</p>

<p>On Saturday, the Lebanese health ministry said Israeli air strikes on two villages located near the capital Beirut killed nine people.</p>

<p>Israel had earlier told residents of south Lebanon not to return home, as its troops fought Hezbollah militants in a war that has killed more than 1,200 people since September 23, and forced more than a million others to flee their homes.</p>

<p>"For your own protection, do not return to your homes until further notice... Do not go south; anyone who goes south may put his life at risk," Israeli military spokesman Avichay Adraee posted on X.</p>

<p>Hezbollah said Saturday it launched missiles across the border into northern Israel, where air raid sirens sounded and the military said it had intercepted a projectile.</p>

<p>In an interview with AFP, UNIFIL spokesman Andrea Tenenti told AFP he feared an Israeli escalation against Hezbollah in south Lebanon could soon spiral out of control "into a regional conflict with catastrophic impact for everyone".</p>

<p>The UN force said five peacekeepers have been wounded by fighting in south Lebanon in just two days, and Tenenti said "a lot of damage" had been caused to its posts there.</p>

<p>Around Israel, markets were closed and public transport halted as observant Jews fasted and prayed on Yom Kippur.</p>

<p>After the holiday, attention is likely to turn again to Israel's expected retaliation against Iran, which launched around 200 missiles at Israel on October 1.</p>

<p>Israel began pounding Gaza shortly after suffering its worst ever attacks from Iran-backed Hamas militants on October 7 last year, and it launched a ground offensive against Hezbollah in Lebanon on September 30.</p>

<p><strong>'Deliberately targeted'</strong></p>

<p>On Friday, Israel faced criticism from the UN, its Western allies and others over what it said was a "hit" on a UN peacekeeping position in Lebanon.</p>

<p>Two Sri Lankan peacekeepers were hurt in the second such incident in two days, UNIFIL said Friday.</p>

<p>Israel's military said soldiers had responded to "an immediate threat" around 50 metres (yards) from the UNIFIL base in Naqura, and has pledged to carry out a "thorough review".</p>

<p>The Irish military's chief of staff, Sean Clancy, said it was "not an accidental act", and French President Emmanuel Macron said he believed the peacekeepers had been "deliberately targeted".</p>

<p>Both countries are major contributors to UNIFIL whose peacekeepers are on the front line of the Israel-Hezbollah war.</p>

<p>Efforts to negotiate an end to the fighting have so far failed, but Lebanese Prime Minister Najib Mikati said his government would ask the UN Security Council to issue a new resolution calling for a "full and immediate ceasefire".</p>

<p>Lebanon's military said Friday an Israeli strike on one of its positions in south Lebanon killed two soldiers.</p>

<p>In a show of support for Iran's ally Hezbollah, the speaker of the Iranian parliament Mohammad Bagher Ghalibaf visited the site Saturday of a deadly Israeli strike earlier this week.</p>

<p>A source close to Hezbollah said the strike had targeted Hezbollah's security chief Wafiq Safa, but neither Hezbollah nor Israel has confirmed he was the target.</p>

<p>Ghalibaf's Lebanon visit, a signal of Tehran's defiance, comes after Israel vowed to respond to Iran's second-ever direct attack.</p>

<p>Israeli Defence Minister Yoav Gallant has vowed that the response will be "deadly, precise and surprising".</p>

<p>The United States is pushing for a "proportionate" response that would not tip the region into a wider war, with President Joe Biden urging Israel to avoid striking Iranian nuclear facilities or energy infrastructure.</p>

<p><strong>Gaza deaths</strong></p>

<p>Iran-backed Hezbollah began firing on Israel in support of its Palestinian ally Hamas following the October 7, 2023 attack on Israel which resulted in the deaths of 1,206 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on official Israeli figures, which includes hostages killed in captivity.</p>

<p>Israel's military campaign in Gaza has wrought devastation and, according to data from the health ministry in the Hamas-run territory, killed 42,175 people, a majority civilians.</p>

<p>Israeli operations in Gaza continue, with the army laying siege to an area around Jabalia in the north, causing more suffering for hundreds of thousands of people trapped there, according to the UN agency for Palestinian refugees.</p>

<p>Adraee, the Israeli military spokesman, posted another evacuation warning Saturday for an area near Jabalia.</p>

<p>"The specified area, including the shelters within it, is considered a dangerous combat zone," Adraee said on X, ordering residents to move to the humanitarian zone in southern Gaza.</p>

<p>Some residents said they were not prepared to do so.</p>

<p>"They tell us to go south, but we won't go because of the dangers and the army is shooting at people there," 27-year-old Sami Asliya told AFP.</p>

<p>"There is no safe place, neither in the south nor in the north -- everyone is at risk of death," he said.</p>

<p>On Friday, Gaza's civil defence agency reported 30 people killed in Israeli strikes in the area, including on schools being used as shelter by displaced people.</p>

<p>An AFP journalist in Gaza reported heavy shelling, explosions and gunfire Saturday further south in Gaza City's Zeitoun neighbourhood.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2015-12/united-nations-reuters_650x400_71450246137.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel has faced a fierce diplomatic backlash over incidents in south Lebanon. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/i-will-kill-you-screaming-delta-passenger-jumps-behind-check-in-counter-dodges-police-6775217]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Screaming Delta Passenger Jumps Behind Check-In Counter, Dodges Police]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/i-will-kill-you-screaming-delta-passenger-jumps-behind-check-in-counter-dodges-police-6775217]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 12 Oct 2024 21:10:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The video shows the woman already standing behind the ticket counter. She loudly declares, "Don't trust cops, only trust firemen."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Delta Air Lines passenger caused a major disruption at an airport, jumping behind the check-in counter and evading police while making threats against them.&nbsp; A video, originally posted on TikTok and now spreading across various social media platforms, shows the woman, dressed in a yellow sweater, already standing behind the ticket counter. She loudly declares, "Don't trust cops, only trust firemen."</p>

<p>When an officer approaches, she shouts, "Get away from me!" and runs off, repeatedly telling the police to stay back.</p>

<p>At one point, she threatens the officers, saying, "I will kill you, I will f***ing kill you," while pointing at them.</p>

<p>As another officer moves to arrest her, she quickly dodges him, causing him to stumble and fall in his attempt to catch her.</p>

<p>The woman then ducks under a barrier and returns behind the counter before finally being restrained by officers at the end of the 30-second clip.</p>

<p><strong>Watch the video here:</strong></p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Woman at Delta Air Check-in Loses It ?<br />
<br />
The incident at Savannah/Hilton Head International Airport (SAV) sees a woman yelling “Get away from me” and continuing to scream before running away as security comes to stop her.<br />
<br />
“Don't trust cops, only trust firemen,” she screams… <a href="https://t.co/kWbLenRQuw">pic.twitter.com/kWbLenRQuw</a></p>
— Steve Gruber (@stevegrubershow) <a href="https://twitter.com/stevegrubershow/status/1844852311618904282?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 11, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>The video, posted on Wednesday, features the caption, "I'm just trying to get my boarding pass," along with a smiling face with a tear emoji.</p>

<p>The incident took place at Savannah/Hilton Head International Airport in Georgia, although the exact date is unclear.</p>

<p>The woman's identity, any charges against her, and the reason for her outburst have not yet been disclosed.</p>

<p>Social media users humorously commented on the moment when she dodged the officer who fell to the ground.</p>

<p>"No one going to talk about the footwork ?? colts about to sign her," a user commented.</p>

<p>Another user remarked of the cop, "Falling like that would push me into retirement."</p>

<p>"give her a football...she's got some moves," the third user wrote on X.</p>

<p><br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/nq5sg31o_us-woman-screams-at-cop_625x300_12_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The incident took place at Savannah/Hilton Head International Airport in Georgia]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/narendra-modi-the-change-maker-we-need-former-uk-pm-boris-johnson-writes-in-memoir-6773521]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Narendra Modi The "Change-Maker We Need": Former UK PM In Memoir]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/narendra-modi-the-change-maker-we-need-former-uk-pm-boris-johnson-writes-in-memoir-6773521]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 12 Oct 2024 21:10:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Narendra Modi has been written about fondly by former British PM Boris Johnson in his memoir 'Unleashed' which will be available in bookstores in the UK in a few days.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi has been written about fondly by former British PM Boris Johnson in his memoir 'Unleashed' which will be available in bookstores in the UK in a few days.</p>

<p>The book, which journeys through Mr Johnson's very eventful, noteworthy and lively political career mentions about his meetings with Prime Minister Modi, calling him the "change-maker" we need. Writing about his very first meeting with the prime minister, Mr Johnson recalls "a curious astral energy" he had felt.</p>

<p>The former British prime minister has written an entire chapter dedicated to India and described ties between the two nations as "a relationship as good as it has ever been."</p>

<p>Calling Prime Minister Modi "exactly the partner of friend" he needed, Mr Johnson credited himself and PM Modi for laying the foundation for a free-trade pact between India and the UK.</p>

<p>The significance of India-UK ties could be seen in the former prime minister's book as he repeatedly mentions the "friendship" shared between the two countries, especially in the context of the Indo-Pacific region and its vision.</p>

<p>"For some reason, we went down to stand in the dark in the plaza by Tower Bridge, in front of a crowd of his supporters," Mr Johnson writes in the chapter titled 'Britain and India', referencing his first meeting with PM Modi during a visit to his City Hall office by the river Thames when he was Mayor of London.</p>

<p>"He raised my arm and chanted something or other in Hindi, and though I couldn't follow it I felt his curious astral energy. I have enjoyed his company ever since – because I reckon he is the change-maker our relationship needs. With Modi, I felt sure, we could not only do a great free-trade deal but also build a long-term partnership, as friends and equals," he writes.</p>

<p>Mr Johnson reveals how a "distinctly sniffy" UK Foreign Office had dissuaded him from meeting Mr Modi during an earlier mayoral trade delegation to India in 2012, a problem, he writes, which was "soon dropped" to pave the way for a relationship that "hit an all-time high".</p>

<p>In the book he also mentions how much he loves India, calling himself a "veteran" of many Indian weddings because his children with Sikh heritage ex-wife Marina Wheeler trace their roots to India.</p>

<p>While he writes with pride of a similar "Anglo-Indian syncretism" in politics with his diverse Cabinet as PM including many British Indians such as Rishi Sunak and Priti Patel, Mr Johnson laments the slow-paced growth of bilateral trade due to unnecessary trade barriers that leave UK visitors "clinking in with duty-free booze" for Indians starved of Scotch whisky at decent prices.</p>

<p>The "tremendous success" of his visit to India as PM in January 2022 he recalls as a much-needed "morale boost" and "balm for the soul" away from an increasingly belligerent domestic politics that would eventually end in his unceremonious exit from 10 Downing Street just a few months later.</p>

<p>He claims he had also wanted to use the visit to make a "gentle point to Narendra" on the issue of relations with Russia at a "global inflection point" with its conflict with Ukraine.</p>

<p>He writes: "I knew all the history and the sensitivities, the reasons for India's post-war non-alignment with the West, the seemingly unbreakable relationship with Moscow. I understand the Indian dependence – like China's – on Russian hydrocarbons."</p>

<p>"But I wondered if it was not time for a modulation, a rethink... As I was to put it to the Indians, Russian missiles were turning out to be less accurate, statistically, than my first serve at tennis. Did they really want to keep Russia as their main supplier of military hardware?" It is in this context that in another section of the book, where he showers the late Queen Elizabeth II with effusive praise for her deep personal knowledge of history and history-makers, he references his efforts to get India to take a "tougher line" with Russians.</p>

<p>"She remembered something the former Indian prime minister Jawaharlal Nehru had told her in the 1950s. 'He told me that India will always side with Russia and that some things will never change. They just are.' I cite that as an illustration of her amazing ability to reassure and to contextualise," he shares, with reference to his customary weekly audiences with the late monarch as prime minister.</p>

<p>Mr Johnson goes on to credit himself with injecting a broader vision for the India-UK partnership to go beyond trade and climate change and educational partnerships and embark on a whole programme of military and technological collaboration.</p>

<p>"Overcoming the qualms of the MoD (Ministry of Defence), who are always worried about India's closeness to Russia, we agreed to work together on all kinds of military technology, from submarines to helicopters to marine propulsion units," he proudly declares.</p>

<p>With 'Unleashed', Mr Johnson seems to be keen to stress a lack of bitterness over his undignified removal as PM in the wake of the partygate scandal of Covid law-breaking parties but is clear that it was Rishi Sunak, his eventual successor at 10 Downing Street, who precipitated the problems by resigning as chancellor from his Cabinet in June 2022.</p>

<p>"It was worse than a crime, I thought, it was a mistake – both for Rishi and for the party, never mind the country. So it proved," he writes, alluding to the recent disastrous general election result for the Tories.</p>

<p>"I don't blame Rishi for prematurely wanting to be PM; in fact I don't blame any of them, really, for trying to turf me out. It's just what Tory MPs do...It goes without saying that if we had all stuck together I have no doubt that we would have gone on to win in 2024, and a lot more of my friends would now have their seats," he claims.</p>

<p><strong><em>(Inputs from PTI)</em></strong><br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-04/ah0mb2r_narendra-modi-boris-johnson-reuters-photo_625x300_21_April_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[PM Modi has been written about fondly by former British PM Boris Johnson in his memoir 'Unleashed']]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/star-health-faces-68-000-ransom-demand-after-major-data-leak-launches-probe-6775106]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Star Health Faces $68,000 Ransom Demand After Data Leak, Launches Probe]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/star-health-faces-68-000-ransom-demand-after-major-data-leak-launches-probe-6775106]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 12 Oct 2024 20:50:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Star Health, India's biggest health insurer, on Saturday said it had received a ransom demand of $68,000 from a cyberhacker in connection with a leak of customer data and medical records.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Star Health, India's biggest health insurer, on Saturday said it had received a ransom demand of $68,000 from a cyberhacker in connection with a leak of customer data and medical records.</p>

<p>Star, which has a roughly $4 billion market cap, is battling a reputational and business crisis since Reuters reported on September 20 that a hacker had used Telegram chatbots and a website to leak customers' sensitive data, including tax details and medical claim papers.</p>

<p>The company, whose shares have declined 11%, has launched internal investigations and has taken legal action against Telegram and the hacker, whose website continues to share samples of Star customers' data.</p>

<p>Star, which has previously said it is a "victim of a targeted malicious cyberattack", on Saturday revealed for the first time that in August "the threat actor demanded a ransom of $68,000 in an email" addressed to the company's managing director and its chief executive.</p>

<p>The statement came after Indian stocks exchanges sought clarifications from Star on a Friday over a Reuters report that the company was investigating allegations that its chief security officer was involved in the data leak.</p>

<p>Star reiterated on Saturday it has found no wrongdoing by the official, Amarjeet Khanuja, though the internal investigation is ongoing.</p>

<p>Telegram has declined to share the account details or permanently ban accounts linked to the hacker - an individual dubbed xenZen - "despite multiple notices issued in this regard," Star said on Saturday.</p>

<p>Star said it has "sought the assistance" of Indian cyber security authorities to "help us identify" the hacker.</p>

<p>Telegram did not respond to a request for comment.</p>

<p>The Dubai-based messenger app has previously said it removed the chatbots when Reuters flagged them to the platform.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/3fpt5288_star-health_625x300_20_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The company has launched internal investigations and has taken legal action against Telegram. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/columbus-final-resting-place-revealed-researchers-to-confirm-ethnicity-6774619]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Columbus' Final Resting Place Revealed, Researchers To Confirm Ethnicity]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/columbus-final-resting-place-revealed-researchers-to-confirm-ethnicity-6774619]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 12 Oct 2024 19:28:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[While Columbus is traditionally believed to have been from Genoa, Italy, alternative theories suggest he may have been a Spanish Jew, Greek, Basque, or Portuguese.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A centuries-old mystery surrounding the origins of Christopher Columbus may soon be solved. Spanish scientists have confirmed through DNA analysis that Columbus's remains are indeed interred in a tomb at Seville Cathedral in Spain. This finding settles the long-standing debate about his final resting place, previously contested by other claims, the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/10/11/world-news/dna-confirms-christopher-columbus-final-official-resting-place/" rel="nofollow, noindex"><em>New York Post </em></a>reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The controversy doesn't end there; questions about Columbus's nationality are also on the verge of resolution. While Columbus is traditionally believed to have been from Genoa, Italy, alternative theories suggest he may have been a Spanish Jew, Greek, Basque, or Portuguese.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Led by forensic expert Miguel Lorente, researchers have analyzed tiny samples of the remains from Seville, comparing them with those of Columbus's known relatives. The conclusions of their study will be revealed in a documentary titled "Columbus DNA: The True Origin," airing on Spain's national broadcaster TVE.</p>

<p>Although Lorente didn't disclose the final results during a recent briefing, he stated that modern technology has definitively confirmed that the remains in Seville belong to Columbus. He acknowledged the challenges in researching Columbus's nationality due to the extensive data involved but noted that the findings are "almost absolutely reliable."</p>

<p>Columbus's remains have a complex history of relocation. He died in Valladolid, Spain, in 1506, but wished to be buried on Hispaniola, now the Dominican Republic and Haiti. His remains were moved to Cuba in 1795 and later thought to have been transferred to Seville in 1898. However, some evidence suggests that parts of his remains could still be in the Caribbean, as bone fragments believed to belong to Columbus were found in a lead casket in Santo Domingo in 1877.</p>

<p>This ongoing debate takes place amid growing criticism of Columbus's legacy. Nick Tilsen, president of the indigenous-led advocacy group NDN Collective, argues that celebrating Columbus Day is "absolutely disrespectful," pointing out the devastation Columbus's expeditions caused to indigenous populations through colonization and disease.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-05/b5i484v_christopher-columbus-pixabay_625x300_19_May_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Researchers have analyzed tiny samples of the remains from Seville]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/systematic-pattern-of-desecration-india-on-bangladesh-durga-puja-attack-6774513]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Systematic Pattern Of Desecration": India On Bangladesh Durga Puja Attack]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/systematic-pattern-of-desecration-india-on-bangladesh-durga-puja-attack-6774513]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 12 Oct 2024 19:07:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India has written to Bangladesh's interim government today expressing "serious concern" over multiple attacks on temples, shrines and puja mandaps or pandals. The attacks include incidents of desecration, vandalism, robbery and defacement.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India has written to Bangladesh's interim government today expressing "serious concern" over multiple attacks on temples, shrines and puja mandaps or pandals. The attacks include incidents of desecration, vandalism, robbery and defacement.</p>

<p>New Delhi, which has been keenly observing the way events are unfolding across Bangladesh since the political crisis in the neighbouring country, said that there has been a systemic pattern in these attack.</p>

<p>Calling the recent attacks "deplorable", the Ministry of External Affairs today said, "We have noted with serious concern, the attacks on a puja mandap in Tantibazar, Dhaka and the theft at the revered Jeshoreshwari Kali Temple at Satkhira."</p>

<p>These attacks "follow a systematic pattern of desecration and damage to temples and deities that we have witnessed over several days now," the foreign ministry stated.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Our statement on attack on Puja Mandap and desecration and damage to Hindu temples in Bangladesh:<a href="https://t.co/KXGnXLhgjq">https://t.co/KXGnXLhgjq</a> <a href="https://t.co/Ty746nPn5c">pic.twitter.com/Ty746nPn5c</a></p>
— Randhir Jaiswal (@MEAIndia) <a href="https://twitter.com/MEAIndia/status/1845027328805536026?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 12, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>Urging Dhaka, New Delhi said, "We call upon the Government of Bangladesh to ensure the safety and security of Hindus and all minorities and their places of worship, especially during this auspicious festival time."</p>

<p>Prothom Alo, a Bangladeshi newspaper, reported that a "crude bomb was thrown" at a Durga Puja pandal in Tantibazar area in Dhaka's old city. The report further stated that the incident happened on Friday and though there was a fire after the crude bomb was thrown, there have been no injuries.</p>

<p>In another incident of theft at the renowned Jeshoreshwari Kali Temple, a hand-made 'mukut' (crown) made of silver with gold plating, that was placed on goddess Maa Kali's idol by Prime Minister Narendra Modi during his visit to the temple in 2021 was stolen.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">We have seen reports of theft of the crown gifted by PM Modi to Jeshoreshwari Kali Temple (Satkhira) in 2021 during his visit to ??<br />
<br />
We express deep concern &amp; urge Govt of Bangladesh to investigate theft, recover the crown &amp; take action against the perpetrators<a href="https://twitter.com/MEAIndia?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@MEAIndia</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/BDMOFA?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@BDMOFA</a></p>
— India in Bangladesh (@ihcdhaka) <a href="https://twitter.com/ihcdhaka/status/1844611078686208421?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 11, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>Durga Puja is predominantly celebrated by Bengali Hindus and coincides with the Hindu festival of Navratri. The festival lasts 9 days-and-nights hence the name "nav ratri'. It culminates in the festival of Dussehra or Vijaya Dashami on the tenth day.</p>

<p>Religious freedom has come under attack in Bangladesh under Nobel Peace Prize winner Muhammad Yunus's stewardship of the country after former Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina's ouster due to politically-motivated protests. Mr Yunus is currently the Chief Adviser to Bangladesh's interim government.</p>

<p>Mr Yunus however, has in recent times called these attacks "politically-motivated", and not "communal". In an interview to Press Trust of India last month, Mr Yunus had claimed the attacks were not communal, but a fallout of a political upheaval as there is a perception that most Hindus supported the now-deposed Awami League regime, which was led by Sheikh Hasina, daughter of Bangladesh;s founder Sheikh Mujib-ur-Rehman.</p>

<p>"I have said this to (Prime Minister Narendra) Modi also that this is exaggerated. This issue has several dimensions. When the country went through an upheaval following the atrocities by (Sheikh) Hasina and the Awami League, those who were with them also faced attacks," the Nobel peace prize winner had said.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/3oqgo7ts_bangladesh-temple-idol-mukut-gifted-by-pm-modi-stolen-pti_625x300_12_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The gold and silver mukut on Maa Kali's idol gifted to Bangladesh by India was stolen in a recent attack.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hezbollah-conflict-update-iran-bans-pagers-walkie-talkies-on-flights-following-attacks-in-lebanon-6774403]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iran Bans Pagers, Walkie Talkies On Flights Following Attacks In Lebanon]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hezbollah-conflict-update-iran-bans-pagers-walkie-talkies-on-flights-following-attacks-in-lebanon-6774403]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 12 Oct 2024 18:50:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iran has banned pagers and walkie-talkies on all flights, local media reported Saturday, weeks after deadly sabotage attacks in Lebanon which were blamed on Israel.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Iran has banned pagers and walkie-talkies on all flights, local media reported Saturday, weeks after deadly sabotage attacks in Lebanon which were blamed on Israel.</p>

<p>"The entry of any electronic communication device, except mobile phones, in flight cabins or in non-accompanied cargo, has been banned," ISNA news agency reported, citing the spokesman for Iran's Civil Aviation Organisation Jafar Yazerlo.</p>

<p>The decision came over three weeks since sabotage attacks targeting members of the Iran-allied Hezbollah group in Lebanon that saw pagers and walkie-talkies explode, killing at least 39 people.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-israel-war-soon-32-killed-as-walkie-talkies-pagers-explode-across-lebanon-6598300" target="_blank">Nearly 3,000 others were wounded in the attack</a>, which Iran and Hezbollah blamed on Israel, including Tehran's ambassador to Lebanon Mojtaba Amani.</p>

<p>Earlier this month, Dubai-based airline Emirates banned pagers and walkie-talkies onboard its planes.</p>

<p>Regional tensions have soared since the outbreak of the Gaza war in October last year, drawing in Iran-aligned groups from Lebanon, Iraq, Syria and Yemen.</p>

<p>Multiple airlines have in recent weeks suspended flights to Iran following Tehran's missile attack on Israel on October 1.</p>

<p>Iran fired some 200 missiles at Israel to retaliate against the killing of Tehran-aligned leaders in the region and a general in Iran's Revolutionary Guards.</p>

<p>Israel has since vowed to retaliate, with defence minister Yoav Gallant saying the response will be "deadly, precise, and surprising".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/chegmv3o_hezbollah-pager-attacks_625x300_19_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Nearly 3,000 others were wounded in the attack, which Iran and Hezbollah blamed on Israel. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/this-is-the-worlds-shortest-flight-it-lasts-only-1-5-minutes-6774312]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[This Is The World's Shortest Flight, It Lasts Only 1.5 Minutes]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/this-is-the-worlds-shortest-flight-it-lasts-only-1-5-minutes-6774312]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 12 Oct 2024 18:34:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Operated by Loganair, the flight connects the Orkney islands of Westray and Papa Westray.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>While most of us think of flights as long-haul journeys, there's a tiny Scottish flight that takes just one and a half minutes to complete its journey. Operated by Loganair, the flight connects the Orkney islands of Westray and Papa Westray.&nbsp;</p>

<p>This quick hop is so short that the actual flying time is often less than a minute! It's faster than many flights take to reach cruising altitude. In fact, the record for the fastest flight is 53 seconds, set by pilot Stuart Linklater, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.mirror.co.uk/travel/uk-ireland/uk-home-worlds-fastest-flight-33863996" rel="nofollow, noindex"><em>the Mirror</em></a> reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DA0ZcO0Shcx/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DA0ZcO0Shcx/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DA0ZcO0Shcx/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DA0ZcO0Shcx/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by Aʋιαƚισɳ Hҽαʋҽɳ ? (@aviation_heaven_)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p></p>

<p>The flight covers a distance of about 1.7 miles across the water, which is roughly the same length as the runway at Edinburgh Airport, the capital of Scotland. The flights are combined with routes to Kirkwall, forming a small triangle.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The airline uses Britten-Norman BN2B-26 Islander aircraft, which have 10 passenger seats. Passengers in the front row can even watch the pilot in action.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Papa Westray, with its 70 inhabitants, relies on this flight for essential connections to the mainland. In recent years, it has become a popular destination for tourists seeking a unique and brief travel experience.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Beyond its brevity, this flight offers a glimpse into a slower pace of life. The Orkney Islands, with their rugged landscapes and rich history, provide a stark contrast to the bustling metropolises of the world.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The flight's passengers, whether locals or tourists are likely to be struck by the beauty of the islands and the simplicity of their lives. The journey may be short, but the memories it creates can last a lifetime.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/ph7q76pg_loganair_625x300_12_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-gaza-conflict-update-19-killed-in-israeli-strikes-as-troops-push-deeper-into-gazas-northern-enclave-6774311]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[19 Killed In Israeli Strikes As Troops Push Deeper Into Gaza's Northern Enclave]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-gaza-conflict-update-19-killed-in-israeli-strikes-as-troops-push-deeper-into-gazas-northern-enclave-6774311]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 12 Oct 2024 18:32:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli military strikes on Gaza overnight killed at least 19 Palestinians, medics said on Saturday, while forces continued to push deeper into the Jabalia area, where international relief agencies say thousands of people are trapped.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli military strikes on Gaza overnight killed at least 19 Palestinians, medics said on Saturday, while forces continued to push deeper into the Jabalia area, where international relief agencies say thousands of people are trapped.</p>

<p>Residents said Israeli forces continued to pound Jabalia, which is in the north of the enclave and is the largest of the enclave's historic refugee camps, from the air and ground.</p>

<p>There has been no fresh Israeli comment but the military said in past days that forces operating in Jabalia and nearby areas killed dozens of militants, located weapons and dismantled military infrastructure.</p>

<p>The operation in this area began a week ago and the military said then it aimed to fight against Hamas militants waging attacks and to prevent Hamas from regrouping.</p>

<p>Palestinian health officials put the number of people killed in Jabalia over the past week at around 150.</p>

<p>On Friday, Israeli strikes hit four houses in Jabalia, killing around 20 people and wounding dozens, medics said. The Israeli military has sent troops into the nearby towns of Beit Hanoun and Beit Lahiya as well as Jabalia and ordered residents to evacuate their homes and head to safe areas south of the enclave.</p>

<p>Palestinian and United Nations officials say there are no safe areas in Gaza. They have also voiced concerns over severe shortages of food, fuel, and medical supplies in northern Gaza, and said there is a risk of famine there.</p>

<p>The Ministry of Health said Israel's threats to evacuate three hospitals operating there by force put the safety of patients and medical staff at risk.</p>

<p>Israel's military campaign in Gaza, aimed at eliminating the operator group Hamas, has killed more than 42,000 Palestinians since it began a year ago, according to Gaza's health ministry, and has laid waste to the enclave.</p>

<p>The war began after a Hamas-led assault on October 7, 2023, on southern Israeli communities in which 1,200 people were killed and about 250 were taken hostage, according to Israeli tallies.</p>

<p>In a statement on Saturday, Hamas said Israel's "massacre against the civilians" aimed to punish the residents of Jabalia for refusing to leave their homes. It also said it was a sign of Israel's military failure to defeat the group.</p>

<p>Israel has denied it targets civilians.</p>

<p>The armed wings of Hamas, the Islamic Jihad, and smaller other factions said their fighters attacked Israeli forces in Jabalia and nearby areas with anti-tank rockets, and mortar fire.</p>

<p><strong>POLIO VACCINATIONS</strong></p>

<p>United Nations officials said on Friday an Israeli offensive and evacuation orders in northern Gaza might affect the second phase of its polio vaccination campaign set to start next week.</p>

<p>The territory's health ministry announced on Saturday that the campaign would begin on Monday in central Gaza Strip areas and would last three days before moving to other territories.</p>

<p>Aid groups carried out an initial round of vaccinations last month after a baby was partially paralysed by the type 2 poliovirus in August, the first such case in the territory in 25 years.</p>

<p>As in the first phase, humanitarian pauses in the fighting in Gaza are planned, in order to reach hundreds of thousands of children.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/lctulsog_northern-gaza-strip_625x300_12_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Israeli military has ordered residents to evacuate their homes and head to safe areas.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-forces-strike-islamic-state-group-in-syria-6774272]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Forces Strike Islamic State Group In Syria]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-forces-strike-islamic-state-group-in-syria-6774272]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 12 Oct 2024 18:29:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US forces have conducted air strikes against multiple Islamic State group sites in Syria, the military said Saturday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US forces have conducted air strikes against multiple Islamic State group sites in Syria, the military said Saturday.</p>

<p>US forces "conducted a series of airstrikes against multiple known ISIS camps in Syria in the early morning of Oct. 11," the US Central Command said in a statement on X, using an acronym for the Islamist militant group.</p>

<p>"The strikes will disrupt the ability of ISIS to plan, organize, and conduct attacks against the United States, its allies and partners, and civilians throughout the region and beyond."</p>

<p>The US military has around 900 troops in Syria as part of the international coalition against the Islamic State (IS) group.</p>

<p>The coalition was established in 2014 to help combat the armed group, which had taken over vast swaths of Iraq and Syria.</p>

<p>Anti-IS coalition forces have been targeted dozens of times with drones and rocket fire in both Iraq and Syria, as violence related to the Israel-Hamas war in Gaza since last year has drawn in militants across the Middle East, including Iran-backed Hezbollah in Lebanon.</p>

<p>US forces have carried out multiple retaliatory strikes against militant factions in both Iraq and Syria.</p>

<p>In September, US forces conducted two separate strikes in Syria, killing 37 "terrorist operatives" including members of IS and Al-Qaeda affiliate Hurras al-Din.</p>

<p>US Central Command said Saturday that its damage assessments were underway and "do not indicate civilian casualties."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2016-02/us-flag-oregon-reuters_650x400_61455255053.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-says-launched-drone-attack-on-base-in-north-israels-haifa-6773925]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hezbollah Says Launched Drone Attack On Base In North Israel's Haifa]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-says-launched-drone-attack-on-base-in-north-israels-haifa-6773925]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 12 Oct 2024 17:29:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hezbollah said Saturday it launched a drone attack on a military base in north Israel's Haifa a day earlier.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hezbollah said Saturday it launched a drone attack on a military base in north Israel's Haifa a day earlier.</p>

<p>Hezbollah fighters at 8:00 pm (1700 GMT) on Friday launched "an air attack with a swarm of explosives-laden drones on an air defence base" in Haifa, a statement from the Iran-backed group said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/brablseg_haifa-_625x300_12_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Ships are anchored off the port of Haifa]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-leads-kamala-harris-on-who-will-handle-israel-ukraine-wars-better-wsj-poll-6773859]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Leads Harris On Who Will Handle Israel, Ukraine Wars Better: Poll]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-leads-kamala-harris-on-who-will-handle-israel-ukraine-wars-better-wsj-poll-6773859]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 12 Oct 2024 17:17:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump has an edge over Democratic Vice President Kamala Harris on who would better navigate the country through the Ukraine and Middle East wars, a Wall Street Journal opinion poll of seven battleground states showed.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former Republican President Donald Trump has an edge over Democratic Vice President Kamala Harris on who would better navigate the country through the Ukraine and Middle East wars, a Wall Street Journal opinion poll of seven battleground states showed.</p>

<p>In overall support, the poll published on Friday showed Harris and Trump tied across the seven states that could decide the November presidential election.</p>

<p>The poll showed Harris with marginal 2 percentage point leads in Arizona, Georgia and Michigan, Trump up 6 points in Nevada and 1 in Pennsylvania, and the two tied in North Carolina and Wisconsin. The poll of 600 registered voters in each state conducted on Sept. 28-Oct. 8 had a margin of error of 4 percentage points in each state.</p>

<p>The neck-and-neck results echo other polls reflecting a tight race before the Nov. 5 election as Americans grapple with concerns about the economy, immigration, women's rights and the nation's democratic values in picking between the two candidates.</p>

<p>A Reuters/Ipsos poll this week also found Trump and Harris locked in a close race nationally, with Harris marginally ahead 46% to 43%.</p>

<p>Surveys of swing state voters can be an important indicator given that state-by-state results of the Electoral College will determine the winner, with the seven battleground states likely being decisive.</p>

<p>Harris would win a narrow majority in the Electoral College if she captures the states where she holds an edge in the WSJ's poll.</p>

<p>According to the WSJ poll, Trump leads Harris in the seven swing states 50% to 39% on who is best able to handle Russia's war in Ukraine. Trump also has a 48% to 33% lead over Harris on who is better suited to handle the Israel-Hamas war.</p>

<p>More voters said they backed Trump on the economy and immigration while more said Harris would do a better job when it comes to housing, healthcare and caring about people like them, the WSJ poll found.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/ldflnci8_kamala-harris-donald-trump-harris-trump-reuters_625x300_12_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Trump has an edge over Harris on who would better navigate the Ukraine and Middle East wars]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-korea-sent-drones-to-scatter-anti-north-korea-leaflets-says-pyongyang-6773850]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[South Korea Sent Drones To Scatter Anti-North Korea Leaflets, Says Pyongyang]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-korea-sent-drones-to-scatter-anti-north-korea-leaflets-says-pyongyang-6773850]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 12 Oct 2024 17:13:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[North Korea accused South Korea on Friday of sending drones to scatter a "huge number" of anti-North leaflets over its capital Pyongyang, in what it called a political and military provocation that could lead to armed conflict.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>North Korea accused South Korea on Friday of sending drones to scatter a "huge number" of anti-North leaflets over its capital Pyongyang, in what it called a political and military provocation that could lead to armed conflict.</p>

<p>South Korea's Joint Chiefs of Staff said it could not confirm the North's accusations but also referred in its statement to Pyongyang's practice of sending into South Korean airspace balloons with bags of trash attached.</p>

<p>North Korea's foreign ministry said the drones were flown over Pyongyang at night this week and last and that the intrusion demanded retaliatory action, the state news agency KCNA reported.</p>

<p>"The ROK (South Korea) should immediately stop such irresponsible and dangerous provocation that may cause an armed conflict and lead to a war between the two sides," the ministry was quoted as saying.</p>

<p>In its statement, South Korea's Joint Chiefs of Staff said it "cannot confirm the truth of North Korea's claims", adding: "All responsibility for the recent series of events" lies with Pyongyang.</p>

<p>It cited "despicable, low-grade and internationally embarrassing acts of filth and garbage balloons and other provocations." More balloons were being sent on Friday, it said.</p>

<p>North Korea has been floating thousands of balloons with trash attached into the South since May, exacerbating tensions between the two countries.</p>

<p>Pyongyang says they are a response to some activists and North Korean defectors in South Korea who fly balloons into the North carrying aid parcels and leaflets criticising leader Kim Jong Un.</p>

<p><strong>BLURRY IMAGES</strong></p>

<p>KCNA distributed photos, including ones showing a blurry, triangular object labelled as a "drone" dropping another object labelled as "bundle of leaflets". One image also showed a cloud of small objects that was labelled as "scattered leaflets."</p>

<p>Another photo showed black, yellow and white leaflets comparing the economic situation in the South to the impoverished North and criticizing North Korean leader Kim Jong Un by name.</p>

<p>South Korea's Yonhap news agency cited an official at the Joint Chiefs of Staff as saying it needs to look into whether a private group had sent leaflets into the North.</p>

<p>In December five North Korean drones crossed into South Korea, prompting Seoul to scramble fighter jets and attack helicopters, and try to shoot them down, in the first such intrusion since 2017.</p>

<p>The two Koreas are still technically at war after their 1950-53 war ended in an armistice, not a peace treaty, and the North has long denounced defectors as "human scum".</p>

<p>There will be no more warnings and the North will immediately take action in the event of another drone being sent by the South into its territory, North Korea's foreign ministry said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2017-07/north-korea-pyongyang-istock_650x400_61500452214.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Pyongyang says they are a response to some activists and North Korean defectors in South Korea. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>