<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Mon, 05 Aug 2024 19:01:02 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/were-protesters-seen-in-bangladesh-pm-sheikh-hasinas-bed-after-she-fled-a-fact-check-6269169]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Were Protesters Seen In Bangladesh PM's Bed After She Fled? A Fact-Check]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/were-protesters-seen-in-bangladesh-pm-sheikh-hasinas-bed-after-she-fled-a-fact-check-6269169]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 05 Aug 2024 18:35:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Protesters lounging on a bed and clicking selfies were among many visuals, being labelled as from inside the Bangladesh Prime Minister's official residence, which went viral online after Sheikh Hasina resigned and left her country.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Protesters lounging on a bed and clicking selfies were among many visuals, being labelled as from inside the Bangladesh Prime Minister's official residence, which went viral online after Sheikh Hasina resigned and left her country. However, it turns out the visuals are two years old and show a scene from Sri Lanka President's palace.</p>

<p>In July 2022, angry protesters took over former Sri Lanka President Gotabaya Rajapaksa's official residence, a culmination of months of protests over the unprecedented economic crisis in the island nation. Like Ms Hasina, Mr Rajapaksa too fled his country before resigning from the top post.</p>

<p>Bangladesh Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina resigned today in a dramatic development amid massive protest against her government that claimed more than 100 lives in the last two days.</p>

<p>The announcement of her resignation came soon after hundreds of protesters defied an indefinite military curfew and stormed her official residence - 'Ganabhaban' - in the capital Dhaka. She had fled by then.</p>

<p>Several photos and videos on social media showed protesters vandalising and looting the building.&nbsp;Many were seen carrying away televisions, chairs and tables from what was one of the most protected buildings in the country.</p>

<p>The day witnessed chaotic scenes after supporters of the ruling Awami League descended on the streets to subdue the anti-government protests who defied curfew to gather for the "Long March to Dhaka".</p>

<p>Some protesters also climbed atop a large statue of independence leader Sheikh Mujibur Rahman, Ms Hasina's father, and began chiselling away at the head with an axe, the visuals showed.</p>

<p>At least 300 people were killed in more than a month of protests that ended the 15-year rule of Ms Hasina.</p>

<p>Bangladesh's army chief General Waker-Uz-Zaman said in a broadcast to the nation on state television on Monday Hasina had resigned and the military would form an interim government.</p>

<p>She has landed at the Hindon Air Force base in Uttar Pradesh's Ghaziabad. She is expected to leave for London soon.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/7cdmtvrg_fact-check-sheikh-hasina-house-_625x300_05_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[During Sri Lanka unrest, protesters were seen sleeping in the former president's bed.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-seizes-26-million-of-palestinian-tax-funds-to-combat-terrorism-6269087]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Seizes $26 Million Of Palestinian Tax Funds To "Combat Terrorism"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-seizes-26-million-of-palestinian-tax-funds-to-combat-terrorism-6269087]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 05 Aug 2024 18:26:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel's far-right Finance Minister Bezalel Smotrich has ordered the seizure of 100 million shekels ($26 million) of tax funds intended for the Palestinian Authority, saying it would be used to pay for Israeli victims of terrorism.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel's far-right Finance Minister Bezalel Smotrich has ordered the seizure of 100 million shekels ($26 million) of tax funds intended for the Palestinian Authority, saying it would be used to pay for Israeli victims of terrorism.</p>

<p>In a statement issued late on Sunday, the finance ministry said the confiscation of funds was "part of measures to combat terrorism".</p>

<p>The statement quoted Smotrich as accusing the Palestinian Authority, which governs parts of the Israeli-occupied West Bank, of diverting the funds to the "families of terrorists".</p>

<p>Israeli politicians have regularly criticised the Ramallah-based Palestinian Authority for granting financial support to the families of Palestinians killed or jailed for acts of violence against Israel.</p>

<p>The finance ministry statement noted that this was the fifth time it had withheld funds, which Israel collects on behalf of the Palestinian Authority.</p>

<p>The Palestinian Authority did not immediately respond to AFP requests for comment.</p>

<p>Since Hamas's October 7 attack triggered the war in Gaza, Israel has imposed economic curbs on the Palestinian Authority, often withholding tax revenues it collects on its behalf.</p>

<p>Smotrich said on Monday on social media site X that the withholding of Palestinian funds was part of a broader strategy to prevent the creation of a Palestinian state "to ensure security" for Israelis, alongside increased settlement in the West Bank.</p>

<p>"We are working on the ground to remove this threat (of a Palestinian state) ... by strengthening settlement through construction, ... fighting the terror funds of the Palestinian Authority and its leaders, and maintaining complete Israeli control over the area."</p>

<p></p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-10/rrd8pc98_israel-palestine-_625x300_08_October_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Since Hamas's October 7 attack, Israel has imposed economic curbs on the Palestinian Authority (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/freedom-war-heros-daughter-to-villain-sheikh-hasinas-biggest-challenge-6269067]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Freedom War Hero's Daughter To Villain: Sheikh Hasina's Biggest Challenge?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/freedom-war-heros-daughter-to-villain-sheikh-hasinas-biggest-challenge-6269067]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 05 Aug 2024 18:21:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Sheikh Hasina, 77, feted chief of the Awami League and three-time Prime Minister of Bangladesh, stepped down today amid a 45-minute ultimatum of the army and took  a flight out of the violence-torn nation for an unknown destination.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sheikh Hasina, 77, feted chief of the Awami League and three-time Prime Minister of Bangladesh, stepped down today amid a 45-minute ultimatum of the army and took&nbsp; a flight out of the violence-torn nation for an unknown destination. It would probably be familiar territory for a leader who started her political journey with an exile after the assassination of her father by officers of the Bangladesh army.</p>

<p>Sheikh Mujibur Rehman -- whose statue was desecrated in today's violence --&nbsp; was the charismatic leader who led East Pakistan to Independence and the birth of a new nation.</p>

<p>Sheikh Hasina, only 28 when Mujibur Rehman was assassinated, remained in exile from 1975 to late 1980s. While in exile, she rose through the ranks to head the party her father founded and on her return, dived into politics.</p>

<p>In 1996, she steered Awami League to victory in the national election, becoming the first woman Prime Minister of Bangladesh.</p>

<p>The initial years of her stewardship brought a phase of huge growth to Bangladesh in terms of both economy and infrastructure that led to rapid change in the living standards in what once was one of the world's poorest nations.</p>

<p>But her strained relationship with the judiciary and handling of an earlier series of protests gave rise to a generation of critics who accused her of totalitarianism and autocracy. Her victory in two subsequent elections saw widespread allegations of rigging – adding layers of controversy to one of the country's most prominent leaders of the time.</p>

<p>Sheikh Hasina's efforts to bring peace after 25 years of conflict in the Chittagong Hill Tracts was recognised by the UNESCO with the Houphouet-Boigny Peace Prize in 1998.</p>

<p>The current wave of student protests – which had started weeks ago as one about quota in government jobs to the families of freedom fighters – had unexpectedly snowballed into demands for her resignation.</p>

<p>As the violence continued, the army took action today, scripting what some see as the last chapter of the political career of the leader whose life has mirrored the ups and downs of the nation since her birth in 1947.</p>

<p>In her tumultuous career, Sheikh Hasina has faced grenade attacks and assassination attempts. She had been placed thrice under house arrest by the army, once over her opposition to the coup and assumption of power by. Lt. Gen. Hussain Muhammad Ershad. Many believe it is still too premature to compose her political epitaph.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/q3ftcvug_sheikh-hasina-_625x300_22_June_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sheikh-hasina-lands-at-hindon-airbase-near-delhi-after-fleeing-bangladesh-6268836]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Sheikh Hasina Lands At Hindon Airbase Near Delhi After Fleeing Bangladesh]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sheikh-hasina-lands-at-hindon-airbase-near-delhi-after-fleeing-bangladesh-6268836]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 05 Aug 2024 17:54:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Bangladesh leader Sheikh Hasina - who resigned as Prime Minister this evening in the face of violent protests - landed at the Hindon Air Force base in Uttar Pradesh's Ghaziabad Monday evening, en route to London.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bangladesh leader <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/topic/sheikh-hasina" target="_blank">Sheikh Hasina</a> landed at the Hindon Air Force base in Uttar Pradesh's Ghaziabad - around 30 km from Delhi - Monday evening. Hours earlier the 76-year-old <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-unrest-live-updates-pm-sheikh-hasina-bangladesh-violence-bangladesh-violence-live-6267300" target="_blank">five-time Prime Minister had resigned from her position</a> after violent protests - over a government jobs quota - killed over 300.</p>

<p>Sheikh Hasina is expected to leave, almost immediately, for London, sources told NDTV.</p>

<p>Sources told news agency ANI Sheikh Hasina's plane - a Bangladesh Air Force C-130 military transport - will be parked near the Indian Air Force's C-17 and C-130J Super Hercules aircraft hangars.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi has been briefed on the situation in Bangladesh by External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar. There is no word yet if Mr Modi will meet Mrs Hasina.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the Bangladesh Army, which gave Sheikh Hasina 45 minutes to resign after her government couldn't control the violence, has taken control. In a televised address <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-waker-uz-zaman-army-general-to-take-bangladesh-charge-6268066#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">Army chief General Waker-Uz-Zaman</a> said the military will form an "interim government" and told protesters to stand down.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://Sheikh Hasina Quits After Bangladesh Army's 45-Min Notice: Top Developments" target="_blank">Sheikh Hasina Quits After Bangladesh Army's 45-Min Notice: Top Developments</a></p>

<p>"There is a crisis. I have met Opposition leaders and we have decided to form an interim government to run this country. I take all responsibility and promise to protect your life and property. Your demands will be fulfilled. Please stop the violence," the Army chief&nbsp;said.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladeshs-sheikh-hasina-quits-flies-out-amid-massive-protests-report-6267468#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">Bangladesh PM Sheikh Hasina Quits, Army Coup Amid Massive Protests</a></p>

<p>Earlier today protesters broke into Gonobhaban - the Dhaka residence of the Prime Minister.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-pm-sheikh-hasina-leaves-dhaka-palace-for-safer-place-report-6267175#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_top">Bangladesh Protesters Storm Sheikh Hasina's Palace Amid Violent Clashes</a></p>

<p>Local media estimated as many as 400,000 protesters were on the streets but it was impossible to verify the figure.&nbsp;Soldiers and police with armoured vehicles had barricaded routes to Ms Hasina's office with barbed wire, AFP reporters said, but vast crowds flooded the streets, tearing down barriers.</p>

<p>But by then the veteran politician had fled.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-pm-sheikh-hasina-leaves-dhaka-palace-for-safer-place-report-6267175#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">Bangladesh Protesters Storm Sheikh Hasina's Palace Amid Violent Clashes</a></p>

<p>100 people were killed and over 1,000 injured in clashes that took place between police and protesters on Sunday alone. Since then the number of dead has crossed 300.</p>

<p>The protests began late last month over a quota system that reserves up to 30 per cent of government jobs for family members of veterans from Bangladesh's 1971 war against Pakistan.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-protests-sheikh-hasina-awami-league-explained-what-led-to-bangladesh-protests-that-has-seen-over-300-killed-6265524#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">300 Killed, Sheikh Hasina Flees: Violent Bangladesh Protests Explained</a></p>

<p>Since then they have escalated dramatically, particularly over the past few days, resulting in pitched battles between students, police, and counter-protesters. Shocking scenes have emerged of vehicles and buildings on fire and mobs rampaging through the streets.</p>

<p>The protests died down, briefly, after the Bangladesh Supreme Court cut the reservations to 5 per cent. But it flared back up after student leaders said the government had ignored some of their demands. This triggered demands for Sheikh Hasina to quit.</p>

<p>India's Border Security Force is on high alert across the country's 4,096 km border with Bangladesh, with field commanders ordered to take "on ground" positions and be prepared for anything. Indian Railways has stopped all trains to Bangladesh and Air India has cancelled its two daily flights to Dhaka.</p>

<p><em><strong>With input from agencies</strong></em></p>

<p><em>NDTV is now available on WhatsApp channels. <a href="https://www.whatsapp.com/channel/0029Va4lixw7z4kcvZI9JM12">Click on the link</a> to get all the latest updates from NDTV on your chat. </em></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/qd5o8k6g_sheikh-hasina_625x300_05_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/amit-nakesh-turkish-media-falls-for-prank-which-claimed-indian-origin-man-killed-ismail-haniyeh-6268765]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Turkish Media Falsely Claimed Indian-Origin Man Killed Ismail Haniyeh]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/amit-nakesh-turkish-media-falls-for-prank-which-claimed-indian-origin-man-killed-ismail-haniyeh-6268765]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 05 Aug 2024 17:46:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israelis quickly recognized the joke, noting that the name "Amit Nagesh" closely resembles the Hebrew word "hamitnakesh," meaning "the assassin."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Turkish media fell for an international prank claiming that an Indian-Israeli Mossad agent named Amit Nakesh had assassinated Hamas political leader Ismail Haniyeh in Tehran last Wednesday.</p>

<p>The sensational story of an Indian-Israeli secret agent with a license to kill captured Turkish headlines, prompting journalists to seek more thrilling details. Akdeniz Gercek Gazetesi reported that Nakesh had completed his military service in Israel before joining Mossad, where he became an expert in assassinations and recruiting intelligence sources, participating in multiple operations against "elements hostile to Israel."</p>

<p>However, it was soon revealed that the story was a global hoax orchestrated by Israeli social media pranksters and meme artists. Israelis quickly recognized the joke, noting that the name "Amit Nagesh" closely resembles the Hebrew word "hamitnakesh," meaning "the assassin."</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Yesterday I posted a joke that the name of Mossad agent who killed Haniyeh is “Amit Nakesh”, which in Hebrew literally means “assassin”.<br />
<br />
Today the Turkish press ran with it, and some even referred to him as Colonel Amit Nakesh ?<br />
? <a href="https://t.co/vFlZ5gwx6S">pic.twitter.com/vFlZ5gwx6S</a></p>
— Dr. Eli David (@DrEliDavid) <a href="https://twitter.com/DrEliDavid/status/1818959599375888776?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 1, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>The Times of Israel reported that Turkish media swiftly retracted all stories about Amit Nakesh, but not before Israeli social media had plenty of fun at their expense. An account even appeared on X (formerly Twitter) under the name Amit Nakesh, claiming to be friends with another fictional character, Eli Copter, purportedly responsible for downing Iranian President Ebrahim Raisi.</p>

<p>Israeli social media often features fake news about daring Israeli exploits, frequently creating prank posts about fictional Israeli soldiers and Mossad agents with punny names.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Turkish President Recep Tayyip Erdogan has made bold political moves, including threatening to invade Israel to end the war in Gaza. In response, Israel's foreign minister suggested that Turkey should be expelled from NATO. Erdogan also temporarily blocked Instagram in Turkey after the platform restricted posts mourning the Hamas leader's death, only to later post and quickly delete a message on the social media site.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/u8p79kgg_amit-nakesh_625x300_05_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Times of Israel reported that Turkish media swiftly retracted all stories about Amit Nakesh]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-bangladesh-student-protests-led-to-sheikh-hasinas-resignation-6268678]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How Bangladesh Student Protests Led To Sheikh Hasina's Resignation]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-bangladesh-student-protests-led-to-sheikh-hasinas-resignation-6268678]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 05 Aug 2024 17:35:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Protests in Bangladesh that began as student-led demonstrations against government hiring rules in July culminated Monday in the prime minister fleeing and the military announcing it would form an interim government]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Protests in Bangladesh that began as student-led demonstrations against government hiring rules in July culminated Monday in the prime minister fleeing and the military announcing it would form an interim government</p>

<p>At least 300 people were killed in more than a month of deadly protests that ended the autocratic rule of 76-year-old Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina.</p>

<p>Here are five key dates explaining how the protests toppled the government in the South Asian nation of about 170 million people.</p>

<p><strong>July 1: Blockades begin</strong>&nbsp;</p>

<p>University students build barricades blocking roads and railway lines to demand reforms of a quota system for sought-after public sector jobs.</p>

<p>They say the scheme is used to stack the civil service with loyalists of Sheikh Hasina's ruling Awami League.</p>

<p>Sheikh Hasina, who won a fifth term as prime minister in January after a vote without genuine opposition, says the students are "wasting their time".</p>

<p><strong>July 16: Violence intensifies&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p>Six people are killed in clashes, the first recorded deaths in the protests, a day after bitter violence when protesters and pro-government supporters fought in Dhaka with sticks and hurled bricks at each other.</p>

<p>Sheikh Hasina's government orders the nationwide closure of schools and universities.</p>

<p><strong>July 18: PM rebuffed</strong></p>

<p>Students reject an olive branch from Sheikh Hasina, a day after she appeals for calm and vows that every "murder" in the protests would be punished.</p>

<p>Protesters chant "down with the dictator" and torch the headquarters of state broadcaster Bangladesh Television and dozens of other government buildings.</p>

<p>The government imposes an internet blackout.</p>

<p>At least 32 people are killed and hundreds are wounded in clashes, which continue in the following days despite a round-the-clock curfew and the deployment of soldiers.</p>

<p><strong>July 21: Supreme Court verdict</strong></p>

<p>Bangladesh's Supreme Court, seen by critics as a rubber stamp for the will of Sheikh Hasina's government, rules the decision to reintroduce job quotas was illegal.</p>

<p>But its verdict falls short of protesters' demands to entirely abolish reserved jobs for children of "freedom fighters" from Bangladesh's 1971 independence war against Pakistan.</p>

<p><strong>August 5: Sheikh Hasina flees</strong></p>

<p>Sheikh Hasina flees Dhaka by helicopter as thousands of protesters storm her palace, with millions on the streets celebrating, some dancing on the roof of armoured cars and tanks.</p>

<p>Her dramatic departure comes a day after the deadliest day of protests in which at least 94 people were killed countrywide, many in battles with her supporters.</p>

<p>In several cases, soldiers and police did not intervene to stem the protests, unlike during the past month of rallies.</p>

<p>Bangladesh's army chief General Waker-Uz-Zaman, says in a broadcast to the nation on state television Sheikh Hasina had resigned and the military would form an interim government.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/8qd6fj9g_bangladesh-protests-afp-_625x300_05_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[At least 300 people were killed in more than a month of deadly protests (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/ai-hallucination-ai-fog-ai-boom-inbred-gibberish-or-just-mad-warnings-rise-about-ai-models-6268579]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Inbred, Gibberish Or Just MAD? Warnings Rise About AI Models]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/ai-hallucination-ai-fog-ai-boom-inbred-gibberish-or-just-mad-warnings-rise-about-ai-models-6268579]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 05 Aug 2024 17:22:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The ultimate concern is that AI-generated content could take over the web, which could in turn render chatbots and image generators useless]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When academic Jathan Sadowski reached for an analogy last year to describe how AI programs decay, he landed on the term "Habsburg AI".</p>

<p>The Habsburgs were one of Europe's most powerful royal houses, but entire sections of their family line collapsed after centuries of inbreeding.</p>

<p>Recent studies have shown how AI programs underpinning products like ChatGPT go through a similar collapse when they are repeatedly fed their own data.</p>

<p>"I think the term Habsburg AI has aged very well," Sadowski told AFP, saying his coinage had "only become more relevant for how we think about AI systems".</p>

<p>The ultimate concern is that AI-generated content could take over the web, which could in turn render chatbots and image generators useless and throw a trillion-dollar industry into a tailspin.</p>

<p>But other experts argue that the problem is overstated or can be fixed.</p>

<p>And many companies are enthusiastic about using what they call synthetic data to train AI programs. This artificially generated data is used to augment or replace real-world data. It is cheaper than human-created content but more predictable.</p>

<p>"The open question for researchers and companies building AI systems is how much synthetic data is too much," said Sadowski, lecturer in emerging technologies at Australia's Monash University.</p>

<h3><strong>- 'Mad cow disease' -</strong></h3>

<p>Training AI programs, known in the industry as large language models (LLMs), involves scraping vast quantities of text or images from the internet.</p>

<p>This information is broken into trillions of tiny machine-readable chunks, known as tokens.</p>

<p>When asked a question, a program like ChatGPT selects and assembles tokens in a way that its training data tells it is the most likely sequence to fit with the query.</p>

<p>But even the best AI tools generate falsehoods and nonsense, and critics have long expressed concern about what would happen if a model was fed on its own outputs.</p>

<p>In late July, a paper in the journal Nature titled "AI models collapse when trained on recursively generated data" proved a lightning rod for discussion.</p>

<p>The authors described how models quickly discarded rarer elements in their original dataset and, as Nature reported, outputs degenerated into "gibberish".</p>

<p>A week later, researchers from Rice and Stanford universities published a paper titled "Self-consuming generative models go MAD" that reached a similar conclusion.</p>

<p>They tested image-generating AI programs and showed that outputs become more generic and strafed with undesirable elements as they added AI-generated data to the underlying model.</p>

<p>They labelled model collapse "Model Autophagy Disorder" (MAD) and compared it to mad cow disease, a fatal illness caused by feeding the remnants of dead cows to other cows.</p>

<h3><strong>- 'Doomsday scenario' -</strong></h3>

<p>These researchers worry that AI-generated text, images and video are clearing the web of usable human-made data.</p>

<p>"One doomsday scenario is that if left uncontrolled for many generations, MAD could poison the data quality and diversity of the entire internet," one of the Rice University authors, Richard Baraniuk, said in a statement.</p>

<p>However, industry figures are unfazed.</p>

<p>Anthropic and Hugging Face, two leaders in the field who pride themselves on taking an ethical approach to the technology, both told AFP they used AI-generated data to fine-tune or filter their datasets.</p>

<p>Anton Lozhkov, machine learning engineer at Hugging Face, said the Nature paper gave an interesting theoretical perspective, but its disaster scenario was not realistic.</p>

<p>"Training on multiple rounds of synthetic data is simply not done in reality," he said.</p>

<p>However, he said researchers were just as frustrated as everyone else with the state of the internet.</p>

<p>"A large part of the internet is trash," he said, adding that Hugging Face already made huge efforts to clean data -- sometimes jettisoning as much as 90 percent.</p>

<p>He hoped that web users would help clear up the internet by simply not engaging with generated content.</p>

<p>"I strongly believe that humans will see the effects and catch generated data way before models will," he said.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/q0nvan58_ai-hallucination-_625x300_05_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Gen AI has raised concerns among researchers, but the industry remains unfazed (AI Generated Image)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-says-has-legal-right-to-punish-israel-for-hamas-chief-ismail-haniyehs-killing-6268527]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[vIran Says Has "Legal Right" To Punish Israel For Hamas Chief's Killing]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-says-has-legal-right-to-punish-israel-for-hamas-chief-ismail-haniyehs-killing-6268527]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 05 Aug 2024 17:16:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iran said Monday it has the "legal right" to respond to the assassination in Tehran last week of Hamas chief Ismail Haniyeh, an attack blamed on Israel amid the Gaza war.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Iran said Monday it has the "legal right" to respond to the assassination in Tehran last week of Hamas chief Ismail Haniyeh, an attack blamed on Israel amid the Gaza war.</p>

<p>"No one has the right to doubt Iran's legal right to punish the Zionist regime", Iranian foreign ministry spokesman Nasser Kanani told a regular news conference, referring to Israel.</p>

<p>He maintained that Iran "does not seek to aggravate tensions in the region", which have soared since the Israel-Hamas war broke out in early October and rose further since Wednesday's attack in Tehran.</p>

<p>Iran's Revolutionary Guards said Israel killed Haniyeh using a "short-range projectile" launched from outside his residence in the Iranian capital which he was visiting to attend the inauguration of President Masoud Pezeshkian.</p>

<p>Iran and Hamas as well as other Tehran-aligned armed groups in the Middle East have vowed to retaliate.</p>

<p>Israel has not directly commented on the killing, which came just hours the assassination of Lebanese group Hezbollah's military chief Fuad Shukr in an Israeli strike on Beirut.</p>

<p>Iran-backed Hezbollah and Israeli forces have traded near-daily fire since early October.</p>

<p>Calls for de-escalation have intensified following the high-profile killings, with world powers fearing an all-out regional war.</p>

<p>Nasser Kanani on Monday said: "We believe the consolidation of stability and security in the region will be achieved by punishing the aggressor and creating a deterrent against the adventurous behaviour and extraterritorial terrors of the Zionist regime".</p>

<p>Iran, which does not recognise Israel, has held talks with multiple Arab countries including Jordan, Egypt, Oman and Qatar since Haniyeh's killing.</p>

<p>Tehran has repeatedly reaffirmed its "inherent right" to take action against foe Israel.</p>

<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu has said his country was at "a very high level" of preparedness for any scenario, "defensive and offensive".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/v49bimrg_ismail-haniyeh_625x300_31_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel has not directly commented on the killing of Ismail Haniyeh (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-aircraft-spotted-over-india-where-is-sheikh-hasina-headed-6268099]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh Aircraft Spotted Over India. Where Is Sheikh Hasina Headed?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-aircraft-spotted-over-india-where-is-sheikh-hasina-headed-6268099]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 05 Aug 2024 16:20:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Bangladesh Prime Minister Shiekh Hasina resigned today and left the country following more than a month of deadly anti-government protests.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bangladesh Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina resigned today and left the country following more than a month of deadly anti-government protests. Army chief General Waker-Us-Zaman said that an interim government would be formed.</p>

<p>The 76-year-old leader is said to have flown in a Bangladesh military aircraft with her sister, reports said.</p>

<p>Footage from airline tracker Flight Radar showed an aircraft of Bangladesh Air Force - Lockheed C-130J Hercules - flying over India. The plane was seen flying over Jharkhand.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/9q7ge9bg_sheikh-hasina-plane_625x300_05_August_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Earlier, some reports claimed that Ms Hasina would fly to West Bengal but as per the airline data, the aircraft bypassed the state.</p>

<p>Ms Hasina, who has ruled since 2009, had defied weeks of demands for her to stand down but fled following a brutal day of unrest on Sunday in which nearly 100 people died.</p>

<p>As per sources, her security team asked her to leave and that she did not find any time to prepare.</p>

<p>The country witnessed chaotic scenes from this morning that culminated in Ms Hasina's resignation. Huge crowds were seen waving flags, and dancing on top of a tank in the streets before hundreds broke through the gates of Ms Hasina'a official residence.</p>

<p>Some smashed a statue of her father Sheikh Mujibur Rahman, the country's independence hero.</p>

<p>Earlier, Ms Hasina's son urged the security forces to block any takeover from her 15-year-rule.</p>

<p>"Your duty is to keep our people safe and our country safe and to uphold the constitution," her son, US-based Sajeeb Wazed Joy, said in a post on Facebook.</p>

<p>"It means don't allow any unelected government to come in power for one minute, it is your duty."</p>

<p>The country's military and other security forces had supported Ms Hasina's government through the unrest that began last month against civil services jobs. The protests escalated into wider calls for her to stand down.</p>

<p>The demonstrations were about the reintroduction pf a quota scheme that reserved more than half of all government jobs for certain groups.</p>

<p>Ms Hasina won her fourth consecutive election in January in an election without a genuine opposition.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-01/3bjks7os_sheikh-hasina_625x300_07_January_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sheikh Hasina, who has ruled since 2009, had defied weeks of demands for her to stand down.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-waker-uz-zaman-army-general-to-take-bangladesh-charge-6268066]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Who Is Waker-Uz-Zaman, Army General To Take Bangladesh Charge]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-waker-uz-zaman-army-general-to-take-bangladesh-charge-6268066]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 05 Aug 2024 16:19:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Shortly after Sheikh Hasina resigned as the Prime Minister of Bangladesh and fled the country, General Waker-Uz-Zaman, the Chief of Army Staff, announced that he would form the interim government.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Shortly after Sheikh Hasina resigned as the Prime Minister of Bangladesh and fled the country, General Waker-Uz-Zaman, the Chief of Army Staff, announced that he would form the interim government. With the world's cameras pointing at him, he stood in front of a podium stating, "I am taking full responsibility."</p>

<p>The 76-year-old Sheikh Hasina resigned and fled Ganabhaban, the palatial residence of the Bangladeshi PM while protesters stormed its premises.&nbsp;</p>

<p>General Waker-Uz-Zaman, donning his military fatigues and cap, spoke to the nation via state television. "We will form an interim government," he said, confirming the resignation of Sheikh Hasina. "The country has suffered a lot, the economy has been hit, many people have been killed - it is time to stop the violence. I hope after my speech, the situation will improve."&nbsp;</p>

<p>But who is General Waker-Uz-Zaman, the man who will replace Sheikh Hasina as the new head of the state for Bangladesh?</p>

<p>A career infantry officer, he has dedicated nearly four decades to the service, including two tours as a UN peacekeeper. His tenure as Chief of Army Staff began in June, succeeding former General SM Shafiuddin Ahmed. His extensive experience spans commanding an infantry battalion, an independent infantry brigade, and an infantry division. His staff appointments include roles at the Infantry Brigade, School of Infantry and Tactics, and Army Headquarters, among others.</p>

<p>Educated at the Bangladesh Military Academy and furthering his studies at the Defence Services Command and Staff College in Mirpur and the Joint Services Command and Staff College in the UK, &nbsp;General Waker-Uz-Zaman holds advanced degrees in Defence Studies from both the National University of Bangladesh and King's College, University of London.</p>

<p>As the principal staff officer of Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina at the Armed Forces Division, &nbsp;General Waker-Uz-Zaman was deeply involved in national defence strategies and international peacekeeping affairs.&nbsp;</p>

<p>His accolades include the Army Medal of Glory (SGP) and the Extraordinary Service Medal (OSP) for his pivotal role in modernizing the army.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/4mqs5ei8_general-wakeruzzaman-_625x300_05_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A career infantry officer, he has dedicated nearly four decades to the service.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/indian-astronauts-set-for-space-mission-touchdown-in-us-for-training-6267896]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Indian Astronauts, Set For Space Mission, Touch Down In US For Training]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/indian-astronauts-set-for-space-mission-touchdown-in-us-for-training-6267896]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 05 Aug 2024 15:57:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Indian Gaganyatri's or astronaut designates set to fly to the International Space Station (ISS) have reached the United States and joined their training at Houston based American commercial company Axiom Space.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Indian Gaganyatri's or astronaut designates set to fly to the International Space Station (ISS) have reached the United States and joined their training at Houston based American commercial company Axiom Space.</p>

<p>ISRO has assigned Group Captain Shubhanshu Shukla and Group Captain Prasanth Balakrishnan Nair - part of India's Gaganyaan Mission - for training at Axiom Space and NASA's Kennedy Space Center and SpaceX. While Group Captain Shukla is the primary astronaut for the Axiom mission, Group Captain Nair is the back-up astronaut for the project. The upcoming flight is designated as the Axiom-4 (Ax-4) mission.</p>

<p>Axiom Space said the two Indian Air Force test pilots have joined the astronaut training regimen that may last several months before the flight to ISS in 2025. It also confirmed that the "crew is expected to spend up to 14 days on the space station".</p>

<p>In a statement Axiom Space said "Axiom-4 will launch to the orbiting laboratory aboard a SpaceX Falcon 9 rocket and Dragon spacecraft from Florida." No launch date has been disclosed just yet.</p>

<p>The Ax-4 crewmembers begin training with Axiom Space, NASA, and SpaceX. The crew assigned to Ax-4 includes American astronaut Commander Peggy Whitson, Mission Pilot Shubhanshu Shukla of India, Mission Specialist Slawosz Uznanski of European Space Agency (ESA)/Poland, and Mission Specialist Tibor Kapu of Hungary.</p>

<p>This will be the fourth commercial crew program spearheaded by Axiom Space and "Ax-4 represents Axiom Space's continued efforts to build opportunity for countries to research, innovate, test, and engage with people around the world while in low-Earth orbit," said Michael Suffredini, CEO of Axiom Space.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"This mission broadens horizons for nations with ambitious goals of advancing scientific, technological, and economic pursuits. Our collaboration with ESA for a second time and the inclusion of Hungary and India underscores Axiom Space's ability to cultivate global partners, expand the scope of exploration, and open up new avenues to grow a global space economy."</p>

<p>A trained biochemist and America's most experienced astronaut, 64-year-old Dr Peggy Annette Whitson, is the designated Commander of the Axiom-4 mission on which Group Captain Shubhanshu Shukla, 39, is likely to fly to the International Space Station in early 2025.</p>

<p>Dr Whitson is a veteran of four flights to space and while she retired as a NASA astronaut in 2018, she now works for Axiom Space, the Houston-based private space company, where she is the director of the human space flight programme.</p>

<p>Axiom Space describes Dr Whitson as "America's most experienced astronaut, who flew on three NASA long-duration space flights and Axiom Mission 2 (Ax-2), accumulating 675 days in space, more than any other American astronaut or woman astronaut in the world."</p>

<p>"I look forward to commanding my second commercial human spaceflight mission with Axiom Space," said Peggy Whitson, Ax-4 commander. "With a culturally diverse crew, we are not only advancing scientific knowledge but also fostering international collaboration".</p>

<p>Axiom Space is confident of pulling of the mission for which India has paid to acquire this astronaut seat. It says Axiom Mission 1 was the first all-private mission to the space station, Axiom Mission 2 launched the first Saudi female to space, and Axiom Mission 3 included both the first Turkish astronaut and first ESA astronaut to fly on a commercial space mission.</p>

<p>Whitson says "now, with Ax-4, we ascend even higher, bringing even more nations to low-Earth orbit and expanding humanity's reach among the stars."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/g11lgh7g_space-mission-_625x300_05_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Ax-4 crewmembers begin training with Axiom Space, NASA, and SpaceX.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/stop-murder-stop-violence-appeals-bangladesh-army-chief-after-taking-over-6267837]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Stop Murder, Stop Violence, Appeals Bangladesh Army Chief After Taking Over]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/stop-murder-stop-violence-appeals-bangladesh-army-chief-after-taking-over-6267837]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 05 Aug 2024 15:49:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[End violence, will meet your demands, said Bangladesh's army chief Waker-Uz-Zaman Monday to protesters, adding that he will form an interim government after prime minister Sheikh Hasina resigned and fled the capital.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>End violence, will meet your demands, said Bangladesh's army chief Waker-Uz-Zaman Monday to protesters, adding that he will form an interim government after prime minister Sheikh Hasina resigned and fled the capital in the face of overwhelming protests.</p>

<p>"We will form an interim government," Waker said in a broadcast to the nation on state television, assuring the protesters that their demands will be met.</p>

<p>"The country has suffered a lot, the economy has been hit, many people have been killed -- it is time to stop the violence," he added.</p>

<p>"I hope after my speech, the situation will improve."</p>

<p>Waker,&nbsp;a career infantry officer who has spent nearly four decades in the military, was appointed to the military's top job as chief of army staff earlier this year.</p>

<p>"If the situation gets better, there is no need for emergency", he said, vowing the new authorities would "prosecute all murders" following weeks of deadly protests.</p>

<p>"Now the task of the students is to keep calm and help us," he said.</p>

<p>Ms Hasina, who has ruled Bangladesh since 2009, had defied weeks of demands for her to stand down but fled following a brutal day of unrest on Sunday in which nearly 100 people died.</p>

<p>Protests broke out over the reintroduction of a quota scheme that reserved more than half of all government jobs for certain groups.</p>

<p>The protests escalated despite the scheme having been scaled back by Bangladesh's top court.</p>

<p>In a hugely symbolic rebuke of Ms Hasina, a former army chief demanded the government "immediately" withdraw troops and allow protests.</p>

<p>The anti-government movement had attracted people from across society in the South Asian nation of about 170 million people, including film stars, musicians and singers.</p>

<p>The 76-year-old prime minister fled the country by helicopter, say reports, shortly after protesters had stormed her palace in Dhaka. Multiple reports say she is headed to an undisclosed location in India.</p>

<p>Bangladesh's Channel 24 broadcast images of crowds running into the compound, waving to the camera as they celebrated.</p>

<p>Others smashed a statues of Hasina's father Sheikh Mujibur Rahma, the country's independence hero.</p>

<p>Ms Hasina and won her fourth consecutive election in January after a vote without genuine opposition.</p>

<p><em>(With AFP Inputs)</em><br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-03/0frtahd_bangladesh-violence-afp_625x300_28_March_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Bangladesh Army Chief]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladeshi-protesters-vandalise-sheikh-mujibur-rahmans-statue-6267746]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bangladeshi Protesters Vandalise Sheikh Mujibur Rahman's Statue]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladeshi-protesters-vandalise-sheikh-mujibur-rahmans-statue-6267746]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 05 Aug 2024 15:39:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hundreds of thousands of Bangladeshi protesters defied curfew and stormed the Prime Minister's palace in capital Dhaka after reports surfaced that Sheikh Hasina has resigned and left the country.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Thousands of Bangladeshi protesters defied curfew and stormed the Prime Minister's palace in capital Dhaka after reports surfaced that Sheikh Hasina has resigned and left the country.</p>

<p>Jubilant looking crowds waved flags on the streets of Dhaka, before hundreds broke through the gates of Sheikh Hasina's official residence.</p>

<p>The crowd also vandalised Ms Hasina's father and former Bangladesh President Sheikh Mujibur Rahman statue in Dhaka.</p>

<p>Soldiers and police with armoured vehicles in Dhaka had barricaded routes to Ms Hasina's office with barbed wire, AFP reporters said, but vast crowds flooded the streets, tearing down barriers.</p>

<p>Local media estimated as many as 400,000 protesters were on the streets but it was impossible to verify the figure.</p>

<p>At least 98 people were killed yesterday, including 14 police officers, in the deadliest day of the unrest. The day's violence took the total number of people killed since protests began in early July to at least 300.</p>

<p>Rallies that began last month against civil service job quotas have escalated into some of the worst unrest of Prime Minister Hasina's 15-year rule and shifted into wider calls for the 76-year-old to step down.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/2re61o78_protester_625x300_05_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Jubilant looking crowds waved flags on the streets of Dhaka]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-sheikh-hasina-who-once-saved-bangladesh-from-military-rule-6267638]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Who Is Sheikh Hasina Who Once Saved Bangladesh From Military Rule]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-sheikh-hasina-who-once-saved-bangladesh-from-military-rule-6267638]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 05 Aug 2024 15:26:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Sheikh Hasina once helped rescue Bangladesh from military rule, but her time in power has seen the mass arrest of her political opponents and human rights sanctions against her security forces.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sheikh Hasina once helped rescue Bangladesh from military rule, but her time in power has seen the mass arrest of her political opponents and human rights sanctions against her security forces.</p>

<p>Since July, the autocratic premier has faced mass protests that began as university student-led rallies against civil service job quotas, but which have morphed into some of the worst unrest of her 15-year tenure, with opponents demanding she step down.</p>

<p>The protests were largely peaceful until attacks on demonstrators by police and pro-government student groups, sparking international condemnation.</p>

<p>The 76-year-old won a fifth term as prime minister in January, with the opposition boycotting a vote they said was neither free nor fair.</p>

<p>At the time, Hasina branded the main opposition party a "terrorist organisation".</p>

<p>Critics accuse her government of a litany of rights abuses including the murder of opposition activists.</p>

<p>The daughter of a revolutionary who led Bangladesh to independence, Hasina has presided over breakneck economic growth in a country once written off by US statesman Henry Kissinger as an irredeemable "basket case".</p>

<p>Last year she promised to turn all of Bangladesh into a "prosperous and developed country", but around 18 million young Bangladeshis are out of work, according to government figures.</p>

<p><strong>- Economic rise -</strong></p>

<p>Hasina was 27 and travelling abroad when renegade military officers murdered her father, prime minister Sheikh Mujibur Rahman, along with her mother and three brothers in a 1975 coup.</p>

<p>She returned after living in exile for six years to take the reins of her father's Awami League party, beginning a decade-long struggle that saw her subjected to lengthy stretches of house arrest.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Hasina joined forces with Khaleda Zia's Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) to help oust military dictator Hussain Muhammad Ershad in 1990.</p>

<p>But they soon fell out and their ensuing rivalry has since dominated Bangladeshi politics.</p>

<p>Hasina first served a term as prime minister in 1996, but lost to Zia five years later.</p>

<p>The pair were then imprisoned on corruption charges in 2007 after a coup by a military-backed government.</p>

<p>The charges were dropped and they were free to contest an election the following year.</p>

<p>Hasina won in a landslide and has been in power ever since.</p>

<p>The 78-year-old Zia meanwhile is in ailing health and confined to hospital after graft charges saw her sentenced to a 17-year prison term in 2018, with top leaders from her party also behind bars.</p>

<p>Hasina has been praised by supporters for leading Bangladesh through a remarkable economic boom, largely on the back of the mostly female factory workforce powering its garment export industry.</p>

<p>Bangladesh, one of the world's poorest countries when it gained independence from Pakistan in 1971, has grown an average of more than six percent each year since 2009.</p>

<p>Poverty has plummeted and more than 95 percent of the country's 170 million people now have access to electricity, with per capita income overtaking India in 2021.</p>

<p>Hasina also received international acclaim for opening Bangladesh's doors to hundreds of thousands of Rohingya refugees fleeing a 2017 military crackdown in neighbouring Myanmar.</p>

<p>And she has been hailed for a decisive crackdown on Islamist militants in the Muslim-majority nation after five homegrown extremists stormed a Dhaka cafe popular with Western expatriates and killed 22 people in 2016.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>- Silencing dissent -</strong></p>

<p>But her government's intolerance towards dissent has given rise to resentment at home and expressions of concern from Washington and elsewhere.</p>

<p>Five top Islamist leaders and a senior opposition figure were executed over the past decade after convictions for crimes against humanity committed during the country's brutal 1971 liberation war.</p>

<p>Instead of healing the wounds of that conflict, the trials triggered mass protests and deadly clashes.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Her opponents branded them a farce, saying they were a politically motivated exercise to silence dissent.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The United States imposed sanctions in 2021 on an elite branch of Bangladesh's security forces and seven of its top officers over charges of widespread human rights abuses.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In the face of mounting protests, Hasina has insisted she has worked for her nation.</p>

<p>Last month she toured areas of Dhaka damaged during days of deadly unrest, including a metro station that was among several government buildings torched or vandalised.</p>

<p>"Over 15 years, I've built this country," she told reporters, condemning the damage to infrastructure. "What didn't I do for the people?</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/qd5o8k6g_sheikh-hasina_625x300_05_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sheikh Hasina first served a term as prime minister in 1996, but lost to Zia five years later.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-protests-sheikh-hasina-resigns-bangladesh-army-gave-sheikh-hasina-45-minutes-to-quit-top-developments-6267616]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[S Jaishankar Meets PM Modi As Sheikh Hasina Flees Bangladesh After Army Coup]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-protests-sheikh-hasina-resigns-bangladesh-army-gave-sheikh-hasina-45-minutes-to-quit-top-developments-6267616]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 05 Aug 2024 15:23:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Narendra Modi has spoken to External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar about the violence in neighbouring Bangladesh - in which over 300 have died so far - and the resignation of former PM Sheikh Hasina and the fall of her government.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<ol>
	<li><a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/topic/pm-modi" target="_blank">Prime Minister Narendra Modi</a> has been briefed on the Bangladesh situation by External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar.&nbsp;There is no word yet if Mr Modi will meet Mrs Hasina.</li>
	<li><a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/topic/sheikh-hasina" target="_blank">Sheikh Hasina</a>&nbsp;- who fled her Dhaka residence shortly before it was overrun - has landed at the Hindon Air&nbsp;Force base in Uttar Pradesh's Ghaziabad, which is 30km from Delhi.</li>
	<li>She arrived in a Bangladesh Air Force C-130 military transport - that has been parked near the Indian Air Force's C-17 and C-130J aircrafts - and is expected to fly to London.</li>
	<li>In India, the Border Security Force is on high alert. India shares a 4,096 km border with Bangladesh, across which travel has been stopped; the Railways and Air India have cancelled trains and flights.&nbsp;The airline operates two flights daily from Delhi to Dhaka.</li>
	<li>Earlier today, after Mrs Hasina resigned, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-waker-uz-zaman-army-general-to-take-bangladesh-charge-6268066#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">Army chief General Waker-Uz-Zaman</a> said the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladeshs-sheikh-hasina-quits-flies-out-amid-massive-protests-report-6267468#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">military will form an "interim government"</a>&nbsp;and urged to protesters to stand down.</li>
	<li>"There is a crisis. I have met Opposition leaders and we have decided to form an interim government to run this country. I take all responsibility and promise to protect your life and property. Your demands will be fulfilled. <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/stop-murder-stop-violence-appeals-bangladesh-army-chief-after-taking-over-6267837#pfrom=home-ndtv_topstories_lastestImg" target="_blank">Please&nbsp;stop the violence</a>," he said.</li>
	<li>Chaos erupted this morning after <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-pm-sheikh-hasina-leaves-dhaka-palace-for-safer-place-report-6267175#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">protesters stormed Gonobhaban - the PM's Dhaka residence</a>. But by then Mrs Hasina - who began a fifth term as PM this year - had fled; sources said she and her younger sister, Sheikh Rehana, left in a military helicopter.</li>
	<li><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-unrest-live-updates-pm-sheikh-hasina-bangladesh-violence-bangladesh-violence-live-6267300" target="_blank">100 people were killed and over 1,000 injured</a> in clashes that took place between police and protesters on Sunday. The protests, which began late last month, have escalated dramatically over the past few days after a pitched battle between students and police.</li>
	<li>The <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-protests-sheikh-hasina-awami-league-explained-what-led-to-bangladesh-protests-that-has-seen-over-300-killed-6265524#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">protests began over a quota system</a>&nbsp;that reserves up to 30 per cent of government jobs for family members of veterans from Bangladesh's 1971 war against Pakistan. The demonstrations quickly grew into a wider anti-government movement that attracted people from all strata of Bangladeshi society, including film stars, musicians and singers.</li>
	<li>The Bangladesh Supreme Court cut the reservations to 5 per cent. Student leaders then put protests on hold but it flared up after they said the government ignored their call to release all their leaders. This triggered demands for Sheikh Hasina to quit.<em> </em></li>
</ol>

<p><em><strong>With input from agencies</strong></em></p>

<p><em>NDTV is now available on WhatsApp channels. <a href="https://www.whatsapp.com/channel/0029Va4lixw7z4kcvZI9JM12">Click on the link</a> to get all the latest updates from NDTV on your chat. </em></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/chefhsdo_sheikh-hasina-_625x300_22_June_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[PM Sheikh Hasina: Sheikh Hasina resigned as Prime Minister of Bangladesh (File).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladeshs-sheikh-hasina-quits-flies-out-amid-massive-protests-report-6267468]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh PM Sheikh Hasina Quits, Army Coup Amid Massive Protests]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladeshs-sheikh-hasina-quits-flies-out-amid-massive-protests-report-6267468]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 05 Aug 2024 15:03:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Sheikh Hasina has resigned as Bangladesh Prime Minister and fled the country amid violent clashes between her party Awami League's supporters and protesters demanding that she quit, news agency Reuters has reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sheikh Hasina has quit as Bangladesh Prime Minister and the Army has taken control amid violent protests demanding her exit. Bangladesh Army chief General <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-waker-uz-zaman-army-general-to-take-bangladesh-charge-6268066">Waker-Uz-Zaman</a> told the media that the Army will form an interim government and has appealed to the protesters to return to the path of peace.</p>

<p>"There is a crisis in the country. I have met Opposition leaders and we have decided to form an interim government to run this country. I take all responsibility and promise to protect your life and property. Your demands will be fulfilled. Please support us and stop violence. If you work with us, we can move towards a proper solution. We cannot achieve anything through violence," he said. The Army chief also confirmed that Ms Hasina has stepped down.&nbsp;</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont">
<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Over 300 people lost their lives as security forces cracked down on in the protests. AFP" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/64dpq37g_bangladesh-protests_625x300_05_August_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Over 300 people lost their lives as security forces cracked down on in the protests. AFP" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">Over 300 people lost their lives as security forces cracked down on in the protests. AFP</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>

<p>The Army General said leaders of Opposition parties and civil society were present at today's meeting, and clarified that nobody from the ruling Awami League attended it.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Ms Hasina, who started her fifth term as Prime Minister earlier this year, left state capital Dhaka in a military aircraft <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sheikh-hasina-lands-at-hindon-airbase-near-delhi-after-fleeing-bangladesh-6268836">for India</a>.</p>

<p>The 76-year-old is accompanied by her younger sister, Sheikh Rehana. Protesters demanding her resignation have, meanwhile, stormed Gono Bhaban, the Prime Minister's official residence, local media reports have said. The Bangladesh Army, it is learnt, had given a 45-minute ultimatum to the Prime Minister to step down.</p>

<p>Shocking visuals of protesters vandalising a statue of Sheikh Mujibur Rahman, Ms Hasina's father and the tallest leader in the country's history who led its fight for Independence from Pakistan, are playing out on Dhaka's streets. The visuals mark a massive shift in the country's political landscape. The legacy of Mujibur Rahman, fondly known as Bangabandhu, is no longer a symbol of Bangladesh's war of liberation. Instead, it represents her daughter's politics that protesters claim has focused on suppressing dissent.</p>

<p><strong>What's Behind The Protests</strong></p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-protests-sheikh-hasina-awami-league-explained-what-led-to-bangladesh-protests-that-has-seen-over-300-killed-6265524">The protests</a> in Bangladesh, which began last month and escalated swiftly, started as an agitation against a quota system under which 30 per cent of government jobs were reserved for family members of Muktijoddhas -- those who fought in Bangladesh's war of independence in 1971. The protesters have said this system favours supporters of the ruling Awami League and want a merit-based system to replace it. As the protests grew, the Awami League dispensation tried to crush it with an iron hand. In the clashes that followed, more than 300 people were killed.</p>

<p>What added to the protesters' anger was a remark by Prime Minister Hasina. "If not the grandchildren of the freedom fighters, then who will get quota benefits? The grandchildren of the 'Razakars'?" she asked. "This is my question. I want to ask the people of the nation. If the protesters don't comply, I can do nothing. They can continue their protest. If protesters damage properties or attack cops, the law will take its course. We can't help."</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="The Sheikh Hasina administration initially tried to crush the protests. AFP" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/gbk16bvg_the-sheikh-hasina-administration-initially-tried-to-crush-the-protests_625x300_05_August_24.jpg?im=FitAndFill,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="The Sheikh Hasina administration initially tried to crush the protests. AFP" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">Displayed in a protest, this poster here says Sheikh Hasina is a "murderer of students". AFP</p>
</div>

<p>The Razakar remark touched a raw nerve. A paramilitary force recruited by Pakistan Army during the 1971 liberation war, Razakars carried out mass atrocities, including mass killings, rapes, and torture.</p>

<p>Reservation has been a burning issue in Bangladesh for several years now. In 2018, an agitation on this issue forced the government to water down the reservation system and cancelled quotas for some positions.</p>

<p>The latest unrest was sparked by a high court order that declared illegal the 2018 government circular cancelling 30 per cent quota for freedom fighters' descendants in government jobs.</p>

<p>This order was scrapped by the country's Supreme Court. The Supreme Court ordered that 93 per cent of government jobs must be allocated on the basis of merit and the remaining be reserved for relatives of freedom fighters. But even the top court's order could not pacify the protesters.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-01/lj3t5fn_sheikh-hasina-oath_625x300_11_January_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sheikh Hasina left Dhaka in a military aircraft and may be headed to India]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-eyes-indian-ocean-island-as-possible-military-base-to-deter-china-6267262]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Eyes Indian Ocean Island As Possible Military Base To Deter China]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-eyes-indian-ocean-island-as-possible-military-base-to-deter-china-6267262]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 05 Aug 2024 14:44:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A remote Australian island close to an Indian Ocean chokepoint for Chinese oil shipments is on a list of possible locations for US military construction aimed at deterring China, with the US saying it "may or may not" support American forces.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A remote Australian island close to an Indian Ocean chokepoint for Chinese oil shipments is on a list of possible locations for US military construction aimed at deterring China, with the US saying it "may or may not" support American forces.</p>

<p>Australia's Cocos Islands is listed along with the Philippines, Timor Leste and Papua New Guinea for anticipated construction projects under the Pacific Deterrence Initiative, designed to enhance US force posture and infrastructure to counter China.</p>

<p>The Cocos Islands, with a population of 600, sits 3,000 km west of the Australian mainland and is described by the Australian Defence Force as key to its maritime surveillance operations in the Indian Ocean, where China is increasing submarine activity.</p>

<p>A US Navy construction tender published in June for various base infrastructures in the Indo-Pacific lists Cocos Islands as a possible project location, an indication the US military is also seeking access to the Indian Ocean territory.</p>

<p>"These projects may or may not support the Darwin Marines Rotational Force," a spokesman for NAVFAC Pacific, the US Navy's Pacific Fleet engineering arm, said in an emailed response to Reuters.</p>

<p>Around 2,000 US Marines are hosted in the northern Australian city of Darwin for six months of the year.</p>

<p>There was no immediate response from the Chinese foreign ministry when asked for comment on the US Navy tender list and Cocos Islands as a possible project.</p>

<p>Cocos Islands is closer to the Strait of Malacca, a chokepoint for half of China's oil shipments than the US Navy base of Diego Garcia, a launch pad for US bombers in the Iraq and Afghanistan conflicts, but whose long-term future is under a cloud.</p>

<p>Darshana Baruah, director of security and geopolitics for the Australia India Institute, told a US Congressional hearing last year that Cocos Islands would be "critical geography" for the US to put pressure on China to deter an attack on Taiwan.</p>

<p>"Cocos is much closer to the theatre where Washington anticipates conflict scenarios," she told Reuters.</p>

<p>"The strategic location of Cocos Islands, close to both the Strait of Malacca as well as Australia's northern approaches, gives it immense geostrategic advantages," she added.</p>

<p>Australia has said it will start construction on an expanded airfield on the island this year, to carry heavier military aircraft, including the submarine-hunting P-8A Poseidon.</p>

<p>"There is currently no US investment at Cocos (Keeling) Island," an Australian Defence Force spokesman said in a statement.</p>

<p>"Australia and the US cooperate closely together to advance our force posture cooperation across various locations in Australia," the statement added.</p>

<p>The US military is constructing bomber runways and facilities at two key northern Australian air bases.</p>

<p>The US has said its Diego Garcia air base plays a vital role in regional security, and it was a matter for Britain and Mauritius to work out its future after the United Nations General Assembly voted in 2019 that it should be returned to Mauritius.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/gqad7vv_military-base-pixabay_625x300_05_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Construction will start on an expanded airfield to carry heavier military aircraft, Australia says.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/french-climber-benjamin-vedrines-breaks-speed-record-on-k2-summit-in-under-11-hours-6266703]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[French Climber Achieves Fastest-Ever Ascent Of K2, Credits Patience]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/french-climber-benjamin-vedrines-breaks-speed-record-on-k2-summit-in-under-11-hours-6266703]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 05 Aug 2024 14:41:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[French mountaineer Benjamin Vedrines counted every second as he made history's fastest-ever ascent of K2, but says he doesn't add up the growing number of records to his name.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>French mountaineer Benjamin Vedrines counted every second as he made history's fastest-ever ascent of K2, but says he doesn't add up the growing number of records to his name.</p>

<p>"It's not the records themselves that interest me, it's also the links that I create with certain mountains and especially in the case of K2," the 32-year-old told AFP.</p>

<p>"It fascinated me from the first moment I saw it."</p>

<p>Vedrines scaled the world's second-highest mountain -- standing at 8,611 metres (28,251 feet) on the border of Pakistan and China -- in 10 hours, 59 minutes and 59 seconds on Sunday, July 28th.</p>

<p>The ascent slashed by more than half the previous record for climbing K2 without bottled oxygen, completed in 23 hours by fellow Frenchman Benoit Chamoux in 1986.</p>

<p>The remarkable feat on the "Savage Mountain" came exactly two years to the day since Vedrines was forced to abort his first attempt as the high altitude starved his brain of oxygen a mere 200 metres from the top.</p>

<p>While his record has made headlines worldwide for its speed, for Vedrines it is remarkable for the opposite reason -- because it was so long in the making.</p>

<p>"I wanted to arrive there really ready, prepared, body, mind," he said. "I pay attention to doing things well, to building them. These are projects that take time."</p>

<h3><strong>'Go slow to go fast'</strong></h3>

<p>Vedrines is considered one of France's pre-eminent climbers and in 2022 set a speed record climbing Pakistan's Broad Peak -- the world's 12th highest mountain -- before descending by paraglider.</p>

<p>Back home in the French Alps, he has also broken a host of records.</p>

<p>He uses the "alpine style" of climbing which relies on minimal use of cumbersome ropes in favour of moving swiftly up the slopes.</p>

<p>But without the aid of oxygen tanks to counteract the thin atmosphere, he faced a paradox on K2 -- needing to move quickly, in one of the world's most unforgiving environments, with minimal effort.</p>

<p>"It requires knowing how to go slowly to go fast," he quips. "It is a little bit of a contradiction that we have to negotiate."</p>

<p>To make matters worse, poor weather on the mountain prevented his attempts to acclimatise.</p>

<p>"I had to face a lot of unforeseen events during this expedition," he said.</p>

<p>"I knew how to persevere. I knew how to be determined, patient and above all humble because this K2 mountain requires a lot of humility."</p>

<p>While Nepal's Mount Everest is around 240 metres taller than K2, the Pakistan peak first scaled in 1954 is regarded as a more challenging ascent.</p>

<p>Elite climbers often talk of a special connection to the mountain despite its fatal reputation.</p>

<p>Historically around one in four ascent attempts have ended in death.</p>

<p>Recent years have seen fewer fatalities, but two Japanese climbers also attempting to scale K2 using the "alpine style" fell the day before Vedrines' ascent, with their motionless bodies spotted by a helicopter.</p>

<p>A rescue was deemed impossible.</p>

<h3><strong>'K2 accepted me'</strong></h3>

<p>At times Vedrines was climbing solo, as well as at record speed.</p>

<p>"I had to forge a little path in the snow and there was this slightly mystical atmosphere that is specific to K2," he said.</p>

<p>Vedrines left K2's Advanced Base Camp at 5,350 metres just after midnight, and covered the 3,261 metres to the top before lunchtime the next day.</p>

<p>After making his descent, he spoke to AFP a week later, on Sunday, in the resort town of Skardu -- the gateway to northern Pakistan which is home to five of the world's 14 mountains above 8,000 metres.</p>

<p>"I feel very grateful that the K2 mountain finally accepted me this year," said Vedrines.</p>

<p>"It was not a form of revenge but a form of reconciliation."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/b2mhp9no_benjamin-vedrines-afp_625x300_05_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Vedrines scaled the world's second-highest mountain at 8,611 meters in 10 hours, 59 minutes, 59 seconds.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-unrest-live-updates-pm-sheikh-hasina-bangladesh-violence-bangladesh-violence-live-6267300]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh Unrest Live: Air India Cancels Flights To Dhaka Amid Protests]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-unrest-live-updates-pm-sheikh-hasina-bangladesh-violence-bangladesh-violence-live-6267300]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 05 Aug 2024 14:40:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Uncertainty looms over the future of Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina after Bangladesh witnessed one of its deadliest days. Tens of thousands of protesters have hit the streets and clashed with cops, demanding Hasina's resignation.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Uncertainty looms over the future of Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina after Bangladesh witnessed one of its deadliest days. Tens of thousands of protesters have hit the streets and clashed with cops, demanding Hasina's resignation. At least 98 people were killed in Sunday violence, surpassing the 67 deaths reported on July 19 when students protested against the quota system for government jobs.</p>

<p>Bangladeshi Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina resigned and fled the country on Monday. The Army chief said that the an interim government will be formed and Army will run the country.</p>

<h2><strong>Here are the LIVE updates on Bangladesh unrest:</strong></h2>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/s1eoet7o_bangladesh-unrest-afp_625x300_05_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sheikh-hasinas-son-issues-your-duty-call-to-bangladesh-army-amid-clashes-6267260]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Your Duty Is...": Sheikh Hasina's Son To Bangladesh Army Amid Clashes]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sheikh-hasinas-son-issues-your-duty-call-to-bangladesh-army-amid-clashes-6267260]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 05 Aug 2024 14:37:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The son of Bangladesh's Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina on Monday urged the country's security forces to block any takeover from her rule as hundreds of thousands of protesters demanded she quit.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The son of Bangladesh's Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina on Monday urged the country's security forces to block any takeover from her rule as hundreds of thousands of protesters demanded she quit. "Your duty is to keep our people safe and our country safe and to uphold the constitution," US-based Sajeeb Wazed Joy said in a post on Facebook.</p>

<p>"It means don't allow any unelected government to come in power for one minute, it is your duty."</p>

<p>Joy, who is also an information and communications technology advisor to Hasina, warned progress made by Bangladesh would be threatened if she were forced out.</p>

<p>"Everything of our development and progress will vanish. Bangladesh would not be able to come back from there," he said.</p>

<p>"I don't want that and you also do not want that," he added. "Myself, Sajeeb Wazed Joy, will not let that happen as long as I can."</p>

<p>His warning comes as Bangladesh's army chief Waker-Uz-Zaman is set to address the nation, a military spokesman told AFP without giving further details.</p>

<p>Rallies that began last month against civil service job quotas have escalated into some of the worst unrest of Hasina's 15-year rule and shifted into wider calls for the 76-year-old to resign.</p>

<p>A senior advisor to Hasina told AFP Monday that the resignation of the embattled leader was a "possibility" after being questioned as to whether she would quit.</p>

<p>"The situation is such that this is a possibility, but I don't know how it will happen," the aide close to the premier said, speaking on condition of anonymity.</p>

<p>The military declared an emergency in January 2007 after widespread political unrest and installed a caretaker government for two years.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/ock6bi28_bangladesh-protests-afp-_625x300_05_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[His warning comes as Bangladesh's army chief Waker-Uz-Zaman is set to address the nation.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>