<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Wed, 14 Aug 2024 23:29:14 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-declares-mpox-global-health-emergency-for-second-time-in-2-years-6339042]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[WHO Declares Mpox Global Health Emergency For Second Time In 2 Years]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-declares-mpox-global-health-emergency-for-second-time-in-2-years-6339042]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 14 Aug 2024 23:09:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The World Health Organization on Wednesday declared mpox a global public health emergency for the second time in two years, following an outbreak of the viral infection in the Democratic Republic of Congo that has spread to neighbouring countries.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The World Health Organization on Wednesday declared mpox a global public health emergency for the second time in two years, following an outbreak of the viral infection in the Democratic Republic of Congo that has spread to neighbouring countries.</p>

<p>Mpox can spread through close contact. Usually mild, it is fatal in rare cases. It causes flu-like symptoms and pus-filled lesions on the body.</p>

<p>Determining a disease outbreak as a "public health emergency of international concern" or PHEIC - the WHO's highest level of alert - can accelerate research, funding and international public health measures and co-operation to contain a disease.</p>

<p>The outbreak in Congo began with the spread of an endemic strain, known as clade I. But a new variant, clade Ib, appears to spread more easily through routine close contact, including sexual contact. It has spread from Congo to neighbouring countries, including Burundi, Kenya, Rwanda and Uganda, triggering the action from the WHO.</p>

<p>"It's clear that a coordinated international response is essential to stop these outbreaks and save lives," said WHO Director-General Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus.</p>

<p>Earlier this week, Africa's top public health body declared an mpox emergency for the continent after warning that the viral infection was spreading at an alarming rate.</p>

<p>More than 17,000 suspected mpox cases and 517 deaths have been reported on the African continent so far this year, a 160% increase in cases compared to the same period last year, the Africa Centres for Disease Control and Prevention said. A total of 13 countries have reported cases.</p>

<p>A different form of the mpox virus - clade IIb - spread globally in 2022, largely through sexual contact among men who have sex with men. This prompted the WHO to declare a public health emergency then, which it ended 10 months later.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/62h05c3g_mpox_625x300_14_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[It causes flu-like symptoms and pus-filled lesions on the body.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-fails-3rd-time-to-unseat-judge-sentencing-him-in-hush-money-case-6338973]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump Fails To Unseat Judge Sentencing Him In Hush Money Case]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-fails-3rd-time-to-unseat-judge-sentencing-him-in-hush-money-case-6338973]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 14 Aug 2024 22:51:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump failed for a third time on Wednesday to force out the judge who is due to sentence him for covering up hush money payments.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump failed for a third time on Wednesday to force out the judge who is due to sentence him for covering up hush money payments.</p>

<p>Lawyers for the Republican presidential nominee had again argued that the work of judge Juan Merchan's daughter for a Democrat-leaning organization created a "perceived conflict of interest" and that he should recuse himself.</p>

<p>A jury convicted the former president of 34 felonies in May for covering up payments to silence former adult star Stormy Daniels over an alleged affair.</p>

<p>On September 16, the judge will consider a separate request by Trump's lawyers to overturn the verdict and dismiss the case following a Supreme Court ruling in July on presidential immunity.</p>

<p>Depending on the outcome of that hearing, Merchan has scheduled Trump's sentencing for September 18.</p>

<p>Merchan forcefully rejected Trump's latest bid to have him removed.</p>

<p>"Stated plainly, Defendant's arguments are nothing more than a repetition of stale and unsubstantiated claims," Merchan wrote in the ruling.</p>

<p>"Defense Counsel's reliance, and apparent citation to his own prior affirmation, rife with inaccuracies and unsubstantiated claims, is unavailing. As such, Defendant's motion is again DENIED."</p>

<p>A New York State ethics panel previously found no issue in Merchan continuing to handle the case, and the judge said the "Court will continue to base its rulings on the evidence and the law, without fear or favour, casting aside undue influence."</p>

<p>Despite the ethics ruling, Trump's legal team insisted that work undertaken by Merchan's daughter, which they said included past fundraising efforts for Trump's rival, Vice President Kamala Harris, undermined the judge's independence.</p>

<p>In a tirade on his Truth Social platform, Trump called an order by Merchan limiting his ability to attack the judge's family members "suppression and manipulation of the vote."</p>

<p>Trump, the first former US president convicted of a crime, has been doing everything in his power to delay multiple trials against him until after the November election.</p>

<p>He faces charges in Washington and Georgia related to efforts to overturn the results of the 2020 election he lost to Democrat Joe Biden.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/9rce5do_donald-trump_625x300_13_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump is the first former US president to be convicted of a crime.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-confirms-its-delegation-to-attend-gaza-truce-talks-in-doha-6338880]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Confirms Its Delegation To Attend Gaza Truce Talks In Doha]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-confirms-its-delegation-to-attend-gaza-truce-talks-in-doha-6338880]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 14 Aug 2024 22:37:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel's spy chiefs will attend talks in Doha on Thursday seeking a Gaza ceasefire and hostage release deal after more than 10 months of war, the prime minister's office said on Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel's spy chiefs will attend talks in Doha on Thursday seeking a Gaza ceasefire and hostage release deal after more than 10 months of war, the prime minister's office said on Wednesday.</p>

<p>"Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu has approved the departure of the Israeli delegation to Doha tomorrow, as well as the mandate for conducting the negotiations," a statement said.</p>

<p>The head of Israel's Mossad spy agency, David Barnea, and Shin Bet security service chief Ronen Bar are part of the team, Netanyahu's spokesman Omer Dostri told AFP.</p>

<p>"The head of the Mossad, the head of the Shin Bet, Nitzan Alon and Ophir Falk" make up the team, Dostri said. Alon coordinates issues related to hostages, and Falk is a political adviser to Netanyahu.</p>

<p>Palestinian militant group Hamas has not said whether it would send negotiators to Doha.</p>

<p>A Hamas official, speaking on condition of anonymity, told AFP that "negotiations with the mediators are continuing and have even intensified in recent hours".</p>

<p>"Hamas wants the Biden plan imposed and doesn't want to negotiate just to negotiate," the official said, referring a ceasefire proposal laid out in late May by US President Joe Biden.</p>

<p>"We have to force the (Israeli) occupation government to stop its policy, which consists of dragging out the negotiations, and force it to stop massacring our people."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/v1jve4og_israel-gaza-afp_625x300_14_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israeli army soldiers operating in the Gaza Strip]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-crisis-can-hit-medical-tourism-inflow-by-10-15-in-2024-report-6338633]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh Crisis Can Hit Medical Tourism Inflow By 10-15% In 2024: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-crisis-can-hit-medical-tourism-inflow-by-10-15-in-2024-report-6338633]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 14 Aug 2024 21:52:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The socio-political unrest in Bangladesh has impacted the medical tourism inflow from the neighbouring country and if the turbulence persists the total footfall from the country may drop by 10-15 per cent this year, a report has said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The socio-political unrest in Bangladesh has impacted the medical tourism inflow from the neighbouring country and if the turbulence persists the total footfall from the country may drop by 10-15 per cent this year, a report has said.</p>

<p>Bangladesh is the leading contributor to medical tourism among neighbouring countries and accounts for 50-60 per cent of India's total medical tourism inflow, says the report released on Wednesday.</p>

<p>Current internal challenges in Bangladesh have impacted the flow of patients as a considerable number of these travellers have either cancelled or postponed their visits, according to a report by knowledge-based analytical group CareEdge Ratings.</p>

<p>According to CareEdge Ratings, if the unrest persists, the footfall is likely to decline by 10-15 per cent from Bangladesh during 2024.</p>

<p>The contribution of medical tourism to the entire Indian hospital sector is about 3 per cent to 5 per cent.</p>

<p>Considering the drop in footfall from Bangladesh along with its gradual revival to normalcy by the end of 2024, the sector will see minimal impact, according to the report.</p>

<p>"The effect on individual hospitals will vary depending on their reliance on Bangladeshi medical tourists. Hospitals with a high dependency on these tourists may experience revenue declines in the second and third quarter of FY25, while larger, multi-location hospitals in India are likely to see a relatively minor impact.</p>

<p>"Most Indian industry players appear to be largely unaffected by the crisis, supported by their strong financial resilience and robust cash accruals," CareEdge Ratings Associate Director D Naveen Kumar added.</p>

<p>In recent years, medical tourism in India has been on a gradual upward trend, driven by the relatively low cost of surgery, high-quality critical care, hospitals with advanced technology, and the expanding e-medical visa facility.</p>

<p>Although 2021, saw some growth in medical tourism following the significant impact of the Covid-19 pandemic the previous year, it remained subdued due to the ongoing travel restrictions in parts of that year.</p>

<p>However, 2022 marked a significant comeback, with medical tourism nearly returning to pre-Covid levels, and the trend continued in 2023, showing a 33 per cent year-on-year growth.</p>

<p>The government's initiative to extend the e-medical visa facility to nationals from 167 countries is expected to further boost medical tourism in the coming years, said the report.</p>

<p>This particularly benefits the hospitals in metro cities the most as they are prime beneficiaries of international patient flow, said the report adding that nearly 70-80 per cent of medical tourists arriving in India are from Bangladesh and Middle East countries.</p>

<p>India ranks among the top 10 countries for medical tourism globally and is especially preferred amongst South-Asian, African and Middle East countries.</p>

<p>Bangladesh stands out as the leading contributor to medical tourism among neighbouring countries, surpassing the Middle East, Myanmar, Maldives, Sri Lanka, and Pakistan.</p>

<p>However, recent socio-political instability in Bangladesh poses a risk to this flourishing segment of the industry as the current internal challenges have shown signs of affecting the flow of patients.</p>

<p>The hospital sector in India was valued at around Rs 5.8 lakh crore in FY23, with an anticipated annual growth rate of 12 per cent over the next three years. Each year, an estimated 3 to 3.5 lakh individuals from Bangladesh seek medical treatment in India.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/693660n8_bangladesh-police-afp_625x300_12_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Contribution of medical tourism to entire Indian hospital sector is about 3 to 5 per cent. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-musk-groove-to-bee-gees-stayin-alive-in-ai-video-now-viral-6338401]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump, Musk Groove To Bee Gees' 'Stayin' Alive' In AI-Video Now Viral]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-musk-groove-to-bee-gees-stayin-alive-in-ai-video-now-viral-6338401]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 14 Aug 2024 21:23:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Billionaire Elon Musk today shared an AI-generated video of him and Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump grooving and performing dance steps to Bee Gees' 'Stayin' Alive' song.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Billionaire Elon Musk today shared an AI-generated video of him and Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump grooving and performing dance steps to Bee Gees' 'Stayin' Alive' song.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Do we have great moves or what?," Mr Musk asked in a humorous manner.&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Best campaign video ever. <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@elonmusk</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/realDonaldTrump?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@realDonaldTrump</a> have moves! <a href="https://t.co/F41ewxJy9o">pic.twitter.com/F41ewxJy9o</a></p>
— Mike Lee (@BasedMikeLee) <a href="https://twitter.com/BasedMikeLee/status/1823581650653204750?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 14, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The video was originally shared by Mike Lee, US Senator for Utah.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The video has garnered over 6,50,7000 views and has more than 3,500 re-tweets. While some users loved the video, some pointed out the drawbacks of AI in the comment section.</p>

<p>"Somehow this will win votes lol," a user wrote.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Best video I've seen made to date!!!," wrote another.</p>

<p>A third user wrote, "I literally have no clue what's real and what isn't anymore."</p>

<p>The video comes days after Trump and Musk discussed the 2024 US presidential elections, his Democratic counterpart Kamala Harris, and climate change on the billionaire's platform X. The much-anticipated discussion was, however, marred by technical issues.</p>

<p>The live stream, delayed by more than 40 minutes due to a DDOS attack and technical issues, drew in over 1.3 million users.</p>

<p>Musk repeated his endorsement of Trump, who faces a resurgent new Democratic candidate, Vice-President Kamala Harris, in November's election.</p>

<p>The former President talked about his past policies on Iran, claiming his administration's measures effectively curtailed Tehran's ability to fund terrorism.</p>

<p>Donald Trump also announced plans to build an Iron Dome defence system, citing Israel's successful implementation of the technology.</p>

<p>Donald Trump was banned from Twitter (now X) after his supporters attacked the US Capitol on January 6, 2021. On February 21, 2022, he launched his own social media platform, Truth Social.</p>

<p>Months later, in November 2022, Elon Musk acquired Twitter and restored Trump's account, @realDonaldTrump.</p>

<p>Last month, the Tesla CEO also endorsed Trump shortly after the former president survived the attempt on his life.</p>

<p>The relationship between the two has shifted over the years and they have traded online barbs in the past.&nbsp;<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/7bnlrm6g_musk-trump_625x300_14_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/newborn-twins-killed-in-gaza-while-father-picked-up-birth-certificates-6338230]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Newborn Twins Killed In Gaza While Father Picked Up Birth Certificates]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/newborn-twins-killed-in-gaza-while-father-picked-up-birth-certificates-6338230]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 14 Aug 2024 21:01:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Mohammed Abu Al-Qumsan had just picked up birth certificates for his newly-born twins when he found out they had been killed, along with his wife and her mother, by an Israeli strike on the Gaza apartment where they were sheltering.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Mohammed Abu Al-Qumsan had just picked up birth certificates for his newly-born twins when he found out they had been killed, along with his wife and her mother, by an Israeli strike on the Gaza apartment where they were sheltering.</p>

<p>He waved the laminated documents, supposed to signify rare joy in the besieged Palestinian enclave, as a man held him while he wept at the morgue where their bodies were brought.</p>

<p>"My wife is gone, my two babies and my mother-in-law. I was told it's a tank shell on the apartment they were in, in a house we were displaced to," said Abu Al-Qumsan, 31, recalling the devastating phone call from people in the neighbourhood.</p>

<p>He and others carried his boy and girl, Asser and Ayssel, who were wrapped in white shrouds - a common sight in Gaza, where Israel's land and air campaign has put hundreds of thousands of people regularly on the move in search of shelter.</p>

<p>A man prayed as the bodies were placed in the back of a car and a crowd gathered and people looked on from the balcony of one of Gaza's overwhelmed emergency rooms, at the Al-Aqsa Maryrs Hospital in Deir al-Balah in the centre of the coastal strip.</p>

<p>Ten months after the Gaza war erupted, air strikes, artillery shells and severe shortages of medicine, food and clean water have brought one of the world's most densely populated places to its knees.</p>

<p>"Today, it was registered in history that the occupation army targets newborn children who are barely four days old, twins along with their mother and grandmother," hospital doctor Khalil al-Daqran said.</p>

<p>Israel says it goes to great lengths to avoid civilian casualties and accuses arch-foe Hamas of using human shields, charges the militants deny.</p>

<p>The Palestinian Iranian-backed militant group started the conflict in an Oct. 7 cross-border raid on Israel, killing 1,200 people and taking over 250 hostage, according to Israeli tallies.</p>

<p>Israel struck back with an offensive that has killed nearly 40,000 people and wounded more than 92,000, according to Gaza health authorities, and reduced much of the enclave to rubble</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/unfsrfjo_gaza-newborn-reuters_625x300_14_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mohammed Abu Al-Qumsan's wife and mother-in-law were also killed by the Israeli strike.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mpox-vaccine-likely-months-away-as-africa-health-body-declares-emergency-6338118]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Mpox Vaccine Likely Months Away As Africa Health Body Declares Emergency]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mpox-vaccine-likely-months-away-as-africa-health-body-declares-emergency-6338118]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 14 Aug 2024 20:48:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Vaccines to help curb an escalating mpox outbreak in Democratic Republic of Congo and neighbouring countries may still not reach the central African country for months.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Vaccines to help curb an escalating mpox outbreak in Democratic Republic of Congo and neighbouring countries may still not reach the central African country for months even as the World Health Organization considers following Africa's top public health agency in declaring the outbreak an emergency.</p>

<p>On Tuesday, Africa Centres for Disease Control and Prevention declared a public health emergency of continental concern for the first time ever, and on Wednesday, a WHO-led panel meets to decide if it represents a global threat.</p>

<p>But while experts hoped the meetings would galvanise action worldwide, many obstacles remain, including limited vaccine supply, funding and competing disease outbreaks.</p>

<p>"It is important to declare an emergency because the disease is spreading," said Jean-Jacques Muyembe-Tamfum, head of Congo's Institut National pour la Recherche Biomedicale (INRB). He said he hoped any declaration would help provide more funding for surveillance as well as supporting access to vaccines in Congo.</p>

<p>But he acknowledged the road ahead was not easy in a huge country where health facilities and humanitarian funds are already stretched by conflict and outbreaks of diseases like measles and cholera.</p>

<p>"If the big declarations remain just words, it won't make any material difference," said Emmanuel Nakoune, an mpox expert at the Institut Pasteur de Bangui in Central African Republic.</p>

<p>Africa CDC said last week it had been granted $10.4 million in emergency funding from the Africa Union for its mpox response, and its director general Jean Kaseya said on Tuesday there was a clear plan to secure 3 million doses of vaccine this year, without elaborating further.</p>

<p>However, sources involved in planning a vaccination roll-out in Congo said only 65,000 doses were likely to be available in the short-term, and campaigns were unlikely to begin before October at the earliest.</p>

<p>There have been more than 15,000 suspected cases of mpox in Africa this year and 461 deaths, mainly among children in Congo, according to Africa CDC. The viral infection is usually mild but can kill, and causes flu-like symptoms and pus-filled lesions.</p>

<p>A new offshoot of the virus has caused outbreaks in refugee camps in the east of Congo this year, and spread to Uganda, Burundi, Rwanda and Kenya for the first time.</p>

<p>Ivory Coast and South Africa are also experiencing outbreaks linked to a different strain of the virus, which spread globally in 2022, largely among men who have sex with men. This outbreak prompted WHO to declare a global emergency before ending it 10 months later.</p>

<p>Then, two vaccines were used - Bavarian Nordic's Jynneos, and LC16, made by KM Biologics. Outside clinical trials, neither has ever been available in Congo or across Africa, where the disease has been endemic for decades. Only LC16 is approved for use in children.</p>

<p>Congo's regulators approved the use of the vaccines domestically in June, but the government is yet to officially request any from either the manufacturers or governments like the United States looking to make donations through the global vaccine group, Gavi.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/fs2pe1v8_mpox-congo-africa-reuters_625x300_14_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mpox, caused by the monkeypox virus, sparks off a painful rash, enlarged lymph nodes and fever]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/high-stakes-gaza-ceasefire-talks-to-be-held-in-doha-on-thursday-report-6337952]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[High-Stakes Gaza Ceasefire Talks To Be Held In Doha On Thursday: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/high-stakes-gaza-ceasefire-talks-to-be-held-in-doha-on-thursday-report-6337952]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 14 Aug 2024 20:23:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Gaza ceasefire talks will be held in the Qatari capital on Thursday, two sources close to the negotiations said, while it remains unclear if Palestinian Islamist movement Hamas will participate.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Gaza ceasefire talks will be held in the Qatari capital on Thursday, two sources close to the negotiations said, while it remains unclear if Palestinian Islamist movement Hamas will participate.</p>

<p>Qatar has been engaged in behind-the-scenes efforts, with support from Egypt and the United States, to reach a deal for a Gaza truce and hostage-prisoner exchange after more than 10 months of war.</p>

<p>A source close to Hamas and a second source close to the talks confirmed Thursday's meeting in Doha.</p>

<p>CIA director William Burns was also scheduled to travel to Doha for talks, according to a US source familiar with the meeting.</p>

<p>The US State Department has said Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu had confirmed Israel's participation.</p>

<p>"Our Qatari partners have assured us that they are working to ensure that there is Hamas representation as well," State Department spokesman Vedant Patel told reporters.</p>

<p>The Israelis should "come to agree on a (deal) or not come at all", said a source close to Hamas, without specifying if the Palestinian movement will take part in the talks.</p>

<p>Qatar, Egypt and the United States last week called for the resumption of talks "to close all remaining gaps and commence implementation of the deal without further delay".</p>

<p>A letter signed by Qatar's emir and the presidents of the United States and Egypt said a framework agreement was "now on the table, with only the details of implementation" left to conclude.</p>

<p>A prospective cessation of hostilities has centred around a phased deal beginning with an initial truce.</p>

<p>Recent discussions have focused on a framework outlined by US President Joe Biden on May 31 which he said had been proposed by Israel.</p>

<p>Ahead of Thursday's ceasefire talks, a Hamas official said the Islamist movement was "continuing its consultations with the mediators".</p>

<p>"Hamas really wants an end to the war and a ceasefire agreement on the basis of the (Biden) plan," another Hamas official said.</p>

<p>Netanyahu's office on Tuesday detailed its conditions for a truce, including "a veto on certain prisoners" being released from its jails.</p>

<p>So far, there has been only one, week-long truce in the Gaza fighting, in November, when dozens of hostages in Gaza were released in exchange for Palestinian prisoners held in Israeli jails.</p>

<p>Thursday's talks come after Iran and its allies blamed Israel for the July 31 killing of Hamas political leader Ismail Haniyeh in Tehran during a visit for the inauguration of President Masoud Pezeshkian.</p>

<p>Hamas named Yahya Sinwar -- the alleged mastermind of the October 7 attack on Israel that sparked the war -- as its new leader, raising concerns the tortuous negotiations have become even more difficult.</p>

<p>US officials have said on several occasions in recent weeks that a deal is close, while urging both Israel and Hamas to accept the current proposal which would lead to an initial six-week truce.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/c94ffj98_israel-army-in-gaza-afp_625x300_14_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[So far, there has been only one, week-long truce in the Gaza fighting, in November (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/french-athlete-muhammad-abdallah-kounta-who-took-part-in-olympics-suspended-for-past-posts-on-x-6337903]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[French Athlete Who Took Part In Olympics Suspended For Past Posts On X]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/french-athlete-muhammad-abdallah-kounta-who-took-part-in-olympics-suspended-for-past-posts-on-x-6337903]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 14 Aug 2024 20:17:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[French 400-meter runner Muhammad Abdallah Kounta, who took part in the Paris Olympics, has been suspended by the French Athletics Federation after an X account dug up hate speech posted by the athlete, the sports minister said on Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>French 400-meter runner Muhammad Abdallah Kounta, who took part in the Paris Olympics, has been suspended by the French Athletics Federation after an X account dug up hate speech posted by the athlete, the sports minister said on Wednesday.</p>

<p>"The Federation's president confirmed he has suspended the athlete and referred the matter both to the public prosecutor and to the Federation's disciplinary committee," Amelie Oudea-Castera said on X.</p>

<p>X account Sword of Solomon on Tuesday highlighted some tweets posted by Kounta between 2021 and 2024 in which, among other things, he professes hatred for Israel.</p>

<p>After the revelations, the athlete posted a picture of himself wrapped in a French flag on his social media accounts, saying he was sorry if he had offended people.</p>

<p>"I'm against genocides and all forms of racism or injustice and I don't think I need to prove how much I love my country. People who were there in the Stade de France (where the athletic events took place) can attest that fact," Kounta said.</p>

<p>The Paris Olympics have been widely considered a dazzling summertime success that reaffirmed French national pride.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/ot9en5vo_muhammad-abdallah-kounta_625x300_14_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Paris Olympics have been widely considered a dazzling summertime success.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mars-to-acquire-pringles-maker-kellanova-for-nearly-36-billion-6337872]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Mars To Acquire Pringles Maker Kellanova For Nearly $36 Billion]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mars-to-acquire-pringles-maker-kellanova-for-nearly-36-billion-6337872]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 14 Aug 2024 20:13:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[M&M's and Snickers maker Mars said Wednesday that it would acquire snack food business Kellanova, marking a multibillion dollar agreement set to result in a new industry giant.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>M&amp;M's and Snickers maker Mars said Wednesday that it would acquire snack food business Kellanova, marking a multibillion dollar agreement set to result in a new industry giant.</p>

<p>The all-cash transaction would value Kellanova -- which is behind snacks such as Pringles and Pop-Tarts -- at $35.9 billion, including debt.</p>

<p>"In welcoming Kellanova's portfolio of growing global brands, we have a substantial opportunity for Mars to further develop a sustainable snacking business that is fit for the future," said Mars chief executive Poul Weihrauch in a statement.</p>

<p>The announcement comes at a time when consumers feel the squeeze from rising costs of living, putting pressure on companies to rein in their price hikes.</p>

<p>The move could, however, attract scrutiny from US regulators who have taken a tough stance on consolidations.</p>

<p>The acquisition for $83.50 per share in cash "accelerates ambition to double Mars Snacking in the next decade, in alignment with global consumer demand trends," Mars said.</p>

<p>This would bring two new billion-dollar brands, Pringles and Cheez-It, into its business.</p>

<p>Already, the company said it has 15 billion-dollar brands.</p>

<p>"Snacking is a large, attractive and durable category that continues to grow in importance with consumers," Mars added.</p>

<p>Kellanova had net sales in 2023 of around $13 billion, and it is present in 180 markets with some 23,000 employees.</p>

<p>Shares of Kellanova were up by 7.3 percent in US pre-market trading.</p>

<p>The Mars statement added that most of Kellanova's snack brands outperform competitors, especially among Gen Z and millennial buyers.</p>

<p>The combined portfolio would also be suited to meet demand in fast-growing markets such as Africa and Latin America, given their supply chains and local operations, the company said.</p>

<p>The plan, according to Mars, is to grow Kellanova's brands further.</p>

<p>The deal, which is anticipated to close in the first half of 2025, will need the green light from Kellanova shareholders and also require regulatory approvals.</p>

<p>Mars plans to fully finance the acquisition via a combination of cash-on-hand and new debt, it said, adding that commitments have been secured.</p>

<p>Family-owned business Mars said it employs about 150,000 workers and has over $50 billion in annual sales.</p>

<p>Besides snacking and food products, the company is also involved in the pet care sector.</p>

<p>In 2022, Mars said it reached a deal to buy whole-fruit snacking brand Tru Fru. And two years before that, it announced its acquisition of Kind North America -- which specializes in healthier snacks.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/s5ge13to_pringles-afp_625x300_14_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The merger would bring two new billion-dollar brands, Pringles and Cheez-It, into its business. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/2-french-rafale-jets-collide-mid-air-instructor-pilot-missing-6337097]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[2 French Rafale Jets Collide Mid-Air, Instructor, Pilot Missing]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/2-french-rafale-jets-collide-mid-air-instructor-pilot-missing-6337097]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 14 Aug 2024 18:39:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Two Rafale fighter jets collided in midair before crashing to the ground in northeastern France on Wednesday, civil and military authorities said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Two French Rafale jets collided in midair Wednesday in a rare accident involving the cutting-edge military aircraft and authorities launched a desperate search for two crew.</p>

<p>One pilot ejected following the crash over northeastern France, but an instructor and a student pilot on the second jet were missing.</p>

<p>The two supersonic jets were from the Saint-Dizier air base, an air force spokesman in Paris told AFP.</p>

<p>"One of the pilots was found safe and sound," Defence Minister Sebastien Lecornu said on the X social media platform.</p>

<p>"The search is still underway" after the crash, he added, thanking armed forces and police involved in the operation.</p>

<p>It was not immediately clear what caused the collision that authorities said occurred over Colombey-les-Belles, a town in northeastern France.</p>

<p>"The military authorities will report on the causes of the accident", said the local prefecture.</p>

<p>The Rafale "multi-role" fighter -- used to hunt enemy planes, strike ground and sea targets, carry out reconnaissance and even carry France's nuclear warheads -- has become a bestseller for the French arms industry.</p>

<p>Accidents involving Rafale jets are rare.</p>

<h3><strong>'Strange noise'</strong></h3>

<p>"We heard a loud noise, around 12:30pm," Patrice Bonneaux, deputy mayor of Colombey-les-Belles, told AFP.</p>

<p>It was not the usual sonic boom of a fighter jet breaking the sound barrier, he said. "It was a strange noise, a percussive sound".</p>

<p>"I assumed that two planes had collided, but we didn't believe it," he said, adding that a road bordering a nearby forest had been cordoned off.</p>

<p>In December 2007, a Rafale jet crashed near Neuvic in southwestern France. Investigators concluded that the pilot had become disorientated.</p>

<p>That was believed to be the first crash of a Rafale.</p>

<p>In September 2009, two Rafale aircraft went down as they flew back to the aircraft carrier Charles de Gaulle off the coast of Perpignan after completing a test flight. One pilot died.</p>

<p>France has sold the Rafale to Egypt, India, Greece, Indonesia, Croatia, Qatar and United Arab Emirates.</p>

<p>Lecornu said in January that France had ordered 42 new Rafale fighter jets, with the first to be delivered in 2027. The French military has now ordered more than 230 Rafales since the jet went into service.</p>

<p>French President Emmanuel Macron has urged defence manufacturers to boost production and innovation as Europe seeks to increase arms supplies to buttress Ukraine, which has been struggling to fight off Russia's invasion, now in its third year.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/ai1un6g_rafale-jets_625x300_14_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The accident occurred in Colombey-les-Belles (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-woman-accidentally-runs-over-12-year-old-daughter-on-first-day-of-school-drop-off-6337030]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Woman Accidentally Runs Over 12-Year-Old Daughter At School Drop-off]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-woman-accidentally-runs-over-12-year-old-daughter-on-first-day-of-school-drop-off-6337030]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 14 Aug 2024 18:29:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 12-year-old in the US was severely injured after her mother accidentally ran her over on her first day of school.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 12-year-old in the US was severely injured after her mother accidentally ran her over on her first day of school. According to <em>People</em>, the incident took place on Monday morning outside Boker Middle School in Florida. The mother, 30, was dropping her daughter off when she accidentally hit her. The child was airlifted to Johns Hopkins All Children's Hospital in St. Petersburg with critical injuries, cops said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to the Florida Highway Patrol (FHP), the 12-year-old had dropped some markers and pens and bent down to pick them up from under the vehicle. Tragically, however, the mother did not realise what her daughter was doing and began to drive off, running over her. "She immediately stopped when she heard her child screaming," FHP Trooper Kenn Watson said, per <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://people.com/mom-accidentally-runs-12-year-old-daughter-over-school-drop-off-8694383"><em>People</em></a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p>A Sarasota County Schools spokesperson confirmed the accident, saying, "A parent accidentally hit their child as the parent was dropping the child off on the street". "The school district encourages all families to follow district &amp; school safety protocols and use the designated student pickup and drop off areas on school campuses," they added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Separately, Mr Watson said, "Here we are, day one, and we've already had a tragedy. We're hoping this does not happen again, but we have to remember to have that good spatial awareness when you are anywhere around a school zone and most certainly when you are letting your kid out of your vehicle".&nbsp;</p>

<p>"You want to avoid being in a hurry and dropping off our kids in the turn lane when we should be directly in front of the school," he continued, adding, "This is a tragedy that one hundred percent could have been avoided by simply paying a little more attention and not being in a hurry."</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/24-year-old-us-man-arrested-for-giving-4-month-old-baby-gasoline-to-drink-6336388">24-Year-Old US Man Arrested For Giving 4-Month-Old Baby Gasoline To Drink</a></strong></p>

<p>In a message to families, Booker Middle School principal LaShawn Frost said the crash "serves as a reminder of the importance of following our established safety procedures".&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Please remember that students should not be dropped off in the middle of Myrtle Street," the principal said. "This practice poses a significant risk to our students' safety and the safety of others on the road," he added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>On Tuesday, officials said that the child is in stable condition. "Johns Hopkins All Children's Hospital has advised that the 12-year-old victim has been upgraded to 'Stable' as of 4:00 p.m. Eastern Time," said Mr Watson.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/an15mbcg_caution-tape-generic_625x300_17_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The incident took place on Monday. (Representative pic)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korea-to-open-borders-for-foreign-tourists-in-december-6336908]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[North Korea To Open Borders For Foreign Tourists In December]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korea-to-open-borders-for-foreign-tourists-in-december-6336908]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 14 Aug 2024 18:13:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[North Korea will resume international tourism to its northeastern city of Samjiyon in December, and possibly the rest of the country, tour companies said on Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>North Korea will resume international tourism to its northeastern city of Samjiyon in December, and possibly the rest of the country, tour companies said on Wednesday.</p>

<p>The move is a sign that the reclusive country is readying to reopen borders to bigger groups of foreign tourists after years of strict COVID border controls.</p>

<p>"We have received confirmation from our local partner that tourism to Samjiyon and likely the rest of the country will officially resume in December 2024," the Beijing-based Koryo Tours said on its website.</p>

<p>International flights in and out of North Korea resumed last year and a small group of Russian tourists flew to North Korea for a private tour in February. Top foreign officials, including Russian President Vladimir Putin in June, have been visiting the country.</p>

<p>However, North Korea has not been fully open to international tourists since 2020.</p>

<p>"Having waited for over four years to make this announcement, Koryo Tours is very excited for the opening of North Korean tourism once again," the firm said, adding its local partner would confirm itineraries and dates in coming weeks.</p>

<p>North Korea has been building what it called a "socialist utopia" in Samjiyon, a city near the Chinese border, and "a model of highly-civilised mountain city" with new apartments, hotels, a ski resort and commercial, cultural and medical facilities.</p>

<p>Leader Kim Jong Un in July sacked or demoted some senior officials for their "irresponsible" handling of his flagship Samjiyon project.</p>

<p>Another travel agency, KTG Tours, also announced that tourists would be able to go to Samjiyon from this winter.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/mnt7e4vo_kim-jong-un-_625x300_14_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[However, North Korea has not been fully open to international tourists since 2020.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-airstrikes-target-gaza-ahead-of-ceasefire-talks-6336678]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israeli Airstrikes Target Gaza Ahead Of Ceasefire Talks]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-airstrikes-target-gaza-ahead-of-ceasefire-talks-6336678]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 14 Aug 2024 17:44:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli air strikes targeted Gaza on Wednesday ahead of ceasefire talks that the United States hopes will stop Iran striking Israel in retaliation for the killing of a Hamas leader.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli air strikes targeted Gaza on Wednesday ahead of ceasefire talks that the United States hopes will stop Iran striking Israel in retaliation for the killing of a Hamas leader.</p>

<p>Iran and its allies blamed Israel for the July 31 killing of Hamas political leader Ismail Haniyeh in Tehran during a visit for the inauguration of President Masoud Pezeshkian. Israel has not commented.</p>

<p>The West has urged Iran to stand down its threat to avenge his death, which came hours after an Israeli strike in Beirut killed a senior commander of Hezbollah, the powerful Iran-backed rebel group in Lebanon.</p>

<p>The escalation has raised fears of a wider conflict after more than 10 months of war in Gaza, which has claimed nearly 40,000 lives, according to the health ministry in the Hamas-run Palestinian territory.</p>

<p>So far, there has been only one, week-long truce in the Gaza fighting, in November, when dozens of hostages in Gaza were released in exchange for Palestinian prisoners held in Israeli jails.</p>

<p>Ahead of Thursday's ceasefire talks, a Hamas official said the Islamist movement was "continuing its consultations with the mediators".</p>

<p>"Hamas really wants an end to the war and a ceasefire agreement on the basis of the (Biden) plan," another Hamas official said, referring to a proposal US President Joe Biden laid out on May 31.</p>

<p>The office of Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu on Tuesday detailed its conditions for a truce, including "a veto on certain prisoners" being released from its jails.</p>

<p>Biden said on Tuesday that a Gaza ceasefire deal could deter Iran from attacking Israel.</p>

<p>Asked if a truce between Israel and Hamas could stave off an Iranian assault, Biden said: "That's my expectation". He added that while negotiations were "getting hard", he was "not giving up".</p>

<p>His envoy for the conflict, Amos Hochstein, was in Beirut on Wednesday where he warned the clock was ticking for a Gaza ceasefire.</p>

<p>"There is no more time to waste and there's no more valid excuses from any party for any further delay," he said after talks with Lebanon's parliament speaker Nabih Berri.</p>

<p>Iran has rejected Western calls for restraint, with foreign ministry spokesman Nasser Kanani saying the demand "brazenly asks Iran to take no deterrent action against a regime which has violated its sovereignty and territorial integrity".</p>

<h3><strong>Israel on 'high alert'</strong></h3>

<p>Israeli President Isacc Herzog said on social media platform X that the country remained on "high alert".</p>

<p>"I want to express my appreciation and thanks to our allies standing united with us in the face of the hate-filled threats of the Iranian regime and its terrorist proxies," he said.</p>

<p>The escalation has prompted Western governments to issue advisories against travel to Lebanon as well as prepare contingency plans to evacuate their nationals from the region if full-scale war breaks out.</p>

<p>A ferry seen off Limassol, Cyprus was on standby to provide assistance "in the event of an evacuation of the conflict zone", a spokesperson for its charterer said.</p>

<p>Fearing an attack by Iran and Hezbollah, the Tel Aviv Museum of Art said it had stashed away its most valuable pieces, including paintings by Pablo Picasso and Gustav Klimt.</p>

<p>"In the last three, four, five days, when this new threat from Hezbollah and from Iran came on the table again, we understood that we needed to take other precautions," said museum director Tania Coen-Uzzielli.</p>

<p>The Biden administration approved more than $20 billion in new weapons sales to Israel on Tuesday, including 50 F-15 fighter jets.</p>

<p>The United States has deployed an aircraft carrier strike group and a guided missile submarine to the region in support of Israel.</p>

<h3><strong>Gaza death count nears 40,000</strong></h3>

<p>The Gaza war began with Hamas's October 7 attack on southern Israel which resulted in the deaths of 1,198 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally of Israeli official figures.</p>

<p>Hamas also seized 251 people, 111 of whom are still held captive in Gaza, including 39 the military says are dead.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory military offensive in Gaza has killed at least 39,965 people, according to the latest count from the territory's health ministry, which does not provide a breakdown of civilian and Hamas deaths.</p>

<p>In the latest violence, the Israeli military said it carried out dozens of air strikes across the Gaza Strip.</p>

<p>It said its troops were "continuing precise, intelligence-based operational activity in the area of Tel al-Sultan" in the southern city of Rafah.</p>

<p>In the past 24 hours, the army said it had "struck over 40" sites across Gaza, including structures from which Hamas fired anti-tank missiles.</p>

<p>The Gaza civil defence agency said its emergency teams pulled the bodies of four people from the same family from the rubble of a bombed apartment in the Qatari-built residential complex of Hamad, near Khan Yunis.</p>

<p>Residents of central Gaza's Nuseirat refugee camp said it was struck by a missile after midnight.</p>

<p>"We were sleeping... and were surprised by a missile targeting the neighbours, children, their father and mother," Jihad al-Sharif told AFPTV.</p>

<p>"The explosion was terrible," he said, adding his family emerged to find the remains of children in the middle of the street.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/d48qn25o_israel-gaza-war_625x300_14_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Gaza war began with Hamas's October 7 attack on southern Israel]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-navys-newest-air-to-air-missile-could-tilt-balance-in-south-china-sea-6336606]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Navy's Newest Air-To-Air Missile Could Tilt Balance In South China Sea]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-navys-newest-air-to-air-missile-could-tilt-balance-in-south-china-sea-6336606]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 14 Aug 2024 17:36:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The U.S. Navy's deployment of new extremely long-range air-to-air missiles in the Indo-Pacific could erase China's advantage in aerial reach, experts say, part of an intensifying focus on projecting power amid high tensions in the region.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The U.S. Navy's deployment of new extremely long-range air-to-air missiles in the Indo-Pacific could erase China's advantage in aerial reach, experts say, part of an intensifying focus on projecting power amid high tensions in the region.</p>

<p>The AIM-174B, developed from the readily available Raytheon SM-6 air defence missile, is the longest-range such missile the United States has ever fielded and was officially acknowledged in July.</p>

<p>It has three key advantages: it can fly several times farther than the next-best U.S. option, the AIM-120 AMRAAM; it does not require new production lines; and it is compatible with the aircraft of at least one ally, Australia.</p>

<p>Crucially, a weapon such as the AIM-174B, which can attack aerial targets as far away as 400 km (250 miles), outranges China's PL-15 missile, allowing U.S. jets to keep threats farther from aircraft carriers, and safely strike "high-value" Chinese targets, such as command-and-control planes.</p>

<p>"The United States can ensure the safety of their important assets, such as carrier groups, and launch long-range strikes on PLA targets," said Chieh Chung, a researcher at a Taipei-based thinktank, the Association of Strategic Foresight, using an abbreviation for the People's Liberation Army.</p>

<p>The West has not easily been able to do that until now.</p>

<p>The AIM-120, the standard long-range missile for U.S. aircraft, has a maximum range of about 150 km (93 miles), which requires the launching aircraft to fly deeper into contested territory, exposing aircraft carriers to greater danger of anti-ship attacks.</p>

<p>Any type of South China Sea conflict, within the so-called First Island Chain, which runs roughly from Indonesia northeast to the Japanese mainland, means the U.S. Navy would operate within a few hundred kilometres of its Chinese adversary.</p>

<p>Supporting Taiwan in an invasion would pull the Navy in even closer.</p>

<p>The AIM-174B changes that equation, keeping PLA carrier-hunting aircraft out of firing range and even endangering their planes attacking Taiwan, Cheih said. That increased the likelihood the United States would get involved in a major conflict in the region, he added.</p>

<p>"The big thing is that it lets the United States push in a little bit further" into the South China Sea during a conflict, said a senior U.S. defence technical analyst, who declined to be identified because the matter is a sensitive one.</p>

<p>"And it's going to potentially change Chinese behaviour because it's going to hold large, slow, unmanoeuvrable aircraft at greater risk."</p>

<p><strong>RANGE ADVANTAGE</strong></p>

<p>For decades, the United States' advantage in stealth fighters, first with the F-117 and then with the F-22 and F-35, meant that missiles such as the AIM-120 were all that was needed.</p>

<p>The U.S. military also leaned into developing the AMRAAM as a cheaper alternative to a new missile, drastically improving its performance over decades, said Justin Bronk, an airpower and technology expert at London's Royal United Services Institute.</p>

<p>The SM-6 is estimated to cost about $4 million each, says the Missile Defense Advocacy Alliance, while an AMRAAM costs about $1 million.</p>

<p>European nations, which lacked access to stealth technology until recent years, developed the ramjet-powered Meteor missile, with a range of 200 km (124 miles), produced by MBDA.</p>

<p>MBDA did not respond to a request for comment.</p>

<p>The advent of Chinese stealth aircraft such as the J-20, and more important, the PL-15 missile it can carry internally - with a range of 250 km (155 miles) or more - eroded the U.S. edge, said Kelly Grieco, a senior fellow at the Stimson Center.</p>

<p>Now a stealthy Chinese aircraft could theoretically spot non-stealthy U.S. aircraft and shoot them down well outside the range where they could even fight back, she said.</p>

<p>Even U.S. stealth aircraft might be forced to fly dangerously close to fire their missiles.</p>

<p>"If a Chinese fighter can outrange an American fighter, it means they can get the first shot," she said. "It's hard to outrun something that's travelling at Mach 4."</p>

<p>The AIM-174B was developed to quickly address that need.</p>

<p>The secretive Lockheed Martin AIM-260, a separate U.S. Air Force program to develop an extremely long-range air-to-air missile small enough for stealth aircraft to carry internally, has been in development for at least seven years.</p>

<p>Lockheed Martin declined to comment on the project.</p>

<p>China is developing missiles with longer range than the PL-15, Bronk said, but the radar of launching aircraft may be unable to spot targets at such distances.</p>

<p>"If you go too big and too heavy with the missiles, you end up trading off fuel" for the aircraft, he added.</p>

<p><strong>AVAILABILITY</strong></p>

<p>Using Raytheon's SM-6, originally designed for a ship-launched air defence role, means production lines are already available. Funding has already been earmarked for more than 100 SM-6 missiles a year.</p>

<p>Raytheon declined to comment on how many AIM-174Bs would be produced or if existing SM-6s would be converted.</p>

<p>So far it has only been shown on U.S. Navy F/A-18E/F Super Hornet aircraft, which are operated by the U.S. and Australian militaries.</p>

<p>The United States sees Australia as a crucial ally and location for projecting power into the South China Sea, and is investing hundreds of millions of dollars in military infrastructure there.</p>

<p>Australia's defence ministry said it "works closely with the U.S. to understand capability options available for Australian consideration".</p>

<p>The U.S. Defense Department referred questions about the AIM-174B to the U.S. Navy.</p>

<p>The Navy said the missile was "operationally deployed" but declined to comment on whether it would be supplied to allies, whether it would be integrated onto other aircraft, and how many AIM-174Bs it wanted each year.</p>

<p>The versatility of the SM-6, which has also been used to hit ships, land targets and missiles, opens up possibilities beyond the AIM-174B, said Peter Layton, a defence and aviation expert at the Griffith Asia Institute.</p>

<p>For instance, if fitted with an anti-radar seeker, it could attack and disrupt surface-to-air missile batteries from extremely long range.</p>

<p>For now, though, adding the AIM-174B to the U.S. Navy's arsenal, even if not yet in large numbers, changes the calculus of a regional conflict, the senior technical analyst said.</p>

<p>"If this is enough to push (China's high-value) aircraft way back, then you don't need many," the analyst added.</p>

<p>"Because the threat has caused the adversary to change their behaviour ... It makes a South China Sea scenario easier."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/jrahrc9o_aim174b-missile_625x300_14_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[An F-18 Hornet fighter jet with an AIM-174B long-range missile.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukrainian-troops-moving-further-in-russias-kursk-says-zelensky-6336396]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ukrainian Troops Moving Further In Russia's Kursk, Says Zelensky]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukrainian-troops-moving-further-in-russias-kursk-says-zelensky-6336396]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 14 Aug 2024 17:10:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[President Volodymyr Zelensky on Wednesday said Ukraine's army was advancing in the Russian region of Kursk where it launched a surprise offensive last week.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>President Volodymyr Zelensky on Wednesday said Ukraine's army was advancing in the Russian region of Kursk where it launched a surprise offensive last week.</p>

<p>"In the Kursk region, we are moving further. From one to two kilometres in different areas since the beginning of the day. And more than 100 more captured Russian servicemen over the same period... This will speed up the return home of our boys and girls," Zelensky said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/qcc3qau8_zelensky-reuters_625x300_11_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/24-year-old-us-man-arrested-for-giving-4-month-old-baby-gasoline-to-drink-6336388]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[24-Year-Old US Man Arrested For Giving 4-Month-Old Baby Gasoline To Drink]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/24-year-old-us-man-arrested-for-giving-4-month-old-baby-gasoline-to-drink-6336388]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 14 Aug 2024 17:09:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 24-year-old man in the United States has been charged with attempted capital murder after he allegedly tried to kill his 4-month-old baby by feeding the infant gasoline.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 24-year-old man in the United States has been charged with attempted capital murder after he tried to kill his 4-month-old baby by feeding the infant gasoline. According to <em>Newsweek</em>, Edgar James Bridgemon of Texas confessed to administering the poison, intending to end the child's life. He was arrested on Saturday for attempted capital murder and later processed and jailed. In addition to the attempted murder charge, he has also been charged with evading arrest, cops said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>After responding to a distressing emergency call, cops learned that the baby was allegedly given a gasoline drink by Bridgemon. While officers assessed the situation, the 24-year-old attempted to flee on foot. But after a brief chase, cops arrested Bridgemon and took into custody, where he later confessed to the crime.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.newsweek.com/texas-father-charged-after-giving-baby-gasoline-drink-1938613"><em>Newsweek</em></a>, the 24-year-old admitted that he had given the baby gasoline with the deliberate intention of ending the child's life.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The 4-month-old, on the other hand, was immediately rushed to Paris Regional Medical Center, where medical staff began initial treatment. However, due to the severity of the poisoning, the child was later transferred to a different hospital in the Dallas-Fort Worth area for more advanced care.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Bridgemon now faces charges including attempted capital murder, which is classified as a first-degree felony in Texas. If convicted, the 24-year-old could face a life sentence.</p>

<p>Additionally, Bridgemon has also been charged with evading arrest, further complicating his legal situation. He is currently being held at the Lamar County Jail with a bond set at $255,000. The case is still under investigation by local authorities.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/feature/chinas-most-handsome-shaolin-monk-dies-in-car-accident-at-21-6334946">China's ''Most Handsome'' Shaolin Monk Dies In Car Accident At 21</a></strong></p>

<p>Meanwhile, in another incident, a mother was recently arrested for allegedly throwing her newborn baby into a trash bag and dumping it in a dumpster. Everilda Cux-Ajtzalam reportedly told police she did this because she feared her boyfriend would break up with her if she didn't. Court records reviewed by Law&amp;Crime show that she was taken into custody on Thursday and charged with felony abandoning a child without the intent to return.</p>

<p>Medics from the Houston Fire Department transported the baby to Texas Children's Hospital, where authorities reported that the child was stable and in good condition. After receiving treatment, the baby was placed in the custody of Child Protective Services.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-11/3eb3kf1_us-police-generic_625x300_14_November_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[If convicted, the 24-year-old could face a life sentence. (Representative pic)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/taliban-three-years-on-still-searching-for-manna-6336026]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: Opinion | Taliban, Three Years On: Still Searching for Manna]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/taliban-three-years-on-still-searching-for-manna-6336026]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 14 Aug 2024 16:25:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[On August 15, 2021, the Taliban swiftly took over Kabul following the withdrawal of the US-led International Security Assistance Force (ISAF), marking a significant diplomatic setback for India.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On August 15, 2021, the Taliban swiftly took over Kabul following the withdrawal of the US-led International Security Assistance Force (ISAF), marking a significant diplomatic setback for India. The Taliban were believed to have support from the Tehreek-e-Taliban-e-Pakistan (TTP) operating around the Durand Line, as well as from moderates in Doha.</p>

<p>Amidst the ensuing chaos, India was forced to shut down its embassy in Kabul, evacuating diplomats and citizens. New Delhi had invested heavily in Afghanistan, but the future seemed uncertain under the shadow of conflict. As of August 2020, there were approximately 1,710 Indians in Afghanistan, working in sectors such as banking, IT, construction, healthcare, NGOs, telecom, security, and education, as well as with Afghan and UN missions.</p>

<p><strong>Aid to Afghanistan</strong></p>

<p>The Taliban's return and the subsequent withdrawal of international forces led many countries, including India, to pull out. However, the Taliban leadership soon realized that running a government required more than just military might-it needed external funds and assistance. New Delhi has cautiously responded to Kabul's appeals for aid. Important delegations visited Afghanistan, and a technical mission was established in June 2022 to better understand and coordinate humanitarian efforts.</p>

<p>Since 2001, India has committed over USD 3 billion to development and reconstruction projects in Afghanistan. Bilateral trade between India and Afghanistan was valued at USD 1.5 billion in 2019-20. India has supported projects such as a new Parliament building in Kabul and two major river dams. More than 500 projects span across 34 Afghan provinces, addressing critical areas such as power, water supply, road connectivity, healthcare, education, agriculture, and capacity building.</p>

<p>Various bilateral and multilateral meetings have taken place, and the Union Budget for 2024-25 allocated Rs. 200 crores to Afghanistan. This represents a decrease from Rs. 350 crores in the 2021-22 budget.</p>

<p>The Taliban have urged India to resume development projects, arguing that such initiatives would create job opportunities, alleviate poverty, and support development.</p>

<p><strong>The China Factor</strong></p>

<p>India's outreach to Afghanistan is influenced by the regional dynamics, including China's growing activity. Initially excluded from China's expansive Belt and Road Initiative (BRI) in Asia, Afghanistan has seen increased Chinese involvement and funding. A Parliamentary Committee on External Affairs report from last year noted the strategic importance for India to deepen ties with its smaller neighbours in response to China's BRI and America's Indo-Pacific vision.</p>

<p>China is courting the Taliban to counter the Uyghur separatist movement. Beijing wants the Taliban to address the Eastern Turkestan Islamic Movement, which, according to a 2021 UN report, is active in Badakhshan, Faryab, Kabul, and Nuristan provinces. The report indicated that the group seeks to establish a Uyghur state in Xinjiang, China, and facilitates the movement of fighters from Afghanistan to China.</p>

<p>Despite its efforts, Beijing's support for Afghanistan has not met all expectations. China has provided funds, machinery, and technical support, but not as generously as Afghanistan hoped. The country's economic growth was recorded at -6.2% in 2022, according to Afghanistan's National Statistics and Information Authority (NSIA).</p>

<p><strong>Pakistan No Longer a Friend</strong></p>

<p>Pakistan has long served as a training ground and launchpad for the Mujahideen in their struggle against Soviet forces. Reportedly supported by the CIA, Peshawar in Pakistan quickly became a crucial hub for the fighters. This is well-documented in The Bear Trap by Brigadier Mohammed Yousuf and Mark Adkin. Yousuf, who led Pakistan's Inter-Services Intelligence (ISI) Afghan desk from 1983 to 1987, and Adkin, a major in the British Army, detail the logistical and military support Pakistan received from the CIA during the Soviet occupation of Afghanistan.</p>

<p>Beyond the USA and the former USSR, several other countries have played strategic games in Afghanistan due to its geopolitical significance. This has resulted in the division of its people along ethnic and cultural lines to serve the interests of these external powers. Peter Hopkirk chronicles this history in The Great Game, a term coined by British intelligence officer Captain Arthur Conolly during the British occupation of the country in the 19th century.</p>

<p>Despite their ethnic differences, Afghans have resisted aggressors for centuries. During the Soviet era, Pashtuns from the south and Tajiks and Uzbeks from the north employed guerrilla tactics, striking and retreating across the country's rugged terrain.</p>

<p>A paper by Amna Puri-Mirza, a researcher specializing in the Middle East, published in September 2022, reveals that as of 2020, Afghanistan's population of approximately 33 million was composed of 42% Pashtuns, 27% Tajiks, and 9% Hazaras. The CIA World Factbook estimates that in 2020, Afghan Persian (Dari) and Pashto were spoken by 77% and 48% of the population, respectively.</p>

<p>The Durand Line, established in November 1893 as the official boundary between undivided India and Afghanistan, remains contentious. Afghanistan has never accepted this boundary, seeking its shift eastward to incorporate Pashtun-majority areas in Pakistan. This disagreement has led to intermittent conflicts.</p>

<p>Relations between Islamabad and Kabul have deteriorated as Pakistan has increased its pressure on Afghanistan for harbouring "Pakistani Taliban" and for alleged strikes on Pakistani soil. Frequent gunfights have led to the closure of the border, causing significant disruptions for Afghan traders. Key border crossings like Torkham and Spin Boldak have been particularly affected, with long queues of stranded vehicles.</p>

<p>India has faced setbacks in its involvement in Afghanistan over the past three decades. In the ongoing great game, countries like China, Russia, and Iran are influential in shaping Afghanistan's future, and India must navigate these shifting alliances carefully.</p>

<p><em>(Jayanta Bhattacharya is a senior journalist writing on polls and politics, conflict, farmer and human interest issues)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/a09f28p_taliban-anniversary-celebration_625x300_14_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-extends-petrol-exports-ban-until-2025-to-maintain-stable-situation-6336012]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russia Extends Petrol Exports Ban Until 2025 To "Maintain Stable Situation"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-extends-petrol-exports-ban-until-2025-to-maintain-stable-situation-6336012]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 14 Aug 2024 16:23:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Russian government announced Wednesday that it was reintroducing a ban on petrol exports for another six months to "maintain a stable situation" on the domestic fuel market after major price hikes.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Russian government announced Wednesday that it was reintroducing a ban on petrol exports for another six months to "maintain a stable situation" on the domestic fuel market after major price hikes.</p>

<p>The government said in a statement that it has "brought in a restriction on exports of petrol from September 1 to December 31, 2024".</p>

<p>The measure is intended to keep prices stable "during a period of continued seasonal demand and planned repairs on oil refineries", the government said.</p>

<p>Russia in March introduced a six-month ban on petrol exports, but then suspended it temporarily between May and July, saying the domestic market was saturated.</p>

<p>The new restriction will not affect deliveries carried out under intergovernmental agreements including those with the Eurasian Economic Union member countries -- Belarus, Kazakhstan, Kyrgyzstan and Armenia -- the government said.</p>

<p>Despite its massive energy reserves, Russia announced a similar export ban on diesel and petrol last year as pump prices hit Russians' purchasing power, already affected by weakening of the ruble due to sanctions.</p>

<p>In 2023, Russia produced 43.9 million tonnes of petrol, according to official figures.</p>

<p>Revenues from oil and gas sales remain essential to Moscow as it gears its economy towards efforts to sustain the military offensive in Ukraine.</p>

<p>In recent months, Ukrainian forces have targeted fuel depots with drone attacks, cutting off vital resources for Russia's forces.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/kog4sr3g_petrol-export_625x300_14_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[In 2023, Russia produced 43.9 million tonnes of petrol, according to official figures. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ousted-thai-pm-srettha-thavisin-says-he-respects-court-decision-6335882]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ousted Thai PM Srettha Thavisin Says He "Respects" Court Decision]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ousted-thai-pm-srettha-thavisin-says-he-respects-court-decision-6335882]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 14 Aug 2024 16:03:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ousted Thai prime minister Srettha Thavisin said Wednesday that he respected a court ruling that removed him from office in an ethics case.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ousted Thai prime minister Srettha Thavisin said Wednesday that he respected a court ruling that removed him from office in an ethics case.</p>

<p>"I respect the verdict. I reiterate that for the almost one year I have been in this role, I have tried with good intentions to lead the country with honesty," Srettha told reporters outside his office after the Constitutional Court ruling.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/465cpv78_srettha-thavisin-afp-_625x300_14_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Prime Minister Srettha Thavisin has been removed from office on Wednesday (file).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>