<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Sat, 23 Nov 2024 00:43:25 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-secretly-placing-hackers-to-cripple-critical-us-infrastructure-top-cyber-official-7082738]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[China Secretly Placing Hackers To Cripple Critical US Infra: Top Official]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-secretly-placing-hackers-to-cripple-critical-us-infrastructure-top-cyber-official-7082738]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 23 Nov 2024 00:05:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Chinese hackers are positioning themselves in US critical infrastructure in the event of a clash with the United States, a top American cybersecurity official said on Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Chinese hackers are positioning themselves in US critical infrastructure in the event of a clash with the United States, a top American cybersecurity official said on Friday.</p>

<p>Morgan Adamski, the executive director of US Cyber Command, said ongoing Chinese-linked cyber operations are aimed at gaining "an advantage in the event of a major crisis or conflict with the US"</p>

<p>Adamski made the comments to researchers at the Cyberwarcon security conference in Arlington, Virginia. On Thursday, US Senator Mark Warner told the Washington Post that a suspected China-linked hack on US telecommunications firms was "the worst telecom hack in our nation's history - by far."</p>

<p>That cyberespionage operation, dubbed "Salt Typhoon," has included stolen call records data, the compromise of communications of top officials of both major US presidential campaigns before the Nov. 5 election, and telecommunications information related to US law enforcement requests, the FBI said in a recent statement.</p>

<p>Beijing routinely denies cyber operations targeting US entities. The Chinese Embassy in Washington did not immediately respond to a request for comment.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/0un17f6g_chinese-hackers-generic-china-hacking-generic-istock_625x300_23_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Chinese hackers have begun preparing for conflict, claims a top US cyber official. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/satellite-imagery-exposes-russia-smuggling-illicit-oil-to-north-korea-7082733]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Satellite Imagery Exposes Russia Smuggling Illicit Oil To North Korea]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/satellite-imagery-exposes-russia-smuggling-illicit-oil-to-north-korea-7082733]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 23 Nov 2024 00:02:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Despite international efforts to sanction North Korea for developing weapons of mass destruction, the country continues to receive illicit supplies of refined petroleum products. These products are crucial for manufacturing weapons.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Despite international efforts to sanction North Korea for developing weapons of mass destruction, the country continues to receive illicit supplies of refined petroleum products. These products are crucial for manufacturing weapons.</p>

<p>A recent analysis using <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.planet.com/pulse/planets-data-used-to-reveal-illicit-shipping-networks-delivering-fuel-to-north-korea-in-violation-of-un-sanctions/" rel="noindex,nofollow">Planet's</a> satellite tasking system has revealed North Korea's involvement in an organized criminal network to obtain fuel in violation of international sanctions. The network relies on a complex and convoluted shipping system.</p>

<p>At the center of this operation is the tanker "Diamond 8." Satellite imagery shows how fuel is transferred from one ship to another, eventually arriving in North Korean ports. This secretive supply chain allows North Korea to bypass international sanctions and continue developing its weapons program.</p>

<p>"It's a constant game of cat and mouse and they are always trying to stay ahead. You cannot see what they are doing without satellite data," Lauren Sung, an analyst at The Center for Advanced Defense Studies said.</p>

<p>According to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cjr4pr0gyyzo" rel="noindex,nofollow">BBC</a>, it is estimated that Russia has been supplying more than a million barrels of oil to North Korea, as a payment for the troops they have received from them for the war in Ukraine.</p>

<p>North Korea is the only country that cannot buy oil on the open market and the number of barrels it can receive is capped at 500,000 by the UN.</p>

<p>It is against UN sanctions to transfer or sell oil to North Korea except in small quantities, in order to make sure they do not develop nuclear weapons and the satellite images clearly show violation of the sanctions. Moreover, there are pictures to support the same, where it is visible that the tankers arrive empty and leave full.</p>

<p>"While Kim Jong Un is providing Vladimir Putin with a lifeline to continue his war, Russia is quietly providing North Korea with a lifeline of its own," Joe Byrne from the Open Source Centre, said.</p>

<p>UK Foreign Secretary David Lammy has told the BBC that, "To keep fighting in Ukraine, Russia has become increasingly reliant on North Korea for troops and weapons in exchange for oil."</p>

<p>Since March, North Korea has received more oil from Russia than double the annual cap.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Dr Go Myong-hyun, a senior research fellow at South Korea's Institute for National Security Strategy, said, "If you're sending your people to die in a foreign war, a million barrels of oil is just not sufficient reward."</p>

<p>Shin Won-sik, Seoul's top security advisor, has said that Russia seems to have helped North Korea with financial and technological support for its space programme.</p>

<p>However, the real concern is what else can be traded between the two countries, since Kim Jong Un has stepped up his support for Russia's war.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/r8d53hbg_vladimir-putin-kim-jong-un-reuters_625x300_22_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Russia has been supplying more than a million barrels of oil to North Korea]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-attended-31-bilateral-meetings-during-his-5-days-of-3-country-tour-7082728]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[PM Attended 31 Bilateral Meetings During His 5 Days Of 3-Country Tour]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-attended-31-bilateral-meetings-during-his-5-days-of-3-country-tour-7082728]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 23 Nov 2024 00:02:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Narendra Modi participated in 31 bilateral meetings and informal interactions with world leaders during his five days of three-country tour, officials said on Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi participated in 31 bilateral meetings and informal interactions with world leaders during his five days of three-country tour, officials said on Friday.</p>

<p>The whirlwind diplomatic engagements included a bilateral meeting with the Nigerian president in Nigeria, 10 bilateral meetings on the sidelines of the G20 Summit in Brazil and nine during Modi's visit to Guyana.</p>

<p>In Brazil, Prime Minister Modi held bilateral meetings with the leaders of the country, besides those of Indonesia, Portugal, Italy, Norway, France, the UK, Chile, Argentina and Australia. These were marked by his maiden bilateral meetings with Indonesian leader Prabowo Subianto, Portugal's Luis Montenegro, the UK's Keir Starmer, Chile's Gabriel Boric, and Argentina's Javier Milei, the officials noted.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Modi also had informal interactions and pull-aside meetings in Brazil with the leaders of Singapore, South Korea, Egypt, the USA and Spain and with the heads and executives of various international organisations like Ursula von der Leyen of the European Union; Antonio Guterres of the United Nations; Ngozi Okonjo-Iweala of the World Trade Organization; Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus of the World Health Organization; and Kristalina Georgieva and Gita Gopinath of the IMF.</p>

<p>In Guyana, the officials said, Prime Minister Modi held bilateral meetings with the leaders of Guyana, Dominica, Bahamas, Trinidad &amp; Tobago, Suriname, Barbados, Antigua &amp; Barbuda, Grenada and St Lucia.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/4gpc48eo_pm-modi_625x300_21_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Prime Minister Modi also had informal interactions and pull-aside meetings in Brazil.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russian-missiles-peak-speed-was-over-13-000-kph-says-ukraine-7082725]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russian Missile's Peak Speed Was Over 13,000 Kph, Says Ukraine]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russian-missiles-peak-speed-was-over-13-000-kph-says-ukraine-7082725]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 23 Nov 2024 00:02:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Russian missile that struck the Ukrainian city of Dnipro on Thursday reached a top speed of more than 13,000 kph (8,000 mph) and took about 15 minutes to reach its target from its launch, Ukraine said on Friday in its first public assessment.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Russian missile that struck the Ukrainian city of Dnipro on Thursday reached a top speed of more than 13,000 kph (8,000 mph) and took about 15 minutes to reach its target from its launch, Ukraine said on Friday in its first public assessment of the new weapon.</p>

<p>Russian President Vladimir Putin said Moscow struck a Ukrainian military facility with a new intermediate-range, hypersonic ballistic missile known as "Oreshnik" as a warning to the West against supporting Ukraine's war effort.</p>

<p>The attack took place with fighting in the war nearing the three-year mark and Ukraine firing longer-range missiles supplied by its Western allies at targets inside Russia.</p>

<p>"The flight time of this Russian missile from the moment of its launch in the Astrakhan region to its impact in the city of Dnipro was 15 minutes," the military's Main Directorate of Intelligence (HUR) said in a statement.</p>

<p>"The missile was equipped with six warheads: each equipped with six submunitions. The speed at the final part of the trajectory was over Mach 11."</p>

<p>Mach is a measurement of supersonic speed. Mach 11 equals about 13,600 kph.</p>

<p>HUR added that the weapon was likely to be from the Kedr missile complex, which deputy head Vadym Skibitsky told Ukrainian media is related to the Oreshnik system and was first tested in June 2021.</p>

<p>Skibitsky said Russia could have at least 10 more such missiles to test before they enter mass production, news agency Ukrinform reported.</p>

<p>Kyiv initially suggested Russia had fired an intercontinental ballistic missile, but US officials and NATO echoed Putin's description of the weapon as an intermediate-range ballistic missile.</p>

<p>Ukraine's foreign ministry on Thursday urged the international community to react swiftly to the strike.</p>

<p>NATO will hold an emergency meeting with Ukraine at the alliance's headquarters in Brussels on Tuesday to discuss Moscow's strike, a NATO source said on Friday.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/0ftmou98_russia-missile-attack_625x300_22_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Russia's attack took place as war with Ukraine nears the three-year mark (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-supreme-court-tosses-case-involving-securities-fraud-suit-against-facebook-7082638]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Court Tosses Case Involving Securities Fraud Suit Against Facebook]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-supreme-court-tosses-case-involving-securities-fraud-suit-against-facebook-7082638]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 22 Nov 2024 23:48:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The US Supreme Court sidestepped on Friday a decision on whether to allow shareholders to proceed with a securities fraud lawsuit accusing Meta's Facebook of misleading investors about the misuse of the social media platform's user data.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The US Supreme Court sidestepped on Friday a decision on whether to allow shareholders to proceed with a securities fraud lawsuit accusing Meta's Facebook of misleading investors about the misuse of the social media platform's user data.</p>

<p>The justices, who heard arguments in the case on Nov. 6, dismissed Facebook's appeal of a lower court's ruling that allowed a 2018 class action led by Amalgamated Bank to proceed. The Supreme Court opted not to resolve the underlying legal dispute, determining that the case should not have been taken up. Its action leaves the lower court's decision in place.</p>

<p>The court's dismissal came in a one-line order that provided no explanation.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Facebook dispute was one of two cases to come before the Supreme Court this month involving the right of private litigants to hold companies to account for alleged securities fraud. The other one, involving the artificial intelligence chipmaker Nvidia, was argued on Nov. 13. The Supreme Court has not ruled yet in the Nvidia case.</p>

<p>The complainants in the Facebook case claimed the company unlawfully withheld information from investors about a 2015 data breach involving British political consulting firm Cambridge Analytica that affected more than 30 million Facebook users. They accused Facebook of misleading investors in violation of the Securities Exchange Act, a 1934 federal law that requires publicly traded companies to disclose their business risks.</p>

<p>Facebook's stock fell following 2018 media reports that Cambridge Analytica had used improperly harvested Facebook user data in connection with Donald Trump's successful US presidential campaign in 2016. The investors have sought unspecified monetary damages in part to recoup the lost value of the Facebook stock they held.</p>

<p>At issue was whether Facebook broke the law when it failed to detail the prior data breach in subsequent business-risk disclosures, and instead portrayed the risk of such incidents as purely hypothetical.</p>

<p>Facebook spokesperson Andy Stone expressed disappointment "in the Supreme Court's decision not to clarify this part of the law."</p>

<p>"The plaintiff's claims are baseless and we will continue to defend ourselves as this case is considered by the district court," Stone said.</p>

<p>Facebook argued that it was not required to reveal that its warned-of risk had already materialized because "a reasonable investor" would understand risk disclosures to be forward-looking statements.</p>

<p>President Joe Biden's administration supported the shareholders in the case.</p>

<p>US District Judge Edward Davila dismissed the lawsuit but the San Francisco-based 9th US Circuit Court of Appeals revived it, prompting Facebook's appeal to the Supreme Court.</p>

<p>George Washington University law professor Alan Morrison said that following the Supreme Court's dismissal of Facebook's appeal, the complainants would be expected to seek discovery, a process that involves the exchange of information among parties in a case. Morrison added that Facebook "might renew their motion to dismiss under a somewhat different standard - partially for purposes of delay."</p>

<p>The Cambridge Analytica data breach prompted US government investigations into Facebook's privacy practices, various lawsuits and a US congressional hearing. The US Securities and Exchange Commission in 2019 brought an enforcement action against Facebook over the matter, which the company settled for $100 million. Facebook paid a separate $5 billion penalty to the US Federal Trade Commission over the issue.</p>

<p>The Supreme Court in prior rulings has limited the authority of the Securities and Exchange Commission, the federal agency that polices securities fraud.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/kr963hso_facebook-generic_625x300_22_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The court's dismissal came in a one-line order that provided no explanation. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hospitals-have-only-2-days-worth-of-fuel-left-says-gaza-health-ministry-7082578]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hospitals Have Only 2 Days Worth Of Fuel Left, Says Gaza Health Ministry]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hospitals-have-only-2-days-worth-of-fuel-left-says-gaza-health-ministry-7082578]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 22 Nov 2024 23:36:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The health ministry in Hamas-run Gaza said Friday that hospitals have only two days' fuel left before they must restrict services, after the UN warned aid delivery to the war-devastated territory is being crippled.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The health ministry in Hamas-run Gaza said Friday that hospitals have only two days' fuel left before they must restrict services, after the UN warned aid delivery to the war-devastated territory is being crippled.</p>

<p>The alarm came a day after the International Criminal Court issued arrest warrants for Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu and former defence minister Yoav Gallant more than a year into the Gaza war between Israel and Hamas militants.</p>

<p>The United Nations and others have repeatedly decried humanitarian conditions, particularly in northern Gaza where Israeli security services said Friday they had killed two commanders involved in Hamas's October 7, 2023 attack that triggered the war.</p>

<p>Medics in the Palestinian territory said an overnight Israeli raid on Beit Lahia and nearby Jabalia resulted in dozens killed or missing.</p>

<p>"We raise an urgent warning as all hospitals in Gaza Strip will stop working or reduce their services within 48 hours due to the occupation's (Israel's) obstruction of fuel entry," Marwan al-Hams, director of Gaza's field hospitals, said during a press conference.</p>

<p>The World Health Organization had already expressed grave concern Tuesday for hospitals still partly operating in Gaza.</p>

<p>"It's getting harder and harder to get the aid in," WHO spokeswoman Margaret Harris said in Geneva.</p>

<p>Late Thursday, the UN's humanitarian coordinator for the Palestinian territories, Muhannad Hadi, said: "The delivery of critical aid across Gaza, including food, water, fuel and medical supplies, is grinding to a halt."</p>

<p>In a statement, he said that for more than six weeks Israeli authorities "have been banning commercial imports" while "a surge in armed looting" has targeted aid convoys.</p>

<p><strong>'Absurd and false'</strong></p>

<p>Vowing to stop Hamas from regrouping in northern Gaza, Israel on October 6 began its air and ground operation in Jabalia and then expanded it to Beit Lahia.</p>

<p>Gaza's civil defence rescue agency could not immediately give an exact toll after the latest Israeli raid, but the health ministry says Israel's operation in the north has killed thousands.</p>

<p>The UN says more than 100,000 have been displaced from the area, and an official told the Security Council last week that people "are effectively starving".</p>

<p>Issuing the warrants for Netanyahu and Gallant, the Hague-based ICC said there were "reasonable grounds" to believe they bore "criminal responsibility" for the war crime of starvation as a method of warfare, and crimes against humanity including over "the lack of food, water, electricity and fuel, and specific medical supplies".</p>

<p>The unprecedented move drew a furious reaction from Netanyahu, who said in a statement: "Israel rejects with disgust the absurd and false actions and accusations made against it."</p>

<p>Netanyahu also said the judges were "driven by anti-Semitic hatred of Israel".</p>

<p>On Friday he thanked his Hungarian counterpart Viktor Orban for his show of "moral clarity" for inviting him to visit in defiance of the ICC warrant which Orban branded "political".</p>

<p>Hungary currently holds the European Union's rotating presidency.</p>

<p>US President Joe Biden, whose country is Israel's top military supplier, called the warrants against Israeli leaders "outrageous", but other world leaders expressed support for the court.</p>

<p>Irish Prime Minister Simon Harris said Friday Netanyahu would be arrested if he set foot in the country.</p>

<p><strong>Warrant for Hamas chief</strong></p>

<p>The ICC also issued an arrest warrant for Hamas's military chief Mohammed Deif, saying it had grounds to suspect him of war crimes and crimes against humanity over the attacks on Israel that sparked the war, and including "sexual and gender-based violence" against hostages.</p>

<p>Israel said it killed Deif in July, but Hamas has not confirmed his death.</p>

<p>On the day the warrants were issued, a UN representative said an Israeli raid on Syria this week was "likely the deadliest" by Israel on the country so far. On Friday a war monitor said the strikes on Palmyra killed 92 pro-Iran fighters.</p>

<p>Israel again bombed Gaza on Friday.</p>

<p>In Gaza City, just south of Jabalia, one man who said he took his cousins to hospital after a strike urged "the world... to put an end" to the war.</p>

<p>"We've had enough," said Belal, who gave only his first name and said 10 members of his family had been killed.</p>

<p>"I'm the only one left," he said.</p>

<p>At least 44,056 people have been killed in Gaza during more than 13 months of war, most of them civilians, according to figures from Gaza's health ministry which the United Nations considers reliable.</p>

<p>Hamas triggered the war with the deadliest attack in Israeli history, which resulted in the deaths of 1,206 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally of Israeli official figures.</p>

<p>The war expanded to Lebanon in late September when Israel escalated air strikes against Iran-backed Hezbollah and later sent in ground troops to southern Lebanon against the group, after nearly a year of tit-for-tat cross border clashes which Hezbollah said were in support of Hamas.</p>

<p>Lebanon's health ministry says more than 3,580 people have been killed in Lebanon, most of them since late September.</p>

<p>Thousands of UN peacekeepers are based in southern Lebanon. They have reported coming under attack numerous times, blaming both Israel and "non-state" actors.</p>

<p>On Friday, Italian Foreign Minister Antonio Tajani said Hezbollah was probably behind a rocket attack that hit their position and left four Italian peacekeepers lightly hurt.</p>

<p>Israeli air strikes again hit Hezbollah's south Beirut stronghold Friday, as well as south Lebanon, the official National News Agency said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/bbi5h46_gaza-hospital-afp-_625x300_23_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[WHO had already expressed grave concern for hospitals still partly operating in Gaza (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/vladimir-putin-orders-mass-production-of-hypersonic-missiles-for-use-in-ukraine-war-7082577]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Putin Orders Mass Production Of Hypersonic Missiles For Use In Ukraine War]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/vladimir-putin-orders-mass-production-of-hypersonic-missiles-for-use-in-ukraine-war-7082577]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 22 Nov 2024 23:36:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russian President Vladimir Putin said Friday that Moscow would carry out more tests of the hypersonic Oreshnik ballistic missile in "combat conditions," a day after firing one on Ukraine.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russian President Vladimir Putin said Friday that Moscow would carry out more tests of the hypersonic Oreshnik ballistic missile in "combat conditions," a day after firing one on Ukraine.</p>

<p>"We will continue these tests, including in combat conditions, depending on the situation and character of the security threats posted to Russia," Putin said in a televised meeting with military chiefs.</p>

<p>Russia fired the new-generation missile at the Ukrainian city of Dnipro early on Thursday in a major escalation of the weaponry being deployed in the nearly three-year conflict.</p>

<p>The Kremlin boss also ordered the missile, which flies at speeds of Mach 10 -- 10 times the speed of sound -- to be put into serial production (mass production). Russia is developing similar advanced systems, he added.</p>

<p>"We need to begin serial production. The decision... has in effect been taken," Putin said, praising the "particular strength of this weapon and its power.</p>

<p>"The weapon system that was tested yesterday is another faithful guarantee of Russia's territorial integrity and sovereignty," he added.</p>

<p>Putin claimed no other countries in the world had such missile technology. While he conceded other states would soon develop them, he said: "That will be tomorrow, after a year or two. But we have this system now. That's important."</p>

<p>His choreographed meeting with the defence minister and those in charge of developing the missile came at the end of a week that has seen the Ukraine conflict escalate rapidly.</p>

<p>Putin said the firing of the Oreshnik missile was a direct response to Kyiv's forces using US- and UK-supplied missiles on Russian territory for the first time.</p>

<p>In an address to the nation on Thursday, Putin said Russia reserved the right to fire missiles at military facilities in countries whose weapons are being used by Ukraine -- specifically the United States and Britain.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/jnf8l4sk_russia-nuclear-missile-drill-reuters_625x300_29_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-hush-money-criminal-case-sentencing-delayed-indefinitely-7082530]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Hush Money Criminal Case Sentencing Delayed Indefinitely]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-hush-money-criminal-case-sentencing-delayed-indefinitely-7082530]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 22 Nov 2024 23:28:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The judge in Donald Trump's criminal hush money case ordered on Friday that sentencing be delayed indefinitely, a legal win for the President-elect as he prepares to return to the White House.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The judge in Donald Trump's criminal hush money case ordered on Friday that sentencing be delayed indefinitely, a legal win for the President-elect as he prepares to return to the White House.</p>

<p>Trump was convicted of 34 felony counts in May after a jury found he had fraudulently manipulated business records to cover up an alleged sexual encounter with a porn star ahead of the 2016 election.</p>

<p>Prosecutors argued that concealing the alleged tryst was intended to help him win his first run for the White House.</p>

<p>Trump, who had been scheduled to be sentenced on November 26, had fought against any effort to sentence him before his return to the presidency in January.</p>

<p>"It is... ordered that the joint application for a stay of sentencing is granted to the extent that the November 26, 2024 date is adjourned," said judge Juan Merchan in an order.</p>

<p>Trump's legal team have cited a Supreme Court ruling giving presidents sweeping immunity for official acts.</p>

<p>That landmark ruling saw the court, with a 6-3 conservative majority, decide that presidents have sweeping immunity from prosecution for a range of official acts committed while in office.</p>

<p><strong>'Motion to dismiss'</strong></p>

<p>Ahead of the election, Trump's lawyers moved to have the case thrown out in light of the Supreme Court decision, a move which prosecutors have firmly rejected.</p>

<p>On Friday the judge granted Trump leave to seek to have the conviction thrown out, likely meaning several further hearings that could be delayed once Trump is sworn in.</p>

<p>"The defendant's request for leave to file a motion to dismiss... is granted," added Merchan's order.</p>

<p>In a separate 2020 election interference case, Special Counsel Jack Smith moved to vacate deadlines, delaying the case indefinitely -- but not yet dropping it outright.</p>

<p>The move was in line with long-standing Department of Justice policy not to prosecute sitting US presidents.</p>

<p>The Manhattan prosecutor previously acknowledged in correspondence with the court that "these are unprecedented circumstances" and called for the competing interests of the jury's verdict and Trump's election to be balanced.</p>

<p>Trump's former attorney general Bill Barr previously said that both the New York case as well as others around the country had been "plainly brought for political purposes (and) have now been extensively aired and rejected in the court of public opinion."</p>

<p>Trump has repeatedly derided the hush money case as a witch hunt, saying it "should be rightfully terminated."</p>

<p>Alongside the New York case, brought by state-level prosecutors, Trump faces two active federal cases: one related to his effort to overturn the 2020 election and the other connected to classified documents he allegedly mishandled after leaving office.</p>

<p>However, as president, he would be able to intervene to end those cases, and Smith, the special counsel handling both cases, has reportedly begun to wind them down.</p>

<p>A Trump-appointed federal judge already threw out the documents case, but Smith had sought to appeal that decision.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/e59m21a8_donald-trump_625x300_07_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Trump has repeatedly derided the hush money case as a witch hunt (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukraine-returns-residents-of-russian-border-region-in-rare-deal-with-moscow-7082470]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ukraine Returns Residents Of Russian Border Region In Rare Deal With Moscow]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukraine-returns-residents-of-russian-border-region-in-rare-deal-with-moscow-7082470]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 22 Nov 2024 23:16:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Dozens of residents from the Russian border region of Kursk have been returned to Russia from Ukraine following rare and "painstaking" talks between Moscow and Kyiv, Moscow said Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dozens of residents from the Russian border region of Kursk have been returned to Russia from Ukraine following rare and "painstaking" talks between Moscow and Kyiv, Moscow said Friday.</p>

<p>Kyiv launched a major ground offensive into the Kursk region in August, capturing large swathes of Russian territory home to thousands of civilians.</p>

<p>It was not clear why the residents had been transported into Ukraine, and there was no immediate comment from Kyiv.</p>

<p>"Today, 46 residents of the Kursk region returned to Russia from Ukraine as a result of a negotiation process with the Ukrainian side," Russian human rights ombudsman Tatiana Moskalkova said.</p>

<p>The residents were all from the Sudzhansky district, home to the border town of Sudzha which Ukraine captured shortly after launching its offensive, according to local governor Alexei Smirnov.</p>

<p>"The painstaking and lengthy negotiations to return our fellow countrymen to their homeland have brought results," he said on Telegram.</p>

<p>The residents included 12 children and were returned via Belarus, with all of them being given "all necessary assistance", he added.</p>

<p>One of the children being returned in the deal was three-year-old Darina, her mother, Anastasia Gridina, told AFP.</p>

<p>"They are already on the way. In four hours I will meet Darina," she said.</p>

<p>Gridina had gone to Moscow for temporary work, leaving her daughter with her grandmother in the Kursk region village of Lebedevka when Ukraine launched its shock offensive.</p>

<p>In October she told AFP she had been pleading for help "everywhere," even writing a personal letter to President Vladimir Putin.</p>

<p>At one point she tried to cross the front line herself, but was forced to turn back.</p>

<p>The deal comes at a tense moment in the Ukraine conflict, with Kyiv firing British and US-supplied long-range missiles into Russia and Moscow firing a hypersonic missile at its neighbour.</p>

<p>The limited return of civilians, as well as exchanges of captured soldiers and bodies of killed fighters have become the only areas of co-operation between the two sides, which have been fighting since Moscow launched its full-scale offensive in February 2022.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/17clffu_ukraine-returns-kursk-residents_625x300_22_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The residents were all from the Sudzhansky district]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fast-forming-alien-planet-has-astronomers-puzzled-defies-current-understanding-of-physics-7082459]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Fast-Forming Alien Planet Puzzles Astronomers. Defies Current Understanding]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fast-forming-alien-planet-has-astronomers-puzzled-defies-current-understanding-of-physics-7082459]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 22 Nov 2024 23:14:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Astronomers have spotted orbiting around a young star a newborn planet that took only 3 million years to form - quite swift in cosmic terms - in a discovery that challenges the current understanding of the speed of planetary formation.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Astronomers have spotted orbiting around a young star a newborn planet that took only 3 million years to form - quite swift in cosmic terms - in a discovery that challenges the current understanding of the speed of planetary formation.</p>

<p>This infant world, estimated at around 10 to 20 times the mass of Earth, is one of the youngest planets beyond our solar system - called exoplanets - ever discovered. It resides alongside the remnants of the disk of dense gas and dust circling the host star - called a protoplanetary disk - that provided the ingredients for the planet to form.</p>

<p>The star it orbits is expected to become a stellar type called an orange dwarf, less hot and less massive than our sun. The star's mass is about 70% that of the sun and it is about half as luminous. It is located in our Milky Way galaxy about 520 light-years from Earth. A light-year is the distance light travels in a year, 5.9 trillion miles (9.5 trillion km).</p>

<p>"This discovery confirms that planets can be in a cohesive form within 3 million years, which was previously unclear as Earth took 10 to 20 million years to form," said Madyson Barber, a graduate student in the department of physics and astronomy at the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill and lead author of the study published this week in the journal Nature.</p>

<p>"We don't really know how long it takes for planets to form," UNC astrophysicist and study co-author Andrew Mann added. "We know that giant planets must form faster than their disk dissipates because they need a lot of gas from the disk. But disks take 5 to 10 million years to dissipate. So do planets form in 1 million years? 5? 10?"</p>

<p>The planet, given the names IRAS 04125+2902 b and TIDYE-1b, orbits its star every 8.8 days at a distance about one-fifth that separating our solar system's innermost planet Mercury from the sun. Its mass is in between that of Earth, the largest of our solar system's rocky planets, and Neptune, the smallest of the gas planets. It is less dense than Earth and has a diameter about 11 times greater. Its chemical composition is not known.</p>

<p>The researchers suspect that the planet formed further away from its star and then migrated inward.</p>

<p>"Forming large planets close to the star is difficult because the protoplanetary disk dissipates away from closest to the star the fastest, meaning there's not enough material to form a large planet that close that quickly," Barber said.</p>

<p>The researchers detected it using what is called the "transit" method, observing a dip in the host star's brightness when the planet passes in front of it, from the perspective of a viewer on Earth. It was found by NASA's Transiting Exoplanet Survey Satellite, or TESS, space telescope.</p>

<p>"This is the youngest-known transiting planet. It is on par with the youngest planets known," Barber said.</p>

<p>Exoplanets not detected using this method sometimes are directly imaged using telescopes. But these typically are massive ones, around 10 times greater than our solar system's largest planet Jupiter.</p>

<p>Stars and planets form from clouds of interstellar gas and dust.</p>

<p>"To form a star-planet system, the cloud of gas and dust will collapse and spin into a flat environment, with the star at the center and the disk surrounding it. Planets will form in that disk. The disk will then dissipate starting from the inner region near the star," Barber said.</p>

<p>"It was previously thought that we wouldn't be able to find a transiting planet this young because the disk would be in the way. But for some reason that we aren't sure of, the outer disk is warped, leaving a perfect window to the star and allowing us to detect the transit," Barber added.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/r3o3fa2s_planet-and-host-star-generic-reuters_625x300_22_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Astronomers spotted a newborn planet orbiting a young star that took only 3 million years to form]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bhutanese-prime-minister-tshering-tobgay-to-visit-india-from-november-24-26-7082399]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bhutanese Prime Minister Tshering Tobgay To Visit India From November 24-26]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bhutanese-prime-minister-tshering-tobgay-to-visit-india-from-november-24-26-7082399]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 22 Nov 2024 23:02:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Bhutanese Prime Minister Tshering Tobgay is scheduled to undertake a three-day visit to India starting Sunday, the Ministry of External Affairs has said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bhutanese Prime Minister Tshering Tobgay is scheduled to undertake a three-day visit to India starting Sunday, the Ministry of External Affairs has said.</p>

<p>The MEA shared a brief itinerary of his upcoming visit on Friday.</p>

<p>Bhutanese Prime Minister Tobgay had visited India in March, his first foreign trip after assuming the charge of the top office in January.</p>

<p>According to the advisory issued by the MEA, the "visit of H.E. Dasho Tshering Tobgay, Prime Minister of Bhutan to India" will be from November 24-26.</p>

<p>Tobgay is scheduled to arrive in New Delhi on Sunday.</p>

<p>On Monday, he will take part in a programme in Delhi and depart on Tuesday afternoon.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-01/f84pvf2o_tshering-tobgay-bhutan-expm_625x300_09_January_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The MEA shared a brief itinerary of his upcoming visit on Friday. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hyundai-recalls-over-145-000-electric-vehicles-after-malfunction-slows-down-cars-7082364]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hyundai Recalls Over 145,000 Electric Vehicles After Malfunction Slows Cars]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hyundai-recalls-over-145-000-electric-vehicles-after-malfunction-slows-down-cars-7082364]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 22 Nov 2024 22:56:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[South Korean carmaker Hyundai Motor is recalling about 145,235 electrified vehicles in the United States due to a loss of drive power, the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration said on Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>South Korean carmaker Hyundai Motor is recalling about 145,235 electrified vehicles in the United States due to a loss of drive power, the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration said on Friday.</p>

<p>The recall includes certain IONIQ 5 and IONIQ 6 EVs along with some luxury Genesis GV60, Genesis GV70 and Genesis G80 electrified variants from model years 2022-2025.</p>

<p>The US auto safety regulator said that integrated charging control units are likely to get damaged and stop charging the 12-volt battery, which can result in a loss of drive power.</p>

<p>Hyundai dealers will inspect, replace and update the software on impacted parts and its fuse for free, the NHTSA added.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/4a3qv7ao_hyundai-electric-cars-reuters_625x300_22_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hyundai displays the new Ioniq 6 vehicle at the 2022 Los Angeles Auto Show.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uks-serious-fraud-office-launches-probe-on-french-defence-giant-thales-7082288]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK's Serious Fraud Office Launches Probe On French Defence Giant Thales]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uks-serious-fraud-office-launches-probe-on-french-defence-giant-thales-7082288]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 22 Nov 2024 22:40:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Britain's Serious Fraud Office (SFO) said Thursday it had launched a joint investigation with its French counterparts into "suspected bribery and corruption" at the France-based multinational defence giant Thales.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Britain's Serious Fraud Office (SFO) said Thursday it had launched a joint investigation with its French counterparts into "suspected bribery and corruption" at the France-based multinational defence giant Thales.</p>

<p>"Investigators from the SFO and French authority Parquet National Financier (PNF) have informed the company of the investigation," it said, noting the two agencies were probing "in their respective jurisdictions".</p>

<p>Thales has its headquarters in Paris. Thales UK is a subsidiary and one of the British government's key defence contractors, employing over 7,000 staff at 16 sites across the country.</p>

<p>It built hundreds of lightweight missiles which the UK sent to Ukraine in September.</p>

<p>A Thales spokesperson confirmed that the SFO and the PNF had "commenced an investigation in relation to four of its entities in France and the UK".</p>

<p>"Thales is co-operating with the PNF in France and the SFO in the UK. The group complies with all national and international regulations.</p>

<p>"As the investigation is ongoing, Thales will not comment further."</p>

<p>The SFO announcement follows police in France, the Netherlands and Spain searching the multinational's offices in June, over suspicions of corruption linked to arms sales, according to reports.</p>

<p>SFO director Nick Ephgrave said he hoped the joint probe would reinforce the SFO's and PNF's "long-standing relationship, built on mutual cooperation and shared success".</p>

<p>"We will together rigorously pursue every avenue in our investigation into these serious allegations," he added in a statement, which did not provide any further details about the accusations.</p>

<p>The SFO is a specialist prosecuting authority tackling top level serious or complex fraud, bribery and corruption, in England, Wales and Northern Ireland.</p>

<p>Thales specialises in defence electronics, and built the 650 so-called Lightweight Multirole Missiles (LMMs) that the UK announced it would supply to Ukraine in September, costing 162 million Pounds ($204 million).</p>

<p>The firm also won a 1.8-billion Pound UK defence contract in February, which will see it maintain the Royal Navy's fleet of ships and submarines for the next 15 years.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/fl0aaips_thales-group-ians_625x300_22_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Thales UK is a subsidiary and one of the British government's key defence contractors.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-to-arrest-benjamin-netanyahu-if-he-visits-says-will-comply-with-world-court-order-7082191]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK To Arrest Netanyahu If He Visits, "Will Comply" With World Court Order]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-to-arrest-benjamin-netanyahu-if-he-visits-says-will-comply-with-world-court-order-7082191]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 22 Nov 2024 22:23:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The British government indicated on Friday that Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu could be arrested on an International Criminal Court arrest warrant if he travelled to the UK.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The British government indicated on Friday that Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu could be arrested on an International Criminal Court arrest warrant if he travelled to the UK.</p>

<p>The ICC on Thursday issued arrest warrants for Netanyahu and ex-defence minister Yoav Gallant in response to accusations of crimes against humanity and war crimes in Israel's war on Hamas in Gaza, triggered by the militant Palestinian group's October 7, 2023 attack.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Keir Starmer's spokesman refused to be drawn specifically on whether UK police would detain Netanyahu, telling reporters he would not "get into hypotheticals in relation to individual cases".</p>

<p>But he added: "The UK will always comply with its legal obligations as set out by domestic law and indeed international law."</p>

<p>Britain signed the Rome Statute, the international treaty that created the ICC, in 1998 and ratified it three years later.</p>

<p>The UK's ICC Act 2001 stipulates that when a government minister receives a request from the ICC for the arrest of an indictee they "shall transmit the request and the documents accompanying it" to an appropriate court.</p>

<p>"If the request is accompanied by a warrant of arrest and the appropriate judicial officer is satisfied that the warrant appears to have been issued by the ICC, he shall endorse the warrant for execution in the United Kingdom," the act adds.</p>

<p>Officials say the act has not yet been used because someone charged by the ICC has never visited Britain.</p>

<p>It is not clear whether the UK court process begins after the ICC issues the arrest or once the indicted person lands on British soil.</p>

<p>"We would obviously fulfil our obligations under the act," added Starmer's spokesman.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2018-02/israeli-prime-minister-benjamin-netanyahu-afp_650x400_51518603268.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[UK has said it will arrest Benjamin Netanyahu if he visits Britain by complying with ICC]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/man-60-shot-dead-by-77-year-old-in-paris-mcdonalds-7082021]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Man, 60, Shot Dead By 77-Year-Old In Paris McDonald's]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/man-60-shot-dead-by-77-year-old-in-paris-mcdonalds-7082021]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 22 Nov 2024 21:54:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A man aged 77 on Friday stormed into a branch of American fast food chain McDonald's in northern Paris, shooting dead a 60-year-old in an apparent settling of scores before being arrested, a source close to the case said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A man aged 77 on Friday entered a branch of American fast food chain McDonald's in northern Paris, shooting dead a 60-year-old in an apparent settling of scores before being arrested, a source close to the case said.</p>

<p>The incident took place at the McDonald's in the 18th district of the French capital, said the source, asking not to be named.</p>

<p>The attacker fired four shots, the town hall of the 18th district said, adding that the men knew each other and that the incident was linked "to a settling of scores following an attempted racketeering", without giving further details.</p>

<p>A police source, also asking not to be named, said the suspected perpetrator did not flee and was arrested at the scene by the police.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-12/sg8ktf4g_france-police-generic_625x300_23_December_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The attacker fired four shots, the town hall of Paris' 18th district said (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/french-man-raped-daughter-for-years-offered-her-to-strangers-jailed-7082002]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[French Man Raped Daughter For Years, 'Offered' Her To Strangers, Jailed]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/french-man-raped-daughter-for-years-offered-her-to-strangers-jailed-7082002]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 22 Nov 2024 21:50:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A court in southeast France on Friday sentenced to 20 years in jail a man who for years raped his teenage daughter and offered her up to strangers for sex.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A court in southeast France on Friday sentenced to 20 years in jail a man who for years raped his teenage daughter and offered her up to strangers for sex.</p>

<p>The case echoed the ongoing high-profile trial that has shocked the nation in which 51 men are accused of raping Gisele Pelicot, drugged by her husband so he could invite strangers to their home to abuse her.</p>

<p>The 38-year-old father was convicted by the court in the southeastern Var region of forcing sexual acts on his daughter from the age of 13.</p>

<p>Prosecutor Estelle Bois described how the father exercised total control over the young girl, his adoptive daughter.</p>

<p>He also brought her to other men, many of them much older, who he contacted through online classified ads.</p>

<p>The father claimed to the other men that he and his daughter were both consenting adults living out a sexual fantasy. But he was convicted and sentenced to the maximum 20 years in prison, in line with the demands of the prosecutors.</p>

<p>Some of the defendants in the Pelicot case have claimed that they were given that same impression by the victim's then-husband, Dominique Pelicot.</p>

<p>Also like Dominique Pelicot, the father in Friday's case directed, participated in and filmed the sex acts involving his daughter, who was blindfolded during the encounters.</p>

<p>He admitted to the accusations, but claimed in court that he had a loving relationship with the young girl and had responded to her initiating sexual contact.</p>

<p>"This is not about love, but about power and domination. He doesn't love (his daughter), he loves having total control over her, her belonging to him, her obeying him," prosecutor Bois said.</p>

<p>She also asked judges to jail for 16 years a second defendant, the only one of the other men to have abused the girl who could be identified.</p>

<p>As in the Pelicot case, the second defendant - a man his 60s with six children - was identified thanks to the photo and video documentation by the father of the abuse, this time via geolocation data.</p>

<p>The second defendant told the court that he had been taken in by the father's claim that the girl was consenting in three of his four meetings with them.</p>

<p>In the fourth, "things went badly. Rather than acting like a responsible man, he followed through on his own pleasure and closed his eyes" to the abuse, his lawyer Christophe Mairet said.</p>

<p>Now aged 18, the girl was accompanied in court by a golden retriever trained to comfort victims of abuse.</p>

<p>She had, like Gisele Pelicot, declined the option of the trial being held behind closed doors.</p>

<p>It was the teenager, then aged 15, who put a stop to her own abuse in 2021 by fleeing after her father's violence and humiliation escalated.</p>

<p>She ran from their home in Cavalaire-sur-mer, south of glitzy resort town Saint-Tropez, before being brought to police by a holidaymaker.</p>

<p>Her father had bombarded her phone with calls and texts throughout her escape.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-04/v3q56dto_france-police-paris-police-afp-650_625x300_25_April_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The father was convicted for forcing sexual acts on his daughter from the age of 13. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-a-childhood-stutter-marked-early-signs-of-dementia-for-bruce-willis-7081826]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How A Childhood Stutter Marked Early Signs Of Dementia For Bruce Willis]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-a-childhood-stutter-marked-early-signs-of-dementia-for-bruce-willis-7081826]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 22 Nov 2024 21:25:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Before Bruce Willis' diagnosis with aphasia and later frontotemporal dementia (FTD), his wife Emma Heming Willis noticed subtle changes in his speech.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Before Bruce Willis' diagnosis with aphasia and later frontotemporal dementia (FTD), his wife Emma Heming Willis noticed subtle changes in his speech. However, she initially attributed these changes to his lifelong struggle with a severe stutter.</p>

<p>People with FTD can live with the disease but there's no cure.</p>

<p>Willis' family announced in 2022 that the "Die Hard" star would retire from acting due to a cognitive disorder. A year later, they revealed that he had been diagnosed with FTD, a rare condition affecting approximately 50,000 to 60,000 Americans.</p>

<p>"For Bruce, it started with language," Heming Willis shared in a recent interview with Town and Country. But she said those shifts in his speech did not alarm her because he used to stutter as a teen.</p>

<p>Willis' stutter was so severe that it took him three minutes to complete a sentence. However, when he became another character in a play, his stutter disappeared. "Yet, when I became another character, in a play, I lost the stutter. It was phenomenal" he says in 'Bruce Willis: The Unauthorized Biography'. This discovery propelled him into acting.</p>

<p>Heming Willis reflected on how Willis' stutter affected his early life and career. "Bruce has always had a stutter, but he has been good at covering it up. As his language started changing, it seemed like it was just a part of a stutter, it was just Bruce."</p>

<p>She admitted that she never suspected that the changes in his speech could be a sign of dementia, especially given his relatively young age.</p>

<p>On the other hand, Demi Moore is basking in the success of The Substance and according to Radar Online, a family insider claimed, "They're worried Demi is working too much and want her home with them and Bruce. It's not like Demi needs the money."</p>

<p>She opened up about Willis and his struggles on October 13th when she was awarded the Career Achievement in Acting Award at the 2024 Hamptons International Film Festival. She said, "The disease is what the disease is. And I think you have to be in real deep acceptance of what that is. But for where he's at, he is stable."<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-03/2ng5gckg_bruce-willis-retirement-afp-650_625x300_31_March_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[People with FTD can live with the disease but there's no cure.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hypothetical-will-comply-with-obligations-uk-on-netanyahu-arrest-warrant-7081402]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Hypothetical, Will Comply With Obligations": UK On Netanyahu Arrest Warrant]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hypothetical-will-comply-with-obligations-uk-on-netanyahu-arrest-warrant-7081402]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 22 Nov 2024 20:24:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The British government indicated on Friday that Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu could be arrested on an International Criminal Court arrest warrant if he travelled to the UK.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The British government indicated on Friday that Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu could be arrested on an International Criminal Court arrest warrant if he travelled to the UK.</p>

<p>The ICC on Thursday issued arrest warrants for Netanyahu and ex-defence minister Yoav Gallant in response to accusations of crimes against humanity and war crimes in Israel's war on Hamas in Gaza, triggered by the Palestinian group's October 7, 2023 attack.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Keir Starmer's spokesman refused to be drawn specifically on whether UK police would detain Netanyahu, telling reporters he would not "get into hypotheticals in relation to individual cases".</p>

<p>But he added: "The UK will always comply with its legal obligations as set out by domestic law and indeed international law."</p>

<p>Britain signed the Rome Statute, the international treaty that created the ICC, in 1998 and ratified it three years later.</p>

<p>The UK's ICC Act 2001 stipulates that when a government minister receives a request from the ICC for the arrest of an indictee they "shall transmit the request and the documents accompanying it" to an appropriate court.</p>

<p>"If the request is accompanied by a warrant of arrest and the appropriate judicial officer is satisfied that the warrant appears to have been issued by the ICC, he shall endorse the warrant for execution in the United Kingdom," the act adds.</p>

<p>Officials say the act has not yet been used because someone charged by the ICC has never visited Britain.</p>

<p>It is not clear whether the UK court process begins after the ICC issues the arrest or once the indicted person lands on British soil.</p>

<p>"We would obviously fulfil our obligations under the act," added Starmer's spokesman.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/jdpp60fk_benjamin-netanyahu-afp_625x300_22_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["The UK will always comply with its legal obligations," said Keir Starmer's spokesman (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sweden-says-wont-be-intimidated-by-putins-warning-to-west-7081059]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Sweden Says Won't Be Intimidated By Putin's Warning To West]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sweden-says-wont-be-intimidated-by-putins-warning-to-west-7081059]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 22 Nov 2024 19:35:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Sweden will not be intimidated by Russia's provocations, Defence Minister Pal Jonson said Friday after President Vladimir Putin hinted at strikes on Western countries supplying weapons to Ukraine.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sweden will not be intimidated by Russia's provocations, Defence Minister Pal Jonson said Friday after President Vladimir Putin hinted at strikes on Western countries supplying weapons to Ukraine.</p>

<p>The Swedish minister's remarks came as he announced "substantial funding" to Ukraine for the procurement of long-range missiles and drones.</p>

<p>"The Russian escalation and provocation that we've been noticing recently is an attempt to scare us from supporting Ukraine, and that will fail. This will not happen," Jonson told reporters at a joint press conference in Stockholm with his Ukrainian counterpart Rustem Umerov.</p>

<p>"Supporting Ukraine is both the right thing to do and it's a smart thing to do, and it's an investment into our own security, because (Ukraine's) security is also our security," he said.</p>

<p>"Ukraine has the full right, in accordance with international law, to defend itself inside and outside of its territory, and we're glad if we can further develop both your capability to produce long-range missiles and also long-range strike drones," Jonson told Umerov.</p>

<p>Putin said Thursday that the conflict in Ukraine had characteristics of a "global" war, criticising Ukraine's allies for granting permission for Kyiv to use Western-supplied weapons to strike targets on Russian territory.</p>

<p>In recent days Ukraine has fired US and UK-supplied missiles at Russian territory for the first time, escalating already sky-high tensions in the nearly three-year-long conflict.</p>

<p>"We consider ourselves entitled to use our weapons against the military facilities of those countries that allow their weapons to be used against our facilities," Putin said.&nbsp;<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/7465u5_swedens-defence-minister-pal-jonson-afp_625x300_22_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sweden will not be intimidated by Russia's provocations, Defence Minister Pal Jonson said]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-notre-dame-de-paris-rises-from-the-ashes-set-to-reopen-next-month-7080469]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Video: Notre-Dame In Paris Rises From The Ashes, Set To Reopen Next Month]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-notre-dame-de-paris-rises-from-the-ashes-set-to-reopen-next-month-7080469]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 22 Nov 2024 18:12:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Five years after a massive fire engulfed the centuries-old Notre-Dame de Paris and toppled its iconic spire, leaving a gaping hole in the heart of Paris while the world watched helplessly, the Catholic cathedral has been restored to its former glory.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Five years after a massive fire engulfed the centuries-old Notre-Dame de Paris and toppled its iconic spire, leaving a gaping hole in the heart of Paris while the world watched helplessly, the Catholic cathedral has been restored to its former glory and is set to reopen next month amid grand celebrations.</p>

<p>X boss Elon Musk, in a post on the micro-blogging site, provided a glimpse into the gothic monument that, several reports claimed, has been rebuilt with the help of hundreds of specialist artisans and millions of donations.</p>

<p>"Notre-Dame has been restored," Musk said on X, as he shared a 94-minute clip of the renovated cathedral that is set to reopen on December 7.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Notre-Dame has been restored!<br />
<a href="https://t.co/g7RKQDHRlr">pic.twitter.com/g7RKQDHRlr</a></p>
 Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1859593835535331439?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 21, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>A report by the National Geographic said everything has been spruced up - the frescoes, checked floor and the bells - which have been removed from the belfry, cleaned of lead dust, and restored at the Norman foundry where they were first cast - among others. A high-tech new lighting system will also contribute to the effect.</p>

<p>According to Forbes, the renovation was carried out at a cost of around 500 million euros.</p>

<p>"A surplus of about 140 million euros will be used for future preservation work on the 861-year-old building," Philippe Jost, who has overseen the project, told Forbes.</p>

<p>An AFP report said before the fire, Notre-Dame was among the most visited buildings in Europe, with 14 to 15 million a year expected to visit once the cathedral reopens next month.</p>

<p>On April 15, 2019, a fire broke out in the attic, beneath the cathedral's roof, causing severe damages to the wooden spire, which had collapsed, and the wooden roof, besides the cathedral's upper walls.</p>

<p>Several works of art and religious relics were moved to safety but others suffered smoke damage. Some of the exterior art was also damaged or destroyed in the blaze. At least two police officers and one firefighter were injured as around 400 firefighters worked through the night, taking roughly around nine hours to extinguish the blaze.</p>

<p>According to the European Commission (a politically independent executive arm of the European Union), a large part of the cathedral roof and spire were made of lead, and some studies suggested that 150 kg of lead was spread during the fire. Others hinted that one tonne of lead must have fallen within one kilometre of the cathedral.</p>

<p>The exact cause of the fire could not be determined but French authorities claimed an electrical fault or a cigarette may have been responsible for the fire, according to Reuters.</p>

<p>Notre-Dame did not hold a Christmas mass in 2019, for the first time since 1803. French President Emmanuel Macron had announced a five-year plan to rebuild what was lost.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/igee9dfo_notre-dame-restoration_625x300_22_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A fire broke out at the Notre-Dame de Paris on April 15, 2019.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>