<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Sat, 14 Sep 2024 14:44:40 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/modi-3-0-is-leaving-nothing-to-chance-with-southeast-asia-6563216]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: Modi 3.0 Is Leaving Nothing To Chance With Southeast Asia]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/modi-3-0-is-leaving-nothing-to-chance-with-southeast-asia-6563216]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 14 Sep 2024 13:14:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Modi 3.0 marks a significant evolution in India's engagement with Southeast Asia, driven by geopolitical imperatives and economic interests.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/i6ubmn8g_modi-malaysia-pm_625x300_20_August_24.jpeg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>As India steps into its third term under Prime Minister Narendra Modi's administration, Southeast Asia has emerged as a central focus of its foreign policy. The region plays a crucial role in the Indo-Pacific theatre and has become pivotal to India's strategic, economic, and diplomatic interests.</p>

<p>Recent high-level engagements, such as Modi's visit to Singapore and Brunei in early September, External Affairs Minister Jaishankar's articulation of India's stance on the South China Sea, and the visits of Vietnamese and Malaysian Prime Ministers to India, signal a continuity in the strategic significance of Southeast Asia to India's foreign policy vision.</p>

<h2><strong>'Look East' To 'Act East'</strong></h2>

<p>The central government's "Act East Policy," an evolution from the previous "Look East Policy," signifies a more proactive engagement with Southeast Asian nations. Under Modi, this policy has become a cornerstone of India's Indo-Pacific strategy, which promotes a free, open, inclusive, and rules-based order.</p>

<p>The region's strategic importance is underscored by its geographical proximity to India and its role as a gateway to the South China Sea, a vital maritime corridor for global trade. Southeast Asia is a crucial part of the Indo-Pacific's geopolitical framework, and India's growing relationship with the region is seen as a counterbalance to China's expanding and often predatory influence. In Modi 3.0, India aims to solidify its position as a reliable partner in the Indo-Pacific region, with Southeast Asia being a crucial element of this strategy.</p>

<p>New Delhi has placed particular emphasis on fostering closer ties with ASEAN (Association of Southeast Asian Nations) member states. Trade between India and ASEAN has grown steadily in recent years, with bilateral trade exceeding $100 billion in 2023. In addition to economic cooperation, India's strategic interests in the region have also deepened.</p>

<h2><strong>Singapore, Brunei, Vietnam</strong></h2>

<p>In Singapore, Modi's talks with newly elected Prime Minister Lawrence Wong resulted in substantive agreements, particularly in the semiconductor sector in addition to health, skilling, and digital security. The "India-Singapore Semiconductor Ecosystem Partnership" inked during the visit, aims to facilitate the entry of Singaporean companies into India. This partnership is integral to New Delhi's ambitions to become a global semiconductor hub, leveraging complementary strengths to build resilience in the global chip supply chain. Parallelly, Modi's visit to Brunei, a strategically located nation in the South China Sea, marked a key moment in India's Act East Policy and Indo-Pacific vision. It was the first visit by an Indian Prime Minister and coincided with the 40th anniversary of diplomatic relations between the two countries.</p>

<p>In Modi 3.0, Vietnam has emerged as one of India's most important Southeast Asian partners. The two countries share concerns over China's growing assertiveness in the South China Sea, where both India and Vietnam have vested interests in oil exploration and freedom of navigation. Discussions on defence cooperation, trade, and energy security marked the visit of Vietnamese Prime Minister Phạm Minh Chính to India. Vietnam is a linchpin in India's Act East Policy and Indo-Pacific strategy, strengthening their naval ties and defence collaboration. India and Vietnam have signed several agreements on defence, maritime security, and energy and economic cooperation. Both countries are committed to upholding international law in the South China Sea, further aligning their strategic interests. The bilateral relationship has also expanded into renewable energy, IT, and infrastructure development, with India playing a significant role in Vietnam's development plans.</p>

<h2><strong>Resetting Ties With Malaysia</strong></h2>

<p>Similarly, the visit of Malaysian Prime Minister Anwar Ibrahim to India highlighted a much-needed reset in bilateral ties following a dip in relations before 2022. Malaysia's importance to India stems from its strategic location along vital maritime routes in the Indo-Pacific and its role as a significant trading partner. During Anwar's visit, the two leaders discussed enhancing economic cooperation, particularly in technology, renewable energy, and digital connectivity. Malaysia's support for India's Act East Policy and its role in ASEAN make it a valuable partner for India as it seeks to expand its presence in Southeast Asia.</p>

<h2><strong>The South China Sea Question</strong></h2>

<p>Finally, India's position on the South China Sea has evolved significantly over the years, shifting from a cautious, neutral stance to one that has now clearly articulated its support for the Philippines' sovereign maritime territorial claims, freedom of navigation and maritime resource exploitation, in line with international law. This aligns India with Southeast Asian nations against unilateral actions by China, while also serving India's strategic interests by ensuring freedom of navigation and bolstering regional security. India's nuanced stance, informed by its own territorial tensions with China on its northern land border, underscores its intent to deter unilateral and unlawful advances.</p>

<p>Modi 3.0 marks a significant evolution in India's engagement with Southeast Asia, driven by geopolitical imperatives and economic interests. The Modi administration has steadily deepened the extent and scope of its ties with Southeast Asian countries, and his third consecutive tenure in office looks poised to build on the gains of the last ten years.&nbsp;</p>

<p><em>(Harsh V. Pant is Vice President – Studies and Foreign Policy, at Observer Research Foundation, and Professor of International Relations at King's College London. Pratnashree Basu is an Associate Fellow - Indo-Pacific, at Observer Research Foundation.)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/i6ubmn8g_modi-malaysia-pm_625x300_20_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-calls-laura-loomer-a-free-spirit-after-her-racist-remark-on-harris-6562830]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Calls Laura Loomer "A Free Spirit" After Her Racist Remark On Harris]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-calls-laura-loomer-a-free-spirit-after-her-racist-remark-on-harris-6562830]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 14 Sep 2024 12:03:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump has defended his ties with Laura Loomer, who has drawn fire from some of his Republican allies for embracing conspiracy theories and making racist comments, including against Kamala Harris.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump has defended his ties with Laura Loomer, who has drawn fire from some of his Republican allies for embracing conspiracy theories and making racist comments, including against Kamala Harris.</p>

<p>"Laura has been a supporter of mine. Just like a lot of people are supporters, and she's been a supporter of mine. She speaks very positively of the campaign," Trump, the former president, said on Friday at a news conference in Southern California.</p>

<p>He was responding to a question from a reporter about his allies expressing concern about his close relationship with Loomer in recent days.</p>

<p>"I don't control Laura. Laura - she's a free spirit. Well, I don't know. I mean, look, I can't tell Laura what to do," Trump said.</p>

<p>&nbsp;"She is a strong person, she's got strong opinions, and I don't know what she said, but that's not up to me," he added.</p>

<p>Several of Loomer's posts on social media this week came under fire, including one where she nodded to a conspiracy theory about the 9/11 attacks.</p>

<p>"23 years later, and there's still a lot of unanswered questions," Loomer posted on Friday, alongside a video of Trump in 2001 questioning whether aeroplanes could cause explosions like the ones that happened at the Twin Towers on 9/11," Loomer wrote.</p>

<p>Loomer, often seen as a right-wing conspiracy theorist, in another post on Sunday, said the "White House will smell like curry &amp; White House speeches will be facilitated via a call centre" if Harris wins the November 5 presidential election.</p>

<p>Harris, a Democrat, will take on Trump in the November election.</p>

<p>NBC News asked Trump whether he'd been informed of Loomer's conspiracy theories.</p>

<p>"I don't know that much about it. No, I don't," he said, adding, "I know she's a big fan of the campaign, but I really don't know." Trump later sought to distance himself from Loomer's statements, though without specifying which ones.</p>

<p>In a Truth Social post, Trump said that Loomer "doesn't work for the Campaign. She's a private citizen and longtime supporter. " Even in that post, Trump defended Loomer and said: "Like the many millions of people who support me, she is tired of watching the Radical Left Marxists and Fascists violently attack and smear me." Several Republicans denounced Loomer for her remarks.</p>

<p>Republican Senator Thom Tillis said Loomer was a "crazy conspiracy theorist who regularly utters disgusting garbage intended to divide Republicans".</p>

<p>"The history of statements by Ms. Loomer are beyond disturbing," Senator Lindsey Graham, also a Republican told The Washington Post on Thursday.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/5s5pk9j8_laura-loomer-_625x300_13_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[In a Truth Social post, Donald Trump said that Laura Loomer doesn't work for the Campaign.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/indian-man-working-with-russian-military-amid-war-with-ukraine-returns-home-6562591]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Indian Man Working With Russian Military Amid War With Ukraine Returns Home]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/indian-man-working-with-russian-military-amid-war-with-ukraine-returns-home-6562591]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 14 Sep 2024 11:13:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Mohammed Sufiyan, 22, said he was promised a security-related job and not told about having to help the Russian troops in the war against Ukraine.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Mohammed Sufiyan, a Telangana native who ended up working as a support staff for the Russian army after being duped by an employment agent, returned home on September 14. The return of Sufiyan (22), who belongs to the Narayanpet district, ends the agonising wait of his family members who were worried about his safety as he was helping the Russian military in its war with Ukraine.</p>

<p>Mr Sufiyan said he was promised a security-related job and not told about having to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/49-ukrainian-prisoners-of-war-return-from-russia-zelensky-6560097">help the troops in the war</a>. He was told that he would have to undergo training for three months after which his salary would increase.</p>

<p>Mr Sufiyan, who left India in November last year, has been working for the Russian military as a support staff.</p>

<p>Speaking to PTI in July this year, Sufiyan's brother Salman hoped for his brother's early return home following PM Narendra Modi's visit to Russia.</p>

<p>Russia had agreed to India's demand to ensure <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/45-indians-inducted-in-russian-army-discharged-efforts-to-rescue-50-more-6549672">early release of Indian nationals</a> working with the Russian military as support staff after PM Modi "very strongly" raised the issue with President Vladimir Putin during his visit.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/p0gpcd_russiaukraine-war_625x300_14_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Representational Image]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/19-people-are-currently-orbiting-earth-heres-all-you-need-to-know-6562485]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[NASA Says 'New Record For Humanity' As 19 People Are Orbiting Earth]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/19-people-are-currently-orbiting-earth-heres-all-you-need-to-know-6562485]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 14 Sep 2024 10:59:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[With the arrival of three more people to the International Space Station (ISS), the Earth's orbit is right now busier than it has ever been.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">With the arrival of three more people to the International Space Station (ISS), the Earth's orbit is right now busier than it has ever been. "After Wednesday's launch to the @Space_Station, there are now 19 humans in orbit—a new record for humanity. We're proud to help expand the boundaries of human exploration. Ad astra," read a post on the official X handle of NASA.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">After Wednesday's launch to the <a href="https://twitter.com/Space_Station?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Space_Station</a>, there are now 19 humans in orbit—a new record for humanity.<br />
<br />
We're proud to help expand the boundaries of human exploration. Ad astra! <a href="https://t.co/3FvzQlbmNN">pic.twitter.com/3FvzQlbmNN</a></p>
— NASA (@NASA) <a href="https://twitter.com/NASA/status/1834692801914634707?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 13, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p dir="ltr">Earlier this week, three people travelled aboard the Russian Soyuz capsule towards the International Space Station. Among these were NASA astronaut Don Pettit as well as Roscosmos cosmonauts Alexey Ovchinin and Ivan Vagner. With this, the orbit around the Earth now has a record-breaking 19 people.</p>

<p dir="ltr">This has surpassed the previous record of 17, set last year, <a href="https://www.space.com/new-record-19-people-orbiting-earth-soyuz-iss">Space.com</a> reported.</p>

<p dir="ltr">The earlier record in orbit was set in May 2023. Back then, there were a total of 17 people aboard both the International Space Station as well as China's Tiangong space station for a brief period of time.</p>

<p dir="ltr">With at least one person in the orbit at all times, the International Space Station has witness an enduring presence since 2000, <a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/nation/2024/09/12/iss-astronaut-space-record/75193569007/">USA Today</a> reported.</p>

<h3 dir="ltr"><strong>The 19 people in space</strong></h3>

<p dir="ltr">Upon their arrival, Pettit, Ovchinin and Vagner have joined nine other astronauts and cosmonauts onboard the International Space Station. Among these are Sunita Williams, Barry Wilmore, Michael Barratt, Tracy Caldwell-Dyson, Matthew Dominick and Jeanette Epps of NASA and cosmonauts Nikolai Chub, Oleg Kononenko and Alexander Grebenkin.</p>

<p dir="ltr">The three people aboard the Tiangong space station are Li Guangsu, Li Cong and Ye Guangfu of the Shenzhou 18 mission.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Besides them, there are four astronauts, who are currently inhabiting a free-flying Crew Dragon. These include Jared Isaacman, Scott Poteet, Sarah Gillis and Anna Menon.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Launched on Tuesday, the Polaris Dawn mission is expected to last for five days.</p>

<h3 dir="ltr"><strong>Sunita Williams to return next year</strong></h3>

<p dir="ltr">Indian-origin astronaut Sunita Williams and Barry Wilmore were launched onboard Crew Flight Test (CFT), the first-ever crewed mission of the Starliner capsule of Boeing, in June this year.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Although the mission was supposed to last a few days, NASA decided to keep the Starliner docked to the ISS after the capsule suffered thruster problems in orbit.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Ultimately, the Starliner returned to the Earth uncrewed, while Williams and Wilmore are now expected to return home on a SpaceX Crew Dragon capsule in February 2025.</p>

<p dir="ltr"></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/al1jc96g_boeing-starliner_625x300_05_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Indian-origin astronaut Sunita Williams and Barry Wilmore were launched onboard in June.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iranian-envoy-invites-indians-says-iran-is-safe-amid-political-turmoil-6562245]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iranian Envoy Invites Indians, Says "Iran Is Safe" Amid Political Turmoil]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iranian-envoy-invites-indians-says-iran-is-safe-amid-political-turmoil-6562245]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 14 Sep 2024 10:05:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Amid the tense situation in West Asia, Iranian Ambassador to India Iraj Elahi has said the tension between his country and Israel is "not new". He assured Indians and other tourists that "Iran is safe" to travel and urged them to explore Persia.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Amid the tense situation in West Asia, Iranian Ambassador to India Iraj Elahi has said the tension between his country and Israel is "not new". He assured Indians and other tourists that "Iran is safe" to travel and urged them to explore the historic land of Persia.</p>

<p>In an interview with PTI on the sidelines of the Iran Tourism Roadshow in Delhi, the envoy also expressed the hope that more direct flights can be set up between the two countries, as well as by Indian carriers from between different cities of India and Iran.</p>

<p>Currently, there are two direct flights between Tehran and Delhi and one between the Iranian capital and Mumbai, he said on Friday.</p>

<p>Asked if the current tense situation in West Asia including the Iran-Israel hostility has cast a shadow on the flow of tourists in the country, Elahi said the situation has not changed, "but Indians and other tourists do not have any security problems" in Iran.</p>

<p>"The tension between Iran and Israel is not new, there have been tensions for a long time. So, it is not something new that will affect the situation in Iran... I assure Indian tourists, and Indian friends and invite them to come to Iran, and visit Iran.</p>

<p>"They should see by themselves how much safer Iran is. And, it is beautiful and attractive," Elahi told PTI Videos.</p>

<p>He emphasised that Iran has passed "imposed" wars and sanctions, in its journey as a nation.</p>

<p>Asked about the status of India-Iran ties in the face of changing global dynamics, the envoy said, "The bilateral ties with India are not only good but fantastic." India and authorities in India observed a day-long mourning when the then-Iranian president Seyyed Ebrahim Raisi died, and condolences expressed are registered in the "national memory of Iran". It is something unbelievable for Iran, and regarding the relations, "the supreme leader of Iran respects India, and I as an ambassador of Iran also fully feel the respect of PM Modi and the government of India," he added.</p>

<p>The government of India had declared one-day national mourning on May 21 as a mark of respect to Raisi who had tragically passed away in a helicopter crash.</p>

<p>Elahi said at the strategic level, both countries have a good mindset about each other, and at the operative level, there are "some difficulties".</p>

<p>"We are in good relation with different structures of India to resolve these difficulties, we need some mechanism. Strategically, we see a willingness on both sides. We do not have any problems between the two countries.</p>

<p>"It is important. It is a strategic asset for both the countries. We have been together, we are now together, and we are now working to be in the future," the ambassador said.</p>

<p>India and Persia, as Iran is historically known, are two ancient civilisations and have had ties in trade, culture and other sectors, going back several centuries.</p>

<p>"Iran and India have a long-standing relation, and one aspect of our relation has been people-to-people relations and interactions. Unfortunately, Covid affected this relation. We organised this roadshow to reactivate and revive the good tourism cooperation between the two countries," he said.</p>

<p>"We believe that India needs to know more about the current Iran and development of Iran, as also Iranians also need to know more about India and the development of India, and the capabilities of the cooperation," the envoy added.</p>

<p>The event saw a gathering of different stakeholders of tourism -- travel agencies, airliners and officials from both countries.</p>

<p>"They have the opportunity to discuss different ways to promote tourism between the two countries. We recently have removed or resolved some concerns of Indians, and we have resolved the visa issue.</p>

<p>"Indians can enter Iran for two weeks without any visa, Indian passport holders are exempted from visa.</p>

<p>"Also, when they enter or depart Iran, their passport will not be stamped. So, they do not have concerns regarding travelling or visiting other countries. This is an important issue," Elahi said.</p>

<p>Another important issue is that the number of flights should be increased. Now, there are two direct flights between Delhi and Tehran, which take about three-and-a-half hours. Another flight between Tehran and Mumbai is about less than four hours. "But, we plan to increase the number of flights." "We have asked and approached Indian airlines and trying to explain the capacity of the big market of Iran for Indian airlines. So, Indian carriers can be welcomed to set up direct flight not only from Delhi or Mumbai, but also Hyderabad, and Bangalore, are good markets, and even Kashmir is good. Different cities of the two countries can be connected with direct flights, we welcome and we hope that Indian carriers can set up direct flights," he said.</p>

<p>Asked what is the increased frequency of direct flights he is expecting, the envoy said, "We are expecting at least one flight per day, seven-day-a-week flights." Elahi said this event is just the beginning in the long-drawn aim of cooperation and Iran hopes that after this event will witness promotion and progress in tourism between the two countries, on both sides.</p>

<p>"We are insisting not just to attract Indian tourists, we are also insisting to attract Iranian tourists to India... According to the latest statistics, in the last year, more than 13 million Iranians have travelled abroad, but the portion that went to India is just about 58,000.</p>

<p>"It is nothing, very low (in number). On the other hand, the number of Indian tourists going to Iran, the figure is huge. So, they can benefit from tourism cooperation. And, we hope that it is a good step," he added.</p>

<p>Besides, Indians can not only buy good souvenirs from Iran but they can also do business with Iran during their visit to Iran, the envoy said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/9p54r2_iran-flag-_625x300_14_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[India and Iran are two ancient civilisations that had ties in trade, culture and so on (representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sunita-williams-butch-willmore-on-2024-us-presidential-elections-boeing-starliner-international-space-station-6561682]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["My Happy Place. Love Being Here": Sunita Williams On Being Stuck In Space]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sunita-williams-butch-willmore-on-2024-us-presidential-elections-boeing-starliner-international-space-station-6561682]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 14 Sep 2024 07:38:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Indian-origin astronaut Sunita Williams and her fellow NASA colleague Butch Wilmore, who took off aboard Boeing's Starliner on June 5, are stuck in space till February 2025.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Indian-origin astronaut Sunita Williams, who is stuck on the International Space Station (ISS), today said it was her "happy place" and that she "loves" being up there. Ms Williams and her fellow NASA colleague Butch Wilmore on June 5 took off aboard the Boeing's Starliner as part of the vessel's first crewed mission, in what was originally meant to be eight days in orbit. Their stay, however, has been stretched to eight months after the Starliner ran into several technical issues and returned to Earth without them last week.</p>

<p>"That's how things go in this business," <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/sunita-williams-isro-nasa-our-future-couldnt-be-brighter-sunita-williams-on-us-sending-indian-astronaut-to-international-space-station-6081277" target="_blank">Sunita Williams</a> said in a video press conference on being stuck in the space.</p>

<p>Ms Williams said the transition to station life was "not that hard" since both astronauts had previous stints there.</p>

<p>"This is my happy place. I love being up here in space," the veteran astronaut said.</p>

<p>"We wanted to take Starliner to the completion and land back on land at home, but you know, you have to turn the page and look at the next opportunity," she added.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">LIVE: From the <a href="https://twitter.com/Space_Station?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Space_Station</a>, astronauts Butch Wilmore and Suni Williams discuss their ongoing mission and answer questions from the media: <a href="https://t.co/ytifGf22Gn">https://t.co/ytifGf22Gn</a></p>
— NASA (@NASA) <a href="https://twitter.com/NASA/status/1834657064913662168?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 13, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Ms Williams and Mr Wilmore are scheduled to return in February with the Crew-9 flight of billionaire Elon Musk's SpaceX.</p>

<p>Ms Williams said she was a little bit nervous that she was not returning home immediately.</p>

<p>"In the back of my mind, there are folks on the ground who have some plans like my family...spending times with my mother. And I think I was fretting more about that. Like the things we had planned for this fall or winter...but everybody was on board and that prepared us," she said.</p>

<p>Mr Wilmore said he was "absolutely not" let down by the decision to stay in space and indicated there were "disagreements" about how to handle the return.</p>

<p>"We could have gotten to the point, I believe, where we could have returned on Starliner, but we just simply ran out of time," he said in the press conference.</p>

<p>"In this case, we found some things that we just could not get comfortable with putting us back in the Starliner when we had other options," he added.</p>

<h3><strong>Sunita Williams, Butch Willmore To Vote In US Elections From Space</strong></h3>

<p>The two astronauts said they were looking forward to casting their ballot in the 2024 US presidential election from the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-indian-origin-astronaut-sunita-williams-dances-on-her-arrival-at-space-station-on-boeing-starliner-with-butch-wilmore-5835758" target="_blank">International Space Station</a>.</p>

<p>Butch Willmore said he has sent down his request for a ballot today.</p>

<p>"It is a very important role that we all play as American citizens," he said. "NASA makes it very easy for us to do that."</p>

<p>Sunita Williams also said it is a "very important duty".</p>

<p>"Looking forward to vote from space, which is pretty cool," she said.</p>

<p>The US elections - a fight between Democrat Kamala Harris and her Republican rival Donald Trump - will be held on November 5.</p>

<h3><strong>Boeing's Starliner Setbacks</strong></h3>

<p>After years of delays, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/why-boeings-starliner-will-return-to-earth-without-sunita-williams-butch-wilmore-6412302" target="_blank">Boeing's Starliner</a> finally lifted off on June 5 carrying Sunita Williams and Butch Wilmore, both former military test pilots, to the International Space Station. However, a day later, as Starliner was approaching the ISS, NASA and Boeing identified helium leaks and experienced issues with the spacecraft's reaction control thrusters.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Hugs all around! The Expedition 71 crew greets Butch Wilmore and <a href="https://twitter.com/Astro_Suni?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Astro_Suni</a> aboard <a href="https://twitter.com/Space_Station?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Space_Station</a> after <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Starliner?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Starliner</a> docked at 1:34 p.m. ET on June 6. <a href="https://t.co/wQZAYy2LGH">pic.twitter.com/wQZAYy2LGH</a></p>
— Boeing Space (@BoeingSpace) <a href="https://twitter.com/BoeingSpace/status/1798804195681947719?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 6, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Five of Starliner's 28 thrusters failed during flight and it sprang several leaks of helium, which is used to pressurize the thrusters. It was still able to dock with the space station, which has housed rotating crews of astronauts for over two decades.</p>

<p>NASA, however, feared the capsule would not be able to achieve the thrust necessary to return to Earth and decided to transfer the two astronauts to a SpaceX mission and return the Starliner empty.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/00gim5tg_sunita-williams-butch-wilmore_625x300_14_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sunita Williams and Butch Wilmore are scheduled to return in February with Elon Musk's SpaceX.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sunita-williams-could-have-returned-on-starliner-why-she-didnt-6561619]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Sunita Williams "Could Have Returned" On Starliner. Why She Didn't]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sunita-williams-could-have-returned-on-starliner-why-she-didnt-6561619]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 14 Sep 2024 07:12:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A US astronaut stuck on the International Space Station said Friday he believed Boeing's Starliner could have carried him home if more time had been available to work through the beleaguered spacecraft's issues.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A US astronaut stuck on the International Space Station said Friday he believed Boeing's Starliner could have carried him home if more time had been available to work through the beleaguered spacecraft's issues.</p>

<p>Last week, Barry "Butch" Wilmore and Sunita "Suni" Williams watched the Boeing Starliner they rode to the ISS three months prior head back to Earth without them.</p>

<p>"We could have gotten to the point, I believe, where we could have returned on Starliner, but we just simply ran out of time," Wilmore said Friday in a video press conference.</p>

<p>On June 5, Wilmore and Williams took off aboard the Starliner as part of the vessel's first crewed mission, in what was originally meant to be eight days in orbit.</p>

<p>After the Starliner ran into several technical issues, their stay is now expected to last for eight months.</p>

<p>Last month, NASA decided Williams and Wilmore would return in February with the Crew-9 flight of Boeing's aerospace rival SpaceX.</p>

<p>Though Wilmore said he was "absolutely not" let down by the decision to stay in space, he indicated there were "disagreements" about how to handle the return.</p>

<p>"In this case, we found some things that we just could not get comfortable with putting us back in the Starliner when we had other options," Wilmore said.</p>

<p>Williams said she was "so happy" Starliner landed on Earth without issues, even if they were not on it.</p>

<p>"We wanted to take Starliner to the completion and land back on land at home, but you know, you have to turn the page and look at the next opportunity," she said.</p>

<p>Both astronauts said the support they have received has helped them transition to the new return timeline.</p>

<p>"I can sum it up in one word, and that's resiliency," Wilmore said. "We are tasked -- and we learn, and we train -- to handle all types of situations."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/be6nk56_butch-wilmore-and-sunita-williams_625x300_30_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Last month, NASA decided Sunita Williams and Barry Wilmore would return in February.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-says-she-will-cut-degree-requirements-for-certain-federal-job-6561407]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris Says She Will Cut Degree Requirements For Certain Federal Job]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-says-she-will-cut-degree-requirements-for-certain-federal-job-6561407]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 14 Sep 2024 06:08:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US Vice President Kamala Harris said on Friday she will cut college degree requirements for certain federal jobs if elected president after the Nov. 5 elections in which she faces Republican former President Donald Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US Vice President Kamala Harris said on Friday she will cut college degree requirements for certain federal jobs if elected president after the Nov. 5 elections in which she faces Republican former President Donald Trump.</p>

<p>The Democratic presidential candidate said the U.S. should recognize the value of paths to success beyond a college degree, like apprenticeships and technical programs.</p>

<p>"As president, I will get rid of the unnecessary degree requirements for federal jobs to increase jobs for folks without a four-year degree," Harris said in her speech.</p>

<p>A degree does not necessarily indicate a person's skills, Harris said. She added: "And I will challenge the private sector to do the same."</p>

<p>Both Harris and Trump have been trying to appeal to voters with economic pledges. Harris has said she will aim to pass a middle class tax cut. Trump has advocated for cutting taxes on overtime pay. Both have supported eliminating taxes on tips.</p>

<p>Harris' speech in Wilkes-Barre, Pennsylvania, also faced some interruption from protesters opposing U.S. support for Israel's war in Gaza that has killed tens of thousands and caused a humanitarian crisis. It followed a deadly Oct. 7 attack on Israel by Palestinian Hamas militants.</p>

<p>Demonstrators in the U.S. have for months demanded an end to the war and restrictions on shipments of weapons to Israel.</p>

<p>Harris reiterated her support for a ceasefire and hostage rescue deal.</p>

<p>"Now is the time to get a hostage deal and ceasefire," Harris said when interrupted. "I respect your voice, but right now, I am speaking," she added.</p>

<p>Harris is in a tight race with Trump. Observers have said that if Muslim and Arab Americans, who overwhelmingly voted for the Democrats in the last presidential election, withhold their vote, it may hurt Harris' chances.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/53o1fa8s_kamala-harris-reuters_625x300_11_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kamala Harris has said she will aim to pass a middle class tax cut.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-we-know-about-us-vice-president-kamala-harris-gun-6561318]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What We Know About US Vice President Kamala Harris' Gun]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-we-know-about-us-vice-president-kamala-harris-gun-6561318]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 14 Sep 2024 05:35:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Democrat Vice President Kamala Harris said during Tuesday's debate with Republican Donald Trump that she owns a gun, a revelation that surprised some voters but carried a deliberate political message.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Democrat Vice President Kamala Harris said during Tuesday's debate with Republican Donald Trump that she owns a gun, a revelation that surprised some voters but carried a deliberate political message.</p>

<p>Harris owns a handgun for personal safety reasons, and it is stowed away in a secure location at her California home, a White House source said on Friday. The source declined to identify the make of gun, but said it is the same gun Harris mentioned in 2019 on the campaign trail.</p>

<p><strong>KEY QUOTES</strong></p>

<p>"This business about taking everyone's guns away — Tim Walz and I are both gun owners. We're not taking anybody's guns away, so stop with the continuous lying about this stuff," Harris said on Tuesday, referring to her running mate Walz.</p>

<p>In 2019, Harris told reporters "I am a gun owner, and I own a gun for probably the reason a lot of people do — for personal safety. I was a career prosecutor."</p>

<p><strong>WHY IT'S IMPORTANT:</strong></p>

<p>Harris along with most of her Democratic Party, has pushed for more gun safety legislation to curb the high rate of gun deaths and injuries in the U.S. Republicans blocking this legislation have argued that Democrats want to seize Americans' guns and overturn the Second Amendment to the U.S. Constitution that gives Americans the right to "bear arms."</p>

<p>Harris is trying to appeal to some voters among the one-third of Americans who own a gun and the two-thirds of Americans who support stronger regulation of gun ownership.</p>

<p><strong>CONTEXT</strong></p>

<p>Harris has called for implementing universal background checks and expanding red flag laws to take away guns from people who are deemed dangerous or unstable. She also wants to ban so-called assault weapons and high-capacity magazines.</p>

<p>"I'm a good marksman," Harris said during an onstage Politico interview in 2015 in California after being asked if she'd ever fired a gun. "Yes, I have shot a gun many times," she said, adding that it was a pistol.</p>

<p>Trump's New York concealed carry license was suspended in April 2023 after his criminal indictment, CNN reported. He turned over two of three pistols he owned and the third was moved to Florida, according to the news outlet.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-08/levm1oso_kamala-harris-afp_625x300_20_August_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[In 2019, Kamala Harris told reporters "I am a gun owner".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/brazil-judge-seizes-3-million-from-elon-musk-to-pay-x-fines-6561245]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Brazil Judge Seizes $3 Million From Elon Musk To Pay X Fines]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/brazil-judge-seizes-3-million-from-elon-musk-to-pay-x-fines-6561245]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 14 Sep 2024 05:10:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Brazil's Supreme Court said Friday that a judge has ordered the transfer of some $3 million from Elon Musk's companies to pay fines incurred by his social network X, which has been suspended in the country.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Brazil's Supreme Court said Friday that a judge has ordered the transfer of some $3 million from Elon Musk's companies to pay fines incurred by his social network X, which has been suspended in the country.</p>

<p>Judge Alexandre de Moraes last month ordered X shut down in Brazil after Musk refused to remove dozens of right-wing accounts and then failed to name a new legal representative in the country as ordered.</p>

<p>A brief statement from the court said Moraes had "determined the transfer to state coffers of 18.35 million reais ($3.28 million) blocked in accounts" of X and the satellite internet firm Starlink, both owned by Musk.</p>

<p>Moraes has repeatedly clashed with the South African-born billionaire after making it his mission to crack down on disinformation.</p>

<p>He also froze the assets of X and Starlink, which has been operating in Brazil since 2022 -- especially in remote communities in the Amazon -- to ensure payment of fines imposed on X for its failure to follow court orders.</p>

<p>The social media platform formerly known as Twitter has more than 22 million users in Brazil.</p>

<p>Moraes also ordered that those using "technological subterfuges" such as virtual private networks (VPNs) to access the blocked site could be fined up to $9,000.</p>

<p>His measures have fueled debate on freedom of expression and the limits of social networks both inside and outside of the country.</p>

<p>Leftist President Luiz Inacio Lula da Silva hailed the ban, while his far-right predecessor Jair Bolsonaro called Moraes a "dictator."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/9r47i6pc_elon-musk-ians_625x300_14_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The social media platform formerly known as Twitter has more than 22 million users in Brazil.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-and-kamala-harris-are-against-life-says-pope-francis-6560817]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Choose Lesser Of Two Evils": Pope Francis On Donald Trump, Kamala Harris]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-and-kamala-harris-are-against-life-says-pope-francis-6560817]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 14 Sep 2024 02:30:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Pope Francis said that both sending migrants away and not giving migrants the ability to work or welcoming them is a sin.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pope Francis said Friday that he considered both candidates for the US presidency "against life", citing Donald Trump's anti-immigrant policies and Kamala Harris's support for abortion rights.</p>

<p>"Both are against life. The one who discards migrants and the one who kills children. Both are against life," Francis told reporters aboard his plane returning to Rome after a 12-day tour of Asia.</p>

<p>"I am not an American and I will not be voting there. But let it be clear: both sending migrants away and not giving migrants the ability to work or welcoming them is a sin, it is serious," he said.</p>

<p>Former president Trump has promised to round up illegal immigrants and deport them as he seeks to return to the White House in the looming November election.</p>

<p>He also paved the way for a 2022 US Supreme Court overturning of Roe v Wade, the 1973 ruling that made abortion a national right for women -- a right that Harris has pledged to restore.</p>

<p>"One has to choose the lesser of two evils. Who is the lesser evil? That lady or that gentleman? I don't know. Everyone have to think and make this decision according to their conscience," Francis said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/7uculc6_pope-francis_625x300_06_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Pope Francis said Friday that he considered both candidates for the US presidency "against life".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-kamala-harris-campaign-in-battlegrounds-as-migrant-row-intensifies-6560544]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump, Kamala Harris Campaign In Battlegrounds As Migrant Row Intensifies]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-kamala-harris-campaign-in-battlegrounds-as-migrant-row-intensifies-6560544]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 14 Sep 2024 01:08:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US presidential candidates Donald Trump and Kamala Harris again took their campaigns to battleground states Friday as a racially charged row over Haitian immigrants intensified with the Republican leader promising "large deportations."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US presidential candidates Donald Trump and Kamala Harris again took their campaigns to battleground states Friday as a racially charged row over Haitian immigrants intensified with the Republican leader promising "large deportations."</p>

<p>Trump, 78, was due to hold a rally later Friday in Nevada, where his campaign says he will focus on voters' economic worries, including inflation.</p>

<p>Harris, coming off a strong performance in Tuesday's televised debate against Trump, was headed to Pennsylvania -- arguably the most crucial of the swing states that decide the winner in close presidential elections.</p>

<p>Opinion polls show a near dead heat with only seven weeks until election day.</p>

<p>Stung by widespread agreement, including among some prominent Republicans, that Democrat Harris won Tuesday's debate, Trump is doubling down on harsh rhetoric about illegal immigration -- the issue at the core of his campaign.</p>

<p>In remarks from his luxury golf course near Los Angeles, Trump accused "communist" Harris of "allowing illegal aliens to stampede across our border."</p>

<p>And he homed in on the small Ohio city of Springfield, saying Haitian immigrants there are "destroying their way of life."</p>

<p>"We will do large deportations from Springfield, Ohio," he said. "We're going to have the largest deportation in the history of our country."</p>

<p>Springfield is at the center of swirling conspiracy theory spread by Republicans and Trump's campaign that claims Haitians are eating local residents' pets.</p>

<p>On Friday, Springfield authorities evacuated schools for a second day amid unspecified threats linked to the growing tension.</p>

<p>The head of the local Haitian community center, Viles Dorsainvil, told AFP that the FBI was investigating threatening phone calls to the organization.</p>

<p>Trump magnified the false story about the pets in extended comments Thursday where he claimed park geese were likewise being killed by Haitians -- and told a rally that "young American girls being raped and sodomized and murdered by savage criminal aliens."</p>

<p>President Joe Biden, who dropped out of his own reelection campaign to endorse Harris instead, intervened Friday to say that Trump "has to stop" inflaming tensions, and that "there's no place in America for this."</p>

<p><strong>- Far-right entourage -</strong></p>

<p>There was also mounting controversy over the presence of far-right conspiracy theorist Laura Loomer in Trump's entourage.</p>

<p>She traveled with him to the debate on Tuesday and also accompanied him to Ground Zero on the anniversary of the September 11 attacks -- despite having claimed that the deadliest terrorist attack in US history was an "inside job."</p>

<p>"I don't control Laura, Laura says what she wants," Trump told reporters in Los Angeles.</p>

<p>"Laura has been a supporter of mine," he said, adding that he'd never heard she had spread 9/11 conspiracies.</p>

<p>Loomer has drawn fire from even hard-right Republicans over her comment that Harris, whose mother was Indian, would make the White House "smell like curry."</p>

<p>As November 5 election day rapidly approaches, Trump has been forced to pivot his campaign to fight Harris, rather than Biden, who at 81 was seen by his own Democratic Party as unlikely to win.</p>

<p>Trump's struggles have been increasingly visible, including his televised remarks at the golf course Friday.</p>

<p>He spoke defensively about the polls, which he claimed showed him far ahead, and insisted again that he had dominated Harris at the debate. He has also refused her challenge to hold another debate.</p>

<p>On Thursday, Trump was in the toss-up state of Arizona, while Harris held two rallies in North Carolina, likewise a battleground.</p>

<p><strong>- 'Turn the page' -</strong></p>

<p>Harris, 59, has largely avoided responding directly to Trump's personal attacks, choosing to pitch herself as a leader from a new generation who will end the constant drama and division that characterized Trump's presidency and post-presidential career.</p>

<p>When Trump brought up the false story about pets being eaten by migrants in their debate, she responded by shaking her head disbelievingly.</p>

<p>On Thursday, Harris told rally-goers in North Carolina, "It's time to turn the page."</p>

<p>Despite raising huge amounts of donations and drawing neck-and-neck with Trump in the polls, Harris again insisted Thursday that she still has a lot of work to do.</p>

<p>"We know ours will be a very tight race until the very end. We are the underdog. Let's be clear about that," she said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/lqgn5nn_donald-trump-kamala-harris_625x300_28_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump, during debate with Kamala Harris, claimed that Haitians are eating local residents' pets.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-says-would-order-large-deportations-from-ohio-amid-migrant-row-6560396]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Says Would Order "Large Deportations" From Ohio Amid Migrant Row]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-says-would-order-large-deportations-from-ohio-amid-migrant-row-6560396]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 14 Sep 2024 00:21:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump said Friday that if elected president again he would initiate "large deportations" from the Ohio city that has seen a recent influx of Haitian migrants, whom he has baselessly accused of eating cats and dogs.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump doubled down Friday on his anti-migrant attacks despite facing criticism for amplifying a conspiracy theory targeting Haitian immigrants, as he and election rival Kamala Harris took their presidential campaigns to swing states on opposite sides of the United States.</p>

<p>Trump, 78, promised "large deportations" from the Ohio town at the center of the racially charged row, as the Republican former president prepared to head to a rally in the western battleground of Nevada.</p>

<p>Democratic Vice President Harris, 59, meanwhile hit the stump in Pennsylvania -- arguably the most crucial of the half dozen states that are set to decide a desperately close election on November 5.</p>

<p>Coming off a strong performance in Tuesday's televised debate against Trump, Harris gave her first solo sit-down interview since her nomination to an ABC television affiliate in Philadelphia, the state's largest city.</p>

<p>"I offer a new generation of leadership," Harris said in the interview, as she spelled out her policies on tax cuts and credits for new parents, homeowners and businesses.</p>

<p>Harris also appealed to moderate American voters, telling them she herself is a gun-owner who wants to preserve the right to bear arms while maintaining common-sense gun safety laws.</p>

<p>Later at a raucous rally in Wilkes-Barre, Pennsylvania, she again pushed her economic plans and bashed Trump on his debate performance.</p>

<p><strong>- 'Large deportations' -</strong></p>

<p>Polls show a near dead heat with only seven weeks until election day, in an incredibly dramatic campaign that has seen Harris suddenly replace the aging Joe Biden and Trump survive an assassination attempt.</p>

<p>Stung by widespread agreement that Harris won Tuesday's debate, Trump is stepping up the harsh anti-immigration rhetoric that appeals to his right-wing base.</p>

<p>A day after telling a rally that "young American girls (are) being raped and sodomized and murdered by savage criminal aliens," the billionaire on Friday returned his attention to the small Ohio town of Springfield.</p>

<p>Springfield has gained international attention following a viral conspiracy theory -- quickly debunked by local authorities but pushed by Trump during the debate -- that Haitian immigrants had stolen and eaten residents' cats and dogs.</p>

<p>Amid growing tensions in Springfield, where some 20,000 Haitians have settled in recent years, authorities evacuated schools for a second day over unspecified threats.</p>

<p>Trump claimed Friday that immigrants in Springfield were "destroying their way of life," and pledged to do "large deportations."</p>

<p>"We're going to have the largest deportation in the history of our country," Trump said from his golf club near Los Angeles.</p>

<p>Biden called Friday for Trump to stop inflaming tensions, saying "there's no place in America for this."</p>

<p>Trump's campaign said his rally in Nevada later was due to focus on voters' economic worries, including inflation -- although many of his recent rallies have turned into grievance-filled diatribes.</p>

<p><strong>- 'Lesser of two evils' -</strong></p>

<p>There was also mounting controversy over the presence of far-right conspiracy theorist Laura Loomer in Trump's entourage.</p>

<p>She traveled with him to the debate Tuesday and also accompanied him to Ground Zero on the anniversary of the September 11 attacks -- despite having claimed that the deadliest terrorist attack in US history was an "inside job."</p>

<p>"I don't control Laura, Laura says what she wants," Trump told reporters in Los Angeles, claiming he had never heard she had spread 9/11 conspiracy theories.</p>

<p>Loomer has drawn fire from even hard-right Republicans over her comment that Harris, whose mother was Indian, would make the White House "smell like curry."</p>

<p>Harris's team meanwhile is keen to build on campaign momentum, announcing she will participate in a live-stream rally event with television icon Oprah Winfrey on September 19.</p>

<p>One key issue where Harris landed punches during the debate was abortion, with November being the first presidential election since the US Supreme Court overturned the nationwide right to the procedure.</p>

<p>Pope Francis weighed into the issue on Friday -- equating Harris's support of abortion to Trump's "sin" of turning away migrants.</p>

<p>"One has to choose the lesser of two evils," Francis told reporters.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/hl6ceebk_donald-trump-afp_625x300_06_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-the-lesser-evil-pope-francis-slams-both-kamala-harris-donald-trump-ahead-of-polls-6560172]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Choose Lesser Of Two Evils": Pope Francis On Donald Trump, Kamala Harris]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-the-lesser-evil-pope-francis-slams-both-kamala-harris-donald-trump-ahead-of-polls-6560172]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 13 Sep 2024 23:35:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Pope Francis on Friday criticized both former US President Donald Trump over his plan to deport millions of immigrants and Vice President Kamala Harris over her stance supporting abortion rights.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pope Francis on Friday criticized both former US President Donald Trump over his plan to deport millions of immigrants and Vice President Kamala Harris over her stance supporting abortion rights.</p>

<p>Asked about the US presidential election on his flight back to Rome from Singapore, the pope said not welcoming migrants is a "grave" sin, and likened having an abortion to an "assassination".</p>

<p>He said US Catholics would have to "choose the lesser evil" when they vote in November, without elaborating.</p>

<p>Francis was speaking in a press conference with journalists after a demanding 12-day tour across Southeast Asia and Oceania. Although the pope did not use Trump and Harris' names, he referred specifically to their policies and their genders. Despite criticizing both candidates, he said Catholics should vote.</p>

<p>"Not voting is ugly," the 87-year-old pontiff said. "It is not good. You must vote."</p>

<p>"You must choose the lesser evil," he said. "Who is the lesser evil? That lady, or that gentleman? I don't know. Everyone, in conscience, (has to) think and do this."</p>

<p>American Catholics, numbering roughly 52 million nationwide, are often seen as crucial swing voters. In some battleground states, including Pennsylvania and Wisconsin, more than 20% of adults are Catholic.</p>

<p>Francis, leader of about 1.4 billion Catholics globally, is usually careful about weighing in on national political elections. But he frequently criticizes abortion, which is forbidden by Catholic teaching, in sharp terms. He has also previously criticized Trump's anti-immigrant rhetoric. During the 2016 election, he said Trump was "not Christian" in his views.</p>

<p>On Friday, Francis said both candidates' policies are "against life".</p>

<p>"Whether it is the one who is chasing away migrants or the one who kills children," said the pope. "Both are against life."</p>

<p>Trump has promised to crack down on illegal immigration and deport millions of immigrants already in the US if elected to a second term as president. He has also refused to rule out building detention camps for undocumented immigrants.</p>

<p>Harris has promised to sign any legislation passed by Congress to restore national protections for abortion access, which were struck down by the Supreme Court in its 2022 Dobbs decision.</p>

<p>The two candidates sparred over both issues on Wednesday in their first debate together. Most polls show a tight race, with Harris leading slightly.</p>

<p>The pope called immigration "a right," citing Bible passages that call orphans, widows and foreigners three kinds of people that society must care for. "Not giving welcome to migrants is a sin," said the pope. "It is grave."</p>

<p>Francis said abortion "is killing a human being". He said there could be no excuses for an abortion. "It is an assassination," he said. "On these things, we must speak clearly. No 'but' or 'however'."</p>

<p>Balancing political priorities has become a subject of discussion among the U.S. bishops, who have issued similar election guidance for each presidential cycle since 2007-08, with some updates.</p>

<p>Their latest version, released with a new introduction in November 2023, states that the "threat of abortion" is a "preeminent priority" for Catholics.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/6cergr58_pope-francis-afp-_625x300_03_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[On Friday, Francis said both candidates' policies are against life. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/man-sues-realtors-after-finding-jeff-bezos-bought-his-home-for-a-discounted-price-6560127]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Man Sues Realtors After Finding Jeff Bezos Bought His Home For Less Price]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/man-sues-realtors-after-finding-jeff-bezos-bought-his-home-for-a-discounted-price-6560127]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 13 Sep 2024 23:29:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Brazilian businessman, Leo Kryss, has filed a lawsuit against realtor Douglas Elliman, alleging he was misled into selling his Miami Beach mansion for $6 million less to Amazon founder Jeff Bezos.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Brazilian businessman alleges a realtor deceived him into selling his Miami Beach mansion for $6 million lower than its true worth to Amazon Boss Jeff Bezos and is now suing him, according to a lawsuit reported reported by <em>The Wall Street Journal.</em> Leo Kryss, one of the founders of the Brazilian toy and electronics company Tectoy, claims the real estate company Douglas Elliman told him that a prospective buyer for his house in exclusive Indian Creek Village won't pay more than $79 million. Mr Kryss had listed the seven-bedroom, 11 1/2-bathroom mansion, covering 19,000 square feet, for $85 million.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Now Kryss is suing Elliman for the $6 million he believes he forfeited by not realizing Bezos was the buyer, according to people familiar with the matter, according to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.wsj.com/real-estate/luxury-homes/jeff-bezos-indian-creek-home-lawsuit-3403cdc7?mod=hp_trending_now_article_pos5"><em>The WSJ.</em></a></p>

<p>The lawsuit filed in July by Kryss said that he asked Douglas Elliman CEO Jay Parker if the interested buyer was the world's second richest man, Amazon founder Jeff Bezos. Parker allegedly let him know that Bezos had nothing to do with it. Later on, in fact, Kryss would agree to sell the mansion for $79 million, unconscious of the fact that Bezos was indeed the buyer, according to the complaint.</p>

<p>The legal dispute highlights the significance of transparency in high-profile real estate deals. At the moment, Kryss is suing them over fraud allegations by the real estate firm.</p>

<p>"Wealthy individuals often shield their identities throughout the process of purchasing a home, from the initial showing through the closing," Miami real estate agent Danny Hertzberg told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.wsj.com/real-estate/luxury-homes/jeff-bezos-indian-creek-home-lawsuit-3403cdc7?mod=hp_trending_now_article_pos5"><em>WSJ</em></a>. "Many billionaires, when they're purchasing a property, are concerned that when the seller knows their identity, they're going to want a larger number," he said.</p>

<p>In February of last year, Bezos announced his move to Miami from Seattle. He now owns more than four bayfront acres on Indian Creek Island, a gated community sometimes referred to as the Billionaire Bunker. The island has drawn well-known residents, including Tom Brady, Jared Kushner, and Ivanka Trump.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-01/505ne8r8_jeff-bezos-lauren-sanchez_625x300_28_January_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kryss claims he was falsely informed that Amazon founder Jeff Bezos was not the buyer.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/49-ukrainian-prisoners-of-war-return-from-russia-zelensky-6560097]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[49 Ukrainian Prisoners Of War Return From Russia: Zelensky]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/49-ukrainian-prisoners-of-war-return-from-russia-zelensky-6560097]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 13 Sep 2024 23:23:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky announced Friday that 49 Ukrainian POWs had been returned from Russia, with news agency AFP witnessing the group being greeted at the border with Belarus.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky announced Friday that 49 Ukrainian POWs had been returned from Russia, with AFP witnessing the group being greeted at the border with Belarus.</p>

<p>Zelensky did not clarify whether it was part of an exchange with Russia, as is usually the case, but AFP journalists had earlier seen Russian prisoners of war being loaded onto a bus near the border.</p>

<p>It would be the second exchange between the warring countries since Kyiv's surprise incursion into Russia's Kursk region.</p>

<p>Zelensky said civilians were also among the returnees, including a "girl who was taken hostage when she came to take care of her sick father".</p>

<p>He said the exchange also included fighters from Mariupol's 2022 Azovstal battle, as well as soldiers, border guards and police officers.</p>

<p>AFP spoke to two women in their 20s wrapped in Ukrainian flags and receiving flowers, who said they were at the Azovstal plant that fell to Russia after a siege in 2022.</p>

<p>"I'm finally home, I can't believe it," said 28-year-old Tamara Miroshnikova, commander of an armed vehicle of Ukraine's National Guard, said.</p>

<p>Another woman, 29-year-old Tetiana Bugay, said she was a medic at the Azov brigade that fought for Azovstal.</p>

<p>Earlier, AFP saw the Ukrainian military driving Russian POWs in a bus, some were wearing hoods hiding their faces, which were removed as they were loaded into a minivan.</p>

<p>AFP spoke to some of them briefly, and all those who spoke said they were taken captive during Ukraine's surprise Kursk offensive last month.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/qcc3qau8_zelensky-reuters_625x300_11_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Volodymyr Zelensky said civilians were also among the returnees. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/brazil-court-lifts-starlink-x-account-blockage-after-3-million-transfer-6560063]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Brazil Court Lifts Starlink, X Account Blockage After $3 Million Transfer]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/brazil-court-lifts-starlink-x-account-blockage-after-3-million-transfer-6560063]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 13 Sep 2024 23:18:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Brazil's Supreme Court Justice Alexandre de Moraes decided to lift blockages previously imposed on Starlink and X accounts after ordering the transfer of 18.35 million reais ($3.31 million) from the accounts to the country's national coffers.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Brazil's Supreme Court Justice Alexandre de Moraes decided to lift blockages previously imposed on Starlink and X accounts after ordering the transfer of 18.35 million reais ($3.31 million) from the accounts to the country's national coffers.</p>

<p>According to a court statement on Friday, the lift was ordered because the amount transferred to Brazil's coffers reached the total X owed the country in fines, which had been imposed amid a feud between billionaire Elon Musk and Moraes.</p>

<p>Elon Musk controls both X and Starlink.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/5g0r9d7_x-generic_625x300_07_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Elon Musk controls both X and Starlink. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/justin-timberlake-given-community-service-in-drunk-driving-case-report-6560033]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Justin Timberlake Given Community Service In Drink Driving Case: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/justin-timberlake-given-community-service-in-drunk-driving-case-report-6560033]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 13 Sep 2024 23:15:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Pop star Justin Timberlake was handed a sentence of community service on Friday after he changed his plea to guilty following his arrest for drink driving, US media reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pop star Justin Timberlake was handed a sentence of community service on Friday after he changed his plea to guilty following his arrest for drink driving, US media reported.</p>

<p>On June 18, the 43-year-old entertainer was pulled over in the town of Sag Harbor, about 100 miles (160 kilometers) east of New York City, after police observed his BMW go through a stop sign and struggle to stay within road lanes.</p>

<p>Sag Harbor Village Justice Court justice Carl Irace handed Timberlake a community service sentence and ordered the star to make a public statement after the 43-year-old pleaded guilty to a lesser charge of driving while alcohol impaired, The New York Post reported.</p>

<p>The officer who pulled over the "Cry Me a River" singer said he was in no fit state to drive.</p>

<p>"His eyes were bloodshot and glassy, a strong odor of an alcoholic beverage was emanating from his breath, he was unable to divide attention, he had slowed speech, he was unsteady afoot, and he performed poorly on all standardized field sobriety tests," the police report said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/njrmgi08_justin-timberlake_625x300_19_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The officer who pulled over the "Cry Me a River" singer said he was in no fit state to drive. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/alleged-mexican-drug-lord-el-mayo-pleads-not-guilty-to-drug-trafficking-charges-in-us-court-6559992]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Alleged Mexican Drug Lord Pleads Not Guilty To Drug Trafficking Charges]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/alleged-mexican-drug-lord-el-mayo-pleads-not-guilty-to-drug-trafficking-charges-in-us-court-6559992]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 13 Sep 2024 23:10:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The co-founder of the deadly Mexican Sinaloa cartel, Ismael Zambada, appeared in court in Brooklyn Friday, pleading not guilty to a raft of charges following his arrest in a dramatic sting by US agents.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The accused Mexican kingpin Ismael "El Mayo" Zambada pleaded not guilty to drug trafficking charges on Friday in the same New York courthouse where fellow Sinaloa cartel co-founder Joaquin "El Chapo" Guzman was convicted five years earlier.</p>

<p>Zambada entered the plea to the 17 felony counts he faces, which also include money laundering and weapons charges, at a hearing before U.S. Magistrate Judge James Cho in Brooklyn.</p>

<p>Cho ordered that Zambada, 76, be jailed pending trial.</p>

<p>Prosecutor Francisco Navarro called Zambada "one of the most, if not the most, powerful narcotics kingpins in the world."</p>

<p>"A United States jail cell is the only thing that will prevent the defendant from committing further crimes and ensure his return to court," Navarro told the hearing.</p>

<p>Defense lawyer Frank Perez did not object to prosecutors' request to jail Zambada.</p>

<p>Wearing a gray short-sleeve shirt, Zambada did not speak other than to answer "yes" or "no" to the judge's questions through an interpreter.</p>

<p>Zambada was taken into custody on July 25 at a New Mexico airfield along with one of Guzman's sons, Joaquin Guzman Lopez, in a major coup for U.S. law enforcement.</p>

<p>He was then taken to El Paso, Texas, where he pleaded not guilty in federal court to separate drug trafficking charges.</p>

<p>U.S. District Judge Kathleen Cardone last week had him transferred to Brooklyn after the U.S. Department of Justice asked that he face trial there first.</p>

<p>Zambada was wheelchair bound for his first court appearance in El Paso, but walked on his own on Friday.</p>

<p>"His health is very good," Perez told reporters after the hearing.</p>

<p>The Brooklyn case began in 2009 and includes allegations related to the trafficking of fentanyl, a synthetic opioid fueling an epidemic in the United States.</p>

<p>Zambada is next due in court on Oct. 31.</p>

<p>"El Chapo" Guzman is serving a life sentence at a maximum security prison in Colorado. His son has pleaded not guilty to drug trafficking charges in Chicago.</p>

<p>Shootouts this week in the western Mexican state of Sinaloa kindled fears that an intra-cartel war is about to break out following Zambada's arrest.</p>

<p>Fighting has killed 12 people since Monday, and on Thursday state authorities canceled national day celebrations and shut schools in response to the escalating violence.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/loklksjo_el-mayo-sketch_625x300_13_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Defense lawyer Frank Perez did not object to prosecutors' request to jail Zambada. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-us-citizens-sentenced-to-death-in-congo-over-role-in-failed-coup-6559913]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[3 US Citizens Sentenced To Death In Congo Over Role In Failed Coup]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-us-citizens-sentenced-to-death-in-congo-over-role-in-failed-coup-6559913]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 13 Sep 2024 22:51:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Three U.S. citizens on trial for their role in a failed coup in Democratic Republic of Congo were sentenced to death by a military court on Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Three U.S. citizens on trial for their role in a failed coup in Democratic Republic of Congo were sentenced to death by a military court on Friday.</p>

<p>Armed men briefly occupied an office of the presidency in the capital Kinshasa on May 19 before their leader, U.S.-based Congolese politician Christian Malanga, was killed by security forces.</p>

<p>His son, Marcel Malanga, was among the Americans on trial, along with Marcel's friend Tyler Thompson who played high school football with him in Utah. Both are in their 20s.</p>

<p>The third American, Benjamin Zalman-Polun, was a business associate of Christian Malanga.</p>

<p>All three were found guilty of criminal conspiracy, terrorism and other charges, and sentenced to death in a ruling read out on live TV.</p>

<p>Malanga had previously told the court that his father had threatened to kill him unless he participated. He also told the court it was his first time visiting Congo at the invitation of his father, whom he hadn't seen in years.</p>

<p>The Americans are among around 50 people, including U.S., British, Canadian, Belgian and Congolese citizens, standing trial following the failed coup.</p>

<p>The verdict was read out under a tent in the yard of Ndolo military prison on the outskirts of Kinshasa. The defendants were seated in front of the judge, wearing blue and yellow prison-issued tops.</p>

<p>The trial began in July.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/h3ejmp0o_court-generic_625x300_02_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Americans are among around 50 people standing trial following the failed coup. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>