<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Sat, 10 Aug 2024 22:29:23 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-polls-give-kamala-harris-lead-over-donald-trump-in-3-key-states-6309307]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[New Polls Give Kamala Harris Lead Over Donald Trump In 3 Key States]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-polls-give-kamala-harris-lead-over-donald-trump-in-3-key-states-6309307]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 10 Aug 2024 21:34:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kamala Harris now leads Donald Trump in three crucial battleground states, according to new polls published Saturday, apparently eroding the advantage the former president has enjoyed there over the past year.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kamala Harris now leads Donald Trump in three crucial battleground states, according to new polls published Saturday, apparently eroding the advantage the former president has enjoyed there over the past year.</p>

<p>The polls of likely voters by The New York Times and Siena College showed Harris leading Trump by an identical 50 percent to 46 per cent margin in Michigan, Pennsylvania and Wisconsin.</p>

<p>Under the US Electoral College voting system, those three populous Midwestern states are considered key to victory for either party.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The polls are a reversal of surveys in those states which for nearly a year had shown Trump either tied with or slightly leading Democratic President Joe Biden, who dropped out of the race last month and endorsed Harris instead.</p>

<p>Much can change in the nearly three months before the November 5 election. The polling showed voters still prefer Trump on the key issues of the economy and immigration, though Harris had a 24-point advantage when voters were asked whom they trust on the issue of abortion.</p>

<p>Democrats, in any case, have taken heart in the surge of enthusiasm that has greeted Harris's candidacy, with many expressing relief after 81-year-old Biden stepped aside.</p>

<p>Her announcement Tuesday of Minnesota Governor Tim Walz as her running mate also appears to have energized Democrats.</p>

<p>The Harris-Walz surge helped cut short a rise in support for Trump that followed the July 13 attempt on his life and the Republicans' successful national convention last month.</p>

<p>But Harris has enjoyed an even bigger bump in favorability -- up 10 points among registered voters in Pennsylvania in just a month, the Times/Siena polling found.</p>

<p>Voters said they saw her as more intelligent than Trump and having a better temperament to govern.</p>

<p>Trump, his running mate J.D. Vance and other Republicans have tried an array of attacks meant to weaken Harris -- with Trump even questioning her racial identity.</p>

<p>But the new polls show Democrats strongly supporting the younger and more vigorous Harris who, with Walz, has been campaigning at a furious pace this week in swing states.</p>

<p>Among Democrats, voter satisfaction with their choice of candidates has shot up by 27 points in the three Midwestern states since May, the polls found.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Three months ago, it was Republicans who expressed a higher level of satisfaction.</p>

<p>The surveys were conducted between August 5 and 9, with at least 600 voters in each state.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/06lu95io_kamala-harris-donald-trump-afp_625x300_03_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The surveys were conducted between August 5 and 9, with at least 600 voters in each state.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/travis-scott-released-from-custody-after-fight-outside-hotel-in-paris-6309191]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Travis Scott Released From Custody After Fight Outside Hotel In Paris]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/travis-scott-released-from-custody-after-fight-outside-hotel-in-paris-6309191]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 10 Aug 2024 21:16:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[French police on Saturday released US star rapper Travis Scott after 36 hours in custody in Paris over suspected violence, a US-based representative for the artist and prosecutors said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>French police on Saturday released US star rapper Travis Scott after 36 hours in custody in Paris over suspected violence, a US-based representative for the artist and prosecutors said.</p>

<p>The 33-year-old, who has had multiple nominations for Grammy Awards, was arrested after fighting with one of his own security guards at a five-star hotel in Paris.</p>

<p>"Travis Scott has been released with no charges," the representative said.</p>

<p>The Paris prosecutor's office confirmed the "release from custody of Travis Scott today as well as the dropping of the case over the offence being insufficiently established".</p>

<p>Police had been called to the Georges V hotel early on Friday, where they arrested the rapper for "violence against a security agent" who had intervened to separate the artist from his bodyguard, the prosecutor's office had said.</p>

<p>A US representative for Scott had said later that evening that management was in "direct communication with Parisian authorities to swiftly resolve" the matter.</p>

<p>Mr Scott was seen attending the Olympics men's basketball semi-finals on Thursday evening.</p>

<p>The rapper, whose real name is Jacques Bermon Webster II, has had previous brushes with the law in the United States.</p>

<p>The music star was arrested in Miami Beach in June for trespassing and disorderly intoxication. Police said he was involved in a fight on a yacht.</p>

<p>In November 2021, 10 people were killed in a crush at his show at a pop festival in his home city of Houston, Texas.</p>

<p>But he continues to be a prolific songwriter and producer. Scott's "Utopia" was a nominee for Best Rap Album at this year's Grammy Awards. And he has merchandising deals with Nike, video game maker Epic Games and McDonald's fast food chain.</p>

<p>Scott has two children with social media influencer and entrepreneur Kylie Jenner.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-08/nt0l9mq_travis-scott_625x300_11_August_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["Travis Scott has been released with no charges," the representative said.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-evacuates-76-000-from-kursk-after-ukraines-incursion-report-6309055]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russia Evacuates 76,000 From Kursk After Ukraine's Incursion: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-evacuates-76-000-from-kursk-after-ukraines-incursion-report-6309055]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 10 Aug 2024 20:51:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[More than 76,000 people have been evacuated from areas bordering Ukraine in Russia's Kursk region.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>More than 76,000 people have been evacuated from areas bordering Ukraine in Russia's Kursk region, the local emergency ministry was quoted by the Tass news agency as saying on Saturday, following Ukraine's incursion into the region this week.</p>

<p>Russia is fighting intense battles against thousands of Ukrainian troops as deep as 20 km (12 miles) inside the Kursk region after Ukraine's biggest attack on Russian sovereign territory since the start of the war in 2022.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/qgiuid7o_russia-strike-on-ukraine-tank_625x300_10_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A Russian army strike on a Ukrainian tank]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/children-torn-apart-israel-strike-mosque-school-in-gaza-93-killed-6308722]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Children Torn Apart": Israel Strike Mosque, School In Gaza, 93 Killed]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/children-torn-apart-israel-strike-mosque-school-in-gaza-93-killed-6308722]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 10 Aug 2024 19:53:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[White body bags littered the floor and mourning filled the air after a school housing displaced Palestinians was struck with Israeli missiles Saturday -- a horrific and increasingly common sight in the Gaza war.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>White body bags littered the floor and mourning filled the air after a school housing displaced Palestinians was struck with Israeli missiles Saturday -- a horrific and increasingly common sight in the Gaza war.</p>

<p>Dawn prayers were shattered by the early morning triple air strike from Israeli warplanes, which gutted Al-Tabieen religious school and mosque in Gaza City.</p>

<p>In the hellish aftermath, body parts were strewn around the rubble and charred, bloodied bodies slumped in the wreckage of the two-storey complex.</p>

<p>Grim-faced volunteers piled corpses in blood-stained blankets into an ambulance, as seriously wounded men lay groaning on the ground.</p>

<p>Gaza's civil defence agency said at least 93 people were killed, 17 of them women and children, making it one of the war's deadliest strikes.</p>

<p>Israel's military disputed the death toll, saying the school was targeted with "precision munitions" because it "served as an active Hamas and Islamic Jihad military facility".</p>

<p>Such incidents have become a pattern in recent weeks. According to an AFP tally, at least 14 schools sheltering Gaza's displaced have been hit since July 6, killing more than 280 people.</p>

<p>"Peaceful people -- women, children, and youths -- were performing the Fajr prayer as usual when suddenly a missile hit them," said Abu Wassim, who lives nearby and came to survey the scene.</p>

<p>"They were reduced to remains. Children were torn apart, and women were burned. What can we say or do? What is in our power?"</p>

<p><strong>- 'They were just praying' -</strong></p>

<p>As the sun climbed and mourners gathered, one man stroked the face of a dead child shrouded in a plastic body bag.</p>

<p>"They dropped a missile on them while they were just praying. Fear God, people! Fear God, Arabs!" a woman wailed over the body.</p>

<p>Another man looked lost as he held a small corpse wrapped in a blanket. Nearby, six body bags lay on the ground, three of them children. Tattered Korans were piled on a window ledge.</p>

<p>"We woke up before dawn to the sound of a strike," said Sakr, a resident from the neighbourhood who gave just one name.</p>

<p>"We headed to the site and found body remains of civilians who were peacefully performing prayers. We found bodies of children scattered in the street."</p>

<p>Another man said: "You can't even recognise the bodies, there were scattered remains.</p>

<p>"The ones who were struck are displaced people taking shelter in a school. What's their fault? What have they done wrong?"</p>

<p>Mohammad Al-Mughayyir, director of the supply and equipment department of Gaza's civil defence service, told AFP that six schools in Gaza City had been targeted in the past week alone.</p>

<p>Israeli military spokesperson Lieutenant-Colonel Nadav Shoshani said that about 20 Hamas and Islamic militants were operating from the Al-Tabieen complex.</p>

<p>"The compound, and the mosque that was struck within it, served as an active Hamas and Islamic Jihad military facility," he posted on X.</p>

<p>Later on Saturday, Gaza civil defence agency spokesman Mahmud Bassal told journalists that the strike "directly targeted" two floors of the school.</p>

<p>The strike hit "the upper floor housing women and children and the ground floor that was used for prayers by the displaced people," he said.</p>

<p>The Gaza war was triggered by Hamas's October 7 attack that resulted in the deaths of 1,198 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli official figures.</p>

<p>Palestinian militants seized 251 hostages, 111 of whom are still held in Gaza, including 39 the Israeli military says are dead.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory military campaign in Gaza has killed at least 39,790 people, according to the health ministry in Hamas-run Gaza, which does not give details of civilian and militant deaths.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/rnicl03_gaza-attack_625x300_10_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Grim-faced volunteers piled corpses in blood-stained blankets into an ambulances.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-mirza-fakhrul-islam-alamgir-sheikh-hasina-was-given-2-choices-be-mobbed-or-leave-key-bangladesh-leader-6308660]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[No Agenda, Some Taking Advantage: Key Bangladesh Leader On Attacks On Hindus]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-mirza-fakhrul-islam-alamgir-sheikh-hasina-was-given-2-choices-be-mobbed-or-leave-key-bangladesh-leader-6308660]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 10 Aug 2024 19:50:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A week of fast-paced developments in Bangladesh, which saw Sheikh Hasina's ouster, widespread violence and the formation of an interim government, has been capped off with the country's chief justice agreeing to step down on Saturday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A week of fast-paced developments in Bangladesh, which saw Sheikh Hasina's ouster, widespread violence and the formation of an interim government, has been capped off with the country's chief justice agreeing to step down on Saturday. While it is unclear when elections will be held, what is certain is that the Khaleda Zia-led Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP), one of the two big political parties in the country, will be playing a key role in them.</p>

<p>Speaking exclusively to NDTV on Saturday, Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir, the general secretary of the BNP, said that the stepping down of the chief justice was brought about by student protests because he was known to be closely associated with Ms Hasina's regime, which "killed many people" in the country.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/4l797np_mirza-fakhrul-islam-alamgir_625x300_10_August_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>In the wide-ranging interview, Mr Alamgir said that Ms Zia will lead the BNP in the elections if she is fit enough to do so and that the party would work to improve the India-Bangladesh relationship if it comes to power. He said that the attacks on Hindus in the country were a result of some people trying to take advantage of the situation and stressed that they were not part of any "systematic agenda".</p>

<p>The BNP leader also said he believes that the Bangladesh army will not interfere in the political process going forward and also claimed that no extremist elements were involved in the protests.</p>

<p>Asked about the chief justice stepping down, Mr Alamgir said, "The chief justice is known here as an associate of the former regime, which killed so many people in this country and extraordinary, unprecedented corruption was done during this period... So there was always a demand for his removal. He was not exactly free, fair and neutral and that's why the demand was very high."</p>

<p>"The judiciary in Bangladesh has totally been destroyed. It is an institution but, with the help of the last regime, it was totally politicised," he added.</p>

<p><strong>Election Timeframe?</strong></p>

<p>While Nobel laureate Muhammad Yunus has taken oath as the head of an interim government and is seen as popular among the movement that led to Ms Hasina being ousted, the question on everyone's mind is when elections will be held again in Bangladesh.</p>

<p>When Mr Alamgir was asked about this and the role 78-year-old Khaleda Zia, who was released from prison this week, would be able to play in the elections, he said, "She's very sick. She's in the hospital. She's suffering from multidisciplinary diseases. Her treatment was not going well in this country and we we requested the judiciary as well as the government several times to send her abroad, but that didn't happen... Doctors say she's not fit to travel right now and we will have to wait for some time before taking her outside the country. If she's physically fit, she will definitely contest the election."</p>

<p>The BNP leader said that while his party is ready for polls at any point, the interim government would need more time to conduct them.</p>

<p>"The entire election machinery has become totally polluted and they are not in a position to hold a free-and-fair election. So they will have to bring some reforms in the election system as well," he said.</p>

<p>Mr Alamgir also rubbished a claim made by Sheikh Hasina's son, Sajeeb Wazed, that the prime minister had not resigned, as well as reports that she was removed at gunpoint.</p>

<p>"The President himself, in the presence of political parties and the army, said she had resigned. There was no coercion or anything... It was a revolution. When the mob of lakhs of people was moving towards Ms Hasina's residence, her security forces and the armed forces told her she had two choices: stay here and be mobbed or leave the country. And, at the last moment, she decided to leave the country,"she said.</p>

<p><strong>Ties With India, Attacks On Minorities</strong></p>

<p>Mr Alamgir emphasised that the India-Bangladesh relationship would continue to be sound and said the BNP would strive to improve it if it came to power.</p>

<p>When the leader was asked about attacks on minorities in the country, including Hindus, Buddhists and Christians, and whether there was a systemic attack, he said, "This is not at all true. When there is a change in our country or any country, especially in third-world countries, there are some people who try to take advantage... In Bangladesh, unfortunately, with every revolution, leaders of the incumbent party are victimised, whether they are Muslims or Hindus. There may be some sporadic attacks (on minorities) but it was not at all a political or systematic agenda. Never," he said, claiming that communal harmony in the country is "superb".</p>

<p><strong>UN Involvement</strong></p>

<p>When the BNP leader was asked whether there would be a vendetta against the supporters of Ms Hasina's Party - the Awami League - or a purge of former army and police officers seen as close to her government, he said that the United Nations has been asked to conduct an investigation.</p>

<p>"If anybody is found guilty of violating human rights, systematic killing of the opposition or enforced disappearances, naturally, their cases will be investigated and they'll be taken to task," he said.</p>

<p>Mr Alamgir also said that he did not believe that there would be any interference from the army in the political process going forward.</p>

<p>"People have confidence in the army that they are the saviours of the country. So I don't think they will do anything which will go against the will of the people," he said.</p>

<p><strong>Extremist Elements?</strong></p>

<p>The violence in the country has died down to a large extent, Mr Alamgir said, and sought to allay fears of extremist elements being involved in the movement against Ms Hasina's rule.</p>

<p>"The Jamaat (Jamaat-e-Islami) is not an extremist political party, but there were other extremist groups in Bangladesh and I don't believe they are in existence now... Extremist elements are not involved (in protests) in any way. Not at all. It is totally (led by) students and most of them are very progressive elements. Some of the people leading the movement are extraordinarily talented. I am certain and I believe that this revolution will definitely succeed," he added.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/544ou8fg_bangladeshihindus_625x300_10_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mr Alamgir said that the India-Bangladesh relationship would continue to be sound.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/when-ex-youtube-ceo-susan-wojcicki-took-sundar-pichai-for-an-ice-cream-6308324]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[When Ex-YouTube CEO Susan Wojcicki Took Sundar Pichai For An Ice Cream]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/when-ex-youtube-ceo-susan-wojcicki-took-sundar-pichai-for-an-ice-cream-6308324]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 10 Aug 2024 18:46:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Alphabet and Google CEO Sundar Pichai has revealed that former YouTube CEO Susan Wojcicki, who passed away after two years of living with lung cancer, once took him for an ice cream and a walk around campus during his Google interview 20 years ago.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Alphabet and Google CEO Sundar Pichai has revealed that former YouTube CEO Susan Wojcicki, who passed away after two years of living with lung cancer, once took him for an ice cream and a walk around campus during his Google interview 20 years ago.</p>

<p>Remembering the days when he joined Google, Mr Pichai said he was so fortunate to have spent so many years working with Susan closely.</p>

<p>"Susan always put others first, both in her values and in the day to day. I'll never forget her kindness to me as a prospective 'Noogler' 20 years ago," Mr Pichai wrote.</p>

<p>He further said: "I was sold - on Google and Susan. She was absolutely loved by her teams. Her time on earth was far too short, but she made every minute count".</p>

<p>Mr Pichai termed Susan's loss as devastating for "all of us who know and love her, for the thousands of Googlers she led over the years, and for millions of people all over the world who looked up to her" as she created incredible things at Google, YouTube and beyond.</p>

<p>Susan was one of Google's earliest employees and had received a 'Google Founders Award' for making AdSense, which helped tremendously in Google's advertising. Her tenure as CEO of YouTube saw the platform's growth into a global powerhouse, impacting millions of content creators and billions of viewers.</p>

<p>Mr Pichai said that Susan's journey, from the garage she rented to Larry Page and Sergey Brin (Google founders) to leading teams across consumer products and building Ads business to becoming the CEO of YouTube, one of the world's most significant platforms, "is inspiring by any measure".</p>

<p>But she didn't stop there. As one of the earliest Googlers -- and the first to take maternity leave -- Susan used her position to build a better workplace for everyone.</p>

<p>In the years that followed, her advocacy around parental leave set a new standard for businesses everywhere. Susan was also deeply passionate about education.</p>

<p>Over the last two years, Susan devoted herself to making the world better through her philanthropy, including supporting research for the disease that ultimately took her life.</p>

<p>"I know that was very meaningful to her and I'm so glad she took the time to do it," said Pichai, adding that let's honour Susan's memory by continuing to build a Google she would be proud of.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/rman2lho_susan-wojcicki_625x300_10_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["Susan always put others first, both in her values and in the day to day," Sundar Pichai wrote]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korea-is-launching-more-trash-filled-balloons-southward-south-korea-6308142]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[North Korea Is Launching More Trash-Filled Balloons Southward: South Korea]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korea-is-launching-more-trash-filled-balloons-southward-south-korea-6308142]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 10 Aug 2024 18:13:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[North Korea is launching more balloons believed to be carrying trash southward, South Korea's military said Saturday, the latest in a series of border barrages that have ignited a tit-for-tat propaganda war.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>North Korea is launching more balloons believed to be carrying trash southward, South Korea's military said Saturday, the latest in a series of border barrages that have ignited a tit-for-tat propaganda war.</p>

<p>North Korea has sent thousands of trash-filled balloons southward since May, saying they are retaliation for propaganda balloons launched by South Korean activists.</p>

<p>The latest launch comes as relations between the two Koreas are at one of their lowest points in years, with the North recently announcing the deployment of 250 ballistic missile launchers to its southern border.</p>

<p>The nuclear-armed North was "again launching (suspected) trash balloons aimed at the South," Seoul's Joint Chiefs of Staff said in a statement late Saturday.&nbsp;</p>

<p>It advised the public to refrain from touching the balloons and to report them to authorities.</p>

<p>Last month, balloons launched by Pyongyang hit the South Korean presidential compound in the capital, prompting the government to mobilise chemical response teams to collect them.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In response to the balloon barrages, Seoul has resumed propaganda broadcasts along the frontier, suspended a tension-reducing military deal and restarted live-fire drills in some border areas.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The isolated North is extremely sensitive about its people's exposure to South Korean pop culture. According to a recent South Korean government report, a man was executed in 2022 for possession of content from the South.</p>

<p>On Thursday, Seoul's military said a suspected North Korean had defected to the South across a de facto maritime border in the Yellow Sea, with some experts suggesting the decision may have been influenced by the South's resumed propaganda broadcasts, which include news reports as well as K-pop content.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/7c3de5f8_north-korea-trash-balloons_625x300_24_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[It advised the public to refrain from touching the balloons.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/japanese-urged-to-avoid-panic-buying-after-megaquake-fear-spreads-6307649]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Japanese Urged To Avoid Panic Buying After Megaquake Fear Spreads]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/japanese-urged-to-avoid-panic-buying-after-megaquake-fear-spreads-6307649]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 10 Aug 2024 16:58:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Authorities in Japan urged people to avoid hoarding as anxiety over a possible megaquake triggered a spike Saturday in demand for disaster kits and daily necessities.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Authorities in Japan urged people to avoid hoarding as anxiety over a possible megaquake triggered a spike Saturday in demand for disaster kits and daily necessities.</p>

<p>In its first such advisory, the weather agency said a huge earthquake was more likely in the aftermath of a magnitude 7.1 jolt in the south on Thursday which left 14 people injured.</p>

<p>At a Tokyo supermarket on Saturday, a sign was put up apologising to customers for shortages of certain products it attributed to "quake-related media reports".</p>

<p>"Potential sales restrictions are on the way", the sign said, adding bottled water was already being rationed due to "unstable" procurement.</p>

<p>On Saturday morning the website of Japanese e-commerce giant Rakuten showed portable toilets, preserved food and bottled water topping the list of the most sought-after items.</p>

<p>In Tokyo, some residents were ramping up their disaster preparedness.</p>

<p>Bar employee Kokoro Takeuchi said she had ordered bottled water online following Thursday's tremor.</p>

<p>"I'm very worried," the 27-year-old told AFP.</p>

<p>"The bar I work at is underground so if a quake happens all of a sudden, there's a good chance we might not be able to escape. So I've been trying to figure out how best to evacuate," she said.</p>

<p>But others were more resigned to the inevitability of the megaquake.</p>

<p>"I am worried of course, but overthinking about it will get you nowhere", company worker Mika Nakagawa, 34, told AFP.</p>

<p>"If it happens, then that's that," she said.</p>

<p>Some retailers along the Pacific coastline also reported similar disaster-related supplies in high demand, according to local media reports.</p>

<p>The advisory concerns the Nankai Trough "subduction zone" between two tectonic plates in the Pacific Ocean, where massive earthquakes have hit in the past.</p>

<p>- Low risk -</p>

<p>It has been the site of destructive quakes of magnitude eight or nine every century or two, with the central government previously estimating the next big one would strike over the next 30 years roughly with a 70 percent probability.</p>

<p>Experts however emphasise the risk, while elevated, is still low, and the agriculture and fisheries ministry urged people "to refrain from excessively hoarding goods".</p>

<p>A magnitude-5.3 tremor rocked the Kanagawa region near Tokyo Friday, triggering emergency alarms on mobile phones and briefly suspending bullet train operations.</p>

<p>Most seismologists believe the Friday jolt had no direct link to the Nankai Trough megaquake, citing distance.</p>

<p>On social media platform X, spam posts taking advantage of fears over the megaquake are rapidly mushrooming.</p>

<p>Public broadcaster NHK said spam disguised as helpful quake-related tips was being posted every few seconds on X, with links that instead direct users toward porn or e-commerce sites.</p>

<p>Such posts are "making it increasingly difficult for users to reach genuine information about quakes", NHK said.</p>

<p>Sitting on top of four major tectonic plates, the Japanese archipelago of 125 million people sees some 1,500 quakes every year, most of them minor.</p>

<p>On January 1, a 7.6-sized jolt and powerful aftershocks hit the Noto Peninsula on the Sea of Japan coast, killing at least 318 people, toppling buildings and knocking out roads.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/llskot2g_japan-_625x300_10_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[In Tokyo, some residents were ramping up their disaster preparedness.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-protests-after-sheikh-hasinas-exit-chief-justice-and-governor-also-resign-all-you-need-to-know-6307598]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What Happened In Bangladesh After Sheikh Hasina's Resignation - A Timeline]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-protests-after-sheikh-hasinas-exit-chief-justice-and-governor-also-resign-all-you-need-to-know-6307598]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 10 Aug 2024 16:49:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Days after Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina's resignation as Bangladesh Prime Minister, the country's Chief Justice Obaidul Hassan also agreed to vacate his post "in principle".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Days after Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina's resignation as Bangladesh Prime Minister, the country's Chief Justice Obaidul Hassan also agreed to vacate his post "in principle". The decision came after the protestors gathered outside the court in the capital Dhaka and demanded the resignation of Hassan and the justices of the Appellate Division.</p>

<p>Mr Hassan, appointed last year, was considered loyal to ousted PM Sheikh Hasina, who fled the country on Monday and has since been sheltering in New Delhi.</p>

<p>Mr Hassan will be tendering his resignation after consulting President Mohammed Shahabuddin this evening, Dhaka Tribune reported, adding that Army personnel were stationed in the main and annexe building as well as other areas around the Supreme Court as they urged hundreds of protesters gathered there to maintain peace.</p>

<p>Obaidul Hassan earlier oversaw the much-criticised war crimes tribunal, which ordered the execution of Sheikh Hasina's opponents. His brother was her longtime secretary.</p>

<p>More than 450 people have been killed so far in the student-led protests that started in July against quotas in government jobs before they also started calling for Hasina's resignation.</p>

<p>Post Hasina's sudden resignation, some of the top appointees, including the central bank governor and the national police chief, were forced out of office, AFP reported.</p>

<p><strong>Appeal for unity</strong></p>

<p>Bangladesh's interim leader Muhammad Yunus on Saturday called for religious unity as he embraced the weeping mother of student protestor Abu Sayed. The 25-year-old was among the first ones to be killed in police firing on July 16 during the Anti-Discrimination Student Movement.</p>

<p>"Our responsibility is to build a new Bangladesh," said Yunus, who returned from Europe this week.</p>

<p>The caretaker administration in the country has stated that restoration of law and order is its "priority".</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the police union declared a strike a few days ago, saying its personnel would not return to work until their safety was assured. As per reports, more than half of the country's police stations were reopened by Saturday.</p>

<p><strong>Attack on minorities</strong></p>

<p>The fall of the Sheikh Hasina-led government has triggered both jubilation and acts of vandalism in Bangladesh. Protestors earlier ransacked her official residence in Dhaka, while the statues of her father, Sheikh Mujibur Rahman, were defaced and brought down.</p>

<p>Multiple reports and TV footage have shown vandalism, looting and attacks on the minorities and their place of worship, Reuters reported.</p>

<p>Hindus constitute about 8% of the Muslim-majority Bangladesh, which has a total population of nearly 170 million people. They have largely supported Hasina's Awami League party in polls.</p>

<p>On Friday, the Bangladesh Hindu Buddhist Christian Unity Council wrote to Yunus asking him to protect the minorities, claiming their homes, businesses and temples were being targeted.</p>

<p>Hundreds of Hindus held a protest march on Friday and shouted slogans demanding peace.</p>

<p><strong>How protests started</strong></p>

<p>Nationwide protests in the South Asian country started after the High Court reinstated a quota system that reserved 30 per cent of government jobs for the family members of freedom fighters and veterans from Bangladesh's 1971 War of Independence.</p>

<p>However, this order was later suspended by the Supreme Court. The quota system was scrapped by Sheikh Hasina's government in 2018 following similar student-led protests.</p>

<p><strong>Protestors' demand</strong></p>

<p>The protestors demanded the government scrap the quota system, claiming that it was majorly benefitting only the Awami League.</p>

<p><strong>What is Bangladesh's quota system?</strong></p>

<p>Introduced in 1972, the quota system in the country has since undergone several changes. Before being abolished in 2018, the system back then reserved 56 per cent of seats in government jobs for various groups. However, the majority of these quotas were benefitting the freedom fighters' families.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/pciqg208_bangladesh-afp_625x300_10_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The fall of the Sheikh Hasina-led government has triggered both jubilation and acts of vandalism.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-american-lawmaker-urges-us-to-bring-end-to-coordinated-attacks-on-hindus-in-bangladesh-6307104]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Help End Attacks On Hindus In Bangladesh: 2 Indian-American Lawmakers To US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-american-lawmaker-urges-us-to-bring-end-to-coordinated-attacks-on-hindus-in-bangladesh-6307104]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 10 Aug 2024 16:23:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Two prominent Indian-American lawmakers have sought the US' direct intervention to stop the "coordinated attacks" against minority Hindus in Bangladesh.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Two prominent Indian-American lawmakers have sought the US' direct intervention to stop the "coordinated attacks" against minority Hindus in Bangladesh, underlining that instability in the region, "fuelled by religious intolerance and violence", is not in the interest of America or its allies.</p>

<p>Members of minority communities in Bangladesh faced at least 205 incidents of attacks in 52 districts since the fall of the Sheikh Hasina-led government on August 5, according to two Hindu organisations -- Bangladesh Hindu Buddhist Christian Unity Council and the Bangladesh Puja Udjapan Parishad -- in the violence-hit nation.</p>

<p>Thousands of Bangladeshi Hindus have been trying to flee to neighbouring India to escape the violence.</p>

<p>In a letter dated August 9 to Secretary of State Antony Blinken, Congressman Shri Thanedar said he is not alone in his stance against the atrocities being committed against Hindus in Bangladesh. Many in the international community, including some from his own district, have condemned the violent actions being committed against minority groups in Bangladesh.</p>

<p>"With Muhammad Yunus stepping up as the interim Prime Minister for Bangladesh, the United States has an obligation to assist this new government, to ensure that violence and civil unrest comes to an end. I urge the Biden administration to grant persecuted Bangladesh Hindus and other religious minorities temporary protected status as refugees," the Congressman from Michigan wrote to Blinken.</p>

<p>Mr Yunus, the 84-year-old Nobel laureate, was sworn in on Thursday as the head of an interim government in Bangladesh.</p>

<p>A number of Hindu temples, households and businesses were vandalised, women assaulted and at least two Hindu leaders affiliated with the Awami League party headed by Hasina were killed in the violence in Bangladesh after she fled the country, according to community leaders in Dhaka.</p>

<p>Mr Thanedar urged Mr Blinken to work closely with Yunus and his government to bring "an end to the coordinated attacks against the Bangladesh Hindus".</p>

<p>He underlined that Mr Yunus has called for an end to the violence and welcomed his willingness to rebuild the country.</p>

<p>"This is a critical time for Bangladesh, and we must do everything we can to support them in their efforts to bring an end to the violent actions and rhetoric being targeted towards Hindus in the country," said the Indian-American lawmaker.</p>

<p>In a letter dated August 8 to Mr Blinken, a copy of which was released to the press on Friday, Congressman Raja Krishnamoorthi said credible eyewitness reports of the anti-Hindu attacks in various media reports demonstrate the scale of the attacks.</p>

<p>"I am writing to you regarding the fluid situation in Bangladesh and the rise of coordinated anti-Hindu violence in the wake of former Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina's resignation. Now that Muhammad Yunus has been sworn in as Chief Adviser for the interim government, it is of utmost urgency that the United States engage with his government for both bringing the violence to an end and the perpetrators to justice," Mr Krishnamoorthi wrote.</p>

<p>"Sadly, this is not the first time that anti-government protests in Bangladesh have metastasised into anti-Hindu violence. The anti-Hindu riots in October 2021 left nine people dead amidst the destruction of hundreds of homes, businesses and temples...In 2017, more than 107 Hindus were killed and 37 'disappeared'...following the International Crimes Tribunal conviction of Jamaat-e-Islami leader Delwar Sayeedi for war crimes," he said.</p>

<p>Mr Krishnamoorthi underlined that instability in the region, "fuelled by religious intolerance and violence, is clearly not in the interest of the United States or our allies".</p>

<p>He urged Mr Blinken to engage "directly" with the interim government and exert US influence to help his administration end the violence and "bring those responsible to justice".</p>

<p>Mr Thanedar in his letter noted that political violence in Bangladesh is not a new phenomenon and that the country has experienced many coups and leadership changes since its inception in 1971.</p>

<p>Targeting of its Hindu population is also not new. Hindus only make up eight per cent of Bangladesh's population, exposing this minority to risk of discrimination and violence, the Congressman said.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/a4sbq318_shri-thanedar-raja-krishnamoorthi_625x300_10_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mr Thanedar underlined that Muhammad Yunus has called for an end to the violence.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/this-belarusian-wheelchair-barista-claims-to-make-the-world-better-6306999]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[This Belarusian Wheelchair Barista Claims To "Make The World Better"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/this-belarusian-wheelchair-barista-claims-to-make-the-world-better-6306999]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 10 Aug 2024 15:06:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[With its sleek interior and freshly ground coffee, the cafe run by Belarusian exile Sasha Avdevich may at first glance seem like yet another trendy spot in Warsaw.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With its sleek interior and freshly ground coffee, the cafe run by Belarusian exile Sasha Avdevich may at first glance seem like yet another trendy spot in Warsaw.</p>

<p>But the lowered, wheelchair-accessible countertop and a sticker reading: "The barista on shift has a hearing impairment" in Polish, English and Belarusian reveal this is no ordinary business.</p>

<p>Avdevich, himself a wheelchair user, founded the first "Inclusive Barista" coffee shop while still in Belarus and quickly shot to fame as a disability campaigner in the country controlled with an iron fist by strongman President Alexander Lukashenko.</p>

<p>The 40-year-old activist took part in the unprecedented mass protests that swept Belarus after a 2020 election slammed by rights groups as fraudulent.</p>

<p>As Lukashenko brutally cracked down on dissent, Avdevich knew he had to flee.</p>

<p>"A lot of people called me back then and said, 'Sasha, if you don't want to end up in a coffin, leave the country,'" he told AFP.</p>

<p>He recounted the Covid pandemic-era journey that saw him flee to Georgia initially, then travel on to the Canary Islands before applying for international protection in France.</p>

<p>He eventually moved to Poland, now home to tens of thousands of fellow Belarusians, who, like Avdevich, fled the repression.</p>

<p>"There are many migrants with disabilities," Avdevich said.</p>

<h3><strong>Rap battle, speed dating&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>As he settled in Warsaw, Avdevich launched barista training for people in wheelchairs, threw festivals where the trainees brewed coffee from specially adapted carts, and began to draw up plans for his first cafe in Poland.</p>

<p>When he found a commercial space suited to people with disabilities, close to his flat and in the city's increasingly popular Praga district, Avdevich and his business partner decided to give it a shot.</p>

<p>"We had money for three months of rent, and we were like: 'Come on, whatever happens, we'll do it,'" he said.</p>

<p>Opened in April, the cafe hires people with various disabilities as well as migrants, not only from Belarus.</p>

<p>The founders said they want their cafe to be as "international" -- and inclusive -- as possible.</p>

<p>"We recently organised a rap battle, we will organise a speed dating event soon," Avdevich said.</p>

<p>The cafe is also launching an inclusive DJing school.</p>

<p>Avdevich lost the use of his legs when he broke his back in a motorbike accident in 2011.</p>

<p>"There's no surgery for this type of disability... it's not possible to walk again, even if I was Bill Gates," Avdevich laughed.</p>

<p>Shortly after the accident, he said he told himself "OK, I'm alive. What can I do? I have working arms.</p>

<p>"And now we're here, in our coffee shop, making this world better."</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/n8jnc1c_wheelchair-barista-afp-_625x300_10_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Avdevich launched barista training for people in wheelchairs, as he settled in Warsaw.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/amid-protests-12-killed-in-twin-bangladesh-jailbreaks-6306944]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Amid Protests, 12 Killed In Twin Bangladesh Jailbreaks]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/amid-protests-12-killed-in-twin-bangladesh-jailbreaks-6306944]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 10 Aug 2024 14:56:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Twin jailbreaks in Bangladesh killed at least 12 inmates and freed hundreds more in the chaotic days after the ouster of autocratic premier Sheikh Hasina, officials told AFP Saturday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Twin jailbreaks in Bangladesh killed at least 12 inmates and freed hundreds more in the chaotic days after the ouster of autocratic premier Sheikh Hasina, officials told AFP Saturday.</p>

<p>An interim government is struggling to restore law and order with police going on strike after Hasina's sudden resignation and flight abroad after 15 years in power.</p>

<p>This week's prison escapes, both north of the capital Dhaka, are the latest in a series of breakouts during weeks of nationwide unrest leading up to her toppling.</p>

<p>Six convicts were killed at Jamapur Prison on Thursday after prison guards were assaulted by escapees, warden Abu Fatah told AFP.</p>

<p>"They attacked us with iron rods and sharp weapons. They torched my office. Then tried to break out and take all 600 prisoners with them," he said.</p>

<p>"We were forced to open fire. At least six inmates were killed including one who was stabbed to death."</p>

<p>Fatah said guards managed to quell the attack before anyone escaped.</p>

<p>On Tuesday another six prisoners were shot dead during a mass breakout at a high security prison in Kashimpur, just 30 kilometres (20 miles) north of Dhaka, warden Lutfor Rahman told AFP.</p>

<p>Rahman said the inmates used iron tools and rebar rods to attack guards and broke through the jail's main gate, forcing army soldiers and jail guards to open fire.</p>

<p>"At least 203 prisoners also managed to escape," he said.</p>

<p>Kashimpur High-Security Prison hosts some of Bangladesh's most notorious convicts, including Islamist extremists and murderers.</p>

<p>Rahman said none of the high-profile inmates had managed to break out of their cells.</p>

<p>Numerous attempted and successful jailbreaks have taken place across Bangladesh since protests against Hasina's government began last month.</p>

<p>More than 800 prisoners fled a jail in the central district of Narsingdi in July when a mob of thousands attacked the British colonial-era institution and set the warden's office on fire.</p>

<p>On Monday, the day of Hasina's ouster, more than 500 inmates fled a jail in the northern district of Sherpur.</p>

<p>More than 450 people died during weeks of clashes between police and protesters leading up to Hasina's ouster, including dozens of police officers.</p>

<p>Police unions declared a strike on Tuesday and said officers would not resume duty until their safety was assured.</p>

<p>More than half of the country's police stations have since reopened, according to the force.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/pciqg208_bangladesh-afp_625x300_10_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Numerous attempted and successful jailbreaks have taken place across Bangladesh since protests (file).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/dozens-of-rohingyas-killed-in-drone-attack-while-fleeing-myanmar-6306886]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Dozens Of Rohingyas Killed In Drone Attack While Fleeing Myanmar]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/dozens-of-rohingyas-killed-in-drone-attack-while-fleeing-myanmar-6306886]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 10 Aug 2024 14:45:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A drone attack on Rohingya fleeing Myanmar killed many dozens of people, including families with children, several witnesses said, describing survivors wandering between piles of bodies to identify dead and injured relatives.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A drone attack on Rohingya fleeing Myanmar killed many dozens of people, including families with children, several witnesses said, describing survivors wandering between piles of bodies to identify dead and injured relatives.</p>

<p>Four witnesses, activists and a diplomat described drone attacks on Monday that struck down families waiting to cross the border into neighbouring Bangladesh.</p>

<p>A heavily pregnant woman and her 2-year-old daughter were among the victims in the attack, the single deadliest known assault on civilians in Rakhine state during recent weeks of fighting between junta troops and rebels.</p>

<p>Three of the witnesses told Reuters on Friday that the Arakan Army was responsible, allegations the group denied. The militia and Myanmar's military blamed each other. Reuters could not verify how many people had died in the attack or independently determine responsibility.</p>

<p>Videos posted to social media showed piles of bodies strewn across muddy ground, their suitcases and backpacks scattered around them. Three survivors said more than 200 had died while a witness to the aftermath said he had seen at least 70 bodies.</p>

<p>Reuters verified the location of the videos as just outside the coastal Myanmar town of Maungdaw. Reuters was not able to independently confirm the date the videos were filmed.</p>

<p>One witness, 35-year-old Mohammed Eleyas, said his pregnant wife and 2-year-old daughter were wounded in the attack and later died. He was standing with them on the shoreline when drones began attacking the crowds, Eleyas told Reuters from a refugee camp in Bangladesh.</p>

<p>"I heard the deafening sound of shelling multiple times," he said. Eleyas said he lay on the ground to protect himself and when he got up, he saw his wife and daughter critically injured and many of his other relatives dead.</p>

<p>A second witness, Shamsuddin, 28, said he survived with his wife and newborn son. Also speaking from a refugee camp in Bangladesh, he said that after the attack many lay dead and "some people were shouting out from the pain of their injuries".</p>

<p>Boats carrying fleeing Rohingya, members of a mostly Muslim minority who face extreme persecution in Myanmar, also sank in the Naf River that separates the two countries on Monday, killing dozens more, according to two witnesses and Bangladesh media.</p>

<p>Medecins Sans Frontieres said in a statement the aid organisation had treated 39 people who had crossed from Myanmar into Bangladesh since Saturday for violence-related injuries, including mortar shell injuries and gunshot wounds. Patients described seeing people bombed while trying to find boats to cross the river, the statement said.</p>

<p>A spokesperson for the United Nations High Commission for Refugees said the agency was "aware of the deaths of refugees from the capsize of two boats in the Bay of Bengal" and it had heard reports of civilian deaths in Maungdaw but that it could not confirm the numbers or circumstances.</p>

<h3><strong>FIGHTING IN THE REGION</strong></h3>

<p>The Rohingya have been long persecuted in Buddhist-majority Myanmar. More than 730,000 of them fled the country in 2017 after a military-led crackdown that the U.N. said was carried out with genocidal intent.</p>

<p>Myanmar has been in turmoil since the military seized power from a democratically elected government in 2021, and mass protests evolved into widespread armed struggle.</p>

<p>Rohingya have been leaving Rakhine for weeks as the Arakan Army, one of many armed groups fighting, has made sweeping gains in the north, home to a large population of Muslims.</p>

<p>Reuters has previously reported that the militia burned down the largest Rohingya town in May, leaving Maungdaw, which is under siege by the rebels, as the last major Rohingya settlement aside from grim displacement camps further south. The group denied the allegations.</p>

<p>Activist groups condemned this week's attacks. A senior Western diplomat said he had confirmed the reports.</p>

<p>"These reports of hundreds of Rohingya killed at the Bangladesh/Myanmar border are, I'm sorry to say, accurate," Bob Rae, Canada's ambassador to the United Nations and a previous special envoy to Myanmar, posted on X on Wednesday.</p>

<p>Myanmar's junta blamed the Arakan Army in a post on its Telegram channel.</p>

<p>The militia denied responsibility. "According to our investigation, family members of terrorists tried to go to Bangladesh from Maungdaw and the junta dropped the bomb because they left without permission," Arakan Army spokesman Khine Thu Kha told Reuters, referring to Muslims who have joined Rohingya armed groups fighting against the Arakan Army.</p>

<h3><strong>TRYING TO GET TO SAFETY</strong></h3>

<p>Reuters was able to confirm the location of the videos seen on social media from the position and shape of the mountain and shoreline, which matched file and satellite imagery of the area.</p>

<p>The fencing featured in one of the videos also matched file imagery of the location. The location of the videos matched the area described by Shamsuddin.</p>

<p>Eleyas described how his wife and daughter died in the aftermath of the attack, and his desperate efforts to find a boat that would take them to Bangladesh.</p>

<p>Before his wife died, "We apologised to each other for any wrongs we may have done in our lives," he said.</p>

<p>Around midnight, he said, he finally found a small boat and managed to cross the border with it.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-03/vt3gmb8_rohingya-afp_625x300_21_March_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Rohingya have been long persecuted in Buddhist-majority Myanmar (file)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-ukraine-war-russia-launches-counter-terror-operation-to-stop-advancing-ukraine-troops-6306803]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russia Launches "Counter-Terror Operation" To Stop Advancing Ukraine Troops]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-ukraine-war-russia-launches-counter-terror-operation-to-stop-advancing-ukraine-troops-6306803]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 10 Aug 2024 14:32:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Moscow on Saturday launched a "counter-terror operation" in three border regions adjoining Ukraine to halt Kyiv's biggest cross-border offensive in the two-and-a-half-year conflict.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Moscow on Saturday launched a "counter-terror operation" in three border regions adjoining Ukraine to halt Kyiv's biggest cross-border offensive in the two-and-a-half-year conflict.</p>

<p>Ukrainian units stormed across the border into Russia's western Kursk region on Tuesday morning in a shock attack and have advanced several kilometres, according to independent analysts.</p>

<p>Russia has deployed additional troops and equipment, including tanks, rocket launchers and aviation units to stop the advancing troops.</p>

<p>Russia's national anti-terrorism committee said late Friday it was starting "counter-terror operations in the Belgorod, Bryansk and Kursk regions ... in order to ensure the safety of citizens and suppress the threat of terrorist acts being carried out by the enemy's sabotage groups."</p>

<p>Under Russian law, security forces and the military are given sweeping emergency powers during "counter-terror" operations.</p>

<p>Movement is restricted, vehicles can be seized, phone calls can be monitored, areas are declared no-go zones, checkpoints are introduced, and security is beefed up at key infrastructure sites.</p>

<p>The anti-terrorism committee said Ukraine had mounted an "unprecedented attempt to destabilise the situation in a number of regions of our country."</p>

<p>It called Ukraine's incursion a "terrorist attack" and said Kyiv's troops had wounded civilians and destroyed residential buildings.</p>

<p>Ukrainian leaders have remained tight-lipped on the operation, and the United States, Kyiv's closest ally, said it was not informed of the plans in advance.</p>

<p>But President Volodymyr Zelensky has appeared to tout his troops' early successes, saying earlier this week that Russia must "feel" the consequences of the full-scale offensive it has waged against Ukraine since February 2022.</p>

<p>Russia's defence ministry published footage on Saturday of tank crews firing on Ukrainian positions in the Kursk region, as well as an overnight air strike, after it said Friday it had deployed yet more units to the border region.</p>

<p>It also said it had downed 26 Ukrainian drones that tried to attack the region overnight.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/o0h6lir8_russia-ukraine_625x300_30_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Russia has deployed additional troops and equipment, including tanks to stop the advancing troops (file).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/after-meeting-s-jaishankar-maldives-president-mohamed-muizzu-calls-india-one-of-closest-allies-6306693]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["India One Of Closest Allies": Maldives President After Meeting S Jaishankar]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/after-meeting-s-jaishankar-maldives-president-mohamed-muizzu-calls-india-one-of-closest-allies-6306693]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 10 Aug 2024 14:17:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Male, Aug 10 (IANS) Calling India as one of the "closest allies" and "invaluable partners", Maldives President Mohamed Muizzu on Saturday reaffirmed his administration's "full commitment" to strengthening the "historic and close connections" between]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Calling India as one of the "closest allies" and "invaluable partners", Maldives President Mohamed Muizzu on Saturday reaffirmed his administration's "full commitment" to strengthening the "historic and close connections" between the two neighbouring countries.</p>

<p>"India has always been one of the closest allies and invaluable partners, facilitating and providing aid whenever Maldives has needed it," Mr Muizzu acknowledged in External Affairs Minister (EAM) S Jaishankar's presence during a ceremony held at the President's Office to handover the completed water supply and sewerage facilities on 28 islands in the Maldives, funded by the Government of India's Line of Credit (LoC) facility through the Exim Bank of India.</p>

<p>In his remarks, Mr Muizzu highlighted that these projects are key milestones in the Maldives' bilateral relations with India and would provide significant economic benefits, boost the local economies, and together contribute to the nation's prosperity.</p>

<p>He also extended "deep gratitude" to Prime Minister Narendra Modi, the Indian government, and the friendly people of India for their "generous and continued assistance" to the Maldives.</p>

<p>"The President also emphasised that the High Impact Community Development Projects under Indian Grant Assistance demonstrate both countries' close engagement in socioeconomic development. He went on to say that numerous revolutionary initiatives are now underway as part of this initiative, and that the plan is to accelerate their delivery to communities. He also expressed appreciation for the flexibility offered in restructuring the line of credit arrangement," the President's office said in a statement following the ceremony.</p>

<p>Mr Muizzu concluded his speech by emphasising that centuries of friendship, mutual respect, and a strong sense of kinship have nourished the relations between the Maldives and India.</p>

<p>"He further stated that Maldivians value the deep and historic ties with the Indian people and are committed to its preservation and enhancement," the statement mentioned.</p>

<p>During his meeting with Mr Jaishankar, the Maldives President also recalled his recent visit to India, to attend the swearing-in ceremony of Prime Minister Modi and expressed appreciation for the invitation and the opportunity to meet the Prime Minister as well as President Droupadi Murmu.</p>

<p>"Privileged to call on President Dr Mohamed Muizzu. Conveyed greetings of PM Narendra Modi. Committed to deepen India-Maldives ties for the benefit of our people and the region," Mr Jaishankar posted after his meeting with Mr Muizzu and the virtual inauguration of water and sanitation projects in 28 islands of Maldives.</p>

<p>Earlier, Mr Jaishankar held a bilateral meeting with Maldivian Defence Minister Mohamed Ghassan Maumoon to discuss enhanced security cooperation between the two countries.</p>

<p>The discussions focused on joint initiatives for maritime security and the shared goal of maintaining regional peace and stability.</p>

<p>He also participated in a symbolic tree-planting ceremony in Male's Lonuziyaaraiy Park along with Maldivian Foreign Minister Moosa Zameer and Thoriq Ibrahim, the Climate Change, Environment, and Energy Minister of the country.</p>

<p>On Friday, immediately after his arrival from India, a ceremony was held at the Maldives' Ministry of Foreign Affairs to mark the inauguration and handover of six projects implemented under the High Impact Community Development Projects facilitated under the Grant Assistance from India, as well as the exchange of a Memorandum of Understanding on the integrated payment system between the Ministry of Economic Development and Trade of Maldives, and the National Payments Corporation of India.</p>

<p>Additionally, an exchange notes for the renewal of the MoU to train 1,000 Civil Service Officers was exchanged between the Civil Service Commission of the Maldives and the High Commission of India.</p>

<p>"I conveyed our sincere appreciation to the people and Government of India for their generous assistance in advancing the lives of Maldivian communities. I also reiterated our commitment to continue working closely with the Government of India, bilaterally, regionally and multilaterally, to further strengthen and deepen the bonds between our two countries," said Minister of Foreign Affairs of Maldives Moosa Zameer.</p>

<p>Addressing the media, Mr Jaishankar highlighted the importance of the visit, his first to the strategically-significant Indian Ocean archipelago since January 2023.</p>

<p>"The Maldives is one of the cornerstones of our 'Neighborhood First' policy, it is also one of our Vision SAGAR, as well as of our commitment to the Global South. To put it succinctly in the words of my Prime Minister Narendra Modi, for India, neighbourhood is a priority, and in the neighbourhood, Maldives is a priority," he said.</p>

<p>He also underscored the common challenges faced by both nations and the importance of their defence and security cooperation.</p>

<p>"As neighbours, we face common challenges and have a shared interest in maintaining peace and security in the region. After all, we both have very big EEZs. Our defence and security cooperation is aimed at confronting many common challenges, and I look forward to fruitful discussions in that regard," he said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/q4evflo_maldives-president-mohamed-muizzu_625x300_10_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[During his meeting with Mr Jaishankar, the Maldives President also recalled his recent visit to India]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/remembering-susan-wojcicki-googles-16th-employee-and-former-youtube-ceo-5-facts-6306686]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Former YouTube CEO Susan Wojcicki Started Career As Photojournalist In India]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/remembering-susan-wojcicki-googles-16th-employee-and-former-youtube-ceo-5-facts-6306686]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 10 Aug 2024 14:14:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former YouTube CEO Susan Wojcicki, who was also one of the first Google employees, has died after a two-year battle with cancer. She was 56.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former YouTube CEO Susan Wojcicki, who was also one of the first Google employees, has died after a two-year battle with cancer. She was 56.</p>

<p>In a post on Facebook, Ms Wojcicki's husband Dennis Troper said that she was battling non-small cell lung cancer. "My beloved wife of 26 years and mother to our five children left us today after 2 years of living with non-small cell lung cancer. Susan was not just my best friend and partner in life, but a brilliant mind, a loving mother, and a dear friend to many," Troper wrote alongside a few family photographs.<br />
<br />
He noted that her impact on the family and the world was "immeasurable."&nbsp;<br />
<iframe allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="true" frameborder="0" height="250" scrolling="no" src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/post.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2Fdtroper%2Fposts%2Fpfbid035AsHMEC3xs1EyqrDWHVBmeVJq6sXXJaGUF5RQH962SxK3zYyihDDhWiza9epUdKTl&amp;show_text=true&amp;width=500" style="border:none;overflow:hidden" width="500"></iframe><br />
<strong>Who was Susan Wojcicki?</strong><br />
<br />
1. Born on July 5, 1968, in Santa Clara, California, she was the daughter of Stanley, who taught physics at Stanford University. Her mother Esther worked as a journalist and teacher at the Palo Alto High School, Bloomberg reported.<br />
<br />
2. Ms Wojcicki studied history at Harvard University and later worked as a photojournalist in India. Within a few years, she returned to California to receive advanced degrees in economics and business. Later on, she took up a marketing role with Intel Corp.<br />
<br />
3. In 1998, when Google co-founders Larry Page and Sergey Brin incorporated the search engine into a business, Ms Wojcicki rented the garage of her home in Menlo Park, California, to them for $1,700 a month. After working there for a few months, they later moved Google into a more formal office.<br />
<br />
4. She was hired in 1999 as the 16th employee of Google and later went on to work towards everything from AdSense, Google Analytics and Google Books to Google Images. In 2006, the company bought her home to serve as a monument to its roots. At the same time, Brin became her brother-in-law and married her sister, Anne, in 2007. However, the former couple parted ways in 2015.<br />
<br />
5. Wojcicki had in 2006 advocated for the $1.65 billion acquisition of YouTube. Being its CEO, she went on to expand its viewership to 2.5 billion monthly users. In February 2023, Ms Wojcicki announced her decision to step down as YouTube's CEO after spending around nine years of being the front and centre of the company.<br />
<br />
From being one of the early employees of Google who helped jumpstart the company in her garage to running the tech giant's advertising business and then YouTube for most of the past decade, Wojcicki has had a journey of a lifetime. Ms Wojcicki married Dennis Troper, who was a fellow veteran Google manager, back in 1998. In February this year, one of their children -- son Marco -- passed away due to an accidental drug overdose at the age of 19.<br />
<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/mreer41g_youtube-ceo-_625x300_10_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Susan Wojcicki was hired in 1999 as the 16th employee of Google.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-unrest-live-updates-chief-justice-resigns-after-massive-protests-one-hour-ultimatum-6306631]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh LIVE: Chief Justice Resigns After Protests, One-Hour Ultimatum]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-unrest-live-updates-chief-justice-resigns-after-massive-protests-one-hour-ultimatum-6306631]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 10 Aug 2024 14:04:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Protests refuse to die down in Bangladesh. The country's Chief Justice, seen as a loyalist of former prime minister Sheikh Hasina, was forced to resign this afternoon after an ultimatum from protesting students.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Protests refuse to die down in <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/search?searchtext=Bangladesh-Protests">Bangladesh</a>. The country's Chief Justice, seen as a loyalist of former prime minister Sheikh Hasina, was forced to resign this afternoon after an ultimatum from protesting students. An interim government is already in place in Bangladesh where clashes during a quota protest claimed at least 400 lives earlier this week and forced Ms Hasina to resign and flee the country.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>Here are the LIVE Updates on Bangladesh Unrest:</strong></h2>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/pciqg208_bangladesh-afp_625x300_10_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Bangladesh Protests LIVE Updates: Protests continue in Bangladesh]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-sheikh-hasinas-ouster-affects-india-bangladesh-diplomatic-ties-6306430]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How Sheikh Hasina's Ouster Affects India-Bangladesh Diplomatic Ties]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-sheikh-hasinas-ouster-affects-india-bangladesh-diplomatic-ties-6306430]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 10 Aug 2024 13:29:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The ouster of Bangladesh's autocratic premier sparked celebrations in Dhaka this week but alarm in neighbouring India, which backed Sheikh Hasina to counter rival China and quash Islamist alternatives, analysts say.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The ouster of Bangladesh's autocratic premier sparked celebrations in Dhaka this week but alarm in India, which backed Sheikh Hasina to counter rival China and quash Islamist alternatives, analysts say.</p>

<p>It has created a diplomatic dilemma for the regional powerhouse.</p>

<p>Hasina, 76, quit as prime minister in the face of a student-led uprising on Monday and fled by helicopter to longtime ally New Delhi.</p>

<p>Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi was among the first to offer his "best wishes" after Bangladesh's newly sworn-in interim leader Muhammad Yunus took power Thursday, saying New Delhi was "committed" to working with Dhaka.</p>

<p>But China was also swift to welcome Dhaka's new authorities, saying it "attaches importance to the development" of relations.</p>

<p>With Hasina's rivals in control in Dhaka, India's support for the old government has come back to bite.</p>

<p>"From the point of view of Bangladeshis, India has been on the wrong side for a couple of years now," said International Crisis Group analyst Thomas Kean.</p>

<p>"The Indian government absolutely did not want to see a change in Dhaka, and had made that very clear for years that they didn't see any alternative to Hasina and the Awami League."</p>

<h3><strong>&nbsp;'Detrimental'&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Bangladesh is almost entirely encircled by India, with a deeply intertwined history long before they were partitioned out of the Indian subcontinent in 1947.</p>

<p>But while India's 1.4 billion population and dominating economy overshadows Bangladesh -- with a population of 170 million -- Hasina also courted China.</p>

<p>India and China, the world's two most populous nations, are intense rivals competing for strategic influence across South Asia, including in Nepal, Sri Lanka and the Maldives.</p>

<p>Hasina pursued a delicate balancing act, benefiting from support from New Delhi, while maintaining strong relations with Beijing.</p>

<p>New Delhi saw a common threat in groups Hasina viewed as rivals and crushed with brutal force, including the key Bangladesh National Party (BNP).</p>

<p>"India... worried that any alternative to Hasina and the Awami League could be detrimental to Indian interests," said Michael Kugelman, director of the South Asia Institute at the Washington-based Wilson Center.</p>

<p>"In New Delhi's view, the BNP and its allies are dangerous Islamist forces that could imperil Indian interests."</p>

<p>Yunus has said he wants elections in Bangladesh "within a few months".</p>

<p>The BNP could be poised for a comeback, holding a mass rally in Dhaka this week.</p>

<p>In the immediate aftermath of Hasina's fall, some businesses and homes owned by Hindus were attacked, a group seen by some in Muslim-majority Bangladesh as having been her supporters.</p>

<p>Hundreds of Bangladeshi Hindus this week arrived on India's border, asking to cross.</p>

<p>Hindu nationalist leader Modi on Thursday said he hoped "for an early return to normalcy, ensuring the safety and protection of Hindus and all other minority communities."</p>

<h3><strong>'She will go back'&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>The fact Hasina is sheltering in India may prove to be a stumbling block to relations between New Delhi and Dhaka.</p>

<p>Indian Foreign Minister Subrahmanyam Jaishankar told parliament Hasina had flown to India "at very short notice", and according to Indian media, intended to stay only briefly in transit.</p>

<p>But her reported bid to travel onwards to Britain was scuppered after London called for a "full and independent UN-led investigation" into the deadly crackdown on protests in the last weeks of her rule.</p>

<p>The United States in the past had praised Hasina's economic track record and saw her as a partner on priorities such as countering Islamist extremism, but Washington more recently imposed visa sanctions over concerns about democracy.</p>

<p>It is not clear how long she will now stay in India, or where else she might go.</p>

<p>Since arriving at a military airbase near New Delhi, she has been hosted in a secret safe house and not spoken publically.</p>

<p>Her daughter Saima Wazed said she was "heartbroken" she could not see her mother.</p>

<p>"As much as I would love to see Ma, I don't want to compromise her whereabouts in any way", Wazed, the World Health Organization's Southeast Asia chief, said in a since-deleted post on social media platform X.</p>

<p>Her son Sajeeb Wazed Joy told the Times of India newspaper his mother still hoped to contest for political office.</p>

<p>"She will go back to Bangladesh the moment the interim government decides to hold an election," he said.</p>

<h3><strong>'Earned the enmity'&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Indian media warn of the "formidable diplomatic challenge" the country now faces.</p>

<p>"New Delhi must actively work to limit the damage, and ensure the high stakes in the relationship are protected," the Indian Express newspaper warned. "This could involve some near-term setbacks."</p>

<p>But Bangladesh's new leader Yunus has offered an olive branch.</p>

<p>"Although some countries, such as India, backed the ousted prime minister and earned the enmity of the Bangladeshi people as a result, there will be many opportunities to heal these kinds of rifts," Yunus wrote in The Economist, shortly before returning to Bangladesh.</p>

<p>Crisis Group's Kean meanwhile said he believes the nations will put the past aside for pragmatic relations.</p>

<p>"India is Bangladesh's most important international partner, and there's no reason that they can't find a way to move forward from this," said Kean.</p>

<p>"Economic forces will compel them to work together."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/g44c91a_pm-modi-and-sheikh-hasina_625x300_22_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[PM Modi was among the first to congratulate the interim leader after Sheikh Hasina fled (file).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/man-who-missed-voepass-flight-that-crashed-in-brazil-begged-to-be-let-on-6306165]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Narrow Escape For Brazilian Man, The Flight He Missed Crashed Killing All]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/man-who-missed-voepass-flight-that-crashed-in-brazil-begged-to-be-let-on-6306165]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 10 Aug 2024 13:20:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Late arrival for boarding helped a Brazilian man escape death as the flight he missed met a tragic end last evening.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Late arrival for boarding helped a Brazilian man escape death as the flight he missed met a tragic end last evening.</p>

<p>Adriano Assis was to board the Voepass 2283 flight that crashed in Sao Paulo, killing all passengers and crew on board. In an interview with local news outlet TV Globo, Adriano said he was stopped from boarding the flight because he was late.</p>

<p>An excerpt from the interview was shared on X with the caption, "This man wasn't allowed to board the plane that just crashed in Vinhedo in Sao Paulo, Brazil because he was LATE. He argued with the man at the boarding gate but ended up hugging him after hearing the plane had crashed. This is unbelievable."</p>

<p>Adriano said the airline employee who stopped him from boarding the flight saved his life. He said a confusion over his flight details got him late for boarding. When the staff refused to let him on the flight, he "argued with him and so on, and that was it. And he saved my life."</p>

<p>According to the flight manifest, the aircraft was intended to carry 58 passengers. The 58th passenger to never make it onboard was Adriano Assis. He added that after finding out about the accident, he searched for the airline employee and hugged him.</p>

<p>"I hugged him because he's done his job. If he hadn't done his job, maybe I wouldn't be doing this interview today. I spoke out of anger, but this chap, I don't even know his name, he really saved my life," he said.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">This man wasn't allowed to board the plane that just crashed in Vinhedo in So Paulo, Brazil because he was LATE.<br />
<br />
He argued with the man at the boarding gate, but ended up hugging him after hearing the plane had crashed.<br />
<br />
This is unbelievable ???? <a href="https://t.co/wrplK3lVr4">pic.twitter.com/wrplK3lVr4</a></p>
 Cillian (@CilComLFC) <a href="https://twitter.com/CilComLFC/status/1821985105105334307?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 9, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Several videos of the Voepass ATR 72 turboprop spinning out of control and slamming into a gated community in Vinhedo, some 80 km northwest of Sao Paulo, went viral on social media yesterday. All those who were on board -- 57 passengers and four crew members -- died. No deaths were reported on the ground, according to authorities.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/kdk2u448_brazil-crash-man-who-survived_625x300_10_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Adriano said the airline staff who stopped him from boarding the flight saved his life.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-chief-justice-says-will-resign-after-massive-student-protests-6306355]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh Chief Justice Resigns After Ultimatum From Student Protesters]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-chief-justice-says-will-resign-after-massive-student-protests-6306355]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 10 Aug 2024 13:11:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The chief justice of Bangladesh's top court agreed to resign "in principle" after an ultimatum to do so from protesters, broadcaster Jamuna TV reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Chief Justice of Bangladesh's top court, Obaidul Hassan, agreed to resign "in principle" following intense pressure from protesters surrounding the Supreme Court, broadcaster Jamuna TV reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The 65-year-old judge will tender his resignation after consulting President Mohammed Shahabuddin in the evening, The Dhaka Tribune newspaper reported.</p>

<p>The protests started after Mr Hassan called for a full court meeting with all justices from both divisions of the Supreme Court. The protesting students viewed the convening of the full court meeting as a judiciary coup and announced a siege of the High Court premises.</p>

<p>In the face of student protest, Chief Justice Hassan postponed the meeting and later said that he would step down.</p>

<p>Hassan, appointed last year and seen as a loyalist to ousted Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina was given an one-hour ultimatum to resign.</p>

<p>Bangladesh Bank Governor Abdur Rouf Talukder has also resigned but his resignation has not been accepted given the importance of the position, finance ministry adviser Salehuddin Ahmed told reporters. Days earlier, four deputy governors were forced to resign by 300 to 400 bank officials accusing them of corruption.</p>

<p>The protests, part of the wider unrest that led to Hasina's departure, have resulted in over 450 deaths, including dozens of police officers. Hasina faces allegations of murder, forced disappearance, money laundering and corruption, and must face the law, Amir Khosru Mahmud Chowdhury, a senior member of Bangladesh Nationalist Party said.</p>

<p>The police union has declared a strike, refusing to return to work until their safety is assured, further complicating the situation.</p>

<p>Hasina has been sheltering in New Delhi since Monday and plans to return to the country and take part in elections.</p>

<p>Many homes and businesses of the country's minority Hindu community have also been vandalised this week, prompting hundreds of them in northwest Bangladesh to try and flee to neighbouring India.</p>

<p>Bangladesh's interim leader Muhammad Yunus appealed for religious unityas he embraced the weeping mother of a student shot dead by police, a flashpoint in mass protests that ended Sheikh Hasina's 15-year rule.</p>

<p>The Nobel laureate's first task is to bring stability to Bangladesh after he responded to a call by student protesters for him to temporarily lead the country following weeks of deadly anti-government demonstrations against the government led by Sheikh Hasina.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/09shvhu4_bangladesh-protest-afp_625x300_10_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Student leaders in Bangladesh demand Obaidul Hassan's resignation.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>