<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Fri, 22 Nov 2024 05:31:02 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-slams-australias-plan-to-ban-social-media-for-kids-under-16-7075957]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk Slams Australia's Plan To Ban Social Media For Kids Under 16]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-slams-australias-plan-to-ban-social-media-for-kids-under-16-7075957]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 22 Nov 2024 05:05:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US billionaire Elon Musk, owner of social media platform X, has criticised Australia's proposed law to ban social media for children under 16 and fine social media platforms of up to A$49.5 million ($32 million) for companies for systemic breaches.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US billionaire Elon Musk, owner of social media platform X, has criticised Australia's proposed law to ban social media for children under 16 and fine social media platforms of up to A$49.5 million ($32 million) for companies for systemic breaches.</p>

<p>Australia's centre-left government on Thursday introduced the bill in parliament. It plans to try an age-verification system to enforce a social media age cut-off, some of the toughest controls imposed by any country to date.</p>

<p>"Seems like a backdoor way to control access to the Internet by all Australians," Musk, who views himself as a champion of free speech, said in a reply late on Thursday to Prime Minister Anthony Albanese's post on X about the bill.</p>

<p>Several countries have already vowed to curb social media use by children through legislation, but Australia's policy could become one of the most stringent with no exemption for parental consent and pre-existing accounts.</p>

<p>France last year proposed a ban on social media for those under 15 but allowed parental consent, while the US has for decades required technology companies to seek parental consent to access the data of children under 13.</p>

<p>Musk has previously clashed with Australia's centre-left Labor government over its social media policies and had called it "fascists" over its misinformation law.</p>

<p>In April, X went to an Australian court to challenge a cyber regulator's order for the removal of some posts about the stabbing of a bishop in Sydney, prompting Albanese to call Musk an "arrogant billionaire".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/04dtmd6g_elon-musk_625x300_22_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Australia's policy could become one of the most stringent with no exemptions. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-koreas-kim-accuses-us-of-escalating-tensions-warns-of-nuclear-war-7075865]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[North Korea's Kim Accuses US Of Escalating Tensions, Warns Of Nuclear War]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-koreas-kim-accuses-us-of-escalating-tensions-warns-of-nuclear-war-7075865]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 22 Nov 2024 04:39:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[North Korean leader Kim Jong Un has accused the United States of ramping up tension and provocations, saying the Korean peninsula has never faced such risks of nuclear war as now, state media KCNA said on Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>North Korean leader Kim Jong Un has accused the United States of ramping up tension and provocations, saying the Korean peninsula has never faced such risks of nuclear war as now, state media KCNA said on Friday.</p>

<p>In a speech at a military exhibition on Thursday in Pyongyang, Kim said his previous experience of negotiations with Washington only highlighted its "aggressive and hostile" policy against Pyongyang, KCNA said.</p>

<p>"Never before have the warring parties on the Korean peninsula faced such a dangerous and acute confrontation that it could escalate into the most destructive thermonuclear war," Kim said, according to KCNA.</p>

<p>"We have already gone as far as we can on negotiating with the United States, but what we became certain of from the result is not the superpower's willingness to coexist, but its thorough stance of power and aggressive and hostile policy toward us that can never change."</p>

<p>During US President-elect Donald Trump's first term, he and Kim held three unprecedented meetings in Singapore, Hanoi, and at the Korean border in 2018 and 2019.</p>

<p>But their diplomacy failed to achieve any concrete outcome due to differences between US calls for North Korea to abandon its nuclear weapons and Kim's demands for sanctions relief.</p>

<p>Trump has long touted his ties with Kim, saying last month that the two countries "would've had a nuclear war with millions of people killed" but he stopped it thanks to their relationship.</p>

<p>North Korean state media has not yet publicly mentioned Trump's reelection.</p>

<p>Kim, in the speech, called for developing and upgrading weaponry into "ultra-modern ones" and vowed to continue advancing defence capabilities to bolster the country's strategic position, KCNA said.</p>

<p>The event, called the Defence Development Exhibition, featured strategic and tactical weapons.</p>

<p>Kim's latest speech came amid international criticism over increasingly deepening military cooperation between Pyongyang and Moscow, with North Korea having sent more than 10,000 troops to Russia to support its war against Ukraine.</p>

<p>Last week, Kim urged the country's military to improve capabilities for fighting a war, blaming the United States and its allies for stoking tension to "the worst phase in history" and calling the Korean peninsula "the world's biggest hotspot."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/pnt3fbdg_kim-jong-un_625x300_22_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kim Jong Un called for developing and upgrading weaponry into "ultra-modern ones". (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-strikes-kill-52-in-lebanon-as-hezbollah-targets-south-israel-7075819]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Strikes Kill 52 In Lebanon As Hezbollah Targets South Israel]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-strikes-kill-52-in-lebanon-as-hezbollah-targets-south-israel-7075819]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 22 Nov 2024 04:20:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Lebanon said Israeli strikes Thursday on the country's east and south killed 52 people, as raids also hit south Beirut and Hezbollah claimed its deepest attack on Israel in over a year.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lebanon said Israeli strikes Thursday on the country's east and south killed 52 people, as raids also hit south Beirut and Hezbollah claimed its deepest attack on Israel in over a year.</p>

<p>More than 11 months of cross-border fire between Israel and Hezbollah over the Gaza conflict escalated into all-out war in September, with Israel conducting an extensive bombing campaign, primarily targeting Hezbollah strongholds, and sending ground troops into southern Lebanon.</p>

<p>"Israeli enemy strikes that targeted the Baalbek district" in east Lebanon's Bekaa Valley left "40 dead and 52 wounded", a health ministry statement said, listing tolls for 10 different locations.</p>

<p>Lebanon's official National News Agency (NNA) said a couple and their four children were killed in a strike on a house in the village of Maqneh, while another couple and their young daughter were among 11 people killed in a raid on nearby Nabha.</p>

<p>The ministry also reported "seven dead and 24 wounded" in "Israeli enemy strikes" on south Lebanon's Nabatiyeh district, and "five dead and 26 wounded" in strikes elsewhere in south Lebanon.</p>

<p>In Israel, first responders said a man was killed after rocket fire from Lebanon hit the Galilee region in the country's north.</p>

<p>In Beirut's southern suburbs, the NNA reported at least 12 strikes throughout Thursday, after relative calm while US envoy Amos Hochstein visited earlier this week, seeking to broker an end to the Israel-Hezbollah war.</p>

<p>Israeli army spokesman Avichay Adraee on social media platform X issued several rounds of evacuation warnings for Beirut's southern suburbs, as well as areas in and around the southern coastal city of Tyre, but none for east Lebanon.</p>

<p>AFPTV footage showed columns of smoke rising from the southern suburbs, usually a densely populated residential district but now largely emptied.</p>

<p><strong>Khiam&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p>Adraee said on X that the Israeli military "targeted a weapons depot, a command headquarters and terrorist infrastructure" belonging to Hezbollah in south Beirut.</p>

<p>Amid a series of attack claims, Hezbollah said its fighters targeted "the Hatzor air base" near Israel's southern city of Ashdod, around 150 kilometres (90 miles) from Lebanon's southern border, "with a missile salvo" -- its deepest target in more than a year of hostilities.</p>

<p>In 10 separate statements, Iran-backed Hezbollah said its fighters also targeted Israeli troops in and near the south Lebanon town of Khiam, including with artillery, rockets and drones.</p>

<p>The NNA said "the enemy army" was "blowing up homes and residential buildings during its incursion into the town".</p>

<p>Lebanon's official news agency and Hezbollah have reported fighting and air strikes in the Khiam area ever since Israeli ground troops first entered Lebanon on September 30.</p>

<p>Earlier Thursday, United Nations special coordinator for Lebanon Jeanine Hennis-Plasschaert visited Baalbek's UNESCO-listed archaeological area, after the UN's cultural body this week granted more than 30 heritage sites in Lebanon "provisional enhanced protection" amid the war.</p>

<p>Lebanon's health ministry said Thursday that at least 3,583 people had been killed in the violence since October 2023. Most of the deaths have been since September this year.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said Wednesday that three soldiers were killed in south Lebanon, bringing to 52 the number killed in Lebanon since the start of ground operations.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/co9n3dg8_israel-lebanon-tensions_625x300_08_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Lebanon's health ministry said that at least 3,583 people had been killed in the violence. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russian-president-vladimir-putin-hints-at-strikes-on-west-in-global-ukraine-war-7075687]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Putin Hints At Strikes On West In "Global" Ukraine War]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russian-president-vladimir-putin-hints-at-strikes-on-west-in-global-ukraine-war-7075687]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 22 Nov 2024 03:36:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russian President Vladimir Putin said Thursday that the conflict in Ukraine had characteristics of a "global" war and did not rule out strikes on Western countries.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russian President Vladimir Putin said Thursday that the conflict in Ukraine had characteristics of a "global" war and did not rule out strikes on Western countries.</p>

<p>The Kremlin strongman spoke out after a day of frayed nerves, with Russia test-firing a new generation intermediate-range missile at Ukraine -- which Putin hinted was capable of unleashing a nuclear payload.</p>

<p>Ukraine's President Volodymyr Zelensky branded the strike a major ramping up of the "scale and brutality" of the war by a "crazy neighbour", while Kyiv's main backer the United States said that Russia was to blame for escalating the conflict "at every turn".</p>

<p>Intermediate-range missiles typically have a reach of up to 5,500 kilometres (3,400 miles) -- enough to make good on Putin's threat of striking the West.</p>

<p>In a defiant address to the nation, Russia's president railed at Ukraine's allies granting permission for Kyiv to use Western-supplied weapons to strike targets on Russian territory, warning of retaliation.</p>

<p>In recent days Ukraine has fired US and UK-supplied missiles at Russian territory for the first time, escalating already sky-high tensions in the brutal nearly three-year-long conflict.</p>

<p>"We consider ourselves entitled to use our weapons against the military facilities of those countries that allow their weapons to be used against our facilities," Putin said.</p>

<p>He said the US-sent Army Tactical Missile System (ATACMS) and British Storm Shadow payloads were shot down by Moscow's air defences, adding: "The goals that the enemy obviously set were not achieved".</p>

<p>Kremlin spokesman Dmitri Peskov did however say Moscow informed Washington of the missile's launch half an hour before it was fired through an automatic nuclear de-escalation hotline, in remarks cited in state media.</p>

<p>He earlier said Russia was doing everything to avoid an atomic conflict, having updated its nuclear doctrine this week.</p>

<p>White House spokeswoman Karine Jean-Pierre told reporters that Washington saw no need to modify the United States' own nuclear posture in response.</p>

<p><strong>'Reckless behaviour'&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p>Ukraine had earlier accused Russia of firing an intercontinental ballistic missile (ICBM) for the first time in history -- a claim later downplayed by Washington.</p>

<p>The Ukrainian air force said Moscow had launched the missile as part of a barrage towards Dnipro, where local authorities said an infrastructure facility was hit and two civilians were wounded.</p>

<p>Putin said that Russia had carried out "testing in combat conditions of one of the newest Russian... missile systems" named "Oreshnik".</p>

<p>Criticising the global response to the strike -- "final proof that Russia definitely does not want peace" -- Zelensky warned that other countries could become targets for Putin too.</p>

<p>"It is necessary to urge Russia to a true peace, which is possible only through force," the Ukrainian leader said in his evening address.</p>

<p>"Otherwise, there will be relentless Russian strikes, threats and destabilisation, and not only against Ukraine."</p>

<p>The attack on Dnipro comes just days after several foreign embassies shuttered temporarily in the Ukrainian capital, citing the threat of a large-scale strike.</p>

<p>"It is another example of reckless behaviour from Russia," a spokesman for British Prime Minister Keir Starmer told reporters.</p>

<p>The spokesman for UN Secretary-General Antonio Guterres, Stephane Dujarric, said the new missile's deployment was "another concerning and worrying development," warning the war was "going in the wrong direction".</p>

<p>Yet a US official played down the threat, saying on condition of anonymity that Russia "likely possesses only a handful of these" experimental missiles.</p>

<p><strong>UK 'directly involved'</strong></p>

<p>The head of the Dnipropetrovsk region where the city of Dnipro is located said the Russian aerial bombardment damaged a rehabilitation centre and several homes, as well as an industrial enterprise.</p>

<p>"Two people were wounded -- a 57-year-old man was treated on the scene and a 42-year-old woman was hospitalised," said the official, Sergiy Lysak.</p>

<p>Russia and Ukraine have escalated their use of long-range missiles in recent days since Washington gave Kyiv permission to use its ATACMS against military targets inside Russia -- a long-standing Ukrainian request.</p>

<p>British media meanwhile reported on Wednesday that Kyiv had launched UK-supplied Storm Shadow missiles at targets in Russia after being given the green light from London.</p>

<p>With ranges of 300 and 250 kilometres respectively, both missile systems' reach is far dwarfed by the experimental intermediate-range system fired by Russia.</p>

<p>Russia's envoy to London on Thursday said that meant Britain was "now directly involved" in the Ukraine war, with Andrei Kelin telling Sky News "this firing cannot happen" without UK and NATO support.</p>

<p>But the White House's Jean-Pierre countered that it was Russia who was behind the rising tensions, pointing to the reported deployment of thousands of North Korean troops to help Moscow fight off a Ukrainian offensive in Russia's border Kursk region.</p>

<p>"The escalation at every turn is coming from Russia," Jean-Pierre said, adding that the United States had warned Moscow against involving "another country in another part of the world" -- referring to Pyongyang.</p>

<p><strong>Kyiv in retreat</strong></p>

<p>The defence ministry in Moscow said Thursday its air-defence systems had downed two Storm Shadows, without saying whether they had come down on Russian territory or in occupied Ukraine.</p>

<p>The missile escalation is coming at a critical moment on the ground for Ukraine, as its defences buckle under Russian pressure across the sprawling front line.</p>

<p>Russia claimed deeper advances in the war-battered Donetsk region, announcing on Thursday that its forces had captured another village close to Kurakhove, closing in on the town after months of steady advances.</p>

<p>Moscow's defence ministry said Russian forces had taken the small village of Dalne, five kilometres (three miles) south of Kurakhove.</p>

<p>Lysak, the governor of the Dnipropetrovsk region, said that 26 people had been wounded in another strike on the town of Kryvyi Rig, where Zelensky was born.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/t156bgn8_putin_625x300_22_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Vladimir Putin earlier said Russia was doing everything to avoid an atomic conflict. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/legal-challenges-ahead-for-googles-forced-sale-of-chrome-7075626]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Legal Challenges Ahead For Google's Forced Sale Of Chrome]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/legal-challenges-ahead-for-googles-forced-sale-of-chrome-7075626]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 22 Nov 2024 03:16:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Efforts by US antitrust regulators to break up Alphabet by forcing a sale of its Google Chrome browser and other proposals to limit its search dominance are likely to run into legal challenges on grounds the remedies are extreme.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Efforts by US antitrust regulators to break up Alphabet by forcing a sale of its Google Chrome browser and other proposals to limit its search dominance are likely to run into legal challenges on grounds the remedies are extreme.</p>

<p>After a ruling in August that Google illegally monopolized the search market, US Department of Justice prosecutors argued to a judge on Wednesday that the company must sell Chrome, share data and search results with rivals and possibly sell its Android smartphone software.</p>

<p>Alphabet shares fell as much as 7%, on track for their biggest daily percentage decline since January 31.</p>

<p>The proposals are part of a landmark case aimed at reshaping how users find information. But a new pro-business administration of President-elect Donald Trump next year could change that effort and legal proceedings could last years, experts said.</p>

<p>"It would strike me as an over-ask," said Kevin Walkush at Jensen Investment Management, which holds Google stock and is skeptical a Chrome divestiture will happen. "You ask for everything possible, not necessarily with an eye towards what would be probable and proportional, and then see what sticks."</p>

<p>The DOJ sought and won a breakup of Microsoft in the early 2000s after alleging it illegally monopolized the web browser market. That ruling was overturned by an appeals court, and Microsoft and the DOJ eventually settled.</p>

<p>Walkush expects the Google case to take years to play out as the company appeals. "The wheels of justice do not turn quickly," he said.</p>

<p>Google called the DOJ's approach "unprecedented government overreach that would harm American consumers, developers, and small businesses," giving as examples diminished user privacy and less funding for companies such as browser maker Mozilla when they feature Google search.</p>

<p>The case could also face challenges from Trump.</p>

<p>While Trump's administration originally filed the search case against Google during his first term, he indicated in October he might not break up the company because it could hurt the American tech industry at a time competition is heating up with China in areas including AI.</p>

<p>Representatives for Trump did not immediately respond to a request for comment.</p>

<p><strong>'SUBSTANTIAL HEADWINDS'</strong></p>

<p>Chrome, the most widely used web browser, is a pillar of Google's business, providing the company with valuable user data that helps it target ads. The search ads business brought in more than half of Alphabet's total revenue of $88.3 billion in the latest quarter.</p>

<p>The value of Chrome, estimated to hold about two-thirds of the global browser market, diminishes sharply as a standalone browser.</p>

<p>"The reason why it's valuable to Google is because Google uses it to enhance its ad business and its search business," said Megan Gray, former general counsel at search rival DuckDuckGO who has also worked as an attorney at the Federal Trade Commission. "If you don't have those, then Chrome would just be a data broker."</p>

<p>A forced sale would not address several key issues raised in the DOJ lawsuit, including a search monopoly, critics say. US antitrust enforcers, who are also pursuing Apple and Amazon in other monopoly cases, would have to approve any potential Chrome buyer.</p>

<p>"DOJ will face substantial headwinds with this remedy," because Chrome can run search engines other than Google, said Gus Hurwitz, senior fellow and academic director at University of Pennsylvania Carey Law School. "Courts expect any remedy to have a causal connection to the underlying antitrust concern. Divesting Chrome does absolutely nothing to address this concern."</p>

<p>The DOJ proposed a blanket ban on Google offering incentives to give its search engine preferential treatment. That would include Google's lucrative partnership with Apple, where it pays the smartphone maker billions of dollars annually to make Google Search the default on Apple smartphones.</p>

<p>Evercore analysts called the proposed curbs "draconian."</p>

<p>Given Google Search's popularity, Apple is likely to continue with Google as the default search engine even without any agreement or payments, Hurwitz said.</p>

<p>DOJ's proposals also include demands for Google to license search results at a nominal cost and share the user data it gathers with competitors for free.</p>

<p>DA Davidson analyst Gil Luria said it was harder to ascertain the impact of Google having to open up its search data until the terms are clearer. The Center for Journalism &amp; Liberty said Google licensing its search data would be "transformative" for news publishers because it would help them better understand their audiences.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/18q05qu_google-generic_625x300_02_April_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Evercore analysts called the proposed curbs "draconian." (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/un-nuclear-watchdog-passes-resolution-against-iran-demands-cooperation-7075552]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UN's 35-Nation Nuclear Watchdog Board Passes Resolution Against Iran]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/un-nuclear-watchdog-passes-resolution-against-iran-demands-cooperation-7075552]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 22 Nov 2024 02:53:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The UN nuclear watchdog's board of governors passed a resolution chiding Iran's poor cooperation with the agency after hours of heated exchanges, diplomats told AFP late on Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The UN nuclear watchdog's board of governors passed a resolution chiding Iran's poor cooperation with the agency after hours of heated exchanges, diplomats told AFP late on Thursday.</p>

<p>The censure motion brought by Britain, France, Germany and the United States at the International Atomic Energy Agency's 35-nation board follows a similar one in June.</p>

<p>But it comes as tensions run high over Iran's atomic programme, with critics fearing that Tehran is attempting to develop a nuclear weapon -- which the Islamic Republic denies.</p>

<p>The resolution -- which China, Russia and Burkina Faso voted against -- was carried by 19 votes in favour, with 12 countries abstaining from the vote, two diplomats told AFP.</p>

<p>Ahead of Thursday's vote, the United States and its European allies sought to rally support for their resolution by denouncing Iran.</p>

<p>In its national statement to the board, Washington said that Tehran's nuclear activities "remained deeply troubling", adding that the country's cooperation was falling "far short" of expectations.</p>

<p>European powers said Iran's "behaviour in the nuclear realm" still represented "a threat to international security".</p>

<p>"The international community must remain firm in its determination to prevent Iran from developing nuclear weapons," Britain, France and Germany said in a joint statement.</p>

<p><strong>Differences laid bare&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p>The confidential resolution seen by AFP says it is "essential and urgent" for Iran to "act to fulfil its legal obligations".</p>

<p>The motion also calls on Tehran to provide "technically credible explanations" for the presence of uranium particles found at two undeclared locations in Iran.</p>

<p>Furthermore, Western powers are asking for a "comprehensive report" to be issued by the IAEA on Iran's nuclear efforts "at the latest" by spring 2025.</p>

<p>Since 2021, Tehran has significantly decreased its cooperation with the agency by deactivating surveillance devices to monitor the nuclear programme and barring UN inspectors.</p>

<p>At the same time, Iran has rapidly ramped up its nuclear activities, including by increasing its stockpiles of enriched uranium.</p>

<p>That has heightened fears that Tehran might be seeking to develop a nuclear weapon, which it denies.</p>

<p>The resolution comes just as IAEA head Rafael Grossi returned from a trip to Tehran last week, where he appeared to have made headway.</p>

<p>During the visit, Iran agreed to an IAEA demand to cap its sensitive stock of near weapons-grade uranium enriched up to 60 percent purity.</p>

<p>"This is a concrete step in the right direction," Grossi told reporters Wednesday, saying it was "the first time" Iran had made such a commitment since it started breaking away from its obligations under the nuclear deal.</p>

<p>The landmark 2015 deal, which curbed Iran's nuclear programme in exchange for sanctions relief, fell apart three years later after the unilateral withdrawal by the United States under then-president Donald Trump.</p>

<p>In retaliation, Tehran began gradually rolling back some of its commitments by increasing its uranium stockpiles and enriching beyond the 3.67 percent purity -- enough for nuclear power stations -- permitted under the deal.</p>

<p><strong>Potential to 'harm efforts'</strong></p>

<p>Although symbolic in nature at this stage, the censure motion is designed to raise diplomatic pressure on Iran.</p>

<p>On Thursday, Iran's Foreign Minister Abbas Araghchi said the censure "will disrupt" interactions with the agency, but stressed Tehran would remain keen to cooperate.</p>

<p>Earlier, Araghchi had warned of a "proportionate" response by Iran if the board passes the resolution.</p>

<p>According to Heloise Fayet, a researcher at the French Institute of International Relations, the resolution has the potential to "harm Rafael Grossi's efforts".</p>

<p>"But Western powers are frustrated by the lack of effectiveness of his diplomatic manoeuvres and are looking for firmer solutions," she told AFP.</p>

<p>On Wednesday, Grossi said he could "not exclude" that Iran's commitment to cap enrichment might falter "as a result of further developments".</p>

<p>Foreign policy expert Rahman Ghahremanpour said Tehran might retaliate to the new censure by "increasing the enrichment levels".</p>

<p>But he does not expect any drastic "strategic measures" as Iran does not want to "aggravate tensions" before Donald Trump returns to the White House.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/2t661ac_un-nuclear-agency-rafael-grossi_625x300_22_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Iran's "behaviour in the nuclear realm" still represented "a threat to international security". (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/brazil-police-call-ex-president-bolsonaros-indictment-over-2022-coup-plot-7075422]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Brazil Police Call Ex-President Bolsonaro's Indictment Over 2022 "Coup" Plot]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/brazil-police-call-ex-president-bolsonaros-indictment-over-2022-coup-plot-7075422]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 22 Nov 2024 02:10:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Brazilian police on Thursday called for the indictment of ex-president Jair Bolsonaro over a 2022 "coup" plot to prevent current leader Luiz Inacio Lula da Silva from taking office.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Brazilian police on Thursday called for the indictment of ex-president Jair Bolsonaro over a 2022 "coup" plot to prevent current leader Luiz Inacio Lula da Silva from taking office.</p>

<p>A police statement said its investigators concluded that Bolsonaro and 36 others planned the "violent overthrow of the democratic state."</p>

<p>"Federal police concluded on Thursday the investigation into the existence of a criminal organization that acted in a coordinated way in 2002 in an attempt to maintain the then-president in power," the statement said.</p>

<p>"The final report has been sent to the Supreme Court with the request that 37 individuals be indicted for the crimes of the violent overthrow of the democratic state, coup d'etat and criminal organization," it said.</p>

<p>It is up to Brazil's attorney general to decide whether the allegations are substantiated enough to warrant criminal charges being laid. The charge of attempting a coup carries a sentence of up to 12 years in prison.</p>

<p>Bolsonaro vowed to "fight" the allegation, and accused the Supreme Court judge overseeing the case of overstepping the law.</p>

<p>"The fight begins at the Attorney General's office," Bolsonaro said on his X social media account.</p>

<p>The judge, Alexandre de Moraes, "leads the entire investigation, adjusts statements, arrests without charges, fishes for evidence and has a very creative advisory team. He does everything that the law does not say," Bolsonaro said.</p>

<p>According to police, the alleged plot was hatched in the final months of Bolsonaro's 2019-2022 presidency.</p>

<p>Lula, a left-winger who was previously president between 2003 and 2010, won October 2022 elections to succeed the far-right Bolsonaro.</p>

<p>The police statement did not draw a direct link between the alleged plot and an insurrection that took place in Brasilia on January 8, 2023, when thousands of Bolsonaro supporters entered the capital's presidential palace, the Congress building and the Supreme Court.</p>

<p>Investigations continue into that upheaval, which echoed scenes from the United States two years earlier, when supporters of Donald Trump protesting President Joe Biden's election win attacked the US Capitol in Washington on January 6, 2021.</p>

<p>Bolsonaro has expressed admiration for Trump in the past.</p>

<p>The list of alleged co-conspirators in the Bolsonaro case included the names of three elite soldiers and a police officer arrested on Tuesday for allegedly plotting to assassinate Lula and Moraes, in a separately announced case.</p>

<p><strong>Trump parallels&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p>Bolsonaro is the target of several investigations, but the one on Thursday placing him at the center of an alleged coup is the most dramatic.</p>

<p>He says he is innocent and the victim of "persecution."</p>

<p>A former army captain, Bolsonaro has already been declared ineligible to hold public office until 2030 for having made unsubstantiated claims of fraud in Brazil's electronic voting system.</p>

<p>He has been prohibited from leaving the country while a vast probe named "Tempus Veritatis" ("the time of truth" in Latin) continues. The investigation has already swept up several of Bolsonaro's closest aides.</p>

<p>Bolsonaro hopes to overturn the ineligibility ruling and attempt a comeback in 2026 presidential elections.</p>

<p>On X, he has posted parallels between his situation and that of Trump, who won over US voters this month to secure a return to the White House.</p>

<p>The police investigation calling for Bolsonaro's indictment detailed an alleged decree the ex-president was said to have given high-ranking military officers in December 2022 ordering them to arrest Moraes.</p>

<p>Moraes was head of the national electoral tribunal that validated Lula's victory in 2022.</p>

<p>That decree was confirmed by the military officers in police questioning, according to transcripts made public by Moraes, who is now in charge of the case at the Supreme Court.</p>

<p>According to a transcript released in March, a retired Brazilian army general, Marco Antonio Freire Gomes, had spoken to police investigators about the December 2022 meetings with Bolsonaro.</p>

<p>He said a Bolsonaro aide had seen legal opinions the then-president had had drawn up supporting his attempt to stay in power.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/6fv7imgg_brazil-expresident-bolsonaro_625x300_22_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The alleged plot was hatched in the final months of Jair Bolsonaro 2019-2022 presidency. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/world-leaders-split-as-icc-issues-arrest-warrant-for-netanyahu-7075339]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[World Leaders Split As ICC Issues Arrest Warrant For Netanyahu]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/world-leaders-split-as-icc-issues-arrest-warrant-for-netanyahu-7075339]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 22 Nov 2024 01:56:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel and its allies denounced the International Criminal Court's decision to issue an arrest warrant Thursday for Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu, even as Turkey -- and rights groups - welcomed the move.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel and its allies denounced the International Criminal Court's decision to issue an arrest warrant Thursday for Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu, even as Turkey -- and rights groups - welcomed the move.</p>

<p>The court also issued warrants for Israel's former defence minister as well as Hamas's military chief Mohammed Deif.</p>

<p>They were issued in response to accusations of crimes against humanity and war crimes in Israel's war on Hamas in Gaza, set off by the Palestinian group's October 7, 2023 attack.</p>

<p><strong>Israel: New 'Dreyfus trial'</strong></p>

<p>"The anti-Semitic decision of the International Criminal Court is comparable to the modern-day Dreyfus trial -- and it will end in the same way," Netanyahu said in a statement.</p>

<p>He was referring to the 19th-century Alfred Dreyfus affair in which a Jewish army captain was wrongly convicted of treason in France before being exonerated.</p>

<p><strong>US: 'Fundamentally rejects'</strong></p>

<p>The United States "fundamentally rejects" the ICC's decision and "we remain deeply concerned by the prosecutor's rush to seek arrest warrants and the troubling process errors that led to this decision", said a National Security Council spokesperson.</p>

<p>"The United States has been clear that the ICC does not have jurisdiction over this matter."</p>

<p><strong>Argentina: 'Deep disagreement'</strong></p>

<p>Argentina "declares its deep disagreement" with the decision, which "ignores Israel's legitimate right to self-defence against the constant attacks by terrorist organisations like Hamas and Hezbollah," President Javier Milei posted on X.</p>

<p><strong>Hamas: 'Justice'</strong></p>

<p>"(It's) an important step towards justice and can lead to redress for the victims in general, but it remains limited and symbolic if it is not supported by all means by all countries around the world," Hamas political bureau member Bassem Naim said of the warrants against Israeli politicians.</p>

<p><strong>European Union: 'Binding'</strong></p>

<p>"It is not a political decision," said EU foreign policy chief Josep Borrell, speaking during a visit to Jordan.</p>

<p>"It is a decision of a court, of a court of justice, of an international court of justice. And the decision of the court has to be respected and implemented."</p>

<p><strong>Israeli victims: 'Significant'</strong></p>

<p>"This arrest warrant against Mr Deif is massively significant," said Yael Vias Gvirsman, who represents 300 Israeli victims of the October 7 Hamas attacks.</p>

<p>"It means these victims' voices are being heard," she added, speaking from outside the court in The Hague.</p>

<p><strong>Palestinian Authority: 'Sign of hope'</strong></p>

<p>The Palestinian Authority, a rival of Hamas, said "the ICC's decision represents hope and confidence in international law and its institutions".</p>

<p>It urged ICC members to enforce "a policy of severing contact and meetings' with Netanyahu and Gallant.</p>

<p><strong>Amnesty International: 'Wanted man'</strong></p>

<p>"Prime Minister Netanyahu is now officially a wanted man," said Amnesty's Secretary General Agnes Callamard.</p>

<p>"ICC member states and the whole international community must stop at nothing until these individuals are brought to trial before the ICC's independent and impartial judges."</p>

<p><strong>Human Rights Watch: not 'beyond' the law</strong></p>

<p>"The ICC arrest warrants against senior Israeli leaders and a Hamas official break through the perception that certain individuals are beyond the reach of the law."</p>

<p><strong>Turkey: 'Positive decision'</strong></p>

<p>The ICC's decision "is a belated but positive decision to stop the bloodshed and put an end to the genocide in Palestine," Turkish Justice Minister Yilmaz Tunc said on X.</p>

<p>Foreign Minister Hakan Fidan welcomed the warrants as "an extremely important step".</p>

<p><strong>Italy: 'Will evaluate'</strong></p>

<p>Italian Defence Minister Guido Crosetto said his country would be obliged to arrest Netanyahu and Gallant if they visited, although he added he believed the ICC was "wrong" to put Netanyahu on the same level as Hamas.</p>

<p><strong>Spain: 'Respects the decision'</strong></p>

<p>Spain said it would follow the ruling, with official sources telling AFP the country "respects the decision and will conform to its commitments and obligations in compliance with the Rome Statute and international law".</p>

<p><strong>Norway: 'Confidence'</strong></p>

<p>"It is important that the ICC carries out its mandate in a judicious manner. I have confidence that the court will proceed with the case based on the highest fair trial standards," Foreign Minister Espen Barth Eide said.</p>

<p><strong>Sweden: 'Independence and integrity'</strong></p>

<p>"Sweden and the EU support the important work of the court and safeguard its independence and integrity," Foreign Minister Maria Malmer Stenergard said.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/c803ouj8_netanyahu-reuters_625x300_28_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The arrest were issued in response to accusations of crimes against humanity in Gaza. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/famous-iceland-geothermal-spa-covered-in-lava-post-volcanic-eruption-7075306]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Famous Iceland Geothermal Spa Covered In Lava Post Volcanic Eruption]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/famous-iceland-geothermal-spa-covered-in-lava-post-volcanic-eruption-7075306]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 22 Nov 2024 01:43:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Lava flowing from Iceland's latest volcanic eruption on Thursday engulfed the main parking lot of one of Iceland's biggest tourist attractions, the evacuated Blue Lagoon geothermal spa, images showed.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lava flowing from Iceland's latest volcanic eruption on Thursday engulfed the main parking lot of one of Iceland's biggest tourist attractions, the evacuated Blue Lagoon geothermal spa, images showed.</p>

<p>A black and orange tongue of lava could be seen covering the area that used to provide parking for 350 cars as well as space for coaches.</p>

<p>A service building used to store visitors' luggage was also engulfed by lava, but there appeared to be no immediate threat to the hot pools as the lava was held back by a defensive wall.</p>

<p>Helga Arnadottir, head of sales, operations and services at the Blue Lagoon, told the daily Morgunbladid she did not know when the site would be able to reopen to visitors.</p>

<p>She added that officials were currently "assessing the situation".</p>

<p>The fishing village of Grindavik and the Blue Lagoon were evacuated late Wednesday after an eruption in the Sundhnukagigar volcanic fissure on the Reykjanes peninsula for the seventh time in a year.</p>

<p>Most of Grindavik's 4,000 residents were evacuated a year ago, shortly before the first volcanic eruption in the area.</p>

<p>Since then, almost all the houses have been sold to the state, with its residents gone.</p>

<p>"About 50 houses were occupied in recent nights," said the civil protection department.</p>

<p>Volcanoes on the peninsula had not erupted for eight centuries until March 2021 when a period of heightened seismic activity began.</p>

<p>Volcanologists have warned that volcanic activity in the region has entered a new era.</p>

<p>Iceland is home to 33 active volcanic systems, more than any other European country.</p>

<p>It is located on the Mid-Atlantic Ridge, a fault in the ocean floor that separates the Eurasian and North American tectonic plates and causes earthquakes and eruptions.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/a1lu8q8o_iceland-lava_625x300_22_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[There appeared to be no immediate threat to the hot pools as the lava was held back by a defensive wall.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/netanyahu-says-icc-arrest-warrant-will-not-stop-israel-defending-itself-7075250]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Netanyahu Says ICC Arrest Warrant Will Not Stop Israel Defending Itself]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/netanyahu-says-icc-arrest-warrant-will-not-stop-israel-defending-itself-7075250]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 22 Nov 2024 01:25:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said Thursday that an arrest warrant issued against him by the International Criminal Court over his conduct of the Gaza war would not stop him defending Israel.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said Thursday that an arrest warrant issued against him by the International Criminal Court over his conduct of the Gaza war would not stop him defending Israel.</p>

<p>"No outrageous anti-Israel decision will prevent us -- and it will not prevent me -- from continuing to defend our country in every way," Netanyahu said in a video statement. "We will not yield to pressure," he vowed.</p>

<p>The premier is accused alongside his former defence minister Yoav Gallant of "war crimes" and "crimes against humanity" for Israel's actions in Gaza.</p>

<p>He described Thursday's decision as a "dark day in the history of nations".</p>

<p>"The International Criminal Court in The Hague, which was established to protect humanity, has today become the enemy of humanity," he said, adding that the accusations were "utterly baseless".</p>

<p>Israel has been fighting in Gaza since October 2023, when a cross-border attack by Hamas militants resulted in the deaths of 1,206 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally of Israeli official figures.</p>

<p>Its retaliatory campaign has led to the deaths of 44,056 people in Gaza, most of them civilians, according to figures from the Hamas-run territory's health ministry which the United Nations considers reliable.</p>

<p>UN agencies have warned of a severe humanitarian crisis in Gaza, including possible famine, due to a lack of food and medicines.</p>

<p>The court said it had found "reasonable grounds" to believe Netanyahu and Gallant bore "criminal responsibility" for the war crime of starvation as a method of warfare, as well as the crimes against humanity of murder, persecution, and other inhumane acts.</p>

<p>Netanyahu said the court was accusing Israel of "fictitious crimes", while ignoring "the real war crimes, horrific war crimes being committed against us and against many others around the world".</p>

<p>In addition to Netanyahu and Gallant, the court also issued an arrest warrant for Hamas military wing chief Mohammed Deif, who Israel said was killed in an air strike last July.</p>

<p>Hamas has never confirmed his death.</p>

<p>Netanyahu mocked the court's decision to issue a warrant for "the body of Mohammed Deif."</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/9c8o8p0g_netanyahu-reuters_625x300_19_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Benjamin Netanyahu said the court was accusing Israel of "fictitious crimes". (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/netanyahu-to-face-arrest-if-he-visits-italy-says-minister-after-icc-warrant-7075213]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Netanyahu To Face Arrest If He Visits Italy, Says Minister After ICC Warrant]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/netanyahu-to-face-arrest-if-he-visits-italy-says-minister-after-icc-warrant-7075213]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 22 Nov 2024 01:16:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Italian Defence Minister Guido Crosetto said Thursday his country would be obliged to arrest Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu if he visited, after the International Criminal Court issued a warrant.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Italian Defence Minister Guido Crosetto said Thursday his country would be obliged to arrest Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu if he visited, after the International Criminal Court issued a warrant.</p>

<p>The ICC earlier also issued arrest warrants for Netanyahu's former defence minister, Yoav Gallant, as well as Hamas's military chief Mohammed Deif.</p>

<p>Crosetto -- whose country holds the G7 rotating presidency this year -- told RAI television's Porta a Porta programme that he believed the ICC was "wrong" to put Netanyahu and Gallant on the same level as Hamas.</p>

<p>But he said that if Netanyahu or Gallant "were to come to Italy, we would have to arrest them".</p>

<p>It was not a political choice but Italy was bound as a member of the ICC to act on the court's warrants, Crosetto said.</p>

<p>Foreign Minister Antonio Tajani had earlier been more cautious, saying: "We support the ICC, while always remembering that the court must play a legal role and not a political role.</p>

<p>"We will evaluate together with our allies what to do and how to interpret this decision."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/l2gd1mb8_netanyahu_625x300_22_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Italy is bound as a member of the ICC to act on the court's warrants. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-sec-chief-gary-gensler-to-step-down-clearing-way-for-trumps-pick-7075134]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US SEC Chief Gary Gensler To Step Down Clearing Way For Trump's Pick]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-sec-chief-gary-gensler-to-step-down-clearing-way-for-trumps-pick-7075134]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:55:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The top US securities regulator, a skeptic towards cryptocurrency who was appointed by President Joe Biden, announced Thursday he will step down in January when Donald Trump takes office.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The top US securities regulator, a skeptic towards cryptocurrency who was appointed by President Joe Biden, announced Thursday he will step down in January when Donald Trump takes office.</p>

<p>Gary Gensler, chair of the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC), said he will resign on January 20, the same day Trump assumes the presidency. The move clears the way for the Republican president-elect to pick Gensler's successor.</p>

<p>The news comes as bitcoin hit a fresh record of $98,473,64 on Thursday.</p>

<p>Gensler's five-year term does not end until 2026, but agency chairs customarily step down when the party of presidential administration turns over.</p>

<p>Gensler took office in April 2021 shortly after the so-called "meme stock" frenzy in January 2021 prompted massive volatility in GameStop and a handful of other stocks.</p>

<p>A former mergers and acquisitions partner at Goldman Sachs, Gensler led rulemaking proposals intended to improve efficiency in capital markets.</p>

<p>But his future in Washington looked precarious in light of the SEC's confrontational approach to cryptocurrency throughout the Biden years.</p>

<p>During the campaign, Trump drew heavy financial support from cryptocurrency backers, some of whom are also close to the president-elect's close ally, Tesla and SpaceX CEO Elon Musk.</p>

<p>In the absence of clear regulations, Gensler took an aggressive stance toward digital currencies, treating them like traditional financial securities such as stocks and bonds.</p>

<p>The approach has prompted SEC lawsuits against major trading platforms including Binance, Coinbase, and Kraken, along with various smaller startups.</p>

<p>Leading legislation in Washington would shift oversight to the Commodities Futures Trading Commission, known for its lighter-touch approach to regulation.</p>

<p>Gensler thanked Biden and fellow commissioners, saying in a statement, "The SEC has met our mission and enforced the law without fear or favor."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/53nq908o_gary-gensler_625x300_22_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The news comes as bitcoin hit a fresh record of $98,473,64 on Thursday. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/noted-surgeon-dr-mathew-varghese-named-the-one-international-7075021]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Noted Surgeon Dr Mathew Varghese Named 'The One International']]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/noted-surgeon-dr-mathew-varghese-named-the-one-international-7075021]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:28:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Noted orthopaedic surgeon Dr Mathew Varghese was named The One International at the prestigious The One gala dinner and award ceremony in Hong Kong.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Noted orthopaedic surgeon Dr Mathew Varghese was named The One International at the prestigious The One gala dinner and award ceremony in Hong Kong.</p>

<p>Launched in 2012 by David Harilela and Rotary International District 3450, The One Humanitarian Award celebrates individuals who have dedicated their lives to alleviating pain, suffering and poverty.</p>

<p>Over HK$2.5 million was awarded to remarkable individuals from Africa, India, and Hong Kong.</p>

<p>Dr Varghese is renowned for pioneering reconstructive surgeries for polio sufferers in India. He is a hero to his patients and other admirers, including Microsoft founder Bill Gates.</p>

<p>On his Facebook page, Mr Gates had described Dr Varghese as "my inspiration and my real-life hero" for "fighting and (having) dedicated his life for polio eradication in India". He is also the co-author of the book 'When Someone Has Hurt', a first aid guide that has been translated into five languages, and 'Prehospital Trauma Care System', which was published by the World Health Organisation (WHO).</p>

<p>Father John Wotherspoon, a dedicated priest aiding drug addicts and the homeless in Yau Ma Tei, was awarded The One Hong Kong.</p>

<p>The international finalists included Dr Satish Gogulwar, who delivers life-saving medical services to tribal communities in India, and Dr Paul Thistle, a surgeon and educator making significant strides in Zimbabwe.</p>

<p>The Hong Kong finalists featured Elli Fu Nga-nei, founder of J Life Foundation, which supports the underprivileged community and Morgan Lam Kai-fai of Hope Through Music, which empowers disadvantaged youth through musical education.</p>

<p>The One has recognised 74 heroes and contributed over US$3.3 million to humanitarian projects, impacting more than three lakh lives globally.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/gi2796hg_dr-mathew-varghese_625x300_22_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Dr Mathew Varghese is renowned for pioneering reconstructive surgeries for polio sufferers]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-korea-court-jails-ex-fiance-of-olympic-medalist-for-13-years-7075013]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[South Korea Court Jails Ex-Fiance Of Olympic Medalist For 13 Years]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-korea-court-jails-ex-fiance-of-olympic-medalist-for-13-years-7075013]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:24:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A South Korean appellate court on Thursday sentenced a former fiance of Olympic fencing medalist Nam Hyun-hee to 13 years in prison for swindling dozens of people out of more than 3.5 billion won ($2.5 million) under the guise of a chaebol heir.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A South Korean appellate court on Thursday sentenced a former fiance of Olympic fencing medalist Nam Hyun-hee to 13 years in prison for swindling dozens of people out of more than 3.5 billion won ($2.5 million) under the guise of a chaebol heir.</p>

<p>The Seoul High Court handed down the sentence to Jeon Cheong-jo, 28, saying she continued to commit fraud even after being released from prison after serving time for previous fraud convictions, including by disguising herself as a man in order to date famous people, Yonhap news agency reported.</p>

<p>The ruling adds one year to a lower court's sentence of 12 years in prison.</p>

<p>"Most of the money was spent on purchasing luxury items, making it difficult to reverse the damage to victims," the court said, noting a total of 35 people were swindled out of a combined 3.5 billion won.</p>

<p>The court also cited a "very high risk of a repeat offence".</p>

<p>Jeon gained notoriety following revelations last year that she had been engaged to Nam, the silver medalist in women's foil at the 2008 Beijing Olympics, under the guise of a man claiming to be an heir to the Paradise Hotel chain. The couple later broke up.</p>

<p>In September, Jeon was sentenced to an additional four years in prison for assaulting and threatening Nam's nephew, but the appellate court combined the two cases at Jeon's request.</p>

<p>The prosecution had demanded a 20-year prison term for Jeon.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2019-07/att9hsso_court-generic_625x300_27_July_19.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The ruling adds one year to a lower court's sentence of 12 years in prison. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-pick-matt-gaetz-withdraws-as-nominee-for-us-attorney-general-7074981]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Pick Matt Gaetz Withdraws As Nominee For US Attorney General]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-pick-matt-gaetz-withdraws-as-nominee-for-us-attorney-general-7074981]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:17:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Scandal-plagued Matt Gaetz, who was nominated by President-elect Donald Trump to be US attorney general, on Thursday pulled out of the confirmation process in an early setback for the incoming administration.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Scandal-plagued Matt Gaetz, who was nominated by President-elect Donald Trump to be US attorney general, on Thursday pulled out of the confirmation process in an early setback for the incoming administration.</p>

<p>Gaetz was one of Trump's several eye-catching selections, including Fox News host Pete Hegseth as defense secretary, vaccine skeptic Robert F. Kennedy Jr. as health secretary and billionaire Elon Musk to head a government cost-cutting unit.</p>

<p>A congressional panel had been investigating alleged illegal activity by Gaetz, including sexual misconduct with a 17-year-old girl -- which he denies -- as well as drug use and misappropriating campaign funds.</p>

<p>He was facing an uphill battle to win confirmation in the Senate for the top legal role of attorney general due to widespread opposition, including from within his own Republican Party.</p>

<p>"I had excellent meetings with Senators yesterday. I appreciate their thoughtful feedback -- and the incredible support of so many," Gaetz said on X.</p>

<p>"While the momentum was strong, it is clear that my confirmation was unfairly becoming a distraction to the critical work of the Trump/Vance Transition."</p>

<p>Gaetz was first elected to the US House of Representatives in 2016 and won reelection this month, but he resigned as a congressman shortly after Trump picked him to be attorney general.</p>

<p>"Matt has a wonderful future, and I look forward to watching all of the great things he will do," Trump said in response to his withdrawal.</p>

<p>Several of Trump's nominations have triggered criticism, and the latest transition turmoil came as new lurid details emerged about Defense nominee Hegseth.</p>

<p>He was investigated for sexual assault after a complaint from an unnamed woman at a 2017 conference in California.</p>

<p>The New York Times reported details from the police investigation, which was closed without Hegseth being charged.</p>

<p>The married woman told officers that she suffered from memory loss and thought her drink might have been spiked, while Hegseth said the encounter was consensual.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/6q6mppd_matt-gaetz_625x300_22_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Trump pick Matt Gaetz was first elected to the US House of Representatives in 2016. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/dark-moment-israeli-envoy-reuven-azar-on-international-criminal-court-arrest-warrant-against-benjamin-netanyahu-7074945]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Dark Moment": Israeli Envoy On World Court's 'Arrest Netanyahu Order']]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/dark-moment-israeli-envoy-reuven-azar-on-international-criminal-court-arrest-warrant-against-benjamin-netanyahu-7074945]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:09:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The International Criminal Court's move to issue arrest warrants for Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu and defence minister Yoav Gallant is a "dark moment" for the court, Israel's Ambassador to India Reuven Azar has said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The International Criminal Court (ICC)'s move to issue arrest warrants for Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu and defence minister Yoav Gallant is a "dark moment" for the court, which acted "without authority" and set a "dangerous precedent", Israel's Ambassador to India Reuven Azar said on Thursday.</p>

<p>In a statement, Mr Azar alleged the world court in The Hague is "serving as a political tool for the most extreme elements working against peace, security and stability in West Asia". The decision to issue the warrants weakens the possibility of reaching a ceasefire deal with those seeking Israel's destruction, he said.</p>

<p>The remarks came hours after ICC issued the warrants of arrest for the two Israeli leaders for "crimes against humanity and war crimes committed from at least 8 October 2023 until at least 20 May 2024". The court also issued a similar warrant for Hamas military chief Mohammed Deif.</p>

<p>Israel said in early August it had killed Deif in an air strike in southern Gaza in July, but Hamas has not confirmed his death. Israel is currently engaged in a conflict with Hamas in Gaza and Hezbollah in Lebanon.</p>

<p>The ICC has no power to enforce its warrants but technically, any country that has signed the Rome Statute - a treaty that seeks to prosecute individuals accused of genocide, crimes against humanity, war crimes and crimes of aggression - would be obliged to arrest Mr Netanyahu, Mr Gallant, or Mr Deif, if they travelled there.</p>

<p>"The ICC acted without authority against the elected leaders of a democracy which is not a member of the court. It's a dangerous precedent," Mr Azar said.</p>

<p>"These are warrants directed not only personally against our leaders. In fact, this is an attack on Israel's right to defend itself. The decision is a moral deficiency that turns good into bad and serves evil. The decision harms the ability of a democracy to fight terrorism," he added.</p>

<p>Mr Azar also said that the world court "completely ignores Israel's actions according to international law to facilitate humanitarian assistance to the Palestinian needy population and its outstanding actions to minimise civilian casualties despite despicable tactics used by the terrorists, including using civilians as human shields."</p>

<p>"As a democracy, Israel has a strong legal system that is capable, able and willing to check the actions of its government. We call all our friends to publicly reject this injustice," he said.</p>

<p>On October 7 last year, Hamas militants conducted a cross-border raid on Israel that killed 1,206 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally of Israeli official figures. Israel has since then been fighting a war in Gaza, which the militant group rules.</p>

<p>Israel, however, has faced growing international criticism over its conduct of the Gaza war, including from its allies, despite global solidarity with the victims of October 7.</p>

<p>The Hamas government's health ministry in the Gaza Strip said on Thursday that at least 44,056 people have been killed in more than 13 months of war.</p>

<p>Hezbollah, the powerful Iran-backed Lebanese militant group, began firing rockets into Israel in October last year in stated support of Hamas.</p>

<p>After nearly a year of limited exchanges of fire on the Israel-Lebanon border, Israel in September this year intensified its air strikes primarily targeting Hezbollah strongholds and later sent ground troops into Lebanon.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/h903pudo_netanyahu_625x300_10_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/un-calls-use-of-new-russian-missile-in-ukraine-worrying-7074940]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UN Calls Use Of New Russian Missile In Ukraine "Worrying"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/un-calls-use-of-new-russian-missile-in-ukraine-worrying-7074940]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:05:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russia's use of a new medium-range ballistic missile to strike Ukraine was a "worrying development," the spokesman for UN Secretary-General Antonio Guterres said Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russia's use of a new medium-range ballistic missile to strike Ukraine was a "worrying development," the spokesman for UN Secretary-General Antonio Guterres said Thursday.</p>

<p>"This is yet another concerning and worrying development. All of this (is) going in the wrong direction," said Stephane Dujarric, calling on all parties to de-escalate the conflict.</p>

<p>He repeated UN chief Antonio Guterres's call for an end to the war in compliance with international law, and urged both sides "to protect civilians, not hit civilian targets or critical civilian infrastructure."</p>

<p>Russian President Vladimir Putin said Thursday that his country's forces had hit Ukraine with a new mid-range hypersonic ballistic missile, dubbed the "Oreshnik," in a "non-nuclear" configuration.</p>

<p>Russia struck the central Ukrainian city of Dnipro with a barrage of missiles early Thursday.</p>

<p>This week, the United States further ramped up aid to its Ukrainian ally by authorizing the supply of anti-personnel landmines, a major policy shift slammed by rights groups.</p>

<p>Asked about the US decision, Dujarric reiterated the UN's opposition to the use of those weapons.</p>

<p>"Our stand against the use of mines anywhere in the world remains the same," he said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/jnf8l4sk_russia-nuclear-missile-drill-reuters_625x300_29_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Russia struck the central Ukrainian city of Dnipro with a barrage of missiles early Thursday.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/all-countries-reject-climate-finance-draft-leaving-cop29-in-crisis-7074922]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[All Countries Reject Climate Finance Draft Leaving COP29 In Crisis]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/all-countries-reject-climate-finance-draft-leaving-cop29-in-crisis-7074922]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:01:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A draft text released early Thursday on a new climate finance package for the developing world was rejected by every single country signatory to the UN climate convention.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A draft text released early Thursday on a new climate finance package for the developing world was rejected by every single country signatory to the UN climate convention.</p>

<p>The COP29 presidency, however, said the draft was far from final and invited countries to submit bridging proposals.</p>

<p>The next version, due Thursday night, will be leaner and packed with numbers aimed at finding the sweet spot for consensus, it said in a statement.</p>

<p>The text shows that developed countries are still dodging a key question: how much climate finance are they ready to provide developing countries every year starting in 2025? The developing world has repeatedly said it needs at least USD 1.3 trillion annually -- 13 times the USD 100 billion pledged in 2009 -- to meet the growing challenges.</p>

<p>Although developed countries have yet to officially propose a figure, their negotiators indicated that European Union nations were discussing a global climate finance target of USD 200 billion to USD 300 billion per year.</p>

<p>However, in the words of Colombian Environment Minister Susana Muhamad, the critical objective of this COP is, right now, an "empty placeholder".</p>

<p>The problem is not that developed countries lack money; the problem is that they are playing geopolitics, she said in an impassioned speech, drawing applause from a plenary full of negotiators, observers, and journalists.</p>

<p>The G77, the largest negotiating bloc at the UN climate talks with over 130 developing nations, said they have been very clear that "we should not leave Baku without a quantum".</p>

<p>Adonia Ayebare, the G77 chair, denounced the developed countries' attempt to turn the climate finance package into a global investment goal that would draw funding from a variety of sources, including governments, private companies and investors.</p>

<p>"We are disappointed that the draft text doesn't even specify a quantum for provisional mobilization," said Bolivia's Diego Pacheco, on behalf of Like-Minded Developing Countries, which includes India.</p>

<p>African Group of Negotiators chair Ali Mohamed said they were deeply concerned by the "lack of mention of quantum". "This quantum is the main mandate for which we are here at COP29." European Union's climate chief Wopke Hoekstra called the draft "imbalanced, unworkable, and not acceptable".</p>

<p>Panama's negotiator Juan Carlos Monterrey Gomez said developed countries call developing countries' proposal for USD 1.3 trillion a year in climate finance "extreme and unreasonable". "Let me tell you what is extreme and unreasonable, spending USD 7 trillion on fossil fuel subsidies".</p>

<p>"Developed countries must stop playing games with our life and put a serious quantified financial proposal on the table," he said.</p>

<p>Pakistan, still reeling from the aftermath of the devastating 2022 floods, said an ambitious outcome on the climate finance package was particularly important for them, but the text lacked "concrete numbers on the quantum.</p>

<p>At the heart of this year's UN climate talks is the new climate finance goal or NCQG aimed at helping developing countries cut emissions and cope with the mounting impacts of climate change.</p>

<p>Developing nations argue they need at least USD 1.3 trillion a year to keep up with the escalating challenges.</p>

<p>But trust is in short supply. Developed nations only hit the USD 100 billion target in 2022 -- two years late -- and a hefty 70 per cent of those funds came as loans, further straining nations already reeling from climate disasters.</p>

<p>Now, developing nations are demanding that most of the funding come straight from developed countries' public coffers. They reject the idea of leaning on the private sector, which they say is more interested in profit than accountability.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the US and EU are pushing for a more expansive global investment goal that draws from public, private, domestic, and international sources. They are also urging wealthier countries like China and Gulf states -- classified as developing in 1992 -- to chip in, pointing to their more prosperous status today.</p>

<p>Developing nations see this as a clever move to avoid responsibility for past emissions by shifting the burden to those who industrialized more recently.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/jjlggl0c_cop29-climate-summit-reuters_625x300_12_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The COP29 president said the draft was far from final and asked countries to submit bridging proposals.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/putin-says-russia-hit-ukraine-with-new-mid-range-ballistic-missile-7074880]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Putin Says Russia Hit Ukraine With New Mid-Range Ballistic Missile]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/putin-says-russia-hit-ukraine-with-new-mid-range-ballistic-missile-7074880]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 21 Nov 2024 23:54:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russian President Vladimir Putin said Thursday that the country's forces had hit Ukraine with a new mid-range ballistic missile.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russian President Vladimir Putin said Thursday that the country's forces had hit Ukraine with a new mid-range ballistic missile.</p>

<p>Putin said in a televised address that Russia carried out "testing in combat conditions of one of the newest Russian mid-range missile systems... Our engineers named it Oreshnik," which means hazel tree in Russian.</p>

<p>Russia struck the central Ukrainian city of Dnipro with a barrage of missiles early Thursday.</p>

<p>The Ukrainian air force and President Volodymyr Zelensky accused Russia of apparently using an intercontinental ballistic missile, while Ukrainian experts were still examining the evidence to ascertain the type of missile used.</p>

<p>Putin said in his address that Russia launched a combined strike on a defence industry target in Ukraine.</p>

<p>He described Oreshnik as a "ballistic missile" that was deployed in this case "in a non-nuclear hypersonic configuration", saying that the "test" had been successful and had hit its target.</p>

<p>Air defences cannot intercept the Oreshnik, which attacks at a speed of Mach 10, or 2.5-3 kilometres per second, Putin said.</p>

<p>"Modern air defence systems... cannot intercept such missiles. That's impossible," he said.</p>

<p>"As of today there are no means of counteracting such a weapon," the president boasted.</p>

<p>He said Russia was testing the Oreshnik in combat conditions "in response to the aggressive actions of NATO countries towards Russia."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ksed4kkg_putin_625x300_20_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Putin said in his address that Russia launched a combined strike on a defence industry target in Ukraine.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-army-chief-bestowed-with-rank-of-honourary-general-of-nepali-army-7074841]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Indian Army Chief Bestowed With Rank Of Honourary General Of Nepalese Army]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-army-chief-bestowed-with-rank-of-honourary-general-of-nepali-army-7074841]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 21 Nov 2024 23:48:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Showcasing the strong ties between the two countries, Indian Army Chief General Upendra Dwivedi was on Thursday conferred with the prestigious rank of Honourary General of the Nepalese Army.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Showcasing the strong ties between the two countries, Indian Army Chief Gen Upendra Dwivedi was on Thursday conferred with the prestigious rank of Honourary General of the Nepali Army.</p>

<p>This exchange of honourary generalship, a unique and cherished tradition between the Indian and Nepali Armies, highlights the deep-rooted historical, cultural, and military ties between the two nations.</p>

<p>General Dwivedi reached Kathmandu on Wednesday on a five-day official visit upon the invitation of General Ashok Raj Sigdel, Chief of the Army Staff, Nepali Army.</p>

<p>The tradition of conferring honourary generalships between the Indian and Nepali Armies dates back to the 1950s. Every three years, the Chief of the Indian Army is made an Honourary General of the Nepali Army, and vice versa.</p>

<p>This practice reflects the mutual respect and enduring friendship between the two countries, particularly in the realms of military cooperation, defence collaboration, and shared strategic interests, a release said.</p>

<p>This symbolic exchange of titles goes beyond mere ceremony--it is a powerful testament to the longstanding solidarity, trust, and commitment to peace and stability in the region.</p>

<p>The tradition underscores the strong strategic partnership between the two forces, who work closely on a variety of fronts, including joint training, military exercises, and disaster response.</p>

<p>Both armies share similar values and a commitment to regional security, making this gesture of honour a reflection of their unity and shared purpose.</p>

<p>The Honourary Generalship is particularly meaningful given the unique socio-cultural bonds and open borders between India and Nepal. With shared security interests and a deep sense of camaraderie, the exchange of titles serves as a reminder of the close ties that transcend formal diplomatic relations.</p>

<p>It reinforces the enduring friendship and cooperation that have defined the relationship between the two nations for decades.</p>

<p>General Dwivedi's visit and the conferral of this honour will not only strengthen military ties but also serve as a reflection of the deep respect between the two countries' armed forces, further advancing the spirit of cooperation and mutual understanding.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/hka8k8bo_general-upendra-dwivedi_625x300_01_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Indian Army Chief Gen Upendra Dwivedi reached Kathmandu on Wednesday. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>