<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Fri, 08 Nov 2024 09:09:10 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/why-did-kamala-harris-lose-because-democrats-guilt-tripped-americans-6969672]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: Why Did Kamala Harris Lose? Because Democrats Guilt-Tripped Americans]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/why-did-kamala-harris-lose-because-democrats-guilt-tripped-americans-6969672]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 08 Nov 2024 08:05:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kamala Harriss campaign raised and spent more money than Donald Trump, but what was the substance? The political messaging barely managed to escape the rhetoric of Save America from Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont">
<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/4sb4k218_kamala-harris_625x300_07_November_24.jpeg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>

<p>It's not misogyny that defeated Kamala Harris. There is a certain insincerity lurking behind this explanation for the decisive victory of the Republican Party, which has led to the installation of Donald Trump, once again, in the White House.&nbsp;</p>

<p>It is the same insincerity with which the Harris-Walz campaign was carried out for months. In the face of an ‘unexpected' debacle, the Democrats in the US, along with other politicians across the world, will do well to introspect. What, indeed, was the problem?</p>

<p>It is easy to employ feminism to explain away Trump's triumph over two women in less than a decade. What is being forgotten easily here is the fact that she was recruited in a huff to replace Joe Biden, who was sure to have lost to Trump. An afterthought. The Democrats were desperate to fight anti-incumbency but addressed it from the wrong end.</p>

<h2><strong>A Guilt Bait</strong></h2>

<p>Harris was used by her party as guilt-inducing bait in the 2024 presidential election, and her defeat has important lessons for everyone. First and most obviously, you cannot guilt-trip voters into supporting you unconditionally. The Harris-Walz campaign doubled down on making the undecided voter feel guilt-ridden for even considering a change. There was a complete lack of self-awareness on the part of campaign designers and ideological Democrat voters that their policies may have anything to do with people's dissatisfaction. Or they knew and smugly brushed it off, armed with weapons of collective guilt. This smugness caused a swing.</p>

<p>The most palpable example of this is the Democrats' tone-deafness around the war in West Asia. In a year marked by relentless anti-war campaigns and demonstrations, Democrats believed Dick Cheney to be their trump card. Cheney's hawkish attitude as George W. Bush's vice-president left a legacy of violence and human rights violations in the US and everywhere else the country intervened militarily. Harris's claims to usher in peace fell flat in the face of such crude irony. Depending on how disappointed or angry they were, anti-war Democrats sat the election out, cross-voted for Trump, or voted for the third alternative to mark their dissent.</p>

<h2><strong>Thick Cosmopolitanism</strong></h2>

<p>Democrats' adaptation of what political scientists call the theory of ‘thick cosmopolitanism' in the domestic domain of immigration did not work in securing them a consecutive second term. The theory argues that when people realise their ingroup's culpability in causing harm to people living in distant nations, they adopt a cosmopolitan helping demeanour. The inherent limitation of the theory, as demonstrated by Nicholas Faulkner, and the revelation of Democrats' hypocrisy ensured that voters rejected their guilt-tripping political campaign. This may partially explain why a substantial diaspora cohort swung towards Trump.&nbsp;</p>

<p>But Democrats were counting on brow-beating dissent with guilt. Unfortunately for them, this strategy backfired. Scholars Gunn and Wilson propose that collective guilt, an important political tool, is often undercut by defensiveness. The Democratic Party forgot that just as an attack on personal identity makes an individual defensive, people are wont to react with defensiveness when their social identities are threatened. Calling voters racist and sexist before, during, and after the polls, Democrats inspired a surge of defensiveness across multiple demographic groups.</p>

<h2><strong>Nobody Knew What Kamala Was About</strong></h2>

<p>Kamala Harris's campaign raised and spent more money than Donald Trump, but what was the substance? The political messaging barely managed to escape the rhetoric of ‘Save America from Trump'. Reeling under high inflation rates, American voters felt invisible when no concrete policy measures were offered for this ‘Save America' operation. The Republicans are guilty of running the same banal campaign, but they had anti-incumbency on their side. Memories of Trump's previous presidency were fading, and that helped him. Trump's campaign counted on the fickleness of public memory and put its bets on people's ability to forget the past when they are obsessing about ongoing concerns.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Team Harris, on the other hand, weaponised memories of the fractured American past to make this election about correcting historical wrongs. Psychologists warn that people do not necessarily react well when confronted with problematic actions of their own. Political scientist Eunbin Chung proposed in the context of East Asia that national identity affirmation can be employed “as a way of disarming the defensiveness that is prompted from recognising guilt of one's country, allowing more prosocial responses to emerge”. Democrats, however, fell short in offering a positive spin to the American identity in a bid to counter its chequered racial history.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>Competitive Defensiveness</strong></h2>

<p>Add to this the Biden administration's no-limits support to Israel despite the growing anti-war chime even within the rank and file of the Democratic Party, and we got a game of competitive defensiveness all around. The leadership and the voters stopped listening to each other.&nbsp;</p>

<p>To peg this defeat as only a misogynistic mistake, therefore, is oversimplifying the matters. This is how Democrats wish to continue to play the guilting game without a shred of introspection.&nbsp;</p>

<p><em>(Nishtha Gautam is a Delhi-based author and academic.)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/4sb4k218_kamala-harris_625x300_07_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-fed-cuts-interest-rates-a-quarter-point-after-trump-victory-6969576]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Fed Cuts Interest Rates A Quarter Point After Trump Victory]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-fed-cuts-interest-rates-a-quarter-point-after-trump-victory-6969576]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 08 Nov 2024 07:37:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The US Federal Reserve shrugged off concerns about the impact of Donald Trump's election victory on interest rates and moved ahead with a quarter point cut Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The US Federal Reserve shrugged off concerns about the impact of Donald Trump's election victory on interest rates and moved ahead with a quarter point cut Thursday.</p>

<p>The Fed sits just a short walk from the White House, where Democratic President Joe Biden will in January hand back the keys to Trump following the Republican's election win.</p>

<p>But as expected, policymakers ignored the political drama playing out up the road, voting unanimously to reduce interest rates by 25 basis points to between 4.50 and 4.75 percent, the Fed said in a statement.</p>

<p>"In the near term, the election will have no effects on our policy decisions," Fed Chair Jerome Powell told reporters, noting there was still uncertainty about what President-elect Trump's actual economic agenda would be.</p>

<p>"We don't guess, we don't speculate, and we don't assume," he said.</p>

<p>Powell also said he would not resign if asked to leave early by the president-elect, adding that firing any of the Fed's seven governors was "not permitted under the law."</p>

<p>The US central bank's rate decision should help ease the costs of mortgages and other loans -- welcome news for consumers, who had widely cited the cost of living as a top concern ahead of Tuesday's vote.</p>

<p>But the cost of borrowing will also depend on how financial markets think a Trump victory will impact the economy over the longer term, and where the Fed's interest rates will need to settle to ensure inflation remains now.</p>

<p>'Economy looks quite resilient'</p>

<p>Experts have pointed to the post-pandemic surge in US inflation -- which saw consumer prices rise more than 20 percent -- as playing a major factor in Trump's victory.</p>

<p>Thursday's decision adds to a previous rate cut in September, when the Fed kicked off its easing cycle with a larger half point decrease, and penciled in additional rate reductions this year.</p>

<p>The Fed's favored inflation gauge has since eased to 2.1 percent in September, while economic growth has remained robust.</p>

<p>The labor market has also stayed strong overall, despite a sharp hiring slowdown last month attributed in large part to adverse weather conditions and a labor strike.</p>

<p>"Generally speaking, the US economy looks quite resilient, and the labor market still looks very good," Jim Bullard, the long-serving former St Louis Fed president, told AFP ahead of Election Day.</p>

<p>Bullard, now dean of the Daniels School of Business at Purdue University, predicted a 25 basis point cut this week, and another cut of a similar size in December.</p>

<p>Futures traders place a probability of around 65 percent that the Fed will cut by a quarter of a percentage-point next month, according to data from CME Group.</p>

<p>But analysts remain split over what the Fed will do next month.</p>

<p>Fiscal discipline 'broken down'</p>

<p>With a Trump victory assured, a lot still depends on whether Republicans can hold onto the House of Representatives, as they appear on track to do -- giving them a "Red Sweep" of both houses of Congress along with the White House.</p>

<p>"Markets tend to like divided government as a way to control spending and keep deficits down," said Bullard.</p>

<p>"What's distressing to an economist like me is that, really, fiscal discipline has broken down for both political parties," he said.</p>

<p>Trump has repeatedly accused Powell -- whom he first appointed to run the US central bank -- of working to favor the Democrats, and has suggested he would look to replace him once his term expires in 2026.</p>

<p>The president-elect has also said he would like "at least" a say over setting the Fed's interest rate -- something that runs against the Fed's current mandate to act independently of Congress and the White House to tackle inflation and unemployment.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/os662ulg_donald-trump_625x300_07_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/susie-wiles-donald-trumps-aid-and-1st-woman-white-house-chief-of-staff-6969540]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["First-Ever In US History": Trump Picks A Woman White House Chief Of Staff]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/susie-wiles-donald-trumps-aid-and-1st-woman-white-house-chief-of-staff-6969540]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 08 Nov 2024 07:23:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Susie Wiles, who is credited for Donald Trump's successful presidential bid, is the daughter of Pat Summerall, a prominent football player and sportscaster.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President-elect Donald Trump on Thursday announced that his campaign manager, Susie Wiles, will be his White House chief of staff. Wiles, 67, will become the first woman to hold the position in the US history.</p>

<p>"Susie Wiles just helped me achieve one of the greatest political victories in American history, and was an integral part of both my 2016 and 2020 successful campaigns," Trump said two days after his decisive US election win over Democrat Kamala Harris.</p>

<p>She is "tough, smart, innovative, and is universally admired and respected", the 78-year-old Republican said.</p>

<p>"It is a well-deserved honour to have Susie as the first-ever female Chief of Staff in United States history," he added.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">President Donald J. Trump Announces Susan Summerall Wiles as White House Chief of Staff <a href="https://t.co/rzU3Zj6d0j">pic.twitter.com/rzU3Zj6d0j</a></p>
— Team Trump (Text TRUMP to 88022) (@TeamTrump) <a href="https://twitter.com/TeamTrump/status/1854655827350581726?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 7, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Wiles, along with fellow campaign manager Chris LaCivita, are credited for <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-2-0-jd-vance-elon-musk-a-galaxy-of-contrarian-characters-set-for-white-house-stints-6961648" target="_blank">Trump's successful presidential bid</a>.</p>

<p>Trump also gave a shout-out to Wiles during his victory speech on Wednesday.</p>

<p>"We call her the 'ice baby'... Susie likes to stay in the background," he said.</p>

<p>US Vice President-elect JD Vance called it a "great news" and said Susie was a "huge asset" to Trump on the campaign.</p>

<p>"She will be a huge asset in the White House. She's also just a really good person," he said.</p>

<h3><strong>Who Is Susie Wiles</strong></h3>

<p>Born on May 14, 1957, Susie Wiles is the daughter of Pat Summerall, who was a prominent football player and sportscaster.</p>

<p>A long-time Florida-based political strategist, she has previously worked on Ronald Reagan's 1980 presidential campaign and helped Florida's Republican Governor Ron DeSantis win the election in 2018.</p>

<p>Early in her career, she also worked for Republican US representatives Jack Kemp and Tillie Fowler.</p>

<p>Wiles also served briefly as the manager of former Utah Governor Jon Huntsman Jr's 2012 presidential campaign.</p>

<p>She served as a senior adviser on <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-age-family-net-worth-political-career-and-more-6558144" target="_blank">Trump's 2016 and 2020 bids</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/eqh3l0to_susie-wiles_625x300_08_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Susie Wiles served as a senior adviser on Trump's 2016 and 2020 bids.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/i-dont-see-my-future-in-us-elon-musks-transgender-daughter-after-trumps-win-6969535]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["I Don't See Future In US": Musk's Transgender Daughter After Trump's Win]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/i-dont-see-my-future-in-us-elon-musks-transgender-daughter-after-trumps-win-6969535]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 08 Nov 2024 07:20:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Following Donald Trump's US election win, Elon Musk's estranged trans daughter, Vivian Wilson, announced her intention to leave the US, saying she doesn't see a future in the country.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Following Donald Trump's US election win, Elon Musk's estranged trans daughter, Vivian Wilson, announced her intention to leave the US, saying she doesn't see a future in the country. Vivian, who Musk once claimed was "killed by the woke mind virus", is transgender and has been estranged from her father since 2022. On Wednesday, she took to Meta's Threads to share her thoughts. "I've thought this for a while, but yesterday confirmed it for me. I don't see my future being in the United States," she wrote.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Even if he's only in office for 4 years, even if the anti-trans regulations magically don't happen, the people who willingly voted this in are not going anywhere anytime soon," she said after Donald Trump's win.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Take a look at the post below:&nbsp;</strong></p>

<blockquote class="text-post-media" data-text-post-permalink="https://www.threads.net/@vivllainous/post/DCDViBCy_w6" data-text-post-version="0" id="ig-tp-DCDViBCy_w6" style=" background:#FFF; border-width: 1px; border-style: solid; border-color: #00000026; border-radius: 16px; max-width:540px; margin: 1px; min-width:270px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style=" padding: 40px; display: flex; flex-direction: column; align-items: center;">
<div style=" display:block; height:32px; width:32px; padding-bottom:20px;"></div>

<div style=" display:block; height:32px; width:32px; padding-bottom:20px;"><strong><a href="https://www.threads.net/@vivllainous/post/DCDViBCy_w6" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%; font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, sans-serif;" target="_blank"><svg aria-label="Threads" height="32px" role="img" viewbox="0 0 192 192" width="32px" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"></svg><strong> </strong><path d="M141.537 88.9883C140.71 88.5919 139.87 88.2104 139.019 87.8451C137.537 60.5382 122.616 44.905 97.5619 44.745C97.4484 44.7443 97.3355 44.7443 97.222 44.7443C82.2364 44.7443 69.7731 51.1409 62.102 62.7807L75.881 72.2328C81.6116 63.5383 90.6052 61.6848 97.2286 61.6848C97.3051 61.6848 97.3819 61.6848 97.4576 61.6855C105.707 61.7381 111.932 64.1366 115.961 68.814C118.893 72.2193 120.854 76.925 121.825 82.8638C114.511 81.6207 106.601 81.2385 98.145 81.7233C74.3247 83.0954 59.0111 96.9879 60.0396 116.292C60.5615 126.084 65.4397 134.508 73.775 140.011C80.8224 144.663 89.899 146.938 99.3323 146.423C111.79 145.74 121.563 140.987 128.381 132.296C133.559 125.696 136.834 117.143 138.28 106.366C144.217 109.949 148.617 114.664 151.047 120.332C155.179 129.967 155.42 145.8 142.501 158.708C131.182 170.016 117.576 174.908 97.0135 175.059C74.2042 174.89 56.9538 167.575 45.7381 153.317C35.2355 139.966 29.8077 120.682 29.6052 96C29.8077 71.3178 35.2355 52.0336 45.7381 38.6827C56.9538 24.4249 74.2039 17.11 97.0132 16.9405C119.988 17.1113 137.539 24.4614 149.184 38.788C154.894 45.8136 159.199 54.6488 162.037 64.9503L178.184 60.6422C174.744 47.9622 169.331 37.0357 161.965 27.974C147.036 9.60668 125.202 0.195148 97.0695 0H96.9569C68.8816 0.19447 47.2921 9.6418 32.7883 28.0793C19.8819 44.4864 13.2244 67.3157 13.0007 95.9325L13 96L13.0007 96.0675C13.2244 124.684 19.8819 147.514 32.7883 163.921C47.2921 182.358 68.8816 191.806 96.9569 192H97.0695C122.03 191.827 139.624 185.292 154.118 170.811C173.081 151.866 172.51 128.119 166.26 113.541C161.776 103.087 153.227 94.5962 141.537 88.9883ZM98.4405 129.507C88.0005 130.095 77.1544 125.409 76.6196 115.372C76.2232 107.93 81.9158 99.626 99.0812 98.6368C101.047 98.5234 102.976 98.468 104.871 98.468C111.106 98.468 116.939 99.0737 122.242 100.233C120.264 124.935 108.662 128.946 98.4405 129.507Z"></path></a></strong></div>

<div style=" font-size: 15px; line-height: 21px; color: #000000; font-weight: 600; "></div>

<div style=" font-size: 15px; line-height: 21px; color: #000000; font-weight: 600; "><a href="https://www.threads.net/@vivllainous/post/DCDViBCy_w6" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%; font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, sans-serif;" target="_blank">View on Threads</a></div>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="https://www.threads.net/embed.js"></script>

<p>After Vivian announced her plans to leave America, Musk responded to the news on X. "The woke mind killed my son," he reiterated in a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://x.com/elonmusk/status/1854576310699348325">tweet</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Vivian shared a screenshot of her father's post on Threads and <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.threads.net/@vivllainous/post/DCFUOgETs7l">wrote</a>, "So, you're still going with the sob-story about how "woe is me, my child was infected by something-or-other and that's totally the only reason why they hate me. Just don't... please don't look into it, god forbid I'm anything but the victim in every scenario imaginable."&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Did anyone ever actually believe this? It's just tired, it's overdone, it's clich&amp;#233;. I'm just bored honestly, like is this really the best you could come up with?" she added.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-in-trump-familys-election-victory-photo-but-melania-is-missing-6963915">Elon Musk In Trump Family's Election Victory Photo, But Melania Is Missing</a></strong></p>

<p>In the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.threads.net/@vivllainous/post/DCFUO7hTEIb">following Thread</a>, Vivian stated that the only reason this news got to her father is because he is mad that he doesn't have power over someone. "You're upset because at the end of the day everyone around you knows you as a delusional and grubby little control freak who hasn't matured as a person for 38 years. However, last time I checked that's not my fucking problem," she said.&nbsp;</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-disowned-by-transgender-daughter-hes-desperate-for-attention-6193039">Vivian Wilson </a>is one of six kids Musk shares with his first wife, Justine Wilson. She legally changed her name in 2022 and sought gender-affirming care. Her billionaire father has repeatedly blamed the "woke mind virus" for her decision and said that she is "dead" to him.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Vivian, on the other hand, described her father as "cold" and "cruel". She claimed that the billionaire harassed her as a young child over her effeminate traits. "He is uncaring and narcissistic," she said.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/jeedva6o_elon-musk-daughter_625x300_13_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Vivian Wilson is one of six kids Musk shares with his first wife, Justine Wilson.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-capitol-rioters-supporters-of-donald-trump-await-pardons-6969400]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Capitol Rioters, Supporters Of Donald Trump, Await Pardons]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-capitol-rioters-supporters-of-donald-trump-await-pardons-6969400]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 08 Nov 2024 06:49:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump supporters who were charged with storming the US Capitol are now expecting pardons from the incoming American president, who has lauded them as "patriots" and "political prisoners."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump supporters who were charged with storming the US Capitol are now expecting pardons from the incoming American president, who has lauded them as "patriots" and "political prisoners."</p>

<p>More than 1,500 people have been charged in connection with the January 6, 2021 assault on Congress which sought to disrupt certification of Democrat Joe Biden's 2020 election victory.</p>

<p>"I am inclined to pardon many of them," Trump, whose first term as president ended under the cloud of the attack, said at a CNN town hall, one of a number of times he made the pledge during his 2024 bid to retake the White House.</p>

<p>"I can't say for every single one because a couple of them, probably, they got out of control," he said.</p>

<p>Trump has repeatedly played down the violence of January 6, even going so far as to describe it recently as a "day of love."</p>

<p>More than 140 police officers were injured in hours of clashes with rioters wielding flagpoles, baseball bats, hockey sticks and other makeshift weapons along with Tasers and canisters of bear spray.</p>

<p>The assault on the Capitol followed a fiery speech by then-president Trump to tens of thousands of his supporters near the White House in which he repeated his false claims that he won the 2020 race.</p>

<p>Several Capitol riot defendants have already seized upon Trump's election victory over Vice President Kamala Harris to ask that their trials or sentencing be put on hold.</p>

<p>Christopher Carnell, a 21-year-old from North Carolina, asked that a status hearing in his disorderly conduct case be delayed in light of Trump's "multiple clemency promises."</p>

<p>Carnell, his lawyer said, "is expecting to be relieved of the criminal prosecution that he is currently facing when the new administration takes office."</p>

<p>Judge Beryl Howell denied the request.</p>

<p><strong>'Never face consequences'</strong></p>

<p>Another defendant, Jaimee Avery, asked that her sentencing on Friday for trespassing convictions be rescheduled to a date after January 20, 2025 -- the day Trump will be sworn in as the 47th US president.</p>

<p>"President-elect Trump, who played an integral role in the events of January 6, 2021, has repeatedly publicly stated that he will pardon January 6 protestors should he win the presidency," her lawyer said in a court filing.</p>

<p>"It would create a gross disparity for Ms Avery to spend even a day in jail when the man who played a pivotal role in organizing and instigating the events of January 6 will now never face consequences for it."</p>

<p>Judge Christopher Cooper denied Avery's request to delay her sentencing.</p>

<p>Trump was charged by special counsel Jack Smith with conspiring to overturn the results of the 2020 election.</p>

<p>But the case never made it to trial, and is now being wound down under the Justice Department's policy of not prosecuting a sitting president.</p>

<p>Trump has not ruled out giving pardons to members of the far-right Proud Boys and Oath Keepers militant groups, who were convicted of seditious conspiracy and received the stiffest prison sentences.</p>

<p>Enrique Tarrio, the former Proud Boys leader, is serving a 22-year prison sentence for directing a military-style assault on the Capitol, while Oath Keepers founder Stewart Rhodes was sentenced to 18 years in prison.</p>

<p>According to the latest figures from the US Attorney's Office for the District of Columbia, 1,532 people have been charged in connection with the Capitol siege, including 571 accused of assaulting, resisting or impeding law enforcement officers.</p>

<p>More than 940 defendants have pleaded guilty to various offenses while another 195 were convicted at trial.</p>

<p>Trump pardoned a number of his close political allies of federal charges before he left office in January 2021, including his 2016 presidential campaign chiefs Paul Manafort and Steve Bannon.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-06/gqsn3b4_capitol-hill-reuters_625x300_08_June_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Over 1,500 people have been charged in connection with the January 6, 2021 assault on Congress.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/f-15-fighter-jets-arrive-in-middle-east-us-military-6969368]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[F-15 Fighter Jets Arrive In Middle East: US Military]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/f-15-fighter-jets-arrive-in-middle-east-us-military-6969368]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 08 Nov 2024 06:37:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[American F-15 fighter planes arrived in the Middle East on Thursday, the US military said, after Washington announced the deployment of additional assets to the region in a warning to Iran.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>American F-15 fighter planes arrived in the Middle East on Thursday, the US military said, after Washington announced the deployment of additional assets to the region in a warning to Iran.</p>

<p>"Today, US Air Force F-15E Strike Eagles from the 492nd Fighter Squadron, RAF Lakenheath, England, arrive in the US Central Command area of responsibility," the military command responsible for the Middle East said on social media.</p>

<p>The United States announced on November 1 that it was sending bombers, fighter and tanker aircraft and ballistic missile defense destroyers to the Middle East.</p>

<p>"Should Iran, its partners, or its proxies use this moment to target American personnel or interests in the region, the United States will take every measure necessary to defend our people," Pentagon spokesman Major General Pat Ryder said in a statement on the deployment.</p>

<p>Israel launched strikes against Iran on October 26, hitting military infrastructure while steering clear of critical nuclear and oil sites, and the country's supreme leader has vowed that Tehran will retaliate for Israeli attacks.</p>

<p>Iran has carried out two major attacks against Israel in 2024 -- one in April after a strike on its consulate in Damascus that was blamed on Israel, and another in October that Tehran said was in response to the assassination of leaders of armed groups it backs in the Middle East.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2018-11/b5dh9oeo_f15-fighter-jet_625x300_10_November_18.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US announced on November 1 that it was sending fighter aircrafts to the Middle East (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/evil-psycho-father-accused-of-killing-pak-british-girl-sara-sharif-blames-her-stepmother-6969212]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Evil": Father Accused Of Killing Pak-British Girl Blames Her Stepmother]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/evil-psycho-father-accused-of-killing-pak-british-girl-sara-sharif-blames-her-stepmother-6969212]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 08 Nov 2024 05:40:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The father of a 10-year-old British-Pakistani girl on Thursday denied her murder and instead blamed the girl's stepmother, calling her "evil" and "psycho".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The father of a 10-year-old British-Pakistani girl on Thursday denied her murder and instead blamed the girl's stepmother, calling her "evil" and "psycho".</p>

<p>Sara Sharif was found dead in her bed in Woking, southwest of London, on August 10, 2023 with injuries including broken bones, burns and bite marks.</p>

<p>Her father, Urfan Sharif, 42, had fled to Pakistan a day before the body was found, along with his wife Beinash Batool, 30, and the girl's uncle, Faisal Malik, 29.</p>

<p>Urfan Sharif then called police in the UK shortly after arriving in Islamabad and said he had "beat her up too much". During the trial, Urfan Sharif said he made up this and another confession to "protect my family".</p>

<p>All three adults were arrested upon their return to the UK a month later. They deny charges of murder and allowing the death of a child.</p>

<p>Details of the extent of Sara's injuries have been detailed at London's Old Bailey court, including claims from Beinash Batool that Urfan Sharif would beat his daughter badly.</p>

<p>Giving evidence for a third day, Urfan Sharif admitted slapping Sara "multiple times" but denied beating, burning, or biting her, insisting that he was "never at home" when she was injured.</p>

<p><strong>Bite marks</strong></p>

<p>Urfan Sharif broke down when his lawyer, Naeem Mian, questioned him about beating Sara, who was home schooled, with a cricket bat.</p>

<p>The taxi driver denied burning his daughter with an iron and instead said he was "made to" slap Sara by Beinash Batool, who constantly accused the girl of behaving badly.</p>

<p>Pointing to Beinash Batool sitting in the dock, Urfan Sharif shouted: "I should not have believed her... I didn't realise I'm living with evil and a psycho".</p>

<p>He also suggested that Beinash Batool was the one who bit her "like an animal".</p>

<p>The jury was previously told that Urfan Sharif and Faisal Malik had provided their dental impressions but Beinash Batool had refused.</p>

<p>"I didn't do it. Faisal didn't do it. Who else was at home?" Urfan Sharif said.</p>

<p>He denied ever being aware of Sara being in pain. "She never told me that," he said and indicated that he did not see injuries because Sara wore full-sleeve tops and long bottoms as well as a hijab head covering.</p>

<p><strong>'Manipulative'</strong></p>

<p>In the month leading up to Sara's death, Mian said Urfan Sharif was out of the house at work from early in the morning to late at night while holing frequent telephone conversations with Beinash Batool, who would largely be at home.</p>

<p>Urfan Sharif wept as he recalled a time he came home and saw that Sara's hands had been tied behind her back with brown packaging tape, accusing Beinash Batool of the act.</p>

<p>Asked why he did not call the police or ask Beinash Batool to leave, Urfan Sharif said that his wife was "manipulative" and that he believed her apology.</p>

<p>"I have been an idiot," he added.</p>

<p>Forensic evidence shown to court included bundles of packaging tape and a white plastic carrier bag fashioned into a hood that could have been used on Sara's head.</p>

<p>The bag had packaging tape stuck to it as well as long, brown hairs that matched Sara's DNA, the court was told.</p>

<p>Both the bag and the non-sticky side of the tape had fingerprints that matched Urfan Sharif's, who denied fashioning a hood out of the plastic bag or using it on Sara.</p>

<p>He said the fingerprints could be a result of him handling the items while sorting the garbage.</p>

<p>Urfan Sharif had previously accused Beinash Batool of being abusive towards him and preventing him from asking Sara about how she obtained her injuries.</p>

<p>In 2022, Beinash Batool texted her sister that Urfan Sharif had suggested using make-up to cover up bruises after beating Sara, to which the sister replied: "LOL it was going to happen you can tell."</p>

<p>In the days before her death, Urfan Sharif said Sara, who did chores around the house, had asked him to "not go to work".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-09/nuqulov_sara-sharif_625x300_12_September_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Urfan Sharif denied ever being aware of Sara being in pain (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/zelensky-says-north-korean-troops-suffered-losses-in-clashes-with-ukraine-6969158]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Zelensky Says North Korean Troops Suffered Losses In Clashes With Ukraine]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/zelensky-says-north-korean-troops-suffered-losses-in-clashes-with-ukraine-6969158]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 08 Nov 2024 05:30:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskiy said on Thursday North Korean troops had suffered casualties in combat with Kyiv's forces and that some of the 11,000 troops sent to Russia's Kursk region had taken part in fighting.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky said on Thursday North Korean troops had suffered casualties in combat with Kyiv's forces and that some of the 11,000 troops sent to Russia's Kursk region had taken part in fighting.</p>

<p>The Ukrainian leader, speaking at a news conference at the European Political Community summit in Budapest, said he believed that more North Korean troops would be deployed on Russia's side unless action was taken in response.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/guf7g9_zelensky_625x300_18_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Some of the 11,000 North Korean troops sent to Russia had taken part in fighting, said Zelensky (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/putin-says-ukraine-must-remain-neutral-for-there-to-be-peace-6969153]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Putin Says Ukraine Must Remain Neutral For There To Be Peace]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/putin-says-ukraine-must-remain-neutral-for-there-to-be-peace-6969153]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 08 Nov 2024 05:24:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[President Vladimir Putin said on Thursday that Ukraine should remain neutral for there to be a chance for peace, adding that the borders of Ukraine should be in accordance with the wishes of the people living in Russian-claimed territory.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>President Vladimir Putin said on Thursday that Ukraine should remain neutral for there to be a chance for peace, adding that the borders of Ukraine should be in accordance with the wishes of the people living in Russian-claimed territory.</p>

<p>"If there is no neutrality, it is difficult to imagine the existence of any good-neighborly relations between Russia and Ukraine," Putin said.</p>

<p>Putin said Russia had recognised Ukraine's post-Soviet borders based on the understanding that it would be neutral. The US-led NATO military alliance has repeatedly said that Ukraine would one day join.</p>

<p>If Ukraine was not neutral, it would be "constantly used as a tool in the wrong hands and to the detriment of the interests of the Russian Federation," Putin said.</p>

<p>Russia controls about a fifth of Ukraine after more than two and a half years of war. Putin on June 14 set out his terms for an end to the conflict: Ukraine would have to drop its NATO ambitions and withdraw all of its troops from all of the territory of the regions claimed by Russia.</p>

<p>Ukraine rejects those conditions as tantamount to surrender and President Volodymyr Zelenskiy has presented a "victory plan" for which he has requested additional Western support.</p>

<p>"We are determined to create conditions for a long-term settlement so that Ukraine is an independent, sovereign state, and not an instrument in the hands of third countries, and not used in their interests," Putin said.</p>

<p>Asked about the future borders of Ukraine, Putin said: "The borders of Ukraine should be in accordance with the sovereign decisions of people who live in certain territories and which we call our historical territories."</p>

<p>Ukraine says that it will not rest until every last Russian soldier is ejected from its territory though even US generals say that such an aim would take massive resources that Ukraine currently does not have.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/p59m2dh8_putin-afp_625x300_13_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Russia controls about a fifth of Ukraine after more than two and a half years of war (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/sugar-in-infancy-linked-to-higher-diabetes-blood-pressure-risks-study-6969152]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Sugar In Infancy Linked To Higher Diabetes, Blood Pressure Risks: Study]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/sugar-in-infancy-linked-to-higher-diabetes-blood-pressure-risks-study-6969152]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 08 Nov 2024 05:23:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Excessive sugar consumption, particularly in early life, is linked to increased risks of chronic diseases like type 2 diabetes and high blood pressure in adulthood.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In this day of technology, where individuals are exercising less, consuming sugar has turned into a sweet risk to human health. In the modern diet, the top sources are soft drinks, fruit drinks, flavoured yoghurts, cereals, cookies, cakes, candy, and most processed foods, and all this has added sugar. But added sugar is also present in items that you may not think of as sweetened, like soups, bread, cured meats, and ketchup.The result: we consume way too much added sugar, which ultimately affects our body.</p>

<p>Recently, scientists have discovered new information about sugar intake during the human body's infancy stage. Type 2 diabetes and high blood pressure in later life may be predicted by the amount of sugar in infants' and toddlers' diets.</p>

<p>A low-sugar diet in utero and in the first two years of life can meaningfully reduce the risk of chronic diseases in adulthood, according to a study published today in the<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adn5421"><em> journal Science. </em></a>The researchers used contemporary data from the UK Biobank to study the effect of exposure to sugar restrictions early in life on health outcomes of adults conceived just before and after the end of wartime sugar rationing in the United Kingdom in September 1953.</p>

<p>As per a <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://newsroom.haas.berkeley.edu/research/exposure-to-sugar-restrictions-in-utero-and-early-childhood-reduces-risk-of-chronic-disease-study-finds/">news release, the study,</a></em> published on Halloween, finds that children exposed to sugar restrictions during their first 1,000 days-including in utero-had up to a 35% lower risk of developing Type 2 diabetes and up to 20% lower risk of hypertension as adults. In-utero exposure alone was enough to lower risks, but disease protection increased with length of exposure after birth.</p>

<p>The study-a collaboration by researchers Tadeja Gracner from the University of Southern California, Claire Boone of McGill University, and Paul Gertler of the University of California Berkeley's Haas School of Business-provides compelling new evidence of the lifelong health effects of early-life sugar exposure.</p>

<p>"Studying the long-term effects of added sugar on health is challenging because it is hard to find situations where people are as-if randomly exposed to different nutritional environments early in life and follow them for 50 to 60 years," said Gracner (PhD 15, Economics). "The end of rationing provided us with a novel natural experiment to overcome these problems."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/fg9nbbtg_sugar-_625x300_08_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sugar restrictions in early childhood reduce the risk of chronic disease.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-names-campaign-manager-susie-wiles-as-chief-of-staff-6969032]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump Names Campaign Manager Susie Wiles As Chief Of Staff]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-names-campaign-manager-susie-wiles-as-chief-of-staff-6969032]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 08 Nov 2024 04:47:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President-elect Donald Trump named his campaign manager, Susie Wiles, as White House chief of staff on Thursday, his first major appointment since winning this week's election.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President-elect Donald Trump named his campaign manager, Susie Wiles, as White House chief of staff on Thursday, his first major appointment since winning this week's election.</p>

<p>"Susie is tough, smart, innovative, and is universally admired and respected," Trump said in a statement. "Susie will continue to work tirelessly to Make America Great Again. It is a well deserved honor to have Susie as the first-ever female Chief of Staff in United States history."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/f93g50lo_donald-trump-susie-wiles-reuters_625x300_08_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["Susie will continue to work tirelessly to Make America Great Again," said Trump (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-and-uks-keir-starmer-set-for-rocky-special-relationship-6968940]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump And UK's Keir Starmer Set For Rocky Special Relationship]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-and-uks-keir-starmer-set-for-rocky-special-relationship-6968940]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 08 Nov 2024 04:12:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Keir Starmer has insisted that the UK-US special relationship will "prosper" under Donald Trump but the British prime minister's Labour government has multiple reasons to fear the Republican's presidential comeback.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Keir Starmer has insisted that the UK-US special relationship will "prosper" under Donald Trump but the British prime minister's Labour government has multiple reasons to fear the Republican's presidential comeback.</p>

<p>Possible trade wars, Labour ministers' unflattering comments about Trump, and any role for Starmer critic Elon Musk in Trump's administration would make for a bumpy ride between the allies.</p>

<p>The UK's "iron-clad" support for Ukraine in its war against Russia's invasion and "unwavering commitment" to the NATO military alliance are also likely to become major bones of contention, experts said.</p>

<p>Starmer made a first move late on Wednesday, phoning Trump to offer his congratulations, telling reporters at a European summit in Budapest Thursday that the call was "very positive, very constructive".</p>

<p>But Richard Whitman, an international relations professor at the University of Kent, said the centre-left government in London will be feeling "nervous" about Trump's return to the White House.</p>

<p>"Most of the broad parameters of British foreign policy are set by responding to what are the major preoccupations of the United States," he told AFP, noting doubts over Trump's commitment to Ukraine and NATO.</p>

<p>Britain has been one of Ukraine's biggest financial and military backers since Russia's full-scale invasion in February 2022 and any shift in policy by Trump would leave the country in an unenviable position.</p>

<p>"(The UK) can't do a 180-degree shift on Ukraine because it's invested too much," said Whitman.</p>

<p>Simon Fraser, formerly the top civil servant in the UK's foreign ministry, added that the UK-US relationship could be complicated by Trump's approach to the European Union -- and whether that includes tariffs on allies.</p>

<p>Trump has threatened to impose tariffs of up to 20 percent on all US imports and 60 percent on Chinese goods.</p>

<p><strong>Economic unpredictability</strong></p>

<p>A trade war between Trump and the EU could see the UK stuck in the middle.</p>

<p>Global economic volatility would hamper Starmer's pledge to fire up Britain's flagging economy.</p>

<p>The National Institute of Economic and Social Research, a leading think tank, has warned that Trump's tariff plans could halve UK economic growth in the next two years, pushing up prices and interest rates.</p>

<p>Lindsay James, investment strategist at Quilter Investors, said a Trump presidency makes it "unlikely that any (UK-US) trade deal negotiations will be resurrected".</p>

<p>"The UK holds no obvious bargaining chip," she added.</p>

<p>Labour is historically close to the Democratic Party, and several senior figures attended its convention in Chicago in July when Kamala Harris was anointed its presidential candidate.</p>

<p>Last month, Trump accused Starmer's government of "blatant foreign interference" in the US election over the visit and Labour staffers campaigning for Harris.</p>

<p>Behind the scenes, Labour has spent recent months trying to build bridges with Trump's team, and Starmer dined for two hours with Trump in September.</p>

<p>Previous comments by senior Labour figures have the potential to make dealings awkward, however, none more so than for Foreign Secretary David Lammy, who in 2018 called Trump a "woman-hating, neo-Nazi sympathising sociopath" and a "tyrant in a toupee".</p>

<p>Senior minister Pat McFadden on Thursday said Trump was a "fan of the United Kingdom" and Starmer's face-to-face meeting with him had been "productive".</p>

<p>"I think in the end, those shared values and interests are more important than some tweet from however many years ago," he said. "You can move past these things."</p>

<p><strong>No plan B</strong></p>

<p>Starmer's political spokesperson on Wednesday insisted Lammy would stay in his post for the entire five-year parliamentary term.</p>

<p>But trouble could also come from Trump supporter and tech billionaire Musk, who earned a rebuke from ministers this summer after claiming that far-right riots across England would lead to "civil war".</p>

<p>Britain and the United States are also likely to disagree on climate, with Trump a self-proclaimed climate change sceptic and Labour determined to make Britain a "clean energy superpower".</p>

<p>Analysts point out the special relationship, forged during World War II, has endured for 80 years despite multiple governments of different persuasions on both sides of the Atlantic.</p>

<p>"Political differences at the top don't mean that the whole relationship is vulnerable. There are checks and balances," said Fraser, citing "institutional structures".</p>

<p>Whitman agreed that it would endure but added: "If it doesn't, then a great thick pillar of British foreign and security policy crumbles.</p>

<p>"And if you set that against what's already happened with (leaving) the EU, (then) the UK is really adrift.</p>

<p>"The UK doesn't have a hedging strategy. It doesn't have a plan B for its relationship with the US."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/nto9e6d8_donald-trump-keir-starmer_625x300_08_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump won against Kamala Harris to become US' 47th President (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-will-trump-2-0-mean-for-us-tech-6968886]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What Will Trump 2.0 Mean For US Tech?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-will-trump-2-0-mean-for-us-tech-6968886]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 08 Nov 2024 03:59:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[What will Donald Trump's second stint in the White House mean for a US tech industry in the throes of an artificial intelligence frenzy? For sure Elon Musk will play a central role in Trump's Silicon Valley policies after backing his campaign.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>What will Donald Trump's second stint in the White House mean for a US tech industry in the throes of an artificial intelligence frenzy?</p>

<p>For sure Elon Musk, the world's richest person, will play a central role in Trump's Silicon Valley policies after backing the Republican's presidential campaign.</p>

<p>"A star is born: Elon!" Trump said in a lengthy shoutout to the Tesla and SpaceX boss during his victory speech after Tuesday's election.</p>

<p>Musk is slated to take a significant role in the White House, where he will likely have influence over the regulation of tech, including in matters related to his companies Tesla, SpaceX and the X platform (formerly Twitter).</p>

<p>At Musk's side, will likely be a group of tech "accelerationists", members of Silicon Valley's more libertarian right-wing, who want innovation to thrive unfettered by the government.</p>

<p>Unlike their early caution during Trump's first term, tech titans were swift to laud the president-elect on his victory.</p>

<p>"Big congratulations to our 45th and now 47th President on an extraordinary political comeback and decisive victory," wrote Amazon founder Jeff Bezos on X.</p>

<p>Bezos had already signaled his shifting position by directing The Washington Post, which he owns, to refrain from endorsing Kamala Harris - a move widely interpreted as an attempt to avoid potential friction with a returning Trump administration.</p>

<p>Apple boss Tim Cook sent his congratulations, as did Mark Cuban, a tech billionaire backer of Harris, who said Trump won the election "fair and square."</p>

<p>Meta supremo Mark Zuckerberg congratulated Trump too and has spent the past months, carefully trying to rebuild a relationship with the president-elect, who often singles out the Facebook founder for his vitriol.</p>

<p>Policy-wise the tech titans will be united in wanting to see the departure of Lina Khan, the head of the Federal Trade Commission, who has pursued a policy of slowing the unrestricted spread of their tech empires.</p>

<p>An early target of Trump's attention could be the executive order from President Joe Biden on regulating artificial intelligence.</p>

<p>The order sets voluntary standards for AI safety, emphasizing privacy protection, fighting bias and offers guidelines on how AI can be deployed by the government.</p>

<p>It also established the US AI Safety Institute (AISI), a body to study risks in AI systems.</p>

<p>The order could be overhauled or rubbished, with Trump sympathetic to arguments that innovation should not be constrained by rules.</p>

<p><strong>Crypto craze</strong></p>

<p>Trump will almost certainly make it easier for cryptocurrencies to thrive after tech moguls closely linked to the industry donated generously to his campaign.</p>

<p>Crypto markets surged higher after his win, with bitcoin hitting a new all-time-high above $75,000.</p>

<p>During his presidency Trump referred to cryptocurrencies as a scam, but has since radically changed his position, even launching his own crypto product.</p>

<p>He will try to remove Gary Gensler, the crypto-skeptic head of the Securities and Exchange Commission, who has become a loathed bogeyman for the sector.</p>

<p>The troubled fate of TikTok could change, with Trump having voiced opposition to a Biden-backed law, ordering that the popular app divest from Bytedance, its Chinese owner.</p>

<p>TikTok has until January to find a buyer or face the ban, but Trump opposes it, saying it would only boost Instagram and Facebook, which he believes treat him unfairly.</p>

<p>Trump has also expressed intentions to dismantle the CHIPS Act, replacing Biden's manufacturing subsidies with aggressive tariffs designed to force companies to build in the US.</p>

<p>Industry analyst Jack Gold cautioned against this approach, noting that "tariffs alone will not work to bring back US chip production.... Tariffs are a penalty, while the CHIPS act is an incentive."</p>

<p>A looming trade war with China also looms.</p>

<p>The share price in Apple didn't see the share price jumps seen on Wall Street more broadly after the Trump win with questions over its dependence on Chinese factories to build iPhones.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/cr0ca1mo_donald-trump_625x300_07_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump won against Kamala Harris to become US' 47th President (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-will-staff-trumps-government-a-look-at-top-contenders-6968879]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump's 1st Appointment Marks A Historic First. Other Top Contenders Are...]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-will-staff-trumps-government-a-look-at-top-contenders-6968879]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 08 Nov 2024 03:53:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President-elect Donald Trump on Thursday made the first appointment of his new administration -- naming a chief of staff -- with other key jobs set to be filled in the "days and weeks ahead," according to his team.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President-elect Donald Trump on Thursday made the first appointment of his new administration -- naming a chief of staff -- with other key jobs set to be filled in the "days and weeks ahead," according to his team. "There are some people that will be returning (from Trump's first term)," senior Trump aide Jason Miller told Fox Business on Wednesday. "And there'll be some new people joining the mix."</p>

<p>Linda McMahon, a former CEO of World Wrestling Entertainment, and Howard Lutnick, the founder of the brokerage firm Cantor Fitzgerald, are leading the transition process.</p>

<p>AFP looks at some of the Trump allies in the running:</p>

<h2><strong>Chief of Staff</strong></h2>

<p>Susie Wiles, his election campaign chief, became Trump's first appointment on Thursday when she was unveiled as his chief of staff, as widely expected. Wiles enjoys wide support inside the Trump team and was notably called on stage by the incoming president during his victory speech on Wednesday morning. "Susie is tough, smart, innovative, and is universally admired and respected," Trump said of the steely 67-year-old Florida native, who will be the first-ever woman to take the high-profile post.</p>

<h2><strong>Attorney General</strong></h2>

<p>Given Trump's radical agenda for mass deportations of illegal immigrants and his ongoing legal problems, the person named as attorney general will hold one of the most sensitive and challenging jobs. Republican Senators Mike Lee, Eric Schmitt and John Ratcliffe, Trump's former director of national intelligence, were reported by The Washington Post on Wednesday to be under consideration.</p>

<h2><strong>Secretary of State</strong></h2>

<p>The next top US diplomat will play a key role in implementing Trump's "America first" foreign policy, likely to see major shifts in US alliances and forcing Ukraine into negotiations with Russia. Ric Grenell, an abrasive former ambassador to Germany who also served as acting director of national intelligence under Trump, is seen as a contender. "If you want to avoid war, you better have a son of a bitch as the secretary of state," he said in a March episode of the "Self Centered" podcast.</p>

<p>The openly gay arch-loyalist, who sought to overturn Trump's 2020 election loss, appeared with Trump during a meeting with Ukraine President Volodymyr Zelensky in September. He could also slot into the crucial role of national security advisor, with Florida Senator Marco Rubio, a finalist to become Trump's running mate, being mentioned by many as potentially secretary of state.</p>

<p>"I always am interested in serving this country," Rubio told CNN on Wednesday.</p>

<h2><strong>Defense secretary and CIA director</strong></h2>

<p>America's foreign allies will be closely following the nominations for these two vital positions. Kash Patel, the son of Indian immigrants and author of a book about the so-called "deep state," has been mentioned as a future CIA chief, as has ultra-conservative Texas Senator Ratcliffe. Arkansas Senator Tom Cotton, who called for troops to be used against Black Lives Matter protesters in 2020, has ruled himself out as defense secretary, Axios reported on Wednesday.</p>

<h2><strong>Treasury secretary</strong></h2>

<p>Billionaire hedge fund manager Scott Bessent, a key donor and advisor, is viewed as a top candidate to be the next treasury secretary in charge of pushing through Trump's agenda of low taxes, low regulation and high tariffs. John Paulson, another billionaire hedge fund manager and advisor, is also in the running for a top economic portfolio, as is Trump transition co-chair Lutnick.</p>

<p><strong>"DOGE"</strong></p>

<p>Trump surrogate and Tesla boss Elon Musk is expected to lead a new "Department of Government Efficiency," targeting $2 trillion in cuts from the federal government's $7 trillion budget -- although no one has explained how such drastic cuts would be made. The world's richest man has pledged to bring his "hardcore" management style to Washington, while promising "fair and humane" transitions for sacked federal workers.</p>

<p><strong>Others</strong></p>

<p>Robert Kennedy Jr., nephew of former president John F Kennedy and a longtime conspiracy theorist, has been promised a "big role" by Trump after ending his own candidacy to endorse the Republican. Trump has teased wide-ranging roles for RFK, including allowing the vaccine skeptic to "go wild on health."</p>

<p>It remains to be seen if Trump will promote family members into roles as aides and advisors, but first-term stalwarts Ivanka and her husband Jared Kushner have stepped back from politics for family and business reasons.</p>

<p>Former congresswoman Tulsi Gabbard, who held the post as a Democrat and has since joined the Republican party, will be expecting a reward for lining up behind Trump.</p>

<p>Former Fox News host and Trump confidante Tucker Carlson might also be eying a spot.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/8nin53pg_trump-with-susie-wiles_625x300_08_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump won against Kamala Harris to become US' 47th President (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-military-judge-rules-9-11-mastermind-plea-deal-is-valid-6968847]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Military Judge Rules 9/11 Mastermind Plea Deal Is Valid]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-military-judge-rules-9-11-mastermind-plea-deal-is-valid-6968847]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 08 Nov 2024 03:45:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Plea agreements with 9/11 mastermind Khalid Sheikh Mohammed and two other defendants are valid and binding, a US military judge said in a ruling published Thursday, three months after the deals were scrapped by Defense Secretary Lloyd Austin.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Plea agreements with 9/11 mastermind Khalid Sheikh Mohammed and two other defendants are valid and binding, a US military judge said in a ruling published Thursday, three months after the deals were scrapped by Defense Secretary Lloyd Austin.</p>

<p>The agreements -- which are understood to take the death penalty off the table -- had triggered anger among some relatives of victims of the 2001 attacks, and Austin has said that both they and the American public deserved to see the defendants stand trial.</p>

<p>Colonel Matthew McCall granted defense motions to schedule a hearing for the entry of pleas in keeping with the agreements made with the three defendants, the ruling said.</p>

<p>They are "enforceable contracts," which "transformed into binding agreements when signed by the Convening Authority, who had authority to sign them when she did so," it said, referring to the official behind the deals, Susan Escallier.</p>

<p>The prosecution has the opportunity to appeal the Wednesday ruling, but it was not immediately clear if they would do so.</p>

<p>Pentagon spokesman Major General Pat Ryder said in a statement that "we are reviewing the decision and don't have anything further at this time."</p>

<p>The plea deals with Mohammed and two alleged accomplices -- Walid bin Attash and Mustafa al-Hawsawi -- were announced in late July.</p>

<p>The decision appeared to have moved their long-running cases toward resolution after years of being bogged down in pre-trial maneuverings while the defendants remained held at the Guantanamo Bay military base in Cuba.</p>

<p>But Austin withdrew the agreements two days after they were announced, saying the decision should be up to him, given its significance.</p>

<p>He subsequently told journalists that "the families of the victims, our service members and the American public deserve the opportunity to see military commission trials carried out in this case."</p>

<p><strong>Torture</strong></p>

<p>Much of the legal jousting surrounding the men's cases has focused on whether they could be tried fairly after having undergone torture at the hands of the CIA in the years after 9/11 -- a thorny issue that the plea agreements would have avoided.</p>

<p>"For too long, the US has repeatedly defended its use of torture and unconstitutional military tribunals at Guantanamo Bay," Anthony Romero, executive director of the American Civil Liberties Union, said Thursday.</p>

<p>Romero described the plea agreements as "the only practical solution" and said Austin "stepped out of bounds" by scrapping them.</p>

<p>"As a nation, we must move forward with the plea process and a sentencing hearing that is intended to give victim family members answers to their questions," he said in a statement.</p>

<p>Mohammed was regarded as one of Al-Qaeda chief Osama bin Laden's most trusted and intelligent lieutenants before his March 2003 capture in Pakistan. He then spent three years in secret CIA prisons before arriving at Guantanamo in 2006.</p>

<p>The trained engineer -- who has said he masterminded the 9/11 attacks "from A to Z" -- was involved in a string of major plots against the United States, where he attended university.</p>

<p>Bin Attash, a Saudi of Yemeni origin, allegedly trained two of the hijackers who carried out the September 11 attacks, and his US interrogators also said he confessed to buying the explosives and recruiting members of the team that killed 17 sailors in an attack on the USS Cole in 2000.</p>

<p>After the US invasion of Afghanistan in 2001, he took refuge in neighboring Pakistan and was captured there in 2003. He was then held in a network of secret CIA prisons.</p>

<p>Hawsawi is suspected of managing the financing for the 9/11 attacks. He was arrested in Pakistan on March 1, 2003, and was also held in secret prisons before being transferred to Guantanamo in 2006.</p>

<p>The United States used Guantanamo, an isolated naval base, to hold militants captured during the "War on Terror" that followed the September 11 attacks in a bid to keep the defendants from claiming rights under US law.</p>

<p>The facility held roughly 800 prisoners at its peak, but they have since slowly been repatriated to other countries. A small fraction of that number remain.</p>

<p>US President Joe Biden pledged before his election to try to shut down Guantanamo, but it remains open.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/1jmfn9g_khalid-sheikh-mohammed_625x300_02_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Plea deals with Khalid Sheikh Mohammed and two alleged accomplices were announced in July (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-says-israel-to-open-new-gaza-crossing-for-aid-as-deadline-looms-6968818]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Says Israel To Open New Gaza Crossing For Aid As Deadline Looms]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-says-israel-to-open-new-gaza-crossing-for-aid-as-deadline-looms-6968818]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 08 Nov 2024 03:31:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel has informed the United States that it will open an additional crossing for aid into Gaza, the State Department said Thursday, as a US-imposed deadline looms next week.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel has informed the United States that it will open an additional crossing for aid into Gaza, the State Department said Thursday, as a US-imposed deadline looms next week.</p>

<p>Secretary of State Antony Blinken and Defense Secretary Lloyd Austin have given Israel until November 13 to improve the humanitarian situation in the war-besieged Gaza Strip or risk the withholding of some military assistance from the United States, Israel's biggest supporter.</p>

<p>They made the demands in a letter before Tuesday's election of President-elect Donald Trump, who has promised to give freer rein to Israel.</p>

<p>State Department spokesman Matthew Miller said that Israel, after recently reopening the Erez crossing, has informed the United States that they "hope to open an additional new crossing at Kissufim" in "the next few days."</p>

<p>"We have continued to press them, and we have seen them, including in the past few days since the election, take additional steps," Miller told reporters.</p>

<p>He stopped short of saying how the United States would assess Israel's compliance with the aid demands.</p>

<p>In the letter, Blinken and Austin had urged Israel to "consistently" let aid through four major crossings and to open a fifth crossing.</p>

<p>Kissufim, near a kibbutz across from southern Gaza that was attacked in the October 7, 2023 Hamas assault that sparked the war, has mostly been in disuse except by the military since Israel withdrew from Gaza in 2005.</p>

<p>The letter called for a minimum of 350 trucks per day to be allowed into Gaza. Miller said 229 trucks entered on Tuesday.</p>

<p>Outgoing President Joe Biden has repeatedly pressed Israel to improve humanitarian aid and protect civilians, while mostly stopping short of using leverage such as cutting off weapons.</p>

<p>Miller said Blinken hoped to keep using the rest of his term to press for an end to the wars in Gaza and Lebanon.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/g9n483co_gaza-aid_625x300_22_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US has given Israel until Nov 13 to improve humanitarian situation in Gaza (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/undocumented-immigrants-in-us-terrified-frustrated-as-trump-returns-6968785]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Undocumented Immigrants In US "Terrified", "Frustrated" As Trump Returns]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/undocumented-immigrants-in-us-terrified-frustrated-as-trump-returns-6968785]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 08 Nov 2024 03:21:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Since learning that Donald Trump will return to the White House, undocumented immigrant Angel Palazuelos has struggled to sleep.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Since learning that Donald Trump will return to the White House, undocumented immigrant Angel Palazuelos has struggled to sleep.</p>

<p>The 22-year-old, a graduate student in biomedical engineering who lives in Phoenix, Arizona, is haunted by the incoming president's promises of mass deportations.</p>

<p>"I was terrified," said Palazuelos, reflecting on the moment he heard the news.</p>

<p>"I am in fear of being deported, of losing everything that I've worked so hard for, and, most importantly, being separated from my family."</p>

<p>Born in Mexico, he has lived in the United States since he was four years old. He is one of the country's so-called "Dreamers," a term for migrants who were brought into the country as children and never obtained US citizenship.</p>

<p>Throughout the election campaign, Palazuelos heard Trump repeatedly rail against illegal immigrants, employing violent rhetoric about those who "poison the blood" of the United States.</p>

<p>Trump has never specified how he intends to go about his plan for mass deportation, which experts warn would be extremely complicated and expensive.</p>

<p>"What do mass deportations mean? Who does that include?" Palazuelos asked.</p>

<p>"Does it include people like me, Dreamers, people that came here from a very young age, that had no say?"</p>

<p><strong>'Suspected'</strong></p>

<p>Compounding the stress, the southwestern state of Arizona has just approved by referendum a law allowing state police to arrest illegal immigrants. That power was previously reserved for federal border police.</p>

<p>If the proposition is deemed constitutional by courts, Palazuelos fears becoming the target of heightened racial profiling.</p>

<p>"What makes someone a suspect of being here illegally, whether they don't speak English?" he asked.</p>

<p>"My grandma, she's a United States citizen, however, she doesn't speak English very well. Meanwhile, I speak English, but is it because of the color of my skin that I would possibly be suspected or detained?"</p>

<p>Jose Patino, 35, also feels a sense of "dread" and "sadness." His situation feels more fragile than ever.</p>

<p>Born in Mexico and brought to the United States aged six, he now works for Aliento, a community organization helping undocumented immigrants.</p>

<p>He personally benefited from the Deferred Action for Childhood Arrivals (DACA) immigrant policy brought in by Barack Obama, offering protections and work permits for those in his situation.</p>

<p>But for Patino, those safeguards will expire next year, and Trump has promised to end the DACA program.</p>

<p>Indeed, Trump already tried to dismantle it during his previous term, but his decree was scuppered by a US Supreme Court decision, largely on procedural grounds.</p>

<p>Faced with this uncertainty, Patino is considering moving to a state that would refuse to report him to federal authorities, such as Colorado or California.</p>

<p><strong>'Frustrating and hurtful'</strong></p>

<p>He remembers well the struggle of being undocumented in his twenties -- a time when he could not obtain a basic job like flipping burgers in McDonald's, and could not apply for a driver's license or travel for fear of being deported.</p>

<p>"I don't personally want to go back to that kind of life," Patino said.</p>

<p>For him, Trump's electoral win is not just scary, but an insult.</p>

<p>"We're contributing to this country. So that's the hard part: me following the rules, working, paying my taxes, helping this country grow, that's not enough," he said.</p>

<p>"So it's frustrating, and it's hurtful."</p>

<p>Patino understands why so many Hispanic voters, often faced with economic difficulties, ended up voting for Trump.</p>

<p>Those who are here legally "believe that they're not going to be targeted," he said.</p>

<p>"A lot of Latinos associate wealth and success with whiteness, and they want to be part of that group and to be included, rather than be outside of it and be marginalized and be considered 'the other,'" he said.</p>

<p>Still, he is angry with his own uncles and cousins who, having once been undocumented themselves, voted for Trump.</p>

<p>"We cannot have a conversation together, because it's going to get into argument and probably into a fight," he said.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/05nbefig_donald-trump_625x300_07_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump won against Kamala Harris to become US' 47th President (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/one-directions-liam-payne-took-cocaine-alcohol-antidepressant-before-death-6968749]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Liam Payne Took Cocaine, Alcohol, Antidepressant Before Death]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/one-directions-liam-payne-took-cocaine-alcohol-antidepressant-before-death-6968749]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 08 Nov 2024 03:10:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[One Direction star Liam Payne consumed cocaine, alcohol and a prescription antidepressant before falling to his death from a Buenos Aires hotel balcony last month, Argentine prosecutors said Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>One Direction star Liam Payne consumed cocaine, alcohol and a prescription antidepressant before falling to his death from a Buenos Aires hotel balcony last month, Argentine prosecutors said Thursday.</p>

<p>The prosecutor's office added that three people were charged with supplying him with drugs and one of them was also charged with abandoning a person in a vulnerable state.</p>

<p>"The results of the toxicological studies, which have been communicated to his family, revealed that, in the moments prior to his death and over a period covering at least his last 72 hours, Payne had traces of polydrug use of alcohol, cocaine and a prescription antidepressant in his body," the prosecutors said.</p>

<p>Payne was found dead on October 16 after plunging from the balcony of his third-floor room at the CasaSur Hotel in the Argentine capital.</p>

<p>An autopsy found he died after sustaining "multiple traumas" and "internal and external hemorrhaging" from the fall.</p>

<p>One of the highest-grossing live acts in the world in the 2010s, One Direction went on indefinite hiatus in 2016.</p>

<p>Payne went on to enjoy a degree of solo success but his career had languished recently.</p>

<p>His death at age 31 prompted a global outpouring of grief and condolences from family, former bandmates, fans and others.</p>

<p><strong>Three charged with drugs supply</strong></p>

<p>Prosecutors said one of the three people charged in the case had accompanied him on a daily basis during his stay in Buenos Aires and was charged with abandoning a person who later died as well as supplying him with narcotics.</p>

<p>The second suspect is a hotel employee accused of twice supplying Payne with cocaine while he was staying at the CasaSur. A third person is also accused of supplying him with the drug on October 14, two days before his death.</p>

<p>The prosecution ruled out self-harm and the "physical intervention of third parties" as the cause of Payne's death, saying that the injuries he sustained were compatible with those caused by a fall.</p>

<p>"Payne was either not fully conscious or was in a state of markedly diminished or absent consciousness at the time of the fall," the report said.</p>

<p>He was found dead after hotel staff called emergency services to report "a guest who is overwhelmed by drugs and alcohol, and destroying his room."</p>

<p><strong>Body flown home</strong></p>

<p>The toxicological report was published a day after the singer's father Geoff Payne repatriated his body to Britain aboard a flight from Buenos Aires to London.</p>

<p>Payne's death has prompted a debate about whether the music industry has a duty of care for the mental health of stars who find fame at a young age.</p>

<p>The singer from Wolverhampton in central England had spoken publicly about struggles with substance abuse and the pressures of teenage stardom.</p>

<p>He first auditioned for the hugely popular television talent show "The X Factor" at the age of 14 but was unsuccessful.</p>

<p>Two years later he hit gold on the program, which teamed him up with Niall Horan, Harry Styles, Louis Tomlinson and Zayn Malik to form One Direction.</p>

<p>Over the next six years, the group enjoyed global fame and legions of screaming fans, selling more than 70 million copies of their five albums. They went on four world tours and won nearly 200 awards.</p>

<p>Payne is survived by a seven-year-old boy, Bear, with Girls Aloud star Cheryl Tweedy.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/lck0ods8_liam-payne_625x300_18_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Liam Payne was found dead on October 16 (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-federal-reserve-chief-jerome-powell-says-will-not-resign-early-if-asked-by-trump-6968683]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Federal Reserve Chief Says Will Not Resign Early If Asked By Trump]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-federal-reserve-chief-jerome-powell-says-will-not-resign-early-if-asked-by-trump-6968683]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 08 Nov 2024 02:54:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US Federal Reserve Chair Jerome Powell said Thursday that he would not resign if asked to leave early by President-elect Donald Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US Federal Reserve Chair Jerome Powell said Thursday that he would not resign if asked to leave early by President-elect Donald Trump.</p>

<p>Speaking at a press conference after unveiling a quarter point interest rate cut, Powell -- whose term as Fed chair ends in 2026 -- added that firing any of the Fed's seven governors was also "not permitted under the law."</p>

<p>His comments underscore the delicate balancing act policymakers may have to play in the next Trump administration, given the US president-elect's recent criticism of the Fed.</p>

<p>On the campaign trail, Trump repeatedly accused Powell -- whom he first appointed to run the US central bank -- of working to favor the Democrats, and has suggested he would look to replace him once his term as Fed Chair ends.</p>

<p>The president-elect has also said he would like "at least" a say over setting Fed interest rates, something not currently allowed under the bank's dual mandate from Congress to act independently to tackle both inflation and unemployment.</p>

<p>Fed governors are nominated by the president, and appointed by the Senate to serve a 14-year term.</p>

<p>They can also be appointed to serve out the remainder of a 14-year term if a Fed governor retires, and must then be reconfirmed.</p>

<p>If he wanted to, Powell could stay on as a governor after he steps down as Fed chair, and serve out the remainder of his term, which expires in early 2028.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2019-08/223gpl1o_jerome-powell-reuters_625x300_01_August_19.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Fed governors are nominated by the president, and appointed by the Senate to serve a 14-year term (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-town-on-alert-after-43-monkeys-escape-research-facility-6968656]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Town On Alert After 43 Monkeys Escape Research Facility]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-town-on-alert-after-43-monkeys-escape-research-facility-6968656]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 08 Nov 2024 02:49:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[More than 40 monkeys were on the loose Thursday in a small US town after escaping a research facility, with authorities warning residents to keep their doors and windows closed.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>More than 40 monkeys were on the loose Thursday in a small US town after escaping a research facility, with authorities warning residents to keep their doors and windows closed.</p>

<p>The rhesus macaques -- described as "skittish" by police in Yemassee, South Carolina -- were reported to have fled their enclosures a day earlier at a facility run by Alpha Genesis, which specializes in primate-based biomedical research.</p>

<p>Search teams were deployed to help locate the monkeys and were "working to entice them with food," the local police department said on social media.</p>

<p>"Residents are urged to keep their doors and windows securely closed and to report any sighting immediately by dialing 911. Please do not attempt to approach these animals under any circumstances," it said.</p>

<p>The police force added that all the 43 primates were young females weighing up to seven pounds (three kilograms), and that they had not been used for testing.</p>

<p>"A spokesman from Alpha Genesis can confirm that these animals are too young to carry disease," it said.</p>

<p>Greg Westergaard, CEO of Alpha Genesis, said the escape was "frustrating," telling CBS News he is "hoping for a happy ending" with the primates returning of their own volition.</p>

<p>He said that the primates were able to roam free after a caretaker failed to secure a door at an enclosure.</p>

<p>"It's really like follow-the-leader. You see one go and the others go," Westergaard said.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/hgk64heg_monkeys-generic-unsplash_625x300_08_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The police force added that all the 43 primates were young females (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>