<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Dec 2024 12:06:58 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fact-check-video-of-attack-on-sufi-shrine-shared-as-temple-vandalised-in-bangladesh-7176582]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Video Of Attack On Sufi Shrine Shared As Temple Vandalised In Bangladesh]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fact-check-video-of-attack-on-sufi-shrine-shared-as-temple-vandalised-in-bangladesh-7176582]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Dec 2024 11:49:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[BOOM found that the incident in the viral video is from an attack on a Sufi shrine in Kazipur, Sirajganj, Bangladesh in August 2024.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Claim:&nbsp;</strong>Video shows a Hindu temple being attacked in Bangladesh</p>

<p><strong>Fact Check:&nbsp;</strong>BOOM found that the incident in the viral video is from an attack on a Sufi shrine in Kazipur, Sirajganj, Bangladesh in August 2024. BOOM Bangladesh reached out to a local reporters who confirmed the location and stated that it is a Sufi shrine and not a Hindu temple.</p>

<p>A video of a mob vandalising a Sufi shrine in Bangladesh in August this year is being shared as an attack on a Hindu temple in the country.</p>

<p>The incident in the video is from August 2024 when the Sufi shrine of Ali Pagla in Kazipur, Sirajganj in Bangladesh was vandalised.</p>

<p>BOOM Bangladesh reached out to a local reporters who confirmed the location and stated that it is a Sufi shrine and not a Hindu temple. Bangladesh has been in a state of flux since former prime minister Sheikh Hasina was forced to flee the country in early August following widespread protests.</p>

<p><strong>Viral video from Bangladesh shared with false claim</strong></p>

<p>The two minutes-long video is being shared on X with the caption, "Hindu temple status in Bangladesh yesterday."</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Click here to view, and here for an archive." id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/i0hoh68o_fact-check-hindu-temple-in-bangladesh-_625x300_05_December_24.jpg?im=FitAndFill,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Click here to view, and here for an archive." /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">Click <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://x.com/Mahaveer_VJ/status/1863533045376074116">here </a>to view, and <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://perma.cc/2UT6-W9P8?type=standard">here </a>for an archive.</p>
</div>

<p><strong>FACT-CHECK: Structure in viral video attacked is a Sufi shrine</strong></p>

<p>BOOM found that the viral video is from August 2024 when Sufi shrine of Ali Pagla in Kazipur, Sirajganj in Bangladesh, was attacked and vandalised.</p>

<p>Taking a hint from <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://x.com/Mrityun91255972/status/1863501729641460172">replies </a>stating that the location in the viral video is not a temple but a Sufi shrine named Ali Pagla in Sirajganj, Bangladesh, we found several Bangladeshi news reports on the incident. The reports stated that Ali Pagla mazhar was vandalised on August 29, 2024.</p>

<p>We found a news report by Kalbela which had reported that the incident in the viral video is from August 31, 2024. The report also has a screengrab that matches the visuals in the video.</p>

<p>The report mentioned that in Kazipur, Sirajganj, Bangladesh, villagers had sacked the imam of a mosque in the area after the shrine was attacked allegedly by his men. The report states that several people in the area had claimed that Imam Golam Rabbani and his men had vandalised the shrine of Ali Pagla on August 29.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Click here to view" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/pqddv988_fact-check-_625x300_05_December_24.jpg?im=FitAndFill,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Click here to view" />&nbsp;</div>

<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">Click <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.kalbela.com/country-news/116989">here </a>to view</p>
</div>

<p>&nbsp;<strong>Local journalists confirm to BOOM Bangladesh the location of the video</strong></p>

<p>BOOM Bangladesh reached out to Abdul Jaleel, a local journalist from Sirajganj, Kazipur, who confirmed that the viral video is from Ali Paglar Mazhar, Sirajganj. Daily Star correspondent Shahidul Islam Nirob, also confirmed to BOOM Bangladesh that the video is from Ali Paglar Mazhar and stated that it is not a Hindu temple as being falsely claimed. The visuals in the below news report on the shrine being vandalised also match the visuals viral video. From the 2.50 minutes timestamp we can see the shrine being attacked with the steel rods.</p>

<p><iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="315" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/XJDiNJM4UpI?si=AAR1bnx8oXSZ-7uy" title="YouTube video player" width="560"></iframe></p>

<p><em>(This story was originally published by <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.boomlive.in/fact-check/hindu-temple-attacked-bangladesh-video-old-sufi-shrine-vandalised-fake-news-27167" target="_blank">Boom</a>, and republished by NDTV as part of the Shakti Collective)</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/n17blp7o_fact-check-hindu-temple-in-bangladesh-_625x300_05_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/deadly-game-woman-jailed-for-after-boyfriend-dies-during-hide-and-seek-7176546]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Deadly Game: US Woman Jailed After Boyfriend Dies In Hide-And-Seek Game]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/deadly-game-woman-jailed-for-after-boyfriend-dies-during-hide-and-seek-7176546]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Dec 2024 11:41:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Florida woman received a life sentence after being found guilty of killing her boyfriend by locking him in a suitcase and leaving him to suffocate, amid a background of domestic and alcohol-related issues.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An American woman from Florida has been sentenced to life in prison for the 2020 death of her boyfriend, whom she trapped in a suitcase and left to suffocate. The sentence was given on Monday by Circuit Judge Michael Kraynick in Orlando. Sarah Boone, 47, was convicted of killing 42-year-old Jorge Torres.</p>

<p>The <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://x.com/CollinRugg/status/1863710143722164260">tragic incident occurred on 24 February 2020</a> at Winter Park, when Boone and Torres, both intoxicated, engaged in a game of hide-and-seek. Boone reportedly zipped in Torres into a suitcase leaving him there, which led to his death by asphyxiation. The case had a history of marital strife and alcohol abuse between the couple.</p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.cbsnews.com/miami/news/florida-woman-sentenced-to-life-for-zipping-boyfriend-into-suitcase-suffocating-him/"><em>CBS News,</em></a> a jury deliberated only 90 minutes on October 25 before convicting Boone of the second-degree murder of Jorge Torres after a 10-day trial. Boone had insisted she was herself a victim of domestic violence at the hands of Torres and had rejected a plea deal offer of a 15-year sentence. Torres' family members testified at the hearing that his death had torn them apart.</p>

<p>"Sarah deserves to rot in jail," said a sister, Victoria Torres. "Sarah has caused a lifetime of pain."</p>

<p>In her own statement, Boone went through a litany of abuse by Torres she said occurred over many years, decried the way her trial was handled and covered by the media, yet asked forgiveness for her actions.</p>

<p>"I forgive myself for falling in love with a monster. I tried breaking the spell ... I never stopped loving him," said Boone, who has been in jail for 58 months. "I didn't mean for this to happen. Forgive me Jorge. Forgive me Torres family."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/tmsuh7c8_boone-and-torres_625x300_05_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sarah Boone (left) suffocated boyfriend Jorge Torres while he was trapped in suitcase.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/intel-stands-by-forecast-after-ceo-exit-vows-to-be-thriftier-7176428]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Intel Stands By Forecast After CEO Exit, Vows To Be Thriftier]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/intel-stands-by-forecast-after-ceo-exit-vows-to-be-thriftier-7176428]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Dec 2024 11:21:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Intel Corp, fresh off the abrupt departure of Chief Executive Officer Pat Gelsinger, stuck with its current financial forecast during a presentation Wednesday while also saying it would keep a tight rein on capital spending.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Intel Corp., fresh off the abrupt departure of Chief Executive Officer Pat Gelsinger, stuck with its current financial forecast during a presentation Wednesday while also saying it would keep a tight rein on capital spending.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"We stand by the guidance that we gave at earnings," Chief Financial Officer and interim Co-CEO Dave Zinsner said during the UBS Global Technology and AI Conference on Wednesday. He also said that Intel's "core strategy" remains intact.</p>

<p>Still, he and Intel executive Naga Chandrasekaran offered a vision for the company that included a more conservative approach to capital spending - something that had been a concern for investors during Gelsinger's tenure.</p>

<p>"There's a significant cultural change that has to happen," said Chandrasekaran, a Micron Technology Inc. veteran who oversees Intel's manufacturing operations and supply chain. The company previously made as many chips as were needed to satisfy demand, an approach Chandrasekaran called "no wafer left behind." Intel now needs to embrace the attitude of "no capital left behind," he said.</p>

<p>Intel announced Gelsinger's retirement on Monday, less than four years after he took the job. His departure came after the board gave him the option to retire or be removed, Bloomberg reported earlier, citing people familiar with the matter. Last month, the company said that sales would be $13.3 billion to $14.3 billion in the current quarter, compared with an average analyst estimate at the time of $13.6 billion.&nbsp;</p>

<p>At the UBS event, the executives said that Intel would continue Gelsinger's strategy of turning the company into a "world-class" foundry - a maker of chips for outside clients. Intel also has no concerns about its Chips Act grant, Zinsner said. The Santa Clara, California-based company is set to get about $7.9 billion in awards as part of a federal program meant to revitalize the domestic semiconductor industry.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"It's an ironclad agreement," Zinsner said. He also noted that much of the Chips Act incentives will come in the form of tax credits, rather than grants, and the incoming Trump administration "values manufacturing."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/ucgoc31_intel-reuters_625x300_02_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Intel announced Pat Gelsinger's retirement, less than four years after he took the job.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uks-keir-starmer-offers-plan-for-change-to-deliver-on-poll-pledges-7176396]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK's Keir Starmer Offers 'Plan For Change' To Deliver On Poll Pledges]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uks-keir-starmer-offers-plan-for-change-to-deliver-on-poll-pledges-7176396]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Dec 2024 11:17:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Keir Starmer will unveil a "plan for change" for Britain on Thursday as he attempts a de-facto relaunch of his government following a bumpy first five months in power.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Keir Starmer will unveil a "plan for change" for Britain on Thursday as he attempts a de-facto relaunch of his government following a bumpy first five months in power.</p>

<p>The Labour leader is to lay out "ambitious milestones" on which voters can judge his administration, seeking to move on from several unpopular decisions that have overshadowed his young premiership.</p>

<p>"Mission-led government does not mean picking milestones because they are easy or will happen anyway," Mr Starmer, who entered office in July, is set to say in a speech near London.</p>

<p>"It means relentlessly driving real improvements in the lives of working people."</p>

<p>Mr Starmer's first weeks were dominated by controversies over scrapping winter fuel payments for millions of pensioners, keeping a child benefit restriction, and for accepting gifts from a wealthy donor.</p>

<p>They were also overshadowed by the departure of his chief of staff Sue Gray following intense media scrutiny over her role and reports of factional in-fighting inside Number 10.</p>

<p>His finance minister's debut budget on October 30 failed to provide a more positive narrative after coverage focused on farmers and business owners angry at increases in inheritance tax and employer payroll contributions.</p>

<p>Critics say the business tax rise, an increase in the national minimum wage, and plans for higher state borrowing will undermine the Labour government's overriding mission to fire up an anaemic economy.</p>

<p>"Some may oppose what we are doing and no doubt there will be obstacles along the way," the premier was due to say in his speech, according to excerpts released by Downing Street.</p>

<p>"But this government was elected on a mandate of change and our plan reflects the priorities of working people."</p>

<p>The speech comes amid plunging approval ratings for the government and a week after Mr Starmer suffered his first ministerial resignation when Louise Haigh quit the transport brief after it emerged she had pleaded guilty to a criminal offence before she became a lawmaker.</p>

<p>Mr Starmer's spokespeople insist his speech forms the next phase of his plan for "a decade of national renewal", after the first stage focused on "fixing the foundations" of the country.</p>

<p>The premier has repeatedly claimed that he is taking "tough decisions" because the former Conservative administration bequeathed Labour a dire inheritance across several sectors after 14 consecutive years in power.</p>

<p>Labour accuses the Tories of leaving behind a &amp;#163;22-billion "black hole" in the public finances ($28-billion), a prison system bursting at the seams and a National Health Service (NHS) on its knees.</p>

<h2><strong>'Honest'</strong></h2>

<p>Mr Starmer's government highlights several policies already announced, including the launching of a publicly owned clean energy company and the lifting of a ban on new onshore wind farms.</p>

<p>It has also strengthened workers' rights and moved to cut planning regulations to help build 1.5 million new homes, while Mr Starmer has visited more than a dozen countries to repair relations damaged by Brexit.</p>

<p>Westminster is very much viewing his speech as a "reset", however, with UK newspapers reporting that he is likely to revise some pledges made during his successful general election campaign.</p>

<p>The prime minister is expected to drop a promise to make Britain the fastest-growing economy in the G7 and replace it with targets to improve living standards.</p>

<p>He is also expected to set a target for NHS waiting lists and will announce his intention to put an extra 13,000 police on Britain's streets to crack down on anti-social behaviour.</p>

<p>"It's about trying to use language that is going to connect with voters," Patrick Diamond, a policy adviser when Labour was last in Number 10, told AFP.</p>

<p>"It's going to be a set of commitments that voters can tangibly judge whether or not the government's really making an impact," added Mr Diamond, now a professor at Queen Mary University of London.</p>

<p>Milestones risk becoming millstones, however. Mr Starmer's predecessor Rishi Sunak was hampered by his failure to meet key pledges.</p>

<p>"This plan for change is the most ambitious yet honest programme for government in a generation," Mr Starmer was to say.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/fgtlk7t8_uk-keir-starmer-afp_625x300_05_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Keir Starmer's first weeks were dominated by controversies over scrapping winter fuel payments]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/britney-spears-reveals-she-moved-to-mexico-to-get-away-from-cruel-paparazzi-7176339]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Britney Spears Reveals She Moved To Mexico To Escape "Cruel" Paparazzi]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/britney-spears-reveals-she-moved-to-mexico-to-get-away-from-cruel-paparazzi-7176339]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Dec 2024 11:10:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The 'Oops!... I Did It Again' singer in her clip said that the media have always been cruel to her]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Singer Britney Spears recently revealed in an Instagram video that she relocated to Mexico to escape "cruel" paparazzi attention. "It really kind of hurts my feelings that the paparazzi make my face look like I'm wearing like a white Jason mask, and it doesn't even look like me," Spears said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The 'Oops!... I Did It Again' singer in her clip said that the media have always been cruel to her. "They've always been incredibly cruel to me, the paparazzi and pictures and the way they've illustrated me to be in some of it. I know I'm not perfect at all, by any means, but some of it is extremely mean and cruel, and that's why I've moved to Mexico," she said in the video.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The 'Toxic' singer shared a separate clip on the same day acknowledging her birthday on December 2, "I'm turning five this year. I'm turning five years old, and I have to go to kindergarten tomorrow," she said.</p>

<p><strong>See the video here:</strong></p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DDGjvzOpLNB/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DDGjvzOpLNB/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DDGjvzOpLNB/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DDGjvzOpLNB/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by XILA MARIA RIVER RED (@britneyspears)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p>Meanwhile, Spears is not the only person who has moved out of the US. In November, actress and film producer Eva Longoria revealed that she, her husband Jose Baston, and their six-year-old son Santiago are splitting their time between living in Spain and Mexico City, the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.independent.co.uk/life-style/britney-spears-moved-mexico-paparazzi-b2658782.html" rel="noindex,nofollow"><em>Independent </em></a>reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In an interview with <em>Marie Claire</em>, the actress said that she noticed Los Angeles was changing to the point where she no longer wanted to live there.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"I had my whole adult life here," she said about California. "But even before [the pandemic], it was changing. The vibe was different. And then Covid happened, and it pushed it over the edge. Whether it's the homelessness or the taxes, not that I want to s*** on California - it just feels like this chapter in my life is done now."</p>

<p>The actress acknowledged that she is "privileged" to be able to move countries.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"I get to escape and go somewhere. Most Americans aren't so lucky. They're going to be stuck in this dystopian country, and my anxiety and sadness is for them."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2019-04/7vv803r_britney-spears-afp_625x300_25_April_19.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Spears is not the only person who has moved out of the US]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bryan-thompson-unitedhealthcare-quiet-walk-silencer-on-gun-how-unitedhealthcare-ceo-was-murdered-7176331]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Quiet Walk, Silencer on Gun: How UnitedHealthcare CEO Was Murdered]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bryan-thompson-unitedhealthcare-quiet-walk-silencer-on-gun-how-unitedhealthcare-ceo-was-murdered-7176331]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Dec 2024 11:08:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The CEO of US-based UnitedHealthcare, Brian Thompson, was gunned down outside a New York hotel on Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The CEO of US-based UnitedHealthcare, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/united-healthcare-ceo-brian-thompson-received-death-threats-before-being-killed-reveals-wife-7174451#pfrom=home-ndtv_topstories" target="_blank">Brian Thompson</a>, was gunned down outside a New York hotel on Wednesday. Mr Thompson, 50, was walking toward the New York Hilton Midtown, where he was set to deliver a keynote address at an investor conference when he was ambushed. Surveillance footage captured the suspect - a white man wearing a hooded jacket, a black face mask, and sneakers -approaching Thompson from behind.</p>

<p>According to the NYPD, the gunman fired multiple shots using a semi-automatic handgun equipped with a silencer in the bustling Midtown Manhattan area.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">NYC has some of the strictest gun laws. That doesn't prevent the execution of UnitedHealthcare CEO Brian Thompson by a gunman using a gun with a silencer attached.<br />
It appears overreaching gun laws don't work.<br />
Murderers don't care about laws.<br />
Go figure. <a href="https://t.co/qhcP7Ty6lP">pic.twitter.com/qhcP7Ty6lP</a></p>
â€” Chris Randolph (@TrumpAF2024) <a href="https://twitter.com/TrumpAF2024/status/1864391488198619202?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 4, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>Initial shots struck Mr Thompson in the back and leg, causing him to stagger and collapse against a wall. Despite the firearm jamming three times, the shooter cleared the weapon and continued firing. After ensuring Mr Thompson was incapacitated, the attacker calmly walked away, later fleeing the scene on an electric bike toward Central Park.</p>

<p>Officers responded to a 911 call, arriving to find Mr Thompson on the sidewalk with critical gunshot wounds. He was rushed to a nearby hospital, where he was pronounced dead.</p>

<p>Surveillance footage revealed the suspect had been near the scene for several minutes before the attack, blending in with morning commuters. Earlier, at 6:17 am, cameras captured the gunman at a nearby Starbucks, purchasing water and power bars while wearing a surgical mask.</p>

<p>According to the CNN, police recovered a water bottle and a phone from an alley near the shooting site, believed to have been discarded by the suspect. Investigators are analysing the phone for potential fingerprints, DNA, or communication records that might reveal the killer's identity.</p>

<p>UnitedHealth Group, the parent company of UnitedHealthcare, issued a heartfelt statement mourning Mr Thompson's loss:</p>

<p>"We are deeply saddened and shocked at the passing of our dear friend and colleague Brian Thompson, the CEO of UnitedHealthcare," UnitedHealth Group said in a statement.</p>

<p>Mr Thompson's wife, Paulette, described the attack as "senseless" and mentioned her husband had received threats in the past, CNN reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The NYPD has released images of the suspect and is offering a $10,000 reward for information leading to his capture. The attacker is described as a white male in his 30s or 40s, wearing a gray backpack, black-and-white sneakers, and a hooded jacket.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/8t1vf4t_unitedhealthcare-ceo_625x300_05_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[According to the NYPD, the gunman fired multiple shots using a semi-automatic handgun.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/marcela-alcazar-rodriguez-actress-dies-at-mexican-spiritual-retreat-after-consuming-deadly-monkey-frog-venom-7176328]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Actress Dies At Spiritual Retreat After Consuming Deadly Monkey Frog Venom]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/marcela-alcazar-rodriguez-actress-dies-at-mexican-spiritual-retreat-after-consuming-deadly-monkey-frog-venom-7176328]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Dec 2024 11:04:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Mexican short film actress Marcela Alcazar Rodriguez tragically passed away after participating in a Kambo cleansing ritual at a spiritual retreat.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Faith holds great significance, but when it lacks rational thinking, it can lead to tragic consequences. This was the case for Mexican short film actress Marcela Alcazar Rodriguez, who sadly lost her life after vomiting and suffering from diarrhoea on December 1 after participating in a cleansing ritual at a retreat. The ritual involved ingesting the venom of the Amazonian giant monkey frog, known as Kambo.</p>

<p>The young actress was attending a spiritual retreat ceremony as part of a Healer Training Diploma when she drank a drink called Kombo, which contains frog poison from South America, and natives have used for toxin cleansing and is banned in some countries. She was in Mexico during the incident.</p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://metro.co.uk/2024/12/05/actress-vomits-amazon-frog-venom-spiritual-cleansing-dies-22124674/"><em>The Metro,</em></a> Rodriguez started throwing up and had severe diarrhoea, which are part of the body's reactions while going through the healing.' She first refused help while feeling ill but eventually gave in when her friend came to see her, witnesses said.Rodriguez was rushed to a Red Cross hospital, where she died.</p>

<p>It was not immediately known how long it took for her to arrive at the hospital. She was identified by the Mexican production company Mapache Films, which posted a tribute to her on Instagram.</p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/DDDzUKYsTu2/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DDDzUKYsTu2/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DDDzUKYsTu2/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DDDzUKYsTu2/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by Mapache Films (@mapache_films)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p>"With deep regret, we mourn the death of our beloved colleague and friend, Marcela Alcazar Rodriguez,' stated the production company in Spanish. Her passing left an immense vacuum in our hearts and in our professional community. Her dedication, joy, and commitment left a profound mark on all of us who had the privilege of working beside her."</p>

<p>This unfortunate incident has ignited discussions about the dangers of such traditional practices and their increasing popularity among wellness seekers.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/fc4389n_marcela-alcazar-rodriguez_625x300_05_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Marcela Alcazar Rodriguez was rushed to a hospital but could not be saved.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chinese-billionaire-yi-zhengs-royalflush-trading-app-is-big-winner-of-stimulus-7176207]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Chinese Billionaire's RoyalFlush Trading App Is Big Winner Of Stimulus]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chinese-billionaire-yi-zhengs-royalflush-trading-app-is-big-winner-of-stimulus-7176207]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Dec 2024 10:48:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The tycoon behind China's RoyalFlush trading app has added $6 billion to his wealth since the nation's stimulus blitz in September, underscoring how the volatility has been a boon for an elite few.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The tycoon behind China's RoyalFlush trading app has added $6 billion to his wealth since the nation's stimulus blitz in September, underscoring how the volatility has been a boon for an elite few.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Yi Zheng, an engineering graduate who founded the entity behind Hithink RoyalFlush Information Network Co. in 1994, four years after China's stock exchanges opened, is overseeing his company's best share performance in half a decade after trading of mainland stocks surged.&nbsp;</p>

<p>While Yi's fortune is up 190% since the announcements, it's not yet clear if the sweeping measures will meaningfully lift the nation's $10 trillion stock market after a turbulent couple of months.</p>

<p>The 54-year-old is now worth $9.2 billion, according to the Bloomberg Billionaires Index. That's largely based on his 36% stake in the company, which also sells financial data. Its shares have more than doubled this year and are on track for the best year since 2019. Volatility on China's benchmark CSI 300 Index had spiked in the past two months, with a 30-day gauge jumping to the highest since 2015, when Asia's largest economy experienced an epic boom and bust in stocks.</p>

<p>Home to the world's second largest stock market, China has allowed trading and software entrepreneurs to accumulate vast fortunes. East Money Information Co., Hithink's biggest domestic competitor, grew more valuable than Credit Suisse in 2020 after frenzied trading in China, making founder Qi Shi a billionaire several times over. The Swiss bank was eventually taken over by rival UBS Group AG. Online broker Futu Holdings Ltd, which has customers in the US, China and Hong Kong, has created vast wealth for founder Li Hua.</p>

<p>That growth has also been marked by stumbles. In 2021, the legitimacy of online brokerages, which had allowed millions of Chinese investors to evade capital controls to trade shares in markets such as Hong Kong and New York, was abruptly questioned. Financial data providers like Hithink have also drawn scrutiny.</p>

<p><strong>Explosive Growth</strong></p>

<p>In October, 6.85 million accounts were opened in China's mainland A-share market - versus the monthly average of 1.5 million in the first nine months of 2024, according to data from HSBC Qianhai Securities.</p>

<p>Hithink has more than 19 million active users per week on its free trading platform, according to the company's website. The Hangzhou, Zhejiang-based company reported revenue of 3.6 billion yuan ($495 million) in 2023.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The recent stimulus has resulted in higher stock trading volume, which could boost demand for better financial information from retail investors," said Yiran Liu, an analyst at HSBC Qianhai Securities.</p>

<p>China's stimulus, which included interest rate cuts, more cash for banks, bigger incentives to buy homes and plans to consider a stock stabilization fund, led to the nation's benchmark index gaining about a third to peak on Oct. 8. It has since given up some of those gains amid concerns about the economy and US President-elect Donald Trump's tariff threats.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Hithink also generates revenue through selling funds and software. For a fee, retail investors on the RoyalFlush app can use AI to find the right price to enter and sell stock positions.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Yi and Hithink didn't respond to a request for comment.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Yi was born in 1970 in Beijing, and his own success is largely tied to the development of the nation's stock markets. He graduated from Zhejiang University with a bachelor's degree in electrical engineering in 1993. While still a student, he developed a securities software for Industrial &amp; Commercial Bank of China Ltd, according to local media reports.&nbsp;</p>

<p>China's two stock exchanges were founded in 1990. In 1994, Yi co-founded Hangzhou Hexin Software Technology Ltd., now a key unit of his Hithink, and made an early win with the Longhubang, or Dragon and Tiger Ranking, which tracked futures contracts to give traders an indication of market sentiment.</p>

<p>In 1997, Yi ventured into developing a securities trading platform, which later morphed into Hithink's signature product. Hithink still uses Longhubang for its listings of the most active traders and stocks.</p>

<p><strong>Royal Flush</strong></p>

<p>The firm's Chinese name Tonghuashun translates to Royal Flush, the best hand in poker. It first debuted in late 2009 on China's Shenzhen Stock Exchange. Its shares have soared more than 4900% since the listing.</p>

<p>The listed entity has since evolved to become a top financial data provider in China, with over 5,000 employees.&nbsp;</p>

<p>But there were bumps along the way. Hithink was caught last month in China's crackdown on influencers and livestreaming platforms that offer investment advice. It was ordered to suspend its investment advisory service unit from adding new clients for three months.</p>

<p>The firm was also investigated by the market regulator in 2015 and fined 6.53 million yuan for selling securities trading systems to unqualified investors.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/7t4k19ig_royalflush-bloomberg_625x300_05_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Yi Zheng is now worth $9.2 billion.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-prince-harry-said-on-separation-rumours-with-meghan-markle-7176109]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What Prince Harry Said On Separation Rumours With Meghan Markle]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-prince-harry-said-on-separation-rumours-with-meghan-markle-7176109]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Dec 2024 10:43:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Over the last few months, whenever Prince Harry and Meghan Markle made solo public appearances, the media and royal family observers wondered if there was trouble in their marriage.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Over the last few months, whenever Prince Harry and Meghan Markle made solo public appearances, the media and royal family observers wondered if there was trouble in their marriage.</p>

<p>And now, Prince Harry has finally addressed all the rumours, saying, â€œApparently we've bought or moved houses 10, 12 times. We've apparently divorced maybe 10, 12 times as well. So it's just like, what?â€<br />
<br />
At The New York Times' 2024 DealBook Summit in New York City on Wednesday, Harry, 40, discussed his life and speculations surrounding his marriage with Meghan, 43.<br />
<br />
At the Summit, DealBook founder Andrew Ross Sorkin asked Harry about the interest many have in the couple's personal life. He shared that when he searched his name on Google News, "there were people fascinated by everything you're doing, all the time. They're fascinated by Meghan being in California right now, and you're here,â€ Sorkin said.<br />
<br />
Asked why the couple was doing independent events and not together, Harry said, "Because you invited me, you should have known!â€&nbsp;<br />
<br />
Sorkin then continued, "True... Is that normal for you? The second there's an article â€” she's in California, you're in New York â€” they say, â€˜Well, what is happening with these two, right?' Is that a good thing for you, in a way, that there's so much interest in you?â€<br />
<br />
To this, Harry replied, "No, that's definitely not a good thing."<br />
<br />
Although Harry admitted that it was hard to keep up with, he tries to ignore it.<br />
<br />
â€œIt's hard to keep up with, but that's why you just sort of ignore it. The people I feel most sorry about are the trolls...Their hopes are just built and built, and it's like, â€˜Yes, yes, yes,' and then it doesn't happen. So I feel sorry for them. Genuinely, I do.â€<br />
<br />
He further said he had â€œno doubtâ€ that his interview with Sorkin â€œwill be spun or twisted somehow against me," adding that maybe "the host will also be trolled relentlessly.â€<br />
<br />
â€œFor that, I can only apologise, but you did invite me, so it's not my fault,â€ he quipped.<br />
<br />
The divorce rumours started when the Duke and Duchess of Sussex were seen appearing separately at various professional engagements. While many called it a â€œprofessional separation,â€ the move was said to be a new â€œtwin-trackâ€ approach that could overhaul their image, <a href="https://nypost.com/2024/12/04/entertainment/prince-harry-breaks-silence-on-meghan-markle-divorce-rumors/" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">The New York Post</a> reported.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-09/7ij5uja8_prince-harry-meghan-markle_625x300_11_September_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Prince Harry discussed his life and speculations surrounding his marriage with Meghan Markle.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/he-has-spent-months-in-capsule-under-the-sea-for-a-world-record-7176160]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[A Home Under The Sea With A Bed, Toilet, TV: All That Is Missing Is...]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/he-has-spent-months-in-capsule-under-the-sea-for-a-world-record-7176160]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Dec 2024 10:41:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Rudiger Koch has been living in a submerged capsule off the coast of Panama for two months.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There are probably easier ways to set a world record, but Rudiger Koch has found his method 11 meters (36 feet) under the sea.</p>

<p>He's been living in a submerged capsule off the coast of Panama for two months -- which means, he told a visiting AFP journalist, he has about two more to go.</p>

<p>"The last time I checked, I was still married," he joked, as fish swim through bright blue Caribbean waters outside the portholes.</p>

<p>But Koch, a 59-year-old aerospace engineer from Germany, has grander plans than simply notching a record. His stunt, he says, could change the way we think about human life -- and where we can settle, even permanently.</p>

<p>"Moving out to the ocean is something we should do as a species," he told AFP.</p>

<p>"What we are trying to do here is prove that the seas are actually a viable environment for human expansion."</p>

<p>Koch's 30-square-meter (320-square-foot) capsule has most of the trappings of modern life: a bed, toilet, TV, computer and internet -- even an exercise bike.</p>

<p>The only thing missing? A shower.</p>

<p>His home under the sea is attached through a vertical tube to another chamber perched above the waves, housing other members of his team -- and providing a way for food and curious journalists to be sent down.</p>

<p>The underwater chamber, meanwhile, provides a shelter for fish and acts as an artificial reef -- providing an environmental benefit.</p>

<p>"In the night, you can hear all the crustaceans," he said. "There's the fish out there, and there's all that stuff, and that wasn't here before we came."</p>

<p><strong>A window into the sea</strong></p>

<p>On a small bedside table lies Jules Verne's "Twenty Thousand Leagues Under the Sea," a 19th century sci-fi classic.</p>

<p>An admirer of the novel's Captain Nemo, Koch, who went down on September 26, is hoping to come up for air on January 24, surpassing by 20 days the record held by American Joseph Dituri, who spent 100 days submerged in a Florida lake.</p>

<p>Two clocks show how much time has passed -- and how much remains.</p>

<p>A narrow spiral staircase leads to the chamber above, the entire contraption located some 15 minutes by boat from the Puerto Lindo coast, off northern Panama.</p>

<p>Four cameras film his moves in the capsule -- capturing his daily life, monitoring his mental health and to provide proof that he's never come up to the surface.</p>

<p>Eial Berja, an Israeli, operates them from the section above, while minding the electricity and back-up generator.</p>

<p>It's not all easy going, he told AFP, noting that a heavy storm almost put an end to the project.</p>

<p>Outside of the media, Koch's only visitors have been his doctor, his children and his wife.</p>

<p>Supporting the project is Grant Romundt, from Canada. Both he and Koch have grander visions linked to the libertarian -- and at-times controversial -- "seasteading" movement that envisions ocean-based communities outside government control.</p>

<p>Though he still has a long way to go to resurface, Koch knows exactly what he'll do first once he's back on land: "a shower, a real shower."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/tp1qiimo_german-aerospace-engineer-rudiger-koch_625x300_05_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[German aerospace engineer Rudiger Koch, 59, inside an underwater room off the coast of Puerto Lindo.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/openai-ceo-thinks-elon-musk-wont-use-political-power-against-rivals-7176107]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[OpenAI CEO Thinks Elon Musk Won't Use Political Power Against Rivals]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/openai-ceo-thinks-elon-musk-wont-use-political-power-against-rivals-7176107]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Dec 2024 10:33:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[OpenAI Chief Executive Officer Sam Altman dismissed concerns that rival Elon Musk might use his newfound political influence to undercut competitors and benefit his own artificial intelligence efforts.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>OpenAI Chief Executive Officer Sam Altman dismissed concerns that rival Elon Musk might use his newfound political influence to undercut competitors and benefit his own artificial intelligence efforts.</p>

<p>â€œIt would be profoundly un-American to use political power to hurt your competitors and advantage your own businesses,â€ Altman said in an interview at the New York Times DealBook Summit on Wednesday. â€œI don't think people would tolerate that. I don't think Elon would do it.â€</p>

<p>Musk has emerged as a top ally to President-elect Donald Trump and was recently <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-to-lead-us-government-efficiency-department-donald-trump-7006239" target="_blank">appointed to lead the new Department of Government Efficiency</a> alongside ex-presidential candidate Vivek Ramaswamy.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Musk and Altman have a tense relationship. Musk, who helped launch OpenAI as a nonprofit, has spent months&nbsp;<a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-11-15/musk-escalates-altman-legal-feud-casting-openai-as-monopolist" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">pursuing litigation</a>&nbsp;against Altman and the ChatGPT maker for allegedly betraying its founding mission. While OpenAI remains the market leader for generative AI products, Musk's company, xAI, has rapidly gained momentum by&nbsp;<a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-10-29/musk-s-xai-in-talks-for-40-billion-valuation-wsj-says" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">raising billions</a>&nbsp;from investors.</p>

<p>In the interview Wednesday, Altman called Musk's startup â€œa serious competitorâ€ to OpenAI and said he had â€œtremendous respectâ€ for Musk's plans to build an xAI data center in Tennessee. Altman also expressed disappointment at the state of their relationship.</p>

<p>It's â€œtremendously sad,â€ he said, when asked about Musk's lawsuit. â€œI grew up with Elon as a mega hero.â€</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/1mq2a6g_openai_625x300_14_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sam Altman called Elon Musks startup "a serious competitor" to OpenAI.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/this-blank-pure-white-canvas-expected-to-sell-for-over-1-5-million-7176018]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[This Blank 'Pure White' Canvas Expected To Sell For Over $1.5 Million]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/this-blank-pure-white-canvas-expected-to-sell-for-over-1-5-million-7176018]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Dec 2024 10:19:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The 1970 artwork, titled General 52" x 52"- a reference to its dimensions-will be available for bidding at the Ketterer Kunst auction house in Berlin on December 6 and 7.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A blank "pure white" canvas by minimalist American painter Robert Ryman, valued at over $1.5 million, is heading to auction in Germany. The 1970 artwork, titled General 52" x 52"- a reference to its dimensions-will be available for bidding at the Ketterer Kunst auction house in Berlin on December 6 and 7, the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/12/03/lifestyle/blank-pure-white-art-canvas-expected-to-sell-for-over-1-5m/" rel="noindex,nofollow"><em>New York Post </em></a>reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>While the canvas appears blank, it is actually painted with white enamel and enamelac, materials typically used for metal surfaces. This choice of medium creates a delicate finish, so sensitive that the piece cannot be transported for viewing prior to the auction, according to the auction house.</p>

<p>"The material is very sensitive and the smallest traces in the flawless surface would immediately reduce the value of the work significantly," said the auction house in a statement. "That's why we are not sending it on a journey."</p>

<p><iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="315" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/KfKvSKxOeo8?si=K8hLZi4t2LNKu7Sf" title="YouTube video player" width="560"></iframe></p>

<p>Although the piece may appear blank, it invites viewers to uncover deeper meaning. "White is not always white. The white colour reveals the light, movement, and structure of the material," explained Simone Wichmann, an expert at Ketterer Kunst. &nbsp;</p>

<p>Wichmann further noted that Ryman's work transforms the viewer into an active participant. "The viewer is challenged and becomes the creator of the art," she said. &nbsp;</p>

<p>Ryman's minimalist works, while often divisive, have achieved significant acclaim and commanded high prices, with some selling for millions. Remarkably, Ryman was a self-taught artist who worked as a security guard at the Museum of Modern Art in New York before earning recognition for his innovative and thought-provoking pieces. &nbsp;</p>

<p>This auction follows a series of provocative art sales that have fueled public debate. Just last month, Maurizio Cattelan's Comedian- a banana duct-taped to a wall- sold for $6.2 million, only to be eaten by the buyer, a cryptocurrency entrepreneur.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/qb21g9lo_blank-canvas_625x300_05_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Wichmann further noted that Ryman's work transforms the viewer into an active participant.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explainer-frances-government-felled-in-no-confidence-vote-what-happens-next-7176003]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[France's Government Ousted In No-Confidence Vote. What Happens Next?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explainer-frances-government-felled-in-no-confidence-vote-what-happens-next-7176003]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Dec 2024 10:15:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The government in France collapsed on Wednesday after lawmakers of both left and right wings joined forces to push a no-confidence against the country's Prime Minister Michel Barnier]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The government in France collapsed on Wednesday after lawmakers of both left and right wings joined forces to push a no-confidence against the country's Prime Minister Michel Barnier, throwing the European Union's second-biggest economic power deeper into chaos that threatens to exacerbate its budgetary and looming economic crises.</p>

<p>The Prime Minister addressed the nation just before the vote, calling it an honour to have served France and its people with dignity. He'd been on the job for just two months and 29 days. With the vote of confidence against him, Mr Barnie will now have to tender his resignation and that of his government to President Emmanuel Macron, making his minority government's tenure the shortest lived in France's Fifth Republic beginning in 1958.&nbsp;</p>

<p>As per French media reports, he is expected to do so on Thursday morning. The president will then address the nation at 1900 GMT, the Elysee Palace said.</p>

<h2><strong>Rise and Fall Of Michel Barnier</strong></h2>

<p>Michel Barnier's government fell after 331 deputies voted against him, making him the shortest-serving Prime Minister in modern French political history. Only 288 votes were needed to pass the no-confidence motion in the 577-member chamber. It was the first successful no-confidence vote since a defeat for Georges Pompidou's government in 1962, when Charles de Gaulle was president.</p>

<p>In France, the President nominates prime ministers. However, lawmakers can reject his picks at any time by passing a no-confidence vote, like in the case of Barnier. National Assembly, the French parliament's lower house, is almost equally divided between the far right, a loosely united left-wing, centrists including Macron's allies, and a few candidates who please all three factions, according to a report by <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.vox.com/world-politics/389827/france-government-collapse-budget-economic-crisis-bernier-macron-le-pen" rel="No Follow, No Index" target="_blank">Vox</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Though not a popular leader, Mr Barnier was seen as a capable choice after the Prime Minister's post following surprise elections this past summer. However, he was met with challenges while trying to lead a government without a majority. He angered lawmakers on both the right and left after he attempted to push through a 2025 national budget without a vote in the lower house of parliament. Amid a standoff over the social security financing bill, France's far-right party and its left-wing alliance each put forward no-confidence motions against him.</p>

<h2><strong>Passage of No Confidence Vote</strong></h2>

<p>The successful vote means President Macron will have to find a new Prime Minister to replace Mr Barnier, which doesn't seem to be an easy affair. A similar situation happened once before in 1962, but the particular situation was dealt with by calling early legislative elections.&nbsp;</p>

<p>However, President Macron doesn't have that choice as he has already called called early poll last June. This means he can't call new ones until next July, because under the French Constitution, the National Assembly must remain in place for a minimum of one year.</p>

<p>So for the moment, France has no government. However, it will have caretaker ministers in place, appointed by the President. Amid limited options given the dysfunction in the National Assembly, Emmanuel Macron needs to appoint a new prime minister quickly to pass the government's budget and, hopefully, prevent an economic crisis from engulfing France.&nbsp;</p>

<p>A source close to Macron told news agency AFP that the president, who has taken time with appointments in the past, has "no choice" but to name the new premier within 24 hours.</p>

<h2><strong>Call For Emmanuel Macron's Resignation</strong></h2>

<p>France's hard left on Wednesday urged President Emmanuel Macron to resign and hold early presidential elections after lawmakers voted to oust the government of Prime Minister Michel Barnier.</p>

<p>"We are now calling on Macron to go," Mathilde Panot, the head of the parliamentary faction of the hard-left France Unbowed (LFI) party told reporters, urging "early presidential elections" to solve a deepening political crisis.</p>

<p>But taking care not to crow over the government's fall, Le Pen said in a television interview that her party -- once a new premier is appointed -- "would let them work" and help create a "budget that is acceptable for everyone".</p>

<p>Laurent Wauquiez, the head of right-wing deputies in parliament, said the far right and hard left bore the responsibility for a no-confidence vote that would "plunge the country into instability".</p>

<p>Macron, however, has rejected calls to resign.</p>

<h2><strong>Growing Crisis In France</strong></h2>

<p>With markets nervous and France bracing for public-sector strikes against the threat of cutbacks, action that will shut schools and hit air and rail traffic, there is a growing sense of crisis. The unions have called for civil servants, including teachers and air-traffic controllers, to strike on Thursday over separate cost-cutting measures.</p>

<p>Moreover, Macron is due to host a major international event on Saturday, with the reopening of the Notre-Dame Cathedral after the 2019 fire, with guests including Donald Trump on his first foreign trip since he was elected to be the next US president.</p>

<p>France also risks ending the year without a stable government or a 2025 budget, although the constitution allows special measures that would avert a US-style government shutdown.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Any new prime minister appointed by the President would face the same challenges as Barnier in getting bills, including the 2025 budget, adopted by a divided parliament. Macron could alternatively ask Barnier and his ministers to stay on in a caretaker capacity while he takes time to identify a prime minister able to attract sufficient cross-party support to pass legislation.</p>

<p>A caretaker government could either propose emergency legislation to roll the tax-and-spend provisions in the 2024 budget into next year or invoke special powers to pass the draft 2025 budget by decree - though jurists say this is a legal grey area and the political cost would be huge.</p>

<p>This could potentially cause further concerns in markets, which are already unnerving investors in French sovereign bonds and stocks. Earlier this week, France's borrowing costs briefly exceeded those of Greece, generally considered far more risky.&nbsp;</p>

<p>France's political turmoil also threatens to weaken a European Union already reeling from the implosion of Germany's coalition government, weeks before US President-elect Donald Trump returns to the White House.</p>

<p>The country's outgoing defence minister Sebastien Lecornu warned the turmoil could impact French support for Ukraine.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/fp3rvmng_french-prime-minister-michel-barnier-reuters_625x300_05_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Prime Minister Michel Barnier now has to tender his resignation to President Macron]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/people/brian-thompson-all-about-unitedhealthcare-ceo-brian-thompson-who-was-shot-dead-in-new-york-7175840]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[All About UnitedHealthcare CEO Brian Thompson Who Was Shot Dead In US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/people/brian-thompson-all-about-unitedhealthcare-ceo-brian-thompson-who-was-shot-dead-in-new-york-7175840]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Dec 2024 10:10:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[UnitedHealthcare CEO Brian Thompson was shot dead on Wednesday morning in New York. The incident occurred before 7 am at a Manhattan hotel, news agency IANS reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/united-healthcare-ceo-brian-thompson-shot-dead-in-new-york-gunman-at-large-7172850Â ">UnitedHealthcare CEO Brian Thompson was shot dead</a> on Wednesday morning in New York. The incident occurred before 7 am at a Manhattan hotel, news agency IANS reported. The 50-year-old was found in an unconscious state with a gunshot wound in the chest. He was rushed to the hospital, where he was pronounced dead.</p>

<p>The shooter fled the scene, and the authorities are on the hunt for a suspect described as a white male wearing a black hoodie, black pants, and black sneakers with white trim. The individual was also reportedly seen carrying a grey backpack and allegedly possessed a firearm fitted with a silencer.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Mr Thompson's wife revealed he had <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/united-healthcare-ceo-brian-thompson-received-death-threats-before-being-killed-reveals-wife-7174451Â ">received death threats</a> before the attack. Authorities have not released further details on the motive or suspect's identity.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
<strong>Who was Brian Thompson?</strong></p>

<ul>
	<li>Brian Thompson, 50, was the CEO of UnitedHealth, the largest private health insurer in the US, overseeing a company with revenues exceeding $371 billion in 2023.</li>
	<li>He graduated from the University of Iowa with a bachelor's degree in business administration in 1997.</li>
	<li>Mr Thompson had a career spanning 20 years in UnitedHealthcare. He joined the company in 2004 and rose through the ranks to become CEO in April 2021. During his leadership, the company saw significant growth, including over 35 acquisitions in the past decade. He earned $10.2 million in 2023. Before that, he worked at PwC for over six years, says his <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/brian-thompson-98065165/Â " rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">LinkedIn profile</a>.</li>
	<li>He lived in a suburb of Minneapolis, Minnesota, with his wife, Paulette, and their two sons. He was mourned as a â€œloving fatherâ€ and a dedicated colleague.</li>
	<li>Mr Thompson's career was not without controversy. He faced insider trading allegations after selling $15 million in UnitedHealth shares while reportedly aware of an ongoing US Department of Justice antitrust investigation. A class-action lawsuit filed by the City of Hollywood Firefighters' Pension Fund accused him and other executives of failing to disclose the probe before selling shares. The lawsuit remains active.</li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/ahschcd8_brian-thompson_625x300_05_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Brian Thompson had a career spanning two decades in UnitedHealth.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/the-renaissance-of-notre-dame-cathedral-miracles-and-controversies-7175934]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[The Renaissance Of Notre-Dame Cathedral: Miracles And Controversies]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/the-renaissance-of-notre-dame-cathedral-miracles-and-controversies-7175934]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Dec 2024 10:01:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[After over five years of reconstruction of Notre Dame cathedral, the building will officially reopen on Saturday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The more than five-year reconstruction of Notre Dame cathedral has featured some near-miraculous recoveries, as well as several controversies.</p>

<p>Ahead of the official reopening of the cathedral on Saturday, AFP looks at some of the key moments:</p>

<p><strong>The saviours</strong></p>

<p>Paris firefighters won universal praise for their swift and decisive action on the evening of April 15, 2019, with officers later saying they thought they were only 30 minutes away from seeing the structure collapse.</p>

<p>Battling smoke and the risk of falling debris, they formed a human chain with church officials to evacuate the most precious artifacts and religious treasures, helping preserve most of the cathedral's irreplaceable contents.</p>

<p>Others saw divine intervention in how a copper statue of a rooster that had sat atop the building's incinerated 19th-century spire was found afterwards intact amid the scorched rubble.</p>

<p>Its contents -- three relics, including a small piece of the Crown of Thorns supposedly worn by Jesus before his crucifixion -- also survived, with the battered rooster now on display in a Paris museum.</p>

<p>Inside the cathedral, images the day after the blaze revealed that a giant gold cross on the altar was still standing amid the still smouldering wreckage, a symbol of hope and defiance for many on a dark day for Christians and the country at large.</p>

<p><strong>Contested design contest</strong></p>

<p>French President Emmanuel Macron called the fire "an opportunity to come together" but any sense of national unity after the disaster quickly broke down.</p>

<p>His suggestion that an "element of modern architecture" be included in the rebuild drew immediate criticism from conservatives who demanded that the reconstruction be faithful to the last major update by architect Eugene Viollet-le-Duc in 1844.</p>

<p>The army general put in charge of the rebuild publicly fell out with the lead architect over the redesign, while entries for an architectural competition to select a new spire resulted in lurid headlines.</p>

<p>One suggestion shown by First Lady Brigitte Macron to then-culture minister Roselyne Bachelot resembled a "phallus with its base surrounded with golden balls," Bachelot wrote in a book.</p>

<p>In the end, a replica of the old spire was built.</p>

<p>Six new stained glass windows are set to be installed featuring work by contemporary artists -- a modest nod to modernity and Macron's original vision.</p>

<p><strong>Lead role</strong></p>

<p>Notre Dame's roof and spire were covered by around 400 tonnes of lead, a toxic heavy metal that melted and vaporised with the heat of the fire, with some of it thought to have polluted the surrounding area.</p>

<p>Authorities cleaned nearby schools and advised local residents to wipe surfaces in their homes because of the risk of poisoning.</p>

<p>A health charity joined forces with a union and parents of local schoolchildren to lodge a criminal complaint in 2022 that accused authorities of failing to take every precaution to prevent pollution.</p>

<p>Charges are possible if authorities or contractors are found to have been negligent in protecting the health of residents or workers sent in to decontaminate the site, with an investigating magistrate overseeing a probe.</p>

<p><strong>Cause unknown</strong></p>

<p>The chief Paris prosecutor at the time of the fire, Remy Heitz, said shortly after the inferno that he believed that an accident such as an electrical fault or a cigarette butt was the most likely cause.</p>

<p>Some of the workers renovating the roof at the time of the fire were known to have smoked on site, but investigators have never been able to pinpoint the exact starting point.</p>

<p>Speculation about an arson attack has been investigated during five years of forensic analysis, but no evidence was found.</p>

<p>The current chief Paris prosecutor Laure Beccuau said in April that "the closer we have got to the spot the fire started, and the more results of analyses come back, the more weight is lent to the theory of an accident."</p>

<p><strong>Fee row</strong></p>

<p>Culture Minister Rachida Dati has proposed that visitors to the restored cathedral pay a five-euro ($5.25) entry ticket, with the funds set to be routed to some 4,000 churches in need of repairs around France.</p>

<p>Charging for entry -- entering Notre Dame was previously free -- would bring the tourist attraction into line with St Paul's cathedral in London or Milan's Duomo.</p>

<p>But senior French church leaders have criticised the idea, with a senior bishop saying churches and cathedrals had "always been places open to all" and making money from visitors would be a "betrayal of their original vocation".</p>

<p>The French state owns Notre Dame and has the final say.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/hs69unro_notredame-de-_625x300_05_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Notre-Dame de Paris cathedral illuminated in Paris.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-paul-atkins-the-cryptocurrency-advocate-nominated-by-trump-to-lead-sec-7175886]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[All About Paul Atkins, Donald Trumps Pick For SEC Chairman]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-paul-atkins-the-cryptocurrency-advocate-nominated-by-trump-to-lead-sec-7175886]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Dec 2024 09:52:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Paul Atkins, a cryptocurrency advocate and former SEC commissioner, has been nominated by President-elect Donald Trump to chair the Securities and Exchange Commission.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President-elect Donald Trump has nominated Paul Atkins, a cryptocurrency advocate and former Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) commissioner, as the next chairman of the regulatory body. Trump praised Atkins as a â€œproven leader for common-sense regulations,â€ signalling his administration's focus on reforming financial oversight.</p>

<p><strong>Early life and education</strong></p>

<p>Born in Lillington, North Carolina, Paul Atkins grew up in Tampa, Florida. He graduated in 1980 from Wofford College with a Bachelor of Arts degree, earning membership in Phi Beta Kappa and Kappa Alpha Order. He later received his Juris Doctor from Vanderbilt University School of Law in 1983, where he served as Senior Student Writing Editor of the Vanderbilt Law Review. Atkins is a member of both the New York and Florida bars.</p>

<p><strong>Legal career and early SEC involvement</strong></p>

<p>Atkins began his career at the New York law firm, Davis Polk &amp; Wardwell, specialising in corporate transactions such as securities offerings and mergers and acquisitions for domestic and international clients. During his tenure, he spent over two years in the firm's Paris office, earning a qualification as a French legal advisor in 1988.</p>

<p>In 1990, Atkins joined the SEC, serving as a staff member for successive chairmen Richard C. Breeden and Arthur Levitt. Under Breeden, Atkins played a major role in improving corporate governance, enhancing shareholder communication and lowering barriers for small and medium-sized enterprises to access capital markets. Under Levitt, Atkins organised investor-focused initiatives, including town hall meetings and the SEC's Consumer Affairs Advisory Committee.</p>

<p><strong>SEC Commissioner</strong></p>

<p>Atkins was appointed the SEC commissioner in July 2002 during the George W. Bush administration, a position he held until August 2008. During this time, he worked under Chairmen Harvey Pitt, William H. Donaldson and Christopher Cox. Known for his emphasis on balancing regulatory innovation with investor protection, Atkins participated in major investigations, including one of the largest Ponzi schemes in US history involving the Bennett Funding Group. He played a big role in stabilising the company's remaining subsidiary, leading efforts to rebuild its operations and increasing its stock value for remaining investors.</p>

<p>As a commissioner, Atkins also displayed crisis management skills during financial instability, focusing on recovering losses for investors and ensuring stricter compliance measures.</p>

<p><strong>Advocacy for digital assets and fintech</strong></p>

<p>After leaving the SEC, Atkins founded Patomak Global Partners, a consultancy firm advising major financial clients, including fintech and cryptocurrency companies. A staunch advocate of digital innovation, Atkins has testified before Congress on restructuring the SEC to eliminate redundancies and reduce regulatory burdens on emerging industries.</p>

<p>His expertise in the evolving digital economy has earned him recognition as a leading voice in the fintech sector. He has consistently championed adopting blockchain technology and developing regulatory frameworks that support innovation while protecting investors.</p>

<p>In December 2016, Atkins participated in a business forum organised by President-elect Trump, where he provided strategic advice on economic policy.</p>

<p>He is married and has three sons.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/080kbv68_paul-atkins-_625x300_05_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump praised Paul Atkins as a "proven leader for common-sense regulations".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/earth-aligns-between-sun-and-jupiter-for-spectacular-december-7-event-7175802]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Earth Aligns Between Sun And Jupiter For Spectacular December 7 Event]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/earth-aligns-between-sun-and-jupiter-for-spectacular-december-7-event-7175802]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Dec 2024 09:38:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[On December 7, Earth will align between the Sun and Jupiter, creating a rare astronomical event known as Jupiters opposition.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There will be a major astronomical event on December 7th when Earth will align itself between the Sun and Jupiter. Because of alignment, known as Jupiter's opposition-the gas giant will be visible all night long, providing skywatchers with a rare chance to see the biggest planet in our solar system.</p>

<p>On December 6, Jupiter will be at a distance of 611 million kilometres, or 380 million miles, from Earth at approximately 5 am IST. This proximity guarantees the planet will shine brightest, thus making it the best viewing opportunity for telescope enthusiasts to examine its atmospheric belts and Galilean moons.</p>

<p><strong>How to Spot Jupiter</strong></p>

<p>On the night of <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://science.nasa.gov/solar-system/skywatching/whats-up-december-2024-skywatching-tips-from-nasa/"><em>December 7, </em></a>look east-northeast near the constellation Taurus as Jupiter rises at sunset and sets at sunrise. With a telescope, you can marvel at its intricate cloud bands and spot its four largest moons-Io, Europa, Ganymede, and Callisto.</p>

<p>This celestial alignment, where sunlight reflected from Jupiter takes approximately 34 minutes to reach Earth, promises a dazzling experience for stargazers across India. Be it an astronomy enthusiast or a curious observer, this event reminds us of the wonders of our solar system.</p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/jamiecartereurope/2024/11/08/whats-that-really-bright-star-in-the-sky-after-dark/"><em>Forbes, </em></a>Earth's faster orbit will momentarily put it between the sun and Jupiter. Consequently, we'll be able to see 100% of the disc of Jupiter, which will also be as close as it can ever be to Earth, at 380 million miles (612 million kilometres).</p>

<p>Since we're now just a few days away from Jupiter being in opposition, the planet is now becoming extremely bright. Although opposition is a specific date, a month on either side is the best time to look at the planet using even a small telescope or a pair of binoculars.</p>

<p><strong>What is 'full' Jupiter?</strong></p>

<p>Opposition means a full Jupiter because its sun-facing side is fully illuminated by the sun. Looking away from the sun into the outer solar system at night, we on Earth see Jupiter's sun-facing side. It's much like a full moon; 50% of the moon is always lit by the sun. Only our perspective of it changes, according to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/jamiecartereurope/2024/11/08/whats-that-really-bright-star-in-the-sky-after-dark/"><em>Forbes.&nbsp;</em></a></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/n98mbafg_earth-aligns-between-sun-and-jupiter-_625x300_05_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The gas giant will shine brightly all night, offering stunning views for skywatchers.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-korea-president-yoon-suk-yeol-clings-to-power-after-martial-law-u-turn-7175801]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[South Korea President Yoon Suk Yeol Clings To Power After Martial Law U-Turn]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-korea-president-yoon-suk-yeol-clings-to-power-after-martial-law-u-turn-7175801]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Dec 2024 09:38:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[South Korean President Yoon Suk Yeol was still clinging to power, with his party announcing they would oppose an opposition impeachment motion put forward after his stunning but brief imposition of martial law.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>South Korean President Yoon Suk Yeol was still clinging to power Thursday, with his party announcing they will oppose an opposition impeachment motion put forward after his stunning but brief imposition of martial law.</p>

<p>Yoon suspended civilian rule late Tuesday and deployed troops and helicopters to parliament only for lawmakers to vote down the measure and force him into a U-turn in a night of protests and drama.</p>

<p>Seoul's allies were alarmed -- Washington said it found out via television -- and on Wednesday, the opposition filed an impeachment motion saying Yoon "gravely violated the constitution and the law".</p>

<p>The opposition aims to bring the bill to a vote Saturday, Yonhap reported.</p>

<p>They hold a large majority in the 300-member legislature and need only a handful of defections from Yoon's People Power Party (PPP) to secure the two-thirds majority needed to pass.</p>

<p>But on Thursday, the PPP leader said that while he had asked Yoon to leave the party, he would block the impeachment motion.</p>

<p>Han Dong-hoon told reporters his party was "not trying to defend the president's unconstitutional martial law".</p>

<p>"All 108 lawmakers of the People Power Party will stay united to reject the president's impeachment," the party's floor leader Choo Kyung-ho said.</p>

<p>If the motion passes, Yoon will be suspended pending a verdict by the Constitutional Court. If the judges give the nod, Yoon will be impeached and new elections must happen within 60 days.</p>

<p><strong>Bad memories</strong></p>

<p>Yoon, who has lurched from crisis to crisis since taking office in 2022, has not been seen in public since his televised address in the early hours of Wednesday.</p>

<p>On Thursday, his office said that <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-korean-defence-minister-resigns-amid-row-over-martial-law-7174994">Defence Minister Kim Yong-hyun had resigned</a>, but other key allies including Interior Minister Lee Sang-min remain in office.</p>

<p><strong>READ </strong>|&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-koreas-yoon-names-new-defence-minister-after-botched-martial-law-7174858">Who Is South Korea's New Defence Minister After Botched Martial Law?</a></p>

<p>Yoon's martial law declaration was the first in more than four decades in South Korea and brought back painful memories of the country's turbulent past.</p>

<p>The move was to "safeguard a liberal South Korea from the threats posed by North Korea's communist forces and to eliminate anti-state elements plundering people's freedom and happiness," Yoon said.</p>

<p>A six-point decree from the army chief banned political activities and parties, "false propaganda", strikes and "gatherings that incite social unrest".</p>

<p>Security forces sealed the National Assembly, helicopters landed on the roof and almost 300 soldiers tried to lock down the building, seemingly to prevent lawmakers from entering.</p>

<p>But as parliamentary staffers blocked the soldiers with sofas and fire extinguishers, enough MPs -- some leaping over barriers -- got inside and voted down Yoon's move.</p>

<p>This brought cheers from the hundreds of protesters braving bitter temperatures outside, many waving national flags and chanting for Yoon to be arrested.</p>

<p><strong>'Unforgivable'</strong></p>

<p>Lawmakers formally presented the impeachment motion in the early hours of Thursday, saying Yoon's decision to impose martial law was intended to "evade imminent investigations... into alleged illegal acts involving himself and his family".</p>

<p>"This is an unforgivable crime -- one that cannot, should not, and will not be pardoned," MP Kim Seung-won said.</p>

<p>The main opposition Democratic Party has also filed a complaint of "insurrection" against the president, ministers and top military and police officials -- which can carry a penalty of life imprisonment or even death.</p>

<p>In a show of public anger, thousands of protesters converged around Yoon's office in Seoul late Wednesday after staging a rally in Gwanghwamun Square, demanding his resignation.</p>

<p><strong>'Robust and resilient'</strong></p>

<p>The United States has around 30,000 troops stationed in North Korea to help protect its ally against the nuclear-armed North.</p>

<p>US National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan said Wednesday that Yoon's imposition of martial law "raised deep concern for us" while praising the National Assembly for operating "according to constitutional processes and procedures" to rescind it.</p>

<p>"South Korea's democracy is robust and resilient, and we're going to continue to speak out publicly and engage privately with South Korean counterparts to reinforce the importance of that continuing," Sullivan said.</p>

<p>China, a key ally of nuclear-armed North Korea, urged its citizens to exercise caution, while Russia -- increasingly close to Pyongyang -- called the situation "alarming".</p>

<p>Japan, whose historically prickly relations with Seoul have thawed under Yoon, said it was following the situation with "exceptional and serious concerns".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/2arajccg_south-korea-protest-_625x300_05_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[People are calling for the resignation of South Korea President Yoon Suk Yeol.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-band-sports-team-robbed-at-gunpoint-near-san-francisco-on-us-tour-7175746]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK Band Sports Team Robbed At Gunpoint On US Tour]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-band-sports-team-robbed-at-gunpoint-near-san-francisco-on-us-tour-7175746]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Dec 2024 09:26:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Footage captured from inside the Starbucks shows the suspect brandishing a firearm at the group's tour manager as she approached the van.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The British indie band Sports Team was robbed at gunpoint on Tuesday during the US leg of their tour near San Francisco, the group revealed on Instagram. In a statement, the six-member band said their tour van was ransacked while they stopped for breakfast at a Starbucks in Vallejo, California, around 8:45 a.m. local time. A thief stole stage equipment, laptops, passports, personal items, and other valuables. A passerby reportedly alerted the band to the break-in, and when members attempted to intervene, the suspect pulled out a gun.</p>

<p>"Somebody opened the door and was like: Does anybody have a white Sprinter van? Because you're being robbed right now," drummer Al Greenwood told the <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cy09gkr08lpo" rel="noindex,nofollow">BBC</a></em>.</p>

<p>"I really thought I was about to watch someone get shot because it took a while for our tour manager to realize," she added.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DDIVv3wTzWk/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DDIVv3wTzWk/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DDIVv3wTzWk/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DDIVv3wTzWk/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by Sports Team (@sportsteam)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p></p>

<p>Footage captured from inside the Starbucks shows the suspect brandishing a firearm at the group's tour manager as she approached the van. The suspect is seen removing items from the vehicle while band members and bystanders sought cover inside.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Obviously, if someone pulls a gun, you run for cover," singer Alex Rice told the BBC. "But the thing that struck me about it was the resignation. The people around us weren't very panicked at all. It seemed like a very everyday occurrence."</p>

<p>The group told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://news.sky.com/story/havent-played-a-note-yet-uk-band-sports-team-robbed-at-gunpoint-on-day-one-of-us-tour-13266532" rel="noindex,nofollow"><em>Sky News </em></a>that items including cameras, laptops, in-ear monitors and other personal items were taken. Thankfully, the instruments were safe because, as they explained, "the back of the van is fortified." However, frontman Alex Rice said three band members had their passports stolen.</p>

<p>The band contacted police, but claim officers declined to respond in person, instructing them to file an online report instead.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Despite the incident, Sports Team, known for achieving two top 10 albums in the UK, plans to continue their tour. They played in Sacramento on Tuesday evening and are scheduled to return to the area for another show on Saturday. Prior to this, their east coast performances had gone without incident.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/ec1cau6_sports-team_625x300_05_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A passerby reportedly alerted the band to the break-in]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/after-french-government-collapses-lawmakers-call-on-president-emmanuel-macron-to-go-7175739]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[After French Government Collapses, Lawmakers Call On "Macron To Go"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/after-french-government-collapses-lawmakers-call-on-president-emmanuel-macron-to-go-7175739]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Dec 2024 09:26:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[French President Emmanuel Macron on Thursday will seek ways out of France's political crisis, after Michel Barnier became the first prime minister to be ousted by parliament in over six decades.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>French President Emmanuel Macron on Thursday will seek ways out of France's political crisis, after Michel Barnier became the first prime minister to be ousted by parliament in over six decades.</p>

<p>Lawmakers voted on Wednesday to oust Barnier's government after just three months in office, approving a no-confidence motion proposed by the hard left but which crucially was backed by the far right headed by Marine Le Pen.</p>

<p>Barnier's record-quick ejection comes after snap parliamentary elections this summer, which resulted in a hung parliament with no party having an overall majority and the far right holding the key to the government's survival.</p>

<p>Macron now has the unenviable task of picking a viable successor with over two years of his presidential term left, with some -- though not all -- opponents calling on him to resign.</p>

<p>Barnier is due to present Macron his government's resignation on Thursday morning.</p>

<p>The president will then address the nation at 1900 GMT, the Elysee said.</p>

<p>The no-confidence motion, brought by the hard left in the National Assembly, came amid a standoff over next year's austerity budget, after the prime minister on Monday forced through a social security financing bill without a vote.</p>

<p>With the support of the far right, a majority of 331 MPs in the 577-member chamber voted to oust the government.</p>

<p>It was the first successful no-confidence vote since a defeat for Georges Pompidou's government in 1962, when Charles de Gaulle was president.</p>

<p><strong>'Calling on Macron to go'</strong></p>

<p>Macron flew back into Paris just ahead of the vote after wrapping up a three-day state visit to Saudi Arabia, an apparent world away from the domestic crisis.</p>

<p>He strolled earlier Wednesday through the desert sands of the Al-Ula oasis, marvelling at ancient landmarks. After landing in Paris, he headed directly to the Elysee Palace.</p>

<p>"We are now calling on Macron to go," Mathilde Panot, head of the parliamentary faction of the hard-left France Unbowed (LFI) party, told reporters, urging "early presidential elections" to solve the deepening political crisis.</p>

<p>But taking care not to crow over the government's fall, Le Pen said in a television interview that her party -- once a new premier is appointed -- "would let them work" and help create a "budget that is acceptable for everyone".</p>

<p>Laurent Wauquiez, the head of right-wing deputies in parliament, said the far right and hard left bore the responsibility for a no-confidence vote that will "plunge the country into instability".</p>

<p>Candidates for the post of premier are few, but loyalist Defence Minister Sebastien Lecornu and Macron's centrist ally Francois Bayrou are possible contenders.</p>

<p>On the left, Macron could turn to former Socialist premier and interior minister Bernard Cazeneuve, a contender in September.</p>

<p>Barnier was the fifth prime minister to serve under Macron since he came to power in 2017, with every premier serving a successively shorter period.</p>

<p>Given the turbulence, the new nominee now risks serving an even shorter term than Barnier, whose tenure was the shortest of any administration since the Fifth Republic began in 1958.</p>

<p>Macron is minded to appoint the new premier rapidly, several sources told AFP.</p>

<p>A source close to Macron said the president, who has taken time with appointments in the past, has "no choice" but to name the new premier within 24 hours.</p>

<p><strong>'His failure'</strong></p>

<p>Macron has rejected calls to resign.</p>

<p>With markets nervous and France bracing for public-sector strikes against the threat of cutbacks, action that will shut schools and hit air and rail traffic, there is a growing sense of crisis.</p>

<p>The unions have called for civil servants, including teachers and air-traffic controllers, to strike on Thursday over separate cost-cutting measures.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Macron is due to host a major international event Saturday, with the reopening of the Notre-Dame cathedral after the 2019 fire, with guests including Donald Trump on his first foreign trip since he was elected to be the next US president.</p>

<p>"His failure," was left-wing daily Liberation's front-page headline, with a picture of Macron, whose term runs until 2027.</p>

<p>In an editorial, Le Monde said Le Pen's move risked upsetting her own supporters, such as retirees and business leaders, by toppling the government.</p>

<p>"In the space of a few minutes, she shattered the strategy of normalisation she had consistently pursued," the daily said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/64ru7ouo_emmanuel-macron_625x300_11_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[French President Emmanuel Macron's term will run till 2027.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>