<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Thu, 28 Nov 2024 13:43:58 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trumps-tariff-talk-spurs-global-jitters-countries-may-retaliate-7124419]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump's Tariff Talk Spurs Global Jitters, Countries May "Retaliate"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trumps-tariff-talk-spurs-global-jitters-countries-may-retaliate-7124419]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 28 Nov 2024 13:26:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump's tariff threats have rattled foreign businesses and governments, with many fearing it could signal the opening salvo of an all-out trade war when he returns to the White House next year.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump's tariff threats have rattled foreign businesses and governments, with many fearing it could signal the opening salvo of an all-out trade war when he returns to the White House next year.</p>

<p>The president-elect on Monday placed both allies and rivals on notice, vowing to quickly slap an across-the-board tariff of 25 percent on Canada and Mexico, and add a 10 percent tariff on China.</p>

<p>Following through on that threat -- or his campaign promise of a 10 percent levy on all US imports -- will spark retaliation and have ripple effects across the global economy, analysts say.</p>

<p>"Our assumption is that all these other countries, all these other advanced economies, especially in Asia, they will retaliate in kind," economist Bernard Yaros of Oxford Economics told AFP.</p>

<p>US tariffs and retaliation including from Europe and Asia would "depress growth" and trade flows, he said, estimating a cut to global growth of 0.1 to 0.9 percentage points in 2026.</p>

<p>Even before tariffs take effect, threats weigh on sentiment and could delay investments and hiring, ING economists Ruben Dewitte and Inga Fechner warned in a note.</p>

<p>Trump has long viewed tariffs as a negotiating tool -- or an "all-purpose bludgeon" as a recent Wall Street Journal editorial put it.</p>

<p>On Monday, Trump said that the tariffs on Mexico and Canada would only be removed when illegal immigration and drug trafficking to the United States are stopped.</p>

<p>While seeking to build US leverage, he also risks longer term impacts, with some suggesting he would push countries toward China, Columbia Law School professor Petros Mavroidis said.</p>

<p>"What he definitely does is alienate all his allies," he told AFP.</p>

<p>Erin Murphy, senior fellow at the Center for Strategic and International Studies, said in Trump's threats "there is no differentiation" regarding countries' economic development status or affinity with Washington.</p>

<p><strong>Europe pushback</strong></p>

<p>Europe could be particularly impacted, Dewitte and Fechner said, warning that "a looming new trade war could push the eurozone economy from sluggish growth into recession."</p>

<p>EU tariffs on car imports were a particular target of Trump during his campaign.</p>

<p>But US reliance on the bloc for strategically important products, mainly in the chemical and pharmaceutical sectors, could give the EU some leverage in talks, ING said.</p>

<p>"European countries will be less likely to strike any kind of bargain with Trump than Canada or Mexico," said Peterson Institute for International Economics nonresident senior fellow Gary Hufbauer.</p>

<p>He expects the EU could offer to reduce auto tariffs and buy more US agricultural products like soybeans, but it may not be enough for an administration seeking greater market access or rules exemptions.</p>

<p>Should the US impose tariffs, the EU will probably retaliate on iconic US goods like iPhones or whiskey, he said.</p>

<p>European countries could turn to the World Trade Organization (WTO), though even favorable rulings from the international body may not significantly change US practices.</p>

<p>EU chief Ursula von der Leyen has said she will work towards "constructive cooperation" with US authorities.</p>

<p>Jovita Neliupsiene, the EU ambassador to the United States, meanwhile said the bloc is ready to respond to new trade frictions.</p>

<p><strong>Avoiding escalation</strong></p>

<p>In Asia, economies like Japan and South Korea could be targeted over metals and auto exports, while Vietnam may also draw US scrutiny over solar panels, Yaros said.</p>

<p>The US trade deficit with Vietnam has widened in recent years on a surge in goods imports.</p>

<p>Yaros said that countries targeted by Trump's tariffs, in seeking to avoid escalation, will "retaliate in a way that's commensurate to the action done by the US, but no greater."</p>

<p>China, based on precedent, might eschew equal retaliation for tools like export controls, he added.</p>

<p>Daniel Russel of the Asia Society Policy Institute said both Tokyo and Seoul are very focused on preparing for potential tariffs.</p>

<p>He expects partners like South Korea could seek exemptions from blanket US tariffs, for example, by citing its high-tech investments in America.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/f12g23c8_donald-trump-afp_625x300_27_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Trump has long viewed tariffs as a negotiating tool.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/90-victims-identified-in-new-probe-against-harrods-owner-mohamed-al-fayed-7124281]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[90 Victims Identified In New Probe Against Harrods Owner Mohamed Al-Fayed]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/90-victims-identified-in-new-probe-against-harrods-owner-mohamed-al-fayed-7124281]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 28 Nov 2024 13:07:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Over 400 women and witnesses have alleged sexual misconduct against late Harrods owner Mohamed Al-Fayed, sparking scrutiny of how the London police force handled complaints stretching back decades.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>London's Metropolitan Police confirmed Wednesday that it had opened a new investigation into sexual assault claims against the late Harrods owner Mohamed Al-Fayed, which has so far identified 90 victims.</p>

<p>It comes in the wake of a BBC documentary, aired in September, that detailed several claims of rape and sexual assault against the billionaire Egyptian businessman, who died in August last year aged 94.</p>

<p>More than 400 women and witnesses have since come forward alleging sexual misconduct against him, sparking scrutiny of how the London police force handled complaints stretching back decades.</p>

<p>The Met said "numerous victims, some reporting multiple offences" had come forward following a renewed public appeal. A dedicated unit would "review all reports and pursue all reasonable lines of enquiry", it added.</p>

<p>The force has previously said it had identified 60 potential victims.</p>

<p>Detectives are now probing "a number of individuals associated with" Al-Fayed and "working to establish what roles those individuals may have played in assisting and facilitating" any offences, it added.</p>

<p>Detectives are also reviewing all previous investigations to identify any "missed opportunities", the Met said, noting that investigative techniques and practices had "progressed significantly over the last 20 years".</p>

<p>They have already reviewed more than 50,000 pages of evidence, including victim and impact statements, according to the force.</p>

<p>"This investigation is about giving survivors a voice, despite the fact that Mohamed Al-Fayed is no longer alive to face prosecution," said Commander Stephen Clayman of the Met's Specialist Crime Command.</p>

<p>"However, we are now pursuing any individuals suspected to have been complicit in his offending, and we are committed to seeking justice."</p>

<p>Clayman acknowledged that "past events may have impacted the public's trust and confidence in our approach".</p>

<p>But he said the force was "determined to rebuild that trust by addressing these allegations with integrity and thoroughness".</p>

<p>Earlier this month, the Met referred itself to the UK police watchdog following complaints from two women about its handling of investigations into Al-Fayed's alleged sexual abuse.</p>

<p>Accusations have also emerged in recent weeks against his late brother Salah Fayed -- who died in 2010 -- during the period when he jointly owned Harrods.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, The New York Times this month published the claims of a victim accusing another brother, Ali, aged 80, of knowing about the "trafficking" of women.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/np1pquv_al-fayed-harrods_625x300_31_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Harrods owner Mohamed Al-Fayed is no longer alive to face prosecution.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/woman-in-china-makes-rs-35-lakh-in-3-months-from-flash-marriages-and-divorces-7124223]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Woman In China Makes Rs 35 Lakh In 3 Months From 'Flash' Marriages]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/woman-in-china-makes-rs-35-lakh-in-3-months-from-flash-marriages-and-divorces-7124223]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 28 Nov 2024 13:00:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A matchmaking scam in China has exploited single men through "flash marriages," where women posed as brides and vanished after receiving hefty bride prices.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The online dating and matchmaking industry is expanding rapidly around the world as people spend more time connected to their devices than in social circles. This growing reliance on digital platforms for choosing life partners has led to a surge in fraudulent activities within the industry. China, in particular, is one of the countries most affected by these deceptive practices in the online matchmaking business.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3288086/chinese-woman-makes-us42000-3-months-flash-marriages-and-divorces?module=top_story&amp;pgtype=section"><em>South China Morning Post, </em></a>a group of matchmaking companies in southwestern China has come under police scrutiny for defrauding desperate single men out of significant sums of money, while some women posed as potential brides in the scam. Some of these women earned as much as 300,000 yuan (Rs 35 lakh) within months.</p>

<p>According to a statement from a court in Guiyang, Guizhou province, released in September, a police station in the Huaguoyuan area has received 180 reports of matchmaking fraud since March last year.</p>

<p><strong>What Are 'Flash' Marriages And Divorces?</strong></p>

<p>As per <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3288086/chinese-woman-makes-us42000-3-months-flash-marriages-and-divorces?module=top_story&amp;pgtype=section"><em>SCMP,</em></a> just days after male clients met the women arranged by the agency, they agreed to marry. They were instructed to sign contracts with the agency and pay hundreds of thousands of yuan as a bride price.</p>

<p>These marriages are referred to as "flash weddings" because the brides would often flee, vanish, or pressure the men into divorce through various means, including frequent conflicts after a brief period together.</p>

<p>A person who had already worked as former customer service representative at one of the agencies before the police raid said that there was no shortage of male customers.</p>

<p>"We do not worry about the source of male customers at all. There are many across the country," the worker was quoted as saying. "We can select a male customer for blind dates from 40 to 50 candidates every day."</p>

<p>He noted that following the intensified crackdown by Guiyang authorities, some of these agencies had relocated their operations to nearby Yunnan province.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/cv8nkorg_flash-weddings_625x300_28_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Police have recorded several such cases since March last year.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/man-who-hanged-nazi-war-criminal-adolf-eichmann-dies-7124125]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Man Who Hanged Nazi War Criminal Adolf Eichmann Dies]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/man-who-hanged-nazi-war-criminal-adolf-eichmann-dies-7124125]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 28 Nov 2024 12:46:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The man who hanged Nazi war criminal Adolf Eichmann in 1962, Shalom Nagar, has died, as per reports.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The man who hanged Nazi war criminal Adolf Eichmann in 1962, Shalom Nagar, has died, Israeli media reported on Wednesday.</p>

<p>Adolf Eichmann, one of the main architects of the "Final Solution" aimed at wiping out Europe's Jews, was tried by an Israeli court in April 1961 after being abducted from Argentina.</p>

<p>He was hanged on May 31, 1962 at Ramleh prison near Tel Aviv, the only person ever to be executed in Israel.</p>

<p>Nagar was a prison service employee at the time and chosen to hang Eichmann.</p>

<p>Eichmann, 55 at the time of his trial, had organised the logistics of the Final Solution that sent some six million Jews to their deaths during World War II.</p>

<p>Born in Yemen, Nagar moved to Israel in 1948 and became religious after leaving the prison service.</p>

<p>A documentary film was made about Nagar in 2011.</p>

<p>"For a year, I had nightmares because of him," he said in the film of Eichmann.</p>

<p>He lived in the Kiryat Arba settlement in the occupied West Bank, according to media reports.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/pjmok74g_death-generic_625x300_12_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-chinmoy-krishna-das-brahmachari-the-iskcon-priest-under-arrest-in-bangladesh-7123388]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Who Is Chinmoy Krishna Das Brahmachari, Hindu Leader Arrested In Bangladesh]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-chinmoy-krishna-das-brahmachari-the-iskcon-priest-under-arrest-in-bangladesh-7123388]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 28 Nov 2024 12:24:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Chinmoy Krishna Das Brahmachari, an ISKCON priest and spokesperson for the Bangladesh Sammilita Sanatani Jagran Jote, was arrested on November 25, 2024, by the Dhaka Metropolitan Police's detective branch.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Chinmoy Krishna Das Brahmachari, an ISKCON priest and spokesperson for the Bangladesh Sammilita Sanatani Jagran Jote, was arrested on November 25 by the Dhaka Metropolitan Police's detective branch. The Hindu monk and spiritual leader was arrested on a sedition charge, which stems from his actions at a rally held in Chittagong in October. Accused of disrespecting the Bangladesh flag, the case was lodged under the country's 1860 Penal Code.</p>

<ol>
	<li>&nbsp;Chinmoy Krishna Das Brahmachari, known within the International Society for Krishna Consciousness (ISKCON) community as Sri Chinmay Krishna Prabhu, is an influential religious leader in Bangladesh. As President of Pundarik Dham, an ISKCON centre in Bangladesh, he has long been a voice for those seeking religious freedom and minority protection. He previously held the position of divisional organising secretary for ISKCON in Chattogram.</li>
	<li>He was born in May 1985 in Karianagar village, located in the Satkania Upazila of Chattogram. Chinmoy Krishna Das Brahmachari gained recognition for his skills as a child orator within religious circles. His spiritual journey began at a young age, and by 1997, at just 12 years old, he took diksha (initiation) and joined ISKCON as a brahmachari.</li>
	<li>Brahmachari's arrest came after a high-profile rally in Chittagong on October 25, 2024. The precise motive behind the charges against Brahmachari remains unclear, but reports indicate that he faces accusations of disrespecting the Bangladeshi flag during a protest rally. Das, along with 18 others, has been charged with sedition. Just days before his arrest, on November 22, he spoke at a rally in Rangpur, denouncing the acts of violence on the Hindu community. On November 26, a Bangladesh court denied Das's bail petition and ordered his detention.</li>
	<li>A few months ago, Brahmachari was relatively unknown. His rise to prominence began when violence erupted against the Hindu community in Bangladesh and their temples following the fall of the Sheikh Hasina regime in August. This turmoil brought the 39-year-old monk into the public eye as he emerged as a key figure advocating for the rights and safety of Hindus in the country. In just a few months, Chinmoy Krishna Das Brahmachari has become one of the most prominent leaders of the Hindu community in Bangladesh.</li>
	<li>In response to Brahmachari's arrest, the Ministry of External Affairs (MEA) of India expressed “deep concern” over the court's decision to deny him bail. An MEA statement emphasised that the arrest occurred against the backdrop of widespread violence against Hindus and other minority communities in Bangladesh. The MEA pointed out that these attacks, including arson, looting of minority-owned properties, theft, vandalism, and desecration of temples and deities, have continued unchecked. It was noted that despite these attacks, religious leaders like Chinmoy Krishna Das Brahmachari, who advocate for peaceful change, are facing charges, while the perpetrators of violence remain unpunished.</li>
</ol>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ninval3k_isckon-priest-hindu-priest-chinmoy-krishna-das_625x300_26_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Chinmoy Krishna Das Brahmachari gained recognition for his skills as a child orator.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-says-ukraine-needs-more-troops-not-only-weapons-to-win-war-7123967]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Says Ukraine Needs More Troops, Not Only Weapons, to Win War]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-says-ukraine-needs-more-troops-not-only-weapons-to-win-war-7123967]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 28 Nov 2024 12:20:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The White House said Ukraine must recruit more soldiers for the war against Russia, including by lowering the draft age, as a lack of manpower rather than weapons is the country's most pressing need.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The White House said Ukraine must recruit more soldiers for the war against Russia, including by lowering the draft age, as a lack of manpower rather than weapons is the country's most pressing need.</p>

<p>President Volodymyr Zelenskiy's government should consider lowering the recruitment age to 18 from 25 to create a much-needed pipeline of new troops to rotate into the front lines, a senior administration official told reporters Wednesday.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The message is the clearest signal yet of impatience from the US and its allies over Zelenskiy's reluctance to recruit younger soldiers. The Ukrainian leader has said that there's no need to lower the draft age, an idea which had been pushed by allies in response to his request for security and economic guarantees he deemed the country's "victory plan."</p>

<p>Zelenskiy's office didn't respond to a request for comment sent outside normal business hours in Kyiv.</p>

<p>With less than two months in office, the Biden administration has also sought to strengthen Ukraine's military capabilities before President-elect Donald Trump takes over.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Trump has pledged to wind down the war quickly, and even Zelenskiy has said the conflict needs to end next year. It's still unclear, however, how that will play out as Russian President Vladimir Putin's forces steadily push further into Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The official said discussions have begun with the incoming Trump team but couldn't comment on what the new administration is planning.&nbsp;</p>

<p>White House spokesman John Kirby, in a statement on Wednesday, offered reassurances that the Biden administration's commitment remained intact. "We're absolutely going to keep sending Ukraine weapons and equipment. We know that's vital," he said. "But so, too, is manpower at this point. In fact, we believe manpower is the most vital need they have. So, we're also ready to ramp up our training capacity if they take appropriate steps." &nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p>Earlier: Trump Picks Keith Kellogg as Envoy for Ukraine and Russia</p>

<p>The Biden official said the administration in its final days intends to provide thousands of artillery rounds and rockets, as well as hundreds of missile interceptors, vehicles and other weapons systems using funds already appropriated by Congress.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Ukraine has maintained that it still requires weapons and equipment for its current soldiers. Zelenskiy said in a Nov. 19 speech that the defense ministry must create incentives for citizens under 25 to join the war effort, but repeated there are no plans to change the draft age.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Let there be no speculation," he said, "our state is not preparing to lower the mobilization age."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ran0o038_ukraine_625x300_26_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Ukraine has maintained that it still requires weapons and equipment for its current soldiers.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/travelling-to-greenland-gets-easier-with-new-international-airport-in-nuuk-7123342]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Greenland Gets International Airport In Capital: All You Need To Know]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/travelling-to-greenland-gets-easier-with-new-international-airport-in-nuuk-7123342]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 28 Nov 2024 12:18:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Nuuk, the capital city of Greenland, has a new international airport. Equipped with a 2,200-meter (7,217-ft) runway, the airport will allow larger planes to land in the region, connecting it with the rest of the world, CNN reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Nuuk, the capital city of Greenland, has a new international airport. Equipped with a 2,200-meter (7,217-ft) runway, the airport will allow larger planes to land in the region, connecting it with the rest of the world, <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/11/27/travel/greenland-nuuk-international-airport-new/index.html">CNN</a> reported.</p>

<p>On average, 130,000 visitors come to Greenland every year on cruise ships or planes. The number is expected to increase with the country's tourism sector opening up. But officials hope it doesn't become too unwieldy.</p>

<p>Greenland's tourism sector and economy are expected to grow with the inauguration of the new airport.</p>

<p>Jens Lauridsen, chief executive of Greenland Airports, estimated that each flight will add $200,000 to the nation's economy. Those arriving in Greenland should know they are not in for a standard tourism experience, he said.</p>

<p>“We're located in the Arctic,” Lauridsen said, adding that visitors will be in for an "adventure".</p>

<p>Starting in June, United Airlines will offer nonstop seasonal flights to the region from major cities such as &nbsp;Newark and New Jersey, and the journey will take a little over four hours only.</p>

<p>Before the new airport, people who wished to travel to Greenland by air had to fly into smaller cities like Kangerlussuaq to the north or Narsarsuaq.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The US military bases, built there during the Second World War, are capable of accommodating larger planes.</p>

<p>The new airport will now serve as the base for Air Greenland, which will operate Airbus A330neo planes to Copenhagen, Denmark. This will allow the airline to handle 800 passengers an hour. There will also be flights linking Nuuk to Reykjavik, Iceland.</p>

<p>By 2026 end, two more airports are scheduled to be inaugurated in Greenland. These will connect Ilulissat in the north and Qaqortoq in the south.&nbsp;</p>

<p>With only around 56 miles (90 kilometres) of paved roads, locals and tourists in Greenland will still be required to fly or take boats to reach their desired destinations, while these airports will significantly open up travel.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/7sai8o2_greenland-airport-_625x300_28_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[On average, 130,000 visitors come to Greenland every year.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/somebody-spell-their-name-wrong-2-biggest-resume-red-flags-from-a-recruiter-7123681]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Somebody Spell Their Name Wrong": 2 Resume Red Flags, From A Recruiter]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/somebody-spell-their-name-wrong-2-biggest-resume-red-flags-from-a-recruiter-7123681]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 28 Nov 2024 11:37:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ms Levine emphasizes the importance of a well-presented resume, free of typos and inaccuracies.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Emily Levine, a seasoned executive at Career Group Companies, has interviewed countless candidates over her 15-year career. Her clientele includes high-profile individuals who rely on her to find top-tier staff. Ms Levine emphasizes the importance of a well-presented resume, free of typos and inaccuracies. She warns that even minor errors can significantly impact a candidate's chances, as they reflect a lack of attention to detail.</p>

<p>"I definitely have interviewed thousands and thousands of people throughout my 15-year career," she says. She shared that each interview process starts with a resume, and she needs to be convinced why she should move forward with that candidate.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"If the resume is not presentable," she says, that can prevent her from passing it along. Here are two of her biggest red flags.</p>

<p>Typos raise eyebrows. "I've seen somebody spell their name wrong," says Levine. "I've seen somebody spell the name of their university incorrectly, or the company that they worked for." Ms Levine says the typos show a lack of attention to detail that reflects poorly on the candidate.</p>

<p>She shared that a single spelling error on a resume can be ignored, but more than that "doesn't look good," adding "it would discourage a company from meeting with a candidate."</p>

<p>Ms Levine revealed that she sometimes helps candidates and gives her feedback on the typos. She recommends every job-seeker "go back and double check all the information to make sure it's accurate" before submitting anything. &nbsp;</p>

<p>Second, a resume needs to be accurate.</p>

<p>"Don't try to fudge the dates [to] make a gap seem shorter" between jobs, says Ms Levine.</p>

<p>Don't lie on your resume. Citing an example, Ms Levine shared don't say you have a degree if you left school a few credits shy of graduating, or if you never attended at all. Some people are "embarrassed to say they don't have" a degree, she says, so they lie and say they do.</p>

<p>She emphasised that the truth will come out in a background check, she says, and it'll make it very hard for that prospective employer to trust you going forward.</p>

<p>"I've seen countless offers being pulled from candidates" who lie, she says.</p>

<p><br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-01/j67moja8_job-interview-generic_625x300_10_January_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A resume needs to be accurate, the recruiter said.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/what-is-swatting-donald-trumps-cabinet-nominees-targeted-with-dangerous-hoaxes-7123632]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What Is 'Swatting'? Donald Trump's Cabinet Nominees Targeted With Threats]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/what-is-swatting-donald-trumps-cabinet-nominees-targeted-with-dangerous-hoaxes-7123632]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 28 Nov 2024 11:29:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[People who carry out a swatting prank call aim to fool emergency services into sending a Special Weapons and Tactics (SWAT) team to respond to the supposed emergency.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Several of President-elect Donald Trump's cabinet and administration nominees were targeted this week with actions including bomb threats and "swatting," a spokesperson for the transition team said on Wednesday.</p>

<p>The threats were made Tuesday night and Wednesday morning, and law enforcement acted quickly to ensure the safety of those targeted, spokesperson Karoline Leavitt said in a statement. While bomb threats are a common occurrence, "swatting" is a less known phenomenon.</p>

<p>An FBI spokesperson said the bureau is aware of numerous bomb threats and swatting incidents targeting incoming administration nominees and appointees and is working with its law enforcement partners.</p>

<p><strong>What is Swatting?</strong></p>

<p>Swatting is the filing of false reports to police to induce a potentially heavy, armed response by officers at someone's home. Law enforcement experts see it as a form of intimidation or harassment that is increasingly being used to target prominent figures.</p>

<p>This is often creating a situation where a Special Weapons and Tactics (SWAT) team arrives ready for a possible violent encounter.</p>

<p>"The individuals who engage in this activity use technology to make it appear that the emergency call is coming from the victim's phone," said one FBI public announcement in 2013, titled, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.fbi.gov/news/stories/the-crime-of-swatting-fake-9-1-1-calls-have-real-consequences1"><em>"The Crime of 'Swatting': Fake 9-1-1 Calls Have Real Consequences - FBI.</em></a></p>

<p>"Sometimes swatting is done for revenge, sometimes as a prank. Either way, it is a serious crime, and one that has potentially dangerous consequences."</p>

<p>Most who engage in swatting are serial offenders also involved in other cyber crimes such as identity theft and credit card fraud, Kolbye said. They either want to brag about their swatting exploits or exact revenge on someone who angered them online.</p>

<p>Kevin Kolbye, an assistant special agent in charge in our Dallas Division suggests making a police report about any swatting threats you receive online. Such threats typically come from the online gaming community, where competitors can play and interact anonymously. With a report on file, if a 9-1-1 incident does occur at your home, the police will be aware that it could be a hoax.</p>

<p>"The FBI takes swatting very seriously," Kolbye said. "Working closely with industry and law enforcement partners, we continue to refine our technological capabilities and our investigative techniques to stop the thoughtless individuals who commit these crimes. The bottom line," he added, "is that swatting puts innocent people at risk."<br />
<br />
<em>(With inputs from Reuters)</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/0t12b96_swat_625x300_28_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Swatters will falsely report major events like bomb threats, hostage situations.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/rare-first-edition-harry-potter-book-auctioned-for-36k-pounds-7123207]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Rare First Edition Harry Potter Book Auctioned For 36,000 Pounds]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/rare-first-edition-harry-potter-book-auctioned-for-36k-pounds-7123207]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 28 Nov 2024 11:22:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Nearly 30 years after being bought for just 10 pounds, a rare first edition of Harry Potter and the Philosopher's Stone sold for 36,000 pounds at an auction on Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Nearly 30 years after being bought for just 10 pounds, a rare first edition of Harry Potter and the Philosopher's Stone sold for 36,000 pounds at an auction on Wednesday. Unaware of the book's future worth, Christine McCulloch bought the copy for her son Adam in 1997 from a Stratford-upon-Avon bookstore. Now, the memorabilia has been sold for a fortune at an auction held at Lichfield, Staffordshire. The bidder paid £45,000, including a buyer's premium, reported <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cx273wnvw9go" rel="nofollow noindex" target="_blank">BBC</a>.</p>

<p>According to Hansons Auctioneers, the book is one of 500 hardback copies printed during the first-ever print run in 1997. It was estimated to be worth between 30,000 pounds and 50,000 pounds.</p>

<p>Adam McCulloch, from Tansley, Derbyshire, said the copy had been stashed in a cupboard beneath the stairs of his family's old Chesterfield home. The family only became aware of its possible worth during the 2020 lockdown after reading about the sales of first editions.</p>

<p>"Once we got it verified it was a bit of a pinch yourself moment," he said.</p>

<p>Talking about her 1997 purchase, Christine McCulloch said, “We went in [the bookshop], bought it for 10 pounds. Adam really loved the book and it started this sort of fascination, as with so many children all over the world now.”</p>

<p>Adam believed it was the right time to sell the book so others could appreciate it.</p>

<p>"In some ways, I think having that bit of a story around it, some tea stains there and a folded over corner here where someone's enjoyed reading it - I think that adds to the magic," he said.</p>

<p>The Harry Potter book series, written by British author JK Rowling, consists of seven books written over 10 years. The series chronicles the lives of a young wizard, Harry Potter, and his friends, Hermione Granger and Ron Weasley, who study at Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/i9lvrq6g_harry-potter-book-auctioned_625x300_28_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The man believed it was the right time to sell the book so others could appreciate it.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/does-uniqlo-use-cotton-from-chinas-xinjiang-what-top-boss-said-7123137]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Does Uniqlo Use Cotton From China's Xinjiang. What Top Boss Said]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/does-uniqlo-use-cotton-from-chinas-xinjiang-what-top-boss-said-7123137]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 28 Nov 2024 11:13:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Uniqlo doesn't use cotton from China's Xinjiang region to make its products, Tadashi Yanai, the chief executive of Fast Retailing, the company behind the global fashion chain, has said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Uniqlo doesn't use cotton from China's Xinjiang region to make its products, Tadashi Yanai, the chief executive of Fast Retailing, the company behind the global fashion chain, has said. "We're not using (cotton from Xinjiang)," Yanai said in Tokyo. "By mentioning which cotton we're using..." he continued but paused and concluded, "Actually, it gets too political if I say anymore so let's stop here".</p>

<p>Although cotton from Xinjiang is considered among the best fabrics around the world, it fell out of favour after it came to light that the Muslim Uyghur minority was pushed into forced labour to produce it, <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c79zqdl7j2go">BBC</a> reported.</p>

<p>China stands as a crucial market for Uniqlo from both customers' points of view and as a major manufacturing hub.</p>

<p>Earlier, tough regulations from the US came into effect on the import of goods from China's Xinjiang region.</p>

<p>In recent times, several global companies have removed products made using cotton from Xinjiang from their shelves. This ultimately led to a fierce backlash in China where big names such as Nike, Adidas, H&amp;M, Nike, Burberry and Esprit were boycotted.</p>

<p>H&amp;M witnessed its clothes removed from major e-commerce stores in China.</p>

<p>Addressing the issue then, Yanai, who is the richest man in Japan, refused to deny or confirm whether Uniqlo was using cotton from Xinjiang. He simply said he wanted to be "neutral between the US and China".</p>

<p>As a result, his decision helped the Japanese brand to remain quite popular in the retail market of China.</p>

<p>While Uniqlo expands its business in Europe and the US, Yanai said, "We are not a known brand globally," adding that Asia remains its biggest market.</p>

<p>As far as the company's presence in China is concerned, it has more stores in the country than Japan, its home country. And Yanai said he was not planning to change that strategy despite the challenges in the second-biggest economy in the world.</p>

<p>He said that while there are 1.4 billion people in China, they only have 900 to 1,000 stores there. "I think we can increase that to 3,000," he added.</p>

<p>Apart from China, the company also makes clothes in India, Bangladesh, Vietnam and Indonesia.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2016-07/uniqlo_650x400_81467657816.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Apart from China, Uniqlo also makes clothes in India, Bangladesh, Vietnam and Indonesia.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/endangered-australian-cockatoo-among-worlds-longest-living-birds-7123425]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Endangered Australian Cockatoo Among World's Longest-Living Birds]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/endangered-australian-cockatoo-among-worlds-longest-living-birds-7123425]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 28 Nov 2024 11:06:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An endangered type of cockatoo found only in southwest Australia is among the longest-living bird species in the world, according to a new research.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An endangered type of cockatoo found only in southwest Australia is among the longest-living bird species in the world, according to a new research.</p>

<p>The research, published in the Pacific Conservation Biology on Thursday, found that Carnaby's cockatoos can live for up to 35 years in the wild, Xinhua news agency reported.</p>

<p>The Carnaby's cockatoo is a large black cockatoo endemic to the southwest of Australia's state of Western Australia (WA). It has been officially recognised as an endangered species since 1999.</p>

<p>The research team from the WA Department of Biodiversity, Conservation and Attractions looked at eight live wild birds, five females and three males, and found their ages ranged from 21 to 35 years.</p>

<p>It puts the species in the top 2 per cent of all wild birds globally in terms of longevity.</p>

<p>The oldest bird, a male, was photographed by the researchers in 2021 and identified by a leg band it was fitted in November 1986.</p>

<p>"This sighting was the first time the cockatoo had been observed since the breeding season in 1986 when it fledged from a nest hollow 5.7 kilometres from where it was photographed," the study said.</p>

<p>"Its estimated hatching date was September 24, 1986, and it was 35 years old when photographed. This is the oldest living Carnaby's cockatoo recorded in the wild."</p>

<p>All eight of the studied birds were still breeding at the time when they were photographed by the researchers.</p>

<p>The 35-year-old had strayed the furthest from its natal site, with the remaining seven all remaining within 2.5 kilometres.</p>

<p>The researchers said that the findings show that conservation efforts for the species should focus on older adults as well as juveniles.</p>

<p>They said it is important for the species' sustainable survival that adults live out their long lifespans and continue breeding.</p>

<p>Carnaby's cockatoos have a low rate of reproduction, with females typically laying only two eggs every year and fledging one hatchling. Juveniles also have low survival rates in the wild -- all characteristics the researchers said are shared by fellow long-living birds such as albatrosses and petrels.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/elco3gqg_australian-black-cockatoo_625x300_28_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Cockatoo has been officially recognised as an endangered species since 1999.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sunita-williams-to-celebrate-thanksgiving-in-space-with-smoked-turkey-mashed-potato-7123264]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Sunita Williams To Celebrate Thanksgiving In Space With This Special Meal]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sunita-williams-to-celebrate-thanksgiving-in-space-with-smoked-turkey-mashed-potato-7123264]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 28 Nov 2024 10:48:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Indian-origin NASA astronaut Sunita Williams is set to celebrate Thanksgiving in space with smoked turkey, mashed potato'.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Indian-origin NASA astronaut Sunita Williams is set to celebrate Thanksgiving in space with ‘smoked turkey, mashed potato'.</p>

<p>Thanksgiving is observed every year in the US on the fourth Thursday of November to honour the blessings and harvest of the year.</p>

<p>“Our Crew up here just wanted to say Happy Thanksgiving to all our friends and family who are down on Earth and everyone who is supporting us,” Williams said in a video message, shared by NASA on Wednesday.</p>

<p>The astronauts shared that NASA has provided them with food items like butternut squash, apples, sardines, and smoked turkey for the occasion.</p>

<p>In a recent interview with NBC News, Williams shared her plans of celebrating the day, along with other astronauts -- Butch Wilmore, Nick Hague and Aleksandr Gorbunov -- aboard the International Space Station (ISS).</p>

<p>The plans include watching the Macy's Thanksgiving Day Parade and a lavish feast with “some smoked turkey, some cranberry, apple cobbler, green beans and mushrooms and mashed potatoes.”</p>

<p>In June Williams and Butch Willmore became the first to ride the much-delayed Starliner, developed by Boeing.</p>

<p>What began as an eight-day sojourn on the International Space Station (ISS) has now extended to eight months in space for Williams and Willmore as the faulty Starliner was declared unfit for human travel by NASA.</p>

<p>While Starliner is back on Earth unharmed, Williams is expected to return to Earth onboard a SpaceX Dragon capsule in February 2025.</p>

<p>Amid concerns for their prolonged stay in space, NASA recently said that both Williams and Willmore “are safe aboard the space station”. Williams also said that she is “feeling good, working out, and eating right,” amid claims of her weight loss in space.</p>

<p>The Indian-Origin astronaut also celebrated Diwali "from 260 miles above the earth on the ISS".</p>

<p>According to NASA, "Sunita has spent a cumulative total of 322 days in space”, and she is the second woman astronaut with the highest number of spacewalks.</p>

<p>--IANS</p>

<p>rvt/</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/217p6adg_sunita-williams-diwali_625x300_29_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sunita Williams shared her plans of celebrating the day.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/after-years-of-strained-ties-mark-zuckerberg-dines-with-donald-trump-at-mar-a-lago-7123376]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[After Years Of Strained Ties, Mark Zuckerberg Dines With Trump At Mar-a-Lago]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/after-years-of-strained-ties-mark-zuckerberg-dines-with-donald-trump-at-mar-a-lago-7123376]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 28 Nov 2024 10:43:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Mark Zuckerberg joined Donald Trump for dinner at his Mar-a-Lago estate Wednesday, with an advisor to the president-elect saying the tech billionaire "wants to support the national renewal of America."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Mark Zuckerberg joined Donald Trump for dinner at his Mar-a-Lago estate Wednesday, with an advisor to the president-elect saying the tech billionaire "wants to support the national renewal of America."</p>

<p>The 40-year-old chief executive of Meta -- which owns Facebook, Instagram and Whatsapp -- has been carefully trying to mend ties with Trump.</p>

<p>Both men have had a strained relationship over the years, with Facebook being among social media networks that banned Trump after the attack on the US Capitol on January 6, 2021.</p>

<p>But on Wednesday, a Meta spokesperson said: "Mark was grateful for the invitation to join President Trump for dinner and the opportunity to meet with members of his team about the incoming Administration."</p>

<p>In a statement, the spokesperson added that it was an important time for the future of American innovation.</p>

<p>It was not immediately clear if billionaire Elon Musk, a close Trump ally who previously challenged Zuckerberg to a cage match fight, also attended the dinner, though he has frequently been present at Mar-a-Lago since the election.</p>

<p>Stephen Miller, Trump's incoming deputy chief of staff for policy, told Fox News on Wednesday that Zuckerberg "has been very clear about his desire to be a supporter of, and a participant in, this change that we're seeing all around America."</p>

<p>"He's made clear that he wants to support the national renewal of America under President Trump's leadership," Miller said in a televised interview.</p>

<p>While treading cautiously in Trump's first term, tech titans were quick to laud the Republican's election victory this time -- with Zuckerberg among those who offered his congratulations.</p>

<p>Before the election, Zuckerberg stopped election-related philanthropy and Meta modified its algorithms to reduce political content.</p>

<p>Zuckerberg had previously contributed large sums to fund nonprofits working to support US electoral infrastructure during the Covid pandemic.</p>

<p>The donations had been seized upon by Trump after his 2020 loss to Joe Biden, falsely alleging that they were part of a plot to swing the election.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/vro3dflo_mark-zuckerberg-donald-trump-afp_625x300_28_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mark Zuckerberg met Donald Trump for dinner at his Mar-a-Lago estate.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/microsoft-faces-broad-antitrust-investigation-from-us-federal-trade-commission-7123322]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Microsoft Faces Broad Antitrust Investigation From US Federal Trade Commission]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/microsoft-faces-broad-antitrust-investigation-from-us-federal-trade-commission-7123322]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 28 Nov 2024 10:33:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The US Federal Trade Commission has opened an antitrust investigation of Microsoft Corporation, drilling into everything from the company's cloud computing and software licensing businesses to cybersecurity offerings and AI products.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The US Federal Trade Commission has opened an antitrust investigation of Microsoft Corp., drilling into everything from the company's cloud computing and software licensing businesses to cybersecurity offerings and artificial intelligence products.&nbsp;</p>

<p>After more than a year of conducting informal interviews with competitors and business partners, antitrust enforcers have crafted a detailed request to force Microsoft to turn over information, according to people familiar with the matter. The demand, which is hundreds of pages long, has been sent to the company after FTC Chair Lina Khan signed off, said one of the people.</p>

<p>FTC antitrust lawyers are set to meet with Microsoft competitors next week to gather more information about the Redmond, Washington-based company's business practices, according to two other people familiar with the plans who like the others asked not to be named discussing a confidential matter.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Microsoft and the FTC declined to comment.</p>

<p>The FTC's scrutiny of Microsoft's cloud computing business gained steam after a string of cybersecurity incidents that involved the company's products. The company is a top government contractor, providing billions of dollars in software and cloud services to US agencies including the Defense Department.</p>

<p>The Microsoft information demand is one of Khan's parting shots as she steps down after helming one of the most aggressive pushes against consolidated corporate power the agency has delivered in decades. While business leaders are hoping that President-elect Donald Trump will usher in an era of lighter regulation, it will fall to his new FTC chair — still unnamed — to decide how to proceed with the case.</p>

<p>The FTC inquiry renews scrutiny of Microsoft for its business practices more than 25 years after the government sued the company over similar conduct involving bundling its Windows operating system and browser and unsuccessfully tried to break it up.</p>

<p>A key focus of the current probe is Microsoft's bundling of both its popular office productivity and security software with its cloud offerings, according to the people familiar with the information request. &nbsp;</p>

<p>Microsoft's cybersecurity failings, combined with its heft as a government contractor, are seen by the FTC as an example of the company's problematic power over the market, those people said.</p>

<p>In a November 2023 report, the FTC highlighted concerns that the concentrated nature of the cloud market means that “outages, or other issues that degrade the service of a cloud provider, could have a cascading impact on the economy or specific sectors.”</p>

<p>The CrowdStrike crash that affected millions of devices operating on Microsoft Windows systems earlier this year was itself a testament to the widespread use of the company's products and how it directly affects the global economy.</p>

<p>A portion of the probe is focused on the company's practices related to security software called Microsoft Entra ID — formerly known as Azure Active Directory — which helps authenticate users logging in to cloud-based software, some of the people said.</p>

<p>Competitors have complained that Microsoft's licensing terms and bundling of software with cloud services makes it harder for rival authentication and cybersecurity companies to compete.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Companies such as Salesforce Inc.'s Slack and Zoom Communications Inc. have said that Microsoft's practice of giving away its Teams video-conferencing software for free in a bundle with popular software products like Word and Excel is anticompetitive and makes it harder for them to compete.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/fungsvmg_microsoft-outage_625x300_19_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[FTC antitrust lawyers are set to meet with Microsoft competitors next week to gather more information.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/1-000-arrests-a-jailed-former-pm-pakistans-political-turmoil-explained-7123258]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[1,000 Arrests, A Jailed Former PM: Pakistan's Political Turmoil Explained]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/1-000-arrests-a-jailed-former-pm-pakistans-political-turmoil-explained-7123258]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 28 Nov 2024 10:22:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The standoff between the Pakistani government and the supporters of former Prime Minister Imran Khan has reached a boiling point. With deadly clashes, sweeping arrests, and widespread discontent, Pakistan once again faces political turmoil.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The standoff between the Pakistani government and the supporters of former Prime Minister Imran Khan has reached a boiling point. With deadly clashes, sweeping arrests, and widespread discontent, Pakistan once again faces political turmoil.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Imran Khan, the former cricket star turned politician, has been in jail since August 2023 on corruption charges. His detention followed a turbulent year in which his government was ousted via a parliamentary no-confidence vote in 2022.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Since then, Mr Khan has faced over 150 legal cases ranging from corruption to sedition. His popularity, however, remains undiminished among his supporters, who view him as a victim of political vendettas by the ruling coalition led by Prime Minister Shehbaz Sharif.&nbsp;</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/70clg28g_imran-khan-pakistan-protests-afp-_625x300_28_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: AFP </span></p>
</div>

<p>On Sunday, Imran Khan's party, Pakistan Tehreek-e-Insaf (PTI), launched a march toward Islamabad, demanding the release of its jailed leader. Thousands of PTI supporters, led by Mr Khan's wife, Bushra Bibi, and other senior party leaders, descended upon the capital.</p>

<p>Mr Khan was arrested in May 2023 arrest over allegations that he and Bushra Bibi, accepted land as a bribe through a trust. Mr Khan also faces anti-terrorism charges tied to clashes that followed his arrest. Other allegations include unlawfully disclosing state secrets in 2022, for which he was acquitted, and an unlawful marriage in 2018, also resulting in acquittal.</p>

<p>In August 2023, Mr Khan was arrested for allegedly selling state gifts, a case in which Bushra Bibi, now leading protests, was also implicated but granted bail in October. Though Mr Khan secured bail in November, he remains imprisoned on other charges.</p>

<h3><strong>Rally Turns Violent</strong></h3>

<p>What began as a support rally for Mr Khan quickly turned violent. By Tuesday night, the situation had escalated into full-scale clashes between protesters and law enforcement. Pakistani security forces, equipped with riot gear and backed by paramilitary personnel, deployed tear gas and barricades to contain the crowds. Protesters broke through multiple security checkpoints, reaching the edge of Islamabad's highly secured red zone, home to key government buildings and embassies.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/vnb0qn4_imran-khan-pakistan-protests-afp-_625x300_28_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: AFP</span></p>
</div>

<p>Amid a blackout in central Islamabad, the Pakistani government launched an operation involving tear gas and mass detentions. The crackdown resulted in over 1,000 arrests, including many senior PTI leaders. At least four paramilitary personnel and six protesters were killed in the clashes, and dozens more were injured, according to news agency Reuters who cited local news reports. &nbsp;</p>

<p>In the aftermath of the raid, PTI announced a temporary suspension of its protest. Citing "state brutality," the party stated that it would regroup and strategise for future action.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Bushra Bibi and Ali Amin Gandapur, a senior PTI leader and chief minister of Khyber Pakhtunkhwa province, retreated to the party's northern stronghold. Mr Gandapur later assured supporters that the protests were not over.</p>

<h3><strong>Party Under Siege</strong></h3>

<p>The PTI described the midnight crackdown as a "massacre" orchestrated by a "fascist military regime." Party officials alleged that live ammunition was used against demonstrators, accusations vehemently denied by the government. Videos circulated on social media allegedly showed excessive use of force by law enforcement.</p>

<p>PTI also claimed that its workers were killed in the operation, with reports suggesting as many as 40 deaths. However, these numbers remain unverified, and government officials have dismissed the allegations as "propaganda."</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/di1k0s98_imran-khan-pakistan-protests-afp-_625x300_28_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: AFP</span></p>
</div>

<p>According to Islamabad Police, 954 protesters were detained between Sunday and Tuesday, with more than 600 arrests occurring on Tuesday alone. Law enforcement defended its actions, arguing that the protests had devolved into "terrorism" after security personnel were targeted and public property was damaged.</p>

<h3><strong>Government's Response</strong></h3>

<p>Prime Minister Shehbaz Sharif's coalition government has deployed massive security forces, shut down mobile internet services, and banned public gatherings in Islamabad.</p>

<p>Interior Minister Mohsin Naqvi dismissed PTI's allegations of excessive force, accusing the party of spreading misinformation to justify its actions.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/egujcvdo_imran-khan-pakistan-protests-afp-_625x300_28_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The crackdown resulted in over 1,000 arrests, including many senior PTI leaders.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fact-check-white-mass-falling-on-ground-is-not-a-natural-cloud-7123134]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Fact Check: White Mass Falling On Ground Is Not A Natural Cloud]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fact-check-white-mass-falling-on-ground-is-not-a-natural-cloud-7123134]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 28 Nov 2024 10:03:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A video allegedly showing a cloud sinking from the sky in Indonesia is doing the rounds on social media.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A&nbsp;<a href="https://www.facebook.com/reel/607397168281029" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">video</a>&nbsp;allegedly showing a cloud sinking from the sky in Indonesia is doing the rounds on social media. In the&nbsp;<a href="https://x.com/BGatesIsaPyscho/status/1860715445793268182" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">video</a>, we can see a few men wearing identical uniforms run towards a white object that falls to the ground from the sky. We fact-check this claim through this article.</p>

<figure><img alt="" height="557" sizes="(max-width: 314px) 100vw, 314px" src="https://factly.in/wp-content/uploads//2024/11/Falling-cloud-in-Indonesia-Claim--577x1024.jpg" srcset="https://factly.in/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Falling-cloud-in-Indonesia-Claim--577x1024.jpg 577w, https://factly.in/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Falling-cloud-in-Indonesia-Claim--169x300.jpg 169w, https://factly.in/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Falling-cloud-in-Indonesia-Claim--768x1364.jpg 768w, https://factly.in/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Falling-cloud-in-Indonesia-Claim--865x1536.jpg 865w, https://factly.in/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Falling-cloud-in-Indonesia-Claim-.jpg 946w" width="314" />
<figcaption>An archived version of this post can be found&nbsp;<a href="https://www.awesomescreenshot.com/video/34057077?key=1ad4b8e1924a676f8e83187980fd9c95" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">here</a>.&nbsp;</figcaption>
</figure>

<blockquote>
<p><strong>Claim:&nbsp;</strong>Video of a cloud sinking/ falling from the sky in Indonesia.</p>

<p><strong>Fact:&nbsp;</strong>The white substance seen in the video is not an actual cloud falling from the sky. The Indonesian Meteorology, Climatology, and Geophysics Agency (BMKG) Director confirmed that it is most likely a condensation of water vapour or gas created due to human activity and not a natural cloud. Hence, the claim made in the post is&nbsp;<strong>False</strong>.&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>

<p>To check the veracity of the viral claim, we searched the internet using relevant keywords to see if the media had reported this incident. This search led us to a&nbsp;<a href="https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/etimes/trending/cloud-falls-from-the-sky-people-capture-on-camera-hug-it/articleshow/115513472.cms" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">news report</a>&nbsp;published by The Times of India about this incident.</p>

<figure><img alt="" height="609" sizes="(max-width: 491px) 100vw, 491px" src="https://factly.in/wp-content/uploads//2024/11/Falling-cloud-in-Indonesia-Image-01--826x1024.jpg" srcset="https://factly.in/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Falling-cloud-in-Indonesia-Image-01--826x1024.jpg 826w, https://factly.in/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Falling-cloud-in-Indonesia-Image-01--242x300.jpg 242w, https://factly.in/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Falling-cloud-in-Indonesia-Image-01--768x952.jpg 768w, https://factly.in/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Falling-cloud-in-Indonesia-Image-01--1239x1536.jpg 1239w, https://factly.in/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Falling-cloud-in-Indonesia-Image-01-.jpg 1316w" width="491" /></figure>

<p>According to this report, this incident did indeed happen in an industrial area in Indonesia. It also mentioned that the local authorities have concluded that the foam-like substance seen in the video “<em>was most likely created due to the condensation of pollutants in the surrounding industrial and mining areas.</em>”</p>

<p>To learn more about this incident, we ran a keyword search on the internet in Indonesian, which led us to multiple local news reports (<a href="https://medan.tribunnews.com/2024/11/17/viral-awan-jatuh-dari-langit-di-area-tambang-kalteng-disebut-awan-kinton-dragon-ball-ini-faktanya" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">here</a>,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.suara.com/tekno/2024/11/16/190000/viral-fenomena-alam-bak-awan-kinton-jatuh-begini-penjelasan-bmkg#goog_rewarded" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">here</a>, and&nbsp;<a href="https://www.bisnis.com/read/20241116/638/1816496/bmkg-ungkap-misteri-gumpalan-awan-jatuh-yang-sempat-gegerkan-warga-murung-raya-kalteng" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">here</a>) on this incident.&nbsp;</p>

<figure><img alt="" height="512" sizes="(max-width: 505px) 100vw, 505px" src="https://factly.in/wp-content/uploads//2024/11/Falling-cloud-in-Indonesia-Image-02--1009x1024.jpg" srcset="https://factly.in/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Falling-cloud-in-Indonesia-Image-02--1009x1024.jpg 1009w, https://factly.in/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Falling-cloud-in-Indonesia-Image-02--296x300.jpg 296w, https://factly.in/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Falling-cloud-in-Indonesia-Image-02--768x779.jpg 768w, https://factly.in/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Falling-cloud-in-Indonesia-Image-02-.jpg 1366w" width="505" /></figure>

<p>As per these reports, this incident happened in the Morong Raya area in the Kalimantan province of Indonesia, and the video went viral on social media.&nbsp;<a href="https://www.cnnindonesia.com/teknologi/20241116131419-199-1167336/heboh-awan-jatuh-di-kalteng-bmkg-pastikan-hanya-gumpalan-uap" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">CNN Indonesia</a>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<a href="https://voi.id/en/news/434278" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">VOI</a>&nbsp;reported that the white mass seen falling from the sky was not a cloud.&nbsp;</p>

<figure><img alt="" height="275" sizes="(max-width: 548px) 100vw, 548px" src="https://factly.in/wp-content/uploads//2024/11/Falling-cloud-in-Indonesia-Image-03--1024x514.jpg" srcset="https://factly.in/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Falling-cloud-in-Indonesia-Image-03--1024x514.jpg 1024w, https://factly.in/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Falling-cloud-in-Indonesia-Image-03--300x151.jpg 300w, https://factly.in/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Falling-cloud-in-Indonesia-Image-03--768x385.jpg 768w, https://factly.in/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Falling-cloud-in-Indonesia-Image-03--1536x771.jpg 1536w, https://factly.in/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Falling-cloud-in-Indonesia-Image-03-.jpg 1542w" width="548" /></figure>

<p>This was confirmed by the Meteorology, Climatology and Geophysics Agency&nbsp;<a href="https://www.bmkg.go.id/profil/?p=tugas-fungsi" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">(BMKG)</a>&nbsp;of Indonesia. Per the reports, the Director of BMKG said that the white mass seen in the video is not a natural cloud but a condensation of water vapour or gas due to human activity that occurs in the mining area.'&nbsp;</p>

<figure><img alt="" height="217" sizes="(max-width: 552px) 100vw, 552px" src="https://factly.in/wp-content/uploads//2024/11/Falling-cloud-in-Indonesia-Image-04--1024x404.png" srcset="https://factly.in/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Falling-cloud-in-Indonesia-Image-04--1024x404.png 1024w, https://factly.in/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Falling-cloud-in-Indonesia-Image-04--300x119.png 300w, https://factly.in/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Falling-cloud-in-Indonesia-Image-04--768x303.png 768w, https://factly.in/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Falling-cloud-in-Indonesia-Image-04-.png 1524w" width="552" /></figure>

<p><em>“Andri explained that the clouds cannot fall to the surface as dense clumps because the particles are very light and scattered with low density. This is because clouds are a collection of very small and light water droplets or ice crystals, so they continue to float in the atmosphere with the help of air currents.”</em>&nbsp;<a href="https://voi.id/en/news/434278" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">VOI reported</a>. He further said that cloud particles generally evaporate before reaching the ground.</p>

<p>According to&nbsp;<a href="https://education.nationalgeographic.org/resource/cloud/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">National Geographic</a>, clouds are a visual accumulation of water droplets in the Earth's atmosphere, and they are found at heights of 2000-12000 meters above the Earth's surface. You can find more information about clouds&nbsp;<a href="https://gpm.nasa.gov/resources/faq/what-are-clouds-made-are-they-more-likely-form-polluted-air-or-pristine-air" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">here</a>,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.usgs.gov/media/images/a-cloud-can-weigh-much-airplane-why-doesnt-it-fall#:~:text=Even%20though%20a%20cloud%20weighs,air%20nearer%20the%20land%20surface." rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">here</a>, and&nbsp;<a href="https://www.noaa.gov/jetstream/clouds/four-core-types-of-clouds" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">here</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<figure><img alt="" height="481" sizes="(max-width: 513px) 100vw, 513px" src="https://factly.in/wp-content/uploads//2024/11/Falling-cloud-in-Indonesia-Image-06-1024x962.jpg" srcset="https://factly.in/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Falling-cloud-in-Indonesia-Image-06-1024x962.jpg 1024w, https://factly.in/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Falling-cloud-in-Indonesia-Image-06-300x282.jpg 300w, https://factly.in/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Falling-cloud-in-Indonesia-Image-06-768x722.jpg 768w, https://factly.in/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Falling-cloud-in-Indonesia-Image-06-1536x1443.jpg 1536w, https://factly.in/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Falling-cloud-in-Indonesia-Image-06.jpg 1852w" width="513" /></figure>

<p>To sum up, a video of a white mass occurring due to condensation of water vapour or gas is falsely shared as visuals of a cloud falling from the sky.</p>

<p>(This story was originally published by <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://factly.in/the-white-mass-falling-on-the-ground-in-this-viral-video-is-not-a-natural-cloud-falling-from-the-sky/">Factly</a>, and republished by NDTV as part of the Shakti Collective)</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/hpv2lou_white-mass-falling-on-ground-fact-check_625x300_28_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[This incident happened in an industrial area in Indonesia.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/final-letter-from-ex-youtube-ceo-susan-wojcicki-released-months-after-her-death-7123085]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Final Letter From Ex-YouTube CEO Released Months After Her Death]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/final-letter-from-ex-youtube-ceo-susan-wojcicki-released-months-after-her-death-7123085]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 28 Nov 2024 09:51:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Before her death on August 9, the ex-YouTube CEO wrote a final letter and talked about lung cancer diagnosis and efforts to research the disease.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>YouTube has shared a heartfelt letter from its former CEO, Susan Wojcicki, three months after she died from lung cancer at the age of 56. The letter, penned just weeks before her death, was released this month in recognition of Lung Cancer Awareness Month. The letter was released on November 25.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In the message, Wojcicki reflected on her battle with the disease and highlighted the critical need for improved treatments. She also underscored the fact that lung cancer remains the leading cause of cancer-related deaths among women.</p>

<p>"At the end of 2022, I was diagnosed with lung cancer. I had almost no symptoms and was running a few miles a day at the time. I had never smoked so I was totally shocked with this diagnosis. My life changed dramatically after that day. I decided to resign from my role as CEO of YouTube, to focus on my health and my family. I was able to live an almost normal life, thanks to modern medicine," she wrote.</p>

<p>After stepping down from her role as YouTube's CEO following her diagnosis, Susan Wojcicki remained active, serving on the boards of companies such as Salesforce, Planet Labs, and Waymo. In her letter, she shared how her illness profoundly altered her perspective on life.</p>

<p>"Having cancer hasn't been easy. As a person, I have changed a lot, and probably the most important lesson I have learned is just to focus and enjoy the present! Life is unpredictable for everyone, with many unknowns, but there is a lot of beauty in everyday life. My goals going forward are to enjoy the present as much as possible and fight for better understanding and cures for this disease," she added.</p>

<p>Wojcicki died on August 10 after a two-year battle with lung cancer. Her legacy now encompasses a dedication to raising awareness and advocating for progress in cancer treatments.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/rman2lho_susan-wojcicki_625x300_10_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Wojcicki died on August 10 after a two-year battle with lung cancer.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/from-boomers-to-gen-z-how-generations-shape-societal-evolution-7122879]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[From Boomers To Gen Z: How Generations Shape Societal Evolution]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/from-boomers-to-gen-z-how-generations-shape-societal-evolution-7122879]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 28 Nov 2024 09:12:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Generational cohorts, from the Greatest Generation to Generation Alpha, reveal how historical, cultural, and technological influences shape societies.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Gen Z, Millennials, and Baby Boomers are examples of generational categories that provide insight into how common historical, cultural, and technological factors change societies. These groups, which often last 15 to 20 years, offer valuable perspectives on parenting approaches, cultural norms, and group dynamics. The main generational cohorts and their characteristics are broken down here.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>1: The Greatest Generation (1901-1927)</strong></p>

<p>They lived through the Great Depression and served in World War II. This group is known as the "GI Generation." Popularized by Tom Brokaw's book The Greatest Generation, their values revolved around resilience, hard work, and patriotism. Events such as the Roaring Twenties and the Stock Market Crash shaped their ethos.</p>

<p><strong>2: The Silent Generation (1928-1945)</strong></p>

<p>This group, which was notorious for conforming during the McCarthy era, saw the end of World War II, the start of the Cold War, and the emergence of television. Their practical philosophy placed a strong focus on stability and discipline in both life and parenting.</p>

<p><strong>3: Baby Boomers (1946-1964)</strong></p>

<p>Born during the post-war population boom, Boomers were shaped by the Vietnam War, civil rights movements, and countercultural revolutions. They pushed for higher education and upward mobility, redefining societal norms.</p>

<p><strong>4: Generation X (1965-1980)</strong></p>

<p>This generation grew up amid the rise of personal computers, video games, and the AIDS crisis. Known for valuing independence and work-life balance, their parenting emphasized choice and individuality.</p>

<p><strong>5: The Millennial Generation (1981-1996)</strong></p>

<p>Millennials, who were the first to live in both the pre- and post-internet periods, witnessed both the digital boom and 9/11. Their emphasis on social justice, technology, and environmental awareness is a reflection of their upbringing in a time of fast change.</p>

<p><strong>6: Generation Z (1997-2012)</strong></p>

<p>The Covid-19 epidemic and the social media revolutions influenced Gen Z, the first generation to be entirely digital. Socially conscious and tech-savvy, they use internet platforms to innovate and engage in action.</p>

<p><strong>7: Generation Alpha (2013-2022)</strong></p>

<p>Coined by social researcher and futurist Mark McCrindle, Generation Alpha represents the first group born entirely in the 21st century. Growing up in an AI-driven world, their future will be defined by unparalleled digital connectivity and technological fluency.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/eat47ok_generation_625x300_28_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Each group, spanning 15-20 years, reflects unique traits, parenting styles, and values.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hidden-message-in-a-bottle-uncovered-by-scottish-lighthouse-workers-after-132-years-7122832]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hidden Message In A Bottle Uncovered By Lighthouse Workers After 132 Years]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hidden-message-in-a-bottle-uncovered-by-scottish-lighthouse-workers-after-132-years-7122832]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 28 Nov 2024 09:01:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[This "once-in-a-lifetime" find is believed to be the first message in a bottle ever discovered inside a Scottish lighthouse.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Engineers have uncovered a 132-year-old message in a bottle hidden within the walls of a lighthouse in southern Scotland. The discovery was made at Corsewall Lighthouse, located at the northernmost tip of the Rhins of Galloway, the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cje0x5j7wgjo" rel="noindex,nofollow"><em>BBC </em></a>reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>This "once-in-a-lifetime" find is believed to be the first message in a bottle ever discovered inside a Scottish lighthouse. Written in quill and ink, the note, dated September 4, 1892, lists the names of three engineers who installed a new type of light in the 100-foot (30-meter) tower, along with the names of the lighthouse's three keepers.</p>

<p>Ross Russell, a mechanical engineer with the Northern Lighthouse Board, found the 8-inch (20 cm) bottle while inspecting the lighthouse. It was wedged behind panels in a cupboard and out of reach. The team used a makeshift tool- a rope attached to a broom handle- to retrieve it. They waited for Barry Miller, the retained lighthouse keeper, to arrive before opening the bottle.&nbsp;</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/DCJdevotnpM/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DCJdevotnpM/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DCJdevotnpM/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DCJdevotnpM/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by Northern Lighthouse Board (@nlb_uk)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p></p>

<p>"My goodness, am I grateful for them doing that," Miller said.</p>

<p>The bottle, made of coarse glass filled with tiny air bubbles, features a distinctive convex base that prevents it from standing upright. It is thought to have once contained oil. The cork stopper had expanded over time, adhering to the glass, while the securing wire had rusted away. To access the message, the team carefully cut and drilled through the cork.</p>

<p>Extracting the note proved challenging as it initially appeared too large to fit through the bottle's narrow neck. Using a custom tool crafted from two pieces of cable, the team gently twisted the message free.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Dr. Miller, 77, recounted the moment he opened the bottle to BBC Scotland News, admitting his hands were trembling with excitement.</p>

<p><em>Corsewall Light &amp; Fog Signal Station, Sept 4th 1892.</em></p>

<p><em>This lantern was erected by James Wells Engineer, John Westwood Millwright, James Brodie Engineer, David Scott Labourer, of the firm of James Milne &amp; Son Engineers, Milton House Works, Edinburgh, during the months from May to September and relighted on Thursday night 15th Sept 1892.</em></p>

<p><em>The following are keepers at the station at this time, John Wilson Principal, John B Henderson 1st assistant, John Lockhart 2nd assistant.</em></p>

<p><em>The lens and machine were supplied by James Dove &amp;Co Engineers Greenside Edinburgh and erected by William Burness, John Harrower, and James Dods. Engineers with the above firm.</em></p>

<p>The bottle was found by Ross Russell, Morgan Dennison and Neil Armstrong.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The note was just sensational, I was just in utter amazement," Ross said.</p>

<p>"Being the first person to touch the bottle after 132 years was just mind blowing.</p>

<p>"It's a once in a lifetime find."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/6upu6b0o_message-in-a-bottle_625x300_28_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The message was written on September 4th 1892.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>