<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Sat, 26 Oct 2024 09:01:28 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/live-updates-israel-will-face-proportional-reaction-says-iran-after-strikes-report-6876417]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Will "Face Proportional Reaction", Says Iran After Strikes: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/live-updates-israel-will-face-proportional-reaction-says-iran-after-strikes-report-6876417]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 26 Oct 2024 08:38:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Four weeks after Iran attacked Israel with a barrage of ballistic missiles to avenge the strikes on ally Hezbollah, the Jewish state responded at the time of its choosing.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Four weeks after Iran attacked Israel with a barrage of ballistic missiles to avenge the strikes on ally Hezbollah, the Jewish state responded at the time of its choosing. The tensions never simmered in the region and now Iran says it is ready to respond to the 'act of aggression'.</p>

<p>Iran is prepared to respond to any Israeli "aggression," Iran's semi-official Tasnim news agency reported, citing sources. "There is no doubt that Israel will face a proportional reaction for any action it takes," <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.tasnimnews.com/en/news/2024/10/26/3185861/iran-ready-for-retaliation-against-israel-source" rel="no follow, no index">Tasnim </a>quotes the sources as saying.</p>

<p>The Israeli army has warned Iran that it will "pay a heavy price" if it begins a new round of escalation.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Israel Strikes Back</strong></p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-iran-war-israel-conducts-precise-strikes-on-iran-explosions-heard-around-tehran-6876065">Iranian state TV reported "strong explosions"</a> around Tehran on Saturday morning, without specifying their cause. The semi-official Tasnim News Agency noted that no rockets or aircraft were reported in the skies over Tehran at the time of the explosions.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Iranian state TV claimed that the blasts heard around Tehran were due to the "activation of the air defence system." "The loud blasts heard around Tehran were related to the activation of the air defence system against the actions of Zionist regime which attacked three locations outside of Tehran city," state TV reported.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-iran-live-updates-israel-begins-strikes-on-military-targets-in-iran-6875837">Israel-Iran Live Updates: Israel Begins Strikes On Military Targets In Iran</a></p>

<p>Iranian authorities suggested the noises could be related to defensive measures, hinting at the possibility that Iran's air defence systems had been activated.</p>

<p>In addition to Tehran, residents in the nearby city of Karaj reported hearing blasts. Iranian authorities say that operations at critical sites such as the Imam Khomeini International Airport, Mehrabad Airport, and a prominent oil refinery south of Tehran were "normal" and unaffected by the strikes. However, several military bases near Tehran were reportedly targeted by Israeli forces, according to Iran's Fars News Agency.</p>

<p>Israeli officials said the attacks are justified as measures of self-defence. IDF's spokesperson Daniel Hagari also urged Israeli citizens to "remain alert and vigilant."</p>

<p>Israel PM Benjamin Netanyahu and other officials are assessing the security situation after the strikes. Meanwhile, Iran has suspended all flights until further notice.</p>

<p><strong>What Happened On October 1</strong></p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-israels-air-defence-system-in-action-to-intercept-iranian-missiles-6695307">A few hours before midnight</a>, Iran attacked Israel with missiles and rockets after tensions escalated in West Asia following artillery and air strikes on Lebanon to target Hezbollah, a Shia militant outfit and a strong ally of Iran.</p>

<p>Iran's Revolutionary Guards said the attack was in response to the killing of Hezbollah chief Hassan Nasrallah.</p>

<p>Videos show the night sky lighting up with explosions after air raid sirens echoed across the country.</p>

<p>The missiles were raining down on Israel and the Iron Dome and Arrow air defence system were in action to intercept and neutralise the targets. Iran fired over 100 missiles, Israeli media reported and several videos showed intercepted missile debris falling over Israeli cities.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/3rv6up2o_israel-attack-on-iran_625x300_26_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Live Updates: Iranian state TV claimed that the blasts heard around Tehran.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-election-time-for-america-to-beyonce-introduces-kamala-harris-at-campaign-rally-in-houston-6876385]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Time For America To...": Beyonce Bats For Kamala Harris At Campaign Rally]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-election-time-for-america-to-beyonce-introduces-kamala-harris-at-campaign-rally-in-houston-6876385]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 26 Oct 2024 08:32:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Beyonce took the stage Friday and introduced Democrat Kamala Harris at the vice president's White House campaign rally in Houston.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pop superstar Beyonce took the stage Friday and introduced Democrat Kamala Harris at the vice president's White House campaign rally in Houston, saying "it's time for America to sing a new song."</p>

<p>Telling the crowd that "we must vote," the Grammy-winning singer said she was participating in the event, which highlighted Harris's push to secure American abortion rights, not as a celebrity or a politician but as "a mother who cares deeply about the world."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/r5kqfo1_beyonce-introduces-kamala-harris_625x300_26_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Beyonce said that it is "time for America to sing a new song".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/illegal-co-operation-south-korea-slams-russia-north-korea-defence-treaty-6876312]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Illegal Cooperation": South Korea Slams Russia-North Korea Defence Treaty]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/illegal-co-operation-south-korea-slams-russia-north-korea-defence-treaty-6876312]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 26 Oct 2024 08:12:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[South Korea urged Russia to stop its "illegal cooperation" with North Korea and voiced "grave concern" on Friday as Moscow moved to ratify its defence treaty with Pyongyang.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>South Korea urged Russia to stop its "illegal cooperation" with North Korea and voiced "grave concern" on Friday as Moscow moved to ratify its defence treaty with Pyongyang.</p>

<p>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky warned shortly after that Russia was planning to send North Korean troops into battle against his country as early as Sunday, and urged world leaders to pile "tangible pressure" on Pyongyang.</p>

<p>Russian lawmakers voted unanimously on Thursday to ratify a defence treaty with North Korea that provides for "mutual assistance" if either party faces aggression. It will now be sent to the upper house of parliament, the Federation Council, for approval.</p>

<p>According to South Korea and the United States, thousands of North Korean troops were training in Russia.</p>

<p>Ukraine said this week that North Korean soldiers had arrived in the "combat zone" in Russia's Kursk border region.</p>

<p>While stopping short of confirming boots on the ground, a North Korean official said any troop deployment to Russia would be in line with international law.</p>

<p>The South Korean government said it "strongly urges the immediate withdrawal of North Korean troops and the cessation of illegal cooperation".</p>

<p>Seoul "expresses grave concern over Russia's ratification of the Russia-North Korea treaty amidst the ongoing deployment of North Korean troops to Russia," the South Korean foreign ministry said in a statement.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Seoul said it would work with allies to "take appropriate measures" over the move, and the country -- a major arms exporter -- has suggested it could revise its longstanding policy that prevents sending weapons directly to Kyiv.</p>

<p>The national security advisors of the United States, South Korea and Japan on Friday discussed the North Korean troop deployment, the White House said, with the officials expressing "grave concern" at the development.</p>

<p>"This deployment is the latest in a series of concerning indicators of deepening military cooperation between the DPRK and Russia," US National Security Council spokesman John Kirby said, using the acronym for the official name of North Korea.</p>

<p>Also on Friday leaders of the Group of Seven wealthy democracies finalized details surrounding a $50 billion loan to aid Kyiv, backed by profits from Russia's frozen sovereign assets, according to a statement by G7 leaders.</p>

<p>They said they "have reached a consensus on how to deliver" the loans that will "support Ukraine's budgetary, military and reconstruction assistance", with an aim to start disbursing funds by the end of this year.</p>

<h3><strong>'Punish escalation'</strong></h3>

<p>Zelensky said North Korean troops could be sent to fight Ukrainian troops this weekend.</p>

<p>"The actual involvement of North Korea in hostilities should be met not with a blind eye and confused comments but with tangible pressure on both Moscow and Pyongyang to comply with the UN Charter and to punish escalation," he said on social media.</p>

<p>A senior official within the Ukrainian president's office said the North Korean troops could be deployed either to the Russian region of Kursk or in eastern Ukraine.</p>

<p>Branding the prospect "very worrying", Germany's Chancellor Olaf Scholz said it showed that Russian President Vladimir Putin was facing difficulties in the war.</p>

<p>"It is serious and, of course, something that escalates the situation further," he told German media while visiting India.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Putin said in an interview that aired Friday on state television that it was up to Moscow how it uses the new defence treaty's clause on mutual military assistance.</p>

<p>"It's our sovereign decision, whether we use something or not," Putin said. "Where, how, whether we need this, or (if) we, for example, only carry out some exercises, training, passing on some experience -- that's our business."</p>

<p>Seoul and Washington have long claimed that the nuclear-armed North is shipping arms to Russia.&nbsp;</p>

<p>One of North Korea's United Nations representatives said at the UN General Assembly's First Committee on Disarmament and International Security that the country was sending neither weapons nor soldiers to help Moscow.</p>

<p>The allegations by South Korea and others are "nothing more than groundless rumours aimed at tarnishing the image of DPRK", Rim Mu Song said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>South Korea's representative flagged videos circulating online of North Korean soldiers in Russian uniforms speaking Korean, but Rim said they "again totally reject the allegation" of troop deployment.</p>

<p>On Friday, a diplomatic official in Pyongyang argued that his country would be well within its rights to deploy soldiers on Russian soil.</p>

<p>"If there is such a thing that the world media is talking about, I think it will be an act conforming with the regulations of international law," said Kim Jong Gyu, North Korea's vice foreign minister in charge of Russian affairs.</p>

<h3><strong>'Provocation'</strong></h3>

<p>South Korean President Yoon Suk Yeol has called the deployment a "provocation that threatens global security beyond the Korean Peninsula and Europe".</p>

<p>Yoon also said South Korea will review its stance on providing weapons to Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Seoul has already sold billions of dollars of tanks, howitzers, attack aircraft and rocket launchers to Poland, a key ally of Kyiv.</p>

<p>In June, South Korea agreed to transfer the knowledge needed to build K2 tanks to Poland, which experts have said could be a key step towards production inside Ukraine.</p>

<p>South Korea's Hanwha Aerospace has signed a $1.64-billion deal with Poland to supply rocket artillery units.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/mvar3a98_russia-north-korea-defence-treaty_625x300_26_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Seoul said it would work with allies to "take appropriate measures" over the move.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/delta-sues-crowdstrike-over-julys-global-outage-that-caused-flight-cancellations-6876319]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Delta Sues CrowdStrike Over Global Outage That Caused Flight Cancellations]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/delta-sues-crowdstrike-over-julys-global-outage-that-caused-flight-cancellations-6876319]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 26 Oct 2024 08:08:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Delta Air Lines on Friday sued CrowdStrike in a Georgia state court after a global outage in July caused mass flight cancellations.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Delta Air Lines on Friday sued CrowdStrike in a Georgia state court after a global outage in July caused mass flight cancellations, disrupted travel plans of 1.3 million customers and cost the carrier more than $500 million.</p>

<p>Delta's lawsuit filed in Fulton County Superior Court called the faulty software update from global cybersecurity firm CrowdStrike "catastrophic."</p>

<p>CrowdStrike has previously rejected Delta's criticism and has suggested it has minimal liability.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/k060c59_delta-airlines_625x300_26_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The global outage disrupted travel plans of 1.3 million customers.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/exercise-of-self-defense-us-defends-israels-strikes-on-iran-6876278]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Exercise Of Self-Defense": US Defends Israel's Strikes On Iran]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/exercise-of-self-defense-us-defends-israels-strikes-on-iran-6876278]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 26 Oct 2024 07:53:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli strikes on military targets in Iran are "an exercise of self-defense" following Tehran's ballistic missile attack earlier this month, the United States said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli strikes on military targets in Iran are "an exercise of self-defense" following Tehran's ballistic missile attack earlier this month, the United States said late Friday, adding it was informed ahead of the strikes.</p>

<p>White House National Security Council spokesman Sean Savett said the "targeted strikes on military targets" are "an exercise of self-defense and in response to Iran's ballistic missile attack against Israel on October 1."</p>

<p>The United States was "informed beforehand and there is no US involvement," a US defense official told AFP, under the condition of anonymity.</p>

<p>The official did not say how far in advance the United States had been informed or what had been shared by Israel.</p>

<p>White House officials said in separate statements later that President Joe Biden and Vice President Kamala Harris had been briefed on the strikes and would continue to receive updates from their national security teams.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/rfo7cd78_israeli-strikes-on-iran_625x300_26_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The United States was informed beforehand and there is no US involvement.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/g7-announces-50-billion-loan-backed-by-russian-assets-to-aid-ukraine-6876245]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[G7 Announces $50 Billion Loan, Backed By Russian Assets, To Aid Ukraine]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/g7-announces-50-billion-loan-backed-by-russian-assets-to-aid-ukraine-6876245]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 26 Oct 2024 07:46:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[G7 leaders have finalized details surrounding a $50 billion loan to aid Kyiv, backed by profits from Russian sovereign assets frozen after its invasion of Ukraine.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>G7 leaders have finalized details surrounding a $50 billion loan to aid Kyiv, backed by profits from Russian sovereign assets frozen after its invasion of Ukraine, according to a statement released Friday.</p>

<p>Leaders of the Group of Seven wealthy democracies said they "have reached a consensus on how to deliver" the loans of approximately $50 billion, with an aim to start disbursing funds by the end of this year.</p>

<p>"The loan proceeds will be disbursed through multiple channels to support Ukraine's budgetary, military and reconstruction assistance," G7 leaders added.</p>

<p>Their announcement came as world financial leaders gathered in Washington this week for meetings hosted by the International Monetary Fund and World Bank.</p>

<p>Finance ministers have "agreed on a technical solution ensuring consistency, coordination, fair distribution of lending, and solidarity among all G7 partners," the statement said.</p>

<p>"We will not tire in our resolve to give Ukraine the support it needs to prevail," the leaders added.</p>

<p>They called on Moscow to end its war and pay for damage caused to Ukraine.</p>

<h3><strong>$20 bn US support</strong></h3>

<p>This week, US President Joe Biden said that as part of the G7 package, the United States would provide $20 billion in loans to Ukraine, to be paid back by the interest earned from immobilized Russian sovereign assets.</p>

<p>This is aimed at supporting Ukraine now, "without burdening taxpayers."</p>

<p>"Our efforts make it clear: tyrants will be responsible for the damages they cause," Biden said.</p>

<p>US Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen signed a statement Wednesday with her Ukrainian counterpart Sergii Marchenko marking their intent to enter into the loan.</p>

<p>The move also committed that new United States or Ukrainian tax dollars would not be the source of repayment.</p>

<p>Economic concerns remain top-of-mind for US voters, with just over a week to go before the country's presidential election on November 5.</p>

<p>Washington aims to provide at least $10 billion of the loans for economic support, with the other half expected to take the form of military aid.</p>

<p>But this will require additional authorization from Congress.</p>

<p>The remaining $30 billion in loans is set to come from a combination of G7 partners, including the European Union, United Kingdom, Canada and Japan, US officials said.</p>

<p>"We have once again made clear our unwavering commitment to stand by Ukraine for as long as it takes," said the G7 statement on Friday.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Time is not on President (Vladimir) Putin's side."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/g1k5pn9g_g7-leaders_625x300_26_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[World financial leaders gathered for meetings hosted by the International Monetary Fund and World Bank.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/human-induced-climate-change-key-cause-for-heatwaves-canada-minister-6876208]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Human-Induced Climate Change Key Cause For Heatwaves": Canada Minister]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/human-induced-climate-change-key-cause-for-heatwaves-canada-minister-6876208]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 26 Oct 2024 07:39:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The tool's first-ever application found that human activity had made a mid-June east coast heave wave two to 10 times more likely.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Canada's environment ministry said Friday that climate change had made nearly all the heat waves recorded this summer more likely, including in an Arctic area where temperatures hit 35 degrees Celcius.</p>

<p>Earlier this year, Environment and Climate Change Canada debuted a new tool that examines the connection between human-caused climate change and extreme weather, by comparing current data with pre-industrial data.</p>

<p>The tool's first-ever application found that human activity had made a mid-June east coast heave wave two to 10 times more likely.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In its latest analysis, the ministry looked at the 37 hottest heat waves recorded this summer across the country.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Four of those 37 were made at least 10 times more likely by human activity. For 28 of the heat waves, the figures were two to 10 times more likely.</p>

<p>"Throughout the summer, we saw above normal temperatures shift across different regions of Canada," environment ministry researcher Nathan Gillet said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Over the past 77 years, summer temperatures have warmed by 1.7 degrees Celsius, nationally, on average, and the principal cause of this warming is human-induced climate change," he told reporters.&nbsp;</p>

<p>One area of the Arctic, the Qikiqtaaluk region of Nunavut, experienced a heat wave that lasted 25 days over September and October.</p>

<p>Further west, in the Arctic town of Inuvik in the Northwest Territories, temperatures hit 35 degrees this summer.</p>

<p>"This is really exceptional in that region," Gillet said.</p>

<p>The ministry said Canada is warming at roughly double the global average rate, and the rate of warming in the Arctic is three times higher than the global average.</p>

<p>"These 'once in 100 years' climate-related weather events are becoming more frequent, severe, and costly," the ministry said.</p>

<p>This winter, the environment ministry expects to use its new tool to assess the correlation between human-caused climate change and extreme cold snaps.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/biq7h78_canada-heatwave_625x300_26_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-500-victims-185-charges-catfish-predator-drives-girl-to-kill-self-gets-jail-for-life-ireland-6876173]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[3,500 Victims, 185 Charges: How 'Catfish' Predator Drove US Girl To Suicide]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-500-victims-185-charges-catfish-predator-drives-girl-to-kill-self-gets-jail-for-life-ireland-6876173]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 26 Oct 2024 07:22:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A prolific "catfish" offender whose cruel campaign of global online blackmail targeted thousands of young victims and drove a 12-year-old US girl to suicide was on Friday jailed for life.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A prolific "catfish" offender whose cruel campaign of global online blackmail targeted thousands of young victims and drove a 12-year-old US girl to suicide was on Friday jailed for life.</p>

<p>Alexander McCartney, 26, posed online as a teenage girl to befriend young females across the world on the social media app Snapchat, forcing them to send him explicit pictures, then threatening to make them public.&nbsp;</p>

<p>He admitted 185 charges involving 70 children and was told he would spend at least 20 years behind bars.</p>

<p>Detective Chief Superintendent Eamonn Corrigan, of the Police Service of Northern Ireland, said McCartney was a "disgusting child predator" whose offending had been on an "industrial scale".</p>

<p>"Sitting in his childhood bedroom in Newry (in Northern Ireland), he began his offending as a late teenager and built what can only be described as a paedophile enterprise," he told reporters outside court.</p>

<p>"McCartney is a dangerous, relentless, cruel paedophile," he added.</p>

<p>Cimarron Thomas from West Virginia in the United States took her own life in May 2018 after McCartney demanded that she involve her younger sister in sex acts he had coerced her into.</p>

<p>Eighteen months later, her distraught father Ben Thomas also died by suicide.</p>

<p>Belfast Crown Court heard earlier other victims had been in the United States as well as in Australia and New Zealand.</p>

<h3><strong>'Sexual deviant'&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Sentencing McCartney, judge John O'Hara said he was unaware of any other case in which an offender had used social media to "inflict such terrible and catastrophic damage on young girls up to and including the death of a 12-year-old girl".</p>

<p>"It is truly difficult to think of a sexual deviant who poses a greater risk than this defendant," he added.</p>

<p>O'Hara said McCartney had been "remorseless" in his offending, ignoring "multiple pleas for mercy".</p>

<p>Even after his third arrest, he said, the former computer science student kept offending in "an even more sinister, dramatic and appalling manner".</p>

<p>McCartney previously pleaded guilty to manslaughter relating to Cimarron's death.</p>

<p>Corrigan told reporters McCartney had even started a countdown when Cimarron threatened to kill herself with a legally owned firearm and told her: "I don't care."</p>

<p>"He may as well have pulled the trigger himself," he added. "There's only one place for him, that's behind bars."</p>

<p>McCartney also admitted 59 counts of blackmail, dozens of charges related to making and distributing indecent photographs and scores more of inciting children to engage in sexual activity.</p>

<h3><strong>'Horrific'</strong></h3>

<p>Police in Northern Ireland worked with other forces internationally to bring him to justice.</p>

<p>Derek Gordon, the US special agent in charge of Homeland Security Investigations based in Washington DC, praised the investigation and prosecution of McCartney by Northern Irish counterparts as "nothing short of brilliant".</p>

<p>"Alexander McCartney committed some horrific and disturbing crimes and deserves every minute he serves in prison," he said.</p>

<p>Catherine Kierans, from the Northern Ireland Public Prosecution Service, said McCartney was estimated to have targeted 3,500 girls, some as young as 10.</p>

<p>Despite exhaustive efforts, however, many of his victims may never be identified.</p>

<p>She urged any child or young person to seek help if they were being threatened by someone demanding sexual images or videos.</p>

<p>"This is a crime. You are not to blame. Please talk to a trusted adult," she said, praising the bravery of the victims who had helped to convict McCartney.</p>

<p>And she called on parents and carers to talk to their children to keep them safe online.</p>

<p>"It is by bringing these issues out into the open that we can break the cycle of secrecy abusers rely on," she said.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p><p><div class='table-div suicide'><table class='table'><thead><tr><th colspan='2'>Helplines</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>Vandrevala Foundation for Mental Health</td><td><a href='tel:+919999666555'>9999666555</a> or <a href='mailto:help@vandrevalafoundation.com'>help@vandrevalafoundation.com</a> </td></tr><tr><td>TISS iCall</td><td><a href='tel:+912225521111'>022-25521111</a> (Monday-Saturday: 8 am to 10 pm)</td></tr> <tr><td colspan='2'>(If you need support or know someone who does, please reach out to your nearest mental health specialist.)</td></tr></tbody></table></div></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/s8ut6gb_online-predator_625x300_26_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[McCartney admitted 59 counts of blackmail, charges related to making, distributing indecent photographs.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-latest-poll-shows-donald-trump-kamala-harris-tied-for-popular-vote-6876136]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Elections: Latest Poll Shows Trump, Kamala Harris Tied For Popular Vote]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-latest-poll-shows-donald-trump-kamala-harris-tied-for-popular-vote-6876136]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 26 Oct 2024 07:12:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[With less than two weeks left for the presidential polls, the race seems extremely tight with both Vice President Kamala Harris and former President Donald Trump tied at 48 per cent in the popular vote.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With less than two weeks left for the presidential polls, the race seems extremely tight with both Vice President Kamala Harris and former President Donald Trump tied at 48 per cent in the popular vote, according to the final national poll conducted by the New York Times and Siena College.</p>

<p>The results of the poll are not encouraging for Harris as it comes just less than two weeks ahead of the elections and as millions of people across the US have already cast votes, according to the New York Times.</p>

<p>The elections in the US are set to be held on November 5, with former US President Donald Trump running for a second term and Vice President Kamala Harris aiming to create history by becoming the first woman president of the US.</p>

<p>In recent elections, Democrats have had an edge in the popular vote while they have lost the Electoral College and thus the White House. They have been looking to Harris to build a strong national lead as an indication that she would perform well in such critical swing states like Pennsylvania, Michigan, and Wisconsin, as reported by the New York Times.</p>

<p>Harris and Trump remain tied even after three months of the most tumultuous months in the recent political history of the US.</p>

<p>In the past few months, the presidential nominees of the Democratic and Republican parties have participated in high-profile debates, two assassination attempts on Trump have been made and the two leaders have held dozens of rallies across the seven battlefield states. In the past few months, hundreds of millions spent on advertisements have seemingly done little to change the trajectory of the race.</p>

<p>Kamala Harris' position, might have declined among likely voters since the last Times/Siena College poll, conducted in early October, the report added.</p>

<p>At the time, Kamala Harris had a narrow lead over Donald Trump, 49 per cent to 46 per cent. The change is within the margin of error. However, the Times's national polling average has registered a tightening in polls over the past few weeks.</p>

<p>Although the latest Times/Siena College poll has given a glimpse into national sentiment, ever, the presidential election will be decided in the seven battleground states where Trump and Harris have spent a lot of their resources and time.</p>

<p>Most polls in those states -- Nevada, North Carolina, Pennsylvania, Wisconsin, Arizona, Georgia, Michigan -- indicate the contest is equally close.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/t62tibb8_donald-trump-kamala-harris-_625x300_11_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Poll results are discouraging for Kamala Harris just two weeks before the elections.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nasa-spacex-crew8-astronaut-hospitalised-after-splashdown-remains-stable-6876108]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[SpaceX Crew8 Astronaut Hospitalised After Splashdown, Remains 'Stable']]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nasa-spacex-crew8-astronaut-hospitalised-after-splashdown-remains-stable-6876108]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 26 Oct 2024 07:11:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A NASA astronaut who just returned from the International Space Station has been hospitalized for an unspecified medical condition.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A NASA astronaut who just returned from the International Space Station has been hospitalized for an unspecified medical condition but remains stable, the US space agency said Friday.</p>

<p>The four-member Crew-8 mission splashed down off the coast of Florida early Friday after nearly eight months aboard the orbital laboratory.</p>

<p>On its way back to Earth, the SpaceX Dragon executed a normal re-entry and splashdown, and recovery of the crew and spacecraft was without incident, NASA said in a blog post.</p>

<p>But during routine medical assessments on the recovery ship, an "additional evaluation of the crew members was requested out of an abundance of caution," it added, without elaborating.</p>

<p>NASA astronauts Matthew Dominick, Michael Barratt and Jeanette Epps, and Roscosmos cosmonaut Alexander Grebenki were all flown to Ascension Sacred Heart Pensacola.</p>

<p>Three were subsequently released, while one of the NASA astronauts remains at the hospital "under observation as a precautionary measure."</p>

<p>NASA said it would not disclose specific medical information to protect the crew member's privacy but would provide updates as available.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/lg1m0qtg_nasa-spacex-astronaut_625x300_26_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Four-member Crew-8 mission splashed down off the coast of Florida on Friday.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/oldest-living-person-in-us-elizabeth-francis-dies-at-115-6876129]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Oldest Living Person In US, Elizabeth Francis, Dies At 115]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/oldest-living-person-in-us-elizabeth-francis-dies-at-115-6876129]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 26 Oct 2024 07:10:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Elizabeth Francis, who was the oldest living person in the United States, has died at the age of 115.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Elizabeth Francis, who was the oldest living person in the United States, has died at the age of 115. Ms Francis died peacefully on Tuesday while surrounded by her family, granddaughter Ethel Harrison, who was also her primary caregiver told <em>ABC News</em>. At the time of her death, Ms Francis was the oldest living person in the US and the third-oldest person in the world, according to LongeviQuest, a global database of the world's oldest individuals. She lived most of her life in Houston, Texas, per the outlet.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Speaking to <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://abcnews.go.com/GMA/Living/elizabeth-francis-oldest-living-person-us-dies-115/story?id=115087261">ABC News</a>,</em> Ms Harrison described Ms Francis as a "person who loved people". "She loved the Lord. Her faith was extremely strong. She was always, you know, jolly, you know, 'how you doing? You're doing okay?' That was just her personality. And she would always say, treat people like you want to be treated. And that was her motto," Ms Harrison added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Separately, in a statement, LongeviQuest spokesperson, Ben Meyers, called Ms Francis "America's Grandmother". "She lived a life of faith and love, always crediting the Good Lord for her longevity. She was beloved by her family and community," Mr Meyers said.</p>

<p>"They are in our prayers, especially her daughter Ms. Dorothy Williams, whom she lived with until the end, and her granddaughter Ms. Ethel Harrison whose joyful dedication made it possible for her grandmother to live at home even at age 115," he added.</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/feature/tech-millionaire-bryan-johnson-shares-how-he-improved-posture-after-mri-scan-showed-it-was-killing-his-brain-6869480">Tech Millionaire Bryan Johnson Shares How He Improved Posture After MRI Scan Showed It Was "Killing" His Brain</a></strong></p>

<p>Ms Francis was born in Louisiana on July 25, 1909. She lived through everything from World War I to the sinking of the Titanic. She raised her daughter as a single mother, ran a coffee shop in Houston and preferred walking over driving. The 115-year-old was alive during the Great Depression, the first aeroplane flight across the Atlantic and 20 presidents from William Howard Taft to Joe Biden.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Earlier this year, on her 115th birthday, Ms Francis also offered a single tip on how to live a long and happy life. "Speak your mind and don't hold your tongue," she said.</p>

<p>Notably, Ms Francis was crowned the country's oldest person in February earlier this year after the previous longevity record holder, Edie Ceccarelli, died a few weeks after her 116th birthday in California. In April, she was then awarded a plaque recognising her as the oldest person in the US from LongeviQuest.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Now, America's oldest living person is Naomi Whitehead, who was born on September 26, 1910, according to LongeviQuest.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/564e1ing_elizabeth-francis_625x300_27_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Elizabeth Francis died peacefully on Tuesday.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-iran-war-israel-conducts-precise-strikes-on-iran-explosions-heard-around-tehran-6876065]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Conducts "Precise Strikes" On Iran, Explosions Heard Around Tehran]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-iran-war-israel-conducts-precise-strikes-on-iran-explosions-heard-around-tehran-6876065]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 26 Oct 2024 06:54:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel has launched targeted strikes against Iran, with its military saying the strikes are in response to the October 1 missile attack, during which Iran fired approximately 200 ballistic missiles at Israel.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="sp_only-ul-ol sp_only-ul-ol-2">
<ol>
	<li>&nbsp;"In response to months of continuous attacks from the regime in Iran against the State of Israel, the IDF is conducting precise strikes on military targets in Iran," the Israeli Defense Forces (IDF) said in a statement.<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-iran-live-updates-israel-begins-strikes-on-military-targets-in-iran-6875837"> Israeli officials</a> have clarified that these attacks are justified as measures of self-defence. IDF's spokesperson Daniel Hagari also urged Israeli citizens to "remain alert and vigilant."</li>
	<li>The United States confirmed it was informed of the impending strike, although no US personnel or assets were involved in the operation. Sean Savett, spokesperson for the White House National Security Council, termed Israel's actions as "an exercise of self-defence and in response to Iran's ballistic missile attack against Israel."&nbsp;</li>
	<li>Iranian state TV reported "strong explosions" around Tehran on Saturday morning, without specifying their cause. The semi-official Tasnim News Agency noted that no rockets or aircraft were reported in the skies over Tehran at the time of the explosions.&nbsp;</li>
	<li>Iranian state TV claimed that the blasts heard around Tehran were due to the "activation of the air defence system." "The loud blasts heard around Tehran were related to the activation of the air defence system against the actions of Zionist regime which attacked three locations outside of Tehran city," state TV reported</li>
	<li>Iranian authorities suggested the noises could be related to defensive measures, hinting at the possibility that Iran's air defence systems had been activated.</li>
	<li>In addition to Tehran, residents in the nearby city of Karaj reported hearing blasts. Iranian authorities say that operations at critical sites such as the Imam Khomeini International Airport, Mehrabad Airport, and a prominent oil refinery south of Tehran were "normal" and unaffected by the strikes. However, several military bases near Tehran were reportedly targeted by Israeli forces, according to Iran's Fars News Agency.</li>
	<li>Reports of explosions from Syria's state news agency SANA noted that Syrian air defences were activated in response to "hostile targets" near the capital, Damascus. While there was no official statement connecting the Syrian incidents directly to the Israeli strikes in Iran, explosions were heard in Damascus and central regions.</li>
	<li>In recent weeks, Israel has intensified operations against Hamas in Gaza and Hezbollah in Lebanon - both allies of Iran - following an unprecedented attack by Hamas on southern Israel on October 7, 2023.&nbsp;</li>
	<li>This brutal assault, labelled the deadliest attack in Israel's history, has triggered relentless Israeli offensives across Gaza and heightened security measures along Israel's northern border with Lebanon to counter Hezbollah's influence.</li>
	<li>Israel's defence minister warned earlier this week that any attempt to harm Israel would result in a "heavy price". The United States, while voicing its support for Israel's right to defend itself, has been diplomatically active, pushing to prevent a chain reaction that could destabilise the entire region.</li>
</ol>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/2lceiu2_netanyahu-khamenei-_625x300_04_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[These strikes early on Saturday have targeted what Israel claims to be military facilities in Iran.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-iran-live-updates-israel-begins-strikes-on-military-targets-in-iran-6875837]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Live Updates: Air Strikes On Iran Military Targets Completed, Says Israel]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-iran-live-updates-israel-begins-strikes-on-military-targets-in-iran-6875837]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 26 Oct 2024 05:40:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel military said that it has launched "precise strikes" on military targets in Iran" early Saturday morning. The strikes against Iran were in response to "months of continuous attacks" from Tehran.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel's military said that it launched <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-conducted-air-strikes-in-iran-report-6875719">"precise strikes"</a> on military targets in Iran" early Saturday morning. The strikes against Iran were in response to "months of continuous attacks" from Tehran. Israel said the air strikes on the military facilities in Iran are completed.</p>

<p>Iran's state TV also confirmed that several strong explosions were heard around the capital, but there was no official comment about the source of the explosions. A few hours later, several explosions were heard in the capital Tehran, which the Iranian state media said was because of the activation of air defence systems.</p>

<p>According to Fox News, the White House was notified shortly before Israel carried out air strikes on Iran.</p>

<h2 style="margin: 0;
padding: 8px  5px;
width: 100%;
line-height: 30px;
color: #b7223b;
font-weight: 600 !important;">Here are the updates on Israel's attack on Iran:</h2>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/lht08q7_israel-strikes-on-iran_625x300_26_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel military said that it has launched air strikes on military targets in Iran early Saturday morning.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-conducted-air-strikes-in-iran-report-6875719]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Conducting "Precise Strikes" On Military Targets In Iran]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-conducted-air-strikes-in-iran-report-6875719]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 26 Oct 2024 05:05:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel conducted air strikes in Iran, an Axios reporter said on Friday on social media platform X, citing two sources.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel hit back at Iran early on Saturday, with its military saying it was conducting strikes against military targets in response to Tehran's attacks on Israel.</p>

<p>The Middle East has been on edge in anticipation of Israeli retaliation for a ballistic-missile barrage carried out by Iran on Oct. 1, in which around 200 ballistic missiles were fired at Israel, Iran's second direct attack on Israel in six months.</p>

<p>"In response to months of continuous attacks from the regime in Iran against the State of Israel – right now the Israel Defense Forces is conducting precise strikes on military targets in Iran," the Israel Defense Forces said in a statement.</p>

<p>Israel says it has the right and duty to respond to attacks from Tehran and its proxies, which have included missile strikes launched from Iranian soil.</p>

<p>"Our defensive and offensive capabilities are fully mobilized," it added.</p>

<p>The scope of the attack was not immediately clear.</p>

<p>Iran's state TV said several strong explosions were heard around the capital Tehran. Semi-official Iranian media said explosions were also heard in the nearby city of Karaj.</p>

<p>The Tasnim news agency said that "nothing has been reported about hearing the sound of rockets or airplanes in the sky of Tehran so far".</p>

<p>State TV cited unnamed Iranian intelligence officials as saying that the origin of the loud explosions "could be from the activation of Iran's air defense system."</p>

<p>Iranian authorities have repeatedly warned Israel against launching an attack, saying any strike on Iran would be met with a stronger retaliation.</p>

<p>The United States was notified by Israel ahead of its strikes on targets in Iran but was not involved in the operation, a U.S. official told Reuters.</p>

<p>"We understand that Israel is conducting targeted strikes against military targets in Iran as an exercise of self-defense and in response to Iran's ballistic missile attack against Israel on October 1st," said White House National Security Council spokesperson Sean Savett.</p>

<p>Washington is seeking to head off further widening of the conflict. U.S. Secretary of State Antony Blinken said on Wednesday that Israel's retaliation should not lead to greater escalation.</p>

<p>Syrian state TV said explosions were also heard in the Damascus countryside and central region.</p>

<p>Israel's defense minister said this week that enemies would "pay a heavy price" for trying to harm Israel.</p>

<p>In the past few weeks Israel has intensified its offensive against Palestinian militants Hamas in Gaza and its Iran-backed ally Hezbollah in Lebanon. The war was triggered a year ago by Hamas' Oct. 7, 2023, attack on southern Israel.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/e9qjrljg_iran-attacks-on-israel_625x300_01_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel has confirmed that it is conducting air strikes on Iran.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/washington-post-says-will-not-endorse-kamala-harris-or-trump-in-election-6875662]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Washington Post Says Will Not Endorse Kamala Harris Or Trump In election]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/washington-post-says-will-not-endorse-kamala-harris-or-trump-in-election-6875662]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 26 Oct 2024 04:41:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The influential Washington Post newspaper, owned by Amazon billionaire Jeff Bezos, announced Friday it will endorse neither Democrat Kamala Harris nor Republican Donald Trump in the US presidential election.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The influential Washington Post newspaper, owned by Amazon billionaire Jeff Bezos, announced Friday it will endorse neither Democrat Kamala Harris nor Republican Donald Trump in the US presidential election.</p>

<p>CEO William Lewis said this was a return "to our roots of not endorsing presidential candidates."</p>

<p>However, the Post editorial board has endorsed candidates for much of the last four decades -- all of them Democrats -- before deciding to stay on the sidelines in one of the most polarizing elections in US history.</p>

<p>Newspaper editorials have little of their once-powerful political heft. But the Post -- whose slogan is "Democracy dies in darkness" -- is one traditional media outlet that retains influence among Washington's elite.</p>

<p>Trump's campaign quickly pounced, crowing that "Harris is so bad, The Washington Post decided to never endorse another presidential candidate again."</p>

<p>The Washington Post Guild, which represents unionized staff at the newspaper, said it was "deeply concerned."</p>

<p>"We are already seeing cancellations from once loyal readers," a statement said.</p>

<p>US media reported that a senior Post figure, editor at large Robert Kagan, had resigned in protest.</p>

<p><strong>- Billionaire owners -</strong></p>

<p>The Post's decision follows a similar move by another of the big remaining US newspapers, the Los Angeles Times.</p>

<p>The billionaire owner of the Times blocked the editorial board from issuing an endorsement for Harris, according to editorial editor Mariel Garza, who resigned in response on Wednesday.</p>

<p>According to a report by The Washington Post on its website, Bezos likewise intervened to block the board from publishing its editorial in favor of Harris. However, a source close to the Post's leadership told AFP that this "is inaccurate."</p>

<p>By contrast, The New York Times endorsed Harris in September, calling her "the only patriotic choice for president" and warning that "it is hard to imagine a candidate more unworthy to serve as president of the United States" than Trump.</p>

<p>On Friday, Harris also scored the backing of The Philadelphia Inquirer, the biggest newspaper in swing state Pennsylvania, which declared that "voters face an easy but tectonic choice."</p>

<p>The Republican got his own boost Friday from the New York Post, the Rupert Murdoch-owned tabloid, which declared that "America is ready for today's heroic Donald Trump to reclaim the presidency."</p>

<p><strong>- 'Cowardice'? -</strong></p>

<p>In a statement, The Washington Post's Lewis wrote that the paper would not make presidential endorsements again.</p>

<p>"Our job at The Washington Post is to provide through the newsroom non-partisan news for all Americans, and thought-provoking, reported views from our opinion team to help our readers make up their own minds," he said.</p>

<p>The Post has been endorsing Democratic candidates consistently as far back as the 1980s, always making clear that the editorial board works separately to the newsgathering operation -- as is typical in US news organizations.</p>

<p>The Post's former executive editor, Marty Baron, lashed out at the daily's "cowardice, with democracy as its casualty."</p>

<p>Baron said that Trump would see the decision "as an invitation to further intimidate" Bezos.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/u5a8lt48_donald-trump-kamala-harris_625x300_24_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The newspaper said it will endorse neither Kamala Harris nor Trump in the US presidential election.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chinese-hackers-targeted-phones-of-donald-trump-and-his-mate-jd-vance-report-6875520]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Chinese Hackers Targeted Phones Of Trump And His Mate JD Vance: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chinese-hackers-targeted-phones-of-donald-trump-and-his-mate-jd-vance-report-6875520]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 26 Oct 2024 03:51:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Chinese hackers have targeted phones used by Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump and his running mate J.D. Vance, US media reported Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Chinese hackers have targeted phones used by Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump and his running mate J.D. Vance, US media reported Friday.</p>

<p>The New York Times, quoting people familiar with the matter, said the hacking attempt appeared to be part of a wide-ranging intelligence collection effort by Chinese hackers.</p>

<p>The newspaper said it involved the infiltration of Verizon phone systems and investigators were seeking to determine whether any communications data was taken.</p>

<p>A person familiar with the matter said the campaign of Democratic candidate Kamala Harris and her running mate Tim Walz was also targeted.</p>

<p>Rich Young, a spokesman for Verizon, told AFP: "We are aware that a highly sophisticated nation-state actor has reportedly targeted several US telecommunications providers to gather intelligence."</p>

<p>The Times said the Trump campaign was informed this week that the former president and Vance were among a number of people inside and outside government whose phone numbers had been targeted.</p>

<p>Western cybersecurity experts believe the hacking was carried out by a Chinese group known as "Salt Typhoon," the newspaper said.</p>

<p>The Washington Post said the hacking campaign is believed to have compromised the phones of two staffers on the Trump-Vance campaign.</p>

<p>The FBI declined to comment on the reports that Trump's and Vance's phones had been targeted.</p>

<p>But the FBI and Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA) said in a joint statement that the "US government is investigating the unauthorized access to commercial telecommunications infrastructure by actors affiliated with the People's Republic of China."</p>

<p>"After the FBI identified specific malicious activity targeting the sector, the FBI and (CISA) immediately notified affected companies, rendered technical assistance, and rapidly shared information to assist other potential victims," they said.</p>

<p>"Agencies across the US Government are collaborating to aggressively mitigate this threat and are coordinating with our industry partners to strengthen cyber defenses across the commercial communications sector," they added.</p>

<p>The United States charged three Iranians last month with involvement in a hacking effort targeting the Trump campaign.</p>

<p>In 2016, a hack of Democratic National Committee emails -- blamed on Russians -- exposed internal party communications, including about candidate Hillary Clinton.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/7u2cgrg8_jd-vance-donald-trump-_625x300_30_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Washington Post reported that phones of two staffers from Trump-Vance campaign were also compromised.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-heckled-by-pro-palestinian-protester-at-rally-in-arizona-6875172]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["How Can You...": Biden Heckled By Pro-Palestinian Protester At Rally]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-heckled-by-pro-palestinian-protester-at-rally-in-arizona-6875172]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 26 Oct 2024 01:59:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[President Joe Biden formally apologized on Friday for the U.S. government's role in running abusive Native American boarding schools for more than 150 years, and was heckled at the event over his support for Israel's war in Gaza.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;President Joe Biden formally apologized on Friday for the U.S. government's role in running abusive Native American boarding schools for more than 150 years, and was heckled at the event over his support for Israel's war in Gaza.</p>

<p>"This to me is one of the most consequential things I've ever had an opportunity to do in my whole career," Biden said in his apology at an outdoor football and track field in Laveen Village, Arizona, near Phoenix.</p>

<p>"It's a sin on our soul. ... I formally apologize."</p>

<p>Several hundred people attended, many of them in traditional tribal dress. They cheered as Biden apologized for the generational trauma faced by the Native American community due to the boarding schools across the country.</p>

<p>Biden faced a brief interruption when a pro-Palestinian protester shouted: "How can you apologize for a genocide while committing a genocide in Palestine?"</p>

<p>The president replied, "There is a lot of innocent people being killed and it has to stop."</p>

<p>U.S. support for Israel's wars in Gaza and Lebanon after the Oct. 7, 2023, Hamas attack on Israel has led to months of demonstrations across the United States. Rights advocates have demanded an arms embargo against Israel as tens of thousands of civilians have been killed in the region, and Palestinians in the Gaza Strip have grappled with hunger and disease.</p>

<p>Israel and Washington deny genocide allegations brought against Israel at the World Court in relation to Gaza, and Washington has maintained its support for its ally.</p>

<p>Friday's trip marked Biden's first time visiting Indian Country while in office and is part of his effort to cement his legacy in his final months in the White House.</p>

<p>Arizona is also one of the seven battleground states in a tight race for the Nov. 5 U.S. election in which Democratic Vice President Kamala Harris faces Republican former President Donald Trump.</p>

<p>U.S. Interior Secretary Deb Haaland, the first Native American to be a cabinet secretary, had launched an investigation to recognize the troubled legacy of federal Native American boarding school policies.</p>

<p>An Interior Department investigative report released in July found that at least 973 children died in these schools. Haaland's family members were among the children forced into the boarding schools.</p>

<p>From 1819 through the 1970s, the United States implemented policies establishing and supporting hundreds of American Indian boarding schools across the U.S. Their purpose was to culturally assimilate Native Americans by forcibly removing them from their families, communities, religions and cultural beliefs.</p>

<p>Like the United States, Australia, New Zealand and Canada have in recent years reviewed past abuse toward Indigenous communities, including children in schools.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/dm0i5fd_joe-biden_625x300_26_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Joe Biden was heckled at the event over his support for Israel's war in Gaza.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-army-says-strike-that-killed-journalists-in-lebanon-under-review-6875030]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Army Says Strike That Killed Journalists In Lebanon "Under Review"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-army-says-strike-that-killed-journalists-in-lebanon-under-review-6875030]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 26 Oct 2024 01:09:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Israeli army said Friday that a strike that killed three journalists in south Lebanon was "under review", maintaining that it had targeted Hezbollah militants.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Israeli army said Friday that a strike that killed three journalists in south Lebanon was "under review", maintaining that it had targeted Hezbollah militants.</p>

<p>"Earlier today, following intelligence information, the IDF (army) struck a Hezbollah military structure in Hasbaya in southern Lebanon," the military said in a statement to AFP.</p>

<p>"The strike was carried out while the terrorists were located inside the structure," it added.</p>

<p>"Several hours after the strike, reports were received that journalists had been hit during the strike. The incident is under review."</p>

<p>Lebanese television channel Al Mayadeen said a cameraman and broadcast engineer were killed in the strike in Hasbaya, which according to the Pro-Iran network targeted a journalists' residence.</p>

<p>Another TV outlet, Al-Manar, run by Hezbollah, said one of its video journalists was also killed.</p>

<p>After the strike, a car bearing a "press" marking was crushed under debris.</p>

<p>Lebanon's Prime Minister Najib Mikati accused Israel of intentionally targeting the journalists in what he called a "war crime" that "aims to terrorise the media to cover up crimes and destruction".</p>

<p>Israel expanded its focus to Lebanon last month, after nearly a year of war in Gaza sparked by Hamas's attack, launching a massive bombing campaign targeting mainly Hezbollah strongholds across the country and sending in ground troops on September 30.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/nh1vl9go_lebanon_625x300_22_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Another TV outlet, Al-Manar, run by Hezbollah, said one of its video journalists was also killed.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sanjay-verma-india-canada-alberta-was-attacked-by-khalistanis-with-sharp-object-recalled-envoy-to-canada-6872258]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Was Attacked By Khalistanis With Sharp Object: Recalled Envoy To Canada]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sanjay-verma-india-canada-alberta-was-attacked-by-khalistanis-with-sharp-object-recalled-envoy-to-canada-6872258]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 26 Oct 2024 00:28:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Recalled Indian High Commissioner to Canada Sanjay Kumar Verma on Friday shared a terrifying moment when Khalistani 'goons' came very close to bodily harm him and attacked him with a 'sharp object' - most likely a 'kirpan' - in Alberta.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Recalled Indian High Commissioner to Canada Sanjay Kumar Verma on Friday shared a terrifying moment when Khalistani 'goons' came very close to bodily harm him and attacked him with a 'sharp object' - most likely a 'kirpan' - in Alberta that could potentially harm him.</p>

<p>In a podcast with ANI, Sanjay Verma shared his experience of threats and intimidation from the Khalistanis.</p>

<p>Sanjay Verma said, "All these attempts to harm me bodily, that was in the presence of Royal Canadian Mounted Police (RCMP) and the local police and the local police on the ground took immediate action, pushed him away because there was a sharp weapon and the RCMP then whisked me from the side door to the venue."</p>

<p>"It was in Alberta. I am not an expert on Canadian law about open carrying so I will not be able to say that. But most likely they would have said that it was 'kirpan' which is a small blade whereas they had swords in their hand. They could come very, very close to me," said Mr Verma.</p>

<p>When asked if the incident was reported, Sanjay Verma said, "It was all reported and we were told that investigations are on."</p>

<p>Speaking of intimidation from the Khalistanis, Sanjay Verma said that the intimidation came through banned organisations associated with the Khalistani extremists.</p>

<p>"Some came through emails during the so-called protests, which I call hooliganism when they gathered in front of the two consulates or the High Commission. They would shout slogans to intimidate us. Whenever we were attending public events, again, they would shout slogans to intimidate us," he said.</p>

<p>Sharing an incident, Sanjay Verma said, "In one instance, close to Diwali, they created 10 heads for me, called me Ravan. And then my effigy was burnt as Ravan. Is that not hate speech? Then they created another poster of mine. And they riddled it with bullets. Is that not hate speech? Then what is it?"</p>

<p>"I reported this to the foreign ministry. The response was that we forwarded it to the relevant authorities, which is correct. We also do the same. But the report never came back. Okay. So we presume that nothing happened. So we presume that it went into a black box. Not to come out," he stated.</p>

<p>When asked if he, at any point, felt threatened physically,&nbsp;Sanjay Verma replied, "Threatened, yes. But did I become threatened? No. In most of my public events, there will be these hooligans outside shouting slogans against India, but also against me. Some of them are very burly-looking tall guys who would also gesture to physically harm me, but just the gestures, except for a few incidents. And so they tried."</p>

<p>"They came close to me. They tried to intimidate me through such, slogans shouting, and abusing me verbally. That was reported," he stated.</p>

<p>Speaking about his security, Sanjay Verma said, "I had Canadian security, both federal and local."</p>

<p>Asked about whether he, at any time, doubted their ability to protect him, he replied, "No, that I won't say. They were very professional, well-trained, and very respectful. So as far as the police officers who were protecting us and now protecting my colleagues there, very, very professional, never had an iota of doubt on their professionalism."</p>

<p>He added, "But unfortunately, the statement which we saw in the Royal Canadian Mounted Police press briefing, where even the investigation has not been concluded, that was a sad thing to see."</p>

<p>Mr Verma said that he was there to serve India's national interest and was committed to doing so.</p>

<p>"So diplomacy for most of us would be, you know, being nice, nice cities. But then the final objective of diplomacy happens to be to safeguard your national interest. National interest could be improving relationships. National interest could be raising awareness against these Khalistani goons. All these are national interests," he said.</p>

<p>"So we work for the national interests. It so happened that my national interest was a bit different than the national interest of most other ambassadors in other countries," said Sanjay Verma.</p>

<p>Mr Verma was recalled from Canada after the country said he was a person of interest in the case of the murder of Khalistani terrorist Hardeep Singh Nijjar. He denied all charges.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The ties between India and Canada soured after Prime Minister Justin Trudeau alleged in the Canadian Parliament last year that he had "credible allegations" of India's hand in the killing of Nijjar.<br />
India has denied all the allegations, calling them "absurd" and "motivated" and has accused Canada of giving space to extremist and anti-India elements in their country.</p>

<p>Nijjar, who was designated a terrorist by India's National Investigation Agency in 2020, was shot and killed outside a Gurdwara in Surrey in June last year.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/7bglg9j8_sanjay-verma_625x300_26_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mr Verma said he was in Canada to serve India's national interest.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/dali-indian-crew-ship-firms-us-agree-on-cost-payment-over-collapse-of-baltimore-bridge-6872029]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ship Firms, US Agree On 'Cost Payment' Over Collapse Of Baltimore Bridge]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/dali-indian-crew-ship-firms-us-agree-on-cost-payment-over-collapse-of-baltimore-bridge-6872029]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 26 Oct 2024 00:01:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ship management firm Synergy Marine and Grace Ocean, owner of the ship with 22 Indian crew members that collided with a US bridge in March, have reached an "agreement" with the US government on cost payment, while rejecting liability for the incident]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ship management firm Synergy Marine and Grace Ocean, owner of the Singapore-flagged cargo ship with 22 Indian crew members that collided with a US bridge in March, have reached an "agreement" with the US government on cost payment, while rejecting liability for the incident.</p>

<p>Container ship 'DALI', with an all-Indian crew of 22 members onboard, had collided with one of the pillars of the Francis Scott Key Bridge in Baltimore in March this year. The crew had issued a mayday call before the collision that led to the collapse of bridge, prompting authorities to limit traffic movement.</p>

<p>"We confirm that Grace Ocean and Synergy have reached an agreement with the United States regarding the payment of those costs, which are fully insured," Synergy Marine Group said in a statement on Friday.</p>

<p>"The settlement strictly covers costs related to clearing the channel, which we would have been responsible for in any case, and is not indicative of any liability, which we expressly reject for the incident that led to the collapse of the Francis Scott Key Bridge," it stated.</p>

<p>According to the statement, Grace Ocean and Synergy are prepared to vigorously defend themselves in the limitation of liability proceedings pending before the Federal Court in Baltimore and to establish that they were not responsible for the incident.</p>

<p>Synergy Marine Group also said "no punitive damages have been imposed as part of the settlement".</p>

<p>"In accordance with the settlement, the United States has dismissed its claim," it said.</p>

<p>In the incident, the cargo ship outbound from Baltimore to Colombo, rammed into one of the pillars of the bridge, while under pilotage with two pilots onboard. Shortly after the collision, the bridge collapsed, crashing on the cargo ship.</p>

<p>Following the disembarkation of crew members from the vessel, Synergy Marine and Grace Ocean have put measures in place to support their well-being, the company said and added the 11 crew members who disembarked in Baltimore and Norfolk in June 2024 are accommodated in serviced apartments in Baltimore.</p>

<p>One crew member was granted approval by the US government to return to India for a family ceremony. The US government further granted an extension to this crew member, who is expected to return to the US in mid-November, to further assist with the ongoing investigation, Synergy Marine said.</p>

<p>Besides, two other crew members who were granted approvals by the US government to return to India for family reasons have joined their colleagues in the US, the company said.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/7r3333hg_baltimore-bridge-afp_625x300_19_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Container ship 'DALI' had collided with one of the pillars of the Francis Scott Key Bridge in March.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>