<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Dec 2024 12:30:01 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nepals-janakpur-prepares-for-sita-ram-vivah-mahotsav-amid-tight-security-7166548]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Nepal's Janakpur Prepares For 'Sita Ram Vivah Mahotsav' Amid Tight Security]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nepals-janakpur-prepares-for-sita-ram-vivah-mahotsav-amid-tight-security-7166548]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Dec 2024 12:28:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The city of Janakpur in Nepal prepares itself for the 'Sita Ram Vivah Mahotsav' amid tight security.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The city of Janakpur in Nepal prepares itself for the 'Sita Ram Vivah Mahotsav' amid tight security. Janakpur, which is the maternal house of Goddess Sita, also got a facelift for the occasion with artists painting murals on the walls around the city depicting the scenes from the holy scripture of Ramayana, giving a fresher and new look to the ancient city.</p>

<p>On November 26, Lord Ram's 'Baraat Yatra' (wedding procession) began from Ayodhya's Ramsevak Puram and reached Janakpur on Tuesday evening.</p>

<p>The wedding rituals will take place on December 4 and 5 as per the culture of Mithila, and on December 6 is Lord Ram's Vivaah Panchami.</p>

<p>On December 7, following the conclusion of the wedding, 'Kalevar' will be organised, and on December 8, 'baraat' will depart from Janakpur and reach Ayodhya on the night of December 9.</p>

<p>Speaking on the security arrangements on the occasion, Dhanusa District Sub Inspector Bhuvaneshwar Tiwari said that the district had prepared a comprehensive security plan for the Ram Janaki Vivaah Panchami.</p>

<p>He stated that the district police office, along with the district security committee, local government, and other security agencies, has coordinated efforts to ensure safety during the event.</p>

<p>A total of 1461 police personnel from Nepal Police, more than 750 personnel from the armed police forces, and other security agencies had been deployed, and reinforcements had also been provided by the Madhesh Pradesh Police Office.</p>

<p>"Dhanusa District Police office, along with the district security committee and other security agencies and in collaboration with the local government, we have prepared an extensive and comprehensive security plan for the Ram Janaki Vivaah Panchami... We have deployed police from the district police office. We have reinforcement from the Madhesh Pradesh Police Office," Tiwari said.</p>

<p>"We have deployed 1461 police personnel from Nepal Police and more than 750 police personnel from armed police forces and other security agencies. The Nepal Army and the National Investigation Division will also be deployed. We are in close cooperation with local youth clubs... We have separate traffic management plans and evacuation plans. We have a stampede prevention plan. We have also planned for emergencies and such unexpected events," he added.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/dbav44lo_-sita-ram-vivah-mahotsav_625x300_04_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The wedding rituals will take place on December 4 and 5 as per the culture of Mithila.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/depleted-by-war-ukraine-gives-absconding-soldiers-second-chance-7168654]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Depleted By War, Ukraine Gives Absconding Soldiers Second Chance]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/depleted-by-war-ukraine-gives-absconding-soldiers-second-chance-7168654]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Dec 2024 12:26:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[As Ukraine's military struggles to find enough troops, particularly infantry, to hold off Russia's much larger army, some units are giving a second chance to those who have absconded from service.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As Ukraine's military struggles to find enough troops, particularly infantry, to hold off Russia's much larger army, some units are giving a second chance to those who have absconded from service.</p>

<p>Data from the prosecutor's office shows nearly 95,000 criminal cases have been opened since 2022 against soldiers going "absent without leave" (AWOL) and for the more serious crime of battlefield desertion.</p>

<p>The number of cases has risen steeply with each year of the war: almost two-thirds of the total are from 2024. With many tens of thousands of troops killed or wounded, it is a depletion that Ukraine can ill afford.</p>

<p>Now, some units are replenishing their ranks by accepting soldiers previously declared AWOL.</p>

<p>One of them is Ukraine's elite 47th Brigade, which published a social media post last month inviting soldiers who had absconded to join.</p>

<p>"Our aim is to give every soldier the opportunity to come back into the fold and realise his potential," the post announced. In the first two days, the brigade said, over a hundred applications came in.</p>

<p>"There was a tsunami of applications; so many that we still aren't able to process them all before new ones come in," Viacheslav Smirnov, the 47th's head of recruitment, said two weeks after the announcement.</p>

<p>Two military units Reuters spoke to said they were only recruiting soldiers who had gone AWOL from their bases, rather than those who had deserted from combat.</p>

<p>The former is seen within the Ukrainian military as a lesser offence. A bill recently signed into law has in effect decriminalised a soldier's first disappearance, allowing them to return to service.</p>

<p><strong>Thousands Of Ukrainian Soldiers Rejoin After Absconding</strong></p>

<p>Colonel Oleksandr Hrynchuk, deputy head of Ukraine's military police, told reporters on Tuesday that 6,000 AWOL soldiers had returned to service in the last month, including 3,000 in the 72 hours since the law was signed.</p>

<p>Mykhailo Perets, an officer from the K-2 battalion of Ukraine's 54th Brigade, said his battalion had already hired over 30 men who had gone AWOL from other units.</p>

<p>"The reasons [for absconding] are very different: for some people it was too tough a transition straight from civilian life, others served for a year or two as qualified [drone] pilots but were then sent to the front line because there wasn't enough infantry."</p>

<p>Perets said those who had applied also included men who had become exhausted and run away after being at war for seven or eight years, having fought Russian-backed forces in eastern Ukraine before 2022.</p>

<p>Gil Barndollar, a non-resident fellow at the U.S.-based Defense Priorities think tank, said the increase in unauthorised absences was most likely driven by exhaustion.</p>

<p>Ukrainian service personnel have previously said how the lack of replacements for lost soldiers puts an unbearable strain on those remaining, exhausting them physically and mentally.</p>

<p>Barndollar also highlighted their average age as an additional strain.</p>

<p>"An army of men, often in poor health, in their 40s, all else being equal, is going to get exhausted sooner and is going to have morale problems faster than a reasonably fit army of 20- or 25-year-olds."</p>

<p>Zelenskiy has responded to questions about the manpower problem by arguing that Ukraine lacks weapons rather than people, and pushed back against U.S. pressure to lower the minimum draft age to 18 from 25.</p>

<p>He said in an interview with Sky News last week that Kyiv's allies had been able to provide the necessary equipment for only a quarter of the 10 new brigades Ukraine had formed over the past year.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/kj5u55cg_ukraine-building-damaged-reuters_625x300_04_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The number of cases has risen steeply with each year of the war.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/indians-abroad/shocking-video-captures-indian-american-family-facing-racist-attack-7168793]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Shocking Video Captures Indian-American Family Facing Racist Attack]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/indians-abroad/shocking-video-captures-indian-american-family-facing-racist-attack-7168793]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Dec 2024 12:22:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Indian American photographer Pervez Taufiq shares a disturbing incident where his family was subjected to a racist rant on a United Airlines shuttle bus.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Famous Indian American photographer Pervez Taufiq is speaking out about a distressing event that he recorded on camera, where a woman on a United Airlines shuttle bus used a racist slur to verbally harass his family.</p>

<p>Just before Thanksgiving, Taufiq, 50, was flying from Mexico to Los Angeles with his wife and three kids when the woman attacked them, calling them "un-American" and using derogatory names like "tandoori" and "stinky" against them.</p>

<p>Taufiq, a well-known wedding photographer whose work has appeared in high-end magazines, posted the footage on his Instagram page to draw attention to the incident.</p>

<p>The argument apparently started between the woman and Taufiq's son aboard the aeroplane bus. On the shuttle bus, things got out of hand.</p>

<p><strong>Watch the video here:</strong></p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DCvmyM-R0MP/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DCvmyM-R0MP/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DCvmyM-R0MP/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DCvmyM-R0MP/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by Pervez Taufiq (@ptaufiqphotography)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p>Video footage shows the woman saying to Taufiq, "Your family is from India; you have no respect, you have no rules, you think you can push everyone, push, push, push. That's what you think you are. You guys are f****** crazy." She also threatened to record his "f-king tandoori a**" after Taufiq referenced earlier comments she made about curry.</p>

<p>"Mortified, we just went through this. This lady was harassing our son on the flight, unbeknownst to us, asking him if he was Indian and making comments. When we landed in LA and got on the transfer bus, she told our son to "shut up." I told her she doesn't have a right to speak to my son that way, and her husband got in my face trying to tell me to not speak to his wife," Taufiq wrote in the caption.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/7qq5np78_shocking-video-captures-indianamerican-family-facing-racist-attack_625x300_04_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A woman hurled racist slurs at Taufiq's family.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/croatia-parents-arrested-over-fatal-neglect-of-two-toddlers-7168728]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Croatia Parents Arrested Over Fatal Neglect Of Two Toddlers]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/croatia-parents-arrested-over-fatal-neglect-of-two-toddlers-7168728]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Dec 2024 12:18:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Croatian police arrested on Tuesday a couple suspected of fatal neglect and abuse of their two toddlers whose bodies were found buried next to their house, a minister said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Croatian police arrested on Tuesday a couple suspected of fatal neglect and abuse of their two toddlers whose bodies were found buried next to their house, a minister said.</p>

<p>The spouses are suspected of "grossly neglecting" their three children due to which two, most likely around 12 months old, have died, Interior Minister Davor Bozinovic told reporters.</p>

<p>The parents, aged 38 and 34, buried the bodies of the toddlers at the family property in the region of the northwestern town of Varazdin, he said.</p>

<p>Local media reported that the remains were buried at the family house yard.</p>

<p>Police were "deeply shocked and horrified" with results of their investigation that had been launched into possible neglect and abuse of the three children by their parents, the minister added.</p>

<p>The bodies of the two toddlers were exhumed earlier Tuesday and the cause of their death will be determinated by an autopsy.</p>

<p>Due to suspicion of neglect and abuse the couple's third child was taken over by social services, the minister said.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/hm81ri38_arrest-generic-image_625x300_03_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Due to suspicion of neglect and abuse the couple's third child was taken over by social services.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/thousands-of-us-government-employees-get-work-from-home-deal-ahead-of-trump-7168710]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Thousands Of US Government Employees Get WFH Deal Ahead Of Trump]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/thousands-of-us-government-employees-get-work-from-home-deal-ahead-of-trump-7168710]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Dec 2024 12:13:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Biden administration appointee has agreed to lock in hybrid work protections for tens of thousands of Social Security staff.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Biden administration appointee has agreed to lock in hybrid work protections for tens of thousands of Social Security staff, part of a slew of organized labor efforts that complicate President-elect Donald Trump's efforts to reshape the federal workforce.</p>

<p>The American Federation of Government Employees, a union representing 42,000 Social Security Administration workers, reached an agreement with the agency last week that will protect telework until 2029 in an updated contract, according to a message to its members viewed by Bloomberg.</p>

<p>The new deal, signed by President Joe Biden's just-departed SSA Commissioner Martin O'Malley, will let workers "maintain current levels of telework," AFGE chapter president Rich Couture wrote.</p>

<p>Under those current arrangements, in-office requirements range from two to five days per week, varying by job, according to people familiar who spoke on condition of anonymity because the new agreement has not been publicized.</p>

<p>"This deal will secure not just telework for SSA employees, but will secure staffing levels through prevention of higher attrition, which in turn will secure the ability of the Agency to serve the public," Couture wrote.</p>

<p>An AFGE spokesperson declined to elaborate on the message. A SSA spokesperson confirmed the independent agency "memorialized its preexisting telework policy in its contract with AFGE," and noted that managers can still make temporary changes based on operational needs or performance issues.</p>

<p>Unions have been pushing the outgoing Biden administration to extend existing collective bargaining agreements with federal workers in advance of Trump's inauguration next month, according to people familiar with the discussions who spoke on condition of anonymity to discuss private conversations. Some union leaders are urging the current White House team to issue an executive order calling for such moves.</p>

<p>A federal Office of Management and Budget spokesperson declined to comment.</p>

<p>Trump has asked billionaire Elon Musk and entrepreneur Vivek Ramaswamy to lead a new task force aimed at cutting government spending and streamlining operations called the "Department of Government Efficiency." Musk and Ramaswamy have said they plan to cull the federal workforce and eliminate work-from-home policies.</p>

<p>"Requiring federal employees to come to the office five days a week would result in a wave of voluntary terminations that we welcome," they wrote in a Wall Street Journal op-ed last month.</p>

<p>The Trump transition team declined to comment directly on the union contracts.</p>

<p>"Under President Trump's leadership, the Government Efficiency effort led by Vivek and Elon will target waste and fraud throughout our massive federal bureaucracy," spokesperson Brian Hughes said. "They will work together slashing excess regulations, cutting wasteful expenditures, and restructuring Federal Agencies."</p>

<p>Organized labor represents over a million federal government employees, and AFGE is the largest federal worker union. Legally-binding union contracts, which dictate terms on working conditions, can be amended during, or extended beyond, their existing timeframes.</p>

<p>While they don't supersede federal law, contract terms can restrict agencies' discretion over how to manage their staff.</p>

<p>AFGE members at the Environmental Protection Agency in May ratified a contract with management that includes new "scientific integrity" safeguards meant to protect their ability to discuss their work with the media and report alleged scientific misconduct without suffering from retaliation. Attorneys at the Department of Justice have been organizing with another group, the National Treasury Employees Union, trying to secure union recognition before Biden leaves office.</p>

<p>Collective bargaining agreements may not deter Trump, Musk or Ramaswamy, who have signaled they plan to challenge precedents limiting executive authority. But reneging on a contract could lead to protracted legal disputes, as well as protests and pushback from lawmakers.</p>

<p>A US president "can't just set aside lawfully signed collective bargaining agreements, without the unions' agreement," Indiana University law professor Kenneth G. Dau-Schmidt said via email. "The US government has to live up to its agreements, too."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-02/4qr1mt3_the-white-house-unsplash_625x300_17_February_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Biden administration appointee has agreed to lock in hybrid work protections for thousands of staff.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mcdonalds-e-coli-outbreak-related-to-fresh-onions-is-over-7168605]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[McDonald's E. Coli Outbreak Related To Fresh Onions Is Over]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mcdonalds-e-coli-outbreak-related-to-fresh-onions-is-over-7168605]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Dec 2024 11:54:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An E. coli outbreak that ensnared McDonald's Corp. is over, the US Centers for Disease Control and Prevention said Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An E. coli outbreak that ensnared McDonald's Corp. is over, the US Centers for Disease Control and Prevention said Tuesday.</p>

<p>Fresh, slivered onions at McDonald's were the likely source of the outbreak, the CDC said, in line with previous reports. Beef had been ruled out earlier as the potential cause.</p>

<p>The Food and Drug Administration also said Tuesday that it had closed its investigation. The announcements give "certainty and validation from leading health authorities, which will be meaningful for our customers and communities," McDonald's said.</p>

<p>A total of 104 people in 14 states reported illnesses, according to the CDC. However, the ultimate number of sickened individuals was likely much larger because many recover without medical care and aren't tested for E. coli. McDonald's had stopped sourcing onions from a Colorado facility of supplier Taylor Farms, which issued a recall after the outbreak.</p>

<p>It's not yet clear how or at what stage E. coli entered the supply chain, a McDonald's spokesperson said in a media briefing. That's why the chain has stopped sourcing from both the facility that processed the onions and the farm where they originated, the representative said.</p>

<p>McDonald's said it's working with industry groups and health officials to see if additional checks are needed for produce, adding that it's confident in its supply-chain processes.</p>

<p>The chain disclosed the outbreak on Oct. 22 and temporarily yanked Quarter Pounders, which have the slivered onions, from many restaurants. It also pledged to spend $100 million to revive sales and support franchisees after the E. coli news scared away many diners. Lately, the company has been seeking to bring customers in with the limited-time offer McRib and the announcement of a new value menu.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/fnvptlsg_mcdonalds-bloomberg_625x300_04_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Beef had been ruled out earlier as the potential cause.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-koreas-whirlwind-stint-in-martial-law-jolts-markets-7168583]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[South Korea's Whirlwind Stint In Martial Law Jolts Markets]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-koreas-whirlwind-stint-in-martial-law-jolts-markets-7168583]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Dec 2024 11:50:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[South Korean President Yoon Suk Yeol's surprise decision to impose martial law in South Korea for the first time in more than 40 years - and then just as swiftly reverse course - sparked whiplash in the country's foreign-traded assets.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>South Korean President Yoon Suk Yeol's surprise decision to impose martial law in South Korea for the first time in more than 40 years - and then just as swiftly reverse course - sparked whiplash in the country's foreign-traded assets and caught global markets off guard, at one point sending US Treasury yields lower as traders sought a haven from potential instability.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In an emergency address delivered live to the nation, Yoon stunned voters, lawmakers and investors alike by declaring martial law on Tuesday after accusing the opposition of trying to paralyze his administration.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The decision, Yoon said, was made to protect freedom and constitutional order, but the market's early verdict was swift: South Korean-related ETFs, its currency and most actively traded stocks all sharply weakened, while US government bonds and even Bitcoin were also briefly caught up in a risk-off flight to quality.</p>

<p>Korean shares and the won then regained some lost ground after South Korean authorities vowed to provide "unlimited liquidity" to markets as needed and lawmakers voted to request lifting the shock measure, which Yoon ultimately agreed to do. Even so, the move, however brief, created fresh uncertainties within a major economy and pillar of global trade, keeping investors on edge.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"This is clearly going to raise longer term concerns about investing in Korea," said Mark Ledger-Evans, an investment analyst at Ninety One UK Ltd. "There will need to be a higher risk premium."</p>

<p>The iShares MSCI South Korea exchange-traded fund (ticker EWY) sank as much as 7.1% in US trading, while London-listed shares of Samsung Electronics lost as much as 7.5%. The onshore Korean won weakened as much as 2.9% to 1444.65 per dollar, leading losses among currency markets amid thin trading during the New York session.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The domestic uncertainty adds to the external pressures in recent weeks as the market is starting to price in the rise of higher US tariffs under the new Trump administration," said Aroop Chatterjee, a strategist at Wells Fargo in New York.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Trading volume for the $3.9 billion iShares MSCI South Korea ETF reached a record for any full day in the fund's more than 20-year lifespan. About 32 million shares traded as of 1:45 p.m. in New York, about 17 times the 20-day average for this time of day.</p>

<p>Other South Korean ADRs also declined. E-commerce company Coupang Inc. fell as much as 9.8% in US trading, alongside losses in steel processor Posco Holdings Inc. and KB Financial Group Inc. The Korea Exchange, the nation's main stock bourse, said Wednesday trading is under review.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>What Bloomberg Strategists Say ...</strong></p>

<p>"While the knee-jerk reaction to South Korea's martial law declaration has largely been contained to local assets, there are still global repercussions for investors to watch given the nation's extensive trade relationships. Globally, markets are well aware of how political discord over budgets can roil financial assets."</p>

<p>- Nour Al Ali, macro markets and squawk, London</p>

<p>The onshore won pared some of its losses, ending the session at 1428.50 per dollar. Still the currency remains the worst performer in Asia this year, weakening by more than 9%.</p>

<p>"Martial law feels like a bit of overkill," said Mark McCormick, global head of FX and EM strategy at TD Securities in Toronto. "Seems like the goal is deflection, reflecting low approval ratings and a fair amount of scandals. Policymakers like to keep a grip on KRW, so I would expect some of the volatility to settle down after today's big move."&nbsp;</p>

<p>Tuesday's is the first overnight shock for the won, which began trading extended hours in July amid authorities' broad push to get its stocks and bonds included in more global indexes. Previously, trading in the currency was halted at 3:30 p.m. local time.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Investors should go long the US dollar as the uncertainty persists, said Win Thin, global head of markets strategy at Brown Brothers Harriman.</p>

<p>"President Yoon may have overplayed his hand but the situation remains fluid," he said. "Coups in South Korea were a real thing when I was growing up but I think most (including me) believe the country had moved beyond that."&nbsp;</p>

<p>The declaration of martial law will likely compound an already protectionist zeitgeist, according to Joe Gilbert, a portfolio manager at Integrity Asset Management, adding that he believes "a viable off ramp exists to ameliorate the situation with the Korean parliament."&nbsp;</p>

<p>In the meantime, Gilbert said he's watching semiconductor stocks, which he says may be winners in the short term if there is any disruption to chip production with the South Korean behemoth Samsung.</p>

<p>South Korean financial authorities said they will use all possible measures to stabilize markets, according to a statement from the authorities. The finance ministry pledged "unlimited liquidity" to the market and the Bank of Korea said its monetary policy board will hold an extraordinary meeting on Wednesday morning.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The stock market will open as usual at 9am local time Wednesday, a Finance Ministry spokesperson said in a text message.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/nvgi07f8_south-korea-protest-bloomberg_625x300_04_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fact-check-infosys-rs-283-crore-fine-for-alleged-us-visa-fraud-is-old-news-7168571]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Fact Check: Infosys' Rs 283 Crore Fine For Alleged US Visa Fraud Is Old News]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fact-check-infosys-rs-283-crore-fine-for-alleged-us-visa-fraud-is-old-news-7168571]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Dec 2024 11:50:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A claim widely circulating on social media states that Infosys was recently fined Rs. 283 crore ($34 million) in the United States.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr" id="isPasted"><strong>What's the claim?</strong></p>

<p dir="ltr">A claim widely circulating on social media states that Infosys was recently fined Rs. 283 crore ($34 million) in the United States. It was first shared in a report by Indian news outlet Jagran English, published on December 1, 2024 (archived&nbsp;<a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20241201151715/https://english.jagran.com/world/infosys-narayana-murthy-slapped-with-rs-283-crore-penalty-for-visa-fraud-abuse-of-us-immigration-process-10204322">here</a>).&nbsp;Local news outlets like&nbsp;<a href="https://archive.is/Osr6L">NewsX</a>,&nbsp;<a href="https://archive.is/1x3aS">India.com,</a>&nbsp;<a href="https://perma.cc/UN2S-JSCK">MSN</a>, and&nbsp;<a href="https://www.puthiyathalaimurai.com/india/infosys-provided-illegal-visas-to-employees-for-profit">Puthiya Thalaimurai TV</a>&nbsp;(PTTV), a Tamil news network, also published similar details.&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">An X user&nbsp;<a href="https://archive.ph/Nqmyv">shared&nbsp;</a>the Jagran article with the caption, ”BIGGEST IMMIGRATION FRAUD Infosys slapped with a record Rs 283 crore fine in the 'biggest ever case of immigration fraud in the United States'. We are definitely not earning the international repute we should be. No news in mainstream media?”&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">At the time of writing this check, the post had reached over 1,00,000 views and over 2,000 likes. Archived versions of more such posts can be found&nbsp;<a href="https://archive.is/0voab">here</a>,&nbsp;<a href="https://perma.cc/5LDX-BZYF">here</a>, and&nbsp;<a href="https://perma.cc/7GNZ-PCSY">here</a>.</p>

<p><img src="https://logicallyfacts.com/storage/img/TEAMPICS/Kulsum/infosys2.webp" /></p>

<p><em id="isPasted">Screenshot of claims shared online. (Source: X/MSN/Modified by Logically Facts)</em></p>

<p dir="ltr">However, this claim is misleading, as the alleged fine is based on a 2013 settlement, not a recent development.</p>

<p dir="ltr"><strong>What we found</strong></p>

<p dir="ltr">At the time of writing this check, we found that the&nbsp;<a href="https://english.jagran.com/world/infosys-narayana-murthy-slapped-with-rs-283-crore-penalty-for-visa-fraud-abuse-of-us-immigration-process-10204322">Jagran article</a>&nbsp;had been updated (archived&nbsp;<a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20241201151715/https://english.jagran.com/world/infosys-narayana-murthy-slapped-with-rs-283-crore-penalty-for-visa-fraud-abuse-of-us-immigration-process-10204322">here</a>) to state that the development is not recent but dates back to 2013.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Logically Facts found no credible mainstream media outlets reporting that Infosys was recently fined $34 million in December 2024. Instead, we&nbsp;<a href="https://www.ft.com/content/2be34c42-406f-11e3-bd57-00144feabdc0">found</a>&nbsp;<a href="https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/nri/visa-and-immigration/infosys-agrees-to-pay-34-million-to-settle-visa-row-with-us/articleshow/24942466.cms?from=mdr">multiple&nbsp;</a>reports from October 2013 containing the same information that is currently circulating online. A report by&nbsp;<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2013/10/30/us/indian-tech-giant-infosys-said-to-reach-settlement-on-us-visa-fraud-claims.html">The New York Times</a>, published on October 29, 2013, elaborated how Infosys had agreed to pay a $34 million fine as part of a civil settlement. The settlement followed an investigation by federal prosecutors in Texas, who had uncovered what they described as “systemic visa fraud and abuse.”</p>

<p dir="ltr">According to an official press release from&nbsp;<a href="https://www.ice.gov/news/releases/indian-corporation-pays-record-34-million-fine-settle-allegations-systemic-visa-fraud">U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE)</a>&nbsp;(archived&nbsp;<a href="https://perma.cc/RAX7-WYPN">here</a>) on October 29, 2013, Infosys was accused of misusing B-1 visas, which are typically meant for short-term business trips. The government agency accused Infosys of bringing temporary workers from India to the U.S. for jobs that should have required H-1B visas. This misuse of the visa system was considered a violation of U.S. immigration laws. The company's actions were part of a broader pattern of alleged visa fraud, prompting U.S. authorities to take legal action.</p>

<p><img src="https://logicallyfacts.com/storage/img/TEAMPICS/Kulsum/infosys3.webp" /></p>

<p dir="ltr"><em id="isPasted">Screenshot showing the 2013 press release by ICE. (Source: ICE/Modified by Logically Facts)</em></p>

<p dir="ltr">As a result, Infosys was fined $34 million in a civil settlement to resolve the allegations. The company agreed to pay the fine and maintained that the settlement was not an admission of wrongdoing but rather a step taken to avoid prolonged legal proceedings.</p>

<p dir="ltr">In an&nbsp;<a href="https://www.infosys.com/newsroom/press-releases/2013/company-statement-official.html">official press release</a>&nbsp;(archived&nbsp;<a href="https://perma.cc/ZV29-YB8Q">here</a>) in 2013, the company denied and disputed any claims of systemic visa fraud, misuse of visas to gain a competitive advantage, or abuse of the immigration system.</p>

<p dir="ltr">This settlement of a $34 million fine resolved the legal matter. Since then, no new fines or allegations have been made against Infosys regarding visa misuse or by any U.S. government agency.</p>

<p dir="ltr"><strong>The verdict</strong></p>

<p dir="ltr">A development from 2013, when the U.S. fined Infosys Rs. 283 crore ($34 million) over charges of visa fraud, has been shared as recent.</p>

<p dir="ltr"><em>(This story was originally published by <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.logicallyfacts.com/en/fact-check/old-news-infosys-fine-34-million-visa-fraud-united-states-shared-as-recent">Logicallyfacts</a>, and republished by NDTV as part of the Shakti Collective)</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/rr6ut0to_infosys-fined-fact-check_625x300_04_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[This claim is misleading, as the alleged fine is based on a 2013 settlement.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-man-charged-with-wifes-murder-after-googling-how-long-does-it-take-to-get-married-after-spouse-dies-7168555]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Man Charged With Wife's Murder After Google Search On Remarriage]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-man-charged-with-wifes-murder-after-googling-how-long-does-it-take-to-get-married-after-spouse-dies-7168555]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Dec 2024 11:46:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Mamta was reported missing on August 5 after failing to show up for work, prompting a wellness check by local authorities.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Virginia man is facing murder charges in connection with his wife's disappearance, as disturbing details continue to emerge. Naresh Bhatt, 33, is accused of killing his wife, 28-year-old Mamta Kafle Bhatt, a native of Nepal. Prosecutors revealed that Naresh allegedly searched online for "how soon can you remarry after a spouse's death" and was seen purchasing suspicious items shortly after Mamta went missing. The investigation is ongoing,&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/12/02/us/naresh-bhatt-murder-charge/index.html" rel="noindex,nofollow"><em>CNN </em></a>reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Court records obtained by <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://people.com/naresh-bhatt-charged-with-killing-wife-mamta-kafle-bhatt-after-she-went-missing-manassas-park-8754203" rel="noindex,nofollow">People</a> show Bhatt has been charged with two felonies in the Prince William County Circuit Court. His wife, Mamta, was last seen on July 29, but her body has not been found.</p>

<p>A Virginia grand jury has indicted Bhatt, a resident of Manassas Park, on charges of murder and defiling a body after evidence surfaced suggesting foul play, including suspicious purchases and troubling online searches in the days following Mamta's disappearance.</p>

<p>Mamta was reported missing on August 5 after failing to show up for work, prompting a wellness check by local authorities. In addition to the murder charge, Bhatt faces accusations of concealing a body. He is scheduled to appear in court to respond to these charges.</p>

<p>Mamta was presumed dead shortly after being reported missing. During questioning, Bhatt told police the couple was in the process of separating. Prosecutors allege that in April, he searched for topics such as "How long does it take to get married after spouse dies," "What happens to debt after a spouse dies," and "What happens if a spouse disappears in Virginia."</p>

<p>Evidence later revealed that Bhatt bought three knives at a local Walmart, with two still unaccounted for. Surveillance footage reportedly showed him purchasing cleaning supplies at another Walmart the following day.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Prosecutors claim Bhatt discarded a bloodstained bath mat and bags into a trash compactor after his wife's disappearance. While Bhatt's attorneys argue that she is still alive, DNA evidence confirmed her blood was found in their home, suggesting she was killed and dismembered. This evidence has strengthened the case against him, despite her body not being recovered.</p>

<p>Initially, Bhatt gave unclear explanations about his wife's disappearance and delayed reporting her missing. He was arrested after a search of their home on August 22 and has remained in custody since being denied bail in September. Surveillance footage showing Bhatt disposing of trash bags has raised further suspicions that Mamta was murdered by her husband, prompting a continued search for the missing mother of one.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/3b1ppaj8_naresh-bhatt_625x300_04_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Evidence later revealed that Bhatt bought three knives at a local Walmart]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-judge-who-rejected-elon-musks-tesla-payday-faces-backlash-7168423]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Judge Who Rejected Elon Musk's Tesla Payday Faces Backlash]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-judge-who-rejected-elon-musks-tesla-payday-faces-backlash-7168423]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Dec 2024 11:30:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The social media blowback for Delaware Judge Kathaleen St. J. McCormick came fast and furious after she blocked Elon Musk's multibillion-dollar Tesla Inc. payday for a second time, spotlighting the pressure that comes with ruling against the world's]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The social media blowback for Delaware Judge Kathaleen St. J. McCormick came fast and furious after she blocked Elon Musk's multibillion-dollar Tesla Inc. payday for a second time, spotlighting the pressure that comes with ruling against the world's richest person.</p>

<p>Musk posted "absolute corruption" on X shortly after the ruling late Monday and Tesla bull Cathie Wood railed against an "activist judge at its worst" who she accused of undermining the rights of shareholders. Other backers of the billionaire dubbed McCormick's decision "insane."</p>

<p>McCormick, the Delaware Chancery Court's chief judge, is an old hand at dealing with Musk-related backlash. In January she got an earful from critics, both in online posts and letters to her chambers, when she first voided Musk's pay package on the grounds that Tesla's board was too beholden to him. Likewise back in 2022 when McCormick refused to let Musk back out of a $44 billion deal to buy X's predecessor, Twitter.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>'Amped Up'</strong></p>

<p>While judges routinely decide thorny legal issues, those determinations get more complicated when they involve the richest and most powerful personalities in the corporate world, said Eric Talley, a Columbia University law professor who focuses on corporate litigation. "Those kinds of cases are particularly amped-up," he said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>McCormick and Musk didn't respond Tuesday to requests for comment.</p>

<p>Musk's influence has reached new heights and his net worth has soared since the US presidential election because he's considered a close confidant of Donald Trump.</p>

<p>The stock options package was initially worth $2.6 billion and spiked to $56 billion by the time the judge canceled it in January. The package was worth $101.5 billion at Monday's closing price. Tesla shares fell 1.6% on Tuesday.</p>

<p>With 206 million followers on X, Musk regularly relies on his internet megaphone to whip up his fans, including legions of Tesla retail investors, into a frenzy. Scores of X users, including many who use anonymous handles, aimed their anger at McCormick for denying Musk the largest-ever pay package awarded to a corporate executive.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>'In Jail'</strong></p>

<p>"She needs to be in jail," one user named Not Jerome Powell wrote in a post, referring to the judge.</p>

<p>Musk has warned that McCormick's ruling will prompt a business exodus from Delaware, the corporate home to about two-thirds of Fortune 500 companies.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The serial entrepreneur has moved to incorporate Tesla, his rocket company SpaceX and other businesses in Texas, where he hopes to take advantage of more lax regulations and a new business-court system.&nbsp;</p>

<p>While McCormick is taking heat for her ruling, she's also reaping praise from some legal commentators for not bowing in the face of pressure over her conclusion that Tesla's board was too rife with conflicts of interest to properly decide Musk's pay.</p>

<p><strong>Courage, Integrity</strong></p>

<p>In her rulings concerning Musk, she has "shown a great deal of courage and the integrity not to back down," said Jill Fisch, a University of Pennsylvania law school professor.</p>

<p>Ann Lipton, a corporate law professor at Tulane University, said that McCormick's ruling was in line with Delaware law and reinforced the idea that Musk must be treated just like other corporate bosses.</p>

<p>"Many of Musk's supporters and admirers believe corporate managers like him shouldn't be restrained," Lipton said. Being the first woman chief judge in Chancery also makes McCormick a high-profile target, she added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Wedbush analyst Daniel Ives said in a note to investors that McCormick's ruling wasn't a surprise and may not be the final word on Musk's pay. Tesla has already said it plans to appeal.</p>

<p>"This continues to be a soap opera playing out in Delaware."</p>

<p>The case is Tornetta v. Musk, 2018-0408, Delaware Chancery Court (Wilmington).&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/h7sq84tg_elon-musk-bloomberg_625x300_04_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Elon Musk posted "absolute corruption" on X shortly after the ruling.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-asteroid-burns-like-fireball-after-entering-atmosphere-above-russia-7168291]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Video: Asteroid Burns Like "Fireball" After Entering Atmosphere Above Russia]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-asteroid-burns-like-fireball-after-entering-atmosphere-above-russia-7168291]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Dec 2024 11:09:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A speedy descent of a small asteroid lit up the sky in Russia's remote far eastern region of Yakutia early on Wednesday, as it burned out after entering the Earth's atmosphere.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A speedy descent of a small asteroid lit up the sky in Russia's remote far eastern region of Yakutia early on Wednesday, as it burned out after entering the Earth's atmosphere. It was the first of two expected asteroid fly-bys this week and provided a natural light show for residents of northern Siberia.</p>

<p>The flying space rock was around 70 centimetres (27.5 inches) in diameter and was spotted about 12 hours in advance of its appearance in the sky, the European Space Agency said earlier Tuesday. Calling the asteroid 'harmless', the space agency said it created a "nice fireball" over Yakutia's area in northern Siberia.</p>

<p>Asteroid C0WEPC5 (temporary designation) entered the atmosphere at 1.15 a.m. local time (1615 GMT), the space agency said.</p>

<p>"Thanks to observations from astronomers around the world, our alert system was able to predict this impact to within +/- 10 seconds," the agency said.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">☄️ Asteroid <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/C0WEPC5?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#C0WEPC5</a> (temporary designation) entered Earth's atmosphere at 16:15 UTC/17:15 CET, creating a fireball over Yakutia witnessed by people in the region.<br />
<br />
The object was discovered roughly 12 hours ago and is thought to have been around 70 cm across.<br />
<br />
Thanks to… <a href="https://t.co/ohya9xsEak">https://t.co/ohya9xsEak</a></p>
— European Space Agency (@esa) <a href="https://twitter.com/esa/status/1864002072238035014?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 3, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Residents of the eastern Russian republic of Yakutia shared their sightings of lightballs on social media. Videos showed the celestial rock on fire, appearing like a ball of fire, as it entered the atmosphere.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">A few minutes ago: Asteroid <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/C0WEPC5?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#C0WEPC5</a> Sighting Reported in Olekminsk, Russia.<br />
<br />
Source: Telegram <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/asteroid?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#asteroid</a> <a href="https://t.co/q5RTrMWLDz">pic.twitter.com/q5RTrMWLDz</a></p>
— Weather monitor (@Weathermonitors) <a href="https://twitter.com/Weathermonitors/status/1863993573932191970?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 3, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The emergencies ministry in Yakutia said all official bodies were placed on alert as the asteroid approached but that no damage had been reported after its descent.</p>

<p>"Residents of Olekminsk and Lensk districts were able to observe in the night a tail similar to a comet and a flash," it said.</p>

<p>"A small one, but (asteroid) it will still be quite spectacular, visible for hundreds of kilometres," astronomer Alan Fitzsimmons of Queen's University in Belfast, told New Scientist magazine before the fireball appeared.</p>

<p>Nasa credited the University of Arizona's Bok telescope for the discovery of the asteroid. "At 11.14 am EST, a very small asteroid will impact the Earth's atmosphere and create a harmless fireball over eastern Russia's Olyokminsky district," the American space agency said on Tuesday.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/5ob7b48_russia-asteroids-reuters_625x300_04_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Asteroid C0WEPC5 (temporary designation) entered the atmosphere at 1.15 a.m. local time.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/bbcs-100-inspiring-women-of-2024-aruna-roy-vinesh-phogat-and-pooja-sharma-among-bbcs-100-inspiring-women-of-2024-7167796]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[3 Indians Among BBC's 100 Inspiring Women Of 2024]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/bbcs-100-inspiring-women-of-2024-aruna-roy-vinesh-phogat-and-pooja-sharma-among-bbcs-100-inspiring-women-of-2024-7167796]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Dec 2024 11:07:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Three Indians have made it to the list of BBC's 100 Most Influential and Inspiring Women of 2024.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Three Indians have made it to the list of <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/resources/idt-4f79d09b-655a-42f8-82b4-9b2ecebab611 " rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">BBC</a>'s 100 Most Influential and Inspiring Women of 2024. Social activist Aruna Roy, wrestler-turned-politician Vinesh Phogat, and funerary rites pioneer Pooja Sharma have joined a stellar lineup that includes stranded astronaut Sunita Williams, Hollywood actress Sharon Stone, rape survivor Gisele Pelicot, Nobel Peace laureate Nadia Murad, and climate activist Adenike Oladosu.<br />
<br />
<strong>Aruna Roy, Social Activist</strong><br />
<br />
Social activist Aruna Roy has dedicated over four decades to championing the rights of India's rural poor. A former civil servant, Ms Roy co-founded the Mazdoor Kisan Shakti Sangathan (MKSS), an organisation advocating for transparency, fair wages, and government accountability. Her efforts were instrumental in enacting India's Right to Information Act in 2005.<br />
<br />
As president of the National Federation of Indian Women, Ms Roy continues to lead grassroots movements and published her memoir, The Personal is Political, earlier this year.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
<strong>Vinesh Phogat, Olympic Wrestler</strong><br />
<br />
Vinesh Phogat, a three-time Olympian and one of India's most decorated wrestlers, has been a strong voice against gender bias in sports. She has earned medals in the World Championships, Commonwealth Games, and Asian Games.<br />
<br />
This year, she became India's first female wrestler to reach an Olympic final but was disqualified after being 100 grams over the weight limit. Following this, Ms Phogat retired from wrestling and ventured into politics.<br />
<br />
Known for speaking out against gender stereotypes, she led a prominent protest by Indian wrestlers against former Indian Wrestling Federation chief Brij Bhushan Sharan Singh, who was accused of sexually harassing female athletes – a charge he denied. The protest gained national attention when Ms Phogat and others were detained by police during a demonstration.<br />
<br />
<strong>Pooja Sharma, Performer Of Funeral Rites</strong><br />
<br />
Pooja Sharma has redefined societal norms by performing funerary rites for unclaimed bodies – a role traditionally reserved for men in Hindu culture – in Delhi. Her mission began after the death of her brother, whose final rites she had to perform alone.<br />
<br />
She is the founder of Bright The Soul Foundation and in the past three years, Ms Sharma has conducted over 4,000 last rites for people from various religions.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/9j9vq19g_aruna-roy-vinesh-phogat-and-pooja-sharma_625x300_04_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Social activist Aruna Roy, Olympic Wrestler Vinesh Phogat and Performer Of Funeral Rites Pooja Sharma.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/after-donald-trump-win-linkedin-co-founder-reid-hoffman-considering-leaving-us-report-7168171]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[After Trump Win, LinkedIn Co-Founder Considering Leaving US: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/after-donald-trump-win-linkedin-co-founder-reid-hoffman-considering-leaving-us-report-7168171]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Dec 2024 10:48:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[LinkedIn co-founder Reid Hoffman is considering leaving the United States after Republican nominee Donald Trump defeated his Democrat rival Kamala Harris in the November 5 presidential election, reports say.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>LinkedIn co-founder Reid Hoffman is considering leaving the United States after Republican nominee Donald Trump defeated his Democrat rival Kamala Harris in the November 5 presidential election, reports say.</p>

<p>Hoffman was vocal in supporting Vice-President Kamala Harris and even donated millions to back her Presidency.</p>

<p>After Ms Harris' defeat, Mr Hoffman reportedly told friends that he was considering relocating overseas, three people familiar with him told&nbsp;&nbsp;<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/11/27/us/politics/democratic-donors-reid-hoffman-democracy-alliance.html" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">The New York Times</a>.</p>

<p>He is worried about retribution from Trump, who has promised to take on his political opponents, including several major Democratic donors.</p>

<p>Mr Hoffman found himself in hot water after the first failed assassination attempt on Trump in July. An old comment of the 57-year-old entrepreneur resurfaced online, sparking massive criticism. He reportedly said he wished the US President-elect was an "actual martyr."</p>

<p>He donated $10 million to a super PAC that backed Ms Harris as the US president. He even helped pay for the defamation lawsuit filed by E Jean Carroll against Mr Trump. In court, Trump's side had argued that Hoffman's role in financing the lawsuit raises "significant questions" about Carroll's credibility.</p>

<p>Later, a jury found Trump liable for sexually abusing Carroll in 1996 as well as for defamation, and she was awarded $5 million in damages. Another jury awarded her an additional $83.3 million in damages earlier this year for defamation after the President-elect said she lied about rape allegations.</p>

<p>Apart from Mr Hoffman, several other major Democrat donors and their advisers have also reportedly considered leaving the country.</p>

<p>"People are kind of shell-shocked - and trying to figure out what happened... People are trying to adjust to reality and plot out a path forward," said tech mogul Steve Silberstein.</p>

<p>The New York Times stated that some of these people are even distributing memos meant to guide the postmortem analysis for the Democrats so that the fund-raising for the party does not dry up.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2016-09/reid-hoffman-afp_650x400_71474079411.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Reid Hoffman donated $10 million to a super PAC that backed Harris as the US president.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/oj-simpson-allegedly-caught-on-tape-confessing-to-murders-claims-ex-bodyguard-7167906]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[OJ Simpson Caught On Tape Confessing To Murders, Claims Ex-Bodyguard]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/oj-simpson-allegedly-caught-on-tape-confessing-to-murders-claims-ex-bodyguard-7167906]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Dec 2024 10:05:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The alleged confession was reportedly captured on a thumb drive seized from Avelli in 2022.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>OJ Simpson's former bodyguard, Iroc Avelli, claims to have a recording of Simpson confessing to the 1994 murders of Nicole Brown Simpson and Ronald Goldman. The alleged confession was reportedly captured on a thumb drive seized from Avelli in 2022, the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://tribune.com.pk/story/2513646/oj-simpson-allegedly-confessed-to-killings-on-tape-ex-bodyguard-claims" rel="noindex,nofollow"><em>Express Tribune </em></a>reported.</p>

<p>Avelli alerted authorities to the device earlier this year, following Simpson's death in April. While the contents of the recording remain undisclosed, the revelation has reignited interest in one of the most infamous trials in American history.</p>

<p>However, Bloomington, Minn. PD say the search of thumb drives, believed to contain a confession by OJ Simpson, uncovered nothing of "evidentiary value," according to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.fox9.com/video/1556741" rel="noindex,nofollow"><em>Fox9</em></a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p>O.J. Simpson, the American football star whose 1995 acquittal in the so-called "trial of the century" for the murder of his ex-wife and a male friend gripped the world, died in April this year, he was 76.</p>

<p>Once a beloved national figure, his fame turned to infamy after the savage killing of Nicole Brown Simpson and Ron Goldman in a suburb of Los Angeles.</p>

<p>The televised police chase to apprehend Simpson, and the extraordinary subsequent trial featuring high-octane lawyers and allegations of racism, were watched by millions on television.</p>

<p>His acquittal in October 1995 after nine months in court was greeted with disbelief by many Americans who had followed every twist and turn in the arguments over details as intricate as whether a pair of gloves really fitted the former athlete's hands.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/5vihvm1_oj-simpson-afp-_625x300_12_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[This new development could potentially reshape one of the most controversial trials in American history.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trumps-dea-pick-chad-chronister-withdraws-after-covid-criticisms-7167895]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump's DEA Pick Chad Chronister Withdraws After Covid Criticism]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trumps-dea-pick-chad-chronister-withdraws-after-covid-criticisms-7167895]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Dec 2024 10:01:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President-elect Donald Trump's pick to lead the Drug Enforcement Administration (DEA), Chad Chronister, has withdrawn his name from consideration.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President-elect Donald Trump's pick to lead the Drug Enforcement Administration (DEA), Chad Chronister, has withdrawn his name from consideration. Florida sheriff Chronister is the second Trump nominee to step back following the nomination after former Florida Representative Matt Gaetz, who withdrew his nomination for attorney general.</p>

<p>Mr Chronister, who currently serves as the sheriff in Florida's Hillsborough County on Tuesday said there is "more work to be done" for those living there.</p>

<p>"Over the past several days, as the gravity of this very important responsibility set in, I've concluded that I must respectfully withdraw from consideration," he wrote in a post on X.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">To have been nominated by President-Elect <a href="https://twitter.com/realDonaldTrump?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@realDonaldTrump</a> to serve as Administrator of the Drug Enforcement Administration is the honor of a lifetime. Over the past several days, as the gravity of this very important responsibility set in, I've concluded that I must respectfully… <a href="https://t.co/bvNF8m9Bh4">pic.twitter.com/bvNF8m9Bh4</a></p>
— Chad Chronister (@ChadChronister) <a href="https://twitter.com/ChadChronister/status/1864068222309277751?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 3, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>"I sincerely appreciate the nomination, outpouring of support by the American people, and look forward to continuing my service as Sheriff of Hillsborough County," the sheriff added.</p>

<p>The Trump transition team did not immediately issue any statement on the issue.</p>

<p>The President-elect on Sunday announced his intention to nominate Mr Chronister to lead the DEA, saying he would focus on stemming the flow of fentanyl across the US border with Mexico. DEA is part of the Department of Justice and is responsible for enforcing US drug laws.</p>

<h2><strong>"Covid Criticism"</strong></h2>

<p>However, his nomination was seen with a critical lens by Mr Trump's supporters, who reportedly opposed the President-elect's choice, citing the sheriff's enforcement of public health orders during the Covid pandemic.</p>

<p>The criticism majorly centred around the sheriff's arrest of a pastor who was charged with ignoring state and local public health orders by holding large church services in March 2020 after the World Health Organization declared Covid-19 a pandemic.</p>

<p>As per a report by the Washington Post, the Constitutional Sheriffs and Peace Officers Association said in a statement that it was “shocked and dismayed” by the selection, citing Mr Chronister's enforcement of Covid mandates.</p>

<p>Mr Chronister, who has spent over three decades working in law enforcement, also appeared to lack the broader experience suited for the DEA role, according to a report by Reuters.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Mr Chronister was first appointed as county sheriff in 2017 by then-Florida Gov. Rick Scott. He then successfully ran for election to the role. Mr Chronister also reportedly overlapped in the office with Pam Bondi, incoming President Trump's pick for attorney general, when she was a state prosecutor.&nbsp;</p>

<p>His withdrawal follows a similar move by former Republican lawmaker Matt Gaetz, Trump's first pick for attorney general. Mr Gaetz dropped out of consideration amid concerns about his previous conduct. He, however, denied any wrongdoing and called the investigation a "smear."&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/voim9sbg_chad-chronister-pam-bondi-twitter_625x300_04_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Chad Chronister overlapped in the office with Pam Bondi, Trump's pick for attorney general]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-cites-hunter-biden-pardon-in-seeking-hush-money-case-dismissal-7167684]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump Cites Hunter Biden Pardon In Seeking Hush Money Case Dismissal]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-cites-hunter-biden-pardon-in-seeking-hush-money-case-dismissal-7167684]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Dec 2024 09:24:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President-elect Donald Trump's attorneys sought to dismiss his historic criminal fraud conviction in a new filing released Tuesday -- arguing President Joe Biden used similar reasoning to pardon his son, Hunter Biden.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President-elect Donald Trump's attorneys sought to dismiss his historic criminal fraud conviction in a new filing released Tuesday -- arguing President Joe Biden used similar reasoning to pardon his son, Hunter Biden.</p>

<p>The Democratic lame-duck president pardoned his son Sunday, after Hunter was convicted earlier this year of tax evasion and illegally possessing a firearm, arguing he was "selectively, and unfairly, prosecuted" by the Department of Justice (DOJ) "only because he is my son."</p>

<p>Trump's motion to dismiss, filed Monday, saw his legal team cite the arguments used by Biden to make their own case to presiding judge Juan Merchan.</p>

<p>Biden's "comments amounted to an extraordinary condemnation of President Biden's own DOJ," the letter's introduction reads. "This is the same DOJ that coordinated and oversaw the politically-motivated, election-interference witch hunts targeting President Trump."</p>

<p>The 69-page brief also invoked the doctrine of presidential immunity -- which the Supreme Court has ruled extends to "official acts" while president -- and the Presidential Transition Act, among other laws, to "immediately dismiss the Indictment and vacate the jury's verdicts."</p>

<p>Trump, 78, was found guilty in May of 34 counts of falsifying business records from covering up the payment of $130,000 to pornographic film actress Stormy Daniels to silence her from coming forward about an alleged extramarital affair during the final stretch of the 2016 election campaign.</p>

<p>Merchan, the judge in the only criminal case against Trump that has gone to trial, indefinitely postponed Trump's sentencing at a hearing on November 22, given his win in the November 5 presidential election.</p>

<p>With Trump's defense team filing to dismiss the case, Merchan will now have to decide whether to throw out the case entirely, or to suspend any legal consequences until after the end of Trump's upcoming term in office, which will begin on January 20.</p>

<p>Manhattan prosecutor Alvin Bragg has supported the latter in light of the "unprecedented circumstances" caused by Trump's electoral victory.</p>

<p>Bragg had argued during the hush money trial that Trump's payments were made to cover up a scandal that would have tarnished his campaign in the 2016 election that Trump ended up winning over Democrat Hillary Clinton.</p>

<p>Trump has consistently denied having an affair with Daniels.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/ra93b5e_donald-trump-joe-biden-hunter-biden_625x300_02_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump's  legal team cite the arguments used by Hunter Biden to make their own case.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/1971-war-dissent-cables-when-a-us-diplomat-archer-blood-defied-richard-nixon-henry-kissinger-to-save-dhaka-7167678]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[When An American Diplomat Stood Up Against Nixon-Kissinger To Save Dhaka]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/1971-war-dissent-cables-when-a-us-diplomat-archer-blood-defied-richard-nixon-henry-kissinger-to-save-dhaka-7167678]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Dec 2024 09:23:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Pakistan Air Force bombed Indian airfields, and then Prime Minister Indira Gandhi declared war against the enemy.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>December, 1971&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p>The Pakistan Air Force bombed Indian airfields, and then Prime Minister Indira Gandhi declared war against the enemy. The breakout of armed hostilities was not due to a sudden escalation but a result of a brutal crackdown by Pakistani troops on its citizens in the east (now Bangladesh).&nbsp;</p>

<p>'Operation Searchlight' as it was called, resulted in a systematic annihilation of Bengalis and other minorities in east Pakistan and death count surpassing 3 million and over 4,00,000 women were subjected to sexual assault. It was genocide the US intentionally ignored.</p>

<h3><strong>Tensions In South Asia</strong></h3>

<p>The 1965 war marked a crucial shift in Indian politics, then Prime Minister Lal Bahadur Shastri died under mysterious circumstances during the Tashkent Agreement in 1966 and Indira Gandhi was elected as the Prime Minister of India. Meanwhile, Pakistan's Field Marshal Ayub Khan handed over the reins to General Yahya Khan who declared martial law across the country after his anointment. A year later in 1970, Yahya Khan declared general elections to legitimise his position and "bring democracy" back into Pakistan.</p>

<p>To his and everyone's surprise, Sheikh Mujibur Rehman's Awami League in East Pakistan won a majority in the 311-member National Assembly. Zulfikar Ali Bhutto was not ready to accept the decision, especially seeing a Bengali rule the Pathans and Mohajirs in West Pakistan. The fire was ignited in the east and the revolution led to a crackdown. Major General Tikka Khan, also known as the Butcher of East Pakistan, ordered an armed suppression of a freedom movement.</p>

<h3><strong>'Dissent Cables'</strong></h3>

<p>Archer Blood was a young American diplomat posted at the consulate office in Dacca. His telegrams to the White House are considered to be one of the most strongly worded opinions against the American policy toward Pakistan and their decision to ignore the crackdown in the east outrightly.&nbsp;</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Archer Blood was a young American diplomat posted at the consulate office in Dacca." id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/7l55khp_archer-blood_625x300_04_December_24.jpg" title="Archer Blood was a young American diplomat posted at the consulate office in Dacca." /></div>

<h5 class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><em>Archer Blood was a young American diplomat posted at the consulate office in Dacca.</em></h5>
</div>

<p>On April 6, 1971, in one of the now-<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nsarchive.gwu.edu/document/30311-document-41-state-department-us-consulate-dacca-cable-dissent-us-policy-toward-east" rel="noindex,nofollow">declassified</a> telegrams, he wrote, "I am aware of the task force proposals on "openness" in the foreign service and with the conviction that the US policy related to recent development in east Pakistan serves neither our moral interests broadly defined nor our national interests narrowly defined...Our government has failed to denounce atrocities. Our government has failed to take forceful measures to protect its citizens while the same time bending over backwards to placate west Pak dominated government and to lessen likely and deservedly negative international public relations impact against them.</p>

<p>"Our government has evidence what many will consider moral bankruptcy," the cable authorized by Blood and signed by 20 others said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Then-US President Richard Nixon and his foreign minister Henry Kissinger did not view India as an ally. They had an inherent emotional dislike towards New Delhi, which was later proven when the US sent the USS Enterprise into the Indian Ocean to threaten the Indian Navy in the east and support the authoritarian Pakistani regime. The 'Dissent Cable' highlights the American hypocrisy and says, "Ironically, at a time when USSR sent President Yahya Khan a message defending democracy, condemning arrest of leader of democratically elected majority party and calling for repressive measures and bloodshed...We have chosen not to intervene, even morally on the grounds that the Awami conflict, in which unfortunately the overworked term genocide is applicable, is purely an internal matter of a sovereign state...."</p>

<p>American journalist Gary J Bass has written the most detailed account in his book - 'The Blood Telegram Nixon, Kissinger, And A Forgotten Genocide', and explains how the American diplomat shared first-hand information to Washington of the atrocities Pakistani troops are committing, especially using American weapons like the Chaffee tanks and the F-86 Sabre jets against its citizens, but the Oval office chose to ignore the gravity of the situation.</p>

<p>The war ended in just 14 days. Over 3,800 Indian Armed Forces personnel were killed in action and over 9,800 were wounded. At least 90,000 Pakistani soldiers in the east surrendered. Bangladesh was born out of the sacrifice of Indian soldiers and the Mukti Bahini.</p>

<p><em>Read more:&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/explained-key-factors-that-forced-93-000-pak-troops-to-surrender-in-1971-4684760">Explained: Key Events That Forced 93,000 Pakistani Troops To Surrender In 1971</a></em></p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Add image caption here" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-12/00mj9hv_1971-warvijay-diwas650_625x300_16_December_20.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Add image caption here" /></div>

<h6 class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><em>Lt Gen Jagjit Singh Aurora and Lt Gen AAK Niazi:&nbsp;At least 90,000 Pakistani soldiers in the east surrendered.</em></h6>
</div>

<h3><strong>Yahya Khan Gets US Backing</strong></h3>

<p>US President Richard Nixon and his foreign minister Henry Kissinger were determined to establish relations with China, for which the duo needed Pakistan, and Islamabad was bought using military and financial aid.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The American objective was to create a new front against the USSR in South Asia, especially after the Sino-Soviet split in the 1960s. The crisis in East Pakistan came at just the right time for the US to show its support to Yahya Khan to bargain a better position in talks with China. Richard Nixon travelled to China the following year in 1972 after Kissinger's back-channel diplomacy with Beijing for some time. The visit came at the cost of a genocide in the east that the US failed to stop. Richard Nixon even snapped at the height of the crisis in east Pakistan and said, "I don't like the Indians," a dislike stemming from India's nonaligned movement and the historically good relations with the Soviet Union since independence.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Add image caption here" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/ou69adlg_yahya-khan-richard-nixon_625x300_04_December_24.jpeg" title="Add image caption here" /></div>

<h6 class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><em>Yahya Khan (left) meeting US President Richard Nixon (right).</em></h6>
</div>

<p>A memorandum sent by Kissinger to Nixon, titled '<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nsarchive.gwu.edu/document/30312-document-42-white-house-memorandum-president-policy-options-toward-pakistan-secret" rel="noindex,nofollow">Policy Options Toward Pakistan</a>', on April 28, almost three weeks after the dissent cable, was declassified by the US. The document states how Kissinger gave three policy options towards Pakistan to President Nixon and suggested that it would be in the best "interests to have the advantage of making the most of the relationship with Yahya while engaging in a serious effort to move the situation toward conditions less damaging to US and Pakistani interests."</p>

<p>"We would not withhold aid now for the sake of applying pressure We would face that question only after giving the West Pakistanis every chance to negotiate a settlement in the face of the costs of not doing so," he said in the memorandum.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"On economic assistance, we would state our willingness to help in the context of a West Pakistani effort to negotiate a viable settlement We would have to point out that it will be beyond the US--or World Bank or IMF- -financial capacity to help Pakistan if the situation drags on and Pakistan faces a financial crisis We would also have to point out that US assistance legislation requires that economic aid be reduced to the extent that there is a possibility of its diversion to military purposes."&nbsp;</p>

<p>Sensing US backing for Yahya, Prime Minister Indira Gandhi signed the Indo-Soviet Treaty of Peace, Friendship and Cooperation in August 1971, setting the agenda that in case of aggression against any of the two parties, then they would immediately consult each other. It irked the Americans, but for New Delhi, it served the purpose of nonalignment and national interests.</p>

<p>The dissent cable advised the White House to rethink its policy toward Pakistan and said, "I hope the most likely eventual outcome of the struggle underway in east Pakistan and the consequent establishment of an independent Bangladesh. At the moment, we possess the goodwill of the Awami League. We would be foolish to forfeit this asset by pursuing a rigid policy of one-sided support to the likely loser."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/hk0ir0l_bangladesh-war-1971_625x300_04_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Yahya Khan ordered an armed suppression of a freedom movement in east Pakistan.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-to-attend-notre-dame-reopening-in-paris-7167670]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump To Attend Notre Dame Reopening In Paris]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-to-attend-notre-dame-reopening-in-paris-7167670]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Dec 2024 09:20:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Notre Dame cathedral will reopen in Paris on Saturday with incoming US president Donald Trump to attend the ceremony marking the resurrection of the Gothic masterpiece five years after a devastating fire.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Notre Dame cathedral will reopen in Paris on Saturday with incoming US president Donald Trump to attend the ceremony marking the resurrection of the Gothic masterpiece five years after a devastating fire.</p>

<p>The Republican confirmed Monday he had accepted an invitation from French President Emmanuel Macron to attend the grand re-opening of the 850-year-old edifice which was nearly lost to flames in April 2019.</p>

<p>It will be Trump's first foreign trip since his re-election last month in a political comeback that has set off alarm bells in much of Europe, including in France where Macron regularly tussled with the New York real estate tycoon during his first term.</p>

<p>Trump posted on his Truth Social website that Macron had "done a wonderful job ensuring that Notre Dame has been restored to its full level of glory, and even more so. It will be a very special day for all!"</p>

<p>The presence of Trump is likely to encourage other world leaders to attend as they seek to build relations before his January 20 inauguration.</p>

<p>After he took office in 2017, Trump's initial dealings with Macron -- then also a fresh face on the world stage -- had the makings of a "bromance".</p>

<p>Their long and muscular handshakes -- which saw each man seek to assert his superiority -- became a light-hearted focus of attention before ties cooled, then soured, following disputes about climate change, trade and defence.</p>

<p>Trump publicly mocked Macron's "very low approval rating" and even aimed a jibe at France's war history during a rancorous 2018 trip to the country.</p>

<p>Macron's current political problems, with his latest government likely to fall this week, risk overshadowing Saturday's ceremony which the French leader hoped to present as a moment of national and personal triumph.</p>

<p>- 'Sublime' -<br />
Parisians watched in horror in 2019 as flames ravaged Notre Dame, a landmark famed as the setting for Victor Hugo's novel "The Hunchback of Notre Dame" and an integral part of the city's identity.</p>

<p>The apocalyptic images were even seen by some as a sign of the demise of Western civilisation, with the edifice saved from complete collapse only by the heroic intervention of firefighters.</p>

<p>Tweeting as the blaze took place, Trump suggested that "perhaps flying water tankers could be used to put it out", leading irritated French officials to dismiss the suggestion and almost certain to devastate what remained of the building.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Some 250 companies and hundreds of experts were brought in to restore the destroyed artwork, blackened walls and damaged facilities at a cost of 700 million euros ($750 million).</p>

<p>During a visit last Friday, Macron praised them for achieving the "impossible" by healing a "national wound".</p>

<p>Accompanied by Paris' archbishop Laurent Ulrich and top city politicians, he gazed at the restored pale-coloured stonework in the nave and praised the edifice as "much more welcoming" and "sublime".</p>

<p>- Politics and diplomacy -<br />
Saturday's ceremony will mix public celebration, politics, diplomacy and religion.</p>

<p>Macron is to deliver a speech in front of a small crowd at the cathedral and up to 50 heads of state and government including German President Frank-Walter Steinmeier who confirmed his attendance on Tuesday.</p>

<p>They will then inspect the monument and attend a mass service overseen by the archbishop of Paris, which will feature the newly restored 8,000-pipe Grand Organ.</p>

<p>Pope Francis will not attend -- to the surprise of some observers. The Catholic church head will instead go on a visit to the French island of Corsica later in December.</p>

<p>A public area with capacity for 40,000 people will be created on the bank of the river Seine opposite Notre Dame, while a concert featuring the Notre Dame choir, the Radio France philharmonic orchestra and singers will be broadcast.</p>

<p>There are unconfirmed rumours that Pharrell Williams will provide some international stardust.</p>

<p>On Sunday, the first mass with 170 bishops and more than 100 Paris priests will take place at 10:30am (0830 GMT) followed by a second service in the evening at 6:30pm which will be open to the public and be attended by Macron.</p>

<p>All tickets for the public mass in the 3,000-seat edifice were reserved within a few hours on Tuesday, according the cathedral's phone app.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/6v4uurv_donald-trump_625x300_12_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump will attend Notre Dame cathedral's reopening ceremony.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/forbes-30-under-30-list-young-innovators-redefining-ai-green-tech-and-social-media-7167640]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Forbes 30 Under 30: Leaders Redefining AI, Green Tech, And Social Media]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/forbes-30-under-30-list-young-innovators-redefining-ai-green-tech-and-social-media-7167640]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Dec 2024 09:18:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[These leaders, with an average age of 27 and over $3.6 billion in funding, are shaping the future through innovation, sustainability, and creative influence.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Forbes released its highly anticipated '30 Under 30' list of young innovators, disruptors, and visionaries building the future in 20 industries. From groundbreaking leaps in Artificial intelligence and Green Tech to revolutionizing creative categories like Hollywood, Music, and Art &amp; Style, this year's list best represents excellence and impact. Together, these young stars have raised over $3.6 billion in funding, have a combined 300 million social media followers, and represent a new wave of leaders with an average age of just 27--the youngest is only 17. Discover their unbelievable stories and successes in all categories from Education to Venture Capital and more.</p>

<p><strong>Meet the Young Trendsetters Excelling in Non-Traditional Careers</strong></p>

<p><strong>Forbes 30 Under 30: Artificial Intelligence</strong></p>

<p>These trailblazers are changing the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.forbes.com/30-under-30/2025/ai">AI scene</a>, from Foundry Technologies' Jared Quincy Davis to Demi Guo and Chenlin Meng, cofounders of Pika. Tech pioneers like Serena Ge and Charley Lee of Datacurve AI and Kiara and Nikhara Nirghin of Chima are pushing the envelope.</p>

<p>Advances in artificial intelligence safety and development are being spearheaded by leaders like Dan Hendrycks, Executive Director of the Center for AI Safety, and Joanne Jang, Head of Product at OpenAI. The future of AI across industries is being shaped by this diverse group.</p>

<p><strong>Forbes 30 Under 30: Pioneers in Energy and Green Tech</strong></p>

<p>Ben Nowack and Tristan Semmelhack, co-founders of Reflect Orbital, are advancing green technologies. Raj Lulla, Namin Shah, and Dante Vaisbort of Haylon Technologies are revolutionizing <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.forbes.com/30-under-30/2025/energy-green-tech">renewable energy and climate solutions</a> with their impactful ventures like Climatebase, Ecotone Renewables, and Oxylus Energy. Industry leaders like Julia Lamb, Head of Cathode R&amp;D at Bedrock Materials, and Fabia Farlin Athena, a Stanford Fellow, are breaking down barriers in clean energy innovation. It is this dynamic group that will reshape the future of sustainability.</p>

<p><strong>Forbes 30 Under 30: Social Media</strong></p>

<p>The Forbes 30 Under 30 list recognizes<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.forbes.com/30-under-30/2025/social-media"> pioneers in social media</a> and the creator economy. Whether they're content creators, such as Drew Afualo and Enola Bedard, or innovators, such as Ian Boggs and Anna Nordstrom, they're revolutionizing the influence that occurs online. Other notable leaders include cofounders like Royce Branning and Oliver Hill of Clearspace and advocates such as Kahlil Greene, who is known as the "Gen Z Historian," among others. This collaborative team is making the future of digital creativity and social media come alive.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/rvdulbjg_forbes-30-under-30_625x300_04_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Forbes 30 Under 30 highlights the next wave of leaders transforming industries.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/watch-asteroid-on-collision-course-with-earth-explodes-above-russia-7167582]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Watch: Asteroid On 'Collision Course' With Earth Explodes Above Russia]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/watch-asteroid-on-collision-course-with-earth-explodes-above-russia-7167582]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Dec 2024 09:09:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[ESA in a post on X confirmed that Asteroid COWEPC5 entered Earth's atmosphere creating a fireball over the Yakutia region.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A small asteroid streaked toward Earth on Tuesday night, burning up in the atmosphere above far northeastern Russia and creating a dazzling light show for residents in the remote region, officials reported.</p>

<p>The asteroid, measuring less than 70 centimetres (27.5 inches) in diameter, was identified earlier in the day on a "collision course" with Earth, according to the European Space Agency (ESA). However, the impact was deemed "harmless."&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Watch the video here:</strong></p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Video of the 70cm asteroid that entered earths atmosphere over northern Siberia today ☄️ <a href="https://t.co/kXdEULUe5X">pic.twitter.com/kXdEULUe5X</a></p>
— Volcaholic ? (@volcaholic1) <a href="https://twitter.com/volcaholic1/status/1864000781961064914?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 3, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>At 5:15 p.m. CET (11:15 a.m. ET), a "beautiful fireball" lit up the skies over northern Siberia, as observed by residents in the Russian republic of Yakutia, the ESA confirmed.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Incoming!☄️<br />
<br />
A small asteroid has just been spotted on a collision course with Earth. At around ~70 cm in diameter, the impact will be harmless, likely producing a nice fireball in the sky over northern Siberia around seven hours from now at ~16:15 +/- 05 min UTC (17:15 +/-5 min… <a href="https://t.co/ie9yj0FHfB">pic.twitter.com/ie9yj0FHfB</a></p>
— European Space Agency (@esa) <a href="https://twitter.com/esa/status/1863877748323930125?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 3, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>NASA described the event as a "harmless fireball" and credited the University of Arizona's Bok telescope for first detecting the asteroid's approach. The space rock, designated as C0WEPC5, caused no reported damage or injuries.</p>

<p>"Asteroid <a dir="ltr" href="https://x.com/hashtag/C0WEPC5?src=hashtag_click" role="link">#C0WEPC5</a> (temporary designation) entered Earth's atmosphere at 16:15 UTC/17:15 CET, creating a fireball over Yakutia witnessed by people in the region. The object was discovered roughly 12 hours ago and is thought to have been around 70 cm across. Thanks to observations from astronomers around the world, our alert system was able to predict this impact to within +/- 10 seconds," the ESA wrote on X.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/uvs6jboo_asteroid-enters-earth_625x300_04_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The impact was deemed "harmless".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>