<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Fri, 05 Jul 2024 22:12:18 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rachel-reeves-45-becomes-first-woman-uk-finance-minister-6042411]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Rachel Reeves, 45, Becomes First Woman UK Finance Minister]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rachel-reeves-45-becomes-first-woman-uk-finance-minister-6042411]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 05 Jul 2024 21:13:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Britain's new Prime Minister Keir Starmer on Friday appointed Rachel Reeves as finance minister, the first woman to hold the position in the country's history, following Labour's landslide election victory.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Rachel Reeves, Britain's first woman finance minister, is a former child chess champion and Bank of England economist who has pledged to grow the nation's economy while showing strong fiscal discipline.</p>

<p>Reeves, 45, becomes chancellor of the exchequer after her centre-left Labour party won Thursday's UK general election by a landslide, ending 14 years of rule by the right-wing Conservatives.</p>

<p>"It is the honour of my life to have been appointed chancellor of the exchequer," Reeves wrote on social media platform X after her appointment by new Prime Minister Keir Starmer.</p>

<p>"To every young girl and woman reading this, let today show that there should be no limits on your ambitions."</p>

<p>Labour had put the economy at the heart of its election manifesto, targeting growth and wealth creation as key priorities in government, while its emphasis on the latter is not normally associated with the party's traditionally leftist policies.</p>

<p>"Economic growth was the Labour Party's mission," Reeves added Friday.</p>

<p>"It is now a national mission. Let's get to work," said the married mother of two children.</p>

<p><strong>'Iron chancellor'</strong></p>

<p>Reeves recently told company bosses that Labour had become "the natural party of British business", adding that the party would show "iron discipline" over public finances.</p>

<p>The comments drew comparisons with 'Iron Lady' Margaret Thatcher, Britain's first woman prime minister.</p>

<p>Unlike Conservative leader Thatcher, who privatised key sectors after becoming prime minister in 1979, Reeves wants a form of renationalisation, notably for energy, as she takes inspiration from policy enacted by US President Joe Biden.</p>

<p>Labour has pledged to create Great British Energy, a publicly owned company that would spearhead funding, alongside the private sector, for the "green" transition away from fossil fuels.</p>

<p>James Wood, senior teaching associate in political economy at the University of Cambridge, said Labour and Reeves were seeking a "responsible" approach to the public purse.</p>

<p>"When she talks about being an iron chancellor, I think what she means is: we're going to balance the books and we're going to be responsible -- and we're going to try and get Britain's economy running... in a responsible way," he told AFP.</p>

<p>London-born Reeves tapped into public anger over Sunak's predecessor Liz Truss, whose unfunded 2022 mini-budget crashed the pound and sent mortgage rates soaring, worsening a cost-of-living crisis.</p>

<p>"They want to distance themselves from fiscal irresponsibility, not making big promises about spending that they can't possibly keep," Wood added.</p>

<p><strong>Banking career</strong></p>

<p>Reeves, whose parents were teachers, is no stranger to outmanoeuvring opponents.</p>

<p>She became British girls' chess champion aged 14 before studying philosophy, politics and economics at the University of Oxford, which was followed by a Master's degree at the London School of Economics.</p>

<p>After graduating, she worked as an economist for a decade, first at the Bank of England before switching to the private sector.</p>

<p>While working for British retail bank HBOS, the global financial crisis struck in 2008, resulting in her employer receiving a huge bailout, along with other lenders, from Gordon Brown's Labour government.</p>

<p>In 2010, when the Conservatives entered power in a coalition with the Liberal Democrats, Reeves was elected Labour MP for Leeds West in northern England.</p>

<p>Eleven years later, Starmer appointed her as Labour's finance spokesperson. Her sister Ellie Reeves is also a Labour MP.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/aogtdje_rachel-reeves-_625x300_05_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-dutch-pm-dick-schoof-under-fire-over-ministers-racist-remarks-6042348]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[New Dutch PM Under Fire Over Ministers' 'Racist' Remarks]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-dutch-pm-dick-schoof-under-fire-over-ministers-racist-remarks-6042348]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 05 Jul 2024 21:05:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Newly-minted Prime Minister Dick Schoof faced a baptism of fire at the opening of the Dutch parliament over remarks by two cabinet ministers about a conspiracy theory with neo-Nazi roots.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Newly-minted Prime Minister Dick Schoof faced a baptism of fire at the opening of the Dutch parliament over remarks by two cabinet ministers about a conspiracy theory with neo-Nazi roots.</p>

<p>Schoof was inaugurated on Tuesday with pomp and fanfare to head a coalition government dominated by far-right leader Geert Wilders and his anti-immigration Freedom Party, the PVV.</p>

<p>Two days later, the new Dutch premier's first lower house debate spiralled into chaos when not only the opposition, but Wilders himself aimed his arrows at Schoof, his own choice for the top job.</p>

<p>No amount of preparation could ready Schoof, a veteran career civil servant, for his first appearance within the bear pit of Dutch parliamentary politics, marked by interruptions and sniping on X, formally known as Twitter.</p>

<p>At the centre of the controversy are two cabinet ministers from Wilders' PVV: new Asylum and Migration Minister Marjolein Faber and Foreign Trade and Development Aid Minister Reinette Klever.</p>

<p>Both have in the past spoken about the so-called "omvolking" -- the Dutch term for the "great replacement theory" that supposes that Europe's white population is being deliberately replaced by immigrants.</p>

<p>While both ministers have "distanced themselves" from the term, they maintained that there was a "worrying demographic development" in the Netherlands, where the ruling coalition now wants to implement the "strictest immigration policy ever."</p>

<p><strong>Isolated</strong></p>

<p>But Schoof reiterated during the debate: "I repeat, this government is against discrimination, racism and exclusion."</p>

<p>The Dutch left-wing opposition accused Schoof of tolerating those who have made "conspiratorial" and "racist" remarks -- which also included criticising the wearing of veils -- within his ministerial team.</p>

<p>Wilders himself then launched a virulent attack on Schoof for not defending his ministers for "being made out as racists", calling Schoof's response "weak."</p>

<p>"The prime minister should immediately distance himself from it. I will not accept anything less!" Wilders said on X.</p>

<p>Schoof, not aligned to any party and who has been appointed by a four-party coalition of the PVV, the Liberal VVD, the farmer-friendly BBB and the new centre-right NSC, appeared isolated on all sides.</p>

<p>Leiden politics professor Ruud Koole told AFP the first debate was a litmus test to see how far the PVV's junior coalition parties would go to normalise extreme views within Wilders' party.</p>

<p>"It turns out very far," he said.</p>

<p>"The statements made in the past by PVV ministers about the 'great replacement' have been swept under the carpet," Koole said.</p>

<p>"All three the other coalition parties have accepted to have the 'great replacement' rephrased as a "demographic phenomenon",' he said.</p>

<p><strong>'Disgusting'</strong></p>

<p>Wilders, who claimed a stunning victory in last year's parliamentary elections, continues to lead his party as an MP.</p>

<p>He gave up on ambitions to become Dutch prime minister after other coalition parties threatened to withdraw because of his anti-Islam and eurosceptic views.</p>

<p>Wilders said he wanted to limit immigration to the Netherlands "as much as possible", but he has indeed called the "great replacement" theory "disgusting".</p>

<p>But during the debate, he aimed his barbs at Schoof for not defending those ministers made out by the left, according to Wilders, as "racist."</p>

<p>Wilders's outburst was immediately criticised by the junior coalition partner leaders of the VVD and the NSC on X.</p>

<p>"I was particularly struck by how defensive Wilders was and how he tried in a frantic and authoritarian way to deny the racism that his party clearly propagates in various ways," said Sarah Bracke, sociology professor at the University of Amsterdam.</p>

<p>"It is intellectually and politically untenable to continue to deny that the ideas at the heart of the PVV, and also of this government, are not racist, or that it would be enough to no longer mention the term 'great replacement' to make extremist and racist ideas disappear," she told AFP.</p>

<p>"If Mr Wilders continues to criticise his prime minister, this could lead to Schoof's resignation," added Leiden University's Koole.</p>

<p>"But we are not there yet," he said.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/jd14b6m_dutch-pm-_625x300_05_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Dutch Prime Minister Dick Schoof]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rishi-sunak-lost-big-youtuber-niko-omilana-mocks-him-with-a-giant-l-sign-behind-him-6042279]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Rishi Sunak Lost Big. YouTuber Mocked Him With A Giant "L" Sign Behind Him]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rishi-sunak-lost-big-youtuber-niko-omilana-mocks-him-with-a-giant-l-sign-behind-him-6042279]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 05 Jul 2024 20:55:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Rishi Sunak lost big at the UK polls. The message was further underlined by a YouTube star who stood behind him holding up a piece of paper with a giant letter "L" on it.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Rishi Sunak lost big at the UK polls. The message was further underlined by a YouTube star who stood behind him holding up a piece of paper with a giant letter "L" on it, as the outgoing Prime Minister was delivering his speech of thanks to his constituents.</p>

<p>The prank, which referred to Mr Sunak as a "loser", was claimed by YouTuber Niko Omilana. "Farewell Rishi, Hold this L," wrote the YouTuber, who has a following of 7.49 million, on X.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">farewell rishi, hold this L <a href="https://t.co/qjqTIxbYSZ">pic.twitter.com/qjqTIxbYSZ</a></p>
— NDL Ringside (@NikoOmilana) <a href="https://twitter.com/NikoOmilana/status/1809071233461317738?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 5, 2024</a></blockquote>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">i did it for the people. <a href="https://t.co/SEoFqGFQYr">pic.twitter.com/SEoFqGFQYr</a></p>
— NDL Ringside (@NikoOmilana) <a href="https://twitter.com/NikoOmilana/status/1809202004297666592?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 5, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>Niko, who is known for his various pranks online, could be seen moving behind the ex-PM to ensure his sign would be caught in the camera shots, as the conservative leader conceded the election to Labour.</p>

<p>Niko was able to make it to stage and behind the Tory leader as he stood as an independent candidate in Sunak's Yorkshire seat, which the outgoing PM has retained.</p>

<p>Last month, the famous prankster had said in a video posted on X that he is planning to "completely remove" the UK's current Prime Minister Rishi Sunak from politics.</p>

<p>There was more misery in store for the 44-year-old leader.&nbsp;</p>

<p>A cartoon posted by X user @Cartoon4sale shows what appears to be Mr Sunak sliding out of the "0" in 10 Downing Street. It suggests a decline in the power and popularity of Mr Sunak and is trolling his misfortune.</p>

<p>Shortly before Mr Sunak had conceded defeat, Irish low-cost carrier Ryanair posted on its X account saying, "Don't worry @RishiSunak we've got a seat for you". The post has since received 3.9m views so far.</p>

<p>The Conservative Party led by Mr Sunak suffered a heavy defeat after 14 years in government, ending his premiership, 20 months after he was sworn in amidst political turmoil in the party.</p>

<p>Mr Sunak saw a record number of his top ministerial team lose their seats, including defence secretary Grant Shapps and House of Commons leader Penny Mordaunt.</p>

<p>Keir Starmer has promised to "rebuild Britain" as he took office as the UK's new prime minister following his centre-left Labour party's landslide general election victory.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/eb81j018_rishi-sunak-l-1200-_625x300_05_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[YouTuber Niko Omilana with the "L" sign behind Rishi Sunak]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/artificial-intelligence/ai-climate-ai-energy-ai-emissions-energy-hungry-ai-whats-the-hidden-cost-of-your-genai-search-6041452]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Energy Hungry AI: What's The Hidden Cost of Your GenAI Search?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/artificial-intelligence/ai-climate-ai-energy-ai-emissions-energy-hungry-ai-whats-the-hidden-cost-of-your-genai-search-6041452]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 05 Jul 2024 18:51:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[When you enter a prompt in an AI chatbot, it is consuming more resources than a traditional web search, driving higher carbon emissions. But can this uptick in resource consumption by the frontier technology of AI be quantified?]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A traditional Google search consumes 0.0003-kilowatt hour (KWh) energy on an average, according to a 2009 Google report. That energy can power your household (9 watt) light bulb for about 2 minutes. Google averages about 8.5 billion searches per day as of 2023, translating to 2,550,000 KWh worth of electricity per day, which is about 2000 times more electricity than an average Indian consumes (1255 KWh) for an entire year.</p>

<p>This May, Google announced that the company will integrate AI into its search engine, which will be powered by its most powerful AI model - Gemini. &nbsp;According to Alex de Vries, a Dutch Data Scientist who spoke to The New Yorker on the subject, a single Google search with AI integrated in it will consume 10 times more energy (3 KWh) than the traditional Google search. That is 20,000 times more than the average Indian's consumption for a year.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Alex de Vries, who is also the founder of Digiconomist-the organisation responsible for Bitcoin Energy Consumption Index- has said that Google's energy consumption will reach about 29 billion terawatt-hours (TWh) per year if they go ahead with the AI integration in its search. This figure is equivalent to the electricity consumption of Ireland, and more than that of Kenya.</p>

<h2>&nbsp;<br />
Why are AI systems so hungry for power?&nbsp;</h2>

<p><br />
AI systems require a lot of computational power for running complex algorithms to process large corpus of ever-increasing data. When you enter a prompt in ChatGPT, it is processed by the chatbot using its servers hosted in data centres. These centres alone account for 1-1.5 percent of the entire global electricity use, according to the International Energy Agency.</p>

<p>"I think we still don't appreciate the energy needs of this (AI) technology," Sam Altman, C.E.O of OpenAI, said at a public event in Davos this January. Altman expressed the immediate need for a "breakthrough" technology like nuclear fusion to power the AI operations given the growth projections of the frontier technology. This is a clear indication that the industry leader of the Large Language Model chatbots is seeking avenues to sustain current electricity consumption levels and safeguard its future demand. &nbsp;</p>

<h2>AI's Carbon Emissions -Setback for UN 2050 Net-Zero Emission Goal?&nbsp;</h2>

<p>Data centres, powering cloud computing as well as AI systems produce 2.5 to 3.5 percent of global greenhouse gas emissions, according to The Shift Project, a French nonprofit working to reduce energy reliance on fossil fuels. This amounts to the same levels of greenhouse gas emissions as the entire aviation industry.</p>

<p>The energy consumption and the subsequent carbon footprint of different AI models vary significantly. For example, BigScience project BLOOM, which is an AI model with 76 billion parameters (internal variables that a model learns during training) consumes 433 megawatt-hour (MWh) of electricity.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In contrast, OpenAI's GPT-3 from 2020, which had a comparable number of parameters at 175 billion, consumed 3 times more electricity at 1287 MWh, according to the Artificial Intelligence Index Report 2024 data, published by Stanford Institute of Human-Centered Artificial Intelligence (HCAI).</p>

<p>The CO2 equivalent emissions (in tonnes), that is the total greenhouse gas emissions expressed in terms of carbon dioxide, for BLOOM was 25 tonnes and for GPT-3, it was a whopping 20 times more, at 502 tonnes.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/2ute79s_ai-models-carbon-emission_625x300_05_July_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"></div>
</div>

<p>The report also states that there is a serious lack of transparency from the AI developers on the environmental impact of their models, with most not making their carbon footprints public.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The recently released Google's Sustainability Report 2024 also reflects the energy hunger of the nascent technology of AI. The company saw a near 50 percent surge in carbon emissions in the last 5 years on the back of powering its new AI technologies. Microsoft's Sustainability Report 2024 shows similar trends with a spike of 29 percent increase in CO2 emission in 2023, compared to the previous year. &nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to SemiAnalysis, a US-based independent AI research and analysis company, AI will drive the increase of electricity consumption of data centres to 4.5 percent of the global energy generation by 2030. Another estimate from the International Energy Agency suggests that data centres' total electricity consumption can double from 2022 levels to 1000 TWh (equaling the current electricity consumption of Japan). India has around 138 data centres, with reportedly 45 more set to be functional by the end of 2025. The United States has the highest number of data centres with 2701 of them. &nbsp;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Lawmakers are starting to take stock of the situation. The European Union has taken cognisance and adopted a new regulation in March this year. Under the scheme, all data centre operators are required to report their energy and water consumption (used for cooling systems). They are also mandated to provide information on efficiency measures being implemented to ensure reduction.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In February, US Democrats introduced the Artificial Intelligence Environment Impact Act of 2024. The act proposes setting up an AI Environment Impact Consortium of experts, researchers and industry stakeholders to address the environmental impact of AI. &nbsp;&nbsp;<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/9p494bbg_ai-electricity-grid-ai-generated-image_625x300_05_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[AI technology is driving an upsurge in energy consumption globally (Disclaimer: AI Generated Image)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/victoria-starmer-the-low-profile-wife-of-new-uk-prime-minister-6041260]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Victoria Starmer: The Low-Profile Wife Of New UK Prime Minister]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/victoria-starmer-the-low-profile-wife-of-new-uk-prime-minister-6041260]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 05 Jul 2024 18:29:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Victoria Starmer, whose husband Keir is the new UK prime minister, works in the public health service, is hardly photographed and has kept a low profile on the campaign trail.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Victoria Starmer, whose husband Keir is the new UK prime minister, works in the public health service, is hardly photographed and has kept a low profile on the campaign trail.</p>

<p>But in the coming days, many Britons will begin to recognise the face of the elegant 50-year-old brunette who has been married to the head of the Labour government for more than 15 years.</p>

<p>Since Keir Starmer became Labour leader in 2020 and during the election campaign, Victoria Starmer has not given an interview and has only rarely partaken in politics.</p>

<p>Her public appearances are few and far between: at the polling station on election days, in the stands at the Wimbledon tennis tournament and Taylor Swift's London concert, or at Buckingham Palace for state dinners and receptions.</p>

<p>A rare exception was when she joined her husband on the stage at the party's annual conference in 2023, donning a red dress in Labour's colours.</p>

<p>Even with the move into Downing Street, the former lawyer intends to continue as an occupational health worker in the NHS.</p>

<p><strong>Former lawyer</strong></p>

<p>Victoria Alexander was raised in north London. Her father is a former accountant from a Polish-Jewish background and her mother was a community doctor.</p>

<p>She studied law at Cardiff University in Wales where she was head of the student union.</p>

<p>She also volunteered in Labour's campaign headquarters under Tony Blair before becoming a solicitor in a law firm.</p>

<p>After that, she joined the NHS.</p>

<p>The new prime minister has recounted their first encounter several times, meeting back when they were both working on a court case in the early 2000s.</p>

<p>He called her up to ask if all the documents she prepared were accurate.</p>

<p>Soon after, he asked her on a date to a pub in Camden in north London.</p>

<p>The couple married in 2007 and have two children -- a 16-year-old son and a 13-year-old daughter whom Starmer never mentions by name in public to protect their privacy.</p>

<p>They live in Kentish Town, in his north London constituency.</p>

<p><strong>'Down to earth'</strong></p>

<p>While the prime minister says he is not religious, his wife has passed on Jewish traditions to their children, including going to the synagogue and Friday night dinners.</p>

<p>Always ready with a compliment for "Vic", as he refers to her, Keir Starmer told Vogue magazine that his wife was "very sassy, very down to earth".</p>

<p>In another interview, he said her current job gave him a "direct line of sight on a daily basis into the challenges of the NHS and the morale of the staff".</p>

<p>A family friend once said Victoria complemented her husband and was "literally the yin to his yang".</p>

<p>Seen by many Labour advisors as an asset to her husband, she has nevertheless kept a safe distance from the media during the election campaign.</p>

<p>Keir Starmer insisted that she wished to focus on their son, who was taking his school-leaving exams this year.</p>

<p>But she could not stop the press mentioning her testimony in court last month in a case where three pro-Palestinian activists went on trial for protesting outside the family home against Labour's stance on Israel's war with Hamas in Gaza.</p>

<p>"I felt a bit sick, to be perfectly honest. I felt apprehensive and uncomfortable", she said.</p>

<p>In Downing Street, the Starmers intend to be "fiercely protective" of their children from the media spotlight to come, the Labour leader has said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/v53ho0f8_keira-starmer-_625x300_05_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/robots-baffling-suicide-in-south-korea-sparks-investigation-6041089]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Did A Robot Really Die By 'Suicide' In South Korea? Experts Probe]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/robots-baffling-suicide-in-south-korea-sparks-investigation-6041089]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 05 Jul 2024 18:08:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A robot employed by the Gumi City Council in South Korea went defunct after falling down a flight of stairs. While some have sensationalised the event as robot suicide', experts believe it is more likely a technical malfunction or glitch.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A robot employed by the Gumi City Council in South Korea went defunct after falling down a flight of stairs. While some have sensationalised the event as ‘robot suicide', experts believe it is more likely a technical malfunction or glitch. The robot was a part of the city hall staff and had been working “diligently” since August 2023, said one of its coworkers. It helped with daily tasks such as document deliveries, providing information to residents and city promotion.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
Before the fall, eyewitnesses reported unusual behaviour, with the robot circling in one spot seemingly confused “as if something was there.” The incident occurred on June 27 at approximately 4 pm, with the 'Robot supervisor' found damaged and lying in the stairwell between the first and second floors of the council building.<br />
<br />
The cause of the fall remains under investigation. Officials believe it may have been due to a navigational error, sensor failure or programming bug. A city council official mentioned that the robot's “pieces have been collected and will be analysed by the company.”<br />
<br />
The robot was the first of its kind to have such a role in the city. Developed by Bear Robotics, a California-based startup, it was designed to work autonomously, navigating between floors using the elevator. Unlike other robots, which are typically limited to a single floor, this robot had the ability to move freely, making it a unique asset to the Gumi City Council. The robot worked from 9 am to 6 pm and was even given its own civil service officer card, just like a human employee.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
The manufacturer, Bear Robotics, is working with the council to investigate and prevent similar incidents in the future.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br />
<br />
South Korea has consistently demonstrated a strong affinity for robotics, spearheading the global adoption of automation technology. With a remarkable ratio of one industrial robot for every 10 employees, the country boasts the highest robot density in the world, as per <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.mdpi.com/2071-1050/15/22/15679 ">reports</a>.<br />
<br />
However, in the wake of the recent robot incident at the Gumi City Council, the municipality has decided to temporarily halt its plans to introduce a second robot officer.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2019-10/h3unm7p8_robot-generic_625x300_25_October_19.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The cause of the fall remains under investigation. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/ex-uk-pm-rishi-sunak-for-whom-everything-that-could-go-wrong-went-wrong-6040945]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: Rishi Sunak: For Whom Everything That Could Go Wrong, Went Wrong]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/ex-uk-pm-rishi-sunak-for-whom-everything-that-could-go-wrong-went-wrong-6040945]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 05 Jul 2024 17:46:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Sunak has said he will remain an MP and he has denied suggestions that he's planning to move to California, where the family has a home. But his time at the highest echelons of British politics is almost over.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/qc80ev5g_rishi-sunak_625x300_05_July_24.jpg?im=FitAndFill,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>"To the country, I would like to say first and foremost, I am sorry". Those were <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/i-am-sorry-uk-pm-rishi-sunak-concedes-defeat-in-uk-polls-6037606">Rishi Sunak's words</a> as he left Downing Street for the last time. "I have heard your anger, your disappointment", he declared, "and I take responsibility for this loss."</p>

<p>Sunak was addressing the nation outside Ten Downing Street, with his wife, Akshata Murty, at his side, before heading to the palace to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-general-election-why-rishi-sunak-lost-from-crumbling-nhs-to-economic-crisis-why-rishi-sunak-lost-uk-election-6039983">resign as Britain's Prime Minister</a>. It was a brief and dignified address, tinged with humility and regret. The scale of the election defeat suffered by Rishi Sunak's Conservatives is truly remarkable. The party has lost two-thirds of its seats in Parliament; there will be just over 120 Conservative MPs among the 650 members of the newly elected House of Commons. It's the Conservatives' worst-ever general election result.</p>

<h2><strong>Verdict: Failure</strong></h2>

<p>The final verdict on Rishi Sunak's 20 months in office has to be: failure. He failed to achieve several of the political goals he had publicly set himself; he didn't cut waiting times for hospital treatment or stem illegal immigration. He failed to unite his own party which, after 14 unbroken years in power, was increasingly quarrelsome and faction-ridden. And he failed to persuade the voters that he had a vision for Britain's future.</p>

<p>There were some successes too. Rishi Sunak, a decent man, restored integrity to the post of Prime Minister after the damage inflicted by Boris Johnson's clowning and deceit; he presided over a gradual improvement in the country's economy; and he sorted out some of the lingering mess in the wake of Britain's departure from the European Union.</p>

<p><strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/can-uks-new-pm-keir-starmer-fix-labours-fragile-relations-with-india-6038590">Also Read | UK Elections: Mending India-Labour Relations Won't Be Easy For Starmer</a></strong></p>

<p>But he proved to have poor political instincts. He never gave the impression of being fully in charge, and was battered and buffeted by the rivalries within his own party. His election campaign was spectacularly inept. And his own reputation was tarnished by a bizarre decision to pull out early from global commemorations of the 80th anniversary of D-Day, a proud moment in Britain's history that marked the turning of the tide against Nazi Germany in the Second World War.</p>

<p>At times, Rishi Sunak has faced political vitriol that some would see as racist. The right-winger Nigel Farage - leader of an anti-immigration party, Reform UK, which took millions of votes from the Conservatives - said during the campaign that Sunak's D-Day misjudgement was because "he doesn't understand our history and culture". But Sunak's lasting place in history is that he has been the first person of colour to head Britain's government, and he has demonstrated beyond doubt that race is no longer a barrier to getting to the very top.</p>

<h2><strong>What Changes Under Starmer?&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p>The Labour Party has achieved a landslide victory with the slogan 'time for change'. Its leader, Keir Starmer - who has now succeeded Sunak as prime minister - will have a huge Parliamentary majority.</p>

<p>But in fact, there is likely to be little immediate change. Starmer has made clear that a Labour government will not increase taxes and there will be no alteration in foreign policy. The only immediate policy reversal is likely to be the abandoning of Sunak's controversial and ill-considered plan to deport asylum seekers to Rwanda in central Africa.</p>

<p><strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-modi-congratulates-keir-starmer-for-win-has-a-message-for-rishi-sunak-6039526">Also Read |&nbsp;PM Modi Congratulates Keir Starmer For Win, Has A Message For Rishi Sunak</a></strong></p>

<p>Rishi Sunak has made clear that he will stand down as leader of the Conservative party, but not straight away. He will remain in the post until a successor is chosen. And he emphasised that Conservatives needed to provide a 'professional and effective' opposition to the new Labour government - which will be seen as a warning against the Conservatives lurching to the right in the aftermath of their stinging defeat.</p>

<h2><strong>Sunak, The Ex-Politician?</strong></h2>

<p>Sunak has said he will remain an MP and he has denied suggestions that he's planning to move to California, where the family has a home. But his time at the highest echelons of British politics is almost over. There is rarely any way back for a vanquished prime minister, and Sunak has been so bruised by his time in office that it's unlikely he wants to return to top level politics. At 44, he's young for a former prime minister, he is formidably clever, and he will not find life as a backbench MP very satisfying. So sooner or later, he's likely to depart the political landscape altogether and carve out a new career.</p>

<p><i>(Andrew Whitehead is an honorary professor at the University of Nottingham in the UK and a former BBC India and Political correspondent.)</i></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/3pihop98_rishi-sunak_625x300_05_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russian-president-putin-to-host-private-dinner-for-pm-modi-on-july-8-centre-6040771]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Putin To Host Private Dinner For PM Modi On July 8: Centre]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russian-president-putin-to-host-private-dinner-for-pm-modi-on-july-8-centre-6040771]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 05 Jul 2024 17:22:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Foreign Secretary Vinay Kwatra on Friday announced that Prime Minister Modi will arrive in Moscow on Monday (July 8) afternoon, he said, adding that the PM will then join a private dinner hosted by Russian President Vladimir Putin.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Foreign Secretary Vinay Kwatra on Friday announced that Prime Minister Modi will arrive in Moscow on Monday (July 8) afternoon, he said, adding that the PM will then join a private dinner hosted by Russian President Vladimir Putin.</p>

<p>Addressing a special briefing on PM Modi's visit to Russia and Austria, Kwatra said, PM Modi will pay an official visit to Moscow on July 8-9, at the invitation of the President of the Russian Federation for the 22nd India-Russia Annual Summit."</p>

<p>Further, he also said that after PM Modi and Putin's informal meeting in Uzbekistan's Samarkand in 2022, both leaders have stayed in touch on the phone multiple times.</p>

<p>"The last, that is the 21st, annual summit, you would recall was held in New Delhi in December 2021. The two leaders thereafter met in September 2022 in Samarkand on the margins of the SCO summit in Uzbekistan. They have also stayed in touch with each other through several telephonic conversations through these years," said the Foreign Secretary.</p>

<p>"As of now, the Prime Minister is scheduled to arrive in Moscow in the late afternoon of July 8. President Putin will host a private dinner for the PM on the day of arrival," he added.</p>

<p>While speaking about PM Modi's visit, Mr Kawtra also announced that the next day after his arrival he would engage with the Indian community in Russia, adding that he will also visit to Kremlin.</p>

<p>"The next day, the PM's interactions would include an interface with the indian community in Russia. As part of the programming elements, the PM will also lay a wreath at the Tomb of the Unknown Soldier in Kremlin and thereafter the PM will visit the exhibition venue in Moscow," said Foreign Secretary on PM Modi upcoming Russia visit."</p>

<p>"These engagements will be followed by a restricted level talk between the two leaders, which will then be followed by delegation level talks led by Prime Minister and the Russian President" he added.</p>

<p>The two leaders will review the entire range of multifaceted ties between India and Russia.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/plr49cuo_narendra-modi-vladimir-putin-modi-putin-ians_625x300_04_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The two leaders will review entire range of multifaceted ties between India and Russia (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-says-hes-1st-black-woman-to-serve-with-black-president-in-latest-faux-pas-6040725]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden Calls Himself "1st Black Woman" In White House In Latest Faux Pas]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-says-hes-1st-black-woman-to-serve-with-black-president-in-latest-faux-pas-6040725]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 05 Jul 2024 17:20:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden mistakenly referred to himself as "the first Black woman to serve with a Black president" in a recent interview.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden mistakenly referred to himself as "the first Black woman to serve with a Black president" in a recent interview.&nbsp;He momentarily confused himself with Vice President Kamala Harris during the interview with Philadelphia's WURD radio station while acknowledging his time serving as Vice President for former President Barack Obama.&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">NEW: President Biden goes on incredibly confusing rant, calls himself the first black woman to serve with a black president.<br />
<br />
He also called himself the “first president that got elected statewide in the state of Delaware, when I was a kid.”<br />
<br />
“By the way, I'm proud to be the, as… <a href="https://t.co/VMNtVe85Pz">pic.twitter.com/VMNtVe85Pz</a></p>
— Collin Rugg (@CollinRugg) <a href="https://twitter.com/CollinRugg/status/1808974408494821730?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 4, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p><br />
He also boasted about appointing the first Black woman to the Supreme Court and selecting the first Black woman as Vice President.</p>

<p>Earlier in the interview, he incorrectly claimed he was the first president elected statewide in Delaware, likely intending to say he was the first Catholic elected statewide, then spoke admiringly of John F Kennedy, another Catholic.</p>

<p>In a 4th of July speech at the White House, the 81-year-old began a story about former President Donald Trump, referring to him as “one of our colleagues, the former president,” before abruptly ending the story with, “probably shouldn't say, at any rate.”</p>

<p>President Biden's verbal missteps continued during his appearance on <a href="https://www.business-standard.com/world-news/joe-biden-says-he-is-first-black-woman-to-serve-with-a-black-president-124070500450_1.html ">The Earl Ingram Show</a>, a program targeting black listeners in Wisconsin. When discussing voting, he made a confusing statement that seemed to reference the Supreme Court's recent decision granting immunity to former President Trump. Biden said, "You need someone, someone who is going to make sure that – the Supreme Court just issued a decision, by the way, that threatens the American principle that we have no kings in America. There's no one above the law."</p>

<p>This incident is the latest in a series of gaffes by the President, particularly after his disastrous performance in the presidential debate, drawing attention and criticism from various quarters.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Biden and his top aides have stated that the president's upcoming activities are part of a campaign effort to show voters, donors and activists that his debate performance was merely “a bad night.” Ammar Moussa, a spokesman for Biden's campaign, criticised the news media for throwing light into the president's stumbles.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/o44j52qo_joe-biden_625x300_03_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Biden also boasted about appointing the first Black woman to the Supreme Court.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/country-first-party-second-keir-starmer-in-first-speech-as-uk-pm-6040718]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Country First, Party Second": Keir Starmer In First Speech As UK PM]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/country-first-party-second-keir-starmer-in-first-speech-as-uk-pm-6040718]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 05 Jul 2024 17:18:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Keir Starmer on Friday promised that his Labour government will work from day one on national renewal, in his first speech as UK prime minister from Downing Street.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Keir Starmer on Friday swept into Downing Street for the first time as UK prime minister, promising urgent action to restore the country's fortunes.</p>

<p>The Labour party leader oversaw a landslide victory in Thursday's general election, ending 14 years of rule by Rishi Sunak's Conservatives.</p>

<p>"The work of change begins immediately," Starmer told reporters outside Downing Street after accepting head of state King Charles III's request for him to form a government.</p>

<p>"But have no doubt, we will rebuild Britain," he added.</p>

<p>Starmer, a 61-year-old former human rights lawyer and chief state prosecutor, paid tribute to Sunak, who was appointed Tory leader and prime minister in October 2022 after Liz Truss's disastrous tenure.</p>

<p>"His achievement as the first British-Asian prime minister of our country, the extra effort that that will have required, should not be underestimated by anyone," he said.</p>

<p>"We pay tribute to that today. We also recognise the dedication and hard work he brought to his leadership," he added.</p>

<p>Flag-waving Labour supporters lined the approach to Downing Street as Starmer and his wife Victoria arrived from Buckingham Palace, shaking hands with and kissing activists.</p>

<p>Starmer faces a daunting to-do list, noting that Britons had grown tired of crumbling public services, higher prices and empty promises from politicians.</p>

<p>His government, he said, would put "country first, party second", promising to restore "respect for politics", after a succession of scandals under the Tories that eroded public trust.</p>

<p>But he sought to temper high expectations of an immediate transformation. "Changing a country is not like flicking a switch," he said.</p>

<p>"The world is now a more volatile place. This will take a while. But have no doubt that the work of change begins immediately."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/3r0lfsrg_starmer-10-_625x300_05_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/labour-partys-keir-starmer-officially-appointed-uk-pm-by-king-charles-6040573]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Labour Party's Keir Starmer Officially Appointed UK PM By King Charles]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/labour-partys-keir-starmer-officially-appointed-uk-pm-by-king-charles-6040573]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 05 Jul 2024 17:00:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Britain's head of state King Charles III officially appointed Labour leader Keir Starmer as prime minister on Friday during an audience at Buckingham Palace.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Britain's head of state King Charles III officially appointed Labour leader Keir Starmer as prime minister on Friday during an audience at Buckingham Palace.</p>

<p>A photograph released by the palace showed the monarch shaking hands with Starmer, whose party won a landslide election victory. The king earlier accepted the resignation of Conservative leader Rishi Sunak.</p>

<p>"The King received in Audience The Right Honourable Sir Keir Starmer MP today and requested him to form a new Administration," a palace statement read.</p>

<p>"Sir Keir accepted His Majesty's offer and kissed hands upon his appointment as Prime Minister and First Lord of the Treasury."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/3mtt47e8_starmer-king-1200_625x300_05_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/liz-truss-loses-seat-as-labour-wins-uk-election-ending-conservative-rule-6040412]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Former Prime Minister Liz Truss Loses Her Seat By 630 Votes In UK Election]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/liz-truss-loses-seat-as-labour-wins-uk-election-ending-conservative-rule-6040412]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 05 Jul 2024 16:42:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Liz Truss, Britain's shortest-serving prime minister, suffered further political ignominy Friday when she sensationally lost her seat in parliament at the British general election.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Liz Truss, Britain's shortest-serving prime minister, suffered further political ignominy Friday when she sensationally lost her seat in parliament at the British general election.</p>

<p>Truss's defeat came as the constituencies of all her predecessors since the Tories won power in 2010 turned either Labour or Liberal Democrat -- a damning indictment on the Conservatives' 14 years in power.</p>

<p>Truss, who sparked financial turmoil during her 49 chaotic days in charge in 2022, lost her Norfolk South West constituency in eastern England to Labour by 630 votes.</p>

<p>Labour candidate Terry Jermy overturned Truss's massive majority of more than 26,000 which she secured at the last election in 2019 -- a notional 27.85 percent swing.</p>

<p>Her defeat, announced shortly before 7:00 am (0600 GMT) capped a shocking performance for Rishi Sunak's Conservative party as Keir Starmer's Labour opposition won a landslide to return to power after 14 years.</p>

<p>Truss, a member of parliament since 2010, was slow hand-clapped onto the stage after keeping the other candidates waiting for several minutes. She left without making a speech.</p>

<p>But she told the BBC afterwards: "I think the issue we faced as Conservatives is we haven't delivered sufficiently on the policies people want."</p>

<p>Asked if she bore some responsibility, she said: "I agree. I was part of that. That's absolutely true."</p>

<p>Truss -- whose shelf-life as premier was lampooned as shorter than that of an Iceberg lettuce -- said she had "a lot to think about" when asked if she wanted to stay in politics.</p>

<p>Sunak held onto his seat in northern England but the Tories also lost the seats held by Truss's predecessors Boris Johnson, Theresa May, and David Cameron.</p>

<p>Labour took Johnson's previous constituency of Uxbridge and South Ruislip in northwest London while May's ex-seat of Maidenhead, also near the capital, was gained by the smaller Liberal Democrats party.</p>

<p>The Liberal Democrats also won Cameron's old seat of Witney in Oxfordshire.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-10/gaphchfo_liz-truss-reuters_625x300_21_October_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Truss lost her Norfolk South West constituency in eastern England to Labour by 630 votes.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/labour-party-sweeps-uk-2024-election-five-key-takeaways-6040213]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[5 Key Takeaways From UK General Election]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/labour-party-sweeps-uk-2024-election-five-key-takeaways-6040213]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 05 Jul 2024 16:16:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The UK general election marks a turning point for the country with Labour returning to power after 14 years of Conservatives in Downing Street.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The UK general election marks a turning point for the country with Labour returning to power after 14 years of Conservatives in Downing Street.</p>

<p>Here are the five biggest takeaways from a dramatic night.</p>

<h3><strong>Labour landslide, but not historic&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Labour won 412 seats in the 650-seat parliament with only three seats left to declare, guaranteeing the centre-left party a whopping majority after 14 years in opposition.</p>

<p>Keir Starmer, a 61-year-old former lawyer, will become prime minister after steering his party from one of its worst-ever performances in 2019 to victory.</p>

<p>His party capitalised on voter anger at the outgoing Tories, particularly in the so-called "red wall" -- post-industrial areas that traditionally voted Labour, but which switched Conservative in 2019.</p>

<p>However, contrary to polling throughout the campaign, Labour's landslide will be less spectacular than that won by Tony Blair in 1997 (418 seats) and the party, paradoxically, looks set to win fewer votes than it did in 2019's nadir election.</p>

<p>In fact, Labour's vote share of around 34 percent will be the lowest ever to secure a majority, highlighting the fracturing of the opposition and the quirks of the UK's electoral system.</p>

<p>Starmer will also face former Labour leader Jeremy Corbyn in the next parliament, who the incoming prime minister blocked from standing as a Labour candidate for his handling of accusations of anti-Semitism within the party.</p>

<p>The veteran left-winger stood as an independent and won, and threatens to be a thorn in the side of Starmer's government.</p>

<h3><strong>Hard-right breakthrough&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>The anti-immigration Reform UK, led by Brexit talisman Nigel Farage, fired a shot across the bows of the establishment by winning more than four million votes, the third-highest vote share of any party.</p>

<p>The party outperformed the Conservatives in many constituencies and performed strongly in "red wall" areas, but only ended up with four seats due to the first-past-the-post voting system.</p>

<p>Farage, 60, was elected for the first time in the constituency of Clacton-on-Sea, southeast England, and promised the result would be "just the first step of something that is going to stun all of you".</p>

<h3><strong>Conservative catastrophe&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>"Massacre, catastrophe, Waterloo..." There was no shortage of words to describe the depths of the defeat for the Tories, who won a landslide only five years ago but looked set to be reduced to around 120 seats.</p>

<p>A record nine senior ministers from the outgoing government lost, although several other big names narrowly saved their seats, including finance minister Jeremy Hunt and party chairman Richard Holden, who won by 20 votes.</p>

<p>A final humiliation arrived in the early morning when former prime minister Liz Truss, whose 49-day rule in 2022 ended when the markets turned against her radical tax-slashing plans, lost her seat.</p>

<p>Next will come the brutal post-mortem, as the party decides how it will rebuild and whether it tacks to the right or centre.</p>

<h3><strong>Scottish nationalists in crisis&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>The Scottish nationalists suffered a terrible evening, with former first minister and independence figurehead Nicola Sturgeon admitting that "it's not a good night" for the Scottish National Party (SNP).</p>

<p>The party has dominated Scottish politics for 15 years but has now ceded control to Labour and been relegated from third to fourth place in Westminster after returning just nine MPs, compared to 48 at the last election.</p>

<p>It is still under investigation over its financing and now has no clear strategy to win independence from the UK, a dream that seemed revived after the Brexit vote.</p>

<h3><strong>Lib Dem comeback&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>The return of the pro-EU Lib Dems as the third largest party and a major force in Westminster is one of the election's more unlikely stories following its dismal showing in 2019.</p>

<p>Winning more than 70 seats, the party enjoyed its best-ever result, eclipsing its success in the early 2000s that led it to form a coalition government with the Conservatives between 2010 and 2015.</p>

<p>The party also benefited from the rejection of the Conservatives by more liberal and centrist voters, who were turned off by its rightward drift following the Brexit vote.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/mrjhen9c_keir-starmer_625x300_05_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Labour won 412 seats in the 650-seat parliament with only three seats left to declare.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/2024-uk-election-result-record-number-of-indian-origin-mps-elected-to-british-parliament-6039751]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK Polls: Record Number Of Indian-Origin MPs Elected To British Parliament]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/2024-uk-election-result-record-number-of-indian-origin-mps-elected-to-british-parliament-6039751]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 05 Jul 2024 16:15:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A record number of around 26 Indian-origin members of Parliament have been elected to the House of Commons in the UK's general election as results were announced today.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A record number of around 26 Indian-origin members of Parliament have been elected to the House of Commons in the UK's general election as results were announced on Friday, with several Conservatives surviving an overall brutal outcome for their party.</p>

<p>Outgoing prime minister Rishi Sunak leads the Tory charge of British Indians holding on to their seats, with a decisive win in his Richmond and Northallerton constituency in Yorkshire. It would have come as small consolation for the Tory leader, who saw his party haemorrhage over 200 seats as the Labour Party's landslide victory unfolded.</p>

<p>"On this difficult night, I would like to express my gratitude to the people of the Richmond and Northallerton constituency for your continued support. Since I moved here a decade ago, you have made me and my family feel so at home and I look forward to serving you for years to come," said Sunak, in a message clearly aimed at dismissing pre-election chatter around his future plans as a politician.</p>

<p>Other prominent British Indian Tories holding on to their seats included former home secretaries, Suella Braverman and Priti Patel, as did Sunak's Goan-origin Cabinet ally Claire Coutinho. Gagan Mohindra held on to his South West Hertfordshire seat for the Conservatives, with Shivani Raja registering a gain for the party in the keenly watched constituency of Leicester East where she was contesting against fellow Indian-origin Labour candidate Rajesh Agrawal. They had both canvassed around the topic of saving the city's famous Diwali lights from being switched off over council budget cuts, as did former MP Keith Vaz who was contesting as an Independent this time.</p>

<p>Among the big losses on the Tory side included Shailesh Vara, who narrowly lost his North West Cambridgeshire seat to Labour, and first-timer Ameet Jogia, who also lost the Tory-held Hendon seat in London to Labour.</p>

<p>Reflective of the overall election results tally, it was the Labour Party that saw the maximum number of winning Indian diaspora candidates, starting with party veterans such as Seema Malhotra – who held on to her Feltham and Heston constituency with a comfortable margin. Goan-origin Valerie Vaz, sister of Keith Vaz, won in Walsall and Bloxwich, as did Lisa Nandy with a big margin in Wigan.</p>

<p>British Sikh MPs Preet Kaur Gill, who defeated Tory first-timer Ashvir Sangha, and Tanmanjeet Singh Dhesi both won back their seats for Labour in Birmingham Edgbaston and Slough respectively. Navendu Mishra (Stockport) and Nadia Whittome (Nottingham East) were among the other Labour MPs re-elected with convincing majorities.</p>

<p>It was among the newcomers that British Indians made a big mark for the Labour Party, with Jas Athwal (Ilford South), Baggy Shanker (Derby South), Satvir Kaur (Southampton Test), Harpreet Uppal (Huddersfield), Warinder Juss (Wolverhampton West), Gurinder Josan (Smethwick), Kanishka Narayan (Vale of Glamorgan), Sonia Kumar (Dudley), Sureena Brackenbridge (Wolverhampton North East), Kirith Entwistle (Bolton North East), Jeevun Sandher (Loughborough) and Sojan Joseph (Ashford) among those set to take their seats in Parliament next week.</p>

<p>For the Liberal Democrats, who had a good election all round gaining over 60 seats, Munira Wilson won back her Twickenham constituency.</p>

<p>One of the seats on the Labour watch list was Islington North, where suspended former party leader Jeremy Corbyn contested as an Independent to defeat his British Indian Labour challenger Praful Nargund.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-07/852d1qa_uk-parliament-generic_625x300_15_July_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Record number of Indian-origin Members of Parliament have been elected to the House of Commons in the UK]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-indias-upi-is-marking-its-presence-ahead-of-the-paris-olympics-6039423]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How India's UPI Is Marking Its Presence Ahead Of The Paris Olympics]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-indias-upi-is-marking-its-presence-ahead-of-the-paris-olympics-6039423]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 05 Jul 2024 15:52:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[After the successful implementation of the Unified Payments Interface or UPI for online ticket booking at Eiffel Tower, NPCI International Payments Limited (NIPL) today enabled the acceptance of UPI at Galeries Lafayette ahead of the Paris Olympics.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After the successful implementation of the Unified Payments Interface or UPI for online ticket booking at Eiffel Tower, NPCI International Payments Limited (NIPL) today enabled the acceptance of UPI at Galeries Lafayette's flagship store in Haussmann, ahead of Paris Olympics.</p>

<p>This is in partnership with Lyra, a French leader in securing e-commerce and proximity payments.</p>

<p>Starting July 26, the Paris Olympics is expected to draw a large number of Indian visitors. According to Jawed Ashraf, Ambassador of India to France and Monaco, this will pave the way for the wide acceptance of UPI in France and support its internationalisation as a means of digital payments.</p>

<p>"Our collaboration with Galeries Lafayette in Paris not only enables UPI payments at a prestigious venue but also boosts UPI adoption as a convenient and secure cross-border payment method for Indian tourists," Ritesh Shukla, CEO of NPCI International, said.</p>

<p>As per NPCI, this partnership will benefit a multitude of Indian tourists visiting Paris every year, allowing them to use UPI at the Galeries Lafayette flagship store.</p>

<p>"Lyra is happy to have enabled for the first time in Europe the in-store acceptance of UPI in the iconic Department stores Galeries Lafayette Haussmann in Paris," said Christophe Mariette, Chairman of Lyra India.</p>

<p>NPCI also mentioned that this initiative aims to broaden UPI's market presence in France and Europe, driving further growth and adoption as a secure payment solution.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-09/r4qbnl6_eiffel-tower-reuters_625x300_13_September_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[India's UPI payments are now available for online ticket booking at the Eiffel Tower.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/alien-contact-war-on-mars-baba-vangas-predictions-for-coming-years-6040031]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Alien Contact, War On Mars: Baba Vanga's Predictions For Coming Years]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/alien-contact-war-on-mars-baba-vangas-predictions-for-coming-years-6040031]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 05 Jul 2024 15:51:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Her prophecies for the future include significant events such as a major conflict in Europe in 2025, contact with extraterrestrials in 2130, and a war on Mars in 3005.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Vangelia Pandeva Gushterova, also known as Baba Vanga, was a blind Bulgarian mystic who died in 1996 at the age of 85. Even after her death, people all across the world are still fascinated by her prophecies. Called the 'Nostradamus of the Balkans,' Baba Vanga claimed that she lost her sight at the age of twelve and then developed the gift of prophecy.</p>

<p>One of her most prominent forecasts, according to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.marca.com/en/lifestyle/world-news/2024/07/03/668524b446163fc7398b45b3.html"><em>Marca.com</em></a>, was the September 11, 2001, attack on the Twin Towers in New York.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chilling-predictions-baba-vanga-made-for-2024-that-came-true-5069402"><strong>Also Read | Chilling Predictions Baba Vanga Made For 2024 That Came True</strong></a></p>

<p>"Two metal birds will crash into our American brothers, wolves will howl from the bushes, and the blood of the innocent will flow in the rivers," she predicted, a message eerily similar to the tragic events that unfolded.</p>

<p>Among her many prophecies, one stands out: the date of the end of the world. According to Baba Vanga, the world will end in the year 5079 due to a cosmic event of "unimaginable" proportions.</p>

<p><strong>Here are Baba Vanga's Key Predictions for the Coming Decades:</strong></p>

<ul>
	<li><strong>2025: </strong>A major conflict in Europe will lead to a significant reduction in the continent's population.</li>
	<li><strong>2028: </strong>Humanity will reach Venus in an attempt to find new sources of energy.</li>
	<li><strong>2033:</strong> The melting of the polar ice caps will cause a significant rise in sea levels.</li>
	<li><strong>2076: </strong>Communism will return globally.</li>
	<li><strong>2130: </strong>Contact with extraterrestrial civilisations.</li>
	<li><strong>2170: </strong>A global drought.</li>
	<li><strong>3005: </strong>A War on Mars.</li>
	<li><strong>3797: </strong>Destruction of the Earth, with humanity capable of moving to another planet within the solar system.</li>
	<li><strong>5079: </strong>The end of the world.</li>
</ul>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/baba-vangas-predictions-for-2024-and-when-the-world-might-end-5368311"><strong>Also Read | Baba Vanga's Predictions For 2024 And When The World Might End</strong></a></p>

<p>Baba Vanga's followers are still fascinated and speculating about these prophecies, which span a remarkably long period of time.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/ir7oc2v_baba-vanga_625x300_03_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Vangelia Pandeva Gushterova, better known as Baba Vanga, was a blind Bulgarian mystic.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-general-election-why-rishi-sunak-lost-from-crumbling-nhs-to-economic-crisis-why-rishi-sunak-lost-uk-election-6039983]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[From Crumbling Public Health Scheme To Economic Crisis, Why Rishi Sunak Lost]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-general-election-why-rishi-sunak-lost-from-crumbling-nhs-to-economic-crisis-why-rishi-sunak-lost-uk-election-6039983]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 05 Jul 2024 15:46:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Why did Labour thump the Conservatives? The crumbling NHS, or National Health Service, state of the economy, and attendant concerns like price rise, were all high on the list of reasons for the defeat.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Out with the old, and in with the new (sort of), UK voters said Friday, handing <a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/topic/rishi-sunak" target="_blank">Rishi Sunak</a>'s Conservatives a thumping defeat in the general election, stripping it off nearly 250 seats in the 650-seat House of Commons. And Sir <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/topic/keir-starmer" target="_blank">Keir Starmer</a>'s Labour has been handed the keys to the castle.</p>

<p>Mr Starmer and his 'new' Labour will now form the next government. Addressing a cheering crowd of party faithfuls at a dawn victory rally in central London, he declared <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-gets-its-future-back-labours-keir-starmer-in-victory-speech-6037737" target="_blank">the UK "gets its future back"</a>.</p>

<p>The scale of the Tories defeat is singular; in power for 14 years, the party was routed in Wales and Scotland, and saw some of its biggest leaders, including ex-Prime Minister Liz Truss, beaten.</p>

<h3><strong>Labour's Landslide</strong></h3>

<p>But perhaps the most chastening blow - the BBC is reporting the Conservatives have lost seats, in the shire counties of England, that they have held since the early 20th century. For example, Labour's Joe Morris beat the Tory's Guy Opperman to end the Tory's 100-year hold on the Hexham seat.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/i-am-sorry-uk-pm-rishi-sunak-concedes-defeat-in-uk-polls-6037606" target="_blank">"I Am Sorry": Rishi Sunak Concedes Defeat In UK Polls</a></p>

<p>The Conservatives are set for one of their worst ever returns in a general election, and Labour, with over 400 seats, its best. Exit polls had predicted just such a scenario, giving Mr Starmer 405 seats.</p>

<h3><strong>Conservatives' Collapse</strong></h3>

<p>Rishi Sunak, the outgoing PM, called for an early election in May.</p>

<p>The warning signs were present then; indeed, they had been present for several weeks, if not months, prior, as UK voters battled a cost-of-living crisis, a growing immigration problem, and poor infrastructure and healthcare, among other issues, and the Tories a serious image problem.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-election-results-live-rishi-sunak-braces-for-huge-loss-as-early-results-herald-labour-keir-starmer-win-6037190" target="_blank">Labour Sweeps UK Polls, Rishi Sunak's Part's First Loss Since 2010</a></p>

<p>At that point the Conservatives - asking the British public for permission to install a sixth Prime Minister since 2010 - were already 20 points behind a rejuvenated Labour, but Mr Sunak seemed to believe he could close and overhaul the gap. Unfortunately, this did not happen.</p>

<h3><strong>Why Labour Beat Conservative?</strong></h3>

<p>Take your pick. But the crumbling NHS, or National Health Service, and the state of the economy, and attendant concerns like price rise, are high on the list of reasons for the defeat.</p>

<p>A poll by IPSOS Issues Index in June said concerns over slashing of funding for the NHS - a free public healthcare scheme that any other country would love to have - was top of the list, followed by the economy, immigration, price rise, housing and schools, defence and anti-terrorism, and crime.</p>

<p>Mr Sunak scored poorly on all these points, including overseeing the country's lowest growth rate since the early 19th century and a steep cost-of-living increase, the highest in 41 years.</p>

<p>The <strong>British economy</strong> has slowed significantly over the past decade, even accounting for the global crisis triggered by the Covid pandemic. GDP per capita grew just 4.3 per cent from 2007 to 2023.</p>

<p>In the previous 16 years that figure was a massive 46 per cent.</p>

<p>This meant incomes stagnated.</p>

<p>A report by the nonpartisan Centres for Cities research institute indicated Britons, on average, had <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.aljazeera.com/economy/2024/6/26/10200-how-much-worse-off-britons-are-after-14-years-of-tory-rule" target="_blank">£10,200 less to save or spend</a> between 2010 and 2022, compared to 1998-2010 growth rates.</p>

<p>And&nbsp;the UK's national debt - £2.7 trillion - is higher than at any point since the 1960s.</p>

<p>There did seem to be some relief soon; in May the International Monetary Fund spoke of a "soft landing" for the economy, and upgraded the growth forecast by 0.2 percentage points to 0.7.</p>

<p>And it was, perhaps, on the back of that expectation Mr Sunak called for the early election.</p>

<p>The <strong>NHS</strong> is seen by many to be the crown in the British government's public services.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Add image caption here" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-05/a5mbqbjo_london-hospital-nhs-650_625x300_31_May_22.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Add image caption here" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">Funding for the UK's national free healthcare scheme, the NHS, has been a key issue (File).</p>
</div>

<p>The Conservatives had repeatedly stressed the importance of the NHS, but that concern seemed not to translate into on-ground support for doctors, nurses, and medical professionals.</p>

<p>Budgetary allocations under the Tories paint a clear picture. Since they came to power in 2010 healthcare spending has grown by an average of 2.8 per cent per year, compared to 3.6 per cent in the past 50. This includes the period of the pandemic.</p>

<p>In April there were an estimated 7.6 million people waiting for treatment under the NHS scheme, of which over 50,000 had been on the list for more than a year. The median wait time was 14 weeks.</p>

<p>The number of people waiting for medical aid, including those with serious conditions, has tripled under Conservative rule, according to data from the NHS published by <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2024/7/4/uk-general-election-2024-key-issues-by-the-numbers" target="_blank">Al Jazeera</a>.</p>

<p>Brexit had its say too, with movement restrictions meaning medical professionals from mainland Europe could either not be hired or chose not to sign up. As horrible as this sounds, this was good news for India, with the NHS turning to its former colony to fill over 2,000 doctors' posts.</p>

<p><strong>Immigration</strong> was also an issue. Mr Sunak's government had promised to crack down on illegal entrants into the UK, but its Rwanda policy - supposed to act as a major deterrent - failed to deliver.</p>

<p>In fact, two years after its announcement not one plane has taken off for the African nation.</p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://news.sky.com/story/general-election-labour-and-conservative-immigration-policies-explained-13146912" target="_blank">Sky News</a>, the Conservatives have spent over £300 million on this scheme, which they said would deter illegal immigrants entering the UK on small boats across the English Channel.</p>

<p>Under this policy, those caught would be sent to Rwanda while they apply for asylum.</p>

<p>As of March-end a total of 1.18 lakh people are waiting for an initial decision on their application.</p>

<p>The rising <strong>cost of living</strong> and skyrocketing <strong>house prices</strong>, as well as steep <strong>increases in rental prices</strong>, have also been a problem the Conservatives seemed not to be able to control.</p>

<h3><strong>Truss, Johnson's Contributions</strong></h3>

<p>It wasn't just Mr Sunak's failures that led to the Conservatives' downfall.</p>

<p>Boris Johnson was elected as the Tories' leader and the PM in July 2019, shortly before the pandemic struck. His dishevelled appearance and chaotic leadership precipitated a revolt by his ministers and, of course, the 'Partygate' scandal that referred to parties at 10, Downing Street during a lockdown.</p>

<p>Mr Johnson resigned in June last year following an investigation that he called a "witch hunt".</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Add image caption here" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/i140sem8_rishi-sunak-liz-truss-boris-johnson_625x300_01_July_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Add image caption here" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">The Conservatives' last three Prime Ministers - Rishi Sunak, Liz Truss, and Boris Johnson (File).</p>
</div>

<p>He was followed by Ms Truss - the UK's fourth female PM and its shortest-serving leader.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-political-crisis-why-the-country-has-seen-3-prime-ministers-in-3-years-6008758" target="_blank">UK In Crisis: Why Country Has Seen 3 PMs In 3 Years</a></p>

<p>Ms Truss - who lost her South West Norfolk seat - faced criticism for the way it handled the economy, including a controversial mini-budget that led to market turmoil. Her leadership was further undermined by U-turns on policy and a loss of confidence among MPs.</p>

<h3><strong>What Now For Labour?</strong></h3>

<p>Mr Starmer's leadership has been pivotal in Labour's revival.</p>

<p>Since taking up the role in early 2020, he has repositioned the party to the centre, and fixed problems within the party that include in-fighting and anti-Semitism.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Looking forward, he will want to avoid repeats of the Tories' mistakes, including&nbsp;October 2022, when Ms Truss' government proposed unfunded tax cuts that spooked markets and tanked the pound.</p>

<p>That ill-advised move cost her her job.</p>

<p>"We did it. Thank you truly... you have changed our country," Mr Starmer told triumphant supporters at a victory rally in central London. "(But) a mandate like this comes with a great responsibility... Today we start the next chapter... begin the work of change, the mission of national renewal, and start to rebuild."</p>

<p><em>NDTV is now available on WhatsApp channels. <a href="https://www.whatsapp.com/channel/0029Va4lixw7z4kcvZI9JM12">Click on the link</a> to get all the latest updates from NDTV on your chat. </em></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/c8u6i1l8_rishi-sunak_625x300_23_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Rishi Sunak, the outgoing British Prime Minister (File).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/i-am-sorry-have-heard-your-anger-rishi-sunak-as-he-leaves-office-6039900]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["I Am Sorry...Have Heard Your Anger": Rishi Sunak As He Leaves Office]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/i-am-sorry-have-heard-your-anger-rishi-sunak-as-he-leaves-office-6039900]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 05 Jul 2024 15:35:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Rishi Sunak on Friday apologised to the public after his Conservatives were trounced by Labour in the UK general election, and said he would step down as party leader.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Rishi Sunak on Friday apologised to the public after his Conservatives were trounced by Labour in the UK general election, and said he would step down as party leader.</p>

<p>The 44-year-old former financier gambled on going to the country six months before he had to, hoping that better economic data would swing public support back towards the Tories.</p>

<p>But Thursday's vote indicated that Britons wanted to send a clear message to the party by kicking them out of power after 14 years of economic hardships, Brexit upheaval and Tory infighting.</p>

<p>"To the country, I would like to say first and foremost, I am sorry," he said outside the Prime Minister's residence at Downing Street, before heading to Buckingham Palace to tender his resignation as prime minister to King Charles III.</p>

<p>"I have given this job my all, but you have sent a clear signal that the government of the United Kingdom must change. And yours is the only judgement that matters."</p>

<p>"I have heard your anger, your disappointment, and I take responsibility for this loss."</p>

<p>The scale of the defeat made it inevitable that Sunak -- the conservative party's fifth leader since 2010 -- would have to step down as Tory head as well.</p>

<p>But he said that he would stay on in the role until the arrangements were made for an internal leadership contest, which is expected to be a fight for the ideological soul of the party.</p>

<p>Sunak saw a record number of his top ministerial team lose their seats, including defence secretary Grant Shapps and House of Commons leader Penny Mordaunt.</p>

<p>His immediate predecessor as prime minister, Liz Truss, also lost her seat.</p>

<p>Sunak -- an observant Hindu who is Britain's first prime minister of colour -- wished his successor Keir Starmer well, calling him "a decent, public-spirited man who I respect".</p>

<p>"One of the most remarkable things about Britain is just how unremarkable it is that two generations after my grandparents came here with little, I could become prime minister," he added.</p>

<p>"And that I could watch my two young daughters light Diwali candles on the steps in Downing Street. We must hold true to that idea of who we are."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/m5vcph5_rishi-sunak-1200_625x300_05_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/swear-words-aimed-at-tories-larry-the-cat-speaks-out-on-uk-poll-results-6039898]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Swear Words Aimed At Tories": Larry The Cat Speaks Out On UK Poll Results]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/swear-words-aimed-at-tories-larry-the-cat-speaks-out-on-uk-poll-results-6039898]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 05 Jul 2024 15:34:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Larry the Cat, Chief Mouser of 10 Downing Street, has shared his thoughts on the recent UK election results.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Larry the Cat, Chief Mouser of 10 Downing Street, has shared his thoughts on the recent UK election results.&nbsp;The beloved feline posted a picture of himself standing at a miniature podium, complete with a tiny microphone as if delivering a speech. Larry's caption poked fun at the election outcome, saying, "The people have spoken and what they've said is mainly swear words aimed at the Tories."<br />
<br />
The post was a purr-fect jab at the Conservative Party's defeat in the general election.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">"The people have spoken and what they've said is mainly swear words aimed at the Tories"<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/GeneralElection2024?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#GeneralElection2024</a> <a href="https://t.co/jHR2iaGKML">pic.twitter.com/jHR2iaGKML</a></p>
— Larry the Cat (@Number10cat) <a href="https://twitter.com/Number10cat/status/1809092277354086895?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 5, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The UK's Labour Party, led by Keir Starmer, <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-general-election-results-2024-live-keir-starmer-labour-party-tipped-for-historic-sweep-rishi-sunak-conservatives-6034921 ">secured a decisive victory</a> with most seats in the House of Commons and ending 14 years of Conservative rule. Rishi Sunak, the outgoing Prime Minister, conceded defeat as several cabinet members lost their seats.<br />
<br />
Larry is a brown-and-white tabby cat rescued from the Battersea Dogs and Cats Home. PM David Cameron and his wife chose him as a pet for their children.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
Throughout the political turmoil of the past 14 years, Larry has remained a constant presence in Downing Street, serving under five Conservative prime ministers since 2011. The cat has since completed 13 years in the Parliament home.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
Last year, <a href="http:// https://x.com/Number10cat/status/1625773929942904834?lang=en ">Larry celebrated his 12 years</a>, saying how he was appointed Chief Mouser to the Cabinet Office “12 years ago” and boasted about outlasting “four Prime Ministers and have been in charge here longer than Thatcher, Blair, Churchill and Disraeli.”<br />
<br />
With the current change in government, Larry will soon welcome his first Labour prime minister, Keir Starmer. The departure of Rishi Sunak also means Larry will bid farewell to Nova, the fox-red labrador retriever.<br />
<br />
Earlier, Rishi Sunak's wife Akshata Murty revealed the behind-the-scenes dynamics of <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/feature/larry-the-cat-or-nova-the-dog-akshata-murty-on-power-struggle-at-10-downing-street-4422196 ">Downing Street's furry residents</a>. “Nova has mixed emotions about (living here) because she sometimes doesn't get on with Larry the Cat. And they've had some heated exchanges and Larry's come out on top," she said.<br />
<br />
In November 2022, Larry voiced his displeasure <a href="https://x.com/Number10cat/status/1587323660817375232 ">on X</a> when Rishi Sunak's family moved in with Nova, saying, "ANOTHER dog?! Bring back Liz Truss..."<br />
<br />
This wasn't the first time Larry had had a problem with canine companions in Downing Street. In 2019, when Boris Johnson's Jack Russell Cross, Dilyn, joined the household, Larry <a href="https://x.com/Number10cat/status/1168478009692708864 ">tweeted</a>, "Confirmation that Downing Street is going to the dogs...."&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/jl6dfvu8_larry-the-cat_625x300_05_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Larry is a brown-and-white tabby cat rescued from the Battersea Dogs and Cats Home.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/artificial-intelligence/whatsapp-ai-meta-ai-ai-whatsapp-ventures-into-personalized-ai-avatars-with-new-feature-development-6039839]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[WhatsApp Ventures Into Personalized AI Avatars With New Feature]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/artificial-intelligence/whatsapp-ai-meta-ai-ai-whatsapp-ventures-into-personalized-ai-avatars-with-new-feature-development-6039839]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 05 Jul 2024 15:27:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[According to The Verge, the feature discovered in the WhatsApp Beta for Android version 2.24.14.7 harnesses a combination of user-provided images, text prompts, and Meta's AI Llama model to generate these custom avatars.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>WhatsApp is in the process of developing a new feature that will enable users to create personalised AI avatars of themselves, capable of being placed in various virtual settings.</p>

<p>According to The Verge, the feature discovered in the WhatsApp Beta for Android version 2.24.14.7 harnesses a combination of user-provided images, text prompts, and Meta's AI Llama model to generate these custom avatars.</p>

<p>According to the screenshots captured by The Verge, users will have the ability to envision themselves "in any setting, from the forest to outer space."</p>

<p>The generated images are reportedly reminiscent of those produced by popular AI generators like Lensa AI or Snapchat's "Dreams" selfie feature.</p>

<p>To generate these personalised avatars, WhatsApp users will initially need to submit photographs of themselves, which will serve as reference images for Meta AI.</p>

<p>Subsequently, users can create their avatars by typing commands such as "Imagine me" followed by a description of the desired setting in Meta AI chat or by using "@Meta AI imagine me..." in other WhatsApp conversations.</p>

<p>This feature is expected to be optional and will require users to manually enable it in WhatsApp settings.</p>

<p>Furthermore, users will have the flexibility to delete the reference images stored in Meta AI settings at any time, ensuring privacy and control over personal data.</p>

<p>Despite its innovative potential, there is no specific timeline for the general availability of this new AI avatar feature. WhatsApp continues to roll out support for its Meta AI chatbot and real-time AI image generation capabilities, particularly in the United States.</p>

<p>Therefore, the launch of the AI avatar feature may be subject to gradual deployment as WhatsApp and Meta navigate the complexities associated with generative AI tools, according to The Verge.</p>

<p>Given previous challenges with generative AI technologies, Meta appears to be adopting a cautious approach to ensure the functionality and security of this upcoming feature.</p>

<p>As development progresses, WhatsApp users can anticipate a new dimension of personalisation and creativity in their messaging experience, facilitated by advanced AI capabilities.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/27iug13o_whatsapp_625x300_05_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[WhatsApp users will initially need to submit photographs of themselves for Meta AI avatars]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>