<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Wed, 10 Jul 2024 04:55:14 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/27-killed-in-strike-on-gaza-school-sheltering-palestinians-report-6071661]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[27 Killed In Strike On Gaza School Sheltering Palestinians: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/27-killed-in-strike-on-gaza-school-sheltering-palestinians-report-6071661]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 10 Jul 2024 04:55:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Palestinian sources said at least 29 people were killed Tuesday in a strike on a school being used to shelter displaced people in Gaza, the fourth such incident in four days, with Hamas blaming Israel for the deaths.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Palestinian sources said at least 29 people were killed Tuesday in a strike on a school being used to shelter displaced people in Gaza, the fourth such incident in four days, with Hamas blaming Israel for the deaths.</p>

<p>Israel's military told AFP it had carried out a strike in the area and was reviewing the incident. It has acknowledged carrying out three other strikes since Saturday on Gaza schools being used as shelters.</p>

<p>The strike hit the entrance to Al-Awda school in Abasan, said a source at Nasser hospital in the nearby southern city of Khan Yunis, where victims were taken, adding that 29 were killed and dozens wounded.</p>

<p>The Hamas-run government media office accused Israel of carrying out a "terrible massacre" and also gave the death toll as 29, saying the "majority" were women and children.</p>

<p>"We were sitting at the entrance of the school... suddenly and without warning, rockets were fired," a witness, Mohammed Sukkar, told AFP about Tuesday's strike.</p>

<p>The Israel military said the air force had used "precise munition" to strike a "terrorist from Hamas' military wing" near the school.</p>

<p>"The incident is under review," the military said in a statement.</p>

<p>Officials in the Hamas-run territory said at least 20 people were killed in the earlier attacks on the schools.</p>

<p>Israel said all three of those strikes had targeted militants hiding in the schools.</p>

<p>On Saturday, an Israeli strike hit the UN-run Al-Jawni school in Nuseirat, central Gaza, killing 16 people, according to the health ministry.</p>

<p>The UN agency for Palestinian refugees, UNRWA, said 2,000 people were sheltering there at the time.</p>

<p>The following day a strike on the Holy Family school in Gaza City killed four, according to Gaza's civil defence agency.</p>

<p>The Latin Patriarchate, owners of the school, said hundreds of people had packed the grounds at the time.</p>

<p>Another UNRWA-run school in Nuseirat was hit on Monday. A local hospital said several people were taken in for treatment.</p>

<p>Israel said it had targeted "several terrorists" using the school for cover.</p>

<p>Hamas has denied Israeli claims that it uses schools, hospitals and other civilian facilities for military aims.</p>

<p>According to UNRWA, more than 500 people have been killed in schools and</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/gfu9afl8_israel-hamas-war_625x300_02_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel said all three of those strikes had targeted militants hiding in the schools.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/australia-accuses-china-backed-hacker-group-of-stealing-user-data-6071428]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Australia Accuses China-Backed Hacker Group Of Stealing User Data]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/australia-accuses-china-backed-hacker-group-of-stealing-user-data-6071428]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 10 Jul 2024 03:34:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Cybersecurity firms backed by the Chinese authorities have been accused of stealing passwords and usernames from unnamed Australian networks in 2022, the Australian Cyber Security Centre (ACSC) reported on Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Cybersecurity firms backed by the Chinese authorities have been accused of stealing passwords and usernames from unnamed Australian networks in 2022, the Australian Cyber Security Centre (ACSC) reported on Tuesday.</p>

<p>The investigation against the CCP-backed hacker group titled APT40 involved Australian Cyber Security Centre, the United States Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA), the United States National Security Agency (NSA), the United States Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI), the United Kingdom National Cyber Security Centre (NCSC-UK), the Canadian Centre for Cyber Security (CCCS), the New Zealand National Cyber Security Centre (NCSC-NZ), the German Federal Intelligence Service (BND) and Federal Office for the Protection of the Constitution (BfV), the Republic of Korea's National Intelligence Service (NIIS) and NIS' National Cyber Security Center, and Japan's National Center of Incident Readiness and Strategy for Cybersecurity (NISC) and National Police Agency (NPA), calling them authoring agencies.</p>

<p>The ACSA claimed that APT40 had conducted several cyber security operations for the PRC Ministry of State Security (MSS).</p>

<p>ACSA also claimed that "The activity and techniques overlap with the groups tracked as Advanced Persistent Threat (APT) 40" quoting the inputs from leading cyber security agencies from the US, Britain, Canada, New Zealand, Japan, South Korea and Germany.</p>

<p>According to the Activity summary section of the report by ACSA APT40 has repeatedly targeted Australian networks as well as government and private sector networks in the region, and the threat they pose to our networks is ongoing.</p>

<p>The tradecraft described in this advisory is regularly observed against Australian networks. Additionally, APT40 possesses the capability to rapidly transform and adapt exploit proof-of-concept(s) (POCs) of new vulnerabilities and immediately utilise them against target networks possessing the infrastructure of the associated vulnerability.</p>

<p>APT40 regularly conducts reconnaissance against networks of interest, including networks in the authoring agencies' countries, looking for opportunities to compromise its targets.<br />
The same report also claimed that the Hacker group also prefers to exploit vulnerable, public-facing infrastructure, using techniques that require user interaction, it puts high priority on obtaining valid credentials to enable a range of follow-on activities using web shells.</p>

<p>The investigative report of the ACSC claimed that in August 2022, a confirmed malicious IP address believed to be connected with the cyber group had interacted with the organisation's computer networks between at least July and August. The compromised device probably belonged to a small business or home user.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-07/g478ahcs_hacking-reuters_650x400_19_July_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The tradecraft described in this advisory is regularly observed against Australian networks.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-to-meet-volodymyr-zelensky-at-nato-summit-tomorrow-6071243]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden To Meet Zelensky At NATO Summit Tomorrow]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-to-meet-volodymyr-zelensky-at-nato-summit-tomorrow-6071243]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 10 Jul 2024 02:26:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden will meet his Ukrainian counterpart Volodymyr Zelensky at NATO's 75th anniversary summit in Washington on Thursday to show "unwavering support" for Kyiv, the White House said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden will meet his Ukrainian counterpart Volodymyr Zelensky at NATO's 75th anniversary summit in Washington on Thursday to show "unwavering support" for Kyiv, the White House said.</p>

<p>"On Thursday afternoon, President Biden will meet with President Zelensky of Ukraine to discuss our unwavering support for Ukraine as it continues to defend itself from Russian aggression," press secretary Karine Jean-Pierre told a briefing Tuesday.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-12/e1fa6t6_biden-zelensky_625x300_07_December_23.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Joe Biden will meet his counterpart Volodymyr Zelensky tomorrow in Washington.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-says-india-has-ability-to-urge-putin-to-end-war-in-ukraine-6071210]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Says India Has Ability To Urge Putin To End War In Ukraine]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-says-india-has-ability-to-urge-putin-to-end-war-in-ukraine-6071210]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 10 Jul 2024 02:13:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India's relationship with Russia gives it an ability to urge President Vladimir Putin to end its war with Ukraine, White House spokesperson Karine Jean-Pierre said on Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India's relationship with Russia gives it an ability to urge President Vladimir Putin to end its war with Ukraine, White House spokesperson Karine Jean-Pierre said on Tuesday.</p>

<p>Jean-Pierre made the remarks after Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi told Putin that the death of innocent children was painful and terrifying, a day after a lethal strike on a children's hospital in the Ukrainian capital, Kyiv.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/u8f6mif_pm-modi-and-putin_625x300_09_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[PM Modi told Putin that the death of innocent children was painful during ongoig Ukraine war.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-would-serve-full-second-term-if-elected-white-house-6070984]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden Would Serve Full Second Term If Elected: White House]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-would-serve-full-second-term-if-elected-white-house-6070984]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 10 Jul 2024 01:02:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden is committed to serving a full second term if reelected in November, the White House said Tuesday, as the 81-year-old fights for political survival as concerns mount over his age and fitness.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden is committed to serving a full second term if reelected in November, the White House said Tuesday, as the 81-year-old fights for political survival as concerns mount over his age and fitness.</p>

<p>"Yes," White House press secretary Karine Jean-Pierre said when asked during a daily briefing if the Democrat pledged to serve another four years should he beat Donald Trump in the 2024 election.</p>

<p>The spokeswoman said she believed Democrats were now "absolutely" united behind Biden, as the party's lawmakers held critical talks on whether he should step aside as candidate in November.</p>

<p>"We do want to turn the page... We want to get to the other side of this," Jean-Pierre said when asked if Biden now believed the crisis was behind him.</p>

<p>"He wants to move forward, unite the party," she said. "The president's going to move forward."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/o44j52qo_joe-biden_625x300_03_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Biden is committed to serving a full second term if reelected in November, the White House said Tuesday.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/8-killed-as-storm-beryl-sweeps-across-us-death-count-rises-to-18-6070782]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[8 Killed As Storm Beryl Sweeps Across US, Death Count Rises To 18]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/8-killed-as-storm-beryl-sweeps-across-us-death-count-rises-to-18-6070782]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 10 Jul 2024 00:05:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[At least eight people were killed in the southern United States after storm Beryl felled trees and caused heavy flooding, before being downgraded to a post-tropical cyclone on Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At least eight people were killed in the southern United States after storm Beryl felled trees and caused heavy flooding, before being downgraded to a post-tropical cyclone on Tuesday.</p>

<p>In Texas, where Beryl entered as a Category 1 hurricane early Monday, at least seven people were killed, while another person died in neighboring Louisiana, authorities said.</p>

<p>Beryl's death toll is now at least 18 after it tore through the Caribbean last week -- at one point as a Category 5 hurricane, the highest recordable strength.</p>

<p>Some 2.2 million households in Texas were without electricity Tuesday due to damaged power grids, even as temperatures were forecast to reach 41C (106F) with humidity factored in.</p>

<p>Another 14,000 homes were also without power in Louisiana.</p>

<p>Air-conditioned shelters for residents were set up while crews worked to restore service.</p>

<p>Beryl weakened Tuesday and was heading northeast towards Canada with 30 miles (45 kilometers) per hour winds, the US National Hurricane Center said, warning it could still generate flooding and tornadoes.</p>

<p>The sprawling city of Houston, home to 2.3 million people, was badly battered by hurricane-strength winds and flooding.</p>

<p>Harris County Sheriff Ed Gonzalez said on X that a 53-year-old man and 74-year-old woman had died in separate incidents of trees falling on houses.</p>

<p>Later, Houston Mayor John Whitmire told a press conference that one person died after a lightning strike possibly ignited a fire, while a police department employee died in floodwaters on his way to work.</p>

<p>Meanwhile in Louisiana, one death was announced by the Bossier Parish sheriff's office, also caused by a tree falling on a home.</p>

<h3><strong>'Very rare'</strong></h3>

<p>Rose Michalec, 51, told AFP that Beryl blew down fences in her south Houston neighborhood.</p>

<p>"It's quite a bit of damage... It's more than we expected," she said.</p>

<p>In downtown Houston, several areas were inundated, including the park where 76-year-old Floyd Robinson usually walks.</p>

<p>"I'm seeing more of this kind of damaging water than I've ever seen before," the lifelong Houston resident told AFP.</p>

<p>"This is just the beginning of July and for us to have a storm of this magnitude is very rare."</p>

<p>Along the Texas coastline, several waterfront homes and buildings had their roofs torn off by the wind.</p>

<h3><strong>Path across Caribbean</strong></h3>

<p>Beryl first slammed Grenada and Saint Vincent and the Grenadines as a Category 4 storm, before plowing past the Cayman Islands and Jamaica, and at one point strengthening to Category 5.</p>

<p>It hit Mexico on Friday, flattening trees and lampposts and ripping off roof tiles.</p>

<p>Beryl left a deadly toll with three deaths in Grenada, two in St. Vincent and the Grenadines, three in Venezuela and two in Jamaica.</p>

<p>It is the first hurricane since NHC record-keeping began to reach the Category 4 level in June, and the earliest to hit the highest Category 5 in July.</p>

<p>Beryl is also the earliest hurricane to make landfall in Texas in a decade, according to expert Michael Lowry.</p>

<p>It is extremely rare for such a powerful storm to form this early in the Atlantic hurricane season, which runs from early June to late November.</p>

<p>Scientists say climate change likely plays a role in the rapid intensification of storms such as Beryl because there is more energy in a warmer ocean for them to feed on.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/plp6s4t_beryl_625x300_09_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Beryl is also the earliest hurricane to make landfall in Texas in a decade]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/saudi-teacher-gets-20-year-jail-term-over-critical-social-media-posts-6070728]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Saudi Teacher Gets 20-Year Jail Term Over Critical Social Media Posts]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/saudi-teacher-gets-20-year-jail-term-over-critical-social-media-posts-6070728]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 23:56:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Saudi Arabia has sentenced a teacher to 20 years in prison over critical social media posts, Human Rights Watch and the convicted man's brother said Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Saudi Arabia has sentenced a teacher to 20 years in prison over critical social media posts, Human Rights Watch and the convicted man's brother said Tuesday.</p>

<p>Asaad al-Ghamdi, 47, was arrested in November 2022, in a nighttime raid on his home in the Saudi city of Jeddah, according to HRW.</p>

<p>He was convicted on May 29 by Saudi Arabia's Specialised Criminal Court, which was established in 2008 to try suspects accused of terrorism, the New York-based rights group said.</p>

<p>He was sentenced "to 20 years in prison on charges related to his peaceful social media activity", HRW added, calling it "yet another escalation in the country's ever-worsening crackdown on freedom of expression".</p>

<p>Court documents reviewed by HRW showed that Ghamdi was charged with "challenging the religion and justice of the King and the Crown Prince" and "publishing false and malicious news and rumors".&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to HRW, the posts used as evidence against him criticised projects related to the Vision 2030 reform agenda.</p>

<p>One post mourned Abdallah al-Hamed, a leading Saudi human rights figure who died in prison following his conviction on charges relating to his activism.</p>

<p>Ghamdi faces the same charges as his brother Mohammad, a government critic who denounced alleged corruption and human rights abuses on social media.</p>

<p>Mohammad was sentenced to death last year based on his social media activity.</p>

<p>Their third brother, Saeed, an Islamic scholar and government critic living in exile in the United Kingdom, condemned the latest move by Saudi authorities.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The accusations are arbitrary and unjust because they are all based on tweets," Saeed told AFP, commenting on the verdict against Asaad.</p>

<p>"Maybe I am the target," he added.</p>

<p>Over the past two years, the Saudi judiciary has convicted and handed down lengthy prison terms to dozens of individuals for their social media posts, according to rights groups.</p>

<p>They include Nourah al-Qahtani, who was sentenced to 45 years in prison in 2022, largely over social media posts criticising the government</p>

<p>Salma al-Shehab, a member of the Sunni-ruled kingdom's Shiite minority, was sentenced to 34 years behind bars in 2022 for aiding dissidents seeking to "disrupt public order" in the kingdom by relaying their tweets.</p>

<p>Manahel al-Otaibi, a 29-year-old blogger and fitness instructor, was arrested in November 2022 for challenging Saudi male guardianship laws and requirements for women to wear the customary body-shrouding abaya robe.</p>

<p>The Specialised Criminal Court sentenced her to 11 years in prison on January 9, but the sentence was only made public later in a Saudi submission to United Nations special rapporteurs enquiring about the case.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-01/fh1k7t2o_jail-generic-getty_625x300_20_January_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/10-killed-in-strike-on-school-in-gaza-fourth-attack-in-4-days-report-6070611]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[10 Killed In Strike On School In Gaza, Fourth Attack In 4 Days: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/10-killed-in-strike-on-school-in-gaza-fourth-attack-in-4-days-report-6070611]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 23:31:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Gaza hospital source said at least 10 people were killed and dozens wounded Tuesday in a strike on a school turned shelter for displaced Palestinians, the fourth such attack in four days.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Gaza hospital source said at least 10 people were killed and dozens wounded Tuesday in a strike on a school turned shelter for displaced Palestinians, the fourth such attack in four days.</p>

<p>The strike hit the gate at the Al-Awda school in Abasan, near the southern city of Khan Yunis, said the source at Nasser hospital in Khan Yunis where victims were taken.</p>

<p>There was no immediate comment from Israel, which has acknowledged carrying out three other strikes since Saturday on Gaza schools used as displacement shelters.</p>

<p>At least 20 people were killed in these attacks, according to officials in the Hamas-run territory.</p>

<p>Israel said all three strikes targeted operatives hiding in the schools.</p>

<p>On Saturday, an Israeli strike hit the UN-run Al-Jawni school in Nuseirat, central Gaza, killing 16 people, according to the territory's health ministry.</p>

<p>The UN agency for Palestinian refugees, UNRWA, said 2,000 people were sheltering there at the time.</p>

<p>The following day a strike on the church-run Holy Family school in Gaza City killed four, according to the civil defence agency.</p>

<p>The Latin Patriarchate, owners of the school, said hundreds of people had packed the grounds.</p>

<p>Another UNRWA-run school in Nuseirat was hit on Monday, with a local hospital saying several people were taken for treatment.</p>

<p>Israel said it targeted "several terrorists" using the school for cover.</p>

<p>Hamas has denied Israeli claims that it uses schools, hospitals and other civilian facilities for military aims.</p>

<p>According to UNRWA, more than 500 people have been killed in schools and other shelters it runs in Gaza since the war started on October 7 with the Hamas attack on Israel.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/4e11d1u8_gaza-school-attack_625x300_09_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel said all three strikes targeted operatives hiding in the schools]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/special-role-of-our-friendship-pm-modi-thanks-putin-for-fertilizer-supply-6070441]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Special Role Of Friendship": PM Modi Thanks Putin For Fertilizer Supply]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/special-role-of-our-friendship-pm-modi-thanks-putin-for-fertilizer-supply-6070441]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 23:01:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India increased its imports of Russian grain and grain products 22 fold, well above other major importers, in the 2023/24 agricultural season, according to data released during Prime Minister Narendra Modi's visit to Moscow.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India increased its imports of Russian grain and grain products 22 fold, well above other major importers, in the 2023/24 agricultural season, according to data released during Prime Minister Narendra Modi's visit to Moscow.</p>

<p>Economic cooperation between the two BRICS members and major agricultural powers is high on the agenda of the visit.</p>

<p>Modi thanked Russian President Vladimir Putin for supporting Indian farmers with stable supplies of fertilizers. At the start of the year, Russia was supplying a third of India's fertilizer imports.</p>

<p>"Thanks to our friendship, we managed to resolve difficulties for Indian farmers. We met all their needs for fertilizers. This is a special role of our friendship," PM Modi told Putin during a meeting in the Kremlin.</p>

<p>Russia and India have set a bilateral trade target of $100 billion across a "broad base" by 2030, up from the current $65 billion, Indian Foreign Secretary Vinay Mohan Kwatra said on Tuesday.</p>

<p>Data released by the Russian agricultural watchdog showed that Russia exported up to 89.3 million tons of grain and grain products in the 2023/24 agricultural season, 21% more than in the previous season.</p>

<p>India, with its 22-fold increase, was well ahead of Indonesia with an eight-fold increase and Tunisia with a three-fold increase. According to the Russian agriculture ministry's data, Russia was the fourth-largest agricultural products exporter to India in the first quarter of 2024.</p>

<p>The agricultural watchdog did not provide specific details of exports to India, but noted that, in the latest agricultural season, overall exports of barley rose by 67% and corn by 31%.</p>

<p>Russia does not currently export wheat to India, which has imposed a prohibitive 40% tax on wheat imports. However, wheat prices in India, the world's second-biggest producer of the grain, have been rising in recent weeks due to concerns over supplies.</p>

<p>In light of these concerns, there is speculation that the Indian government may abolish or reduce the current import tax to keep prices low, potentially opening the way for wheat from Russia, the world's leading wheat exporter, to enter the local market for the first time in six years.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/90845qlg_modi-putin_625x300_09_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["Thanks to our friendship, we managed to resolve difficulties for Indian farmers," PM Modi told Putin]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rwanda-government-says-uk-migrant-deal-did-not-stipulate-return-of-funds-6070340]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Rwanda Government Says UK Migrant Deal Did Not Stipulate Return Of Funds]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rwanda-government-says-uk-migrant-deal-did-not-stipulate-return-of-funds-6070340]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 22:48:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Rwandan government said Tuesday that its controversial migrant deal with the UK did not stipulate the return of funds, following the decision by Britain's new government to scrap the scheme.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Rwandan government said Tuesday that its controversial migrant deal with the UK did not stipulate the return of funds, following the decision by Britain's new government to scrap the scheme.</p>

<p>British Prime Minister Keir Starmer announced on Saturday that the plan forged by the ousted Conservative government to deport asylum seekers to the East African country was "dead and buried".</p>

<p>London has already paid Kigali £240 million ($307 million) since ex-PM Boris Johnson first announced the scheme in April 2022, despite a slew of legal challenges over the plan in the UK that had prevented it from ever getting up and running.</p>

<p>"The agreement we signed did not stipulate that we should return the money," Rwanda's deputy government spokesperson Alain Mukuralinda told state television on Tuesday.</p>

<p>"Let this be clear, paying back the money was never part of the agreement."</p>

<p>Mukuralinda said the UK had approached Rwanda and requested a partnership, which was "discussed extensively."</p>

<p>"The agreement went to the courts, and it was even amended after the results from the courts," he said.</p>

<p>A spate of legal challenges had dogged the controversial scheme, with the UK Supreme Court in November last year ruling that it was illegal under international law.</p>

<p>However, earlier this year, Sunak had pushed through legislation in parliament that deemed Rwanda a safe country, clearing one hurdle for the flights despite concerns about human rights laws.</p>

<p>"It went to the parliament and eventually became a treaty between two countries. A treaty provides an exit clause," Mukuralinda said.</p>

<h3><strong>Starmer scraps scheme</strong></h3>

<p>The Labour Party said before the July 4 election that it would ditch the scheme, which the Conservative government had said was designed to deter huge numbers of migrants trying to get across the Channel to the UK on boats from northern France.</p>

<p>Following the leftwing party's landslide win earlier this month, Starmer announced in his first press conference that the scheme would be scrapped.</p>

<p>"The Rwanda scheme was dead and buried before it started," he told reporters.</p>

<p>"I'm not prepared to continue with gimmicks that don't act as a deterrent."</p>

<p>Starmer said previously that Sunak's policy was neither a deterrent nor value for money, instead pledging to tackle the issue "upstream" by smashing the people-smuggling gangs behind the crossings.</p>

<p>Immigration has become an increasingly central political issue since the UK left the European Union in 2020, largely on a promise to "take back control" of the country's borders.</p>

<p>Rwanda, home to 13 million people in Africa's Great Lakes region, claims to be one of the most stable countries on the continent and has drawn praise for its modern infrastructure.</p>

<p>But rights groups accuse veteran President Paul Kagame of ruling in a climate of fear, stifling dissent and free speech.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/3jhafdkg_rwanda-bill_625x300_23_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Rwanda is home to 13 million people in Africa's Great Lakes region]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-court-issues-warrant-for-putin-critic-alexei-navalnys-wife-6070283]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russia Court Issues Warrant For Putin Critic Alexei Navalny's Wife]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-court-issues-warrant-for-putin-critic-alexei-navalnys-wife-6070283]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 22:39:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russia on Tuesday issued an arrest warrant for Yulia Navalnaya, accusing the exiled opposition figure of participating in an "extremist organisation".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russia on Tuesday issued an arrest warrant for Yulia Navalnaya, accusing the exiled opposition figure of participating in an "extremist organisation".</p>

<p>A court said it had "approved the request of the investigators and decided a preventive measure in the form of detention for two months".&nbsp;</p>

<p>Navalnaya has vowed to continue the work of her husband Alexei Navalny, Russian leader Vladimir Putin's main opponent who died in an Arctic prison in February.</p>

<p>Navalnaya slammed the warrant in a statement, &nbsp;saying :"Vladimir Putin is a killer and a war criminal. He belongs in prison".</p>

<p>The activist's team also dismissed the allegations.</p>

<p>Navalnaya "was arrested (in absentia!) for 'being a member of an extremist community' by the infamous Basmanny court of Moscow," wrote Leonid Volkov, Navalny's former chief of staff, on X.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Quite a recognition of Yulia's determination to continue Alexei's fight!" he added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Navalny's organisations have been outlawed in Russia, labelled an "extremist" group and put on an official "terrorist" list.</p>

<p>Navalnaya, an economist, stood by her husband as he galvanised mass protests in Russia, flying him out of the country when he was poisoned before defiantly returning to Moscow with him in 2021, knowing he would be jailed.</p>

<p>Following his death, Navalnaya vowed to take up her late husband's work and has lobbied against &nbsp;Putin's government from abroad. &nbsp;</p>

<p>During Russian elections in March, Navalnaya called for mass protests against Putin by forming long queues outside voting stations.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-02/7v3it1_yulia-navalnaya_625x300_20_February_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The activist's team also dismissed the allegations.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/challenge-me-at-convention-biden-goes-full-trump-to-save-white-house-bid-6070196]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Challenge Me At Convention: Biden Goes 'Full Trump' To Save White House Bid]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/challenge-me-at-convention-biden-goes-full-trump-to-save-white-house-bid-6070196]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 22:28:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[With their president calling into a morning TV show and bashing so-called elites, US voters could be forgiven a sense of deja vu. But this time it's Joe Biden, not Donald Trump who's on the other end of the line.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With their president calling into a morning TV show and bashing so-called elites, US voters could be forgiven a sense of deja vu. But this time it's Joe Biden, not Donald Trump who's on the other end of the line.</p>

<p>As the 81-year-old Democrat fights to save his reelection bid after a catastrophic debate against the 78-year-old Republican, Biden is increasingly turning to the aggressive playbook pioneered by Trump.</p>

<p>And while Trump has stayed silent since the June 27 debate, it is Biden who has launched a media and campaign blitz to counter growing concerns about his age.</p>

<p>In a scene reminiscent from Trump's days as president when he would routinely phone in to conservative Fox and Friends, Biden dialled into the liberal-leaning MSNBC network's Morning Joe program on Monday.</p>

<p>"I'm getting so frustrated by the elites -- I'm not talking about you guys -- the elites in the party, 'oh, they know so much more,'" a fiery-sounding Biden said as he mocked Democrats who have called for him to stand down.</p>

<p>"Any of these guys that don't think I should run -- run against me. Announce for president, challenge me at the convention."</p>

<p>Populist politicians including Trump have portrayed themselves as men of the people against "elites" to appeal to voters, while being part of the elite themselves.</p>

<p>Reactions were mixed to the call-in.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Legendary Hollywood director Rob Reiner, who made the comedy classic "When Harry Met Sally," said that if Biden kept up similar performances until the election "he'll be able to shut up people like me who think he should step aside."</p>

<p>And Jon Favreau, a former speechwriter for president Barack Obama, said Biden's "energy is great" on his Morning Joe call but that his "message absolutely sucks."</p>

<p>"Angry, defensive, lashing out at all the wrong people," he said on X.</p>

<h3><strong>'Big crowds'</strong></h3>

<p>Biden has taken other leaves out of his predecessor's playbook since the debate.</p>

<p>Touting huge crowds at his rallies? Check.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"We've been drawing big crowds. Ever since the debate, not joking, even that night we had big crowds afterwards," Biden told a campaign rally in Harrisburg, Pennsylvania on Sunday.</p>

<p>Bragging at length about his accomplishments? Check -- at rallies, in a letter to congressmen, and to reporters.</p>

<p>And cherry-picking polls -- whether to incorrectly claim underdog status in his 2020 battle with Trump, or to deny record low approval ratings this time around? That too.</p>

<p>"Look, I remember them telling me the same thing in 2020, 'I can't win. The polls show I can't win,'" Biden, who was ahead in the polls against Trump four years ago, said during a post-debate interview with ABC's George Stephanopoulos last week.</p>

<p>But in many ways the signs have been there for months.</p>

<p>Biden has taken an increasingly aggressive tone against Trump since the start of the year, starting by calling him a "loser" and threat to democracy and finally blasting him during the debate for having "sex with a porn star".</p>

<p>Trump has appeared to move in the other direction.&nbsp;</p>

<p>His debate performance was restrained by the former reality TV star's standards, avoiding the frequent interruptions of four years ago.</p>

<p>Right-wing commentators have meanwhile speculated that Biden is copying another Trump trademark -- his spray-tan.</p>

<p>Biden appeared pale during the debate but there has been a rash of internet memes that his skin looked orange in more recent appearances including the ABC interview.</p>

<p>Paul Murray, a commentator on Sky Australia, said Biden had gone from "white to orange", joking: "Is he trying to trick the voters of America that he's Donald Trump?"&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/7geecs9o_biden_625x300_07_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Biden has taken an increasingly aggressive tone against Trump (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-russia-sign-9-agreements-on-trade-climate-during-pm-modis-moscow-visit-6070175]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India, Russia Sign 9 Agreements On Trade, Climate During PM's Moscow Visit]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-russia-sign-9-agreements-on-trade-climate-during-pm-modis-moscow-visit-6070175]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 22:21:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India and Russia inked nine MoUs and agreements on several areas, including trade, climate and research, during Prime Minister Narendra Modi's two-day high-profile visit to Moscow which concluded on Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India and Russia inked nine MoUs and agreements on several areas, including trade, climate and research, during Prime Minister Narendra Modi's two-day high-profile visit to Moscow which concluded on Tuesday.</p>

<p>To facilitate a further increase in trade and joint investment projects between the Far East Region of Russia and India, the two countries inked a program of bilateral cooperation in trade, economic and investment spheres in the Russian Far East for the period from 2024 to 2029 as well as of cooperation principles in the Arctic zone of the Russian Federation, according to the list of agreements and MoUs released by the Ministry of External Affairs.</p>

<p>To facilitate investment by Russian companies in the Indian market by promoting and fostering investment cooperation, a Joint Investment Promotion Framework Agreement was inked between Invest India and JSC "Management Company of Russian Direct Investment Fund".</p>

<p>A memorandum of understanding (MoU) between the Trade Promotion Council of India and All Russia Public Organisation "Business Russia" was signed to promote bilateral trade and investment, organise B2B meetings, and business promotion events; and exchange of business delegations.</p>

<p>An MoU was signed between the Ministry of Environment, Forest and Climate Change and the Ministry of Economic Development of the Russian Federation on the issues of climate change and low-carbon development.</p>

<p>Under the deal, a Joint Working Group on the issues of climate change and low-carbon development will be set up. There will also be an exchange of information, best practices and co-hosting research to develop low-cost technologies.</p>

<p>A MoU was also signed between India's National Centre for Polar and Ocean Research and Russia's Arctic and Antarctic Research Institute on cooperation in research and logistics in polar regions.</p>

<p>A Cooperation Agreement was signed between the Indian International Arbitration Centre and the International Commercial Arbitration Court at the Chamber of Commerce and Industry of the Russian Federation. The agreement aims at the facilitation of settlement of civil law disputes of a commercial nature.</p>

<p>Among other MoUs signed were between Survey of India and the Federal Service for State Registration, Cadastre and Cartography, Russian Federation; Prasar Bharati and ANO "TV-Novosti" (Russia Today TV Channel) on cooperation and collaboration on broadcasting; and Indian Pharmacopoeia Commission and Russia's Federal State Budgetary Institution "Scientific Centre for Expert Evaluation of Medicinal Products".&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/5amqvco8_modi-putin-ani_625x300_09_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[PM Modi meets with Russian President Vladimir Putin prior to a bilateral meeting in Moscow]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/war-crime-russia-under-fire-at-un-for-systemic-attacks-on-ukraine-6069685]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["War Crime": Russia Under Fire At UN For "Systemic" Attacks On Ukraine]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/war-crime-russia-under-fire-at-un-for-systemic-attacks-on-ukraine-6069685]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 21:13:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russia came under fire at the UN Security Council on Tuesday for conducting "systemic attacks" on Ukraine's medical facilities after a wave of deadly strikes across the country.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russia came under fire at the UN Security Council on Tuesday for conducting "systemic attacks" on Ukraine's medical facilities after a wave of deadly strikes across the country.</p>

<p>President Volodymyr Zelensky said 38 people across Ukraine were killed -- including four children -- and 190 wounded in the wave of nearly 40 missiles that targeted several towns and cities on Monday, damaging medical facilities.</p>

<p>"Intentionally directing attacks against a protected hospital is a war crime and perpetrators must be held to account," Joyce Msuya, acting under-secretary for humanitarian affairs, told the emergency meeting.</p>

<p>"These incidents are part of a deeply concerning pattern of systemic attacks harming healthcare and other civilian infrastructure across Ukraine," Msuya added.</p>

<p>Kyiv said a children's hospital was struck by a Russian cruise missile with components produced in NATO member countries, and announced a day of mourning in the capital.</p>

<p>"First Responders attending the scene immediately after the attack found children receiving treatment for cancer in hospital beds, set up in parks and on the street, where medical workers had quickly established triage areas," Msuya said.</p>

<p>Ukrainian ally France's envoy Nicolas de Riviere said "Russia has deliberately targeted residential neighborhoods and healthcare infrastructure."&nbsp;</p>

<p>"France condemns these flagrant violations of international law, which are yet another entry and note list of war crimes for which Russia will be held accountable," he said.</p>

<h3>'<strong>Abominable' attacks</strong></h3>

<p>China, which has long called for a negotiated settlement between Russia and Ukraine, said that both sides should "show political will, meet each other halfway and start peace talks at an early date."</p>

<p>"China will continue to actively promote peace talks," said Beijing's envoy Fu Cong.</p>

<p>Russia previously claimed the extensive missile damage in Kyiv was caused by Ukrainian air defense systems.</p>

<p>"We continue to insist that we do not strike civilian targets," spokesman Dmitry Peskov told reporters in a daily briefing Tuesday.</p>

<p>However, the United Nations said there was a "high likelihood" that the children's hospital in Kyiv suffered "a direct hit" from a missile "launched by the Russian Federation."</p>

<p>Russia currently holds the rotating presidency of the Security Council and its envoy to the United Nations, Vasily Nebenzya, indicated earlier this month he will take a firm line with Ukraine and its Western allies.</p>

<p>As a permanent member of the UN's top security body, Moscow wields a veto which it has used on several occasions to thwart efforts to censure its war in Ukraine.</p>

<p>It initially appeared that Russia would seek to block Ukraine from participating in Tuesday's meeting after Nebenzya said Kyiv had not correctly formatted its letter requesting to participate.</p>

<p>Ukraine could participate "only on condition it was requested by the United States... we regret that Ukraine cannot act independently... (and) it has to be led by its sponsor," said Nebenzya.</p>

<p>"Mr President, we are appalled by the strikes on Ukraine by the country that you are representing," Slovenia's representative to the UN Samuel Zbogar said to Nebenzya, calling the strikes "brutal" and "another low."</p>

<p>UN Secretary-General Antonio Guterres described the deadly Russian strikes in Ukraine as "particularly shocking," his spokesman Stephane Dujarric said on Monday.</p>

<p>UN rights chief Volker Turk echoed Guterres, calling the attacks "abominable," and saying that "the strikes severely damaged the intensive care, surgical and oncology wards of Okhmatdyt, which is Ukraine's largest children's referral hospital."</p>

<p>Zelensky has been urging allies to bolster Ukrainian air defense systems and was expected to renew those calls as a NATO summit kicked off later Tuesday in Washington.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/5ti0o1e_ukraine-attacks_625x300_09_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Emergency personnel along with medics clear the rubble of the destroyed building in Ukraine]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-how-indians-were-duped-into-fighting-for-russia-in-ukraine-war-6069574]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: How Indians Were Duped Into Fighting For Russia In Ukraine War]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-how-indians-were-duped-into-fighting-for-russia-in-ukraine-war-6069574]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 20:57:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India said on Tuesday that Moscow has agreed to begin discharging its citizens who were "misled" into serving in the Russian army following talks between Prime Minister Narendra Modi and President Vladimir Putin.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India said on Tuesday that Moscow has agreed to begin discharging its citizens who were "misled" into serving in the Russian army following talks between Prime Minister Narendra Modi and President Vladimir Putin.</p>

<p>Here is a look at the problem and how the countries thrashed out a solution.</p>

<h3><strong>How Were Indians Misled Into Joining Russian Army?</strong></h3>

<p>A human trafficking network extending from New Delhi to Tamil Nadu used social media platforms and local agents to lure people to Russia by offering them lucrative jobs or admission to what Central Bureau of Investigation (CBI) called "dubious private universities".</p>

<p>Once they reached Russia, however, the victims' passports were taken and they were trained in combat roles before being deployed at the front.</p>

<p>Police have arrested at least four people involved in the racket.</p>

<h3><strong>How Many People Were Lured?</strong></h3>

<p>The government estimates between 30 and 40 Indian citizens are currently serving in the Russian army.</p>

<p>At least four people have been killed in the conflict.</p>

<h3><strong>How Did India Tackle The Problem?</strong></h3>

<p>India has said that every case brought to its attention is being "strongly taken up" with Russia to ensure the "early discharge" of stranded people, and 10 Indians have been brought back as part of this effort so far.</p>

<p>Russia has not commented on the issue and has not responded to Reuters' requests for comment.</p>

<h3><strong>Have Other Countries Made Similar Allegations?</strong></h3>

<p>Nepal has said that several of its youth were similarly illegally recruited, estimating the number to be as high as 200, and stopped issuing permits for work in Russia and Ukraine in January.</p>

<p>Sri Lanka also said that several of its war veterans were lured to the Russia-Ukraine war with false promises, at least 37 of whom have been wounded and a "significant number" killed.</p>

<p>While Nepal has an agreement with India and Britain that allows its citizens to serve in their armies, Sri Lankans are not permitted to fight in armies of foreign nations.</p>

<h3><strong>What Kind Of Relationship Do India And Russia Share?</strong></h3>

<p>India has had a close relationship with Russia since the days of the Soviet Union and has emerged as the biggest buyer of its oil after 2022, when Europe banned Russian oil imports.</p>

<p>India has also refused to condemn the Ukraine war, instead calling for peace through dialogue and diplomacy.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-03/d8lq3hp_punjab-youth-claim-stuck-in-russia-made-to-fight-ukraine-war_625x300_05_March_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Police have arrested at least four people involved in the racket.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-modi-departs-for-austria-after-fruitful-2-day-visit-to-russia-6069513]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[PM Modi Leaves For Austria After 2-Day Visit To Russia]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-modi-departs-for-austria-after-fruitful-2-day-visit-to-russia-6069513]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 20:50:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Narendra Modi on Tuesday departed for Austria after a fruitful two-day visit to Russia during which the two countries discussed ways to further shore up bilateral cooperation in sectors such as energy, trade, manufacturing and fertilis]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi on Tuesday departed for Austria after a fruitful two-day visit to Russia during which the two countries discussed ways to further shore up bilateral cooperation in sectors such as energy, trade, manufacturing and fertilisers.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Modi on Monday began a high-profile visit to Russia to hold the 22nd India-Russia annual summit with President Vladimir Putin, in his first trip since the start of Moscow's invasion of Ukraine.</p>

<p>Last night, the Russian president hosted a private dinner for the Indian prime minister at the former's residence on the outskirts of Moscow.</p>

<p>The Ukraine conflict also came up during Modi's talks with Putin. Modi told Putin that a solution to the Ukraine conflict is not possible on the battlefield and that peace talks do not succeed amidst bombs, guns and bullets.</p>

<p>Earlier in the day, President Putin thanked Prime Minister Modi for trying to help find a peaceful solution to the Ukraine crisis.</p>

<p>"I am grateful to you for the attention you pay to the most pressing issues, particularly trying to find ways to resolve the Ukraine crisis, primarily through peaceful means," Putin was quoted as saying by the official TASS news agency.</p>

<p>PM Modi was on Tuesday officially conferred the 'Order of St Andrew the Apostle' award by President Putin for his contribution to fostering bilateral ties between the two countries. The award was announced in 2019.</p>

<p>When PM Modi lands in Vienna, it will be the first visit by an Indian prime minister to Austria in over 40 years, the last being of Indira Gandhi in 1983.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-03/j0770vig_pm-modi-ani_625x300_06_March_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[It will be the first visit by an Indian prime minister to Austria in over 40 years (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/meta-expands-hate-speech-policy-to-remove-more-posts-targeting-zionists-6069492]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Meta Expands Hate Speech Policy To Remove More Posts Targeting 'Zionists']]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/meta-expands-hate-speech-policy-to-remove-more-posts-targeting-zionists-6069492]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 20:45:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Meta Platforms said on Tuesday it would start taking down more posts that target "Zionists", where the term is used to refer to Jewish people and Israelis rather than representing supporters of the political movement.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Meta Platforms said on Tuesday it would start taking down more posts that target "Zionists", where the term is used to refer to Jewish people and Israelis rather than representing supporters of the political movement.</p>

<p>The Facebook and Instagram parent said in a blog post it would remove content "attacking 'Zionists' when it is not explicitly about the political movement" and uses antisemitic stereotypes or threatens harm through intimidation or violence directed against Jews or Israelis.</p>

<p>Meta's hate speech policy prohibits direct attacks on people on the basis of what it calls protected characteristics, which include race, ethnicity, religious affiliation, disability and gender identity, among others.</p>

<p>The social media giant said its existing policies, which treat the term "Zionist" as a proxy for Jewish or Israeli people in just two narrow circumstances, did not sufficiently address the ways people use the word more broadly.</p>

<p>The policy update, which follows Meta's consultations with 145 stakeholders representing civil society and academia across global regions, comes as tensions escalate in the Middle East amid the Israel-Hamas war.</p>

<p>Meta has been criticized for years on how it handles content involving the Middle East, and those criticisms shot up further after the start of the war, with rights groups accusing the company of suppressing content supportive of Palestinians on Facebook and Instagram.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/o6cm085g_meta-generic-_625x300_30_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Meta has been criticized on how it handles content involving Middle East (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/indians-abroad/4-indian-americans-charged-for-running-human-trafficking-racket-in-us-texas-report-6069477]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[4 Indian-Americans Charged For Human Trafficking In US: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/indians-abroad/4-indian-americans-charged-for-running-human-trafficking-racket-in-us-texas-report-6069477]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 20:43:00 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Four Indian-Americans, including a woman, have been charged with allegedly running a human labour trafficking scheme out of a home in the US state of Texas, a media report said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Four Indian-Americans, including a woman, have been charged with allegedly running a human labour trafficking scheme out of a home in the US state of Texas, a media report said.</p>

<p>The Princeton Police Department released details of an investigation that led to four people being arrested after 15 women were found inside the home as alleged victims of human labour trafficking, news portal Fox4News.com said on Monday night.</p>

<p>Chandan Dasireddy, 24, Dwaraka Gunda, 31, Santhosh Katkoori, 31, and Anil Male, 37, all arrested in March, are now charged with trafficking of persons, a second-degree felony, and more arrests are expected, the channel reported, quoting police.</p>

<p>The authorities found that all the young women, living in the same home, were forced to sleep on the floor at a home on Ginsburg Lane in Collin County, Princeton. "There was basically no furniture inside the home at the centre of human trafficking, just a bunch of computer electronics and blankets," police said.</p>

<p>Another news portal, McKinney Courier-Gazette said officers with the Princeton Police Department were dispatched on March 13 to a residence regarding a welfare concern and suspicious circumstance.</p>

<p>"After further investigation of the initial report, Princeton Police CID detectives obtained a search warrant for the home of Santhosh Katkoori, where 15 adult females were located. During the investigation, it was discovered that the females were forced to work for Katkoori and multiple programming shell companies owned by him and his wife, Dwaraka Gunda," it said.</p>

<p>While the search warrant was executed, multiple laptops, cell phones, printers and fraudulent documents were seized. It was later determined that multiple locations within Princeton, Melissa, and McKinney were involved in the forced labouring of the victims, including adult males, the portal said, adding, additional laptops, cell phones, and documents were seized from the other locations.</p>

<p>The original concern was raised by a pest control company, which was called for possible bed bugs. "Once inside, the inspector noticed that each room had 3-5 young females sleeping on the floors. There were also large amounts of suitcases. The company contacted police," Fox4News.com added.</p>

<p>The news portal quoted Princeton Police Sgt Carolyn Crawford who said over 100 more people are involved, "more than half of them victims." However, she did not reveal what type of labour operation was happening.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-07/6835sp0g_us-police-generic_625x300_27_July_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[While the search warrant was executed, multiple laptops, cell phones were seized. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/all-you-need-to-know-about-russian-strike-on-ukraines-children-hospital-6069324]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[All You Need To Know About Russian Strike On Ukraine's Children Hospital]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/all-you-need-to-know-about-russian-strike-on-ukraines-children-hospital-6069324]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 20:24:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A day after a Russian missile strike on a children's hospital in Kyiv, rescuers continued to clear rubble from the scene as a day of mourning was held in the Ukrainian capital.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A day after a Russian missile strike on a children's hospital in Kyiv, rescuers continued to clear rubble from the scene as a day of mourning was held in the Ukrainian capital.</p>

<p>But like similar strikes in the past, the Ukrainian government and the Kremlin were at odds over what exactly happened.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Here's a quick rundown of what we know about the strike and the aftermath.&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>What was hit</strong></h3>

<p>The strike on the hospital was part of a barrage that targeted cities across Ukraine on Monday morning, according to Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky. &nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p>The president said 38 people across Ukraine were killed -- including four children -- and 190 wounded.&nbsp;</p>

<p>During the attack, Ukrainian officials said a cruise missile slammed into the Okhmatdyt children's hospital in Kyiv.</p>

<p>The strike caused the collapse of the facility's toxicology wing and damaged large portions of the surrounding buildings that house several different medical departments, according to AFP journalists at the scene.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"At the time of the attack, 627 children were in the hospital. Of these, eight were injured. Unfortunately, two adults were killed," said military authorities in Kyiv.</p>

<p>The hospital complex holds around 700 beds and oversees an estimated 10,000 surgeries a year.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Before the strike, medical staff halted operations at the facility after an air raid siren was activated and sent patients, family members, and others to the building's basement to seek shelter.&nbsp;</p>

<p>However, not all were able to evacuate.</p>

<p>According to a doctor at the scene, some children remained in the hospital's surgical theatres where operations had already commenced and moving them would have been difficult.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Seven other districts in Kyiv were also damaged by direct hits or debris from falling missiles, said the city's military administration.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Ten residents at an apartment block were killed during the onslaught in central Kyiv's Shevchenkivsky district, the mayor said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Five medical staff and two patients also died at the Adonis fertility centre, the clinic said.</p>

<h3><strong>The weapon</strong></h3>

<p>The Security Service of Ukraine (SBU) said its initial assessment found that Moscow had struck the facility with a Kh-101 strategic cruise missile.&nbsp;</p>

<p>A Western expert working in the defence sector told AFP on the condition of anonymity that an image of the attack "clearly shows a Kh-101 airborne cruise missile in its dive phase".</p>

<p>"The missile shows no signs of damage, and its dive angle is itself consistent with that observed in other strikes," the expert added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Yohann Michel, expert at Institute for Strategic and Defence Studies (IESD), drew similar conclusions.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"You'd have to check that the images haven't been altered, but on one of them you can clearly see a Kh-101 in perfect condition," he told AFP.</p>

<p>The strike was part of a wider barrage aimed at overwhelming Ukraine's air defences and focused on "different targets and used missiles with different trajectories and altitudes", Michel added.</p>

<h3><strong>Russian response</strong></h3>

<p>Following the strike, Russia's defence ministry said its forces had struck their "intended" defence industry and military targets.</p>

<p>The minister went on to blame the extensive damage inflicted on civilian targets on Ukrainian air defence missiles.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Kremlin spokesman Dmitry Peskov said that Russia had not targeted civilian structures.</p>

<p>The United Nation disagreed, saying there was a "high likelihood" that the children's hospital suffered a direct hit from the Russian missile.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/9lmjplj_childrens-hospital-in-kyiv_625x300_09_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The strike on the hospital was part of a barrage that targeted cities across Ukraine]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-ukraine-war-sandbags-bomb-shelters-on-crimea-beaches-after-deadly-missile-strike-6069020]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Sandbags, Bomb Shelters On Crimea Beaches After Deadly Missile Strike]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-ukraine-war-sandbags-bomb-shelters-on-crimea-beaches-after-deadly-missile-strike-6069020]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 19:42:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Tourists thronging the Black Sea beaches of the Russian-annexed Crimean peninsula this summer share the space with a grim new arrival: bomb shelters and sandbags.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Tourists thronging the Black Sea beaches of the Russian-annexed Crimean peninsula this summer share the space with a grim new arrival: bomb shelters and sandbags.</p>

<p>For more than two years, the beaches of the peninsula, which Moscow annexed in 2014, have been only one step removed from the raging battles of the war in Ukraine.</p>

<p>Last month, fragments from Ukrainian missiles killed four people, including two children, on a beach in the city of Sevastopol, injuring 151 more. Footage on Russian state television showed some victims being carried off on sun loungers.</p>

<p>Thousands of Ukrainian civilians have been killed since the start of the more than two-year-old war, and a much smaller number of civilians inside Russia or in parts of Ukraine, such as Crimea, that Russia claims to have annexed.</p>

<p>At the beach in Uchuyevka, on the outskirts of Sevastopol, bathers now share a pebbled shoreline with a concrete bomb shelter, reinforced with sandbags - a reminder of the unwelcome ways in which the war that Moscow calls a "special military operation" has encroached on the lives of ordinary people.</p>

<p>Irina, a tourist from the close Russian ally of Belarus, said: "In my opinion (the bomb shelters) are necessary."</p>

<p>"We are visiting friends here and we were told that it is very scary here, but here there are shelters and all safety measures are observed, I think it is very important."</p>

<p>Sevastopol's Russian-installed governor Mikhail Razvozhaev said last Friday that additional defence measures were necessary and accused Ukrainian authorities of being unhinged.</p>

<p>Ukraine has carried out multiple air and naval strikes on Russian military targets in Crimea. But legions of Russian tourists continue to visit each year for their annual holiday.</p>

<p>A Russian tourist, Alexander Zhukovskiy, said: "Probably, it will be calmer to be on the beach, to rest when you are sure that at any moment you can get under protection. So yes, they are needed."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/v6nfivqg_crimea_625x300_09_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Ukraine has carried out air and naval strikes on Russian military targets in Crimea (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>