<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 09:23:32 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/criminal-shortage-leads-to-near-empty-prisons-in-this-european-country-6297422]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Criminal Shortage Leads To Near-Empty Prisons In This European Country]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/criminal-shortage-leads-to-near-empty-prisons-in-this-european-country-6297422]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 09:14:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Netherlands faces a unique challenge of underpopulated prisons due to declining crime rates, unlike many countries grappling with overcrowding.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>While many countries grapple with overcrowded prisons, the Netherlands faces a unique challenge: too few inmates. Unlike the UK and other nations, the Dutch prison system struggles with empty cells due to low crime rates.</p>

<p>According to a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/magazine-37904263"><em>BBC report,</em></a> in the past few years, 19 prisons have closed down, and more are slated for closure next year. How has this happened, and why do some people think it's a problem? A decade ago, the Netherlands had one of the highest incarceration rates in Europe, but it now claims one of the lowest.</p>

<p>One empty prison was turned into a fancy hotel south of Amsterdam, with its four most expensive suites named The Lawyer, The Judge, The Governor, and The Jailer. But others, converted into asylum reception centres, have provided work for some former prison guards.</p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2023/oct/06/prison-lessons-from-the-netherlands"><em>The Guardian,</em></a> since 2014, 23 prisons have been shut down, turning into temporary asylum centres, housing, and hotels. The country has Europe's third-lowest incarceration rate, at 54.4 per 100,000 inhabitants. According to the justice ministry's WODC Research and Documentation Centre, the number of prison sentences imposed fell from 42,000 in 2008 to 31,000 in 2018, along with a two-thirds drop in jail terms for young offenders. Registered crimes plummeted by 40% in the same period, to 785,000 in 2018.</p>

<p>Miranda Boone, a professor of criminology at Leiden University, has studied the collapse in the prison population. "There is no doubt that the prison population has been reduced very significantly in the last 13 years-an amazing and, in the western world, unparalleled development," she says.</p>

<p>Interestingly, one vacant prison in south of Amsterdam was transformed into a luxury hotel, with its four premium suites aptly named The Lawyer, The Judge, The Governor, and The Jailer. Meanwhile, other empty prisons were repurposed into asylum reception centers, offering employment opportunities to former prison guards. This creative reuse of space reflects the Netherlands' unique approach to addressing its shortage of inmates.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/gqiq853g_jails_625x300_09_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Empty jails have been repurposed as asylum centers, providing employment for former guards.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/inside-muhammad-yunus-led-bangladesh-interim-government-who-are-its-key-members-6297421]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Inside Bangladesh Interim Government: Who Are Its Key Members]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/inside-muhammad-yunus-led-bangladesh-interim-government-who-are-its-key-members-6297421]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 09:13:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Bangladesh's Nobel laureate Muhammad Yunus on Thursday took oath as the head of an interim government, days after student-led protests ended the 15-year rule of Sheikh Hasina.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bangladesh's Nobel laureate <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/pm-modi-extends-best-wishes-after-muhammad-yunus-takes-oath-as-head-of-interim-bangladesh-government-6294569" target="_blank">Muhammad Yunus</a> on Thursday took oath as the head of an interim government, days after student-led protests ended the 15-year rule of <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/s-jaishankar-his-uk-counterpart-david-lammy-discuss-situation-in-bangladesh-west-asia-6294020#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">Sheikh Hasina</a>.</p>

<p>The 84-year-old was sworn in as the chief advisor - a position equivalent to prime minister. He swore to "uphold, support and protect the constitution", in front of political and civil society leaders, generals and diplomats at the presidential palace in the capital Dhaka.</p>

<p>More than a dozen members of his cabinet -- given the title of advisers, not ministers -- also took the oath. The caretaker administration is a civilian team, bar one retired brigadier-general.</p>

<h3><strong>Bangladesh Interim Government&nbsp;Members</strong></h3>

<p>A 16-member council of advisers was announced in the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-is-bangladeshs-caretaker-leader-muhammad-yunus-economic-thinking-6294710" target="_blank">Muhammad Yunus-led interim government</a>, which will lead the crisis-stricken Bangladesh for a certain period and oversee the election to transition power to an elected government.</p>

<p>Brigadier General (retd) M Sakhawat Hossain, women's rights activist Farida Akhtar, right-wing party Hefazat-e-Islam's deputy chief AFM Khalid Hossain, Grameen Telecom trustee Nurjahan Begum, freedom fighter Sharmeen Murshid, chairman of Chittagong Hill Tracts Development Board Supradip Chakma, Prof Bidhan Ranjan Roy and former foreign secretary Touhid Hossain are also among the advisory council members.</p>

<p>Besides Md Nazrul Islam, Adilur Rahman Khan, AF Hassan Ariff, Syeda Rizwana Hasan, Supradip Chakma and Farooq-e-Azam, the group also included two top leaders of the Students Against Discrimination group that led the weeks-long protests against the Sheikh Hasina government, Nahid Islam and Asif Mahmud,&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>Violent Protests In Bangladesh</strong></h3>

<p>The new interim government was formed after <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/muhammad-yunus-ahead-of-oath-ceremony-bangladesh-got-second-independence-6291591" target="_blank">Bangladesh witnessed weeks of violence</a> and clashes, forcing Sheikh Hasina, a five-time prime minister, to resign and flee to India on Monday.</p>

<p>Trouble had been brewing in Bangladesh since before the January 7 elections, which was won by Ms Hasina's Awami League in a landslide, but the electoral exercise was widely seen as being far from free and fair.</p>

<p>A fresh wave of protests led by students began in June - in which over 450 people have been killed so far - &nbsp;after a Bangladeshi high court reinstated 30 per cent reservation in government jobs for family members of freedom fighters and veterans from Bangladesh's 1971 War of Independence.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The quota was later scaled back by the country's Supreme Court but Ms Hasina's handling of the protests and her alleged use of an offensive label for the protesters infuriated students.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Protests continued with students demanding that Ms Hasina step down and clashes between agitators and the police left over 100 dead and dozens injured across the country on Sunday. A day later, lakhs of students flooded the streets and headed towards the prime minister's official residence, Ganabhaban, forcing Ms Hasina to resign and flee to India.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/bqlfmhv8_muhammad-yunus_625x300_09_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Nobel laureate Muhammad Yunus has been sworn in as chief advisor]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/shes-barely-competent-donald-trump-on-kamala-harris-ahead-of-debate-6297328]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris Is Barely Competent, Says Donald Trump Ahead Of Debate]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/shes-barely-competent-donald-trump-on-kamala-harris-ahead-of-debate-6297328]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 08:57:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump and Democratic opponent Kamala Harris will debate on Sept. 10 on ABC, setting up the first face-to-face match-up between the rivals in what polls show is a close race.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump and Democratic opponent Kamala Harris will debate on Sept. 10 on ABC, setting up the first face-to-face match-up between the rivals in what polls show is a close race.</p>

<p>In a news conference at his Palm Beach, Florida, residence, Trump said he wanted additional debates on Sept. 4 and Sept. 25 that would air on Fox and NBC.</p>

<p>Harris said in a post on X that she was looking forward to the Sept. 10 debate after Trump "finally committed."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">I hear that Donald Trump has finally committed to debating me on September 10.<br />
<br />
I look forward to it.</p>
— Kamala Harris (@KamalaHarris) <a href="https://twitter.com/KamalaHarris/status/1821656821662134368?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 8, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>She told reporters after a Detroit-area campaign stop that she was open to discussing more debates, but a campaign official reiterated their position that a Sept. 4 Fox debate is off the table.</p>

<p>Discussions on future debates depend on Trump's participation in the Sept. 10 debate on ABC, the official said. The Harris campaign had already opposed a Fox debate, saying the host network should be one that sponsored recent primary debates by both parties.</p>

<p>Trump previously suggested he might back out of the ABC debate, scheduled before Harris, the US vice president, replaced President Joe Biden as the Democratic presidential candidate less than three weeks ago, upending the contest. The Sept. 10 debate on ABC was to be the second of two agreed upon between Biden and Trump, following their June 27 debate on CNN.</p>

<p>An Ipsos poll published on Thursday found Harris has widened her lead over Trump since late July. She leads Trump 42% to 37%, compared with a July 22-23 Reuters/Ipsos survey that showed her up 37% to 34% over Trump.</p>

<p>Thursday's Palm Beach news conference was Trump's first public appearance since Harris selected Minnesota Governor Tim Walz as her running mate on Tuesday.</p>

<p>Harris and Walz have headlined rallies in the battleground states of Pennsylvania, Michigan and Wisconsin this week, drawing tens of thousands of attendees in a fresh sign of how her late entry into the race has galvanized Democrats. Thursday's stop by the Democratic pair at a union hall came as the campaign said it sees labour groups as a key to tipping the balance in the election.</p>

<p>Harris' rapid rise has sent Trump's team scrambling to recalibrate its strategy and messaging. Opinion polls show Harris has erased the lead Trump had built over Biden, and Democrats have raked in hundreds of millions of dollars from voters and big donors since she became the party's candidate.</p>

<p>Trump insisted on Thursday he has not altered his approach to the race. In a question-and-answer session with reporters that stretched beyond an hour, Trump hopped from topic to topic and said Harris and Walz are weak candidates.</p>

<p>Nevertheless, Trump lamented that he isn't able to face Biden in the Nov. 5 election, suggesting the president was a victim of a plot to dislodge him from atop the Democratic ticket.</p>

<p>Biden dropped his faltering reelection bid under pressure from fellow Democrats worried about his chances of victory after a poor debate performance against Trump.</p>

<p>Asked about his controversial comments last week that Harris, who is of Black and Indian decent, recently "happened to turn Black," Trump said: "You'll have to ask her that question because she's the one that said it, I didn't say it. ... To me, it doesn't matter. But to her, from her standpoint, I think it's very disrespectful to both, really, whether it's Indian or Black, I think it's very disrespectful to both."</p>

<p>Trump's initial comments, delivered to an audience of Black journalists, drew widespread condemnation and left donors and aides baffled and alarmed. The Trump campaign didn't immediately comment further to provide evidence of remarks by Harris that Trump said he was referring to.</p>

<p>Trump on Thursday also mocked the size of Harris' campaign crowds, even though they have matched his of late. He falsely claimed the size of the crowd he addressed on Jan. 6, 2021 - the day his supporters stormed the US Capitol - was as large as those who packed the National Mall in Washington for Dr. Martin Luther King Jr.'s "I Have a Dream" speech in 1963.</p>

<p>"We actually had more people," Trump said. "But I'm ok with it because I liked Dr. Martin Luther King."</p>

<p>King delivered his speech to an estimated 250,000 people in August 1963, according to the National Constitution Center. Trump's rally on Jan. 6, 2021, drew about 53,000 supporters, according to the House of Representatives Select Committee's "187 minutes of dereliction" report.</p>

<p>Echoing a recent attack line from his campaign, Trump criticized Harris for not doing a press interview since launching her campaign.</p>

<p>"She can't do an interview. She's barely competent," Trump said, later again calling her "nasty," a go-to line that he often uses to disparage female critics.</p>

<p>Trump has conducted a steady stream of media interviews, though they are usually with friendly, right-leaning outlets and reporters. On Wednesday, he called into the "Fox &amp; Friends" morning program and took questions from the program's hosts.</p>

<p>Trump announced the Palm Beach news conference on Thursday morning on his social media platform. Only a select group of reporters were given the advance notice needed to travel to his Florida resort in time. Reuters was not extended an invitation.</p>

<p>Harris answered a handful of questions from reporters after meeting with auto workers in Wayne, Michigan, on Thursday, following the United Auto Workers union's endorsement of her candidacy. She said she wants to schedule a sit-down interview "before the end of the month."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/kqs5e0o4_kamala-harris-donald-trump_625x300_27_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump had previously suggested he might back out of the ABC debate (file).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/i-suspect-pakistani-spy-agency-isi-incited-protests-in-bangladesh-sheikh-hasinas-son-6291041]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What Sheikh Hasina's Son Said When Asked If She'll Return To Bangladesh]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/i-suspect-pakistani-spy-agency-isi-incited-protests-in-bangladesh-sheikh-hasinas-son-6291041]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 08:43:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Bangladesh went into a tailspin after nationwide protests over job quota flared up. Following the agitation, Sheikh Hasina resigned as Bangladesh's Prime Minister and fled the country.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bangladesh went into a tailspin after nationwide protests over job quota flared up. Following the agitation, Sheikh Hasina resigned as Bangladesh's Prime Minister and fled the country.</p>

<p>In an exclusive interview, the former Prime Minister's son, Sajeeb Wazed, told news agency IANS that the protests went out of hand as some groups kept inciting the demonstrators and he suspects the involvement of Pakistan's ISI or Western groups in it.</p>

<p><strong>Q: What is your take on the current situation in Bangladesh?</strong></p>

<p>A: Our government had removed the quota two to three years ago, but the families of freedom fighters reached court. That's why the protests started. Initially, it was a minor protest, but, I think all along Western groups kept inciting it. We wanted a peaceful resolution. We wanted the judicial committee to resolve the problem, and investigate, and we suspended police officers.</p>

<p>But, I think there was some group that kept inciting the protesters. Ultimately, the protests turned violent and it became an issue of my mother's safety. They were marching on the Prime Minister's residence. My mother didn't want to leave the country even at the last minute. She went to the military air base and she told her sister that she didn't wish to leave. But, I talked to her and convinced her to leave. I told her 'leave because they will kill you.' So, this is the situation in Bangladesh. This situation was escalated deliberately. First of all, there was no reason for the protests as it was not the decision of our government. It was the decision of the courts. Our government was appealing against the decision of the courts.</p>

<p>The protest was peaceful at the start, but on the night of July 15, someone started marching at Dhaka University chanting 'We are Razakars.' They started saying that my mother had called students 'Razakars' but she didn't say this.</p>

<p>The students got angry and started protesting and police used excessive force to stop them. Our government immediately suspended those police officers. Our government formed a judicial team to investigate. But, the whole incident was designed to flare up. The protest escalated and they demanded the resignation of the Prime Minister. Many of the protesters had firearms. They attacked police stations with guns. From where did they get the guns?</p>

<p><strong>Q: Reports suggest that whatever is happening in Bangladesh is because of the US, China, and Pakistan. Do you agree?</strong></p>

<p>A: I don't think China is involved in this as it has never been involved in our internal matters. We were friends with every country. With China and India, we had good relations. We consider India our best friend. The US also had good relations but Pakistan (ISI) was always against the independence of Bangladesh. We fought for independence from them. So, I suspect that ISI was involved in inciting protests.</p>

<p><strong>Q: Is it true that the Army Chief had given an ultimatum to Sheikh Hasina to leave the country within 45 minutes?</strong></p>

<p>A: That's not true. They met, and I was there with my mother before and after the meeting. There was no ultimatum from the Army Chief. My mother had ordered the police and military not to kill the protesters. When they started demonstrating, the military barricaded Dhaka city. So, at the time when the protesters were marching, the military took my mother to safety. So, the allegations are completely false.</p>

<p><strong>Q: Sheikh Hasina was giving a speech to the nation and in the middle of it she had to stop as the protesters were marching towards her residence. What do you want to say about this?</strong></p>

<p>A: No, she was planning to resign. She told me that she didn't want bloodshed anymore. She would resign, make a statement, and arrange for a peaceful transfer of power as per the Constitution. But, unfortunately, the protesters declared their march on the Prime Minister's residence. She didn't have time to make a statement or speech.</p>

<p><strong>Q: Nobel Laureate Muhammad Yunus will be the chief of the interim government. What are your comments on this?</strong></p>

<p>A: Unfortunately, the whole situation is unconstitutional. There is no constitutional provision for an interim government. In fact, our Supreme Court has ruled that any unconstitutional situation has to be dealt with but you cannot fulfill all the demands of protesters. It has to happen within the Constitution. However, nothing matters, as there is no law and order in the country now. Riots, looting, and vandalism are going on throughout the city. There is a little bit of security in Dhaka city as the military is deployed there. But, outside Dhaka, if you look at social media, there is complete anarchy. There is no police and there is no law and order. I am waiting to see how an interim government is going to control this because an interim government cannot bring law and order. Then Bangladesh will become Afghanistan.</p>

<p><strong>Q: Muhammad Yunus said that this is the second liberation day of Bangladesh, the first was in 1971. Your comments?</strong></p>

<p>A: He is talking about liberation from whom? Riots? Vandalism or anarchy? Is this freedom for Bangladesh? If this is the freedom that he thinks Bangladesh wants, then that's fine. Good luck to them. People are dying. There is no law and order in the country. There is looting. Everyone is being looted. That's freedom!</p>

<p><strong>Q: Yunus is claiming that students will get jobs, as they were not getting them due to reservation.</strong></p>

<p>A: Well, that's fine, let him take over. Let him prove it. We will see the results soon.</p>

<p><strong>Q: What is the future of Bangladesh now?</strong></p>

<p>A: Well, today Bangladesh looks like Syria or Afghanistan. There is no law and order. After this, it's up to Mr Yunus' government, if they think they can control it. Maybe we will have democracy again. If they can't, then Bangladesh will become like Afghanistan.</p>

<p><strong>Q: Will Sheikh Hasina return to Bangladesh?</strong></p>

<p>A: She will return as my mother loves Bangladesh. It is her country and she will definitely return when the situation is in control.</p>

<p><strong>Q: What is your message via our platform?</strong></p>

<p>A: I want to see a democratic Bangladesh soon. I want India to use its powers to ensure free and fair elections in Bangladesh.</p>

<p><strong>Q: What's your take on minorities being killed in Bangladesh?</strong></p>

<p>A: Our government wants the safety of minorities of Bangladesh as we believe they are also our voters. The BNP should leave Jamaat-e-Islami. They have to accept that we have minorities in Bangladesh. If they cannot accept this and if they come to power, the minorities in Bangladesh will never be safe.</p>

<p><strong>Q: Why did the protests not stop after the Supreme Court's order?</strong></p>

<p>A: Exactly, that is my point. I am sure someone is provoking all this, even after the Supreme Court's order, they didn't stop. Despite all efforts to control the situation in Bangladesh, they wanted my mother's resignation. That means it was pre-planned.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/gnshs24c_sheikh-hasina-son-sajeeb-wazed_625x300_09_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sheikh Hasina's son Sajeeb Wazed suspects the involvement of Pakistan's ISI.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/argentina-money-heist-metal-rod-foils-repetition-of-argentinas-heist-of-the-century-6297249]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Metal Rod Foils Repetition of Argentina's 'Heist Of The Century']]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/argentina-money-heist-metal-rod-foils-repetition-of-argentinas-heist-of-the-century-6297249]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 08:37:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[It could have been a new heist of the century -- if it hadn't been for a metal rod popping up in the middle of a cobblestone street.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It could have been a new heist of the century -- if it hadn't been for a metal rod popping up in the middle of a cobblestone street.</p>

<p>Authorities in San Isidro, Argentina -- the location of the fabled 2006 "heist of the century" -- announced Thursday that they had prevented a repeat crime.</p>

<p>On Wednesday, a parked driver heard a noise in the chassis of his car that turned out to be caused by the rod emerging from the street surface.</p>

<p>After police arrived at the scene on the northern outskirts of Buenos Aires, an excavation found a tunnel beginning in a warehouse about 220 meters from a branch of Macro Bank.</p>

<p>Large amounts of earth had been moved and extraction machines were discovered.</p>

<p>The tunnel was lined with wood, had ventilation and electric light, and ended almost at the door of the bank, according to police. So far, police have not found the would-be robbers.</p>

<p>Investigators said construction took between six and nine months and called the tunnel an engineering feat "better than the one El Chapo Guzman" used to escape from prison in 2015 in Mexico.</p>

<p>The incident was reminiscent of the so-called "heist of the century," which took place in 2006 in the same upmarket town, when criminals, with meticulous planning, stole nearly $19 million from a bank and escaped through a tunnel.</p>

<p>In that robbery, which spawned books, TV series and films, the robbers used toy weapons and left a note in the vault that read "In a neighbourhood of rich people, with no weapons or grudges, it's just money."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/cjndsbfg_argentina-heist-afp-_625x300_09_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The tunnel had ventilation and electric light, and ended almost at the door of the bank, said the police.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rising-whooping-cough-cases-in-the-uk-lead-to-tenth-child-death-6297111]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Rising Whooping Cough Cases In The UK Lead To Tenth Child Death]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rising-whooping-cough-cases-in-the-uk-lead-to-tenth-child-death-6297111]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 07:58:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The outbreak is part of a global resurgence of the disease, which has seen cases and deaths in countries like China, the Philippines, the Czech Republic, and the Netherlands.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Another baby has died from an infection of whooping cough, bringing the total number of deaths of infants in England since the outbreak began to 10, officials at the UK Health Security Agency (UKHSA) said.</p>

<p>This death coincides with recent UKHSA data showing that confirmed laboratory cases of whooping cough in England topped 10,000 in this year. While most cases are in people aged 15 or older, more than 300 have been in babies under three months - the most at-risk group from the infection.</p>

<p>It is believed that the outbreak started in England last November, and 10 infant deaths have now been confirmed. The first death was reported in December 2023, and the rest occurred between January and June 2024.</p>

<p>According to a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/deadly-whooping-cough-outbreak-spreads-globally-heres-all-you-need-to-know-5418315"><em>Bloomberg report,</em></a> Whooping cough is making a comeback in several parts of the world, with deaths reported in China, the Philippines, Czech Republic and the Netherlands, and outbreaks in countries including the US and UK.</p>

<h3><strong>What is whooping cough?</strong></h3>

<p>The highly-contagious disease is caused by the bacterium Bordetella pertussis, which targets the upper respiratory system, releasing toxins which can cause the airways to swell, according to the US Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC).</p>

<h3><strong>What are the symptoms?</strong></h3>

<p>Early symptoms of whooping cough look very much like the common cold - with a stuffy nose, low-grade fever and a mild cough often reported. That makes it difficult to diagnose until more severe symptoms emerge.</p>

<p>After a week or two symptoms can progress to "rapid, violent, and uncontrolled coughing fits," according to the CDC, accompanied by a high-pitched "whoop" sound upon inhalation at the end of the fit. Coughing fits can go on for up to 10 weeks.</p>

<h3><strong>Who is most at risk?</strong></h3>

<p>Children are more likely to suffer the most violent symptoms of whooping cough, while babies don't usually cough but can stop breathing. Teenagers and adults often exhibit more mild symptoms, but even then, debilitating coughing fits can keep them up at night. One complicating factor is that adults with no obvious signs of the disease can continue to spread the infection.</p>

<h3><strong>How do you treat it?</strong></h3>

<p>Once diagnosed, preferably before coughing begins, doctors will generally treat the infection with antibiotics. If a patient has been coughing for more than three weeks, antibiotics are not required as the bacteria has likely left the body and the coughing is a result of damage done to the airways.</p>

<h3><strong>Is there a whooping cough vaccine?</strong></h3>

<p>In China, free vaccines are usually given in a combined shot that also protects infants against diphtheria and tetanus. In the US there are two vaccines available - one for children under the age of seven, and one for people older than seven. In the UK, shots are routinely given to babies, while the Philippines has warned of a potential shortage in supply by May.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/4mgtf2u8_whooping-cough_625x300_09_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Whooping cough is a highly contagious disease.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-doesnt-support-israel-arms-embargo-says-top-aide-6296769]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris Doesn't Support Israel Arms Embargo, Says Top Aide]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-doesnt-support-israel-arms-embargo-says-top-aide-6296769]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 06:02:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kamala Harris does not support an arms embargo on US ally Israel, a top aide said Thursday, in one of the first substantive statements on her Gaza war policy since her July entry to the 2024 White House race.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kamala Harris does not support an arms embargo on US ally Israel, a top aide said Thursday, in one of the first substantive statements on her Gaza war policy since her July entry to the 2024 White House race.</p>

<p>The comment came a day after the US vice president was heckled by pro-Palestinian protesters at a rally for the first time since she became the Democratic candidate less than three weeks ago.</p>

<p>Harris also met with groups opposed to the war after the rally in Detroit, Michigan. Participants reportedly said they brought up the issue of halting US arms supplies to Israel.</p>

<p>"She does not support an arms embargo on Israel," Harris's national security advisor Phil Gordon said on X.</p>

<p>He added that the vice president "has been clear: she will always ensure Israel is able to defend itself against Iran and Iran-backed terrorist groups."</p>

<p>Harris faces pressure from the left wing of the Democratic party to change course from President Joe Biden's strong military and political support for Israel's war in Gaza since the October 7 attacks by Hamas.</p>

<p>The issue is also critical in Michigan, a battleground state in November's election with a large population of Arab Americans who are vocally opposed to the war.</p>

<p>In Detroit on Wednesday, Harris found herself repeatedly interrupted by Gaza protesters.</p>

<p>"If you want Donald Trump to win, then say that. Otherwise, I'm speaking," she said, her expression hardening as she sought to quell the disruptions.</p>

<p>Harris will also be keen not to alienate the majority of US voters whom polls say support Israel.</p>

<p>As vice president, Harris has sometimes been more critical than Biden of the civilian casualties caused by Israel's offensive in Gaza.</p>

<p>Harris then made a major shift in tone after Biden dropped out of the 2024 election, saying in a strongly worded statement after she met Israeli premier Benjamin Netanyahu that she would "not be silent" on the situation.</p>

<p>But the comments by Harris's adviser appeared to make it clear she would not go as far as endorsing any kind of all-out pause in arms transfers.</p>

<p>Under Biden, the White House has only halted the delivery of a single shipment of heavy bombs to Israel over concerns about how they would be used.</p>

<p>On Wednesday in Detroit, Harris and her new running mate Tim Walz briefly met the leaders of the "Uncommitted" group that mobilized people to cast protest votes against Biden in this year's Democratic primary, US media reported.</p>

<p>Its founders told the New York Times that they had asked Harris for a full meeting to discuss their calls for an embargo, and Harris told them she was open to a meeting.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/f31c6agc_kamala-harris-reuters_625x300_29_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kamala Harris will also be keen not to alienate the majority of US voters whom polls say support Israel.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-agrees-to-resume-gaza-truce-talks-on-august-15-6296739]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Agrees To Resume Gaza Truce Talks On August 15]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-agrees-to-resume-gaza-truce-talks-on-august-15-6296739]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 05:51:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel has agreed to resume Gaza ceasefire talks on August 15 at the demand of US, Qatari and Egyptian mediators, Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's office said on Thursday, as regional tensions skyrocket over the war.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel has agreed to resume Gaza ceasefire talks on August 15 at the demand of US, Qatari and Egyptian mediators, Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's office said on Thursday, as regional tensions skyrocket over the war.</p>

<p>Gaza's Hamas-controlled civil defence agency said Israeli bombardment killed more than 18 people in strikes on two schools on Thursday, as Iran accused Israel of wanting to spread war in the Middle East.</p>

<p>After a week-long pause in November, US, Qatari and Egyptian mediators have endeavoured to secure a second truce in the 10-month-old war sparked by Hamas's unprecedented October 7 attack on Israel.</p>

<p>In a joint statement on Thursday, the three countries' leaders invited the warring parties to resume talks on August 15 in Doha or Cairo "to close all remaining gaps and commence implementation of the deal without further delay".</p>

<p>A framework agreement was "now on the table, with only the details of implementation" left to conclude, and the mediators were "prepared to present a final bridging proposal" to resolve remaining issues, they said.</p>

<p>Netanyahu's office said later Thursday Israel would send a negotiating team on August 15 "to the agreed place to conclude the details of implementing a deal".</p>

<p>A prospective cessation of hostilities also involving the release of hostages held in Gaza and scaled-up aid deliveries has centred around a phased deal beginning with an initial truce.</p>

<p>Recent discussions have focused on a framework outlined by US President Joe Biden in late May which he said had been proposed by Israel.</p>

<p>"It's not like the agreement's going to be ready to sign on Thursday. There's still a significant amount of work to do," a senior Biden administration official said of the talks that come after calls between Biden and the Egyptian and Qatari leaders this week.</p>

<p>Israel had been "very receptive" to the idea of the talks, the official told reporters on condition of anonymity, rejecting suggestions that Netanyahu was stalling on a deal.</p>

<p>The announcement of the talks came after Hamas named Yahya Sinwar -- the alleged mastermind of the October 7 attack -- as its new leader, sparking fears the torturous negotiations have become even more difficult.</p>

<p>- 'Strategic mistake' -<br />
On the ground in Gaza, the Hamas-controlled civil defence agency said Israeli strikes hit Al-Zahra and Abdel Fattah Hamoud schools in Gaza City, killing more than 18 people.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Senior agency official Mohammad al-Mughayyir said 60 people were wounded and more than 40 still missing.</p>

<p>"This is a clear targeting of schools and safe civilian facilities in the Gaza Strip," he said.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said the schools housed Hamas command centres.</p>

<p>At least 13 people were killed elsewhere in Gaza, rescuers and medics reported, as the Israeli military issued its latest evacuation order, for parts of the main southern city of Khan Yunis.</p>

<p>Diplomats pressed efforts to defuse tensions in the region, sky-high after the killing of two top militant leaders in attacks blamed on Israel that the militants and their Iranian backers have vowed to avenge.</p>

<p>Iran's acting foreign minister, Ali Bagheri, told AFP that Israel had committed "a strategic mistake" by killing Hamas's political leader Ismail Haniyeh in Tehran last week -- hours after the assassination in Beirut of Hezbollah's military chief.</p>

<p>Although Israel has not admitted to killing Haniyeh, Iran and its allies have vowed to retaliate.</p>

<p>Israel seeks "to expand tension, war and conflict to other countries", but has neither "the capacity nor the strength" to fight Iran, Bagheri said.</p>

<p>Netanyahu, speaking at a military base on Wednesday, said Israel was "prepared both defensively and offensively" and "determined" to defend itself.</p>

<p>- 'Cycle of reprisals' -<br />
Officials in the Middle East and beyond have called for calm, with Britain's minister for international development, Anneliese Dodds, telling AFP on a visit to Jordan: "We must see a de-escalation."</p>

<p>The United States, which has sent extra warships and jets to the region, has urged both Iran and Israel to avoid an escalation.</p>

<p>France's President Emmanuel Macron spoke Wednesday with his Iranian counterpart Masoud Pezeshkian and later with Israel's Netanyahu, telling both to "avoid a cycle of reprisals", according to the French presidency.</p>

<p>The Israel-Hamas war in the Gaza Strip has already drawn in Tehran-aligned militants in Syria, Lebanon, Iraq and Yemen.</p>

<p>Lebanese Hamas ally Hezbollah, which has traded near-daily cross-border fire with Israeli troops throughout the Gaza war, has vowed retaliation for military chief Fuad Shukr's killing.</p>

<p>- Israel PM 'sorry' -&nbsp;<br />
The unprecedented Hamas attack that triggered the war in Gaza resulted in the deaths of 1,198 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli official figures.</p>

<p>Palestinian militants seized 251 hostages, 111 of whom are still held in Gaza, including 39 the Israeli military says are dead.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory military campaign in Gaza has killed at least 39,699 people, according to the Hamas-run territory's health ministry, which does not give details of civilian and militant deaths.</p>

<p>Netanyahu, who has resisted making an apology for security failures over Israel's worst-ever attack, said in an interview published Thursday that he was "sorry, deeply, that something like this happened".</p>

<p>"You always look back and you say, 'Could we have done things that would have prevented it?'" Netanyahu told Time magazine.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/i85alm98_benjamin-netanyahu_625x300_25_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Netanyahu's office said Thursday Israel would send a negotiating team on August 15 for Gaza peace talks.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/venezuela-president-nicolas-maduro-blocks-social-media-platform-x-for-10-days-in-country-6296687]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Venezuela President Blocks Social Media Platform X For 10 Days In Country]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/venezuela-president-nicolas-maduro-blocks-social-media-platform-x-for-10-days-in-country-6296687]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 05:37:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Venezuelan President Nicolas Maduro, who has claimed reelection following a disputed vote, said Thursday that social media platform X would be blocked in the country for 10 days.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Venezuelan President Nicolas Maduro, who has claimed reelection following a disputed vote, said Thursday that social media platform X would be blocked in the country for 10 days.</p>

<p>The state agency in charge of telecommunications will "remove the social network X, formerly known as Twitter, from circulation in Venezuela for 10 days," Maduro said, after previously accusing the site's owner Elon Musk of an "attack" against his reelection.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2015-03/president-nicolas-maduro_650x400_41426377989.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Nicolas Maduro had accused Elon Musk of an "attack" against his reelection.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-leads-donald-trump-by-5-points-in-latest-survey-6296461]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris Leads Trump By 5 Points In Latest Poll Survey]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-leads-donald-trump-by-5-points-in-latest-survey-6296461]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 04:10:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Democrat Kamala Harris leads Republican Donald Trump 42% to 37% in the race for the Nov. 5 U.S. presidential election, according to an Ipsos poll published on Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Democrat Kamala Harris leads Republican Donald Trump 42% to 37% in the race for the Nov. 5 U.S. presidential election, according to an Ipsos poll published on Thursday.</p>

<p>The poll found Harris had widened her lead since a July 22-23 Reuters/Ipsos survey, which found her up 37% to 34% over Trump.</p>

<p>The nationwide poll of 2,045 U.S. adults, conducted Aug. 2-7, found 4% of those surveyed backed independent candidate Robert Kennedy Jr., down from 10% in July.</p>

<p>Ipsos conducted the August poll independently from Reuters. The poll, conducted online, had a margin of error of around 3 percentage points.</p>

<p>Harris entered the race on July 21 when President Joe Biden, 81, folded his campaign and endorsed Harris following a disastrous debate performance on June 27 against Trump.</p>

<p>Democrat Kamala Harris leads Republican Donald Trump 42% to 37% in the race for the Nov. 5 U.S. presidential election, according to an Ipsos poll published on Thursday.</p>

<p>The poll found Harris had widened her lead since a July 22-23 Reuters/Ipsos survey, which found her up 37% to 34% over Trump.</p>

<p>The nationwide poll of 2,045 U.S. adults, conducted Aug. 2-7, found 4% of those surveyed backed independent candidate Robert Kennedy Jr., down from 10% in July.</p>

<p>Ipsos conducted the August poll independently from Reuters. The poll, conducted online, had a margin of error of around 3 percentage points.</p>

<p>Harris entered the race on July 21 when President Joe Biden, 81, folded his campaign and endorsed Harris following a disastrous debate performance on June 27 against Trump.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-11/jhmacdl_kamala-harris-afp_625x300_19_November_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The poll found Harris had widened her lead since a July 22-23 Reuters/Ipsos survey.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musks-misleading-election-posts-viewed-1-2-billion-times-report-6296247]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk's Misleading Election Posts On X Viewed 1.2 Billion Times: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musks-misleading-election-posts-viewed-1-2-billion-times-report-6296247]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 03:01:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[False or misleading US election claims posted on X by Elon Musk have amassed nearly 1.2 billion views this year, a watchdog reported Thursday, highlighting the billionaire's potential influence on the highly polarized White House race.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>False or misleading US election claims posted on X by Elon Musk have amassed nearly 1.2 billion views this year, a watchdog reported Thursday, highlighting the billionaire's potential influence on the highly polarized White House race.</p>

<p>Ahead of the November election, researchers have raised alarm that X, formerly Twitter, is a hotbed of political misinformation.</p>

<p>They have also flagged that Musk, who purchased the platform in 2022 and is a vocal backer of Donald Trump, appears to be swaying voters by spreading falsehoods on his personal account.</p>

<p>Researchers from the Center for Countering Digital Hate (CCDH) identified 50 posts since January by Musk -- who has more than 193 million followers on the social media site -- with election claims debunked by independent fact-checkers.</p>

<p>None of the posts displayed a "Community Note," a crowd-sourced moderation tool that X has promoted as the way for users to add context to posts, CCDH said, raising questions about its effectiveness to combat falsehoods.</p>

<p>"Elon Musk is abusing his privileged position as owner of a... politically influential social media platform to sow disinformation that generates discord and distrust," warned CCDH chief executive Imran Ahmed.</p>

<p>"The lack of Community Notes on these posts shows that his business is failing woefully to contain the kind of algorithmically-boosted incitement that we all know can lead to real-world violence."</p>

<p>The posts analyzed by CCDH carried widely debunked claims, such as that Democrats are encouraging illegal migration with the aim of "importing voters" or that the election is vulnerable to fraud. Both claims amassed hundreds of millions of views.</p>

<p>Last week, Musk faced a firehose of criticism for sharing with his followers an AI deepfake video featuring Trump's Democratic rival, Vice President Kamala Harris.</p>

<p>In it, a voiceover mimicking Harris calls President Joe Biden senile before declaring that she does not "know the first thing about running the country."</p>

<p>The video, viewed by millions, carried no indication that it was parody -- save for a laughing emoji. Only later did Musk clarify that the video was meant as satire.</p>

<p>"Musk behaves as if he is beyond reproach despite growing evidence of the harmful role he is personally playing to fuel disinformation and division ahead of the US elections," Nora Benavidez, from the advocacy group Free Press Action Fund, told AFP.</p>

<p>"As his behavior edges closer to election interference, it's up to others -- the public, regulatory agencies and advertisers -- to hold him accountable for his anti-democratic behavior."</p>

<p>Musk, who purchased the platform in 2022 for $44 billion, is facing growing scrutiny over his potential influence on voters.</p>

<p>On Monday, a bipartisan group of five US secretaries of state sent an open letter to Musk, urging him to fix X's AI chatbot known as Grok after it produced election misinformation.</p>

<p>Hours after Biden stepped down from the presidential race last month and endorsed Harris as the Democratic nominee, Grok churned out false information about ballot deadlines, which was amplified by other platforms.</p>

<p>X -- which also faced criticism for stoking tensions during recent far-right riots across England -- has gutted trust and safety teams and scaled back content moderation efforts once used to tame misinformation, making it what researchers call a haven for disinformation.</p>

<p>X did not respond to an AFP request for comment.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ldckr8sg_elon-musk_625x300_18_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Elon Musk had purchased X platform in 2022 for $44 billion.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-qatar-egypt-invite-israel-and-hamas-to-resume-talks-on-august-15-6296188]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US, Qatar, Egypt Invite Israel And Hamas To Resume Talks On August 15]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-qatar-egypt-invite-israel-and-hamas-to-resume-talks-on-august-15-6296188]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 02:48:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Qatari, Egyptian and U.S. leaders called on Israel and Hamas to resume urgent talks on Aug. 15 either in Doha or Cairo to bridge all remaining gaps in the proposed Gaza ceasefire agreement.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Qatari, Egyptian and U.S. leaders called on Israel and Hamas to resume urgent talks on Aug. 15 either in Doha or Cairo to bridge all remaining gaps in the proposed Gaza ceasefire agreement and start implementing it without any delay, the three countries said in a joint statement on Thursday.</p>

<p>"It is the time to conclude a ceasefire agreement and release hostages and prisoners," the statement added.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/1nebbspo_israel-hamas-war_625x300_08_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[More than 37,000 people have been killed since war began between Israel and Hamas.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-vows-to-fight-aggression-from-hezbollah-with-all-its-might-6295832]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Vows To Fight Aggression From Hezbollah "with All Its Might"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-vows-to-fight-aggression-from-hezbollah-with-all-its-might-6295832]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 01:00:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Defence Minister Yoav Gallant said on Thursday that Israel would fight Hezbollah "with all its might" if the Lebanese armed group continued its "aggression" across the border.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Defence Minister Yoav Gallant said on Thursday that Israel would fight Hezbollah "with all its might" if the Lebanese armed group continued its "aggression" across the border.</p>

<p>"We will not allow the Hezbollah militia to destabilise the border and the region. If Hezbollah continues its aggression, Israel will fight it, with all its might," Gallant said in a message addressed to the people of Lebanon, according to a statement from his office.</p>

<p>Hezbollah has traded near-daily fire with Israeli forces in support of ally Hamas since the Palestinian militant group's October 7 attack on Israel triggered war in Gaza.</p>

<p>Fears of all-out war have mounted after Israel killed Hezbollah's top military commander Fuad Shukr in an air strike in a Beirut suburb last week.</p>

<p>Reminding the people of Lebanon of the 2006 war between Israel and Hezbollah, Gallant warned Lebanon to "learn the lesson of the past so as not to fall into a dangerous scenario in August 2024".</p>

<p>The devastating 34-day war in July-August 2006 killed more than 1,200 people in Lebanon, mostly civilians, and some 160 Israelis, mostly soldiers.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-10/g7dminco_yoav-gallant-_625x300_08_October_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel Defence Minister said that it will not allow the Hezbollah militia to destabilise the border.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-says-will-peaceful-transfer-of-power-if-us-election-is-fair-6295719]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Will Be "Peaceful Transfer" Of Power If...: Trump]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-says-will-peaceful-transfer-of-power-if-us-election-is-fair-6295719]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:30:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump said Thursday there would be a peaceful transfer of power after the US presidential vote -- but immediately questioned whether there would be "honest elections."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump said Thursday there would be a peaceful transfer of power after the US presidential vote -- but immediately questioned whether there would be "honest elections."</p>

<p>"Of course there'll be a peaceful transfer, and there was last time," Trump told a news conference, despite a mob of his supporters storming Congress in 2021 after his loss. "I just hope we're going to have honest elections."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/7s3biquo_donald-trump-afp_625x300_30_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["I just hope we're going to have honest elections," Trump said.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-offers-three-tv-debates-against-kamala-harris-next-month-6295682]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Offers Three TV Debates Against Kamala Harris Next Month]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-offers-three-tv-debates-against-kamala-harris-next-month-6295682]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:20:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump proposed three September debates against Kamala Harris Thursday as he sought to wrest back some of the attention lavished on his rival since her blockbuster entry into the US presidential election.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump proposed three September debates against Kamala Harris Thursday as he sought to wrest back some of the attention lavished on his rival since her blockbuster entry into the US presidential election.</p>

<p>Harris has ignited the Democratic ticket in the last 18 days, pulling in record fundraising and obliterating the Republican ex-president's polling lead to open up a much broader path to victory than her party would dare to have hoped for just a month ago.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The country's first female, Black and South Asian vice president heads into her party's national convention in Chicago in mid-August on the back of a series of packed rallies that have won plaudits for a positive message that has reenergized the Democratic base.</p>

<p>Meanwhile Trump -- who addressed journalists at his oceanfront estate in Florida -- has found himself on unfamiliar ground as something of a bystander, eclipsed by Harris's rise as he has scaled back his own campaigning.</p>

<p>"I hope she agrees," Trump told journalists, after he said he had arranged debates with television networks on September 4, 10 and 25.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Trump revived a series of familiar attacks on his opponent -- repeatedly questioning the intelligence of the former state attorney general and US senator, in an event punctuated by falsehoods.</p>

<p><strong>- 'Same policies' -</strong><br />
Trump made untrue claims on all manner of topics around the election and his record in office, from the price of gasoline to his crowd sizes, US military deaths in Afghanistan and the 2021 insurrection at the US Capitol by his supporters.</p>

<p>He assured reporters there would be a peaceful transfer of power after the November 5 vote -- but questioned whether the election would be honest and claimed that the last transfer had been peaceful, despite the deadly Capitol riot.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Trump also rejected a suggestion that he would need to recalibrate his campaign to take account of his new opponent after Harris replaced President Joe Biden on the ticket on July 21.</p>

<p>"It's the same policies, open borders, weak on crime. She is, I think, she's worse than Biden," he said.</p>

<p>The rival campaigns had sparred over Trump backing out of a previously scheduled ABC presidential debate on September 10. The network said Thursday both candidates have now agreed to the face off.</p>

<p>Trump-friendly Fox News would host the first of the three debates while NBC would take the final slot. There was no immediate word those dates from the Harris campaign.</p>

<p>The former president's debate with a dismally performing Biden in June spelled the end of the president's reelection campaign, but Trump had been reluctant to face Harris on neutral territory.</p>

<p>The 78-year-old has been struggling to come up with effective attack lines to define Harris while delivering a series of increasingly confounding nicknames for his opponent.</p>

<p><strong>- 'True stre</strong>ngth' -<br />
The news conference was his first public appearance since Harris -- a generation younger than Trump at 59 -- announced running mate Tim Walz and embarked on a tour of closely fought election battlegrounds.</p>

<p>She and Walz appeared Thursday in Michigan ahead of a trip to the racially diverse "Sun Belt" states of Arizona and Nevada for rallies on Friday and Saturday.</p>

<p>"The true measure of the strength of a leader is not based on who you beat down. It's based on who you lift up," she told a crowd of around 170 supporters in Detroit, at a much smaller event than her recent arena rallies.</p>

<p>Sabato's Crystal Ball, a leading election forecaster, shifted three of its ratings in favor of Democrats on Wednesday, moving Minnesota and New Hampshire from "leans Democratic" to "likely Democratic" and Georgia from "leans Republican" to "toss-up."</p>

<p>Meanwhile Marquette University Law School released a nationwide survey showing that, among likely voters, Harris now leads Trump by six points -- 53 percent to 47 percent.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Despite her intensive campaign schedule, Harris has taken almost no questions from reporters since entering the race and Trump had been seeking to turn her lack of media exposure into an election issue even before Thursday's news conference.</p>

<p>"She hasn't done an interview -- she can't do an interview, she's barely competent... But I look forward to the debates, because I think we have to set the record straight," he said in Florida.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/06lu95io_kamala-harris-donald-trump-afp_625x300_03_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Trump also assured reporters there would be a peaceful transfer of power after November elections.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pak-spy-agency-isi-fuelling-unrest-in-bangladesh-claims-sheikh-hasinas-son-6295392]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Pak's ISI Fuelling Unrest In Bangladesh, Claims Sheikh Hasina's Son]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pak-spy-agency-isi-fuelling-unrest-in-bangladesh-claims-sheikh-hasinas-son-6295392]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 23:26:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Sheikh Hasina, who quit as prime minister and fled Bangladesh, will be back in the country as soon as democracy is restored, his son Sajeeb Wazed Joy said on Thursday and blamed Pakistan's intelligence agency, ISI, for fuelling the ongoing unrest.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sheikh Hasina, who quit as prime minister and fled Bangladesh, will be back in the country as soon as democracy is restored, his son Sajeeb Wazed Joy said on Thursday and blamed Pakistan's intelligence agency, ISI, for fuelling the ongoing unrest in the country.</p>

<p>In an interview with PTI, Mr Joy said that although 76-year-old Sheikh Hasina would return to Bangladesh, it has not yet been decided whether she will be back as a "retired or active" politician.</p>

<p>He also asserted that the members of the Sheikh Mujib (Sheikh Mujibur Rahman) family will neither abandon its people nor leave the beleaguered Awami League in the lurch.</p>

<p>He expressed gratitude to Prime Minister Narendra Modi and his government for protecting his mother and appealed to India to help build international opinion and exert pressure to restore democracy in Bangladesh.</p>

<p>"Yes, it is true that I had said she wouldn't return to Bangladesh. But a lot has changed in the last two days following continuous attacks on our leaders and party workers across the country. Now we are going to do whatever it takes to keep our people safe; we are not going to leave them alone."&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Awami League is the largest and oldest political party in Bangladesh, so we cannot just walk away from our people. She will definitely return to Bangladesh once democracy is restored," he told PTI over the phone.</p>

<p>Terming Awami League an "all-weather ally of India", he said India must ensure the security of Awami League leaders in Bangladesh by building international pressure.</p>

<p>Mr Joy also urged the interim government, headed by Nobel laureate Mohammad Yunus, to restore law and order, noting that "the country is turning into a state of anarchy and becoming a second Afghanistan in the region." He said he also expects the interim government to create a level playing field whenever democracy is restored and fresh elections are held.</p>

<p>"You cannot exclude the Awami League and have a representative democracy in Bangladesh ever. Whatever his (Mohammed Yunus) personal views are, he has said that he wants a government of unity and wants to move forward and not let the mistakes of the past cloud over the future. I hope he stays true to his word," he asserted.</p>

<p>Prof Yunus took oath as the head of Bangladesh's interim government on Thursday and was administered the oath of office by President Mohammed Shahabuddin at a ceremony in Dhaka.</p>

<p>Sheikh Hasina resigned and fled the country following violent protests against her government over a controversial quota system in jobs. She flew to the Hindon air base, near Delhi, in a Bangladesh military aircraft on Monday.</p>

<p>Mr Joy mentioned that once democracy is restored, either the Awami League or BNP will come to power, and the "Mujib family and Sheikh Hasina will be around." "She has been in touch with all our party leaders for the last two days. My mother was going to retire anytime soon, so we thought now that she is gone, they (rioters) would leave our party people alone, but that did not happen. Instead, they started attacking," he said.</p>

<p>Declining to comment directly on whether he and his sister Saima Wazed, who is currently the South East Asian regional director for the World Health Organization, would enter politics, Joy said he would do whatever it takes to protect Bangladesh from total anarchy.</p>

<p>"I can't give a definite reply to this question. But I will do whatever it takes to save Bangladesh and protect the Awami League. The Mujib family would not leave them in a lurch," said Joy, the former Information and Communication Technology Advisor to Hasina.</p>

<p>Blaming Pakistan for fueling the unrest in Bangladesh, Joy said there is circumstantial evidence suggesting foreign interference and alleged involvement of Pakistan's Inter-Services Intelligence agency.</p>

<p>"I am quite certain given the circumstantial evidence; I suspect Pakistan ISI's involvement. The attacks and protests were very coordinated, meticulously planned, and intentional efforts to keep inflaming the situation through social media. No matter what the government did to control the situation, they kept trying to worsen it," he said.</p>

<p>He also pointed out that the rioters attacked police with guns which could only be provided by terror outfits and foreign powers.</p>

<p>On reports of involvement of a US intelligence agency like the CIA, Joy said he had no evidence but added, "maybe, they are". He dismissed any Chinese involvement when asked about it.</p>

<p>Dismissing reports of Hasina seeking asylum in the UK or any other country as "rumours", Joy said the reports of her US Visa being revoked are also untrue.</p>

<p>"Nothing of this sort has been planned (seeking asylum). Sooner or later, there has to be a restoration of democracy in Bangladesh and hopefully, that will be between the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) and Awami League. Then Sheikh Hasina will be back." "At this point, she wants to go back to Bangladesh. It's a question of when rather than if," he said, hinting that the ousted Bangladesh PM will be staying at an undisclosed location in India for now.</p>

<p>Joy, who spent much of his childhood studying in India, appealed to the Indian government to ensure the quick restoration of democracy for stability in the region.</p>

<p>"I want to thank the Indian government for protecting my mother. I owe my heartfelt gratitude to Prime Minister Modi. If India wants stability in its eastern backyard, then they have to pressure the international community and take the lead to ensure the quick restoration of democracy," he said.</p>

<p>Speaking on the 'INDIA-out' campaign in Bangladesh, he said, "the anti-India forces are already very active, and with Awami League out of power, the ISI is now free to supply as many weapons as it wants to the anti-India forces." Joy said India must act fast before anti-India forces gain more ground.</p>

<p>Refuting claims that Ms Hasina ran away to save her own life, he said the family insisted on stopping the bloodshed.</p>

<p>"She was not willing to leave the country. The Prime Minister's security was ready to protect her till the end. But that would have led to hundreds of deaths of protestors who were marching towards the PM's residence. We convinced her for the sake of Bangladesh, we cannot let her get killed," he said.</p>

<p>"Our government was not weak, but my mother did not want to harm the students. Even after her leaving the country, the bloodshed has not stopped. The people will now understand the difference with and without Sheikh Hasina," he said.</p>

<p>The death toll in the anti-government protests in Bangladesh climbed to 440 on Wednesday, with the recovery of 29 more bodies of Hasina's Awami League party members across the country through Tuesday, taking the overall death toll to 469 in nearly three weeks since the protests began in July"Asatya Not J: When Amit Shah Helped Out Kiren Rijiju In Parliament</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/d3t8m64g_bangladesh-protests-reuters_625x300_07_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[He expressed gratitude to PM Modi and his government for protecting his mother]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/4-new-banksy-murals-depicting-animals-appear-in-london-6295151]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[4 New Banksy Murals Depicting Animals Appear In London. What Do They Mean]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/4-new-banksy-murals-depicting-animals-appear-in-london-6295151]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 22:57:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A goat, two elephants, three monkeys and one wolf. Four Banksy murals which have appeared in London this week have left many pondering the meaning behind the elusive street artist's latest work.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A goat, two elephants, three monkeys and one wolf.</p>

<p>Four Banksy murals which have appeared in London this week have left many pondering the meaning behind the elusive street artist's latest work.</p>

<p>It began with the mountain goat on Monday, appearing to be perched on a ledge with rocks falling off and depicted in Banksy's signature stencil style on a wall in Richmond, west London.</p>

<p>Next came two elephant heads, peering out of two blocked out windows on the side of a house in affluent Chelsea, followed by three monkeys which appear to be hanging from a railway bridge near east London's Brick Lane.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/p577brm8_banksy-elephant-mural-reuters_625x300_08_August_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: Reuters</span></p>
</div>

<p>The silhouette of a wolf, howling at the sky, appeared on a satellite dish atop a heavily graffitied building in Peckham, southeast London, on Thursday. Banksy has posted pictures of each on his Instagram account.</p>

<p>London's Metropolitan Police said the satellite dish had been reported stolen within hours of being unveiled. Pictures in local media showed it being removed by a person who had their face covered with a mask.</p>

<p>Theories swirled on social media as to the meaning of the works, by an artist who has highlighted themes such as war and climate change in his previous work.</p>

<p>Some speculated they could be related to the riots and racist attacks that have swept the country in the past week, others to the idea that humanity is seeding its own downfall.</p>

<p>"Nice one Banksy. I see this as a critique on the wild and chaotic behaviour currently erupting across the UK. Far right thugs on the prowl," one user "barrybrexiter" commented on Banksy's Instagram post.</p>

<p>Another "leticia_vega" wrote "Humanity is not going to last ... animals will be taking over."</p>

<p>The Bristol-based artist's last mural, also in London, depicted green paint sprayed across the side of a building to mimic the foliage of a real, heavily pruned tree that stands a few metres in front of it. Many took that mural as speaking to a need to preserve nature.</p>

<p>In December, Banksy depicted three drones on a stop sign, again in Peckham. It was stolen very shortly after it went up.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/qpgh614_banksy-animal-mural-reuters_625x300_08_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A mural depicted three monkeys that appeared to be hanging from a railway bridge.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-f-22-stealth-warplanes-arrive-in-middle-east-amid-fears-of-iran-israel-war-6295101]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US F-22 Warplanes Arrive In Middle East Amid Fears Of Iran-Israel War]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-f-22-stealth-warplanes-arrive-in-middle-east-amid-fears-of-iran-israel-war-6295101]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 22:38:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Advanced American F-22 stealth warplanes arrived in the Middle East on Thursday, the US military said, as Washington boosts its forces in the region ahead of an expected Iranian counterattack on Israel.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Advanced American F-22 stealth warplanes arrived in the Middle East on Thursday, the US military said, as Washington boosts its forces in the region ahead of an expected Iranian counterattack on Israel.</p>

<p>The deployment is part of "force posture changes in the region to mitigate the possibility of regional escalation by Iran or its proxies," US Central Command said on social media, without specifying the number or exact location of the planes.</p>

<p>The Pentagon said last week that Defense Secretary Lloyd Austin had ordered assets including additional warships and a fighter squadron to the region.</p>

<p>Seven American personnel were wounded in a rocket attack in Iraq earlier this week that Washington blamed on an Iran-backed militia group.</p>

<p>And Tehran and its allies are expected to launch an attack on Israel in retaliation for the killing of top Hamas and Hezbollah figures in strikes last week either blamed on or claimed by Israel.</p>

<p>The killings are among the most serious in a series of tit-for-tat attacks that have heightened fears of a regional conflagration stemming from the Gaza war.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/h4dem9g_us-f22-_625x300_08_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Seven American personnel were wounded in a rocket attack in Iraq earlier this week.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/residents-flee-beiruts-hezbollah-stronghold-fearing-israeli-airstrikes-6295064]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Residents Flee Beirut's Hezbollah Stronghold Fearing Israeli Airstrikes]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/residents-flee-beiruts-hezbollah-stronghold-fearing-israeli-airstrikes-6295064]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 22:34:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Batoul and her family have been scrambling to secure housing outside Beirut's southern suburbs where an Israeli strike killed a senior Hezbollah commander last week, but spiking demand has sent prices soaring.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Batoul and her family have been scrambling to secure housing outside Beirut's southern suburbs where an Israeli strike killed a senior Hezbollah commander last week, but spiking demand has sent prices soaring.</p>

<p>Many in the southern suburbs -- a packed residential area known as Dahiyeh which is also a Hezbollah bastion -- have been trying to leave, fearing full-blown war between the Iran-backed group and Israel in the wake of the commander's killing.</p>

<p>"We are with the resistance (Hezbollah) to death," said Batoul, a 29-year-old journalist, declining to give her last name as the matter is sensitive.</p>

<p>"But it's normal to be scared... and look for a safe haven," she told AFP.</p>

<p>Iran and its regional allies have vowed revenge for the killing, blamed on Israel, of Hamas's political leader Ismail Haniyeh in Tehran last week, just hours after the Israeli strike in Beirut's southern suburbs killed Hezbollah's top military commander Fuad Shukr.</p>

<p>Hezbollah has traded near-daily fire with Israeli forces in support of ally Hamas since the Palestinian militant group's October 7 attack on Israel triggered war in Gaza.</p>

<p>After the twin killings, fears have mounted of an all-out war, with foreign airlines suspending Beirut flights and countries urging their nationals to leave.</p>

<p>Last week's Beirut strike also killed an Iranian adviser and five civilians -- three women and two children.</p>

<p>"Whoever says they want to stay in Dahiyeh while it's being bombed is lying to themself," Batoul said.</p>

<p><strong>'No choice'</strong></p>

<p>On Tuesday, Hezbollah chief Hassan Nasrallah said his Shiite Muslim movement and Iran were "obliged to respond" to Israel "whatever the consequences".</p>

<p>Batoul said she had been trying unsuccessfully to rent in "safe areas" -- unaffiliated to Hezbollah -- outside Beirut, but landlords were charging "exorbitant prices".</p>

<p>She said one landlord cancelled suddenly even after she agreed to pay six months' rent in advance for a flat in the mountain town of Sawfar.</p>

<p>A 55-year-old teacher and Hezbollah supporter, who requested anonymity because the matter is sensitive, said she felt lucky to find a flat about 15 kilometres (nine miles) outside Beirut.</p>

<p>But it came with a price tag of $1,500 a month, in a country battered by more than four years of economic crisis.</p>

<p>The teacher, also a Dahiyeh resident, said price gouging was rampant, noting another apartment was listed online for $1,500 a month "but when we arrived, they asked for $2,000".</p>

<p>"They know we have no choice. When there is a war, people will pay any amount of money to be safe," she said.</p>

<p>But "many people will stay (in Dahiyeh) because they cannot afford to rent," she added.</p>

<p>Riyad Bou Fakhreddine, a broker who rents out homes in the Mount Lebanon area near Beirut, said apartments were being snapped up "within half an hour to an hour of being listed".</p>

<p>Some landlords have asked him to raise apartments normally priced at around $500 a month to as high as $2,000, he said.</p>

<p>He said he refused.</p>

<p>"I tell them I'm not a crisis profiteer. I don't want to take advantage of people's fears," he said.</p>

<p><strong>'Polarisation'</strong></p>

<p>Almost 10 months of cross-border violence have killed some 558 people in Lebanon, most of them fighters but also including at least 116 civilians, according to an AFP tally.</p>

<p>On the Israeli side, including in the annexed Golan Heights, 22 soldiers and 25 civilians have been killed, according to army figures.</p>

<p>Ali, who rents serviced apartments in central Beirut, said his phone had "not stopped ringing" ahead of Nasrallah's speech.</p>

<p>"I booked 10 flats in two days," he said.</p>

<p>"Many people walked in and booked on the spot... Or called me and were here within an hour," said the 32-year-old, who requested to be identified only by his first name.</p>

<p>In 2006, Hezbollah fought a devastating war with Israel, whose air force bombarded Beirut's southern suburbs nightly for a month, flattening hundreds of apartment blocks.</p>

<p>Back then, many people from across Lebanon's sectarian divides expressed support for Hezbollah and solidarity with the Shiite Muslim community, many of whom lost their homes and livelihoods.</p>

<p>But this time, Dahiyeh resident Batoul said solidarity was lacking, with politicians divided after Hezbollah decided unilaterally to begin attacking Israeli positions on October 8.</p>

<p>In 2006, "there wasn't such polarisation," she said.</p>

<p>Landlords and others profiting from high demand on housing now are simply driven by greed, Batoul said.</p>

<p><br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/kceck6_beirut-afp-_625x300_08_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Almost 10 months of cross-border violence have killed some 558 people in Lebanon.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/canadian-north-korea-expert-detained-in-switzerland-on-espionage-charges-reports-6294998]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Canadian North Korea Expert Detained In Switzerland On Espionage Charges]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/canadian-north-korea-expert-detained-in-switzerland-on-espionage-charges-reports-6294998]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 22:30:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A former UN official from Canada who now works as a North Korea specialist has been detained in Switzerland on charges of spying, likely for China, media reports said on Thursday, citing unnamed intelligence sources.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A former UN official from Canada who now works as a North Korea specialist has been detained in Switzerland on charges of spying, likely for China, media reports said on Thursday, citing unnamed intelligence sources.</p>

<p>The reports were part of a joint investigation by the German news outlet Der Spiegel, the Swiss media company Tamedia and North Korea-focused website NK News.</p>

<p>The Swiss attorney general's office did not immediately respond to a request for comment on the case.</p>

<p>The suspect regularly travelled to China for his work as an environmental consultant before being arrested earlier in the spring on espionage charges, said NK News, an online outlet that has staff in the US, Europe and South Korea.</p>

<p>It said it did not publish the official's full name as he has not been convicted and authorities have not made public charges against him.</p>

<p>The person, in his 50s and a resident of Geneva, was in pretrial detainment for several months pending the conclusion of an investigation by the Swiss attorney general's office, the NK News report said.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-04/l1qrg5s8_belarus-spying_625x300_07_April_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The person was in pretrial detainment for several months. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>