<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Sep 2024 06:05:59 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-russia-send-greetings-to-kim-jong-un-on-north-koreas-founding-anniversary-6521724]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[China, Russia Send Greetings To Kim Jong On N Korea's Founding Anniversary]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-russia-send-greetings-to-kim-jong-un-on-north-koreas-founding-anniversary-6521724]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Sep 2024 05:29:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Chinese President Xi Jinping and Russian President Vladimir Putin sent greetings to North Korean leader Kim Jong Un on the occasion of North Korea's founding anniversary, state media KCNA said on Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Chinese President Xi Jinping and Russian President Vladimir Putin sent greetings to North Korean leader Kim Jong Un on the occasion of North Korea's founding anniversary, state media KCNA said on Monday.</p>

<p>"I am sure that the comprehensive strategic partnership between Russia and the DPRK will be strengthened in a planned way thanks to our joint efforts," Putin said, according to KCNA.</p>

<p>DPRK is short for the Democratic People's Republic of Korea, the North's official name.</p>

<p>Xi called for deeper strategic communication and cooperation with North Korea in his message, KCNA said.</p>

<p>Last year, Kim marked the country's founding day on Sept 9 with a parade of paramilitary groups and diplomatic exchanges in which he vowed to deepen ties with China and Russia.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/qnmnpi2o_kim-jong-un-afp-_625x300_16_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-house-republican-report-blasts-biden-over-chaotic-afghan-withdrawal-6521723]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US House Republican Report Blasts Biden Over Chaotic Afghan Withdrawal]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-house-republican-report-blasts-biden-over-chaotic-afghan-withdrawal-6521723]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Sep 2024 05:25:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[U.S. House of Representatives Republicans will release a long-awaited report on Monday blasting Democratic President Joe Biden's administration for failures surrounding the chaotic and deadly U.S. withdrawal from Afghanistan in August 2021.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>U.S. House of Representatives Republicans will release a long-awaited report on Monday blasting Democratic President Joe Biden's administration for failures surrounding the chaotic and deadly U.S. withdrawal from Afghanistan in August 2021.</p>

<p>The report contends that the administration made its decision to evacuate noncombatants far too late, formally ordering it only on Aug. 16, failed to communicate between departments in Washington and among officials in Afghanistan, and botched the paperwork for the departure of Afghan civilians eligible to leave the country.</p>

<p>It is the result of a three-year investigation led by Representative Michael McCaul, Republican chair of the House Foreign Affairs Committee.</p>

<p>"America's credibility on the world stage was severely damaged after we abandoned Afghan allies to Taliban reprisal killings - the people of Afghanistan we had promised to protect," the report said. "And the moral injury to America's veterans and those still serving remains a stain on this administration's legacy."</p>

<p>The withdrawal has become intensely politicized ahead of the Nov. 5 U.S. presidential election. Last month, the Republican nominee, former President Donald Trump, shot video for his campaign at Arlington National Cemetery where he appeared at a ceremony honoring troops killed in the evacuation.</p>

<p>Trump has also attacked Biden and Vice President Kamala Harris over the exit from Afghanistan during campaign appearances, blaming them personally for the deaths at Kabul airport's Abbey Gate. On Aug. 26, 2021, as U.S. forces were trying to help Americans and Afghans flee as the Islamist Taliban movement took control of the country, a suicide attack at the Abbey Gate entrance to Kabul's airport killed 13 Americans, compounding the U.S. sense of defeat after two decades of war.</p>

<p>Harris is the Democratic presidential nominee.</p>

<p>Democrats have insisted that some blame for the messy end of the war - less than seven months into Biden's presidency - should be laid at the feet of Trump, who began the withdrawal process by signing a deal with the Taliban in 2020.</p>

<p>"When former President Trump took office, there were approximately 14,000 American troops in Afghanistan. Days before leaving office, the former President ordered a further reduction to 2,500," Representative Gregory Meeks, the top Democrat on the Foreign Affairs panel, said in a letter to committee Democrats about the investigation.</p>

<p>Republican committee aides dismissed that contention as partisan politics, saying Biden could have ignored Trump's agreement or enforced it, accusing officials who served during Biden's presidency of allowing the Taliban to disregard its commitments.</p>

<p>Some 800,000 U.S. servicemembers served in Afghanistan following the U.S.-led invasion triggered by the Sept. 11, 2001, attack on the U.S. by Afghanistan-based al Qaeda.</p>

<p>During the war, 2,238 U.S. servicemembers died and nearly 21,000 were wounded. Independent estimates put the number of Afghan security forces and civilians killed at more than 100,000.</p>

<p>McCaul has subpoenaed Secretary of State Antony Blinken three times in connection with the Afghanistan investigation, most recently last week, saying that he wants him to testify in person.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/vj7m4c84_joe-biden-afp-joe-biden-white-house-afp_625x300_06_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bharat-jodo-yatra-introduced-the-idea-of-love-in-politics-rahul-gandhi-in-us-6521554]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Bharat Jodo Yatra Introduced The Idea Of Love In Politics": Rahul Gandhi]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bharat-jodo-yatra-introduced-the-idea-of-love-in-politics-rahul-gandhi-in-us-6521554]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Sep 2024 04:24:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Rahul Gandhi, the Leader of the Opposition in Lok Sabha, while interacting with the students at the University of Texas, Dallas in the US, said that Bharat Jodo Yatra introduced the idea of love in politics.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Rahul Gandhi, the Leader of the Opposition in Lok Sabha, while interacting with the students at the University of Texas, Dallas in the US, said that Bharat Jodo Yatra introduced the idea of love in politics.</p>

<p>Elaborating the reasons for conducting the Bharat Jodo Yatra, Rahul Gandhi said, "The reason [behind conducting Bharat Jodo Yatra] is that all avenues of communication in India were shut. No matter what we did, it was all shut. We spoke in parliament. That's not televised. We go to the media, they don't pick up what we say. We even go with documents to the legal system, nothing happens. So all our avenues were shut. And for a long time we literally couldn't understand how to communicate. And then suddenly we hit upon the idea... what better way to go directly than to literally go walking across the country? And so that's what we did..."</p>

<p>"But it went surprisingly easy. And it fundamentally changed the way I think about my work... It completely changed how I view politics, how I view our people, how I communicate, how I listen. To me, the most powerful thing that happened organically, was that we introduced certainly for the first time in India, possibly for the first time in many countries, the idea of 'love' in politics. And this is strange... because... [in] the political discourse in most countries, you will never find the word 'love'... You'll find hatred, anger, unfairness, corruption... and the Bharat Jodo Yatra actually introduced that idea into the Indian political system, and it has amazed me how that idea has worked," he said.</p>

<p>The Congress leader also said that India has to think about the act of production and organising production.</p>

<p>"India has to think about the act of production and organising production. It's not acceptable that India simply says, manufacturing or production is going to be the reserve of the Chinese... or Vietnamese... or Bangladeshis. Bangladesh completely outcompetes us in textiles, regardless of the problems they're facing right now... We have to reimagine how to produce in a democratic environment. Until we do that, we will face high levels of unemployment. And frankly, it's not sustainable. So... if we carry on down this path... you're going to see massive social problems coming in India and in the United States and in Europe. The polarization of our politics is because of this," he said.</p>

<p>Talking about issues faced by the youth due to unemployment, the Raebareli MP said that the act of production creates jobs. But India organises consumption, which is the reason of worry.</p>

<p>"If you look at the United States in the 1940s, 50s and 60s, they were the center of global production. Anything that was made- cars, washing machines, TVs- all made in the United States. Production moved from the United States... [then] to Korea, [from there] it went to Japan. Eventually it went to China... China is dominating global production. [In] India, the phones... furniture... clothes, [most are] made in China. That's a fact. The West, America, Europe, India have given up on the idea of production and they've handed it to China. The act of production creates jobs. What we do, Americans do, the west does, is organize consumption. Uber, Foxconn, Mahindra, Bajaj organize production. These are the guys who create the jobs..."</p>

<p>Mr Gandhi added that not all countries have an employment problem.<br />
"Let's be clear. Not everywhere on the planet has an employment problem. The west... [and] India has an employment problem. But there are many countries in the world that don't have an employment problem. China... [and] Vietnam doesn't have an employment problem. So there are places on the planet that are not struggling with unemployment. There's a reason," he said.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/1hho8df8_raga_625x300_09_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/drought-sinks-longest-polish-river-to-record-low-level-6521499]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Drought Sinks Longest Polish River To Record-low Level]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/drought-sinks-longest-polish-river-to-record-low-level-6521499]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Sep 2024 04:04:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Poland's longest river, the Vistula, on Sunday hit a record-low water level in the capital because of drought, the national weather agency said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Poland's longest river, the Vistula, on Sunday hit a record-low water level in the capital because of drought, the national weather agency said.</p>

<p>Its level at one Warsaw measuring station fell to 25 centimetres (10 inches), beating the last record by a centimetre, according to the IMGW weather institute.</p>

<p>"It's worse than in 2015 -- and the water continues to fall!" the institute added on X, formerly Twitter.</p>

<p>Most of Poland's rivers are suffering from drought, IMGW hydrologist Grzegorz Walijewski told AFP last week.</p>

<p>"We've been dealing with hydrological drought in Poland for a while. Since 2015 there's been permanent drought," he said.</p>

<p>He said climate change was to blame, as milder winters with less snow alongside fewer days of rain and higher temperatures push down water levels.</p>

<p>The Vistula, which is the EU member's longest river at more than 1,000 kilometres (621 miles), splits the country in half and deposits in the Baltic Sea.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/u5mvmemg_drought-generic-_625x300_16_May_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/thousands-defy-roadblocks-in-rally-for-pakistan-ex-pm-imran-khan-6521389]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Thousands Defy Roadblocks In Rally For Pakistan Ex PM Imran Khan]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/thousands-defy-roadblocks-in-rally-for-pakistan-ex-pm-imran-khan-6521389]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Sep 2024 03:23:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Thousands of supporters of Pakistan's former prime minister Imran Khan gathered in Islamabad on Sunday despite authorities' attempts to block the protesters' main routes into the capital, AFP journalists noted.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Thousands of supporters of Pakistan's former prime minister Imran Khan gathered in Islamabad on Sunday despite authorities' attempts to block the protesters' main routes into the capital, AFP journalists noted.</p>

<p>The demonstration, led by Khan's Pakistan Tehreek-e-Insaf (PTI) party, is the largest in Islamabad since the retired international cricketer was jailed last year on several charges, some of them still before the courts.</p>

<p>The rally's "size and popularity ensure (PTI's) mobilization capabilities remain intact despite relentless attempts to curb it," said Michael Kugelman, Pakistan specialist at the Wilson Center, a US-based think tank.</p>

<p>Protesters on Sunday cleared containers used by Pakistani authorities to block major roads into Islamabad ahead of the demonstration.</p>

<p>"They closed the city with containers. But despite this, thousands are here. They cannot stop this motivation and emotions the people have right now," Humayun Mohmand, a PTI senator, told AFP.</p>

<p>In jail since August 2023, Khan insists along with his party that the charges against him are designed to prevent him from returning to office.</p>

<p>Backed by the military, which wields enormous influence, he rose to power in 2018 by standing against widespread corruption embedded in the country's revolving door of dynastic politics.</p>

<p>But he was ousted in 2022 after falling out with the military establishment.</p>

<p>That furthered a sense of helplessness and frustration among many Pakistanis who want the generals to stay out of politics in a country that has been ruled by the military on and off for much of its history, and where a civilian prime minister has never served a full term.</p>

<p>Khan's first arrest, on corruption charges in May 2023, sparked nationwide demonstrations by supporters expressing anger at the army. In response, the army orchestrated a massive crackdown on the PTI.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/7pt9hf3g_imran-khan-rally_625x300_09_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Protesters on Sunday cleared containers used by Pakistani authorities to block major roads]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukraine-attacks-oil-storage-depot-in-russian-border-region-reservoirs-catch-fire-6521363]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ukraine Attacks Oil Storage Depot In Russian Border Region]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukraine-attacks-oil-storage-depot-in-russian-border-region-reservoirs-catch-fire-6521363]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Sep 2024 03:17:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The governor of Russia's southern Belgorod region said on Sunday Ukrainian forces attacked a fuel depot, triggering a series of fires after Moscow and Kyiv accused each other of launching overnight attacks on border regions.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The governor of Russia's southern Belgorod region said on Sunday Ukrainian forces attacked a fuel depot, triggering a series of fires after Moscow and Kyiv accused each other of launching overnight attacks on border regions.</p>

<p>"The Ukrainian military, aided by lethal drones, attacked a fuel storage site in Volokonovsky district," Vyacheslav Gladkov wrote on Telegram, referring to an area near the border.</p>

<p>"Several reservoirs caught fire in an explosion. Firefighting crews are putting out the blaze."</p>

<p>Gladkov also reported drone attacks on three other localities. There were no casualties reported in the incidents.</p>

<p>In the overnight air attacks, Ukrainian officials said two people died and four were injured in Sumy region. Gladkov reported three civilians were injured in Belgorod.</p>

<p>Two children were among those injured in Sumy, the military administration of the northeastern Ukrainian region said on Sunday on Telegram. Several homes and cars were damaged.</p>

<p>In Belgorod region, three civilians, including two children, were injured. Gladkov said two residential buildings were destroyed and more than 15 buildings in total were damaged.</p>

<p>The Russian defence ministry said it had destroyed one drone over Belgorod region and another over Kursk region, where Ukrainian forces launched a cross-border incursion last month. It said two drones were intercepted over Belgorod overnight.</p>

<p>Reuters could not independently verify the reports.</p>

<p>Border regions on both sides have been subject to frequent attacks. Both Moscow and Kyiv deny targeting civilians, saying the attacks are aimed at destroying each other's infrastructure critical to war efforts.</p>

<p>Thousands of civilians have died in the war, which Russia started with a full-scale invasion on Ukraine in February 2022. Millions of Ukrainians have also been displaced, while their cities and villages have become piles of rubble</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/dihogkno_russia-ukraine_625x300_09_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/another-fire-breaks-out-at-kenyan-school-third-incident-in-2-days-6521360]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Another Fire Breaks Out At Kenyan School, Third Incident In 2 Days]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/another-fire-breaks-out-at-kenyan-school-third-incident-in-2-days-6521360]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Sep 2024 03:12:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A blaze destroyed a dormitory at a Kenyan school on Sunday, police said, the third such incident in just days.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A blaze destroyed a dormitory at a Kenyan school on Sunday, police said, the third such incident in just days.</p>

<p>A dorm at Njia Boys High School in the central county of Meru caught fire as students were having supper and no casualties were reported, a police statement said.</p>

<p>The building housing about 150 students "completely burnt down, the inferno consuming everything, and property of unknown value was destroyed", it said.</p>

<p>Last Thursday, 21 boys perished when flames engulfed their dormitory at the Hillside Endarasha Academy in Nyeri county as they were sleeping.</p>

<p>And on Saturday, another fire erupted at a girls' high school in Isiolo county, also in the centre of the country.</p>

<p>A local official said there were several injuries, but police said no one was hurt.</p>

<p>Last week's deadly inferno has thrown the spotlight on safety at Kenya's schools, with President William Ruto vowing that those responsible would be brought to justice.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-05/c590rf94_fire-generic_625x300_17_May_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Last week's deadly inferno has thrown the spotlight on safety at Kenya's schools (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/21-killed-67-injured-in-market-shelling-in-sudan-report-6521334]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[21 Killed, 67 Injured In Market Shelling In Sudan: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/21-killed-67-injured-in-market-shelling-in-sudan-report-6521334]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Sep 2024 03:08:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Shelling at a market in Sennar in southeast Sudan killed 21 people and wounded another 67 on Sunday, a medical source told AFP, blaming paramilitaries for the attack.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Shelling at a market in Sennar in southeast Sudan killed 21 people and wounded another 67 on Sunday, a medical source told AFP, blaming paramilitaries for the attack.</p>

<p>The Sudan Doctors Network, which was set up after the start of the war in April 2023, reported a similar death count, but said the number of wounded was more than 70. It blamed the paramilitary Rapid Support Forces (RSF) for the shelling.</p>

<p>The RSF, led by Mohamed Hamdan Daglo, is fighting the Sudanese army under the country's de facto ruler Abdel Fattah al-Burhan.</p>

<p>The government has in the past accused the RSF of systematically targeting civilians and civilian institutions.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-04/870oehpg_sudan-clashes-reuters_625x300_18_April_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The government has in the past accused the RSF of systematically targeting civilians (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/golden-eagle-attacks-norwegian-toddler-killed-by-gamekeeper-report-6521042]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Golden Eagle Attacks Norwegian Toddler, Killed By Gamekeeper: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/golden-eagle-attacks-norwegian-toddler-killed-by-gamekeeper-report-6521042]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Sep 2024 01:25:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A golden eagle attacked a toddler in Norway on Sunday, with her mother and a neighbour fighting the bird off repeatedly until a game warden killed it, Norwegian media reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A golden eagle attacked a toddler in Norway on Sunday, with her mother and a neighbour fighting the bird off repeatedly until a game warden killed it, Norwegian media reported.</p>

<p>The 20-month-old girl, who was playing on her family's farm in Trondelag in central Norway when the eagle swooped down on her, required stitches to the back of her head and had scratches from the eagle's talons on her face, her father told public broadcaster NRK.</p>

<p>"The eagle came out of nowhere and grabbed our youngest daughter," said the father, whose name was not disclosed.</p>

<p>"Her mother jumped up and grabbed hold of the eagle, but had to fight to get it to let go. A neighbour also had to help her and our little girl," he said.</p>

<p>Gamekeeper Per Kare Vinterdal, who killed the eagle, told NRK the bird saw the little girl as "prey".</p>

<p>He said the mother and neighbour managed to get the eagle off the girl "but it kept coming back" even though "the neighbour chased it away with a stick".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/svphobi_eagle-generic_625x300_26_June_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Gamekeeper Per Kare Vinterdal killed the eagle (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kolkata-doctor-rape-murder-rg-kar-hospital-protests-across-25-countries-over-130-cities-over-kolkata-rape-murder-case-6520789]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Protests Across 25 Countries Over Kolkata Rape-Murder Case]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kolkata-doctor-rape-murder-rg-kar-hospital-protests-across-25-countries-over-130-cities-over-kolkata-rape-murder-case-6520789]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:03:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Thousands of diaspora Indians were protesting in more than 130 cities across 25 countries on Sunday, organisers said, to demand justice after last month's rape and murder of a trainee doctor at a hospital in the city of Kolkata.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Thousands of members of the Indian community were protesting in more than 130 cities across 25 countries on Sunday, organisers said, to demand justice after last month's rape and murder of a trainee doctor at a hospital in the city of Kolkata.</p>

<p>The protests started in large and small groups across Japan, Australia, Taiwan and Singapore, before spreading to cities in several European countries. Sixty were planned in the U.S.</p>

<p>They added to ongoing protests around India after the August 9 killing of the 31-year-old postgraduate student of chest medicine.</p>

<p>A suspect has been arrested along with the former principal of R.G. Kar Medical College where the victim was studying.</p>

<p>At one of the protests in the Swedish capital Stockholm, scores of mainly black-clad women gathered in Sergels Torg square to sing songs in Bengali and hold signs, demanding accountability for the crime and safety for Indian women.</p>

<p>"The news of this heinous crime committed on a young trainee doctor while on duty numbed and shocked each of us at the sheer ruthlessness, brutality and disregard of human life," said Dipti Jain, an organiser of the global protests.</p>

<p>Ms Jain, now a British citizen and alumni of the Calcutta National Medical College and Hospital, had last month organised a female doctors protest in the UK.</p>

<p>The Supreme Court has listed the next hearing of the trainee's case for Monday.</p>

<p>Although tougher laws were introduced after the 2012 gruesome gang rape and murder of a 23-year-old student on a moving bus in New Delhi, activists say the Kolkata case shows how women continue to suffer from sexual violence.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/7aathulg_worldwide-protests-kolkata-horror_625x300_09_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sixty protests were planned in the US]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/national-grandparents-day-kamala-harris-recalls-long-walks-with-her-grandfather-and-what-they-discussed-6520786]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris Recalls Walks With Her Grandfather,  And What They Discussed]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/national-grandparents-day-kamala-harris-recalls-long-walks-with-her-grandfather-and-what-they-discussed-6520786]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:01:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Indian-origin Democratic presidential candidate Kamala Harris on Sunday, recalling her fond memories with her grandparents in India, wished National Grandparents Day to all the grandparents who help shape and inspire the next generation.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Indian-origin Democratic presidential candidate Kamala Harris on Sunday, recalling her fond memories with her grandparents in India, wished National Grandparents Day to all the grandparents who help shape and inspire the next generation.</p>

<p>"As a young girl visiting my grandparents in India, my grandfather took me on his morning walks, where he would discuss the importance of fighting for equality and fighting corruption. He was a retired civil servant who had been part of the movement to win India's independence," Ms Harris said in a post on X.</p>

<p>"My grandmother travelled across India-bullhorn in hand-to speak with women about accessing birth control," the incumbent vice-president said.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">As a young girl visiting my grandparents in India, my grandfather took me on his morning walks, where he would discuss the importance of fighting for equality and fighting corruption. He was a retired civil servant who had been part of the movement to win India's independence.… <a href="https://t.co/vOpgtsomQN">pic.twitter.com/vOpgtsomQN</a></p>
— Kamala Harris (@KamalaHarris) <a href="https://twitter.com/KamalaHarris/status/1832805919781974438?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 8, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The Democrat added that her grandparents' "commitment to public service and fight for a better future" lived in her today.</p>

<p>"Happy National Grandparents Day to all the grandparents who help shape and inspire the next generation," Kamala Harris, who is contesting against former president Donald Trump, said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/7crakfag_kamala-harris-childhood_625x300_09_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kamala Harris is contesting against former president Donald Trump]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-debate-donald-trump-kamala-harris-tied-in-latest-polls-ahead-of-televised-presidential-debate-6520668]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump, Harris Tied In Latest Polls Ahead Of Televised Presidential Debate]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-debate-donald-trump-kamala-harris-tied-in-latest-polls-ahead-of-televised-presidential-debate-6520668]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Sep 2024 23:38:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The US presidential race remains neck-and-neck according to polls released Sunday, two days before Kamala Harris and Donald Trump hold their first -- and potentially only -- televised debate.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The US presidential race remains neck-and-neck according to polls released Sunday, two days before Kamala Harris and Donald Trump hold their first -- and potentially only -- televised debate.</p>

<p>The latest polling confirms that Trump retains locked-in support from about half of voters, despite the Republican's historic status as a convicted felon and his role in instigating the unprecedented attempt to overturn his 2020 loss to Joe Biden.</p>

<p>Harris, who only jumped into the race after President Biden abruptly quit in July, has rapidly transformed herself from a little-noticed vice president into a serious contender. However, the polls show she has not made a major breakthrough, leaving the race a toss-up.</p>

<p>A New York Times/Siena poll found that 78-year-old Trump is leading Harris nationally by 48 to 47 percent, well within the margin of error.</p>

<p>US presidential elections are decided by tallying the results of state-by-state contests, rather than an overall national popular vote, meaning that a tiny handful of swing states typically decide the balance.</p>

<p>The poll found Harris, 59, narrowly ahead in Wisconsin, Michigan and Pennsylvania and tied in four other swing states -- Nevada, Georgia, North Carolina and Arizona.</p>

<p>A CBS News/YouGov poll put Harris ahead by one percentage point in Michigan and Wisconsin and tied in Pennsylvania.</p>

<p>The election is already chaotic, with 81-year-old Biden dropping out amid concerns over his age, Trump narrowly surviving an assassin's bullet at a rally, and fears mounting that Trump will again refuse to concede if he loses in November.</p>

<p>However, the latest numbers confirm that each candidate retains a remarkably stable base of loyalists, almost evenly splitting the country.</p>

<p>One game changer could be Tuesday's ABC News debate, the only one scheduled between the two.</p>

<p>Trump will be under pressure to rein in his characteristic use of insults and intimidation as he stands next to a mixed-race candidate vying to become the first female president in US history.</p>

<p>Harris will need to use the huge viewership to connect with Americans in a way that she was unable to as vice president and has had little time to accomplish in her super-condensed campaign run.</p>

<p>With Trump now the oldest presidential nominee in US history, she is pitching an optimistic, forward-looking message in contrast to Trump's apocalyptic claims that the country faces terminal decline without him in the White House.</p>

<p><strong>Sexist taunts</strong></p>

<p>At the same time, Harris will have to solve the conundrum of how to debate Trump, who habitually makes false statements on nearly every topic and loves to get under his opponents' skin. Biden, in his only debate against Trump before dropping his candidacy, found himself entirely unable to cope.</p>

<p>Already, Trump has been subjecting Harris in his speeches to racist and sexist taunts, deliberately mispronouncing her name and calling her "crazy" and a "Marxist."</p>

<p>"It will take almost superhuman focus and discipline to deal with Donald Trump in a debate," Harris supporter and current transportation secretary Pete Buttigieg told CNN.</p>

<p>The Harris campaign announced it would "barnstorm battleground states" after the debate, beginning in North Carolina, then Pennsylvania.</p>

<p>Trump held a rally in Wisconsin on Saturday where he appealed to his mostly white, working class base with a dark speech claiming that he is struggling against a "rogue regime" where Democrats "imported murderers, child predators and serial rapists from all over the planet."</p>

<p>On his Truth Social platform, he warned that once back in the White House he would impose "long prison sentences" on all those he said were planning "cheating" in November.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ugf3uu1g_trump-harris-_625x300_22_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Latest numbers confirm that each candidate retains a remarkably stable base of loyalists. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-we-are-afraid-israeli-strike-kills-gaza-civil-emergency-service-director-6520591]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["We Are Afraid": Israeli Strike Kills Gaza Civil Emergency Service Director]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-we-are-afraid-israeli-strike-kills-gaza-civil-emergency-service-director-6520591]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Sep 2024 23:20:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An Israeli airstrike on a house in Jabalia on Sunday killed Mohammad Morsi, deputy director of the Gaza Civil Emergency Service in the northern areas of the Gaza Strip, and four of his family, health officials said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An Israeli airstrike on a house in Jabalia on Sunday killed Mohammad Morsi, deputy director of the Gaza Civil Emergency Service in the northern areas of the Gaza Strip, and four of his family, health officials said.</p>

<p>The Civil Emergency Service said in a statement that Morsi's death raised to 83 the number of its members killed by Israeli fire since Oct. 7.</p>

<p>There was no immediate Israeli comment on Morsi's death.</p>

<p>Residents said Israeli forces had also blown up several houses in the Zeitoun suburb of Gaza City 5 km from Jabalia. Medical teams said they were unable to answer desperate calls by some of the residents who had reported being trapped inside their houses, some wounded.</p>

<p>"We hear constant bombing in Zeitoun, we know they are blowing up houses there, we don't sleep because of the sounds of explosions, the roaring of tanks sound close and the drones don't stop circling," said one resident of Gaza City, who lives around 1 km away.</p>

<p>"The occupation is wiping out Zeitoun, we are afraid about the people trapped in there," he told Reuters via a chat app, refusing to be named.</p>

<p>Later on Sunday, the Gaza health ministry said Israeli military strikes across the enclave killed at least 15 people.</p>

<p>Residents of central and southern Gaza areas reported interruption in internet and communication services, which the Palestinian Telecommunication Company said was because of "the ongoing (Israeli) aggression."</p>

<p>Palestinians say internet and communication outages, the first in months, impact the ability of medical staffers to dispatch ambulances to bombed areas and make it difficult for people to check on their relatives or report attacks.</p>

<p>Israel and Hamas continued to blame one another for the failure of mediators, including Qatar, Egypt and the U.S., to broker a ceasefire. The U.S. is preparing to present a new proposal, but the prospects of a breakthrough appear dim as gaps between the sides' positions remain large.</p>

<p>Meanwhile on Sunday the United Nations, in collaboration with local health authorities, extended by a day a campaign to vaccinate children in the southern Gaza Strip against polio before it moves on Monday to the north.</p>

<p>The campaign aims to vaccinate 640,000 children in Gaza after its first polio case in around 25 years. Limited pauses in the fighting have allowed the campaign to proceed.</p>

<p>U.N. officials said they were making progress, having reached more than half of the children needing the drops in the first two stages in the southern and central Gaza Strip. A second round of vaccination will be required four weeks after the first.</p>

<p>The latest bloodshed in the decades-old Israeli-Palestinian conflict was triggered on Oct. 7 when the Hamas group attacked Israel, killing 1,200 and taking about 250 hostages, according to Israeli tallies.</p>

<p>Israel's subsequent assault on Gaza has killed more than 40,900 Palestinians, according to the local health ministry, while also displacing nearly the entire population of 2.3 million, causing a hunger crisis and leading to genocide allegations at the World Court, which Israel denies.</p>

<p>The Palestinian health ministry does not distinguish between combatants and non-combatants in its casualty reports, but health officials say that most of the fatalities have been civilians.</p>

<p>Israel, which has lost 340 soldiers in Gaza, says at least a third of the Palestinian dead are fighters.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/h828s4n8_gaza-reuters-_625x300_04_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel says at least a third of the Palestinian dead are fighters. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/48-killed-after-fuel-truck-explodes-in-nigeria-after-collision-with-vehicle-6520563]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[48 Killed After Fuel Truck Explodes In Nigeria After Collision With Vehicle]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/48-killed-after-fuel-truck-explodes-in-nigeria-after-collision-with-vehicle-6520563]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Sep 2024 23:15:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[At least 48 people were killed on Sunday in a fuel tanker truck explosion following a collision with another vehicle in north-central Nigeria, the state's disaster management agency said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At least 48 people were killed on Sunday in a fuel tanker truck explosion following a collision with another vehicle in north-central Nigeria, the state's disaster management agency said.</p>

<p>The State Emergency Management Agency in north-central Niger state said the fuel truck collided with a truck carrying travellers and cattle. Several other vehicles were also caught up in the accident, it said.</p>

<p>The agency's spokesperson Hussaini Ibrahim put the death count at 48 and officials were still trying to clear the scene of the incident.</p>

<p>Nigeria's state-owned firm NNPC Ltd last week hiked the price of gasoline by at least 39%, the second major increase in more than a year but shortages have continued, forcing motorists to queue for hours in the country's major cities and towns.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-02/rr7gtng_blast-generic-fire-generic-unsplash_625x300_27_February_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Nigeria's state-owned firm last week hiked the price of gasoline by at least 39% (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/violent-clouds-4-dead-14-missing-after-heavy-flooding-morocco-6520239]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Violent Clouds": 4 Dead, 14 Missing After Heavy Flooding Morocco]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/violent-clouds-4-dead-14-missing-after-heavy-flooding-morocco-6520239]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Sep 2024 22:08:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Moroccan authorities on Sunday said four people died and 14 were missing in flooding caused by an "exceptional" climate phenomenon in southern areas.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Moroccan authorities on Sunday said four people died and 14 were missing in flooding caused by an "exceptional" climate phenomenon in southern areas.</p>

<p>"Four people have died and 14 have gone missing" since heavy rains began on Friday in the province of Tata, some 740 kilometres south of Rabat, a local official told AFP, saying the death count could potentially rise.</p>

<p>"Eight houses were washed away by floods in some valleys" near Tamanart, a rural area in the Tata region, said the official, who did not wish to be named.</p>

<p>Usually arid areas in southern Morocco and Algeria have been drenched in floods caused by massive rainfall since Friday, officials told AFP Sunday.</p>

<p>Areas in southern Morocco have been affected "by an extremely unstable tropical air mass", the spokesman for the Moroccan General Directorate of Meteorology, Lhoussaine Youabd, told AFP.</p>

<p>This "led to the formation of unstable and violent clouds" that caused massive rainfall, he said.</p>

<p>Youabd described the phenomenon as "exceptional" and said the areas saw "heavy thunderstorms and significant rainfall, leading to river flooding" as "humid tropical air masses moved northward".</p>

<p>As a result, the Ouarzazate region received 47 millimetres of water in three hours, and Tagounite, near the Algerian border, some 170 millimetres, according to the Moroccan weather service.</p>

<p>The heavy rains hit regions of Morocco that have been suffering from drought for at least six years.</p>

<p>In neighbouring Algeria, authorities meanwhile confirmed one person dead and one missing in flooding in the south.</p>

<p>Algerian civil defence said an unnamed young girl was swept away by the waters in Illizi, in the far south, and another person who was trapped in a vehicle was still missing.</p>

<p>It also said it had rescued several families trapped by flooded rivers, mostly in Illizi and Bechar, also in the south.</p>

<p>Videos posted on social media showed that some areas in the Sahara desert were drenched.</p>

<p>In Morocco's Ouarzazate, entire streets were flooded.</p>

<p>"We haven't seen such rain for about 10 years," Omar Gana, a local, told AFP.</p>

<p>Morocco has been experiencing severe water stress after six consecutive years of drought, shrinking dam levels to less than 28 percent of capacity by the end of August.</p>

<p>The rains were accompanied by strong winds, reaching up to 100 kilometres per hour in Ouarzazate and 76 km/h in Marrakesh, where they caused "an optical phenomenon, giving the sky an orange tint", according to the General Directorate of Meteorology.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/f499p918_morocco-flooding_625x300_08_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[In Morocco's Ouarzazate, entire streets were flooded.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russian-military-drone-crashes-on-nato-territory-says-latvia-6519914]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russian Military Drone Crashes On NATO Territory, Says Latvia]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russian-military-drone-crashes-on-nato-territory-says-latvia-6519914]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Sep 2024 21:09:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Latvia's president on Sunday said a Russian military drone had crashed on its territory, adding that airspace breaches had increased along NATO's eastern borders.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Latvia's president on Sunday said a Russian military drone had crashed on its territory, adding that airspace breaches had increased along NATO's eastern borders.</p>

<p>The Baltic state, which was once ruled by the Soviet Union but is now an EU and NATO member, has had tense relations with Moscow following independence, and ties have further deteriorated since Russia invaded Ukraine in February 2022.</p>

<p>A "Russian military drone... crashed in the eastern part of Latvia yesterday. There is an ongoing investigation," Latvian President Edgars Rinkevics said on X.</p>

<p>"We are in close contact with our allies. The number of such incidents is increasing along the eastern flank of NATO and we must address them collectively," he added.</p>

<p>Latvia's defence ministry said in a statement that the drone had flown into the country's airspace from Belarus and crashed in the municipality of Rezekne.</p>

<p>"This situation is a confirmation that we need to continue the work we have started to strengthen Latvia's eastern border, including the development of air defence capabilities and electronic warfare capabilities to limit the activities of UAVs of different applications," said Defence Minister Andris Spruds.</p>

<p>Fellow NATO member Romania also on Sunday said a Russian attack drone targeting civilian infrastructure in neighbouring Ukraine overnight had entered its airspace.</p>

<p>Bucharest strongly condemned the "renewed violation" brought on by Moscow's "illegal attacks".</p>

<p>Since launching its invasion, Russia has repeatedly carried out night attacks on cities across Ukraine, frequently targeting ports in the southern Odesa region after exiting a grain export deal.</p>

<p>Poland has also recorded at least two cases of its airspace being violated by Russian missiles or drones attacking Ukraine, most recently in December.</p>

<p>Warsaw late last month declared that a flying object had intruded into its airspace but later backtracked on the claim.</p>

<p>In an interview with the Financial Times published last week, Polish Foreign Minister Radoslaw Sikorski said Warsaw should have the right to shoot down Russian missiles targeting Ukraine before they enter Polish airspace, despite NATO opposition.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-10/6e8i71v_missile-generic_650x400_17_October_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Poland has also recorded 2 cases of its airspace being violated by Russian strikes. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-mass-shooting-suspects-mother-warned-school-on-call-before-attack-report-6519604]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Mass Shooting Suspect's Mother Warned School Before Attack: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-mass-shooting-suspects-mother-warned-school-on-call-before-attack-report-6519604]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Sep 2024 20:11:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The mother of the teenager charged with fatally shooting two students and two teachers at a Georgia high school on Wednesday called the school that morning and warned a counselor about an "extreme emergency," the Washington Post reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The mother of the teenager charged with fatally shooting two students and two teachers at a Georgia high school on Wednesday called the school that morning and warned a counselor about an "extreme emergency," the Washington Post reported.</p>

<p>Marcee Gray, the mother of the suspected shooter, 14-year-old Colt Gray, said she told the counselor to find her son immediately, the newspaper reported. Phone records provided by a relative to the Post show a 10-minute call to Apalachee High School in Winder, Georgia, at 9:50 a.m., about 30 minutes before the attack began.</p>

<p>Gray declined to detail what prompted her call but told the Post on Saturday she had shared that with law enforcement. She expressed remorse for the "pain and suffering" that the victims and their families are going through.</p>

<p>A school administrator went to her son's math class that morning, according to another student, the Post reported, but he was not in the room.</p>

<p>The Georgia Bureau of Investigation, the lead investigative agency, referred questions to the Piedmont Judicial Circuit District Attorney's Office, which is prosecuting the case. The office did not immediately respond to a request for comment on Sunday.</p>

<p>Colt Gray has been charged as an adult with four counts of murder. His father, Colin Gray, is also charged with murder, involuntary manslaughter and cruelty to children, in an emerging legal strategy to hold parents responsible for allowing access to firearms to minors who carry out attacks.</p>

<p>Prosecutors say Colin Gray provided the weapon used in the shooting.</p>

<p>In May 2023, investigators from a neighboring county interviewed both Colin and Colt Gray about online threats to carry out a school shooting. Colt Gray said he had not made the threats, and his father said his son did not have free access to his hunting rifles.</p>

<p>The case was closed after investigators could not substantiate that either Gray was connected to the threats.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/fs1b6gm_colt-gray_625x300_08_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Colt Gray has been charged as an adult with four counts of murder. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chinese-man-dies-from-organ-failure-after-working-for-104-days-with-only-1-day-off-6519534]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Chinese Man, 30, Dies After Working For 104 Days With Only 1 Day Off]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chinese-man-dies-from-organ-failure-after-working-for-104-days-with-only-1-day-off-6519534]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Sep 2024 20:01:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[He died from multiple organ failure due to a pneumococcal infection, often linked to a weakened immune system.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a tragic incident that highlights the devastating effects of overwork, a 30-year-old Chinese man died from organ failure after a gruelling 104-day work stretch with only one day of rest. According to the <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3277316/china-man-30-worked-104-days-1-day-dies-organ-failure-court-orders-compensation" rel="nofollow, noindex">South China Morning Post</a></em>,&nbsp;the man identified as A'bao, who worked as a painter, contracted a pneumococcal infection leading to his death in June 2023. Notably,&nbsp;A'bao had entered into a contractual agreement with a company&nbsp;in February last year, committing to work on a project until January of this year.</p>

<p>Following the signing of the contract, A'bao was assigned to a work project located in Zhoushan, a city in the eastern Chinese province of Zhejiang. He then&nbsp;embarked on an exhausting work schedule, working every day for 104 consecutive days from February to May last year, with only one day of rest on April 6. On May 25, he finally took a sick day, feeling unwell and spending the day resting in his dormitory. However, his condition rapidly deteriorated, and by May 28, he had to be rushed to the hospital by his colleagues. Doctors diagnosed him with a lung infection and respiratory failure. He died on June 1.</p>

<p>After his death, his family filed a lawsuit against his employer, alleging gross negligence. The legal action came after social security officials controversially ruled that A'bao's death could not be classified as a work-related injury, citing the timing of his death as the reason. However, his family argued that the prolonged period of excessive work and lack of rest contributed directly to A'bao's death.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the company also claimed that A'bao's workload was reasonable and that any additional hours worked were voluntary. Further, the company shifted the blame to A'bao's pre-existing health conditions and alleged that his failure to seek timely medical attention aggravated his situation.&nbsp;</p>

<p>However, a Chinese court ruled in favour of the painter's family, holding A'bao's employer 20% liable for his death.&nbsp;The court found that A'bao died from multiple organ failure due to a pneumococcal infection, often linked to a weakened immune system. The court also determined&nbsp;that A'bao's prolonged work period of 104 consecutive days was a blatant violation of Chinese Labour Law, which explicitly stipulates a maximum of 8 working hours per day and an average of 44 hours per week.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The court awarded A'bao's family a total of 400,000 yuan (approximately Rs 47,46,000) in compensation, comprising financial reparation and a separate sum of 10,000 yuan for emotional distress. Though the company appealed, the original verdict was upheld in August.&nbsp;</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/94adrob_man-in-hospital_625x300_08_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The court awarded his family a total of 400,000 yuan (approximately Rs 47,46,000) in compensation]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/greece-to-impose-fee-on-cruise-passengers-to-mykonos-and-santorini-6519473]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Greece To Impose Fee On Cruise Passengers To Mykonos And Santorini]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/greece-to-impose-fee-on-cruise-passengers-to-mykonos-and-santorini-6519473]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Sep 2024 19:54:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Greece plans to impose a 20-euro levy on cruise ship visitors to the islands of Santorini and Mykonos during the peak summer season, in a bid to avert overtourism, Prime Minister Kyriakos Mitsotakis said on Sunday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Greece plans to impose a 20-euro levy on cruise ship visitors to the islands of Santorini and Mykonos during the peak summer season, in a bid to avert overtourism, Prime Minister Kyriakos Mitsotakis said on Sunday.</p>

<p>Greece relies heavily on tourism, the main driver of the country's economy which is still recovering from a decade-long crisis that wiped out a fourth of its output.</p>

<p>But some of its most popular destinations, including Santorini, an idyllic island of quaint villages and pristine beaches with 20,000 permanent residents, risk being ruined by mass tourism.</p>

<p>Speaking at a press conference a day after outlining his main economic policies for 2025, Mitsotakis clarified that excessive tourism was only a problem in a few destinations.</p>

<p>"Greece does not have a structural overtourism problem... Some of its destinations have a significant issue during certain weeks or months of the year, which we need to deal with," he said.</p>

<p>"Cruise shipping has burdened Santorini and Mykonos and this is why we are proceeding with interventions," he added, announcing the levy.</p>

<p>Greek tourism revenues stood at about 20 billion euros in 2023 on the back of nearly 31 million tourist arrivals.</p>

<p>In Santorini, protesters have called for curbs on tourism, as in other popular holiday destinations in Europe, including Venice and Barcelona.</p>

<p>Part of the revenues from the cruise shipping tax will be returned to local communities to be invested in infrastructure, Mitsotakis said.</p>

<p>The government also plans to regulate the number of cruise ships that arrive simultaneously at certain destinations, while rules to protect the environment and tackle water shortages must also be imposed on islands, he said.</p>

<p>Greece also wants to increase a tax on short-term rentals and ban new licenses for such rentals in central Athens to increase the housing stock for permanent residents, Mitsotakis said on Saturday.</p>

<p>The government will detail some of the measures on Monday.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/hc5iuvrg_greece-tourist-afp_625x300_08_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Greece relies heavily on tourism, which is the main driver of the country's economy]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/egyptian-archaeologist-calls-on-berlin-to-return-queen-nefertiti-bust-6519427]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Egyptian Archaeologist Calls On Berlin To Return Queen Nefertiti Bust]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/egyptian-archaeologist-calls-on-berlin-to-return-queen-nefertiti-bust-6519427]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Sep 2024 19:40:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prominent Egyptian archaeologist and former antiquities minister Zahi Hawass has launched a petition for the return to Egypt of the pharaonic bust of Queen Nefertiti from the Neues Museum in Berlin.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prominent Egyptian archaeologist and former antiquities minister Zahi Hawass has launched a petition for the return to Egypt of the pharaonic bust of Queen Nefertiti from the Neues Museum in Berlin.</p>

<p>Nefertiti's famous painted limestone bust was uncovered at Tell el-Amarna, around 300 km (185 miles) south of Cairo, in 1912 by a German archaeological mission, which shipped it to Berlin the following year.</p>

<p>Amarna was the short-lived capital of Nefertiti's husband, the 18th dynasty Pharaoh Akhenaten, who reigned until about 1335 BC.</p>

<p>Akhenaten, called the heretic king, was notorious for promoting the worship of the god Aten to the exclusion of Egypt's other gods. His reign also introduced a radical change in Egyptian art.</p>

<p>In his petition launched on Saturday, Hawass asked for the return of the bust, saying it was removed from Egypt illegally after its discovery.</p>

<p>"We announce today that Egypt - this is the national committee, it is not a government committee - asks for the return of the bust of Nefertiti," Hawass said.</p>

<p>"What I need from everyone here is to go to my website... hawasszahi.com, and you will sign, one signature, to show that you would love for this bust to come back."</p>

<p>Hawass said he is not calling for the repatriation of artefacts taken out of Egypt legally. His campaign is focused on repatriating "three main beautiful objects" including the bust of Nefertiti, the Rosetta Stone and the Dendera Zodiac.</p>

<p>Officials at Berlin's Neues Museum were not immediately available for comment.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/th2rirg8_nefertiti-reuters_625x300_08_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Queen Nefertiti's famous painted limestone bust is currently housed at the Neues Museum in Berlin]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>